Welcome everyone to the advanced Quanto IPN topic section of the course now that we understand the basics
of algorithmic trading with Quanto open platform let's move on to discuss some more advanced topics.
We'll cover the following topics in this section.
First off we'll go through a real example of a pipeline structure using Quanto in previously in the
last section we discussed how pipelines generally work but we haven't actually seen and implemented
example using the ID.
Then we'll discuss various other topics such as leverage hedging.
We'll discuss PI Foleo for portfolio analysis.
We'll show you how to use stock sentiment as a trading strategy.
And then finally we'll discuss futures OK.
Let's get started.
I'll see at the next lecture.