Welcome back everyone.
And this lecture we're going to quickly go over the pandas visualization exercises the problems and
in the next lecture We'll show you the solutions for them.
All right here I am at the exercise notebook and basically a quick exercise for you to review the various
plots that we showed the previous lecture and what I want you to do is actually use the F 3 as the C
S V file source for data frame and this is actually already kind of laid out for you in the very beginning
and we're going to go ahead and read do throughout this exercise try to recreate the plots that are
shown in the notebook.
Something to take note of is you probably want to insert cells instead of overwriting the actual cell
above the plot.
Otherwise if you run something and don't get the right result you won't be able to see that plot again.
So he can do is just go ahead and for instance click on this markdown instruction and then say insert
cell below and here you have an extra cell.
The other way to do this automatically is by saying alt enter and that will also insert a cell below
it.
OK.
That way you don't have to type in the cell and accidently overwrite this figure.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see at the next lecture when we go over the solutions.
Is exercise.