Welcome back everyone to this lecture on stock sentiment analysis.
We've currently only looked at numerical data as a trading signal but there's actually a lot more information
out there in the world and a common source for signal is to use sentiment analysis sentiment analysis
uses natural language processing to attempt the tech sentiment in some sort of text.
For example if you had the text saying this is bad it's going to fail natural language processing and
sentiment analysis could say hey this piece of text has a negative sentiment or if you have a piece
of text that says something like Great job it is a winner.
Again using an LP or natural language processing you'd be able to tell that there's a positive sentiment.
So the actual mechanics behind sentiment analysis algorithms is beyond the scope of this course but
luckily you can easily obtain positive and negative sentiment scores from negative one to one from a
variety of source on Quanto Appian.
Keep in mind the sort of data is almost never free.
Quanto Appian does have a free version of sentiment analysis available only for years 2013 through 2015.
But keep in mind this may change in the future.
So always look at the documentation to see what years are currently available for free and this free
data is provided by Acer and alpha one and it provides a sentiment score from negative 1 to 1 and an
impact score from 0 to 100.
So the impact is a measure of how likely a stock price will change as a result of the sentiment according
to whatever metrics they're measuring this by and in the following lectures we're going to show you
how to access this free data and set up a trading strategy with it.
So let's go ahead and hop over to Quanto in will jump straight to the ID and code it all out.
OK so here I am at the Quanto open idea.
The first thing to do is a bunch of imports and we're going to be using a pipeline to actually get our
sentiment data.
So I'll start off by doing a couple of necessary imports.
So one of them is from Quanto in the algorithm.
Import the attached pipeline that we've seen before and then pipeline underscore output that we've also
seen before.
And then we also some other general pipeline imports to do.
And sometimes you can import these from other places but I'll just do this for now.
We're going to say import pipeline and then we'll see from Quanto up in the pipeline factors in your
average dollar volume okay.
They're going to do is actually import our free data source and that's going to come from Quanto up
in the pipeline data CRN in poor alpha one underscore free.
So keep in mind since we're using the free dataset it's only going to work on particular time periods.
So we'll go over that in a second.
But right now as far as the time I'm filming this kind of in mid 2017 it's only available for the years
between 2013 2015 they can always check the documentation and that will let you know what's currently
available for free.
So we're going to do here is as always our initialize function and this takes in context and we're just
going to attach the pipeline and we're going to call make a pipeline which we haven't defined yet but
we will in just a second and we'll call it just pipeline again kind of call it whatever you want.
Okay.
So we made the pipeline.
So it's actually.
So we're going to do in this pipeline function.
So in this make pipeline function we're going to do a couple of screens here.
Let's go ahead and say dollar volume.
So I'll say out of all the stocks that the average dollar volume
and we're going to give it a window length of let's say 20 days this kind of all just arbitrary and
then we're going to the fine is liquid to be dollar volume and we can actually rank these actually actually
let's go ahead and say grab the top 1000.
So that's kind of a quicker way to do this.
Sometimes you also see it done in the following manner just so you know you'll see someone say dollar
volume of some sort of filter and then they're going to rank them and then they say something like ascending
equals false and then less than 1000.
So this rank is kind of similar to this call where essentially grabs the ranking if you sort them in
descending order or ascending the Pentagon on what you call here and then it just grabs the 1000 of
them.
So we'll just say grab the top 1000.
So this is a top 1000 liquid stocks.
What we can also do is import.
1200 U.S. from before but we're just going to not really focus on that we really want to focus on the
sentiment analysis and how we can do that.
So it's actually quite simple with the pipeline operations.
You just say impact is equal to Alpha 1 free and then offer this we're going to call impact score and
the way you know what to call it just looking it up in the documentation.
So we want the latest impact score from Alpha 1 and we'll set that is impact and then we'll say sentiment's
is Alpha 1 free thought and it's called Article sentiments and grab the latest sentiment.
So let us actually do.
Well we go ahead and select the top 1000 based off the average dollar volume of the last 20 days and
then off of this we have an impact score which is from zero to 100 100 It means alpha one thinks it's
going to have a large impact on the actual stock price.
And then 0 means it believes it's going to have no impact on the stock price.
And then we have sentiment which goes from negative 1 which is a negative sentiment all the way to positive
1 which is a positive sentiment.
OK.
So you can imagine if we had 100 impact with 1.0 sentiment we would think that the price would go up
and if we had negative on 100 impact you would think that the price will go down because of a large
negative impact.
So then we're going to do is just return all of this as a pipeline will say return pipeline columns
and then we're going to say here we just have impact's be impact and then we're going to have sentiment's
sentiment lips
and then let's finish off this.
Actually that's all we need for our column so we'll just have those two columns impact and sentiment
and then apply a screen which is our liquid screen and again the screen could have been the Q 5200 at
us or whatever you really wanted.
So another we have that we we've attached it and we call that pipeline which means we can call it in
other places.
So what I'm going to do is a period initialize.
I'm going to schedule a function and I'm going to call this my rebalancing function which we haven't
defined yet but we will in just a second and I'm going to have it run.
Let's just have it run every day.
OK.
So schedule a function it's going to rebalance every day based off this pipeline so let's go ahead and
create a rebalancing function.
So this is essentially where you're going to be doing the logic of what you want to actually do as far
as the impact is concerned.
So to do this all say if my rebalance context and data so this rebalance function is going to basically
say are we going to order securities in long shore or we're going to exit out of our positions.
So in order to do that that means basically as we've done before we actually grab the stocks that we're
going to go long on and the stocks that we're going to go short on.
So let's go ahead and do that before the trading actually starts before trading start.
And this should feel pretty familiar based off some of the last examples we've gone through as far as
the pipeline examples will take in context and data and I'm going to create our portfolio or just some
object for our pipeline.
I remember we call pipeline output pipeline and this grabs the data offering that we created in the
pipeline.
So off of this we're going to grab the stocks that we're going to go along on.
So there's a context longs is equal to and this is where it gets a little tricky because you kind of
have to decide on what you're going to choose.
So let's go ahead and go long on stocks to have 100 impact and a sentiment score of at least greater
than 0.5.
So the way we do that is through pandas.
So this is going to be multiple filters.
So we'll see where the impact is equal to 100 EON's
portfolio where the sentiments is greater than 0.5.
But again remember this is panderers going to zoom out just a little bit here so we can see the whole
lines.
Remember this is panderers.
So I'm going to filter this out based off the portfolio itself.
So hopefully this kind of reminds you a lot more of what Panda looks like.
Remember to put each of these conditions in princes and if you're kind of confused on what port actually
is what this pipeline actually looks like.
All you have to do is just say print port and then run this for a day somewhere and you'll end up being
able to see it in your logs.
But essentially it's just a data frame with an impact column and a sentiment column and all we're doing
is saying hey for context that longs that's going to be the securities where the impact is equal to
100.
And the sentiment is greater than 0.5 But remember the securities our are in the index so when you say
that index to list and that gives us a list of securities.
So those are our lungs and we're going to do something really similar for the shorts.
So instead of Longs here we'll say shorts and we do want where the impact is 100.
But instead of greater than 0.5 we're going to say less than negatives or 0.5.
And if you want to kind of play around with this you could say 0.75 and negative point 7 5 et cetera.
It's really up to you.
Is where you can kind of play around see how impacts score affects things how sentiment score affects
things or maybe you want to do a whole other strategy to maybe only look at impact score or you only
look at sentiment scores etc..
So it's really up to you can play around a lot of this.
It's a fun data set to play around with.
And again usually you have to pay for this kind of thing.
Obviously we can only look at historical data here.
We have to pay if we want the most recent data.
Ok so now that we have our longs in our shorts Well we need to do is actually compute the weights.
And this is a really similar function to them in the past.
We're just going to say my compute weights takes in some context and it's going to say okay the long
wait is going to be half of our portfolio divided by context.
Wongs and then we'll say the same thing for the short way which is going to be negatives or 0.5 number
that's a short and we're going to say length of context shorts and for this particular example we all
have to deal with the actual checking if its length is zero or not.
There's pretty much always going to be something in Longs or something in shorts that as we previously
discussed sometimes you want to check to make sure that the length of context that long or the length
of context that shorts isn't actually zero and you don't get some sort of division by zero error.
But in our case it will work fine if you run the same dates I do.
So now we're going to say rebalance this.
And let's go ahead and put in that logic and this is logic.
I'm just going to copy and paste that from the notes because we've actually done this before a few times.
So let me copy and paste this and then go over it real quick.
So let me zoom out so we can see the whole thing.
So what does sludging actually say.
Well the first thing I check is for the security in my portfolio positions.
If the security is not in current context longs and it's not in shorts and I can trade the security
Well I should exit that position because I'm holding it and I no longer want to go long or short it.
So I'll just set it to zero.
Then for security in context that longs I'll check.
I'll check first if I can trade the security then if I can for that security I'll say go for the long
wait there and then for the one that shorts I'll check if I can trade it.
And if so I will order a certain percentage to short it.
OK.
And that's really all we have to do.
This should pretty much be it.
So very basic function.
The part you really want to play around with are these two lines 29 or 30 whether you're going to go
long or short.
What's the impact factor are going to look for.
Was sent them a factory to look for et cetera.
Let's go ahead and back test this.
We're going to back test this.
Remember we're going to go from let's say 2015 to 2013.
And if you get errors here make sure you actually check the documentation because sometimes the update
on what's available for free.
Well let's go ahead and build this algorithm make sure we don't have any typos anywhere.
OK long way is a sign and never used.
Short ways assigned but never used.
So let's make sure I actually called these correctly context that long way short wait.
OK so what I had to do is actually set this so I'm going to do the following.
Let's go ahead and say I forgot to actually assign the weights.
We're going to return long waits and waits and then every day here when we call context that long is
a context that shorts we're going to do is say context thaw a long way in context short wait is going
to equal to my compute the weights and then I'm going to pass in a context object there.
OK so now let's try this again.
So it's like kind of totally forgot to save the actual weights.
Let's build this.
Now let's make sure we don't have any more errors.
Run this again same back test and then hop forward in time to this finish backtesting.
All right so if hop forward in time this is done running the back test and notice we actually performed
quite poorly.
We only got 3.3 percent returns over this time period when the actual benchmarks move something way
closer to like 50 percent returns.
So what's actually happening here.
Well if we take a look back at what we're doing all the logic of our trading is basically here in line
29 and 30 and what we're saying is go long when the sentiment is high and then go short when the sentiment
is low and the impact is 100.
But something to keep in mind is this sort of sentiment analysis is obtained from things like social
media or news outlets.
So what might actually be happening here is we're kind of late to the party when we actually realize
that sentiment is positive and it's going to have a high impact.
This stock may have gone all the way up already that it's going to go and then we come in and buy kind
of that peak price and we hold it there which is probably not so great.
Probably wanted to be there earlier in the game and then for the shorts it's basically the same thing.
The stock has probably bottomed out by the time we're actually realizing that the sentiment is poor
and it's going to have a strong impact.
So we're basically going in at the bottom and the stock might start rising again.
So we're kind of doing this at one of the worst times possibly depending on how we actually use this
data and someone else to keep in mind is this sort of thing is not novel.
Anyone can have access to this data.
So this strategy is definitely not unique and everyone could have access to the same data as long as
they pay for it.
And other companies have their own data sets for sentiment Alliss that may even be better than this
one.
So all those topics are things to keep in mind as you decide to use some sort of sentiment analysis
or some of these paid resources for your trading strategies.
Again if you're going to pay for this information definitely look at the documentation and familiarize
yourself with it.
It could change often.
So my best judgment is if you're really interested in paying for some sort of sentiment else this is
go to documentation and read up on it thoroughly.
OK.
I hope you enjoy this project.
I'll see you at the next lecture.