Welcome everyone.
This lecture on an introduction to fut. before we actually dive into how to trade futures on Quanto
in let's get an introduction and first discuss what features actually are you may have heard of the
term derivative when discussing financial topics and futures are an example of a simple derivative.
So let's discuss what a derivative actually is.
A reactive is a contract between two or more parties whose value is based on an agreed upon underlying
financial asset index or security and common underlying instruments or things such as bonds commodities
currencies interest rates market index values and stocks derivatives can be extremely complex.
But luckily futures contracts are relatively simple derivative.
But before we actually discuss what a futures contract is we need to discuss a forward contract.
Forward contracts are an agreement between two parties to pay a delivery price which will call OK for
some asset at some future point in time the person selling the asset is said to be in the short position
and the person to buy it in the future is said to be in the long position.
So let's go ahead and walk through a simple example and keep in mind we're walking through an example
of a forward contract not a futures contract.
We'll discuss futures after we learn about forward contracts.
So let's say we have two people Sandy and Billy Sandy over here on the left and Billy on the right.
Billy runs a gas station and needs gasoline and Billy knows that he's going to need gasoline not just
today but a year from now as well.
Sandy produces gasoline refinery so Billy knows he's going to need gas a year from now.
But as we all know oil production fluctuates which can cause the price of gasoline to fluctuate.
And Billy wants a way to guarantee a price now for his purchase a year from now so Sandy is also subject
to the same fluctuations.
And she wants a way to reduce the volatility in her pricing a year from now.
So it's beneficial to Sandy to get some sort of guaranteed price as well as Billy to also get some guaranteed
price.
Later on we'll see winners and losers in certain situations.
So this is where the forward contract actually comes into play.
What happens is Billy on the right of his gas station agrees to pay Sandy a fixed amount one year from
now for a barrel of gasoline.
Billy has entered the long forward position and Sandy has entered the short forward position.
So who really benefits from this transaction.
Well this depends on the future price of gasoline a year from now.
So let's walk through the two possible scenarios.
So the first example we're going to go through is that a year from now the market price is higher in
the future.
So let's say we have a forward contract and the Ford contract says the following that Billy will pay
$100 for a barrel of gasoline one year from now in he thinks that's a fair price for gasoline one year
from now.
So both parties agree.
So then a year passes and the market price for gasoline is actually $150 a barrel Well Billy.
Now according to his forward contract only has to pay Sandy $100 for a barrel saving himself $50 from
having to go out into the market and buy a barrel himself.
So in that last case that we just discussed the market price went up meaning Sandy had lost a potential
profit.
If Sandy was able to just give that barrel out to the market she would have made $150 instead because
of her forward contract.
She had to give it up for $100 to Billy.
But what if the future market price was actually lower than the four to contract them out.
So let's go over this second example where the market price is lower in the future.
So again same forward contract Billy's going to pay $100 for a barrel of gasoline one year from now
and Sandy agrees.
A year passes and the market price of gasoline has crashed to let's say $25 a barrel so Billy according
to his forward contract still has to pay Sandy a hundred dollars for that barrel regardless of the market.
So actually happens now is Sandy's really happy because she gets an extra $75 above the current market
value a year after that forward contract was signed so Billy would have saved $75 without the contract.
But that again takes risk.
He negotiated this price a year in advance so you can see Sandy comes out ahead.
Instead of Billy.
So why would Billy and Sandy agree to a forward contract in the first place.
Well on both sides of the transaction it reduces risk since both parties know how much the price is
going to be in the future for this particular asset.
Obviously calculating that future price is absolutely critical and both parties are incentivized to
get the best deal possible for themselves.
And we can actually formally describe the sort of payoff each party gets.
Mathematically if we say again that K is the pre-determine future price and we'll say s of t is the
actual market price at some time t we can find the payoff for both the long party and the short party.
The payoff for the long position is the following.
S of t minus k so you can see that if you're going long on this forward a contract position as the price
goes up as you mature what happens is you get a better payoff because you don't have to pay that much
at the market price.
Instead you hit some whatever k value and if the market price ends up going down your payoff ends up
going negative because you could have saved money had you bought at the market.
The payoff for the short position is essentially reverse.
It's going to be the agreed upon price of the asset K minus the current price of the market.
Once that actual forward contract has matured.
So what actually happens here is as the price goes down it means that the short position has actually
benefited.
They got to sell that asset such as Sandi's barrel of oil at a higher price than what the market was
actually willing to pay for it.
But as the price goes up they end up losing potential profit.
So even though the forward contracts are quite simple there are some issues with them.
There's things such as counterparty risk which is if someone that you'd negotiate with just decides
to not pay up.
There's also a lack of liquidity.
You have to wait until the actual contract matures before you can execute any of these asset transactions.
And then you also need to negotiate many customized terms of the contract.
A lot of this could really depend on what particular asset you have the Ford contract for.
So this is where futures contracts come in and futures contracts our forward contracts that have been
standardized for trade on an exchange basically being bringing in a third party to kind of handle the
transactions and hold that contract for the two other parties.
So a single futures contract is for a set amount of the underlying whatever happens to be either an
asset securities financial fundamentals etc. with agreed upon settlement delivery date and terms.
And on top of this the exchange acts as an intermediary virtually eliminating counterparty risk.
The main idea of a forward contract is a futures contract is this introduction of the third party essentially
the exchange futures for a given asset are standardized so the terms of corn futures may differ from
Turns for instance pork bellies futures.
Now the existence of future contracts can lead to things like futures speculation and futures hedging
which we're going to discuss and a lot more detail when we actually show you how to implement features
in Quanto.
But things like speculation occur when market participants such as yourself anticipate a price change
in the underlying asset in the future.
Maybe you think the price of pork bellies is going to go down because there is some sort of disease
or some sort of overproduction etc..
So you never know what's going to happen.
But sometimes if you have really good domain experience you can anticipate price changes.
So one last feature of futures is that they're actually settled daily with a margin account at a broker
held by the holder of the futures contract.
So each day the change in price of the underlying asset which just is shortened to underlying is reflected
in an increase or decrease in the amount of money in the margin account.
And this process is called marking to market.
So now that we understand the basics of what futures are.
Let's go ahead and see how they work with Clintonian.
Keep in mind this is a really advanced topic and there's a lot more features and what we can cover in
these lectures.
But hopefully after viewing these lectures you'll get a basic idea of how to work with features in the
Clintonian platform.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.