Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on short selling We're going to quickly discuss what short
selling is and we're actually going to be able to do short selling when we deal to Quanto pian platform
basically short selling allows you to profit if a stock drops in price.
However it does come with a greater risk due to the fact that there's technically no ceiling to the
amount of money you could possibly lose.
So let's actually go over the way it works.
So let's start with what we'll call step zero.
So before anything actually takes place we'll say that alphabet or Google stock is currently valued
at five hundred dollars.
But you think it's going to drop in the future.
So we have basically kind of three players here you in blue on the top left someone in red who has 10
shares of alphabet stock.
And then the current market basically a third party anyone else who buys and shares stock.
So we start with step point where you end up doing is you borrow Redds shares of alphabet or GOOG.
So you have 10 shares you borrowed from Brett.
You haven't actually paid for them you're just borrowing them and you promised to return them at a future
date to read and the current price of alphabet is $500 that to you immediately then go and sell these
10 shares to the market.
So when the current price is $500 that means you have 10 stocks of $500 and you have $5000.
So you went to the market and you sold off those 10 shares.
Now if you were correct in thinking that the share price was going to drop.
Let's imagine that the price of Google has dropped to $100.
So what you do is once the price has dropped you go out and you buy 10 shares for a thousand dollars
because a 100 times ten is a thousand dollars.
Then Step 4 you now give back the 10 shares you owe back to red and you've made $4000 technically because
of the drop in price from five hundred to 100.
So again you just borrow those 10 shares immediately sold them waited for the price to drop.
Then you go ahead and buy those 10 shares back at a profit and you give them back to red so you should
know however that if the price actually goes up instead of down you will lose money buying back the
stock to give it back to red or whoever we actually borrowed the stock from.
And keep in mind all these transactions would happen through a broker not theorically with someone OK.
Now let's move on to discussing cap em or the capital asset pricing model.
I'll see you in the next lecture.