Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on cap the capital assets pricing model or cap M is one of
the most fundamental topics in investing.
It is a model that helps us drive risk and it helps separate market return versus your portfolio strategies
return.
Let's go ahead and review a few things so he can really understand a cap.
Remember that a portfolio is a set of weighted securities.
We can define the returns as the following in this equation will have on the left hand side of the equal
sign we'll say returns of our portfolio at some time t is equal to the sum from eye to the end number
of securities or stocks in your portfolio where we take the weights of a particular security.
Multiply it by the return of time.
So again it's basically just a wait times a return for each specific stock and then you some of them
all up.
And that gives you the return of your entire portfolio.
Well we can also do is imagine the entire market as a portfolio.
For example the S&amp;P 500.
So how do we actually get waits for each company in an entire market.
Well what we can do is use the market cap where the market cap is the number of shares of a company
multiplied by the price.
And that equation looks like the falling will say the weights of a particular company in the market
is equal to the market cap of that company divided by the sum of all other market caps.
Now the cap and or capital assets pricing model equation states the following.
We say the return of buy at time t is equal to some Bayda term multiplied by return of them at time
T plus some alpha term a time T So notice that there's two terms here.
There's a beta term and an alpha term and we'll be visiting these later on when we learn about the Quanto
IPN platform.
And you should know how this model is almost like a simple regression line like Wells and mix plus B
where we have y being the actual return is equal to a beta term or M multiplied by X the return of time
T plus some other factor intercept we'll call it the alpha term the cap m equation describes a return
of some individual stock.
I and again comprise of two terms this Bayda term and the self term the beta term implies that the return
of a stock is equivalent to the return of the market multiplied by this beta factor plus some residual
Alpha term.
So what does it actually mean.
Well if we look on the left hand side of the equal sign we're seeing some return for a particular stock
at time t is equal to a specific beta value for this stock of-I multiplied by the return of the entire
market at time t.
So for example the return of the entire S&amp;P 500 plus some residual Alpha term.
So you can imagine that if bedo was equal to one then this stock moves in line with the market if Bayt
is equal to 2 then the stock moves up and down twice as much as the general market.
Since the return first thought is not going to match exactly the beta term we need to add some sort
of alpha term and cap em states that you expect this alpha term to be zero and essentially a cap is
stating is that the return of any individual stock is just a weight multiplied by the return of the
entire market.
And then there's some sort of residual Alpha term that will end up being very close or go to zero.
And so if cap and stating that the alpha should be expected to be zero it basically implies that you
cannot actually beat the general market.
So again Cap and also says that Alpha is random and cannot be predicted.
And this basically creates the argument of passive versus active investment.
Now we're behaving as active investors and we believe that we can actually predict Alpha to some sort
of degree.
And remember that we actually need to be 100 percent correct on Alpha.
We should just be able to predict it correctly more than 50 percent of the time for our portfolio and
theoretically we should get some sort of profit out of that.
Since we believe we can actually have a good idea for values of Alpha what we can do is break it up
per security so we can see the return of our portfolio at time t is equal to some beta term of our portfolio
multiplied by the entire market plus the sum of those Waite's times in Alpha term at time t for each
individual security in our portfolio.
Now the overall main point here that we want to get across of the cap and model is that there will be
some relationship between our portfolio return and the overall market return.
And that's the beta term.
Now remember that cap says that this alpha term cannot be predicted.
However we're going to fundamentally disagree with that model of thinking.
Instead we're going to see if we can create strategies using algorithmic trading that allows us to have
significant Alpha terms meaning our strategy beats the market.
These two terms beta and Alpha will come up again once we learn how to use Quanto platform.
For now let's go ahead and quickly use Python and create an example of cap em in the next lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.