Welcome back everyone to part 4 of the Arema code along in this lecture will finally implement the Arema
model and actually use it to forecast future data points.
Let's go ahead and get started.
All right.
Here I am at the notebook.
Let's go ahead and get started.
First we'll show you how to import in a Rehema model.
In case you ever find yourself needing to use it and then we'll show you how to import stat's models
Seasonale a Rhema model.
So in case you want in a Rieman model for non seasonal data you can say from stat's models the TSA Arema
underscore model import Arema and then offer that you can just call the Arema model and if you do shift
Tapin you see it's the auto recip integrated moving average Arema PD queue model.
So there you provide it it's p and q depending on what you got back out from parsha autocorrelation
plots and autocorrelation plots and make sure you've done the resource reading assignments to understand
how to choose p and q values especially how to choose the capital P and Q values that go along for Seasonale
model.
And in case you ever want to see the full documentation in code just say help on this Arema object and
it gives you the full documentation string here.
OK so there's lots of information there that you can check out.
In our case we have seasonal data so we'll be using the seasonal Arema model that's available for us
in Stets models.
OK let's show you how you can actually import the seasonal Arema model.
So to do that you actually need to call it seal say S.M. the TSA dot and it's under the state space
and then you're going to call s Arema X where we have S for seasonal Arema for auto regressive integrated
moving average and then the X stands for X genius variables which allows you to take into account external
variables and that's kind of useful for things like a weather forecast.
So we're going to use that and we're going to pass in our actual data.
This is the original data we had milk in pounds per cow and then going to set this to be my model and
then I'm going to need to add in two things.
One is the order and the other one is the seasonal order.
So based on what we've seen so far we're going to see an order of 0 1 0 and then our seasonal order
and you can kind of mess around with this to see what works best is going to set it to one on 1 and
then 12 because there's told months in a year.
So we will run that and then we're going to do is actually check out the results of this.
So in order to check out the results we need to fit the model.
So it's kind of two steps here once you've assigned the model you then call it to be fit on the data.
So the fitting doesn't actually happen until you call it.
Once you've done that and that may take a while depending on how large of a dataset you have you'll
go ahead and just print out results and the call the summary method off those results and you'll get
back your state space model results will tell you the dependent variable it was trying to predict the
number of observations and a bunch of different information you can check out here.
Now all of this is going to be useful to us now but it's in case you ever need it.
It's pretty much all here.
So that's the summer result.
We're going to go ahead and show you is probably something that's a little more intuitive.
If you take your results that you just did and you call it off of it's and it's a mixture called results
that reside we can see the residual values.
So basically what this did is it has the error based off what it would predict for our original data.
So what I mean by that we can just plot this and these are the residual error so you can see 1963 kind
of the big error there.
But after that it pretty much just smoothes out.
So what we can do is also do a plot of our results and call Rossett plots and then say kind is equal
to KDE and this will give us a kernel density estimation to see kind of distribution of our errors.
You could see that were mostly distributed around zero which is good for us.
The cost of these residual errors is 0 the better.
So let's go ahead and show you how we can use this to predict future values or actually perform forecasting.
So we can get an idea of how well our model performs but just actually predicting for values that we
in essence already know.
So we're going to do the following I'll say if and I'm going to kind of do a little fake forecast a
critical thing called forecast and it's going to be results and then I'm going to call the Predict method
off of this and I'm going to predict PC to predict we have a start and that end.
So I will say start is equal to next point let's say 150 and then the end point.
Remember we had like 160 points.
So I'll just state that there.
And then what I'm going to do is say forecast actually let's get both of these columns will say milk
in pounds per cow and hopefully I spelled this with the correct capitalization.
Let me just make sure.
Looks like the key is incorrect so let me grab that.
I'll just say the thought columns and looks like a milk in pounds per cow.
That's what actually was going to copy that.
That C should be capitalized.
Let's put that in that Rigaud Now let's add one more quote there.
Let's stick with that hash tag.
All right so a million pounds per cow.
That's one of the columns I want to plot and then forecast is the other one so I will plot this time
series and will plot a fix size of let's say 12 8.
OK so what does this actually doing.
Well this is showing you what your Arema model would have forecasted serial model is forecasting this.
Now we can see how it compares to our actual real data and necessarily a pretty good forecast.
We're only a little bit off on certain seasons but in general the trend seems to be correct.
And the general seasonality of this seems to be correct.
So so far we're doing pretty good even on the data that we already know.
But what we actually want to do is forecast for future data.
So things beyond 1 6 8.
So you may think you would just come over here to end and give more points we would say okay predict
to index to 50.
But unfortunately if you were to run that you would end up getting all the way until the end where you
stopped having data points.
So you actually need is more time periods.
So you can end up doing is actually create them with panderers onto our original data frame.
So let me show you how we do that how we can fix this problem and set a higher end date for us to actually
forecast real values.
So take a look in detail here all the way at the end we have the milk impounds seasonal different seasonal
first difference and then we have this forecasted value.
So you can see here the real value the forecasted value.
And then earlier we actually saw the residuals themselves was essentially the real value minus the forecasted
value in all we're going to do now is add on some more months to this dataset with empty values and
then once these index positions are there all these values are empty we can still forecast on them.
All right.
So what we need to do here is actually create an additional number of rows with time stamps with date
time index that is going to represent future dates.
So starting from 1975 December 1st let's go ahead and see if we can create one or two years after this
Solus try to end it.
Let's just say like November 1977 or something like that.
See if we can predict about two years worth of milk production.
So to do that we can use some panderers tools will say from Pandurs that T-Series the offsets import
They offset.
So if we take a look at what they offset does it allows you to do some sort of standard kind of date
increment used for a date range.
So that's what we're going to be using and we're going to do is set the argument months equal to and
we'll show you what that's going to be a second that we do that I'm going to say future dates is equal
to this and I'm going to basically do a list comprehension.
I'm going to start with DSF index minus 1 and I'd say plus they offset where months is equal to x.
And then I'm going to say for x in range 0 to 24.
All so what is this actually doing.
I look at this if we see DMF index negative one.
That is the last index value.
So this right here this is December 1st 1975 then I'm going to add a the offset where months is equal
to x.
So I'm going to add an offset of 0 months one month two months three months etc..
Now I shouldn't actually start at zero months.
I should start at one month because I don't want to have a duplicate.
1975 December 1st.
So let's run that.
And if you check out with future dates look like it's a list of time stamps where we have time stamps
that are basically the very next month part.
So we have 1975 December 1st that we have 1976 January 1st.
So we have now or future dates that we're ready to concatenate to this data frame.
So let's do that now.
We'll end up doing is we just scroll down here we'll say the data frame or create a data frame where
the index is equal to the future dates and the columns is equal to our original columns the columns
and also that to be equal to a future data frame.
So if I take a look at my future data frame it's just empty values but the index indicates the future
something we don't know yet 1976 and then we're going to set that future data frame.
So if you scroll down here I'm going to set my final data frame equal to PD non-cat and I'm going to
concatenate my original data frame with my future data frame.
And if I take a look at my final data frame Take a look.
The head of it we have our original data starting at 1962.
There's no forecast there.
And if we take a look at the tail of it we have all this feature data and there is no information there.
So now this will allow us to easily forecast for future data points.
So let's try that forecasting again.
And now we'll be able to predict up to basically 24 points ahead.
So I'll say the following DMF forecast and this is actually in the final T.F. So filed the forecast
is going to be go to results and then I'm going to predict I will start at that very last point we had
which was 168.
And then I'm going to end it let's just say something like 1 88 actually saw more points of say 1 94
or 182 excuse me.
So that's 24 points ahead.
And then we'll say run that's.
So now if I look at my final T.F. let me look at the tail of it.
I now have a forecast value for these future months.
So let's actually plot this out and see if it makes sense or not.
So I will say the following will say final DMF I'm going to take my milk and pounds per cow.
I'm going to plot that and then also going to my final d f and then I'm going to plot the forecast on
this
and we can see here that our forecast here is an orange and if we actually want the labels we can just
put this all in a single plot come in.
So I'll just say pass and a list here.
And then let's also put in milk and pounds per cow.
So this will just make it a little more clear what's the forecast.
Even though it's probably pretty obvious what's the forecast here.
So I'll say fixed size told by.
OK so now we see clearly milk in pounds per cow and we're able to create a realistic looking forecast.
We can see that there's obviously increasing the seasonality is being taken into effect.
And if we take a look at just how accurate we were in general in comparison to our old data it wasn't
so bad it was kind of right on top of our old data.
Now we can see here the residuals mostly are around zero.
Looks like we had some air for those younger values but really doesn't a matter too much for accurate.
Further along the time series.
OK.
So not bad.
I hope you enjoyed learning about real models is clearly a complex topic.
Make sure you do all the reading assignments if you intend to run a ream of models in the future.
Now it comes to a point where I need to discuss why Arema models aren't always so great when you're
dealing with financial data.
So a lot of this stuff assumes that the y value is directly connected to the time and that the time
is a really important aspect of the Y value.
Now while that is true for a lot of financial data that doesn't really take into account things like
force outside of the market such as external traders being able to also buy and sell stock and affect
its price.
And because of that often you'll hear stock and securities prices are following some sort of Brownian
motion almost like a random walk.
So they go up and down all the time when you zoom in really close.
It almost looks random which is why we'll also cover Monte-Carlo simulations because of those aspects
of financial data and securities data this sort of forecasting method doesn't really work with stock
data in general which is kind of inconvenient because you can see here it performs really well on this
sort of data where your time has a clear relationship with your y value.
But first stock market data.
It doesn't really work that way.
So that's why we can't really use a lot of these techniques with financial data.
OK.
So I hope you enjoyed that discussion in general and I will see you at the next section of the course.