Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on the Clintonian platform.
So now that we understand the basics of finance Hammerfall is its time to learn how to use Quanto Appian
platform for algorithmic trading.
This section is going to cover the following topics.
We'll have a review of what totally it is.
We'll talk about basic algorithm methods.
Talk about building trading algorithms discuss trading algorithm exercises and then discuss Clintonian
pipeline's.
Before we begin if the more technical topics.
Let's go ahead and jump to w w w that Quanto Appian dot com and explore the site a bit and explain what
it is.
OK so here I am at Quanto dot com and the pinning on when you visit the site it may look slightly different
to you but the basic idea behind Quanto open is that it allows anyone who knows how to code in Python
to write in an investment algorithm and select authors can then license their algorithms to Quanto Appian
and get paid based off the performance of that algorithm.
So you can write algorithm using Python in their interactive development environment or their idea which
will show you later on and you can also clone algorithms from the community as people share algorithms
so you can start off an idea customize the code beyond that and then what's really nice it has a whole
backtesting library so you can then backtesting algorithm against 14 years of U.S. stock price data.
And they also provide free fundamental data things like price earnings ratios that you can use in your
strategy where you can also do is ploy to live trading so you can either enter into their monthly contest
or you can also connect it to your interactive brokers account and they also support Robinhood accounts
in the United States.
So if you kind of scroll through this Web site it tells you what they're all about.
They have a research environment which is kind of like a Jupiter notebook environment where you're going
to be exploring later on and they also have an idea or development environment so you can test stuff
on U.S. equities data.
And then also coming soon.
U.S. futures so show how to do that as well.
Then you can compete.
So every month they award prizes the winning algorithms and if you win you earn $5000 and if your algorithm
is really good it's one of the best.
What happens is they may be selected to receive capital allocations from Quanto up in and then if your
algorithm is selected for an allocation you get a share of your algorithms net profits and then here's
just some various perks like intellectual property you're going to own your own algorithms and they're
kept the secret unless you want to share them.
There's backtesting you can do real money trading with your own money if you really want that.
And there's also the race community there's researchers data sets et cetera.
So if you go ahead and join Quanto and you can just click here on the sign up page and you go when you
hit sign up you can sign up with your first name last name email and password.
Let me show you what it looks like.
If you already have an account so you have an account to log in right now.
So once you log into the Web site you'll end up going to Quon topee and community where there's post
like interest seeing us and it's just a different post based off what people are interested in.
So basically kind of almost like a discussion forum here and they have a little cue here that means
they're officially part of Pantaleone but anyone can just post something here.
So if I really wanted to I could hit New posts.
Now if we go ahead and check out some of the different things we're going to be exploring one of them
is research superhit and research and then go to notebook's select that it will load up some notebooks
and basically this is the super PAC environment hosted on Quanto Appian.
So you can do is you can check out different tutorials and documentation they have as well as different
data sets they have.
But on the plus side it will end up creating a new notebook.
And here we have a Jupiter in environment.
So there's various things you can do here but anything from like import Panthers as PD shift from shift
enter to run that cell.
And it all works just as we've been working with things locally.
So they have this notebook environment for research.
We'll be exploring that later on.
But I also want to show you that you have a I-T or interactive development environment that's a more
common environment to use when you're doing algorithmic trading on Quanto.
If you click on this little queue go ahead and leave this we don't care if it's being saved or not.
But it hit on the key.
I'll take you back to the home page click here which says start coding.
Select that and that will take you to the page and it's fills it up with a algorithm here.
So this is typically what the algorithms look like and then what you can do is you come back test.
So here's a sample mean reversion algorithm.
And the third copy of it.
So I'm going to go ahead and build that algorithm but I don't want to test it on so much we'll just
test it on let's say a couple months of data.
So if you hit build algorithm here it's going to run a back test.
So it's going to initialize the back test and it's going to show you how well this particular algorithm
performed.
Now Quanto ping has a very specific API.
So you have to build functions in a particular way.
And we'll be showing you how to do all of that.
But once you have your algorithm ready to go well you can see is logged so it will tell you kind of
like what purchases you did etc. anything to print out.
We have this record method to actually records our purchases and then we can see how well the algorithm
performed versus the benchmark.
And in this case we're using the S&amp;P 500 as our benchmark.
So right now it's back testing it against the data I provided.
And then once this back test is done running you can see how it performed against our actual benchmark.
So here is the blue and then red is the benchmark and kind of CEO goes along.
And what's also really nice is it tells you the alpha and beta parameters as well as the sharp ratio
and we'll be discussing returns and draw down later on.
Now you can also run a full back test.
So let me make this just a little short of a time frame.
We'll just do let's say one week back to us things like since the 19th.
And then if you run a full back test it will take you to another page and then it runs a full back test.
And basically this is a back test that performs a lot more metrics so has things like benchmark returns
alpha beta sharp but also things like volatility max draw down daily positions and gains transaction
details etc..
So there's a lot more information than a typical Just quick back test.
So if you ever want a kind of final algorithm to be fully back tested you can run that back test.
But keep in mind that this takes a lot longer.
Even if I'm just doing like a week or so of data it takes it's taking it almost as much time as it did
to do that several months beforehand because it is calculating the daily returns that different transactions
etc..
So just keep that in mind that if you hit that fool back to us it's going to be a lot longer process.
Typically it's just something you set and then maybe go for lunch.
All right so if click back here and then cut back one more time you can see it.
It saves the accessory algorithm.
It also has a bunch of different names that we are testing algorithms.
The number of back tests you ran on it and for instance this first I'll go I can click on it.
Take me here and then I can check out different things for it.
And then I also collaborate has an API reference I can get back to us here and it shows me the different
back tests I ran and what they I ran them as well as the different returns so you can see some are canceled
some are completed etc..
And then if you click on it they'll take you to that particular test or you can rerun it again.
So I'm going to go back here and there's community there's forums events contests capital etc..
Well it's also really important to understand about Quanto open.
Is that a lot of these libraries that run the back test do the algorithmic trading.
They're all a lot of them at least are open source so I'm going to show you Quanto paeans get hub now
so you can check out the open source libraries.
OK so here I am at a dot com slash Quanto Appian and this Quanto up in public Hub's the open source.
A lot of technology that runs Quanto PIENSO zip line is one of their most popular libraries and it's
basically an algorithmic trading library but most importantly it's the backtesting portion of what their
platform runs off.
So if we go ahead and check it out click on that link.
Quanto pansit blind tickey the zip line the I.O. where basically describes everything that you can install
it.
Typically it's a little more difficult to install than just Pipp install and you can see the various
installation instructions here.
That's because it depends on Champine several C extensions.
You can also try installing it through Khanda because of the more complicated installation for zip line.
We are just going to use Quanto Appian platform so we don't have to worry about all that stuff but all
the functions we do in case you ever want to run them locally if you don't want your stuff on the Antoninus
platform.
You can just use ziplining to do the backtesting the exact same way that we show in the lecturer's now
says things like Alpha lens which is a performance analysis and that has Pamphylia which is risk analytics
in Python.
You can check these out.
They all have kind of links to what they end up doing.
So Alpha lends Python library for performance analysis predictive or alpha stock factors number we discuss
that cap and model and then they have pie Foleo which kind of discusses risk analytics risk analysis
of financial portfolios and you could see kind of gives you the tear sheet of information as well as
cumulative returns.
The Rolling portfolio Bayda as in regards to spy or S&amp;P 500 the rolling Sharpe ratio as time goes on
and then things like under-water plots or the draw down exposure etc. so there a lot of stuff here.
Some of it we'll be discussing some of it we won't.
But keep in mind if you ever don't want to use Quanto APENAS platform a lot of their stuff that they
use is open source free access which is important to me as an instructor choosing them.
The fact that in case anything happens Quanto up in all the code is still open source and we can still
use everything we learn on our own computers.
OK.
So that's it for Quanto openness was as far as the overview is concerned.
Later on in future lectures would definitely be using it a lot.
So make sure that you have an account.
It's free to create an account on Quanto open.
So go ahead and create the account and the next lecture will show you the basics of using Quanto Appian
platform.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.