Hello everyone will.
The section on visualization a lot of financial techniques will actually require us to be able to visualize
our data clearly.
Now there are many libraries for visualization with Python will focus on map plotted and planned those
visualizations that are actually built directly on top of that plot lib will really cover any other
libraries in order to quickly focus and move on to the financial aspects and algorithmic trading portions
of the Course instead of just having a giant section on visualization.
However keep in mind there are many other great libraries.
Some of my favorites include seaborne cufflinks Plott Lee Bocca Vincent and many more.
If you just google search for Python visualization libraries you'll get a plethora of results and I
encourage you to check them out.
We're going to start by covering the basics of map plotted.
It's kind of the grandfather of visualization libraries for Python and then with that knowledge we're
going to be able to easily leverage panels visualizations because pandas actually comes with built in
visualization tools that are directly built on top of that live.
So it's important to understand my lib first before going on to Panas visualizations.
We're also going have a lecture focusing on time series visualizations with pantless.
Keep in mind that the majority of all our plots in this course are going to be static.
That is not interactive but we will show you a quick trick of Jupiter that will allow it to interact
the plots that we create Laurie as a quick recap.
This section is going to cover the following topics we'll discuss.
Matt plotless visualization We'll also discuss pandas visualization.
We'll have a little lecture on pantless time series visualization specifics then we'll have a map plotted
exercise for you to do as well as a tandem visualization exercise for you.
OK let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.