Hello everyone and welcome to the first section of the course which is the python crash course before
we get started.
The rest of the course what we're going to do is have a quick review of how to work with Python.
If you already know Python you can feel free to skip this section.
Keep in mind that this section is not meant to be a complete comprehensive review of Python.
Instead what it's meant to be is just a quick overview of how to use Python.
If you're completely new to programming in general this is probably not a best fit for you.
If you've programmed in another language extensively and you just want to quickly get around to learning
how to use Python syntax or fi's Python a while ago and just need a quick refresher then this is the
right course for you.
So we're going to be using a Jupiter notebook environment for the majority of this course but please
feel free to use any development environment or ID that you prefer for Python whether it be a text editor
like Adam text editor or sublime text editor or the full blown I-T like pite charm.
Everything we do here is going to work in any I-T each choose.
After this quick crash course you're going to have an exercise no book for a few tasks to go through.
Then after that we'll go through the solutions book OK.
Let's get started.
By opening up the python crash course notebook and then going through and reviewing Python I'll see
you at the next lecture.