Welcome back everyone to this lecture on a pipeline example we've already learned how pipeline works.
In the last section but we haven't really explored any deeper examples specifically actually implementing
a pipeline in the ID.
Remember that our main approach will be to select some sort of universe of stocks to trade from and
then either go long or short depending on some sort of factor or filter from the pipeline we'll go ahead
and start in the research note environment and then switch over to I-T and Quanto open for implementation.
So I'll have two tabs open one with a new research notebook and one of a new algorithm in the ID.
OK let's hop over to the browser now.
OK.
Here we have a research notebook open called pipelined example.
And then in another tab I have an.
Ready to go but we're going to start off just with the notebook itself.
Let's go ahead and review the main imports for a pipeline we'll say from Quanto in the pipeline import
pipeline and then we'll also say from Quanto in research in poor run pipeline and from Quanto in the
pipeline data built in will import the U.S. equity pricing.
So those are some really common imports.
When you're using pipelines Now the next thing I want to introduce to you which you'll see used a lot
in Quanto in examples as you see other people's algorithms are the Q and US or Q 15:00.
Q Three thousand or Q 500 US filters that Quanto provides for you.
Our first show you how to import them and they will discuss what they actually are.
Say from Quanto up in pipeline that filter's import.
And if you type q here and then hit TAB notice here.
Q 15:00 Q Three thousand and q 500.
So typically Q Fifteen hundred US is the most common one.
But it really depends on your algorithm.
But first let me describe what these fifteen hundred three thousand five hundred universes of stocks
are actually doing.
The point of this sort of universe of stocks is to try to avoid that sort of not traded error that you
sometimes get maybe your trades aren't being fulfilled and that may mess around your algorithm.
So these are default universes that contain respectively either 50 100 U.S. stocks 500 U.S. stocks or
three thousand U.S. stocks and the constituents of the actual group of stocks are chosen at the start
of each month by selecting what they call the top 1100 tradable stocks and they're the most tradeable
based off their 200 day average dollar volume that is.
What are the top 50 100 stocks that are being traded around based on how much money is being traded
up these stocks.
And they're also capped at 30 percent of equities allocated to any single sector.
So there's a bunch of other factors that go into choosing these 15 stocks.
Things like the stock must be the primary share class for its company.
So really large companies such as for instance alphabet sometimes they have multiple shares of stock
so they have like a class A share a class B share etc..
So to make sure that your algorithm is not getting confused by these multiple classes.
Each company has a primary share and.
Q Fifteen hundred US has already done the work for you of figuring out what's the primary share for
that company.
There's also other factors such as the stock must not be the positive receipt.
It can't be traded what's known as over-the-counter TC.
It can't be part of a limited partnership.
It must have a known previous day close price and it must have a non-zero volume on the previous trading
day.
So basically these are the kind of top fifteen hundred stocks and Quanto Open's already done a lot of
the filtering work that you would normally do to make sure you don't get any errors.
As far as not being able to trade the stocks so check out the resource link would actually Shoji all
the filters that are being used here.
But you're going to see this used a lot in algorithms especially that are used in the pipeline.
So we'll go ahead and import that and then move onto the next step.
So again the two main benefits of using either 15:00 us or five US or three thousand us is that they
really greatly reduce the risk of an order not being filled and they also allow for more meaningful
comparisons between strategies as now that can be used as standard universes for various algorithms
so it makes a lot easier to compare two different strategies on the same universe of stocks so now as
we continue let me just collapse this header click on that little icon and other we have basically our
basic universe of stocks inside our make a pipeline.
We're going to have something that looks like this will say universe is equal to chips.
Q Fifteen hundred U.S. executed.
So that will basically show you the actual filter.
Again this will actually go inside or make pipelined But this is essentially what it's going to look
like.
Now let's go ahead and quickly review how to filter the universe further with classifiers such as those
Morningstar classifiers So we went over last time.
So let's go ahead and try to grab stocks that are only in the energy sector and there's a link in the
notebook provided as far as how to actually get these sector codes.
But the way we do this is the following method will say from Quanto in pipeline that data import.
And we're gonna import Morningstar and then off of Morningstar this is really similar to the get fundamentals
so we covered a lot earlier.
The basic idea being that if you hit tab here you have basically 13 types of fundamental data.
So let's go ahead and grab assett classification and then we'll say here and then there's the various
things that are kind of sub sections of asset classification as well as just some methods that are more
Python related.
But we're going to go ahead and grab Morningstar sector code and then we're off of this.
We'll say latest and we can set that equal to sector.
Now if you remember back to our previous lectures on pipeline we actually showed you kind of a quick
shortcut to doing this sector because it's such a common classifier and the way you did that is you
just did these two lines you could say from Quanto opened up pipeline that classifiers Morningstar import
sector and then you would say Morningstar sector or sector is equal to actually implementing or ex-king
sector.
This is the exact same thing as what we appear.
Now while this code is actually probably more efficient.
My personal preference is to actually go through the full steps of choosing the category and then choosing
the subcategory and then calling the latest.
Because here I can see where I am actually grabbing sector code from what actual 13 Group classing is
in.
So I prefer this method.
This method is a little more efficient but just kind of personal preference there.
So I'm going to delete that because we essentially already have that here.
And then the sector we want is the energy sector.
So again check out the link in the notebook to see the different sector codes.
But the way you would do this is if you want the energy sector you would call sector and then do that.
Q So basically asking where the sector is equal to and you type in the sector code which is a numerical
code and for the energy sector is 3 or 9.
Again there's a link for the different sector codes in the notebook.
So now this is a classifier because it's going to classify the assets into their sectors.
And from this classifier using the stock ECU for equals I made a filter filtering for the energy sector.
So now essentially I have two filters.
One is this giant filter already provided from Quanto in which gives me the top fifteen hundred tradable
stocks.
And then this filter from a classifier that gives back stocks that are only in the energy sector.
So let's quickly review masking filters so masks can be applied to methods that return filters like
top bottom and percentile between.
And masks are most useful when we want to apply a filter in the earlier steps of a combined computation.
Remember what we discussed that masking can really help make your code a lot more efficient.
So for example suppose we want to get the I don't know 50 securities with the highest open price that
are also in the top 10 percent of dollar volume.
Masking is a good way to do that.
And then we can also do things like Rab's stocks that are in the 19th to 100 percentile based on close
price.
So let's go ahead and import some factors and show you how we can actually execute those we'll say from
Quanto in the pipeline.
Factors import.
And we've done these imports before.
Things like simple moving average and then there's another one average dollar volume.
So we're going to zoom out just a little bit so we can see it simply moving average average dollar volume.
Those are two really common factors you'll see all the time.
So let's go ahead and kind of create instances of these factors.
So the way that would look is essentially just a bunch of steps and these steps would be implemented
inside your make pipeline function.
So a lot of these things that we're doing such as the cell number three and the cell number 6 as well
as all the imports related to them.
Those would actually go in relation to that make pipeline function right now since we're in the research
now but we're doing it sell by so but later on when you actually go to the idea we'll have a giant function
that does all this.
As far as grabbing the sort of masking filters the way this will work is we'll create something called
dollar volume and set that equal to the average dollar volume.
And then this is going to take some sort of window length so you can see it takes a bunch of other arguments
but really it's is when the length so I'll say window length window underscore length is equal to 30
days.
So this gives me back.
Hey what was the average dollar volume for the past 30 days.
Then once you have dollar volume what you can do is well let me just run this so we can see this ourselves.
Once you have dollar volume you can say dots and you notice there's a bunch of different methods some
of them basically kind of totally useless to us.
But the really common ones that you'll be using are things like top.
So this returns wups sort of turns back essentially the top and asset values of self.
So if I wanted the top five based off average dollar volumes the top five securities based on the average
dollar volume traded for the past 30 days I can say top and then pass five.
So that's a really common one to use if you want the bottom.
Then you just do that bottom.
And if you look at this it's going to construct a filter matching the bottom and assets values for each
self day.
And then finally the last really common one is percentile between.
So if you don't want the top 10 or the top let's say you don't want to top 10 or the bottom 10 Instead
you want the top 15 percent.
So you actually want to do as a percentage base instead of just an actual number of securities based
you can just use percentile between the past and two arguments.
So if you want the top 10 percent of stocks based on average dollar volume you're going to say give
me between the top 90th percentile and the 100 percent tile.
So you would call this something like dollar volume.
So again all we're doing here is we're asking hey give me the average dollar volume factor and then
based on the past 30 days that's the volume of dollars traded based in the past three days.
And give me the top 10 percent of stocks.
So that's those are high dollar volume stocks basically stocks that are being traded a lot.
So since these are high dollar volume stocks we know that we're always going to be able to execute our
trades and we also know implicitly that these are very popular stocks.
So there are a lot more liquid than other stocks.
And then another thing we can do is actually combine these sort of mass skiing's with filters.
So for example we want a top open price filter so we can do something like U.S. equity pricing the open
price.
Give me the latest open price and then ask for the top 50 and I will say these are the top open prices
but what I'm going to also add onto this is a mask based off of this filter this high dollar volume
filter.
So basically kind of combining these and I'll say umask is equal to high dollar volume.
So now what is actually going on.
Well I'm basically saying go ahead and grab the top 10 percent of securities based off their dollar
volume traded over the past 30 days and then from that only giving back the top 50 based off the open
price.
So I'm kind of doing the top 50.
But before that I'm applying this mask.
So now I have this kind of top open prices.
Another example of doing this would be something like let's say high close price.
I could say grab U.S. equity pricing the latest close price for that and then maybe something like percentile
between where.
Give me the top 10 percent off the close price.
And then I could do something like another mask and I can actually then apply this mask to it so I can
kind of keep piling these on top of each other and then say top open prices.
So now essentially what I'm doing is saying OK every dollar volume past three days top 10 percent of
that the top 50 of those softer open price and then off those top 10 percent based off their clothes
price.
So you can see how we can kind of continually filter these and applying these factors as filters and
masks.
So that's all we're going to do for now.
Well we're going to do it in the next lecture is actually put all of these things to work inside of
a nice make pipeline function then off of that and then lecture after that we're going to go ahead and
show you how you can implement that in the ID.
OK.
Do you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But definitely check out the notebook.
There's a lot more explanatory text and helpful links there.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture.