Hello everyone and welcome to the stock market analysis capstone project.
I want to welcome you to your first large project.
This project is going to guide you through using all the skills you've covered in the first half of
the course.
The first half of the course really focused on teaching you the basic libraries that were going to be
using throughout the course.
Things like pi panels for data analysis that lived for visualization etc. and also using things like
stat's models for time series analysis.
The second half the course is going to focus on using all those skills in financial analysis situations
as well as algorithmic trading everything you need for this project is located under the fold or stock
market analysis some project which is in the top level of that SIV file.
There's an exercise Jupiter notebook as well as a solution's Jupiter notebook.
There's also some CNC files you can use in case you need them.
I want you to note that this project exercise is optional.
You can basically treat it as an exercise where you open up the exercise notebook work through it do
the reading and then answer the questions in it.
Or you can treat it as a code long project where you go with the solutions lecture.
Coming up next and actually just follow along in code along with me whatever your style preferences
go ahead and go for it.
Now there's a few bonus tasks inside the exercise notebook such as the candlestick visualization that
require exploring the documentation.
There's a couple of things to do some of these bonus tasks that we actually haven't covered yet so feel
free to skip these and wait until the solutions lecture to actually see how they're done.
Or if you're feeling up to the challenge go ahead and go for it.
Another major part of this project is to slowly introduce a few new financial concepts to get us ready
for the second half of the course.
These are just basic things like returns and cumulative daily returns.
The methods for these financial analysis techniques are described really thoroughly in the notebooks.
So quite a bit of reading will be involved this project to make it a full learning experience so when
you're learning how to actually calculate the cumulative daily returns there's some things to read in
that actual exercise notebook and one last note the note book will want you to use panderers data reader
in order to actually get stock information directly with Pancho's from the internet.
However for some geographical locations or if your computer has a firewall or you don't have full admin
settings that may actually limit your use of Pandurs data reader.
So all the CSB files that you're going to be using are provided just in case you need them.
All right let's explore the exercise notebook and walk you through it so you can decide how you would
like to approach the project either as a fool exercise or as a code along solutions project.
Let's hop over the exercise notebook now.
OK.
Under the Python for finance repo folder you have the stock market analysis capstone project.
You can go ahead and open up the stock market analysis project notebook and then the corresponding note
book for the solution.
No but don't click on that unless you actually want to see the solutions that click on stock market
analysis that will open up this notebook.
And here we have the stock market analysis project.
And then here's the note again.
If you treat this as a fool exercise or just be the solutions that have be echoed along.
So there's your first capital project and then zoom out just a little bit so we can read some of this
stuff.
So separate out into parts so part zero just importing various libraries.
Then part one getting that data.
So this project focuses on car companies and analyzing the returns of car companies and comparing them
to each other.
So we focus on comparing things like the Tesla company versus the general motors versus Ford and how
their stock performs from January 1st 2012 to January 1st 2017.
So we're just dealing of historical data here.
So we have getting the data.
So using Panas data reader again in case you can't use Pandurs data reader we had the cxxviii files
for you.
So it walks you through getting the data and then also wants you to repeat this step for Ford and General
Motors.
So then once you get that data there some visualization tasks.
So I want you to visualize things like a basic plot of what the stock performance looks like so you
can see here Tesla much higher than General Motors and Ford although keep in mind this doesn't take
into account things like total market cap.
This is just price per stock.
Then I also want you to plot the volume of stock trading each day.
Things like that.
And then there's a little bonus question what happened that day.
So these little bonus questions require you to do a little bit of Google searching.
For instance Ford has a really big spike in late 2013.
I want to ask like what happened that day.
Like what is this day.
Cetera.
And an example answers right there.
There's also some more questions here.
Trading total traded et cetera more plots moving average plots.
We've discussed those already scatterplot which which we've also discussed seen trends et cetera.
Then there's this bonus visualization task.
This is really hard.
Well not really hardish just requires you to kind of check up this finance demo documentation and eventually
if you actually end up doing it you'll get a little candlestick plot that looks something like this.
Now we haven't actually covered how to do this yet so always feel free to kind of skip this bonus task
here.
So going along we come to part 3 which is the basic financial analysis so this is where we actually
begin to focus on a few key financial calculations.
Nothing too crazy just things like daily percent change which is the daily percent change formulated
by the price at time t divided by the price.
T minus one minus one.
So the ratio of the current price divided by yesterday's price minus one.
And that's your return which makes sense because it's basically the ratio of how much you made from
yesterday and then you'll calculate returns.
You'll keep going down.
There's some more stuff with moving averages etc. you'll do some histograms kind of measuring volatility
here are the various stocks.
Compare them one on top of each other so more visualisations you'll do some kernel density estimation
plot's you'll do some box plots etc..
He'll compare daily returns between the stocks see if something's correlated or not so you can see kind
of Ford and GM have a higher correlation versus Tesla and then you have cumulative daily returns so
there's a little bit of reading here free to do in case you don't know how to actually calculate cumulative
daily returns.
There's a little bit of explanation of a daily return versus a cumulative return.
There's also some formulas here you can follow.
And here's the formula here.
And then here's the actual Pancho's formula that you'll be using.
So you'll do that you'll calculate it you'll get the returns and then the cumulative return and then
you'll plot them out.
And that's the end of the project.
If you have any questions feel free to post on to Q&amp;A forums or just check out the solutions lecture
or I'll be explaining everything and a lot more detail as we actually cut through the projects.
OK.
Best of luck and remember you can approach this project however you feel best works for you.
I'll see if the solution is lectures.