Welcome back everyone to part of this python crash course and we'll start off by talking about comparison
operators so comparison operators things like less than greater than equal to not equals to light compared
to items.
So for example we can say is less is one less than two should enter.
And that returns a boolean so comparison operators pretty much always going to return some sort of boolean
either true or false.
So that's the comparison operators for less than you can do greater than you can do less than or equal
to.
You can do greater than or equal to.
And then you can do things like CheckFree qualities and say is one greater than one and an inequality
is exclamation point equal sign.
So is one not equal to three.
That ends up being true.
You can also do equality for various objects like strings.
You can check is the string equal to this string and they happen to be true.
Now keep in mind this will also take into account data types.
So the number one will not be equal to the string one.
So keep that in mind.
Then once you've learned about comparison operators we can discuss logical operators so logical operators
basically allow you to combine multiple comparison operators.
And those are things like and or not statements.
For example if you wanted to check if one was equal to two and if one was equal to one you can use the
keyword.
And Python makes this really easy because it just uses the English word and in other languages it's
the ampersand or the pipe operator for these sort of things.
Python just keeps the simple uses this plain-English word.
So that's one of them.
Copy and paste this here.
And that's the and operator.
So both conditions have to be true for the operator.
There is the OR operator where only one condition has to be true.
So is one equal to two or is one equal to one.
This will return true because one of those conditions is true.
And then finally the last logical operator or the logic operator is the not keyword.
That's basically checking the opposite of the condition.
So you can check for something like is 1 and I put these in parentheses just because it makes it more
readable for me.
The various comparison operators don't really need to be princes but I do recommend that some checking
is one equal to one.
And I can say not and in some other comparison.
So for instance one equal to two.
And this returns true because I'm checking for the opposite of this condition here.
That's what the knot does.
All right.
Now let's move on to if elif and L statements basically control flow in Python.
So Python makes use of what's known as whitespace.
So let's start off with a very simple if statement.
So I say if and then I going to pass in some sort of condition that I want to check.
So if something is true or false I'm going to end up actually having control flow to work with it.
So if it's going to check if some condition is true execute a block of code so I'm going to say if true
and then I have a colon.
And when you hit enter you'll see an indentation of whitespace.
That is what Python uses to indicate if a block of code matches up with an if statement.
So I'm going to say if true prince Hello.
So I ran this and I can see that print's Hello actually happened if I were to say if false then nothing
actually happens because if only executes on true conditions.
So we can also then add in just comparison operators so I can say if one is equal to one prints hello
that sort of thing.
Now if we come up here and changes to one is equal to two we see nothing as the output.
If you do want something to execute at the very end in case the if statement doesn't actually happen
you can line up an L statement with it.
So we can say if this condition is true execute that indented block of code else.
We're going to do something else like Prince.
If statements wasn't true this was not true.
And they'll say if statement was not true.
So let's come back here and change this is something that will be true just to make sure that if we
say if one is equal to one print Hello.
So we expect just Helots were printed out and you can also check for multiple conditions so maybe don't
just want to check if one is equal to one check for another condition.
You can line up in eyelift statement that essentially.
Else if.
And that also just takes in some other condition so that the condition can be.
Two is equal to two colon Prince to.
Run this and we get hello because the first condition executed.
But if we make the first condition be false then you actually don't need this princess here.
In other languages you do.
But they're actually kind of uncommon for Python you just say if and then whatever condition checking.
Now we run this we get two.
So what's happening here.
Well we say if you check this first Can this be true if it is have a colon in it.
Execute that indented block of code.
Elif condition to check if true that's true.
Execute this and then that block code else.
If none of these happen to be true we print this statement and that's the basics of F 11 l statements
and control flow with Python.
Now let's talk about for loops.
So for loops allow you to iterate through some sort of iterable sequence and then execute actions for
every element in that sequence.
So let's start off by creating an example sequence we'll just start off the list sequence will be just
one two three four five and then the way you do this is say for item and then the key word in sequence
colon and you're going to execute something for every item in that sequence so you can say something
like Prince.
Hello
and then it's going to happen is for every item in the sequence that is for every number in this list.
We're going to perform this block of code in this case just in the printing Halo 5 times.
Now you can also use this item itself inside of this for loop so we can say something like instead of
prints hello print out the item
in there I can see now one two three four or five.
Now this item this temporary variable name can be whatever you want so you can actually say something
like for jelly in CQ the sequence print jelly.
And if I run this now it says one or two you'll get back the exact same result.
One two three four five.
So you call this variable name really whatever you want.
And I can actually perform actions with this.
So for instance if I wanted to print the square of every number I could say jelly to the power of two
and you get something like this 1 4 9 16 25.
Now obviously I should probably choose better names and jelly.
So a good name here would be numb because these are numbers and then I have kind of a really readable
for loop here I'm saying for Num. in the sequence.
Prince Nahm to the power of two or the squared number.
Run that and you get the same result.
So let's say for loop just doing something for every item in the sequence.
Now this also works not just for lists but it also works for strings and even dictionaries where a dictionary
will be for every key.
Just keep in mind that dictionaries aren't sorted so you may go through them in kind of a random order.
Now let's talk about while loops.
So while loops are loops of code that end up continually executing while a condition is true.
So let me show you what I mean by that.
I'm going to set a variable equal to one and only say while I is less than 5 Colan execute a block of
code.
So what I will do is I will say print is currently and then I will actually say that.
Format an insert.
They're using the formatting we talked about earlier and then what's important here as the last step
is to add one to I.
So then set reset equal to I plus 1.
So if I run this I see eyes currently 1 2 3 4 and then at that very last loop I becomes 5 because four
plus 1 is 5.
Which means I'm no longer less than 5.
So this while loop stops executing.
So again if we take a look at this logic I starts at 1.
1 is less than 5.
We print out eyes currently 1 and then we say OK now Isaac will 2 plus 1 which is going to be one plus
one which makes two and and so on.
This keeps repeating until this condition is no longer true.
You should be careful while loops because it's really easy to actually make a condition that last forever
and you get an infinite while loop meaning instead of seeing a number here you see a little Asterix
and it just keeps going on forever and forever if that ever happens to you.
Well you can try to do is come over to kernel and then say restart.
No restart the kernel.
Keep in mind that will also delete all the variable names that you assigned earlier.
So you may need to rerun themselves so you can do is kind of comment out your while loop.
In case it was causing you errors and then say cell and then you can say run all the cells run all above
all below etc..
So keep that in mind in case you ever come for a while loop that ends up running for ever.
Sometimes depending on what the while loop was doing it's really hard to bring your mouse over to click
kernel because it just continually executes over and over again.
In that case you may just need to kind of closure tab and restart Jupiter notebook or reopen the notebook.
OK so now we're going to discuss a few key things that are built into Python as well as functions.
One of the things I want to discuss is the range function.
The range function is a generator for generating a sequence or a list of integers.
So let me show you what I mean by that.
If you just call range Phi in Python 3 you'll get back this range object that says zero comma 5.
We can in the doing's iterating through this so say for item in range 5 and then you'll say print the
item and they'll end up printing 0 1 2 3 4.
So if we actually take a look at what range is returning it's returning a sequence of integers with
a spacing of one from 0 all the way to whatever you asked for.
But it doesn't actually include it because kind of like slicing indexing starts at zero.
It doesn't include this last one.
If you shift tab at range it will tell you what ranges range stop you get back this range object and
you can actually specify a start stop and a step size.
So for instance if we don't want to XLE actually want to start at zero we can do is say start at 1 and
then go up to but not including five and that those one two three four if you want to indicate a step
size.
For instance if we go 20 here start at zero and then stay a step size of 2.
That ends up going in step sizes to 0 2 4 6 8.
Cetera actually brings out all those even numbers.
Now range is a generator.
So if you ever just call range by itself you get back this range generator object if you want the list
where you can do is you can just say List Range and then whatever you want let's say from 1 to 11.
Run that and then we get one up to and including 11.
All right.
So that's the basics range.
So the next thing we're going to discuss is known as a list comprehension.
So that's list comprehension and a list comprehension is just another way of rewriting or flattening
out a for loop that happens to build out a list.
And if you don't get it your first time don't worry about it too much you won't see it used that often
throughout the course.
But I just want you to be aware of it.
So we're going to do is create a list let's say just one two three four.
Now let's imagine that we want to create a list of numbers similar to x except every number in X is
squared.
Well we could do a simple for loop for this.
I could say create an empty list called out and say for now in my list x colon say out dots a pens and
a pen that number to the power of two.
So if I run this and then ask for the out list after running that what ends up happening is I have the
square of every number my original list.
1 2 3 4 becomes 1 4 9 16.
If you find yourself doing something like this running a for loop and appending to a list this is a
common enough operation where you can use a list comprehension something that's built into Python.
So we're going to do is rewrite this for loop as a list comprehension.
So the way you do that is because you know the output is going to be a list you start with some square
brackets and then whatever you were going to append to the list is what you start off with.
So we just copy this.
We were going to append some square.
So we'll put that here and then you type in four and then you type in whatever this form was say for
now.
And then we say an X..
So you basically take this top line of your loop and then write it in after whatever you're going to
a pen and this will by itself reproduce that same list.
And this is known as a list comprehension.
You can kind of think of it as a flattened out for loop inside of brackets.
Now we'll cover this again later on when we see it.
I'll give you a quick refresher reminder of how it works.
But I just want you to be aware of it and the fact that it exists.
All right.
So we'll end this part two for now.
And coming up next we'll talk about functions lambda expressions map and filter and a few methods.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.