Hello everyone and welcome to part two of the stock market analysis project solutions in part two we're
going to take a little aside and focus on the bonus visualization task of actually coding that candlestick
chart.
If that doesn't interest you go ahead and hop over to Part 3 where we actually end up doing some financial
analysis.
OK.
Here I am at the Jupiter notebook.
This bonus visualization task now a quick note.
We wanted to do is create some sort of candlestick chart for Ford in January 2012.
If you did this for the entire data frame.
It's not really going to look good for candlestick chart.
You won't get that much information you'll see a bunch of light green and red lines everywhere.
So there's also a link here.
Finance them all HTL.
And if you click on that link they'll take you to this page where essentially just shows you a full
example of how to actually create this candlestick chart.
So you could have done it many ways either just directly copy and paste from this example or actually
use the data for what we provided.
So we're going to kind of do a mix of both.
A lot of our codes going to come from that example directly but some of it won't.
We're going to do is start off with some of the imports that are in that example.
First one being from public finance I'm going to import candlestick underscore HLC so HLC that stands
for open high low close essentially indicating that's the order it expects the array's tuples to come
in and will actually create a list or array of tuples later on then we're going to save from map plot
live dot dates import or an import a couple of things here we can import formatter.
We're going to import date to numb that is date to number which converts a date time object to a number
that loop can understand.
Then we also import weekday locator day locator and then in all caps Monday which kind of sets What
day is Monday of the week.
OK so all those imports and a lot of the imports are kind of following the examples here from these
first couple of imports.
Next thing I want to do is we take a look at our Ford data frame right now.
Just take a look at the head of it.
We have open high low close volume and then total traded from before our dates right now is still at
the index.
We want to kind of play around that and apply some things to it.
So let's go ahead and reset this back to be part of a column.
So we're going to say is Ford underscore reset and anoints set that equal to first off is crap everywhere.
That has January values so we'll just say for Alosi and we'll say 2012 0 1 and WIPs.
So if we take a look at forward reset right now
you'll notice this is actually all the January values.
So we have all the January values and then we're going to also reset that index
so we're seeing both those commands resets that date index.
So keep in mind all I've done here is I grabbed everything that was in the January month of 2012 and
then I reset the index.
And the one I'm going to do here is if I call info I can see that my date column is still a date time
object.
So the next thing to do is once I have this date time object as a column I'm going to say Ford underscore
resets going to create a new column called dates underscore x.
Let me zoom in one more level here.
Scroll up so dates underscore X for axes and then we're going to take the forward reset theta frame
again.
I'm going to take my current day column and I'm going to apply the following lambda expression my land
the expression is going to take in that date and then it's going called date to come on it and we'll
see what that is in just a second.
So run that and then if you take a look at forward reset just the head of the data frame.
Notice that this data axes value is now a numerical value and this numerical value is going to be part
of what we give.
Matt Lyd my lib doesn't do such a great job as Pandurs as far as directly interpreting a time series
index.
So one way to get around that is by actually just writing this number.
Now there's many ways to not have to do this but this is kind of the simplest far as a one liner way
of cravenness candlestick chart.
So we have this data underscore a x object that will continue to use and then we're going to do is finally
create basically an array of tuple values.
So we're going to save forward underscore values.
Now we're going to set that equal to we'll call a tuple of owls.
For vowels in for reset.
And then the columns I want are my limits it's actually pass and illis the columns here.
Fact Let's make this into a different variable so it's a little clear.
So list of calls the ones are going to are my day axes first and then it expects the open high low close
in that order.
So I'll say open
low close and I'm going to grab that list of columns.
From Ford reset.
So I'm saying OK for the values in this list the columns are going to end up doing is off of this I
will call the values to actually get those values out.
OK so what does that actually doing.
Well if we take a look at for the values and ends up just being a list of tuples where the tuples are
at the individual row values for that list column.
So I have this data X object.
The open price at that axes object the high price the low price and the closing price.
And this is the kind of format that we can easily use.
Matt Paul lib just a list or array of tuples So we have these four values.
Now all we need to do is set the ticks so we can plot it which essentially is just going to be kind
of just copying and pasting from what we have here.
This week they locator they locator the formatter and the formatter.
So we're going to just copy and paste this directly from this example and instead of on days we can
call this up.
That's the on there that should be Mondays.
So that's should be.
Mondays will have all days week format or day for matter.
So everything there we'll use the same as in the example and then we're going to do is actually come
back the example.
And we're also going to just copy and paste this from here
and this is the actual plotting formatter so that sets all the axes.
But right now there's nothing there.
The last thing we need to do is call candlestick.
So that's this line right here.
Candlestick Oh HLC.
So let's actually do that.
We'll say candlestick 0 Chelsea pasan a X which is the axes This creates using these Piazzi that subplots
we pass and the values we calculated which is four to values and then we can give it a width of 0.6.
You can play around with later on.
And if we just stick with this and run this we end up getting a bunch of outputs.
But then we set the default here on the candlestick.
So then the next thing to do is say to find color up to be green and the fine colored down to the red
and let's put a call in here.
We don't see that huge output.
And there we have it.
We have our candlestick chart and you can measure this with parameter to kind of make these things a
little wider.
So if you want them to be a little skinnier or point one you can see they're a little skinnier.
OK.
So definitely a lot of new stuff there.
And a lot of stuff of that pot lib that we didn't discuss and is like very specific to this example.
If you got stuck on this for having a hard time understanding it really don't worry about it too much.
This is not something we're going to be focusing on in this course.
Mainly this is just an exercise of can I come over to the documentation example check out some code
and then kind of copy and paste it to apply it to my own situation.
That's really what this is an exercise and it's not an exercise.
Can I immediately understand what this weekday locaters doing and what this kind of strange capitalize
that Monday's doing which just adds major ticks on the Mondays.
And then Meyer takes on the rest of these.
So again don't worry too much about the actual code here.
We're going to be talking a lot more about candlestick plots later on when they actually represent how
you can read them and better ways of making them with all this stuff from that public.
OK.
So again this is mainly an exercise of kind of come over to an example page kind of copy and paste format
my data and get a similar result using my own candlestick code versus actually understanding every single
line and what it's doing.
OK so let's move on to part three which will be the next lecture where we actually go over some basic
financial analysis.