Welcome back everyone.
And what we're going to do in this lecture is grab our make pipeline function from the previous lecture
copy it and then paste it into the ID and I can actually see excellently call that pipeline.
So let's go ahead and give that E for make pipeline and I like autocall that here it's at Pipeline as
well but not really a huge deal here.
OK so we have our giant pipeline function from the research notebook.
So once you're done using the research in a book you need to do is add a couple more steps here to make
it work in the actual IP.
So we're going to have as always initialize function.
So we'll say initialize and this always takes in a context and then we're going to do it in order to
actually basically have the pipeline in our ID we say My pipe is equal to make pipeline actually calling
that function to return the pipeline because remember make pipeline if you scroll down actually returns
that pipeline object.
Once in the initialize function you've created this pipe object.
What you do is you call the following function you say attach pipeline you'll say attach underscore
pipeline and then you say my pipe and then what you want to call it usually you just call it something
like my pipeline.
But in order to use that attach pipeline you actually need to import that.
So you can just save from Quanto up in Dot algorithm import attach pipeline.
So this is basically the main function that translates your pipeline from a research notebook environment
into an ideal environment.
You say import attached pipeline and then the other one we're going to end up using later on is Pipeline
underscore output.
So those are the two main ones that basically connects a pipeline into the ID and from here let's go
ahead and do the other imports that are make pipelined function of the pends on things like getting
the sector.
Q Fifteen hundred U.S. average dollar volumes simple moving average etc..
So I'll say from Quanto up in the pipeline import pipeline because we use that at the very end of that
make pipeline function then also save from Quanto up in the pipeline
data that built in import U.S. equity pricing.
And then we'll also say from Quanto up in the pipeline factors we're going to import that average dollar
volume and simple moving average.
And if you don't really want to waste your time typing these all out you can just copy and paste them
either from the provided notebook or even from the notebook we were working in before and we just have
two more imports here from Quanto up in pipeline filters.
Make sure you spell pipeline right.
I'm sure we'll have to debug a few typos later on at the end of all this but we'll say from Quanto up
in our pipeline that filters Morningstar import.
Q Fifteen hundred us because we use that and then from Quanto up in the pipeline that data in poor Morningstar
now the next thing to do is add in the remaining functions.
So we're going to have one main rebalancing function.
So I will define it and then schedule it so I'll say my rebalance function.
Or you can just call it rebalance always takes in context and data and then right now we'll just say
pass.
So up here in initialize what I'm going to do is schedule it.
So we'll say schedule this function and I'm going to schedule my rebalance and let's have it as far
as date rules.
And this is something you can really just play around with.
We'll have it at the week's start.
And then we can also add some time rules so we can say time rules do it at market open maybe one hour
something so hours equal to 1.
So one hour after the market opens I'm going to call this rebalance function.
Currently there's nothing in it because what I want to do is add in two more functions to this.
So I'm also going to say have my compute Waites function that takes in a context object.
Right now it just passes.
And then after this I'm also going to have a before trading starts.
Context and data.
OK so right now I just have passed and all three of these functions we're going to start off by executing
the compute weights or filling it out I should say.
So I fill up my compute weights first then we'll have rebalance and then we'll have before training
start.
So before trng start it's going to be the one that basically shows us how i can connect the pipeline
I created to an actual function.
So so far we have this giant make pipeline function that we've already covered just like in the research
notebook and it returns a pipeline object in order to use that pipeline object throughout the rest of
the code.
We need to do is up and your initialize function actually create the pipeline and then attach the pipeline
to your workspace and you pass in the pipeline and then the name that you're going to call that pipeline.
So then the way you can actually grab the pipeline and other functions is I can say context the output
I remember context that output this could be called whatever you want you could say context jelly or
something similar but usually want to say context.
My pipeline or context it up.
Etc..
And the reason I call it output is because this function pipeline output can actually grab the pipeline
we attach to the space and the way you do that is we just call it by name.
So again we attached this my pipe object calling it the name my pipeline.
And then inside these other functions I can grab it by saying.
Pipeline output and then passing in the name of the pipeline.
So now that I have that what I want to do is figure out what securities am I going along on and what
securities am I going to short.
Now remember this pipeline object is essentially just a data frame with a date index and then the security
index and then the values you ask for.
I remember down here the column names are longs shorts and percent difference.
Lets actually print this out.
We're going to say print out the context dot output and I'm just going to say this and I'm going to
run this algorithm just for one day so I can see here in the logs what this actually looks like.
So let's say on January 4th 2011.
Let's change this year to January for 2011.
Or even the fifth.
So I'm going to build the algorithm and make sure that this context that output looks like I have undefined
names sector.
Let's make sure actually imported that.
So when I try to run this right off the bat I ended up getting error it says say global name sector
is not the final So if you check out in line 41 I had the energy sector is equal to sector equals or.
If you copy and paste directly from the notebook we were working on instead of the notebook that we
provide we actually forgot to define what sector is.
So we did it in a cell above and our previous notebook.
Let's go ahead and copy that.
So going to come back to the notebook.
Scroll up here.
And basically what I need is this line right here.
Sector is equal to Morningstar asah Cl. Morningstar sector code latest.
So I'm going to copy that.
Bring it back down to this make pipeline example and put it here.
And line 40.
So that should take care of that so let's save this.
Build the algorithm.
Make sure we don't get any more errors here and are going to cost less.
So it's loading the pipeline data that sometimes takes a minute or two.
So since we only ran it for one day.
Here we go.
OK so if we look at the logs I can see here that I'm basically getting the data framed that we had last
time where you have longs percent difference and shorts and these index here is a list of all the equities.
So I want to go ahead and grab that index object.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So essentially he's going to use pansit codes and this is a panel data frame.
So in order to grab the long stocks I'm going to say context the Longs and I want this list where this
happens to be true where I'm going.
True on longs.
So the way we're going to do this is the falling we'll say context thoughts output and then we'll say
context output longs and since it's already essentially a boolean series that's actually all we have
to do.
We could also say it's equal to true.
But since it is already a series of booleans we don't really need to do that.
And then we're going to call the index off of that which is the list of securities and then we'll say
to a list and we're going to do the exact same thing for shorts.
So I'm going to copy this and paste it for my shorts.
But instead of saying longs we'll say shirts and then sit here longs we'll say shorts and there we go.
So all I'm doing is using the pandas knowledge so we have already learned about this is a series of
boolean values longs or shorts.
Remember you can go back to the logs and check that out.
Then I'm calling the index which is the actual panel a series index of all those equity names.
And then I'm calling the method to list which essentially just returns a list of the securities using
that list of securities is what I'm going to be calling when I actually call rebalance here.
But before I can call rebalance I need to somehow compute the weight.
So how much my profile is going to go short.
How much.
My portfolio is going to go a long so under here and compute weight.
Now let's go ahead and fill that in.
So there's lots of ways to do this but one way to do it is to say long waits is equal to let's say I
want to say I want half my portfolio to go long and I want to go long equally in all the stocks in context
that longs than what I'm going to say 0.5 divided by the length of context that lungs.
And that will make sure that 50 percent of my portfolio is equally allocated to every single stock in
that list of context that long.
And I can then do the same for the shorts.
So a short weight is equal to negatives or 0.5 divided by the length of context that shorts and you
can play around with these weights.
I believe in the provided note book it says 90 percent of portfolio goes long 10 percent of it goes
shorts.
Right now 50 50 really depends you can play around with that whatever you want.
But when I'm going to return here is a tuple long waits and then short wait.
And I can later on.
Unpack that.
You actually don't need these princes to kind of just there for readability but once you have that you're
ready to actually calculate the rebalance function.
So let's do that as well.
So I'll say my rebalance and I'm going to do the following.
And going say for security in context the portfolio positions and this basically gives you a list of
every single security that's currently in your portfolio.
I'll do the following.
If the security
is not in context that longs and security sure spell that right.
Is not in so Skewes not in context that long security is not in context shorts and we'll say data.
I can trade this particular security
let's expand this just a little bit so we get some more room here.
So if it's not in Longs if it's not in shorts and they can trade it then I'm going to say Order target
percents of that security
and I'm going to say zero.
So why am I saying zero here.
Well this is a really common rebalancing structure.
We may or may not ever really exit our positions but essentially what the saying is if at some certain
point we have a security in our portfolio that doesn't happen to be in our list of stocks to go long
on or doesn't also happen to be in our list of stocks.
Go on.
And they can treat it.
I'm going to exit out of that position because my pipeline basically said hey this is no longer in my
list of stocks being returned maybe happened to drop out of that top 5 percent tile or maybe even change
sectors.
Who knows.
But something happened here where it's no longer on my list of Longs or shorts.
So I just exit out of that security position.
For the rest of them I'm either going to go long.
So say for security in context that longs remember that's that list of actual security names to go along
on.
We'll say first creating context that longs if I can trade that security.
I will say Order target percent's and order target percent is going to be grab that security and then
I'm going to call context
long waits.
Now keep in mind here I'm calling long waits off this context object.
So I somehow need to actually attach that long way from my compute weights into the context.
So what I'm going to do is down here before trading starts I'm going to say context.
Long waits and then comma context short waits is equal to my compute weights number that function pass
in the context because right now it's not attached to the context I was just returning.
If we come back here and it could have also just attached it to the actual weights here and compute
weights.
But I want it to happen everyday before the treating start.
Which is why I happened here before training start actually attached these long waits and short weights
every single day.
OK.
So we have that going on here which means now I can pass it in here and we're going to do the exact
same for loop except for the shorts.
So we're going to copy and paste that in and then replace lung's of shorts.
So that basically sets our positions for our shorts and our locks so definitely take the time to kind
of go logically kind of step by step along to your finger or something and kind of get the logic here.
But it's actually not so bad if you're just starting Quanto and saw this.
You'd have no idea what's going on.
But hopefully now that you kind of have some more experience it's actually more or less obvious what's
happening here.
I am sitting out of my positions in this first for a loop are no longer in the Longs and shorts.
And then there's the for loops and going long on these bases the weights are calculated and then in
short based off the weights I calculated here.
Now all that's left to do is make sure we don't have any bugs.
Ambac test this so I'm going to expand our back test.
And let's go ahead and just back test it for I don't know two years or something we'll say January 1st
2017 to January 1st 2015 and you can choose any dates you really want here and you can play around with
our short and long portfolio percentages.
Right now we have 50 50.
I believe in the notebook it's slightly different but either way should be fine.
Let's go ahead and Bilour algorithm make sure we don't have any errors like saying that an indent error
on line 24.
So let's see line 24.
It's nice to be back once space but not that one.
It's like over here real analysis try saving this and build this again and you can always copy and paste
the notes directly from the note book that should run of no problems.
And it looks like we're not having any runtime errors right now loading the pipeline data.
Let's go ahead and jump forward in time.
Here we go.
So we have before treating star more than two values to impact.
So looks like a have a comma there instead of dots will come back down here.
Make sure it's has context but short wait.
Save it build it again and obviously debugging is definitely a real part of the process hopefully is
kind of showing you some realistic example of kind of typos and bugs you'll find along the way.
Well make this less slow in the pipeline data right now.
It's good to jump forward in time and this area says shorts waits plural.
I think I actually just call that short wait.
So let's see.
Short wait down here.
When I actually call it I'm just calling it short wait.
So we'll come back up here and make sure that's short wait ok.
Hopefully I have no more typos again will build this jump forward in time.
So as I was running this something I encountered was zero division error and that is something you may
encounter not just in this algorithm but many algorithms in this case cases float division by zero.
So what's actually happening here is for whatever reason in a particular time stamp I'm trying to divide
by zero.
So there's actually no longs securities in this list.
So what we're going to do is say at an if statement to kind of fix that.
So let's go ahead and go back to compute weights.
So going back to the compute weights we can attempt to fix this through the following manner we'll say
if the length of context longs is equal to zero we'll say long waits is equal to zero.
Then we'll say else and then we'll actually perform this calculation.
And we'll do the same thing for shorts.
We're going to copy this and then paste it here and we'll turn the lungs into shorts.
So say if that's now also say short here and then we'll make this short and then this context is going
to be Shortz.
OK so that should be able to fix those.
That kind of error and it's more or less a common error.
So I'm going to save this and then build the algorithm.
OK let's hop forward in time until it's finished running.
All right now that this is done we can go ahead and check out our returns here and we can see for the
majority of this time period we're actually doing a lot worse than the benchmark.
But we basically squeaked at the very end to be a little bit better than the S&amp;P 500.
But keep in mind as far as a general strategy we really didn't think about this too much we should just
use the same strategy as before in the previous pipeline.
And then just added in some examples to show you how pipeline can work the ID as far as a general strategy.
This was basically all essentially made up.
Okay.
So I hope you enjoyed that and I hope you now have a better understanding of how you can integrate a
pipeline into Quanto plans.
Id Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.