Welcome back everyone to this lecture on Quanto in basic algorithm methods.
Remember that the corresponding code for this lectures notebook will only work inside the Clintonian
ID.
We're going to start off beginning exploring how to create trading algorithms.
And there's a few key functions that we need to learn about.
It's initialize handle data and then before tradings start once we understand how these key functions
work inside the Quanto open.
Ideally we'll be able to expand on them to create our own trading algorithms.
But first let's start off with the basics.
Let's chumped Clintonian dot com and show you how to get to the ITC or here and at Quanto Appian dot
com.
And there's two ways to actually get to the development environment.
One is just click on this queue and then click on start coding.
And the other way is if you click on research and then go to algorithms.
This will take you to a list of all the algorithms you created.
You can see here I created a bunch of them.
So we're going to do is select here new algorithm and then give your algorithm a name so I'll say BASIX
algo or whatever you want to call it and then create algorithm and this will eventually create an algorithm.
It will auto fill this of a template for you to work with and it will become more useful to us later
on.
But for now you can go ahead and just do control or command and delete everything.
This left panel here is basically like an editor so you can code in Python here etc. and then you can
save this to save any changes once you hit build algorithm it will begin a simple back tests here.
And if you want to run a full back to us with a lot more information and click here and run full back
to us.
But that just takes a lot longer.
And then there's also a log's panel here.
So anything that gets printed out you'll see it in the logs or if you didn't actually successfully execute
a trade.
It will also log that for you.
And then if you ever get any errors there's runtime errors.
All right.
So let's get started on the very basics.
So the very first function you talk about is the initialize function and then we also need discuss the
handle data function.
What we're going to be doing is we're going to use the tech stock portfolio that we calculated in earlier
lectures when we're talking about portfolio optimization.
Keep remember that we had the Apple Cisco Amazon IBM stock that we were trying to optimize a portfolio
holding.
So our basic algorithm here is just going to be by those three stocks in the optimized portfolio allocation
that we discovered earlier.
It's truly a trading algorithm it's a very simple one.
Essentially just buy three stocks and hold them for a specific time period.
We're really focused here on learning how can we use Quanto paeans ID to take what I think is a good
trading algorithm idea and then actually code it out.
So again the key function when you talk about here is initialize.
So we have initialize and that's going to take in context.
And so to initialize those it's called exactly once when our algorithm starts.
And it requires context as input and this context variable is essentially an augmented Python dictionary
that's used for maintaining the status of your algorithm during your back test or during a live trading.
And it can be referenced in different parts for algorithms so we'll be passing around this context object
throughout our actual functions and it should be used instead of global variables throughout the algorithm
and properties can be assigned that accessed using dot notation.
So let's go ahead and show you how you can do that.
First we'll show you how to reference stocks.
So you end up doing you say contex dot and then you'll notice you have a count in portfolio already
attached to this context.
We'll discuss that later on.
Well we're going to do is we're going to essentially add a property to it and we're going to add AAPL
for Apple and then we're going to use the builtin as ID function.
And this is the security ID function remember as we discussed earlier we don't really want to use symbols
you want to use numerical IDs in case a symbol name has ever been changed or reassigned or been dropped.
So the North uses ID you just type an ID open print season a should see a little window pop up and then
you can search here for company names.
You can search by Ticker.
So you say AAPL will bring up Apple or you can search by the actual company name such as Apple and it
will end up showing you different companies like Applebee's Apple Inc.
Etc. so we end up going.
And then up and down on your key on the keyboard then enter here 24.
If you click your mouse it sometimes doesn't work so keep that in mind.
And now we have our security.
The 24 is linked to context Apple.
And we're going to do this two more times one for Cisco as ID and I began searching Cisco and I found
that here hit enter 19:00 and in context thought AMCON and it's going to be Amazon.
So I'll say the and I will say 16 8 401.
And there it is.
Amazon.com Inc.
Okay.
So that is initialize function.
And the next function we don't need to do is handle data so create a new function here called handle
underscore data.
And this also takes in context but then it also takes in data.
And this is required these two arguments context and data.
So this handle data function is called Once at the end of each minute and it requires that context and
data as input context is a reference to that same dictionary type object in initialize.
So this context is going to have access to this information from initialize so we call initialized first.
And now we've assigned Apple Cisco and Amazon to these three security IDs and we don't have access to
that inside that context.
Data is an object that stores several API functions that we're going to discuss at a later time.
For now we're mainly just going to be working with this context data.
So what we're going to do is learn about one of the fundamental already built in functions in the ID
which is order target percent.
So we're going to say order and you'll see it begins kind of helping you here.
S..
Order target percent.
Go ahead and select that one and it will say place in order to adjust the position to a target percent
the current portfolio value.
So what you end up doing is you pass in a security I.D. and then a target percent.
So what does this actually mean.
Well this handled data function is called At the end of each minute throughout your back test and then
it's going to attempt to order this target percent.
So that is going to pass and here contex that Apple because remember this apple in this context Apple
is that security I.D. for Apple.
I could have also just pass an ID 24.
But it's a lot nicer to read if actually pass an apple here.
And then the second argument is the actual percentage.
I want to order and back when we did our portfolio optimization we figured out that point 2 7 was optimal
for Apple.
So I'm going to do this a couple of more times here for the other stocks.
We're going to say Order target percent's will say contex Cisco and order 20 of that 20 percent of that
and that order target percent's and then say context that AMD ZMM for Amazon and that's going to be
point 5 3.
Now keep in mind this is being called at the end of each minute this may be too often for a more realistic
trading algorithm.
Right now it kind of is want to go over the basics so essential we're going to do is try at the end
of every single minute rebalance our entire portfolio to make sure these percentages are true.
So it's either going to sell or buy securities as needed.
So let's go ahead and save this.
So it's already been saved for us.
And let's run a quick back test on this.
So I have 7:26 20:17 here.
Let's go ahead and run a quick two year back test on this or a little more over two years and we'll
start with let's say just a million dollars and then we're going to say build algorithm again if you
hit run full back.
I'll take you to another page or there's a lot more stuff instead we'll just say build algorithm it
will build it and then it will begin to initialize the back test and then we'll also start taking logs
of what happened during your test.
So you can see here it begins warning you hey your order for 18 shares of Apple failed to fill.
So later on we'll see how we can kind of avoid these fill orders or errors I should say but you can
see here that we're beginning to back to us.
We have our algorithms returns versus the benchmark returns.
So let's go ahead and jump forward in time until the spec test is finished should take just a few minutes
depending on how much time you put in here and how complicated your algorithm is going to jump forward
in time now.
All right so that just finished running that took several minutes for me the pinning on how far your
back Tessa's it could take longer and if you shorten it up they'll take less time.
Now you'll notice here the results are kind of wacky.
We have a huge amount of returns but we have kind of a crazy drawdown and we're going to split the draw
that is at a later date.
But keep in mind that because we're ordering our target percentage every single minute we're going to
get some pretty crazy behavior here.
So I don't think that this was some amazing strategy.
The volatility here is quite bad and you even have a negative sharp ratio.
So we're going to do is show you how you can more realistically achieve trading algorithms later on.
But what I want to do is quickly discuss this data.
So to do that we're going to do a couple of things here.
The first we're going to do is instead of saying each individual ID has its own attribute.
We're going to comment this out.
It's going to highlight this and then do control forward slash and I'm going to create a context object
called let's say tekkies for my tech stocks and it's just going to be a list of these IDs so I'll do
the following.
I have this this and this and so now I have a list of my IDs.
We can expand this just a little more so we get some more room here in the pinning on how much you're
zoomed in you may not get more room so you zoom out and we can see we have more room now for the typing.
And then over here in order target percent I'm actually not going to be ordering anything.
So let's go ahead and comment these out.
It's going to be doing is showing you how we can use data.
So off of this result I'm going to say the following I'll say data dots.
And you notice I have currents can trade is Stael history and fetcher assets.
First off we're going to discuss current.
We'll discuss.
Can trade is stale in history later on.
But we're going to do current and current gets the current value of the specified field for one or more
assets so what does that actually mean.
We can passen either a single ID or a list of IDs.
So for instance I can pass and context that tekkies which is my list of IDs and then I can ask for a
specific field.
And if you want the list of fields and click here and learn more.
But one of the fields that's available is just lowercase.
Close and let's set this equal to our tech close is equal to data current.
And then I'm going to print out that value tech close.
So let's go ahead and see what this looks like when I actually run it and I'm going to make this a lot
shorter.
Let's just make this just essentially one day will say 2017 7 and let's make this the 25th.
All right.
So we're just doing one day back to us and I'm going to make sure that say that I'm going to build the
algorithm.
And let's see what happens here.
So essentially there's nothing to actually back test which means we basically get no results appear.
Instead what I want you to focus on are the logs.
So if we kind of zoom in on the logs here you'll notice we get back this prints equity Apple 1 5 2 3
6 equities Cisco 3 1.9 7 equity Amazon 1 0 3 5.
So what this is doing is remember that handled data operates every single minute.
So every single minute it's grabbing the current closing price for this technical tech stock and then
printing it out and you'll notice that it's printing it out as a panda series.
So I can prove that to you by saying prints the type of tech close and also print a newline here so
we can separate it out.
So prints a new line.
Let's go ahead and save this and build the algorithm and where we should see it.
Oh whoops in bold syntax forgot to close.
Princess here.
Right close the Sprint CS now save and build the algorithm.
Take a look at our logs we can see it storing the initialised back to us just one day and I can see
here my time series and it's going to print out hey this the panels that core series.
So what this is doing is grabbing your current data closing price and you can print it out.
Now usually you won't be printing it out especially if you're running this every minute.
Instead you'll be using the sort of data for your trading algorithm so you could do things like hey
if Apple's current stock price is greater than a certain percentage of Cisco stock price sell Cisco
etc just kind of different things like that so that's the use of data sexy GRABBE current data for use
in your algorithms.
Now there's two other methods I want to discuss off data and that is the is Stael method as well as
they can trade a method.
So we're going to do is the following.
We're going to say we come in all this out or just delete it but in case you ever want to know if the
last traded date for the asah is different than the current algorithm time you can use the is stale
and it's just gonna return a boolean true or false.
So a person in ID for example let's say Apple.
And then we can say print data is stale.
So essentially what that tells you is hey is the current data that I'm getting back equal to the current
data in my back test.
So let's go ahead and build this algorithm.
Let it run.
So here we can see in the log.
It just prints out false.
So again this data is stale method.
What it does is for the given asah or can also taken in iterable of assets such as a list it returns
true if the asset has ever traded.
And there is no trade data for the current simulation time.
And then if the asset has never traded just returns false in our case we're not really trading it.
So it just returns FALSE.
And is just the way you can check if the current data that you're getting is current with the specific
time and the back test.
And then finally the last month I don't want to show you off this data object is can trade it.
So let's go ahead and show you how we can do that so we can say data can trade.
So analysts say if data and we'll see here can trade and this basically just returns true or false.
And it's true if the asset is alive and has traded at least once and we just Pessin in SD here.
So you don't need the extra princes passenger side it's just say for Amazon So Amazon that come sole
say if data can trade this as ID I'm going to order target percent's And let's just say grab SITD of
Amazon which was 1 6 8 4 1
and then we can say what percentage of it we want which is make our whole portfolio that.
So all this is doing is going to be use the term and if the assets currently listed on a supported exchange
in a returns true for a particular asset in a given minute bar in our backtesting result and whether
or not we're able to place an order for that asset and it's actually a really important Guard to have
in your algorithm.
If you're handpicking securities that you want to trade that we don't ever stumble into any errors.
If for some reason you're trying to order a specific stock and maybe sometime in your backtesting gets
delisted or something else happens where you make an error there.
So if data that can trade if you're dealing with particular stocks it's always a good idea to try to
include that.
All right.
So there's the very basics we learned about initialize which is called the once at the beginning of
the algorithm and then handle data which is called every single minute.
So we're going to learn about before trading start which is going to occur before the start of the trading
day.
Let's go ahead and discuss that in the next lecture with part two of the basic algorithm methods.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.