Welcome everyone to the lecture on E.W. a models so we've previously seen how calculating a simple moving
average of pandas rolling can allows create a simple model that describes some sort of general trend
level behavior of a time series.
For example when we were calculating the simple moving average using pandas rolling we did things like
calculate a six month average a 12 month moving average etc..
So looking at that passenger airline data again we can use the simple moving average to kind of try
to grab that general trend.
And the longer the window the time period the more you're focused on a long term trend.
Here you can see that that 12 month moving average basically describes on a year to year basis what
the trend is and we can see year to year.
It's slowly moving up we can improve the simple moving average by actually calculating an exponentially
weighted moving average.
So this is because a simple moving average has a few weaknesses and some of those weaknesses are things
like smaller windows will lead to more noise rather than signal.
It's always going to lag by the size of the actual window itself.
So you'll always have missing data.
The very first point and then it's never actually going to reach the full peak or Valley of the data
due to the averaging.
It also doesn't really inform you about possible future behavior.
All that really does is describe trends in your data and extreme historical values can also skew your
SMK significantly to help fix some of these issues.
We're going to do is use E.W. M-A which stands for exponentially weighted moving average.
Let's describe how E.W. M8 works.
So exponentially weighted moving averages will allow us to reduce the lag effect from a simple moving
average and it will put more weight on values that occurred more recently.
And that's easy to do.
All we have to do is apply more weight to more recent values and that's how it gets its name.
So as the values get closer to the present time we actually apply more weight to them when calculating
the average.
So the amount of weight applied to the most recent values will depend on the actual parameters used
in the E.W. M8 and the number of periods given in a window size those parameters can be messed around
with empanadas until you get the desired effect.
So we're going to do in the next lecture is coda an example of using pandas to create an E.W. a model
in the very next lecture.
We've already talked about as composition and we've already talked about E.W. here.
So let's kind of switch gears and go to the Jupiter notebook.
We'll first talk about E.W. may then in the next lecture after that we'll talk about TSD composition
and then we'll shift gears to talk about ARIMA models in general.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture.
Are we actually code out E.W. may using pandas.