Hello everyone and this lecture we're going to quickly go over the exercises for the python crash course
section let's jump to the Jupiter note book and get started.
All right.
So in the zip file that goes along this course the Python for finance repo folder you'll find the python
crash course folder and inside of that there's three files the python crash course notebook which went
through everything that we just covered and there's two notebooks the exercises and the exercise solutions.
Go ahead and click on the exercise notebook.
Open it up and then that will have the python crash course exercises.
And again there's just different tasks free to do and the tasks are related to a little bit of financial
data.
But again very basic stuff will get into a lot more detail finance data later on in the course.
These are just basic tests to review the python crash course material.
So given a price of three hundred Python to figure out the square root of the price there's different
ways you can do that and you can see the expected answers here as output to themselves.
You just fill in the cell with whatever method you thought was best.
Task number two given the string stock indexes equal to espie 500 grabbed 500 from the string using
indexing and slicing task number three.
Given the variables these two guys use that format to print out this following string so that string
interpretation and the DOT format method task number four given the variable of a nested dictionary
of nested lists what I want you to do is just copy and paste this or you actually already have it here.
Use indexing and key calls to grab the following items so you have this dictionary.
And there's actually a nested dictionary inside of it.
And there's another key with a list and a nested list.
So it's kind of a complicated exercise in grabbing keys and grabbing list indices don't worry nothing
in real life for the rest of the course going to be this complicated this nested this is just a practice
to make sure you really understood what we're talking about.
So use indexing he calls to grab this value 250 which is yesterday's S&amp;P 500 price and the number 365
nested inside a list.
So if we come over here you can see there's 365 all the way back there.
So I want you to grab those two values or elements using key calls and index calls task number five.
Given some strings of this form right here what I want you to do is create a function called Source
finder that returns the source.
So you can either price some price than it says source dash dash and source of whatever this data was.
I want you to create a function called Source finder that when you pass the stream here it will return
back the string.
QUANDO as number five is create a function called Price finder that returns true if the word price is
in a string and then returns false with the price is not in a string.
So the keyword is going to be really helpful here.
And as a quick note your function should work even if prices capitalize or an extra punctuation.
So you can see here that what is the price next to questionmark that worked.
Dude what is price on all caps that also works and the price is 300.
That also worked.
So again the keyword is going to be helpful there.
Then test number six is to create a function called Count price that counts the number of times the
word price occurs in a string and then account for capitalization.
And if the word is next to punctuation.
So here we get a string that says wow that is a nice price.
Next to a very nice price Persse couple as I said price three times.
If you pass that string as into the function count price it should be able to count how many times price
showed up then the last task.
Task number seven is create a function called AEG underscore price or average price that takes in a
list of stock price numbers and calculates the average So the average is just the sum of the numbers
divided by the number of elements in the list and it should return a float.
So you see average price three four or five.
And here's a quick hint to this one.
If you want to get the length of a list you can use the built in LTE and length function.
So if you ask for the length of this lists one two three four it returns back.
There's four elements or if you ask for the length of the list a be it returns back to elements so they'll
be useful for this particular task.
OK.
And that's it.
Best of luck on the exercises.
Coming up next are the solutions to.