Again you should always be caution narry with shorting stock but just to show you how we can do that
you just add a negative sign here and All-State that half your portfolio should be attempting to short
IBM.
So there's some complexities that happen when you're trying to short stock.
But for now it's kind of the simplest way to do it and then go create another function called Record
underscore the A R S A record of variables and a passing context and data here an I'm going to do the
following.
So I'm going to call record and record as a built in function here and what it does it just is going
to record some information for you so you can see it in a plot and the way it works is you essentially
give a name to the series that you're trying to record.
So for example M.Z. AZN underscore clothes that's the name I'm going to assign this when I'm actually
recording here.
And then when I actually do is Passons some sort of data object to be recording.
So I'll say to that current context AMCON close and balance off the princes and then we're going to
do the same for the following.
We'll say record and then I'm going to say IBM underscore close and just to make sure that it's clear
that I can call this first parameter whatever I want to say.
IBM closed jelly just to make it very clear to you guys what is actually happening here.
This is not some pre-determined parameter argument.
It's just whatever you want to call it it'll show up here on the plot and then you pass in the data.
So we're going to be recording the current price of IBM and will say close their current close price.
OK so we have this rebalance function and this record variable's function.
Now it's actually schedule these.
So inside our initialize function we're going to call schedule the underscore function and let's first
off risk scheduling rebalance so pass and the date rules and we're going to have this run every day
you get rid of that help there.
So every day this is going to look say a data rules not the rules.
There are no rules.
Every day this is going to happen.
And let's have it be at market open OK.
So I've scheduled that function going to schedule another one.
And then what I'm going to do here is I'm going to say record underscore verus the rules have this record
every day and then time rules.
Let's just say market close.
OK so that's balanced out now.
I'm going to make sure that say it and then I'm going to build the algorithm.
So let's go ahead and try it out.
All right so let's take a look at the results here.
We can see how our algorithm actually performed against the benchmark that was this rebalancing ordered
Targa percent so long on Amazon shorting IBM.
But notice here now we have an extra plot and this is the record variable's plot that we just created.
So this record function is actually going to record some data and then plot it up for you and you can
then click on these buttons to see it or toggle it on or off.
Now I wanted to show you here is that this argument here of IBM underscore closed jelly that's essentially
just the name of whatever you decided you want to call whatever you're recording.
Typically you'll try to call it as close as you can to whatever you're recording like Amazon close price
or even close price.
But I just wanted you to be clear that not to get confused on these parameters.
This first parameter like IBM close Chelly is whatever we decide to call this here.
So you have total control over what you want to actually call that.
It's not some default parameter.
So again it's just the record function whatever you wanted this side of what you're going to call this
recorded data.
And then the actual data points that you're recording and then we'll plot them up for you automatically
over the time period.
So that's how the record function works and that's how schedule function works.
Now in your note book there's some more information about slippage and commission.
There's a set slippage function as well as a set commission function.
Those allow you to edit the simulations abilities to do slippages which is basically estimating the
impact of orders on the fill rate and the execution price.
So for example if you were to ask for $200 million worth of Apple stock you would expect the price to
immediately jump up.
So Quanto Appian trying to take that into account with a slippage model and the default values pretty
much are what you should use.
But if you want to set your own slippage if you're a extremely advanced user you could set slippage
yourself.
You could check out the note book provided for this lecture to Sless slippage yourself.
Now there's also a sec commission.
So to actually execute a trade usually you have to pay some sort of commission value.
Typically the default commission model charges about point 007 five cents per share with a minimum trade
cost of at least one dollar.
Now if you wanted to you could set commissions to be higher than that or lower than that Quanto been
really recommends you just keep the defaults.
So we won't actually Masseron of slippage or set commission.
Keep in mind they are available to you if you're a more advanced users.
But I really just recommend that you always use the defaults because they're are fairly realistic.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.
Welcome back everyone to part 2 of open basic algorithm methods and this lecture we're going to discuss
checking historical data as well as scheduling functions in the ID.
Let's hop over back to where we were last time and continue.
OK so here we are back.
The idea we previously discussed the data can trade a method that you can call off of it.
And we also discussed that at current.
Now we're going to talk about data that history data that history allows you to call historical information
on the equities and the return data is adjusted for splits mergers dividends at the current simulation
date.
So whenever you're calling that history off the data object you don't have to worry about those things.
Everything's already been adjusted for you.
So let's show you how we can actually use it.
So I'm going to say context that tekkies.
Keep those three technical companies there and I'm going to ask for price history and I'm going to set
the sequel to data dot and then I'm going to use history and what it does.
It just gets a window of values for the given fields and given assets.
So you in either a list or a single asset and then the fields either list a field or a single field
and then there's bar counts in frequency which will learn about in just a little second.
So let's kind of expand this here.
So the first thing to do is say context and let's go ahead and just passen tekkies which is the list
of those security IDs.
And then the fields we want we can either pass in a list of fields or a single string for fields and
I'm just going to ask for a price.
And if you ever want to know what fields are available you can click here and learn more and I'll give
you the list of fields that you can passen.
Then the next thing you ask for is a bar count and we're going to set the bar count equal to 5.
Now what the bar count does it just specifies the number of days or minutes to include in the Panthers
data frame that's returned by the history function.
And it only accepts integer values so we'll say bar count is equal to 5 comma here.
And then we're going to determine the frequency of the data and get rid of this right here.
The frequency is going typical too.
And this is a string code.
So I'll say one day for one day.
And again you can check out that learn more link to get the various frequencies that are allowed but
typically you're going to either see it either daily or minute data.
So it's going to be usually either 1 D or 1 m whether you want daily data or minute by minute data and
then for other frequencies where you can do is you can actually use the pandas sample function.
So let's actually just show you what this example actually looks like.
I'm going to then printouts price history
and keep in mind this is going to print out price history for every single minute since it's still under
handle data.
We'll talk about putting this in another function later on.
But let's go ahead and run this.
So say build the algorithm once it's been saved and we should see a bunch of logs printout and just
the second.
All right.
So if you take a look at what's going on here we can see that we got returned a data frame with for
equity's information kind of expand this and let's show more here.
And we have a data frame and the formatting is a little strange just because it does have enough space
to print everything but all the information is there.
So it's equity of Apple equity and Cisco and then equity Amazon So these are the historical prices for
the last five days so I can see I have indexed our days the 19th 20th 21st 24th and 25th and then the
prices for Apple Cisco and Amazon in repeating this information every single minute because it's under
the handle data.
Typically you won't be asking for data that history in the handle data.
Otherwise you'll get it back every single minute.
So instead what you're probably going to want to do is schedule this.
So let's discuss how his schedule functions because putting everything and handle data probably isn't
a wise decision because you're executing it every minute.
So we're going to collapse this again.
Let's show you how to schedule a function so you can use a schedule underscore or function and then
pass in the functions you want to schedule.
First let's actually create some functions here.
Let's delete all of this.
So in deleting my handle data function and then going to say create new function called open positions
and any function that you want to have scheduled needs to take in both context and data and then what
this is going to do it's going to let's say Order target percent's so say Order target percents and
we're going to say context Apple.
In fact licious instead of having all these techies who just have a single idea here.
So we're just really dealing with one Apple stock.
So order target percents and with say Order Apple and make it 10 percent of my entire portfolio.
And then will have another function called close positions.
Passing context pasand data.
And then what this is going to do it's going to say Order target percent.
And if I want to close everything out on apples so basically just get rid or liquid They all my apple
positions all set this as zero.
So I have a function here open positions and it's just basically open positions on Apple and it says
Hey add of all the money I have mixture 10 percent of my portfolio is allocated to Apple stock since
that's a security ID.
Here they have a function called close positions which says okay close all my positions on Apple set
my entire portfolio to have zero percent for Apple.
So essentially just look with all that.
As soon as it can.
Now we can actually schedule these functions and we can schedule them inside initialize.
So we'll call schedule underscore function.
And here we can see the arguments it takes it takes my phunk a date rule or time rule and then half
days whether true or false we don't really worry about that.
Is going to take in these three main arguments the function you're going to schedule the date rule and
then the time rule and you can click here and learn more for more information about it particular documentation
that essentially is just going to say how often do you want to run this function.
So the very first thing you need to pass on is the actual function of the fine.
So I have open positions.
So let's go ahead and pass that in open positions.
And keep in mind I'm not calling the function to execute here so I won't have these parentheses.
I'm just passing in the function itself.
So once you've passed in the function what you're going to have is date rules.
So we're going to say dates underscore rules dots and you can see here there's a list of rules that
can passen I can either say have this happen every day happen every week at the start of the week at
the end of the week at the month start or at the end of the month.
So let's go ahead and have this every single week so say a week start and then I can actually offset
it by a certain day.
So if it wants happened on Tuesdays or Wednesdays instead of just Mondays I can put it day off set as
well but we'll just have thoughts or week underscore starts.
Remember you called date rules dot and you see your various options and then the third one was the time
rules.
So I'll say time rules dot and then we have marked open market close.
So if I choose market open I can say hours and minutes.
So this is going to schedule a function to run relative to the market open time.
So if I don't pass in anything it just has hours the for zero minutes once a basically one minute after
market opens it begins executing this function.
All right.
Now let's go ahead and schedule the close positions function so we'll do the same thing here will say
schedule underscore function then we pass in the function I want to schedule in this case it's close
positions.
So say close positions is a function we want to schedule.
And the next thing you do is specify the date rules.
So let's do it at the end of the week where we close out our positions on Apple.
So I'll say rules and then we'll see week end.
So this is at the end of the week.
And then I can also offset that in case I want to go backwards.
And then the final thing I want to do is time rules say time rules and sort of market open.
I'm going to say market close and this is going to schedule to run the function relative to the market
close time.
So if I have market close here and I add in minutes equal to 30 that means 30 minutes before the market
closes execute the close positions which generally just dump all Apple stock.
So I'll say here minutes is equal to 30 and it could've all specify to do it like in two hours before
etc..
But essentially what this is doing is it says OK initialize this context here I'm setting context the
apple to be the security ID of Apple Inc.
And then of scheduling these two functions I'm saying open positions at the start of the week.
The rules go ahead and execute it at the market open with no extra parameters in there.
What I could do is say wait an hour after the market opens etc. but it's really up to you the penny
what your trading algorithm is we are going to put in for your time rules and executes positions which
then says order target percent apple 10 percent rate per Foleo and then schedule a function close positions.
At the end of the week 30 minutes for the market closes go and execute close positions which century.
So your portfolio have zero percent now Apple stock.
So we could do is come back to us this just a week or so let's see what happens we can build the algorithm
and we'll have an invalid syntax.
Let's make sure that's all right.
Looks like my princes are our belts let's make sure those are balanced out so I can see green highlighted
there.
Let's save this build the algorithm again and I can get less here.
So I don't see that many logs and I can see over the week how my actual algorithm did.
Now this is essentially not doing much because it only executes once during this entire back.
So we shouldn't really see anything during the back test results.
It looks like we've got a quick air accidentally wrote a piece.
So let's make sure that's AAPL down here.
Let's save that build the algorithm again.
And now it's Click here less so we don't see all the logs and there I can see my algorithm actually
initializing the back test.
All right.
So essentially we can see almost nothing happened there is the benchmark.
And there's my algorithm.
It buys some stock at the beginning of the week holds it then sells it and they can see I got 0.2 percent
returns off that.
OK.
Let's show you how we can get portfolio information and record it.
Record is a really nice function we can use to see other plots here.
Let's say I wanted to not just record my algorithm versus the benchmark but actually wanted to record
the price of Apple stock or any other historical information we can record basically any data we want
and it will automatically build a plot for us.
Let's show you how we can do that.
We're going to clear all of this so we can get a little more practice billing this out.
First thing I need to do as I always say in my initialize function and then passing context to it and
off of this will say context of Amazon check the ID pass and Amazon here enter.
And then let's also do IBM will say Id pass an IBM let it Search for International Business Machine
corporation that looks good.
And then we're going to schedule two functions later on.
But for now we'll create another function and it will be rebalance in passing context and data and what
we're going to do is we're going to the following we're going to have half her portfolio go long on
Amazon.
So we'll have half of our own money just by Amazon stock.
So say Order target percent and we'll pass and contex Amazon and we'll say 0.5.
So half my for Hoyle's going to be going long on Amazon and then we'll say Order target percent and
we're actually going to short IBM.
So the way that is you pass an