Hello everyone and welcome to this first trading algorithm.
So now let's go ahead and apply what we've learned about Antonina research and Quanto paeans idea to
create our first trading algorithm.
We're going to be conducting a strategy known as pairs trading.
So we're going to implement a simplified approach of the parish trading strategy basically where we
take two securities we believed to be paired together such as Coca-Cola or Pepsi or two airlines.
And we'll see how we can use that relationship to actually create an algorithm that trades off that
relationship.
Keep in mind this approach is not something you should actually trade with especially the simplified
approach that we show here.
Instead we're going to really be focusing on understanding Quanto PIENSO platform.
So make sure to do the additional reading and the resources.
If you're further interested in a more realistic example of pairs trading in our case we're going to
focus the first part on conducting research getting the stock information seeing how these two securities
are correlated to each other.
And then the second part is going to focus on actually implementing the strategy against a simplified
version of Paris trading.
All right let's get started.
I might jump over to Quanto in COM and open up a new notebook there.
OK here I am at Quanto dot com.
I've gone to research notebooks and I've created a new research notebook.
I'm going to zoom in one more level here and the notebook that's provided for you for this lecture is
a notebook that you can actually run locally for the first part of it.
That is the research half and it uses Quando.
We're not going be able to use quando here in the research notebook area but instead we can just use
get pricing.
So let's go ahead and do a couple of imports here will say important umpires and the import panderers
as PD and then we'll import plot lib type plots as Piazzi.
So we're going to run that since we're in Quanto it means research notebook we don't need to say map
Cutlip in line.
Now it's time to actually get the pricing data.
So we'll say get pricing and you can do shift tab here to actually get the pricing but remember it just
takes in the symbol the start and the end date.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to compare United Airlines to American Airlines.
So we'll show you how we can start with that.
We'll say AOL for United Airlines and set this equal to United and we'll set our start dates and end
dates so let's do that our souls will say Star is equal to.
And let's say something like 2015 0 1 0 1 and we'll set the end date to be 2017 0 1 0 1.
So we just have two years of data here.
And then let's go ahead and set that as our start date sort of say start date is equal to start and
then we'll say our end date is equal to end and we're going to copy the same command here and do the
exact same thing for American Airlines.
And our basic idea here is if for instance fuel costs go up American Airlines stock should maybe go
down because the price of airlines going to get more expensive or airline tickets at least.
And we would expect United to behave the same way.
So let's go ahead and run this and get this pricing information and we're going to save it as to data
frame's and then let's check out what we get for United.
So we check out the head of United and we get the open high low close price volume and then price and
by default here we're getting daily data and we can check out the same thing for American and we can
see their price.
So let's go ahead and plot both of these out and see how similar they are as far as their behavior is
concerned.
We'll see.
American and will use leadership tap here will tell us that we have close underscore price sources close
underscore price and willing to plot this out and let's give this the label AAA for American Airlines
and we'll set the figure size to be something like 12 by 8 so make sure that's an equals the next they're
going to do is say United grabbed the close price of their And they were going to plot this out and
give it the label for United.
And in fact let's just to make it really clear when you say united
and then we can say peel the legends so we can actually see the results.
So we'll run that and we can see here American Airlines and United Airlines and I can zoom out just
another bit and it looks like their behavior is highly correlated between each other.
So let's actually try to get these correlation coefficient to see how correlated these two stocks are.
Now remember for more advanced pairs trading We would it just look a correlation we will look at things
like CO integration which is different than correlation and it's actually a lot harder to find to purchase
of securities to have good CO integration prepares trading it's easier to find things that have just
a correlation.
So this is why we're using a simplified approach here.
Now one easy way to get correlation is just to call some pie.
We'll zoom back in here and MPI can basically create a correlation coefficient matrix.
So say c o r r so a correlation coefficient.
And again it just returns that Peerson correlation coefficient and then we passen the two time series
we want to check.
So say American clothes price.
See how correlated it is with United States United and its close price.
So we'll run that and we basically get this correlation matrix where one in one just represent how correlated
is American Airlines to itself.
That's one how correlated is United Airlines itself.
That's one.
And then the correlation between each other.
So here you can see there 0.19.
So they're highly correlated.
Now due to the fact they're highly correlated working to do the following assumption for our trading
strategy we're going to assume that because they're highly correlated that any significance and difference
in the spread of their prices may be a trading opportunity.
So let's actually calculate the spread and then we'll normalize the spread of a z score.
So first calculate just the normal spread.
So I'll say spread is equal to American the close price minus United close price and then we're going
to plot this out and we'll say label is equal to spread and let's give this a good fig size maybe something
like 12 by 8 and if we just run that we can see the spread itself.
So let's actually mark a horizontal line on the average spread so we'll say peel.
And if you ever want to draw just a straight horizontal line you can use X line for axis horizontal
line and then this just takes a single value along the y axis.
So that single value for me is just going to be the average spread.
So what's the average Out of all these values.
So we say spread that mean and then we're going to signify a color here just seasonal to our.
So this should give us a nice red line here.
So here this red line is representing the average spread.
And then over time we can see the real spread.
So let's go ahead and normalize this with the score because the two stock prices are technically different
so we're going to normalize them now.
So let's do that ourselves we'll say DPF z score.
And it takes in stocks and it's going to return the following.
We're going to say stocks minus the average of that time series of stocks divided by the standard deviation
of the stocks will say that a CD of stocks so that takes a time series of stocks and basically normalizes
it by subtracting the average and then dividing it by the standard deviation.
So let's call it z score on our spread.
Remember spread originally was just the difference between those two close prices.
So we're going to normalize that.
And then we will plot that out.
And I will say Fix size is equal to 14 by 8.
And this is going to give us something that we can actually trade on.
And let's go ahead and create a horizontal line and we'll say the score of spread mean and whip's spread
first needs to be passed and sizzix score and then take them enough for that.
OK so what I'm doing here is I'm taking that spread passing it through the score first and then taking
the average of it and then let's also give this a color will say color is just give it black then I'm
going to plot another horizontal line and this is going to go at one point zero.
Well first before we actually do that let's just show you what this should look like.
So you noticed that my z score the behavior looks the same as what we have up here.
But now the actual values have been normalized which means by definition because we're subtracting the
mean and dividing by the standard deviation and normalizing the spread the actual mean should be hovering
around zero.
And now we have something that we can actually trade on so we can set limits on the top spread.
And the bottom spread and then say something like Hey if it ever goes below this particular normalized
spread score we'll go long on the stock or we'll short the stock and then if ever goes above a particular
spread score we'll let go long and one stock and go short on the other airline stock.
So let's actually add in those horizontal lines
we'll say one point zero for the first one let's say give it the color red and then let's say Ls for
line style and make it kind of a dash line and then we'll cover all do the exact same thing.
And then let's make this one.
Well let's make this first one green.
Second one to read.
Doesn't really matter the color that much.
And the next one is going to get negative 1.
Now that we have this nice plot here let's go ahead and discuss it how we can actually use this for
a trading algorithm.
So I have zero being my mean value blue line actually representing the normalized spread.
And then the green and red lines depicting plus or minus one off this average value.
My main strategy is the following.
I'm going to say that if there's ever a dip either a below the negative one or you know some other arbitrary
value below the mean or there's ever a peak above another value that we can choose maybe 1.
If you want it to be higher like 1.5 that's also OK.
But the main idea being if it ever dips below a particular point here below the normalized score spread
or if it ever peaks above it then I expect there to be what we call a reversion to the mean.
So eventually that spreads should that back down.
And the reason I think that is because in the past I think these stocks are highly correlated which
means our actual spread of value when you normalize it shouldn't be that big of a difference.
Now this may not always be true.
As you can see here Historically it hasn't been true but it does hopefully eventually come back to some
sort of average range.
Now picking this range is a little more complicated and we're not taking it to affect things like integration
which would probably say that these particular stocks are not well-suited for pairs trading but for
the simplified approach this makes sense to us.
So again basic approach is I think these two stocks are highly correlated to each other which means
their spread shouldn't be that significant especially when we normalize it.
So if the spread ever dips below a particular remark or goes above particular remark I'm going to either
go long or short on the stocks the pending home calculating that spread.
Now there is one small problem with this is the fact that I was able to plot out this spread using the
entire time series if were back testing this on Quanto Appian.
We're not going to immediately have the entire time series of our full back test available to us.
Instead what we're going to have to figure out is how to calculate a rolling z score.
So let's show you how we can do that.
So we're going to do is a following we're going to first calculate a one day moving average of the price
spread.
So I'm going to say spread moving average one.
So what does this actually become.
This is the spread going to call rolling off this time series by one day and take the average off of
this.
So that's my one day moving average which is essentially if you kind of think about it.
Today's price almost.
And then we're going to do a 30 day moving average so will say spread moving average 30 day spread spread
rolling and this is going to be 30 days and then we'll take the average of that that I'm going to take
the rolling 30 day standard deviation.
So I'll say the standard deviation of 30 Krita variable that kind of accounts for that.
Take the spread.
Rolling 30.
But instead of calling me I'm going to call a standard deviation off of this then I'm going to compute
the z score for each of these days so I'll say z score let me 30 underscore one is equal to the following.
So it's going to be equal to the spread moving average one.
So this basically accounts for kind of the current spread.
So if we go back up here to where we're calculating the z score number we took the current stock minus
that stock's average and then divided by the standard deviation.
This current stocks were essentially representing it by saying OK just rolling one day moving average
then we're going to say the following I'll say that minus the 30 day moving average and then we're going
to divide that by the standard deviation over the 30 days.
So this is essentially a rolling version of the z score function we have a peer.
And the reason we need that rolling method is because we're not going to have access to the entire time
series or actually implementing our algorithm.
We're not going to access future information.
So instead we're going to wait 30 days until our algorithm actually kicks in.
Then once we have 30 days gone past we can begin to calculate that normalized the score and we can see
how the current price whether it's inside or outside the bounds that we happen to indicate.
So now we have a rolling z score we can go ahead and plot it.
So we'll say the score thirty one well plotted out give it a big size of something like 12 by eights
and let's go ahead and label this let's say rolling 30 day z score and we'll plot some horizontal axis
line we'll do it.
Zero color all the black
and then let's go ahead and just put in one more horizontal line and we'll say one point zero color
is red.
Now let's make this lifestyle just be dashed.
So we plot that out and we get the following.
Now we have a rolling z score that we can actually execute on.
And you can adjust this one value and we actually go onto implementing this in the next lecture of the
IEEE.
We'll see how adjusting this value here kind of as our cutoff affects the algorithm.
But this is essentially what we need to actually execute the trading algorithm.
So in the next lecture Rexy going to implement this strategy where we use the initialize function and
as well as scheduling functions to have Quanto and execute the strategy.
So at some certain point wants to spread goes beyond an arbitrary mark that we choose We're going to
execute a trading strategy which is either short American Airlines or go long and United etc depending
how you actually calculate the spread.
But that's the basic idea behind this simplified version of Paris trading.
So we're mainly dealing with the spread because we think if they're highly correlated then the spreads
should at some point go down to some sort of average value.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But make sure you do the reading in case you're interested in the heavy mathematics behind Pear's trading
strategy.
Coming up next we're actually going to implement the strategy using the ruling's the score with contrarian's
ID.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.