All right here I am the notebook for the most part lip exercises.
Let's go ahead and jump right in and get started.
We're going to go out and run that first cell to get the data.
And let's go at an import map plot lived up high plots as Piazzi and map plotted in.
Now there's one more question which is what Comanche is if you are using a Jupiter note book and as
a reminder that would be Piel Tiede that show at the end of all your plotting commands.
Let's to sort of exercise one.
We want to create a figure object called fig using Pilat figure.
All right.
So this is just the object oriented method of using Map Cutlip where we say fig is equal to peel T-Dog
figure and then we want to use add underscore axes to add a set of axes to this figure.
And I'm going to go in and say x is equal to Fig and underscore axes.
And we actually get the position we wanted that 0 0 1 1.
And then finally I wanted to plot x comma y on that and run this.
OK it looks like we have a good match here and we want the labels and titles to match below.
So if we go ahead and set that in we want to say set X label
to be X and then x whip's x set y label TB Y.
And we also want to set the title and it should have just been a simple title.
All right.
So what do we do here.
We went ahead and created a figure object added a set of axes a figure object plotted on that figure
object and then set the X label the y label and the title.
Let's go ahead and move on to exercise 2 which is a very similar exercise.
We're going to say fig is equal to peel T-Dog figure to create the figure object.
And then we want to put two axes on it x 1 the next to go and say x 1 and x 2 and I'm going to say fig
thought add underscore axes.
First one is located at 0 0 1 0 1.
That's the larger one.
And then the second one is located at 0.2 point five point two point two.
It's going to run that and it looks like we get a same result here.
Great.
Now continue this exercise we want to do is plot both x and y on both axes here.
Let's go ahead and add that into the cell.
So I will say x 1 plot x y and x to plot x y.
And here we have the same plot right here.
You want to be red.
You could have just added in the color arguments red
you just pass in a string and now it will be red to match this lower plot.
And then if you wanted to you could have also added in the X labels and the y labels it's good to move
on to exercise three which was create the plot blow by adding to access to a figure object at these
specific canvas points.
All right.
So not as much guidance though on exercise 3.
First thing I want to do is create a figure object something to say fig is equal to peel t the figure
and then the next thing I want to do is begin to add the sets of axes.
I want to say x is equal to Fig dot axes.
And we'll put them at the same locations that were requested.
I will say x 2 is equal to Fig dot and underscore axes or we'll set these at point to point five point
four point four.
All right.
Running that looks like you get the same result and then coming up next you wanted to use the x y and
z arrays to recreate this plot below.
Let's go ahead and check out that plot below to comment these out and bring this a little closer so
we can see it.
Let me zoom out a little bit.
OK.
So it looks like we have a couple of things going on here in the outer Plaut we have X versus Z.
Let's go ahead and add that in.
So in the large plot which has X in our case it's going to plot x versus Z and I'm actually going to
set the labels for that.
So the X label wups set X label set that to X and X the set y label set that to Z.
So this is the large plot and now it's going to talk about the insert plot so we take a look at the
insert plot has going on.
It's going to be X by Y over here it looks like the title is zoom.
So I'm going to go ahead and say X plot x y and then I'm going to set the title to be zoom and I'm also
going to go ahead and set those labels to be X and then or the Y to be y.
You know we're actually not quite finished yet let's go and run this and see what difference we get
so note right now.
I made a mistake that should have been on the insert.
So this should have been x 2 for all of these it's go ahead and run this and this is looking OK.
But there's still a difference here.
Notice on the zoom the x and y limits X goes from 20 to 22 and y goes from 30 to 50.
Here we're just using the default limits.
Let's go in and change those on the insert.
That's going to be X to dot
set X slim and we want to go from 20 to 22.
Add that in 20 to 22.
And I'm also going to set the while him and if we scroll back down we can see the Whyland went from
30 to 50.
So we'll say 30 comma 50 in this list run that.
And now we can see that we're matching completely on both the insert and the outer plot.
All right now we're on exercise four.
Let's go ahead and use that subplots to recreate this plot below.
I'm going to say Fig.
Come axes is equal to peel T-Dog subplots and one row by two columns.
Let's go in and run.
That's And looks like we get that output correctly.
Now we want to plot x and y and x versus Z on the axes and I want you to play around with the line with
and style.
Let's see if we can match these up correctly.
I'm going to go ahead and plots over here.
Let me empty that out.
And let's go ahead and say xes 0 members using subplots now.
So we're going to be able to iterate or call the sequence of the array of axes.
So I'm saying axes zero plot and it looks like I'm going to go ahead and mess around this would say
x y and on the axes one will go in and plot x z.
You know it's going to set these colors so we'll see that color for the second one to be red and it
looks like the line with a little ticker.
And then this one.
The first one looks like let's go in and set the color to be blue as a string.
And it also looks like the line style LS is a dashed line.
Go and add that in.
It also looks like it's a little thicker sole but in LW we call three it's going run this.
See if we get everything looking OK.
All right.
Not bad.
Looks like we're getting a match.
And now we want to see if we could resize the plot by adding in this Fig's size arguments.
Let's go in and check that out.
Remember we can just add fig size arguments into the subplots call so we can say Fix size is equal to
and looks like we want wide and short.
So we want the first number to be larger so some wider numbers which just well in the second number
to be smaller so we're going say 12 to.
And if we run that looks like we're going to match to the second plot over here.
And they also messed around the stiles a little bit so switch it up on us.
We can go out and do that ourselves.
We just say something like this over here is equal to dash lines.
Now we switched it and matched it.
All right.
That's it for the exercises for Matt plotless.
Hopefully really drilled in as far as the syntax for using Object Oriented map plot live.
All you have to do is say call the figure axes to the figure and then plot on those axes or if you're
using subplots as in the last problem call fig come axes to peel t those subplots and then iterate through
those axes or call using the array of axes to plot on each particular subplot.
That's really all there is to it.
Go ahead and review the solutions book in case any of this was unclear or feel free to post a question
to the Q&amp;A forums.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.