Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on missing data.
Now typically when you're dealing with financial datasets you hopefully don't actually ever have any
missing data.
Usually the stock price is going to be known for pretty much every day.
So it's not very often the asset of missing data.
But there are going to be some cases where you may have to either drop missing data or fill in missing
data.
So let's go ahead and go over Pandurs tools for dealing with missing data.
Let's jump to the Jupiter notebook now.
All right.
Here I am at the Jupiter notebook.
What I want to go out and do is create a data frame and just like we create we could create a series
from a dictionary we can actually create a data frame from a dictionary as well.
This dictionary is going to have three kids in it.
It's going to keep a key B and key C and what these are going to be are columns in our data frame and
then we can do for the actual data points is pasan a list of values for each key and those will be the
data points for each row in that column name.
We'll go ahead and say Key A has a list one 2 and then we're going to use any n to signify a missing
ordinal value.
Then we're going to say for key it's going to be 5 and P and then and P and then and then finally Keesey
our third column.
So we're going to retain all values 1 2 and 3.
So has no missing values.
And then we can go ahead and say is DFAC equal to PD data frame and then pass in the dictionary.
And then when we check out our data frame we get this nice looking data frame of columns A B and C and
then rows 0 1 and 2 no rows 0 has no missing values and Column C has no missing values.
And then there's a few missing values here in ráby or column B and one missing value in column A.
Let's go out and explore the drop and a method.
A lot of times you just want to drop missing values from your data set.
Especially if it's just a few missing values.
If you say drop an A just by itself and call it as a method of close parentheses what occurs is that
panderers is going to drop any row with any single or water more mill or missing values meaning if any
of these rows had a null value in it one or more it went ahead and dropped them.
If you want to perform this action on the columns which you can do is check out shift tab here and notice
that there's an axis argument.
That means by default the access is zero meaning the operation occurs along the rows.
But if you want to do the operation along the columns being drop any columns that have a null value
you can specify access is equal to 1.
And that's going to drop any columns with a null value so I don't see the comparison here.
And that means the drop troponin Atropos any rows any row values in it and then you have to drop in
a with access equal to one is going to drop any columns of null values in it which you can also do is
specify a threshold.
And if we go in and check this out we'll say DMF drop at a news shift town to check out the documentation
that is that there's a thresh arguments now what the argument is it's an integer value and you will
require that many not and a values in order to not get dropped.
For instance let me go and set the threshold equal to 2.
And again we're just going to do this along the rows.
So notice here how we have in Roseboro three nonne and a values in row 1.
We have two non and a values and in row two we have only one.
Number three not any values.
That means if I say drop it like this it drops everything but Roseboro.
However if I set the threshold to be equal to 2 and run this it went ahead and kept row 1.
And basically what that means is because row 1 had at least two not any values 2.0 and the two it went
ahead and kept that row.
All right.
Let's go ahead and move on to fill in.
Right now we just focus on just dropping missing values.
Well a lot of times you'll want to actually replace those missing values.
We take a look at our data frame again.
We have these missing values here.
If we wanted to fill in those missing values we can use to fill and a method and this if we go and take
a shift tab here has a couple of different arguments.
But notice it has a value argument.
And what she can do here is as a value set in your fill value.
I'm just going to pass on a string to make it very obvious here.
What's going on and notice it was able to fill in that value of whatever value we wanted in this case
just a string that said fill value.
However a lot of times when you're going to want to do is actually fill in the value of maybe the mean
of the column and you can do that for example as such you can say DSF of a.
So that's my a column.
And notice the missing point here.
I'll go ahead and say fill and a and I will set the value to the mean of that column.
And now that value has been filled as the mean of the value.
Now there's a whole philosophy and way of thinking and statistical methods for filling in missing values
appropriately.
I'll let you go ahead and explore those on your own.
So they really depend on what kind of data you're working with.
For now all I want you to be aware of is that there's a fill and a method and a drop and a method OK.
That's it for now.
Hopefully you remember just that these two methods are available for you and you can specify what access
you want to perform the action on as well as the thrush argument and the value arguments.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.