Hello everyone and welcome to the solutions lecture for the python crash course exercises.
Let's hop over to the notebook and get started.
All right.
Here I am at the python crash course exercises notebook and we're going to go ahead and do just scroll
down to the first task.
So task one was given the price is equal to 300 use Python to figure out the square price.
So let's define price equal to 300 by running that sell.
And then there's two ways you could do this.
One way is to take the price and take the exponent to the power of one half.
So one divided by two and that gives you seven point three two or you could just say to the power of
0.5.
That's the same thing as taking the square root of something taking the power to it's reciprocal.
The other way you could do this and we actually showed this during the crash course is you can import
math and then say math as security square root of the price and that returns the same thing.
OK moving on to task number two is given the string stock underscore indexes equal to Espey five hundred
GRABBE 500 from the string using indexing or slicing.
So if we run this find it all you have to do after that is call stock index and then we want 500 So
that's going to start at index 0 1 2 which means we want to go from to Colan all the way to the end.
So we run this and we get back 500 task number 3 was given the variable stock index sequel's espie 500
price 300 used that format to print out the following string.
The S P 500 is 300 say Okay.
So we'll run that to find those two variables and then we'll start off first string will say the curly
braces is at curly braces today.
Then I'll say doc formats and I'm going to pass in stock index and is using tabs autocomplete there
and they'll say tab price.
There we go.
And then print out this entire thing wrapped in parentheses.
And there you go.
S&amp;P 500 is 330.
Task number four given the variable of NSA dictionary if it lists and this one's a little tricky gets
kind of giant variable thing use indexing and he calls to grab the following items to 50 and then number
3 6 5.
So I'm going to zoom out just a little bit so you can see this entire dictionary.
So we have the stock info dictionary.
And what we're gonna do is try to first grab this 250 from it and this is tricky.
First specially if you're not used to this sort of thing.
But let's check out stock info.
And let's just find out what the key is it has so say stock info.
Keys and we can see that the top level keys presented here are espie 500 and info.
These other keys those are in the Knesset keys inside of this other key.
So we don't actually get to see and they're not actually part of stock in folkies.
They're part of the nested dictionary keys.
So the top little keys are SPF 100 and info so I can see that I want to grab S&amp;P 500 first to get back
this dictionary then from that dictionary.
I want to grab yesterday to get back this 250 value.
So that's exactly what I'll do.
I'll say stock info and then I will grab S&amp;P 500 and if I run that I get back today 300 yesterday to
50.
So then I'm going to just do another call here and call yesterday and that gives me back to 250.
So it's stock info.
Key call Espey 500 call yesterday.
The next we want to get is 3 6 5.
So 3 6 5.
We take a look at it it looks like it's on info.
So we'll start off with that we'll say stock info.
Grab the info key that returns this list which is actually in nested list.
We have time and then 24 7 3 6 5.
So now I have to use numerical indexing.
So this list is the second item out of this our list which means I need to use indexing one here and
then that returns back 24 7 3 6 5.
So if I want 365 that is an index to which gives him back 3 6 5 sose info then one then two.
And if get trouble of these don't worry about too much but a really great practice.
It just kind of break down the layers so keep kind of peeling away at this.
To get an idea of what's actually happening here.
Now let's go to task 5 which is given the strings with this form or the last source value is always
separated by two dashes.
That's kind of the key here.
Always separated by two dashes create a function called Source finder returns the source.
So that's actually going to be pretty simple the split method.
So it's going to zoom in here and write or function.
So to start off to actually create the function will use the DFA keyword and then we'll type out source
finder and we'll just accept that string and then what I'm going to do on the string is I'm going to
split these two dashes.
So I'm going to return the string and I'm going to split it on the two Ashes.
So if I just run this I will get back a list where the last item on my list is always going to be equal
to that source which means I can just index it say negative 1 and then off of that I get quando the
source.
So I'm just splitting those two dashes and then grabbing the last item in that list of the split result.
Or I test them for 5st a function called Price finder that returns true if the word price is in a string.
So your function should work even if price is capitalized or next to punctuation.
So the way we do that is the following.
We will say DMF resume here one more level and then we'll say price underscore Finder.
It's going to take in some string as it's going to return checking if the string price is in S.
So if we just do that by itself it's actually not enough because it's going to happen is a trigger for
this first one.
But for the second one it will say false because this is capitalized and it's looking for this exact
stream.
So the next thing we can do here is on s I will call the DOT lower method.
And so what that ends up doing is it lower case a string and then checks if price it lower case is in
the lower case version of string and then we'll get true off all these.
Okay task number 6 is to create a function called Count price that counts the number of times the word
price occurs in the string.
And it says to account for capitalization afterward is next to punctuation.
So that one's probably a little more complicated of a function.
We're going to say if cowled price takes in a string and we'll say count as equal to zero at first so
we'll initialize our count and then we're going to do the following.
We'll say four word in and I'm going to say as the lower and then we'll split it all the whitespace.
We're going to say if price is an word I'm going to add one to my count I'll say counts as equal to
counts plus 1.
Then at the end of this once the for loop is done.
Note in the station here I'm going to return the counts.
So no the and then Station.
I'm not doing Return here in the 4 instead I'm doing it aligned with the four.
So it does actually this is the following.
It's going to say set my count equal to zero then four word in estopped lower at that split that's going
to lower case everything then split it on the whitespace which gives me back a list of the lowercase
words if price is in that lowercase version of the word Adelanto the count.
And then finally return the count.
So I can run this and you get three.
So that also works.
There's actually a simpler method and the simpler method is to just say if Count price then you're going
to return the lower.
And then there's actually another method you can call called Count.
You kind of stack these methods on top of each other.
You can just say that count price and that works the exact same way.
This was a little more advanced than I would expect you to kind of get it right away unless you're familiar
with Python.
This is kind of the more logical way to do it.
And then finally test number 7 create a function called average price that takes in a list of stock
price numbers and calculates the average.
So all we need to do here is say the average price takes in some stocks and then I'm going to return
the some of the stocks in this one.
You may have had to look up the word some was a big enough hint there.
And then divided by the length of the stocks.
And there you have it.
OK.
Hope that those tests weren't too hard for you if you felt that this was kind of an overwhelming challenge.
I would recommend you take some sort of refresher course in basic Python if you felt these were pretty
easy or you know OK that's good.
That's exactly what we should be to continue on with the rest of the course.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next section.