Welcome back everyone as you mentioned the last lecture and this lecture we're going to actually look
more into the effects of hedging.
So to start off we're going to try to make a function in order to fictionalize essentially taking the
benchmark return and the stock we're looking at.
In our case Apple and then returning back an alpha and beta value.
So we're essentially going to just create a function called alpha beta.
It takes in some let's say benchmark return so say benchmark underscore or a T and it takes the stock
and what it's going to do it's going to run the linear regression that we did above previously.
So a benchmark is equal to S-M at constant to that benchmark return and then we're going to create a
model regression linear model.
Well yes and it's going to be run on the stock with that benchmark.
So note here that this benchmark is the one of the constant which is the one I'm putting in here.
Transform from the input benchmark return and then we'll see that fit.
And then what I'm going to return is modeled perhaps.
And I'm just going to kind of return as a tuple so say model that pro-ams 0 and modeled that programs
1.
So now essentially made a function out of what we previously did defer the linear regression and we're
going to do here is start off by getting the Alpha and Beta estimates for the last year.
So going to come up here and copy and paste some code that we previously did and you can copy and paste
this from the notebook as well but essentially I want these few lines of code here.
As well as the benchmark ups and then I'm going to copy and paste this CELSS come all the way back down
here and I'm going to copy and paste this.
So we're going to call this cell.
Essentially my pops 20:16 itself.
So here's my data for 2016.
I have an asset I have my benchmark and mislabelled these assett 2016 and benchmark 2016 because later
on we're going to end up using this for 2017 as well.
So then I'm going to set my asset return 2016 to be equal to the asset of 2016.
Percent change one.
And then we're going to grab everything from index 1 and beyond and we're going to essentially copy
and paste this well actually just rewrite it a little be a little faster we'll say benchmark return
or benchmark return.
2016 is equal to benchmark 2016 percent change one and then grab one on where it's and then we're going
to do here just a couple more steps.
We're going to get the asset return values so we can end up plotting some of this stuff and actually
end up passing this to the alpha beta function.
So we'll say values is equal to asset return 2016 the values essentially everything we've done before
and then we'll say benchmark return values is equal to benchmark returns 2016 dot values.
So I can use this information for plotting and this information of passen the alpha beta function so
I will say Alpha 2016 beta 2016 is equal to the function call alpha beta passing in my.
I believe it takes benchmark returns first.
Yes.
So benchmark return values and then the asah return values.
And let's have a couple of print statements at the others will say print something like 20:16 values.
That I'm going to print alpha and then I'll just concatenate this string of 2016 that I'm going to print
beta and I will concatenate a string of the 2016.
OK so let that run and this should give us all the information for 2016.
So we have our Alphaville you one point six seven times since the Barnette five and our beta value.
And this is for Apple stock.
So we're going to do now is essentially create a hedged portfolio in compute alpha beta from there.
So what you actually mean by that.
Well I'll create a portfolio object and do exactly what we did last time.
Multiply by negative 1 beta of 20:16 and then I'm going to multiply that by my benchmark returns of
2016 and I'm going to add my Assar returns of 2016 and don't be too confused by the fact that I have
asked 2016 and acet returns 2016 and asset return values.
The only difference between all these is acet.
That's just the actual price values asset returns.
That is the daily return value minus that first row and then asset return values is the same as asset
return except it doesn't have the time stamp information.
So we're going to run our portfolio and then we're going to do the following we'll say alpha beta equal
to alpha beta and then we're going to pass and the same thing we did last time I will say actually will
say benchmark returns 2016 and then I'm going to pass in my portfolio.
So then I'm going to say Prince portfolio alpha and beta and I'm going to print a couple more things
here and then we'll explain what's actually going on.
So then I will say Alpha here kind of the same as last time and they will say print beta here plus the
string representation of beta OK.
So what is actually going on here.
Well we first calculated based off 2016 the Alpha and Beta values for Apple versus the market and those
were alpha of 1.6 times Tensen negative 5 and a beta of 1.0 or 2.
So you can see it does have some behavior in Apple moves along the market which makes sense because
Apple actually is a huge proponent of the market.
So then here we said Okay I just want to trade on Alpha itself.
So I'll say portfolio minus one times that beta value between 16 times the benchmark returns in 16.
So this first beta term plus Alpha term which is the assassin.
So then we ran this into alpha beta to get back those actual Alpha terms alpha beta and benchmark returns
16 and this portfolio the hedged version and now we can see that we have some alpha value that essentially
is the same but our beta is almost zero.
This is 1.3 six times ten to the negative 16.
So weve essentially completely eliminated beta.
So what we have here is now were trading completely on Alpha that is Apple itself.
So I can plot this out.
So maybe its a little more clear to you so we can say portfolio plot's and lets give this.
And not to get confused by Alpha terms this is just the alpha for how C-3 or how transparent the color
is.
Don't get too confused there and it will give a label of Apple with the hedge and then I'm going to
say my asset returns for 2016 plot those out and let's give this an alpha value of 0.5 and then my benchmark
returns of 2016.
I'm going to plot those out with an alphabet of 0.5 and say p t y label they return.
Let's get this election.
PULTE the legend.
Remember you can always copy and paste this from the provided notebooks.
So we run this and we end up getting a chart that looks like this.
So again you can see here at clear points.
This is essentially what we just did last time.
Exit now it kind of functional eyes that we see Apple with hedge.
And if there's a big dip in the market such as in the middle of July apple of the head doesn't really
respond to that behavior.
So we can see that while regular apple does go down that market when we're focusing on that pure Alpha
term we don't kind of follow the market there but it does mean for big drops where the market was pretty
steady and big peaks where the market is relatively flat.
We also get those as well.
OK.
So what does it actually mean in terms of kind of the average returns.
Well if we take a look at Foleo the mean value of this these are our average daily returns 1.6 seven
times since the power of 5.
And if we took out the asset by itself so asset returns of 20:16 and get the mean value here we end
up getting 0.00 5.
So the general idea here being is that we greatly reduced or sometimes not greatly in our case it's
greatly just because Apple is a huge part of the S&amp;P 500 it makes up a large proponent as far as total
market capitalization.
So I would definitely suggest that you experiment with everything we've done here.
Replace Apple stock with a smaller market cap.
But in our case because we ended up kind of hedging against the market we've reduced our actual average
return.
But if we take a look at our volatility we'll see portfolio SDD that's going to calculate at two point
zero one two.
Let's take a look at just the asset by itself that is Apple's Steria deviation.
We can see here we reduced our volatility or standard deviation not by a whole lot by point 0 0 2.
But yes by around I would say let's looks like around 10 percent reduction in volatility.
Now was that worth the huge reduction in average terms.
Probably not.
Now again Apple's kind of a special case so I would again suggest using another stock besides Apple
to kind of explore and play with this hedging idea yourself.
The reason we kind of get this extreme behavior and Apple is because again Apple has such a huge market
cap that its own movements really affect the market by itself.
So what we can do if we wanted to kind of play around with this some more we could copy and paste what
we did appear except change this to be from 2016 2017 to just be kind of the first half of 2017.
So I'm actually going to copy and paste this from the provided notes.
It's essentially everything that we just did here except instead of 2016 it's for 2017.
So we'll come down scroll down and I'm going to paste that here and note here my start date and end
date.
Everything else is essentially the same.
And the fact that it's all 20:17 and let me change is to be 20:17 based figures.
So I'm going to run that and that's going to tell me the value and the value for 20:17 at least kind
of the first half of 2016 for Apple stock by stock.
And you'll notice if we take a look at Alpha 2016 and Alpha looks better 2016
that there is definitely some change especially for this stock that became more and more in line as
the market cap for Apple grows larger and larger.
It's going to get stronger and stronger because it represents more of the market.
So a move in Apple is going to affect the market more and more so we can see here as time goes on that
basic term gets stronger.
So that means that unfortunately if you're trying to hedge based off historical information such as
trying to hedge your 2017 trades based off the 2016 beta value you're going to eventually get a little
bit more of a larger and larger error term.
So to kind of show what's going on here.
We'll go ahead and create a portfolio based off the 2016 beta estimate so we can say something like
portfolio is equal to minus one times.
And previously we use the perfect beta value.
So if we come back over here we use the perfect value that is beta 20:16 against benchmark returns 2016.
But we're going to pretend that we didn't have access to 20:17 information and we had to use some historically
calculated value.
It's kind of called out of sample because we're going to run this on data that we weren't able to sample.
So we'll say multiply negative 1 by the beta of 2016 and we're going to attempt to hedge based off historical
information and it is not going to be as effective as hedging against the most recent information.
But you're not always going to have access to kind of knowledge of the future.
So now we've created a portfolio that uses the previous year's beta on today's information.
So say Alpha Beta is equal to Alpha Beta and then I'm going to pass in benchmark returns for 2017.
And then my portfolio itself which is this new portfolio value here.
And then what we can end up doing is pasan or just kind of show you Alfas now.
And what it is now and you can compare these to see how well they actually work against the figures
we previously calculated 2016 2017.
And then we can also see here the Alpha and Beta values that we calculated were there as far as our
portfolio is concerned.
So our beta is not zero and that's because we're using beta 2016.
So let's go ahead and plot out what this actually looks like and see the returns.
So I can say something like my portfolio
the mean is point zero or a one to one versus my actual asset returns for 2017.
If I take a look at that mean ends up being greater.
So you can see here we've reduced our average return but hopefully we were able to also reduce the volatility
your standard deviation.
So for fully Osteria deviation points there are a 9.
Let's take a look at asset returns.
SiRNA deviation that's point 0 1.
So again kind of dropping it by 10 percent again.
So the most common tradeoff here is that you're typically sacrificing average returns for less volatility.
Again this is highly dependent on the security securities that have or that make up a large percentage
of the total market cap for this 500 like Apple are going to have much stronger beta values because
they themselves the find the beta or the way the market moves I should say but we can see here that
in general even if we're using historical information for data values which is kind of the most realistic
representation you can't calculate beta at that exact point in time.
But we can calculate some historical data we could say like Beta's like a week off or a day off et cetera
here are kind of an extreme example as a whole year off but it still does what we expect to do.
It lowers the mean and lowers histeria deviation.
Okay.
So that's the basic idea of hedging against the market.
I hope you understood the general concept.
It's basically just cackling in that beta value and then multiply it by negative 1 to essentially cancel
out any benchmark returns.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.