Welcome back everyone here we are at the same notebook where we left off last time and this lecture
we're going to take this process and go ahead and repeat it thousands of times.
So to do this we're going to do the following first.
We're going to get rid of all these print statements since we weren't really technically need them because
we don't want thousands of print statements.
So let's go ahead and get rid of those.
But the actual code we're going to go ahead and keep.
So let's do the following have this and then have the weights attached.
We'll call this just weights.
So we're going to do here is all of this inside a for loop.
But what we also need to do is we want to save a lot of these results so we can plot them out later.
So let's create a couple of variables.
We're going say the number of possible positions we're going to do or number of actual portfolios is
going to be let's say 5000 and you can increase this depending on how fast your computer is or you can
decrease it also if you have a slower computer.
We're going to create an array to hold all the weights so we can save them and it's going to be the
number of ports by the length of the actual stocks column so I could just put four there.
But that way if I say length stocks columns then this is a little more expandable to different portfolios
that have more than just the four stocks.
We're concerned with then I'm going to create an array to hold the returns we'll say zeros and passing
the number of portfolios we want to apply and to create an array that holds the number of volatility
measurements we take.
Again pasand number of ports.
And then finally an array of the sharp ratios of cockily now again will be zero.
Let's make sure this one says zeros.
And then finally again a number of ports great.
And we're going to do is say for index in that range.
Number of ports will do the following.
We'll create the random weights and then rebalance them.
So that's a first step and we can do shift tab here or excuse me just tab to tab everything over.
So we want to rebalance the weights after we make them.
And then let's go ahead and save the weights.
So we're going to save the weights and we're going to take all the weights that variable we just made.
And at the particular index we're on for all those values we'll set it equal to weights basically just
using non-pay broadcasting here.
So that saves the weights then we get the expected return.
And instead of saving it as a variable here we're going to do is get our return or a and set that particular
index equal to the results of this and we're going to the same thing here for the volatility instead
of saving it to just a single variable.
We'll say the volatility array at that index is equal to this results.
And then finally for the Sharpe ratio will do the same thing take the sharper way we just made.
And at that particular index we'll sit this equal to these results.
But notice here I'm using the same variables from before.
So we actually want to replace those.
We're going to say the value return array at this index divided by the volatility or a value at this
index so we're going to run this and make sure we don't make bucks here so for and looks like I misspelled
the range let's fix that real quick.
OK.
So we are going to run this now the pending how fast your computer is.
This may take some time.
In the notebook provided for you.
I ran it twenty five thousand times five times longer than what I just had here.
But 5000 should be enough for us to actually see the bullet shape.
So let's kind of explore it just a little bit.
And delete this and let's check out the sharp array and we're going to do is ask for the max.
So looks like the maximum Sharpe ratio we got was one point zero three years maybe a little different
remember depending if you have this random seed number inside the same cell you may get different results
here.
But if you actually set the random seed in the same cell and have all these same coat here you should
have actually gotten the exact same result I did.
Or something extremely similar.
So if one of another location of this sharper.
We can just say Max and returns back the location of the best SERP ratio so I can take the index location
and do the following.
I can say okay for all the weights go ahead and pass it in the index location 14:20 and then grabbing
the allocations.
And here we can see the optimal allocation out of these 5000 random allocations.
So moving along here.
Let's go ahead and plot out the data.
So we're going to say peel t figure and the Sorge is going to set the fix.
Real quick.
Say create a 12 by 8 and then I'm going to call that plot lives scatter functionality and we're going
to pass in the volatility array the return array for the returns and then I'm going to color this by
the sharp re-issue array and I personally like for this plot the plasma color mapping that you can in
whatever color mapping you want or just use that default.
Don't even bother if a color mapping here kind of up to you and then to actually see something on the
color bar you can give a label Sharpe ratio and let's give some labels to the x and y axis so say peel
T X label that's going to be our volatility.
And then the peel t y label that's going to be your actual return.
And before we run this cell let's make sure we spell color bar correctly.
Let's run this make sure it works.
And here we have that bullet shape so we can do is see the volatility and the return colored by the
Sharpe ratio and depending on how many points you did this may be less or more filled out here.
But we're counting or we're going to do now is go ahead and put a red dot for the max Sharpe ratio we're
going to be somewhere around here based off the color bar scheme.
Let's go ahead and do that.
We're just going to basically do another scatterplot except this time with just one point.
We're going to say grab that.
Max Sharpe ratio.
So let's go ahead and show you how he can grab that.
So remember we have this all Waite's 14:20 going to do the following.
We'll say Max as our return is equal to return array at that particular index 14:20 and then the max
Sharpe ratio volatility is equal to volatility array at that index 14:20.
So we run that and then we're going to scatterplot those two points.
So say Max as our volatility and then Max as our return we'll give the color to be red and then let's
go ahead to make the size much larger.
So it's like really obvious.
And then let's also even give it an edge color.
So that's also obvious we'll say it's colors or just black.
OK so give us a nice little red circle here.
And as far as our 5000 random allocations it looks like the best only got was overy around here.
Well if I can point to one volatility and around a point two in the return.
OK.
So that's the way we can do this randomly in the next lecture we're going to do is actually optimize
this mathematically and show you how you can calculate the efficient frontier which is essentially going
to be this borderline which points out the max return per volatility.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.