All right.
So we're back where we left off last time we recreated this plot.
Now let's move on from random allocations to actually performing a mathematical optimization.
Luckily all the heavy lifting will be done with Type-I for us so we just have to do a couple of things
to set up the optimization function.
We're going to start off by creating a simple function that can take in some weights and then return
back an array consisting of the returns the volatility and the Sharpe ratio.
So I'll say this function is called gets r t the o l s r waits so we pasand some weights and let's make
sure that the weights are in umpiring.
So we'll just pass them in as an array just in case we forget and we pass them in as a list.
We'll have that little safeguard for us and then we're going to do the same things we did last time
we'll take the some of the log return mean multiplied by the weights and then we're going to multiply
that by 252.
And technically it doesn't really matter if this 2:52 goes inside the some or outside the sum.
Since you're multiplying it throughout it's basically going to be the same result either way next for
volatility.
We're going to say take the square roots of the dot product just like we did last time where we transpose
the weights and then we're going to take the internal dot product here of the covariance of the returns
multiplied by 252 with the weights here.
All right there we go.
So that should balance out.
And then finally the Sharpe ratio is just equal to these returns divided by the volatility that we're
going to return in the array and it's going to be an array consisting of the returns the volatility
and the Sharpe ratio.
OK.
So there we have it.
Then what we're going to do is say from site PI optimize import minimize who have already talked a little
bit about minimization of functions.
If you want to get the full details on this particular function you can say help minimize and I'll give
you this really nice large helpful documentation for the minimization function here from site pipe where
it's going to show you the basics doing a deeper dive into this particular optimization algorithm is
a little beyond the scope of this course but we're going to show you how you can easily use say abilities
in order to use some of these functions.
We first have to create some helper functions.
So the first one is going to be called negative sharp.
It's going to take in some weights and then it's just going to return the result of return volatility
Sharpe ratio.
We pasand those weights and then remember that the sharp ratio.
That's the second indexed item or index to excuse me because we have 0 1 and 2 if we look back at the
array we're returning here it's 0 1 and index 2 has a sharper ratio.
So we'll come over here and I just want to return the Sharpe ratio but remember as we discussed we want
to minimize the negative sharp ratio.
So we're going to multiply this by negative 1.
So what is actually doing well this function is going to take in some way allocation and then it's going
return back the negative Sharpe ratio.
This is the thing that we're actually trying to minimize.
So we've kind of functional ised that aspect of it.
Up next we have constraints so we can help our off my zation minimization function with constraints
because if we have constraints that means there's less things to check.
So one of the constraints that we have to do is going to be called checksummed.
Remember that our allocations all need to add up to one as long as we're not shorting anything.
So then are we're going to see His return and piece some of the weights minus one.
So what does this actually do.
Well it's going to return 0 if the sum of the weights is one.
If not it's just going to return how off you are from 1 itself.
So that's kind of the format it needs to be in for constraints.
And we're going to pass in just some constraints and some bounce as dictionaries and tuples and then
we'll put that all into the minimize function.
So actually using the minimise function it's a little complicated at first but once we see it again
when we actually perform the efficient frontier you'll kind of get a handle on it.
Don't worry about it too much because we don't really use it throughout the course.
It's just kind of the way we're actually going to optimize our portfolio in this case.
So since we just have one single constraint I'm going to create a variable called constraints and essentially
what is it's a tuple with a dictionary inside of it in the dictionary takes in a first argument and
says Type E Q And basically what this says is hey this constraint is going to be an equation type constraint
because basically I have an equation here and then the second item in this dictionary goes under a function
and then we just pass in the function itself which is checked some so by convention this minimized function
should be a function that returns zero for the correct conditions.
And then we also have bounds so these bounds is going to be a tuple of tuples and we'll explain what
that actually stands for in a second.
So essentially we're just going to have this same tuple repeated four times.
So there we go.
So what are these actual bounds.
Well since we know that the sum has to equal to 1.
We also know that the bounds of the actual weights themselves have to be between 0 and 1.
So we have this bounds variable that we're going to be able to pass in as well.
And then finally we need to start off with some sort of initial guess.
So usually the best initial guess you can do is just and even allocation for say 0.35 and whip's this
needs to be a list 0.5 0.2 5 0.5 and then 0.5 OK.
So those are initial guesses.
Now we're going to put this all into the minimization function so will say optimal results is equal
to you can minimize here.
And so first thing we do we check minimize is what does the actual function we're trying to minimize
or remember we're trying to minimize this function.
Negative sharp.
So this first and mean passen negative chirp and then we see here it takes x 0 or X not.
That basically stands for the very first x values to put in or your initial guess.
So that's we're going to put in all say in its guess.
Then the next argument it takes in is method.
Now a discussion of different methods is a little beyond the scope of this course.
But if you scroll down here there's different types of solvers.
So these are all different algorithms you can use to minimize the function.
We're going to go ahead and use this right here.
Ls l l s l s q p.
Check of the documentation a little more.
It has links for each of these minimization functions and it tends to recommend this one for most basic
tasks so we'll go ahead and passen method here to be equal to this particular minimization method.
And if you're wondering what s l s p stands for.
It just stands for sequential at least squares algorithm here.
So we'll continue on and the next thing we're going to add in are the bounds.
So the bounds we want is just equal to bounds and then our constraints dictionary is just going to be
equal to conc.
So we run that.
And if we take a look at our Opta results we have various things that come with it.
Function Giacobbe in this message terminated successfully that means it was able to find some sort of
minimal value there.
And if you actually want the values that minimized the particular function we're looking for you say
Opt. results and then the values are held in this array.
This last one I see say Opta results.
X.
So if you hit tab here you can see everything you can grab off of it.
We just want the X actual values and there is are actual allocation so we can do is say get read vol
s r.
So get return volatility S.R. and passen Opta results.
X and this returns back the daily returns volatility and the Sharpe ratio.
So it looks like the picture operation we can possibly get is 1 point 0 3 and out of the guesses we
did last time it was around there so if we Krenov scroll back up here we saw we had like a 1 point zero
of three values.
So even with just like 5000 random guesses that we did or never have that number happened to be we got
pretty close.
We didn't get the exact weights but pretty darn close.
Now something to keep in mind because we only had 4 securities or four stocks.
Actual guessing and checking with the Monte-Carlo simulation.
That didn't take too long but if you have a portfolio consisting of hundreds of securities definitely
go through this optimization instead of the random allocation.
OK so we have our optimal results.
Now we're going to do is check all optimal portfolios and this is called the efficient frontier.
So what the fishing frontier is it's just a set of optimal portfolios that offers the highest expected
return for the defined that level of risk or the lowest risk possible for a given level of expected
return depending on which way you want to think about it.
Basically what's the best value for each x value.
So let's go ahead and create that.
So only to do here say front tier of y and this is going to be equal to and P and we're going to call
Lynde's space.
So we're going to go from zero to 0.3 because if you look at our previous plot it looks like our results
go from around 0 to let's say 0.3 here.
So it looks like it doesn't reach higher than point 3.
So that's how we're getting those values.
So those will be the frontier values and then we're going to do is kind of optimize each x value for
each of those y values.
So we should get basically that efficient frontier curve and eventually we'll kind of just peak and
go up at the very end and they'll also go straight down at the very end here.
So we just kind of want to get this bullet shape.
So scroll back down do that.
So these are going to be our actual VI y values and then we're going to do here just say let's go ahead
and get 100 points.
You probably don't need this money but it should be good enough.
We're going to say minimize now the volatility because we're actually going along the x axis so say
minimize the volatility takes and some whites and it's going to return the get return of all.
As are we pasand those weights and then we grab the very next one which is that volatility.
OK.
So we actually want to minimize volatility.
No need to multiply this by negative one because remember volatility if we just want to minimize that.
That's the actual value.
We don't need to inverse it like we did a sharp ratio and wanting them to do here is save front tier
volatility.
Is an empty list and then I'm going to do the part the following.
I'll say for every possible return in front here of why.
So what does that actually mean.
Well remember frontier why that's essentially the y axis which from the plot is the returns.
So I'm saying for every possible return on this Y-axis What is the best volatility value I can get.
So we'll come over here.
So every possible return in front tier of why I'm going to have my constraints and they're going to
be the following.
So the first one is going to be we first say type q free equation and then the function I'm passing
in is checksum because that's still the same and then the other thing in the passen is another equation
here will say type
equation.
And then for this function I'm going to do the following.
I'm going to say lambda W going to say gets return of all s r of W.
So for those weights zero minus the possible return.
OK so what does this actually doing.
Well I'm going to be saying OK for a possible turn blah blah.
Have these constraints checked some we know all the sums have to equal to 1 point zero.
The second one says for some land that W.
So for some weights essentially just the way check sums took weights we're doing the same thing here.
So for some weights we're going to do is we are going to get the zero or the very first item which is
the returns.
So I'm going to get those returns and then subtract the possible return because I know in my frontier
what I am essentially doing is saying well that's the max possible return.
So that's what this equation is trying to do as far as the constraints are concerned.
And then the result itself is going to be minimize and are going to pass in the function.
I want to minimize that to minimize volatility.
All have the same initial guess as last time.
We'll do the same method will say assess Cupie and then has the same bounds.
And then for the constraints I'm just going to pass in what we have here and then finally once I have
the result I'm going to append it to my frontier volatility list.
So I'll say append results in what I'm actually going to do is append fun.
So if you take a look back here we got the sexual function value.
So that's why we're going to spend here.
So let's run that.
This may take a little bit of time depending on how many points you added here.
So if this is taking too long for you just check less points make this like 10 or something.
But eventually it should be finished running.
So what we can do here is say Piazzi figure say Fig's size is let's say told by eight's and that ongoing
appeal to scatter in effect where we're actually going to copy and paste this from up here.
So it's copy and paste this bring it all the way down so let's make sure that works for us.
So here's our initial guesses from the Monte-Carlo simulation.
But on top of that I'm going to plot out my front tier vault or Frontier volatility on the x axis and
then my front tier y values and we can just add in a code here.
Let's have a dasht green line and let's make that line with let's say three just so it's a little thicker
so we can see it OK.
So it's actually going on here.
Well we went ahead and we plotted out a line and this line represents for each desired level of volatility.
What is the best possible return you can get.
Now you know it is because the bullet shape eventually comes back around.
But if you take the max of this function value you should get the max return possible.
So let's say you're an investor and the max volatility you want is point 2 to someone's given you money
and they say hey I'm not willing to see anything more volatile than that.
So you say no problem.
Check this volatility.
You go up to the max possible optimization you check the screen line get the function of value and say
I can expect this return the sharp ratio based off my historical data.
Remember that's not a perfect indicator of future data.
Everything may change in the future but based on historical data I can expect the sort of return.
And then you can decide what the allocations you want are for that case.
Now keep in mind we're actually saving the allocations instead.
We're saving the results of the function itself.
Okay.
So that's it.
This is known as Marco portfolio optimization.
That's the actual technique.
And again the main idea here is what's the best possible return for your indicated level of volatility.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Q&amp;A forums as far as the overall expectation
here for your understanding.
I would not expect you to be a pro in using any of these methods or functions as far as minimization.
We won't really see them again in the course.
This is just the mathematical way we can use size power to actually get this optimization line.
I wouldn't worry too much about understanding the full details under the hood because we won't really
need to use them throughout the course.
However if you are interested in those aspects I definitely recommend you check out the CPI documentation.
It's really clear and has really full explanations for each of the parameters we covered.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.