and this video,
we're going to speak about our field lists and our four different areas at the bottom.
So if we go back to your data,
you will see that the names off our column headers for a data match those off the pivot
table fields that we have here on our field list.
Now at the bottom,
we have our different fuel list areas.
We have four different field ist area,
so you get the filters,
columns rose and values,
and in thes field list areas,
we can actually drag and drop any of our field.
So let's say I want to put my product name on the row section.
I can actually click on it and drag it and drop it in the row section.
Alternatively,
there is a check box beside it,
and if I click on that check box so I can un check and then check again and you could see
her,
it's been inserted on the rose area.
However,
it's not always guaranteed that it would go to the right area that you want when you click
on the check box,
so it's better to drag it and drop it to the area that you want and usually the fields that
you would put in the rose section would be feels that you want to group by so you can group
buy the product.
It could be also the reason it could be a certain business unit,
a certain manager sales person.
So these air the fields that you'd usually put in the roast section.
Now,
on the columns area,
you usually put deals where you would want to show the trend of the data.
So usually you put the weeks,
the months,
the quarters or the years usually feels where you would want to show a trend.
So here on the column section,
I'm gonna put the years I'm going to drag and drop the year here on the column section.
Now,
on the values area here,
you would usually put feels that you would want to aggregate,
so you'd usually want to put the sum of sales the average price,
the maximum price.
So these air quantitative feels that you would want to aggregate So here,
I'm gonna put actually this sales amount.
I'm going to drag and drop the sales amount,
and you can see here it defaults to showing the some.
If you need to do a different type of aggregation,
you can click on this arrow here and go to value field settings and then choose a different
type of aggregation.
You can choose the Count average Max Hman product,
all these different types of aggregations.
But here,
I'm just going to stick with the some I'm gonna click.
OK,
Okay.
So let's take a step back here and analyze what we've got on our pivot table.
So in this cell here that I've got highlighted,
we've got the sales for product one in 2016 which is 1,095,430.
Now,
if you go back to our data and we filter our data for product one and for the year 2016 you
can see here these air older sales that happened for product one for 2016.
Now,
if we highlight the column here for the sales amount,
all the values for a calm for the sales amount and we check the summation here it's
1,095,430.
So basically,
the pivot table is summarizing our data here nicely,
and the same goes for product to in 2016.
So this cell re presents the sales for product to in 2016 and so on and so forth.
So,
as you can see here,
the pivot table is a nice way to summarize your data.
Now let's speak about our final area,
which is the filter.
So the filter's area is an optional area where you can put a field and usually you would
want to put fuels that you would want to filter with.
So,
for example,
the sales person or the region.
So here I'm gonna put the region,
for example,
I'm gonna put the sales person,
and this way you're able to filter the data on your pivot table with certain cart iria.
So,
for example,
I can filter only for the sales that happened in the Americas.
And you can see here the values have changed to show only the sales that happened for the
Americas and for the sales person,
I can also filter by a certain sales person.
As you can see here,
it shows me on Lee the sales amount for that particular sales person and also for the
Americans.
Because we've got an America's filter applied already as well.
Using a pivot table,
you're also able to swap your feels.
So,
actually,
I'm gonna swap here the product,
name the location for the product name,
put it in the columns and then take the year and put it in the roads.
So it's actually a nice way to get your data in different forms here,
and you can also hear Remove the filter as you can see here,
by selecting all to this way you've removed you filter.
So,
as you can see are the pivot table is a nice way to put your data in any shape that you
want.