in this video,
we're going to see how we can filter or select items from a slicer,
so to select items from a slicer.
So to select a single item from a slicer,
you can just click on that particular item and to select multiple items,
you can click on the first item and then press and hold the control button on your keyboard
and then start selecting the other individual items.
If you need to select contiguous items,
you can click on the first item and then press and hold the shift key and then press on the
lost item in the list that you need to select.
And there you go.
You can see here that all the items between your first item and your last item have been
selected.
You could also select multiple items by pressing on one item and then holding the left
mouse button and then dragging down to the last item like this,
you could drag from top to bottom.
You could also drag from bottom to top as well.
You could also de select some items in the middle by pressing and holding the control key
and then starting to de select your items.
And if you need to de select all the items or unfiltered the slicer,
you can just click on this button to clear all the filters here.
Okay,
so that's say,
guys on how to select items in the slicer.
Thank you so much for watching this video and a C on the next one.