Now we're going to speak about timelines,
So timelines are basically slicers that can only filter fields that have dates in them.
So on this pivot table here,
we've got the salesperson on the roads section and we've got the year on the columns
section and we've got the submission of sales amount on the submission of Value Section.
And let's try to insert a timeline here So a timeline will help us filter this pivot table
by days or months or quarters or years.
That's the flexibility and the beauty of a timeline.
So I'm gonna go to the insert tab here on the ribbon after selecting his cell in my pivot
table.
And then I'm going to click here on timeline and notice here that it only offers me when
field to use on my timeline,
which is the order date field because the ordered a field or the ordered A column Is the
Onley field a my data that has Onley dates in it.
This is why this is the only field offer to me to create a timeline over.
So I'm gonna click,
OK,
here and here is my time light as it gets here.
So this timeline allows me to filter my data by years for examples I six council ECT year
2019 and it would only show the 2019 data.
I can extend that to 2018 as well to show me 2018 and 2019 and then I can go to quarters
and econ filter my data by quarters.
So this is the first quarter of 2019.
I can also do the fourth quarter 2018 in the first quarter of 2019 for example,
and I can select fourth quarter of 2019.
I can extend that as much as I like is against year.
So this offers a lot of flexibility for me to filter my data,
and it's,
ah,
pretty user friendly as well.
And then I can go to the my months here,
and it's because here it gives me the ability to filter by months.
As you can see here,
here,
here are the months and there.
There's also the year here,
so this is December 2018 but I can go into January 19 as well.
I can go back all the way to July 18.
So that's July 18th January 19 as you can see here,
or I can do it by the individual days,
Okay,
and you can also create styles and edit the styles,
and you can also choose a different style here.
For your timeline,
you can create a new style just the same way that we explained how to do it for slicers.
So it's basically a slicer,
but only four fields that have dates in them.
You can also change the connections.
So which,
ah,
pivot table that that timeline connects to.
If you click here on report connections or if you right click here and go to a port
connections as well,
you can change which pivot table is connected to that particular timeline.
So it gets treated basically just like a slicer,
except for the fact that it could only be built upon fields that have dates on Lee in them
.
Okay,
so that's the timeline