in this video,
we're going to see how we can protect our worksheets without protecting our slices so we
can actually protect our worksheets in order to make other users not able to edit them or
make changes to them unless they have the password.
But we can actually exclude our slices from being protected so that the users can actually
select items from the slicer and view results on the pivot tables,
but without being able to edit other items on the worksheet.
So,
first of all we need to exclude are slicers from being blocked as a result of protecting
our worksheet.
So to do that,
we can actually select one slicer and the press control and a to select all the other
slicers on the sheet.
Or you can select one slicer and then president hold the control button to select other
slices as well,
and then you can right click and then click on size and properties.
And then when you click on size and properties here under the properties option or top here
,
you're going to see this locked check box.
You need to make sure to uncheck this lock check box.
Now we've excluded are slicers from being blocked.
Now we can go ahead,
unlock our worksheets,
so to lock or protect our worksheets,
we go to the review top here on the ribbon and then click on Protect,
Cheat.
And we have some options here.
So there is the select locked cells.
This option will enable us to select cells here on the worksheet after it's been locked.
So if you need the users to be able to select cells,
you can keep this checked.
But if you uncheck it,
users will not be able to even select cells.
But they won't be ableto edit the cells anyways to be able to select them in case that this
is checked,
but they won't be able to edit them.
And here you're gonna have select unlocked cells.
You got to keep this check because this is going to enable you to select your slicers and
then at the bottom.
Here there is the use pivot tables and pivot charts.
You need to make sure that this is checked as well,
so that you be able to use the pivot tables and pivot charts on your locked or protected
cheat.
And then,
if you need to have a passer toward the sheet.
You can write it here.
If you leave this empty,
the sheet will be locked without a password if you click.
OK,
here.
Now your sheet is locked and as you can see,
her were not able to select cells because they are locked here.
And then you can select items from your slicer without any problems,
as you can see here.
And this is how you can look a worksheet without locking your slicers.
You can also go ahead or toe unlock or unprotected sheet here by clicking here on on
protect sheet.
If there had been a password for the sheep than Excel would have justice for the password
as well after pressing the UN protect sheet button.
Okay,
so this is how you can protect our luck,
your worksheets without locking your slicers.