Now we're going to discuss calculated feels in pivot tables.
So calculated fields are virtual columns that you can create in pivot tables where usually
perform calculations so they are essentially virtual calculated columns.
These columns do not exist initially on your data,
but you actually create them from feels or columns.
In your data.
You can even create calculated columns that depend on other calculated columns.
So to create a calculated column,
you need to select your pivot table,
first of all,
and then on the ribbon,
you will have the pivot table,
analyze top or on other Excel versions.
It might be cold.
Just analyze,
and then you go here to fields,
items and sets.
Under Calculations group,
you go to fields,
items and sets,
and then you click on calculated,
healed.
And first of all,
you have to enter the name of the field like you need to give it a name,
so I'll give it a name of colleagues.
It's basically going to be the cost of goods sold,
and we do have here the fields the are available in our data or the columns are available
in our data set and the cost of goods sold should be the cost divided by this sales amount
.
And in calculated fields,
you can use the standard mathematical operations in Excel.
So the plus sign the miners,
the division,
the multiplication sign you can even use greater than unless than comparison operators.
However,
I've never had a case where I needed to use them.
But you might have a case to do so.
So you can basically use the standard mathematical operators that use in Excel.
So this is gonna be are calculated field and with the guts to naming the calculated field.
There are different practices that people do.
So some people put an asterisk before the name so that this would denote the it is a
calculated field.
I personally like to name it as Calcutta before the name of it.
I mean,
different people do different things and you can choose whatever you would like to do and
then press OK,
here and now we do have are calculated field here,
which is the cost of goods sold,
and this should be a percentage.
So we're just gonna change the number formats or right click number format,
and we're gonna choose percentage here and click OK,
as you can see here now we have the percentage,
which is the cost of goods sold here.
And as you can see here,
it says some off talc cost of goods sold.
You could even change its name here,
the title on it so that it wouldn't say some off.
So click on the field itself,
go to value field settings and then you just name it whatever you want,
so I can name it.
For example,
Astra's cost of goods sold and click OK here so that it would show as this name as you can
see her.
And it has the Astros before it just to denote that it is a calculated field.
Okay,
so this is basically how you can create a calculated field.
Calculated fields are basically calculated columns.
The are based on either the columns currently existing on the table,
or they can also be based on other calculated fields