Okay,
Now we're going to create a calculated field from another calculated field.
So we've got a pivot table here,
and we've already got a calculated feed,
which is the cost of goods sold its named here on the pivot table fields.
Cal cost good sold,
and we've given it a title here of Astra's cost of a good soldier that he wouldn't have the
some off prefix.
And now we want to create another calculated field,
the school sales margin to calculate the sales margin,
which is basically one minus the cost of goods sold.
So to do that,
we're going to select our pivot table here and then go to pivot table,
analyze top here and then go to feels,
items and sets,
click on calculated field,
and then I'm gonna call it talc sales margin,
for example,
And then the formula is gonna be one minus the Cal cost of goods sold year and click OK,
and as you can see your it's created the calculated field.
However,
we need to change the number format,
so I'm going to select the whole column here,
and then I'm gonna click control and one to get the number formats here and then go to
percentage.
And here we're going to set a percentage and with no decimal places,
click.
Okay,
Here and now we have changed the number formatting for it to be a percentage.
So this is basically how you can create a calculated field from another calculated field on
.
Of course,
you can change its name here,
click on the field itself value field settings.
So it's a change its title here.
So we can put Asterix sales margin for example,
and click OK here so that we wouldn't have this some off prefix here and we would have
something denoting that.
This is a calculated field,
which is the asterisk before the name of the calculated field.
So this is basically how you can create a calculated field from another calculated field.
So thanks for watching this video you see on the next one