Now we're going to speak about creating formulas in calculated fields,
so we're able to use any Excel function in calculated fields as Unger's.
We're not referring to a cell,
so we're not referring to sell a two or B one or any cell in Excel is our as long as we're
not referring to a cell,
were able to use Excel formulas and functions in calculated fields.
So let's create a calculated field based on an excel function the F function,
for example.
So I'm going to select my pivot table here,
go to pivot table in I stab fields and fields,
items and sets and then click on calculated field.
And then I'm gonna create a calculated field,
which is ah,
discount.
Basically,
we're going to give a discount if the sales amount is greater than a certain threshold.
Which anarchists gonna be 250,000 for example?
So if the sales amount is greater than 250,000 then we're gonna go give a 5% disco else.
We're just gonna give a zero disco.
So now,
as you can see here,
this formula does not reference any South,
so it should work now Let's press,
OK?
And as you can see,
her are calculated.
Field has been created here and I'm just going to change here the format of that field.
So I'm just going to select the whole field,
press control and one on my keyboard percentage and press OK here.
And as you can see here we have a 5% discount whenever our sales amount exceeds 250 $1000.
Also,
as you can see here,
this formula is even being applied to the sub totals.
So the sub culture of the whole January,
for example,
and this is probably not what we want to do because we're applying this formula to the
sales for each reason here.
So we're going to give a discount if a reason,
for example,
buys products from us greater than 250,000.
But we don't want to give a discount on the sub total of January.
That is not what we want to do.
So were probably,
in this case,
need to turn off the sub totals in order for pivot table to reflect meaningful numbers.
So to turn off our sub totals,
we need to select our pivot table good of the design tab on the ribbon and then go to
subtitles here and then Do not show sub totals.
And,
as you can see here now are Pivot Table is giving us a more meaningful result.
So that's eight guys on how to use formulas and functions and pivot table calculated fields
.
Basically,
in order to use an Excel function in a calculated field,
you need to make sure that you're not referring to individual cells.
So thank just watching this video and Nazi on the next one.