Okay,
so let's so another type of chart here,
which is the bar chart.
So I've got my data here on May Pivot Table.
I've got the sales people on the roast section.
I've got the sales amount on the submission of value section,
and I've got the product name on the column section,
and we're going to create a bit of a more sophisticated chart in this video.
So I'm actually going to select here a cell inside my pivot table.
I'm gonna go to the insert tab on the ribbon,
and then I'm going to go here to this area here,
which is the column and bar charts,
and then I'm gonna select a clustered bar chart.
So here I created a clustered bar chart,
as you can see here.
And as you can see here,
there are many sales people here on my team.
So maybe I just want to focus on the top five salespeople in terms of sales amount,
so I can actually filter here using this button,
I can click on it,
and then I can go to value filters,
and then I'm going I can go to top 10 and then I'm actually going to change the top 10 toe
.
Only top five people by sales amount.
Here,
top five items by sales amount.
I'm gonna click OK here.
So,
as you can see here,
my pivot chart has been filtered to include only the top five people.
And the tough I people have been selected based on this grand total column.
So it's just the top five people by grand total.
And now on this chart,
I can see here the top performing sales people and I can see the breakdown of their sales
as well.
Byproduct.
So I can see who has been able to sell which product the most as well.
I can give my charts and data labels year so I can right click and then add data labels and
add my data labels year.
I can do that for every item here for every product.
So I can click on that product here and add the data labels to it,
and what I can do as well to make it easier to read.
The labels here is to give some number formatting here to my numbers here so I can just
give it a currency formatting here and that would make it much easier for me to read my
numbers.
And Onizuka sear the number formatting on my ex accesses well changed to be the same as the
number formatting All my numbers as well.
I can clean my chart up a bit more here if I can just right click on any of these field
buttons,
and then I'm gonna hide all the fuel buttons on the chart.
It makes it much easier to read the chart.
I will also remove my vertical grid lines here are click on them and press delete on the
keyboard,
and that would make my chart much easier to read as well.
And,
of course,
this pivot chart would interact with my pivot table.
So if I decide to remove the product name here and add the region instead on the column
section,
you can see here that the pivot chart reacts to whatever changes I make on the pivot table
.
So,
as you can see here,
this is a bit of a more complex chart here that we managed to create by having elements in
both at the Rose section and the columns section,
as well off the pivot table