Okay,
So let me tell you that pivot charts have some limitations,
actually,
and one of the limitations is that you can't create every kind of chart that you're
normally able to create using a pivot chart.
So pivot charts are limited in that sense.
So,
for example,
here,
all my pivot table,
I'm going to go to the insert tab on the ribbon.
And then there is a new kind of chart that's been added to Excel,
which is a treatment chart,
but you can't create a pivot chart out of that chart.
You also cannot create a scatter chart out of a pivot chart.
You also cannot create a map chart out of a pivot chart.
And if I also go to the recommended charts here,
there are some other chart types that you can't create.
So the hissed a gram you can see here there's no option to press okay,
and the box and whisker as well.
There is no option and the waterfall chart.
There's no option to do that and the funnel chart as well.
So all these shorts you cannot create using a pivot chart,
and I believe the stock chart as well.
You can't create a stock chart using a pivot chart,
and you can't create a sunburst chart as well.
So just be aware of that.
Pivot charts have some limitations.
You cannot create all kinds of charts using pivot charts.