Let's speak about moving pivot charts.
So if you want to move your pivot charts to maybe another sheet,
you have two options.
You can either press on the pivot chart itself,
and then you can press control and X on your keyboard to move on.
Then you can paste it in another sheet,
like I'm pasting it here in the data sheet.
So that's one option.
That's one thing that you can do.
I'm gonna move it back again to the pivot sheet here.
Another option is that you can click on your pivot chart and then you can right click here
on.
Then you can go to move chart.
Or you could go to the design tab on the ribbon and click on Move Chart here.
And because here you've got the option to move it to an existing worksheet,
which is the same thing as pressing control and acts on your keyboard to cut it and paste
it in the other sheet.
Or you have the option to move it to a new sheet,
which is actually gonna be H.
Archie.
And be careful because this option here is irreversible so you can't press control and Z on
your keyboard to reverse that process.
Once it's done,
once it's moved to with a charge sheet,
you cannot undo that.
So if it press okay here,
it's moved it to its own chart sheet here.
It's still linked to the pivot table,
though,
so if I,
for example,
remove the filters year,
we have a filter here for filtering the salespeople for for the top five salespeople you
consider if I remove the filter because here we have more sales people here,
so it's actually interactive.
It's still linked to your pivot table.
I personally do not recommend using the charge sheet.
I don't use them personally,
but it's up to you.
This option exists if you need to use it.
So in this case,
if you need to go back,
you cannot simply press a control and Z on your keyboard.
You just have to delete this chart sheet here,
and then you can re insert a chart again.
Here we insert the bar chart again.
So I just wanted to give you a heads up about the option and be careful with it because you
will not be able to undo that.
If you move your chart to a chart sheet,
you will have to delete the charge sheet and then start again and build your chart again.