Alright,
guys.
So now we're gonna have some practical examples and case studies for using pivot tables.
So I'm going to get some data from some statistics website like Stats Canada,
for example on we're going to start exploiting this data with pivot tables and try to
understand the data and draw conclusions from it because this is the ultimate goal at the
end of the day,
from using pivot tables.
Anyways,
the ultimate goal is to actually be able to understand your data and analyzing.
So this state of here of gas and data that I got from Stats Canada and it's about the
population by mother tongue in Canada.
So this data shows how many people speak English as their mother tongue or French or any
other non official language in Canada's.
So So it shows whether people speak English or French,
which are the two official languages in Canada.
Or it shows if someone is speaking any other language other than English and French as his
for first language.
So this shows the first language of the people,
their mother tongue.
And,
you know,
Canada has a lot of immigrants,
has a great immigrant population,
so their mother tongue.
There's ah,
there's a lot of people in Canada that don't have their mother tongue is the English or the
French language.
It could be any other language.
So we're gonna use pivot tables on this data and try to understand it and maybe draw some
pivot charts and draw some conclusions out off the data.
So I get this data from Stats Canada and I cleaned it using power query.
I'm not going to go into that at the moment.
I'm not gonna go into Parkway because that needs a separate course by itself.
But this is our data here,
and it is in a tabular form.
I created a table out of it and let's create a pivot table.
Order that data and try to understand the data you can see here.
We've got the year a year column,
and the province on the province basically includes the provinces and the territories in
Canada.
And there is the mother tongue,
Whether which what is the mother tongue of these people here living in that particular
province and in that particular year and the number of people having that particular mother
tongue in the particular province and year.
So I'm gonna insert a pivot table here,
insert a pivot table on.
I'm gonna put it in the new worksheet.
So here is our pivot table,
and now I'm gonna put the province year on the road section and I'm gonna put in the mother
tongue here on the column section,
and I'm gonna put the number of people here on the submission of value section,
and it's important as well to be able to slice that by the year.
I think that will give us a lot of information.
So if I right click here and add as slicer on the year,
I'll be able to create a year slicer.
And now you can see here we've got some numbers.
Well,
I can give these numbers a bit of formatting as well learned on our pivot table so I can go
to the pivot table,
analyze stab.
I'll go the select entire pivot table,
and then Argo the select again and then select the values on the pivot table.
So I selected only the values and now I can do some formatting.
So maybe I'll put a comma here on the numbers that you will be able to understand the
numbers better.
So,
for example,
this is 4,828,000 115 people.
This is 576,000 and 608 people on so on and so forth.
So this way a be able to read the numbers easier.
And now I could also because I've got these numbers here,
but it's actually better to express the numbers in terms of percentages.
And you'll see here how we would be able to do different ways of expressing numbers
percentages to,
and we will actually get different conclusions off the data when doing that.
So numbers by themselves are OK,
but you be even able to understand them better if you convert these numbers to percentage
is this is one of the easiest ways to understand your numbers.
So I'm actually gonna go here to my values.
I'm gonna click on it,
and then I'm gonna go to value field settings,
and then I'm gonna go to show values as and here instead of the no calculation,
let's do a percentage of grand total and see what we get out of that.
So a press Okay,
Here and as you can see her to be able understand these numbers.
So basically these numbers say that 7.53% off the people who live in Canada and that's over
all over all the years.
So maybe I'll select a year here to be more specific about a certain years that here says
8.73% off the population off Canada.
They speak English,
and they live in Alberta.
So this is what the number meats.
And it says,
for example,
that 26.11% off the population in Canada speak English and live on in Ontario.
Okay,
so this is what these numbers mean,
But I can actually copy this pivot table.
I'm gonna paste it here,
and I can change the calculation method so I can go to a new pivot table here,
go to submission of values,
value,
fields,
settings.
Ah,
goaless show values as.
And then I'll change that to percentage of column tall Toto,
Let's try the percentage of column tota and see what we get here.
So a press.
Okay.
Here.
So what does that mean?
So here you can see here that the column totals toe 100% this way.
So this is 100%.
This is 100%.
So all these numbers here are 100% right?
So what do these numbers mean here?
It means that 15.32% for example,
off the people who speak English,
they live in Alberta.
Okay,
so here it's not expressing the number of people as the percentage of the Canadian
population as a whole is actually expressing them here.
It's a percentage of column,
Toto.
So here the column says English,
Right?
So it's expressing people in as percentages of the column total,
which in this case,
this column is English.
So it's expressing them as a percentage of English speakers and hear This column is French
,
so it's expressing them in the the percentage of French speakers you can see here,
45.79% of the people who have their mother tongue as English in Canada.
They reside in Ontario.
And here,
of course,
in Quebec you'll see the 86% of the people who have French as their mother tongue.
They reside in Quebec.
Which makes sense,
of course,
because Quebec has the highest population of people who speak French as their native
language or as there mother tongue in Canada,
of course.
And you know,
it makes sense here in Ontario because Ontario has actually the greatest population in
Canada.
The greatest population in Canada resides in Ontario.
Okay,
and most of them speak English.
So this is what the numbers mean in this case,
after we've done a percentage off column total.
Now,
I can also copy this pivot table and let's do a percentage of roe total on see what we get
out of these numbers here.
So when you do the percentage of Roe total,
it will give you the percentage of people who have a particular language spoken as their
mother tongue in any province.
So it is here that 75% off the people who live in Alberta,
they speak English as their mother tongue.
And 22 percent of these people,
they have other languages as their mother tongue.
So you can see here with three different options.
We got three different views and we can look at our data from three different perspectives
,
right?
So this is actually how powerful pivot tables are.
We managed to look at our data from three different perspectives and draw insights from our
data.
Now,
as a best practice,
what we can do as well is name these pivot tables here.
So I'm going to go to the pivot table in ally staff for the first pivot table here.
So I'm gonna name it PVT Percentage population overall.
And here I'm just gonna name it the percentage of population.
Ah,
by language.
So PVT percentage pop by length,
which Okay,
and here I'm just gonna name it PVT percentage pulp by province.
Okay,
so now we have three different pivot tables with three different names.
And let's make sure our slicer is connected to all the pivot tables year.
So I'm gonna go to report connections and you can see her are slicer is actually connected
to all three to the tables.
And when we change the year on our slicer,
we get the different percentages for all three pivot tables