Okay,
so now let's create some charts out off our pivot tables.
So I'm just gonna create in you worksheet here.
I'm just gonna name it charts,
for example,
and I'm gonna remove the grid lines year.
So I'm gonna go to view and then untech the grid lines here to make it look a bit cleaner.
And then I'm gonna go to my pivot tables here.
I'm going to take my first pivot table.
I'm gonna goto insert,
and then I'm gonna actually create a column chart out of that.
So I'm gonna create a clustered column chart out of that here because here,
a short was created and then are actually going to remove these buttons year because I
don't like them.
They obstruct the view here on the chart and just gonna make it a bit cleaner.
I'm also gonna remove these grid lines year by selecting them impressing delete all my
keyboard,
and then I'm actually going to cut that chart and then I'm gonna paste it.
Any new worksheet here.
And so this chart we can give it a title here so we can add a chart title here,
and the chart title would be we could make it mother tongue speakers overall in Canada,
and we can make it a percentage of mother tongue speaking speakers.
Percentage of mother tongue speakers year overall in Canada.
So,
as you can see here,
it shows the percentage of people who speak a certain mother tongue overall in Canada.
So here if,
for example,
we add the data labels for everything.
So let's add the deal labels for the different ones here,
the different colors here on for the languages.
You can see here that these data data labels,
for example it says here it's 26.61% off the people in Canada who speak English.
They live in Ontario,
and I'm also gonna actually cut and paste the slicer as well.
So I'm gonna cut it,
and then I'm gonna paste it so control and X and control and be here,
and this will enable me as well to control the numbers on the chart.
You can see here that the data labels they are starting to overlap here,
and they're starting to look ugly.
And I'll show you how we can go around that and make it look much better and more readable
.
So I'm going to do this same,
actually,
for the other charts as well.
So I'm just gonna go to the pivot table here,
Insert on.
Then I'm gonna insert another chart here.
Another pivot chart.
I'm going to remove the buttons,
and I'm going to remove these grid lines.
I'm gonna cut it,
and I'm gonna paste it.
And this time is going to be the percentage of province population per mother tongue in
Canada.
Her mother tongue in Canada.
Right.
So now we're gonna add the data labels here for each one I'm going to show you as well how
to work around these ugly data labels.
The are overlapping.
At the moment.
I'm going to do the same here for the 3rd 1 So insert.
And then I'm going to remove the buttons I'm going to remove as well the grid lines and
just gonna cut it and paste it here.
And now we're gonna name this one here percentage,
mother tongue speakers per province in Canada.
So now I'm gonna add the detail labels here gonna have the data labels for each one.
And now let's actually do a work around for these data labels So one of the easiest things
that you can do is that you can actually color the background or fill the background of the
data labels with the same color off the bar.
So here,
if I select the data label one of the data labels of the orange bars,
for example,
it will select all the data labels for the Orange Force,
and then I can goto format,
and then I can actually fill that shape with the orange color.
Okay,
so this way it's gonna be easy to distinguish the numbers for the orange one.
And maybe I could change the fund for that to be a white that's more readable.
And then I'm going to do the same here for the gray.
So again go.
So I'm gonna go to the format.
I'm gonna make it gray here.
Maybe a darker gray.
Right.
So this way you're able to distinguish here the numbers for the gray ones,
and,
uh,
I'm going to do the same here for the blue.
Maybe a bit of a lighter blue here.
Yeah,
and maybe I can make the front whites as well.
Well,
maybe we could make the blue a bit darker in this case here.
Yeah,
so that there would be more contrast.
Well,
they're still overlap,
but the effect of the overlap has been reduced a lot by coloring the background off the
data label right there,
more,
much more readable now.
And even if you want to zoom onto one of them,
you're going to be able to read it much easier,
right?
You can even move one of them here.
You at least you know what?
You're moving right?
And it's much easier to read these data labels from Ellen.
So I'm going to do the same for the other charts as well.
Okay,
guys of then this same for the other charts as well.
And we can also make the background of the whole chart transparent so that it would be,
you know,
it would show what's behind it and,
of course,
what's behind it.
It's just a white matt here,
But you know,
if you have a different color this way,
it would show the color underneath it if you want to do that,
so I just show you how to do that.
The easiest way to do it is to select the whole chart and then press control and one on
your keyboard.
Or you can also right click and Goto format chart area.
And then on the Phil here,
you got to do no no feel,
and you can do no under the border.
You do know lines.
So now the chart is pretty much transparent and it shows what's behind it.
And you can do the same for the other two charts as well.
No,
Phil,
no line And no Phil,
no line here.
All right.
And now these charts are being controlled by the slicer.
You can also off course change the color of your slicer.
May be the gray would be a bit better here.
You would lend with everything.
So as you can see here,
we managed to create some sort of Ah ah,
quick dashboard here,
if you will.
This is not like a really complex dashboard.
I do actually teach dashboards on another course,
and maybe you could watch that and we use pivot tables a lot.
But this is kind of a quick dashboard that you can create a quick report,
if you will,
for your manager.
If you need to create something like that on the fly.
It's easy with pivot tables,
as you can see here,
and but you can draw some conclusions out of that data.
You're able to look at your data from different perspectives,
as we explained,
and that is the beauty of pivot tables.
Indeed.
All right,
so thank you guys watching this video on.
I'll see you on the next one.