Okay,
guys.
So now let's have another case study for using pivot tables to drive insights from a data
set.
So here,
I've got a data set that I got from stats Canada.
It's for the employees by industry.
So it shows here what the number of employees are in a particular industry in a particular
Canadian province or territory,
and by the type of employees as well,
it breaks him down by the type of the employees.
Okay,
so we're going to study the that data set and see what we can get out of it.
guys.
So first of all,
the first step is to create a table out of our data set.
So I'm gonna go here to insert a table,
and I'm gonna insert a table on my data set,
and I'm gonna coldest TVL data.
Now,
I've created a table out of my data set and you'll notice here that we've got some rose on
the number of people call him that don't have any values.
That does not necessarily mean that the value is zero here.
For the number of people working in that particular industry,
it could also mean that they couldn't get any statistics on the number of people working in
that particular industry under that particular type of employees and in that particular
province and year,
so it doesn't necessarily mean it.
Zero It could be a zero,
or could be that we don't have enough information to get statistics about the number of
people there,
so you could either leave it as it is.
And the pivot table is actually gonna consider that a zero in all its calculations when
adding so it won't make a difference.
Or you can replace the values by zero if that's what you want to do.
So it's really up to you.
I'm just gonna leave it as it is for now.
And it would be a good idea to give some number formatting for the number of people column
.
So I'm just going to select the whole column here by pressing control,
shift and end,
and this will select the whole column.
And then I'm just gonna click here to give it a common style so that reading numbers would
be easier this way,
and I'll also give it no decimal places.
It would be zero decimal places by decreasing the decimals all the way to zero because this
is a number of people,
so we don't need decimals.
So that's something that I could do for my numbers to make every new breeding my numbers
easier.
And now I'm going to create a pivot table out of my data.
So I'm gonna go to insert a pivot table here,
and I'm going to click on OK,
here to insert it in the new worksheets.
I'm gonna insert my pivot table in and you worksheet and let's give this new worksheet a
name here.
Prevette and I'm also going to give my pivot table and name here,
So I'm gonna go to Pivot Table,
analyze year and give it a name,
maybe PVT employees by industry.
Okay,
so I gave my pivot table and name here,
and I'll put my province or territory here on the road section.
Also put the industry under it as well on the road section.
So you can see here it's the province or territory,
and then the industry,
and I'm gonna put the number of people here on the value section here,
and I'm gonna insert here a couple of rose above my pivot tables so as to allow some space
for some slicers I'm gonna add on top of it.
And I'm also going to remove here the grid lines because this makes Molly spreadsheet look
cleaner and,
um,
gonna put a slicer here for the year.
So right,
click and then add as a slicer.
Or you could also go toe insert and then slicer here and then select the year and here you
can see here.
I've got four years here,
and I'm gonna actually make my slicer have four columns us to be spread here horizontally
like this.
This would make it fit in that space better.
And I'm also gonna insert another slicer here for the type of employees.
So right,
click and then add as a slicer.
Or you could also go to insert and then slicer and select the employee type.
And I'm gonna make this two columns here,
and I'm just gonna put the slicer here at the top and also here for the number of people on
my values column here.
I could give this some number formatting so I can go to here to the pivot table,
Analyze stab.
I'll go to select entire pivot table and then I'll go to select again and then alc select
my values here.
And then I'm just going to give it here,
this number formatting here so as to make reading the numbers easier or I go.
So let's start getting some information from our data set after would build our pivot table
.
So first of all,
let's select a year here and let's select a type of employees,
for example to say the hourly employees.
And then let's actually change the calculation here on the some of number of people.
I'm just going to click here on that field on the values section and then click on value
field settings.
I'm gonna click on show values as and I'm gonna go here 2% of parent row Toto,
because this will give me the percentage of the parent row for each rose to the parent row
here,
for example,
for the industry is actually the province,
so he will give me the percentage of the number of people in a province here for each
industry,
so ah,
click OK here.
So what this means here at the moment is that 11.66% of the total number of employees that
are hourly employees in Canada in 2016 are in Alberta on then for each industry here under
a Berta,
it's actually the percentage out of the 11.66%.
Okay,
so this year is giving me the percentage apparent row.
The parent row for the industry is the province,
and the parent row for the province is actually the grand total,
which is the whole off Canada.
Okay,
so we can actually take a quick helicopter view here.
Taken a quick overall view about the breakdown of off the number of employees in Canada.
So what province,
for example has the highest number of employees?
We can do that easily by right clicking here on a province,
and then we can go to expanding collapse,
and then we can actually collapsed the entire field.
If we collapse the entire field,
it will quickly here collapse all the fields.
So this means that it's gonna un expand the provinces which have all the industries under
it.
We're just gonna just un expanding that we're doing that quickly for all the provinces.
So us to no.
Which province has the most number,
employees and it's clear it is Ontario because here in Ontario has almost 40% off the
number off employees in Canada here,
so across most of the years,
and actually they are always hovering.
Around 40% of 40% of the employees in Canada reside in Ontario,
whether their hourly employees or salaried employees inside employees or even more,
they are approaching now.
Ah,
spare the latest data.
They're approaching 45%.
So most of the employees in Canada or in Ontario,
which makes sense because Ontario is actually the most populated,
the most densely populated province in Canada.
Right?
So that's Ah,
quick insight that we can get out of our data and we can actually click here on the plus
next to Interior to know what is the most industry that people work at by your own.
Uh,
I've sorted that already.
So I've started in a descending order.
But if it doesn't show like that for you can right click and sort and sort largest to
smallest here.
So you can see here that it's already sorted here in descending order,
and you can see here that the most industries is thean industrial aggregate,
excluding unclassified businesses and service producing industries and educational services
.
These air the top three industries.
So there are a lot of universities in Ontario on people come to study in Ontario.
So that is actually a significant portion here of the employees of Ontario here for
salaried employees.
Ah,
for hourly employees,
it's a bit different.
So it's Industri aggregate and service producing industries,
but but a different percentage.
And then there's goods producing industries as well.
So as you can see here,
the the industries they change whether you choose Arlie employees or salaried employees,
let's check.
Actually,
a province like Noona VAT,
which is a bit of,
ah,
remote provinces,
a remote area.
It's far up north in Canada,
and it doesn't have a large population.
It only has about 36,000 people living in it and is you can hear the most.
Industries is service producing industries and service producing industries include the
banking and the finance and,
ah,
the insurance industries.
So there's not much.
They're not much production or anything.
It's just the industries that people where people can do like office jobs,
or so,
as you can see here and there is accommodation and Food services,
which is basically the hospitality industry,
like the restaurants and the hotels.
And that's pretty much it.
So,
ah,
most off the economy of ah.
None of it is just dependent on service industries and accommodation and food services.
This is something this is an insight that you can get out of this data set,
and that makes sense because it's a very,
very cold area.
So,
uh,
people rarely go out about.
So it makes sense that most of the industry's air indoor jobs and not much of outdoor jobs
so you can see her.
The Nunavut has mostly the service producing industries and the accommodation and food
services.
These are the main industries that people work at.
And,
by the way,
the fact that the other industries are zeros doesn't mean necessarily that there are no
people working in these industries.
It could mean that there was no data available,
which is weird,
actually,
because stats can and should be able to the pain data for that,
it's it's May.
It's their main focus.
But sometimes there might not be enough data or so for for the other industries,
so that doesn't necessarily mean that there are no people working in the other industries.
It might mean that there's no accurate data for that.
Alright,
guys.
So this was a quick exploration off this data set,
and you will have some sort of exercise or home work to do on this data set.
I'll give you some questions too.
Answer about this data set.
So hope you found the video helpful,
and I'll see you on the next one.