this video,
I'm going to show you one of my favorite tips for dealing with Pivot table field.
So actually it involves sorting.
The pivot table feels alphabetically because it makes finding the pivot table feels so much
easier.
So sometimes when you have a lot of feels when you have a table with lots of columns here,
you would have a long list even longer than this off pivot table fields.
And if they are not sorted,
it's not gonna be easy to find them,
so you can easily sort them in an A to Z fashion by clicking on this gear icon here and
then clicking on sort HZ.
Alternatively,
you can go to the analyzed tab on the ribbon click on options.
Then you're gonna click on display here,
and then you're gonna have an option here for feel this sort eight easy and click.
OK does a very nice tip that you can use in order to sort your pivot table fuels in an A to
Z fashion or in ascending order so that you confined your fields easily