Okay,
Here's another tip that I want to show you,
which is that we can double click on any row or column label items to show more fields.
So,
for example,
here if we double click on product one,
which is on the road section here,
we can get we get a list of the fields and we can actually add more feels,
which basically would breakdown product one.
So,
for example,
we can break down products one by region if you click.
OK,
here,
you guys hear that?
Now we have a breakdown for product one by region,
which is America's Australia and Europe.
So we get the sales a month for each region under product one.
As you can see here as well,
the region field has been added to the rose section below product one.
And when it's put below product one like this,
this means that it breaks down product one by region,
okay and use.
You can see here as well.
Product to and product three and product for all have been broken down by region as a
result of the action that I've taken,
which is adding the region under the product name basically and we can do the same for the
year here for double click on the year Weaken.
Break it down by the month.
So by its sales month,
if we click OK,
here,
he could hear that.
Now we have 2016 and then older months and then 2017 and in all the months and our pivot
table is getting pretty long.
But you get the idea.
Okay,
so that's a nice tip.
You can double click on the label for any field,
and you will get a list of the fields and you can break down that field by other fields.