Okay,
so that's speak about a term that you were here are lot when dealing with pivot tables,
which is called the pivot cash.
So when you create a pivot table,
a copy of your data is stored in what is called a pivot cash.
So the pivot cash is basically a duplicate of your data table,
and it's created whenever you create a pivot table and the pivot cash is like a snapshot of
your data table.
So whenever your data is updated so more Roeser added,
or values in your data are changed,
you will need to refresh your pivot table in order for another snapshot to be taken from
your data and put in your pivot cash and ultimately get your pivot table updated within you
data.
So the pivot cash is just a snapshot from your data.
And this is why whenever your data is updated,
this snapshot becomes old and we need to take another snapshot.
And when we take another snapshot,
which is by refreshing our pivot table are pivot table gets updated with the new values.
So in this lecture,
we were just explaining the concept of the pivot cash and how it works and the pivot cash
the data in the pivot.
Catch guests stored in the background system of your computer and off course because it's a
duplicate of your data or a snapshot of your data if you have a big amount of data.
If you have hundreds of thousands of rose and and you don't have enough resource is on your
computer,
you might see your computer slowing down when you're dealing with pivot tables having
hundreds of thousands of rose.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
for the pivot.
Cash.
Thanks for watching I'll see on the next one.