Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about refreshing your pivot table.
So we've spoken before about the pivot table cash and that it's a snapshot of your data
that is underlying the pivot table.
So actually,
when you change any of your data or if your data changes,
basically you have to refresh your pivot table.
So we're going to see how we can do that in this video.
And also,
I want to demonstrate something else.
So I'm gonna copy my pivot table.
I'm gonna hide like my whole pivot table here.
I'm gonna copy but pressing control and see on my keyboard and then paste it just below
here,
creating just a copy of my pivot table by pressing control and V on my keyboard.
Now I'm gonna go make a change on my data.
So let's say on any off the rose for product one.
I'm just gonna change the sales amount,
make it one million,
for example,
on 23456 and then actually,
for the new numbers to reflect on the pivot table,
I need to refresh it.
So to refresh my pivot table,
I can either select my paper table and then go to the data tab on the ribbon.
Click on this arrow here on the refresh old and then click on Refresh and you will notice.
Actually,
although I'm refreshing just one pivot table,
both pivot tables will be refreshed,
and the numbers on product one will update on both pivot tables.
So it's just refresh it here,
and you can see here in the number here for product one has updated for in 2016 because the
change that we've done here waas in product 14 2016.
This is why the numbers have updated for 2016 Mexicans here.
The refresh has been done for both pivot tables.
So why is that the case?
It's because both pivot tables are linked or tied to the same pivot cash.
So the data source is the same,
which is the same pivot cash,
which is our data.
You can also refresh your pivot table by right clicking and then clicking on refresh so
right clicking on the pivot table and then clicking on refresh.
And this will also refresh your pivot table.
OK,
so basically,
whenever your data gets updated you will need to refresh your pivot table because your
pivot cash is just a snapshot from your pivot table.
And so when the data gets updated,
we need to update that snack shop by refreshing our pivot table.
OK,
so thanks,
guys watching I'll see on the next one.