Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to show how we can refresh multiple pivot tables in a workbook that have
different data sources.
So here we've got to pivot tables on this worksheet.
We get the pivot table on the left,
which is linked to data one,
or has its data sources data one.
And we get the pivot table here on the right,
which is linked to data to or has its data source as date is too.
So basically,
we're going to make changes to both data sets and see how we can refresh both pivot tables
at the same time.
So here,
we're going to make a change on data one for product 1 2016 So go to data one and have
highlighted the seldom gonna change here.
And I'm gonna put one million here on the sales amount and for data to as well of
highlighted this selling gonna change,
which is for product to in 2016 as well.
So I'm gonna put one million as well on this cell and then to refresh both pivot tables
were going to go to the data tab here on the ribbon.
And then we've got a button here that says,
Refresh all.
And there's an arrow is well,
you compress on the arrow and click on Refresh Old.
Or you can click on the button and just refresh all the pivot table.
So you can see here that both pivot tables have been refreshed with the changes,
and the changes have reflected on both pivot tables when we clicked on refresh all.
So when you click on re fresh old,
you refresh Oh,
the pivot tables in your workbook,
even if they have different data sources.
OK,
so this is how you can refresh all the pivot tables on your workbook,
even if they have different air sources,
which is using the refresh old feature here in Excel.
OK,
so thanks guys watching,
I'll see on the next one.