Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to see how we can connect to and re fresh external data.
So let's say you've got a file that you share with your colleagues,
and it's sitting on a server somewhere.
So let's say we've got this file here,
which is gold external data that sits in a server.
That's emissions.
This foul sits in the server,
and you need to connect to the data in that file.
So this files teams data and you need to connect to it.
So actually you can insert a pivot table and then you're gonna click on use X,
an external data source,
and click on Choose Connection here.
And then you're gonna click on,
browse for more and then browse to your Felda fell a cheese on my desktop.
So I'm just gonna browse for it here external data,
and I'm gonna double click on it.
As you can see here,
we have a view here that shows us the tabs inside that file,
and we've got only one top,
which is called Data,
and the first wrote of the data contains columns and headers.
It's just the same day that we've been using.
But it's in this external data file.
I'm gonna click OK,
here.
So you're going to choose the top where your data lies and you're gonna click,
OK,
and then click OK again.
And now we're able to connect to that file with the external data,
and we're gonna be able to construct a pivot table using the data in that particular file.
So I'm gonna put the product name here on the Rose and put the sales amount on the value
section and you're able to connect that file.
And if the data on the external data file changes,
you can always refresh it as usual by right clicking and then clicking on refresh here.
And there are some options as well that you want to show you.
So I'm going to right click on my pivot table and then click on Pivot Table Options year
and then on the data top.
There is an option here that says refresh data when opening the file.
So if you check the option and click OK,
whenever you open your new file that has the pivot table connected to your external data
file,
Excel will refresh the pivot tables in the new file.
So this is also a useful feature,
since it always make sure that your pivot tables are refreshed whenever you open the file
that is connected to the external data file.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
this is how you can connect to data in an external pile or an external data source.
So thanks,
guys watching I'll see on the next one.