if you've got multiple filters applied to your pivot table.
So here I've got Filter for the Americas,
for example in the region and for the salesman.
I've got some filters applied here for some particular months,
and I just need to clear all the filters all at once with just a click of a button so you
can quickly clear the filters on your pivot table by selecting a cell inside your private
table going to the analyzed tab on the ribbon,
and then here,
under this clear button,
you press on the arrow,
and then there is clear filters,
and this will clear all the filters on your pivot table.
So now we don't have any filters on our pivot table and if you've created the your pivot
table in a certain layout,
so you put some fields in the rose area and some peels in the columns,
infusing the values,
and you need to clear the pivot table and just redo it from the very beginning again.
So you can also go back to the clear here and then click on clear old and this will clear
pivot table and it will be ready again to be reconstructed