Okay,
so now we're going to speak about selecting and formatting certain sections of our pivot
table.
So first,
to select informant a certain section,
we need to make sure that an option is enabled on our pivot table.
So,
first of all,
we need to select a cell inside our pivot table,
and then we're going to go to the analyze,
stab on the ribbon and then go to select,
and then you need to make sure there's an option called enable selection.
You need to make sure that this is enable it's currently enabled,
and you will see that it has ah,
gray filling here in sight.
If I disable it,
you'll see that the great feeling will disappear.
So you just need to make sure it's enable and it has that grey feeling here inside.
So now,
with enabled selection of a certain section of our pivot table.
Now let's say we want to select a certain product here and change its color in this pivot
table.
So I say I'm gonna hover over product one.
And when I have this arrow here,
this thick black arrow pointing towards the right,
I'm just gonna collect here and you can see here,
it's selected Product one.
Now I'm gonna go to the home tab on the ribbon.
I'm gonna make Let's say I'm gonna make the fund reds and as you can see here now we have
the fund for product one red.
So if you actually change the layout over pivot table So say we moved the product names to
the column section he can see here that product one after being moved to the column section
is still having a red fund.
Now will press control and Z on my keyboard to get the pivot table to the previous layout
again.
Now let's say I want to change the color for quarter one in all the products to yellow the
fill color.
So I'm just gonna hover over key one until I get this arrow here and then I'm gonna press
on it and you could see your key.
One is highlighted on all the products.
I'm just gonna make it yellow the fill color here.
And now we have you one in yellow.
Now,
if you move the quarter to the column section of a pivot table,
you can see here that key one is yellow on all the products.
It remains yellow.
After we changed the layout of our pivot table,
press control and Z back here,
too,
put the pivot table back to its previously out.
Now let's say I want to apply a change to all the role labels here for all the products.
So I'm just gonna hover over my product,
any product,
just product one,
for example.
And I need to hover over and be on the right hand side a bit to the right,
and I will have a narrow ethic,
arrow pointing downwards here.
So I'll just click here and deacons here.
I've selected all the row headings for all the products.
Now let's say I'm just going to increase their fund size like this.
And also now,
if I put them to the column section instead of the Rose section,
you can see here that the product labels have a bigger fund size for all the products.
I'll press control and Z on my keyboard to put the pivot table back in the previous form,
You can also apply certain formatting to a Hill column.
So,
for example,
let's say when I apply is certain formatting to the year 2017 here.
So I'm just gonna have our over until I get this arrow pointing downwards.
And now I can actually put a border around it.
So I put a thick outside border here around it around 2017 for example.
And then if I change how my pivot table look,
So move the quarter,
for example,
toe the columns.
You can see here that 2017 has a thick water around it,
even after we changed.
How are pivot table looks?
So all press control and Z,
um,
a keyboard here to go back,
and you could basically do the same thing for any section in the pivot table.
Just make sure to hover over the section until you see the arrow and then click on it and
highlighted,
Then apply whatever formatting you would like.
And this romantic will stick to it even when the layout or the orientation of the pivot
table would change.
Now we've spoken about selecting each individual section on our pivot table.
So how do we select the whole pivot table?
Well,
there are two ways the first way is to go to the very most upper left corner here,
which is this cell and under the sum of sales amount.
Here you can see the arrow.
If you click on it,
you will select the whole pivot table.
Another way,
which is much easier,
in my opinion,
is to go to the analyzed tab on the ribbon,
go to select and then entire pivot table,
and this will select the whole pivot table for you.
And then you can delete it to press delete on your keyboard and you pivot table will be
delete it.
Just press control NZ on my keyboard here to restore my pivot table again.
OK,
so that's it for selecting and formatting.
I'll see you on the next one.