and this video,
we're going to speak about the different report layouts for a pivot table.
So excel pivot tables have different layouts that you can choose from,
and in this video we're going to speak about the different layouts.
So in order to change the layouts for you,
pivot table,
you need to select a cell inside your pivot table and then go to the design tab on the
ribbon and then under the layout group here,
you've got the report layout option,
and currently we are in the compact form,
the compact form lee out.
So this is the default lee out that you get when you create a pivot table.
So this is the compact form.
And as you can see here,
we've got two fields in the rose section,
the product name and the sales person.
And,
as you can see here,
both feels are in the same column as you can see here.
So got each product,
and then we've got each sales person.
They are old on the same column and at the top here with just got a generic label.
It doesn't say product name or sales person.
It just says grow labels Now let's try the other layup that we have here,
which is the outline form and,
as you can see here when we select the outlying form,
because here that each field on the Rose section now has been moved to its own column here
.
So you got the product name in the first column and then the sales person in the second
column.
You can see here as well that the labels or the headings for each product here.
So for product one product to and product three,
you can see here that it's in.
It's own separate TRO above any sales person.
So,
as you can see here,
this is the first sales person.
But you can see here that the product being above it in the Rose section each product is in
its own row.
Because here that we have our sub totals at the top,
however,
we can always have them at the bottom,
just like we showed on a previous video and injections year.
Now we have an extra row inserted for subtitles,
and they are at the bottom off the group.
When using this outline form were able to also repeat the item labels so we can actually
make product one appear in each row here.
And to do that we can go to the airport layout and then we have an option that says,
repeat all item labels and you will see here that now the row headings are gonna be
inserted in each row,
so this is actually useful.
If you're trying to do a look up And if you're trying to get your data in a tabular form or
if you're trying to print your data in tabular form,
this would be useful.
I'll press control and zeal my keyboard to undo that and remove the repeating off item
labels.
And now the third report layout that we have here is the tabular form.
So if we select that,
you can see here that now the labels of the first row field are not on their separate TRO
anymore.
Aziz,
you can see here now it's product one,
and then we have the sales person,
the first sales person starting on the same row.
Where is on the outline form?
You can see here that this first sales person starts on the following Rome not the same bro
.
So this is the tabular form for you.
You're also able to repeat old item labels on that form.
And,
as you can see here that Sepp totals on the tabular form appear at the bottom.
But they cannot appear at the top anymore because we don't have space for them.
Because now the item labels for the salesperson start on the same row as the item labels
for products.
So as you can see her if I go to sub totals and I tried to show the subtitles at the top,
I can't do that on the tabular form.
I can either just remove the sub totals or have them appear at the bottom.
I want to point out as well that if we go to the compact form were not able to repeat item
labels because basically,
there is no space for the item.
Lee was to be repeated because all the item labels here are owned the same column.
So the product name and the sales person they're both on the same calm.
There's no space to repeat the item labels.
They're already there.
Okay,
so these were the three different layouts for pivot tables that you can choose from by
default.
You do get the compact form at the beginning,
and then you can choose which ever form that you want.
But when you create a pivot table,
it's always gonna be created in the compact form.
So thanks guys watching this video and I'll see on the next one.