Okay,
So before creating our pivot table,
we need to make sure of three things.
Number one is the Our data is in a tabular format.
Number two is that we do not have any gaps in our data.
And number three is that we form it our data properly.
In this video,
we're going to speak about having our data in a tabular format.
So you should actually have your column Names at the top showing a distinct category.
So each column showing a distinct category.
So we have a column for customers,
another call for products region sales amount,
order,
mount order,
date.
And this is supposed to be the year.
And this one is supposed to be the quarter.
However,
we do not have them labeled here because we want to demonstrate something.
OK,
so let's try to create a pivot table here.
I'm gonna click inside my data press control and a on my keyboard to select only data,
even including the columns that are not labeled.
And then I'm gonna click on the insert tab on the ribbon click on pivot table,
and then I'm gonna insert a pivot table and you worksheet click.
OK,
here.
And as you could see her,
a pivot table has been created.
But our columns that are not labelled have not been included in the pivot table.
Feels so the columns that were not labeled where,
the quarter and the year.
So this is why we need to make sure to label our columns.
So if you go back to our data here and then create some labels for columns year and then
quarter and then create another pivot table insert to select all our data,
insert a pivot table and then click OK here.
And you can see here that the columns have been created because they do have labels.
So the bottom line from this lesson is that you need to make sure to create labels for all
your columns,
and please note as well that in older Excel virgins,
instead of creating a pivot table without the unlabeled columns,
you might actually get an error while creating a pivot table for columns that are not label
.
So always make sure to create labels for your columns before creating a pivot table