and this video,
we're going to speak about moving and shifting around fields on items in our pivot tables.
So when it comes to items,
we can actually move on item from one position to another in a pivot table.
So here,
for example,
for product to which is an item under the product name field.
It's not the first item here on the field.
You can see here that first item here is product one,
but we can actually move product to to replace product one here and become the first item
on the product name field.
And to do that,
you can just click on product to here and then hover over the corner for product.
Two year until you get this foresighted arrow.
Click and drag upwards here to replace product one.
And as you can see here,
we managed to replace product one with product to and product to is now the first item on
the product name field.
I'll press Control and Z on the keyboard toe.
Undo that,
and alternatively,
you can also click here on product one,
and then you can type product to instead,
and this will replace product one here with product to and product who becomes the first
item here.
Ah,
press control NZ to undo that and then you can also do the same thing with the year.
So here we've got 2017 is the first year we can make 2016 the first year here.
Or we can put back 2017 to be the first year normally,
but default.
You should have 2000 and 16 as the first year here.
You have other options as well,
so you can move around on item label by right,
clicking on it here.
And then there is a move option here,
and then you can move it one step down.
So move product one down will move it.
One step down here to replace product to,
or you can also move it to the end.
And that means that you will go down to the very bottom here,
and when it's at the very bottom,
you will have an option here,
move it to the beginning or move it up.
So up one step or to the very beginning,
to put it back here to the very top position,
you get the idea,
and if we explore the move option more right click move.
Here you can see air more product name to the right or to end,
and this will basically move the field.
Either one step down or to the very end here on the roads section.
Or you can also move it to the column section.
So if you click on this move product name to the right,
this will move it one step down on the roast sections.
As you can see here and now,
it's sales person than product name.
And if there had been three fields,
we would have been able to notice here the end option.
But you know the end option.
We've got only two fields.
But if you add 1/3 field the quarter,
for example,
we can make the product name field.
For example,
if you used the end option here,
we can make it at the very bottom field here.
You can also use this Rosen column section as well to move around fields,
and this is much easier even.
And of course,
you can move items fields from the rose section to the column section.
This way.
So basically,
this has been a demonstration on how to move and shift around fields on items in our pivot
table.
So thanks so much watching,
I'll see on the next.