Okay,
so here we've got a pivot table.
We've got our months on the road section and we've got the submission of sales amount here
on the submission of Value section.
And let's say we want a place of formatting to the submission of sales amount.
So Atacama and a currency so we can click on any cell here on the sales amount and then
right click and go to number format.
Alternatively,
compressed control on one on your keyboard and you'll get to the same dollar box here we
can go to accounting.
We can remove the decimal places and give it an accounting form.
And we can also select our currency here.
English,
United States press okay.
And Deacon sear that we've applied formatting to the submission of sales amount.
However,
if we put the sales amount again on the submission of Value Section to do,
let's say a different kind of announces,
he can see here that the formatting has not been applied and we'd have to reapply it again
.
So to get around this and make our formatting stick,
we need to do it in a different way.
So press control and Z twice on my keyboard here so that I would go back to the original
form and then while selecting a cell inside my pivot table,
I can go to the analyzed tab on the ribbon and then go to select and entire pivot table,
and then I'll go back to select and go to values year,
and then we need to go to the number formatting.
But instead of right clicking,
you cannot right click.
In this case,
you have to press control on one on your keyboard to press control,
and one because if you right click and select format cells,
it will not work.
So we pressed control,
and one,
we are now on the format cells dialog box.
We're gonna go to accounting,
remove the decimal places and select English United States.
And then we're gonna press.
Okay,
Jake is here.
The formatting has been applied.
Now,
if we drag and drop the sales amount again on the submission of Value Section,
you can see here that the formatting has stuck to this sales amount and this is how you can
apply formatting to your values and make it stick