Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to show a nice tip that you can use when you have more than one field in the
values area to Currently we have only one field,
which is the sum of sales.
So that's at another field to the value section.
And let's make the aggregation be the count for the sake of argument.
So I'm just going to drag the sales amount here to the submission of Value Section,
and I'm gonna change the aggregation on it.
So I'm gonna left click on it and then value field settings.
And then I'm going to select count instead of some and then press OK year because here that
we now have two aggregation fields.
But you can see here as well that we have an extra field that's appeared here on the world
section,
which is the Sigma Values field.
And this field allows you to move multiple aggregation feels at once.
So actually,
this field here,
the signal values feel with all hours to move the sum of sales and count of sales both at
the same time,
so I can actually move it to the column section and because here the view has changed.
And we've got actually our aggregation fields here stacked across the columns.
And if we move it back,
you can see her.
The view that we've got here,
which is that each sales person has a breakdown by the some of sales amount and account of
sales amount.
And we can also move it above the sales person.
And in this case,
we're gonna have a breakdown for each aggregation.
So there's some and account.
We're gonna have it broken down by the else person.
So that is a nice small tip for you here,
which is that you can move multiple aggregation feels at once using this submission of
values field that appears when you have multiple aggregation.
Feels so.
Thanks,
guys watching.
I'll see on the next one.