Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So as you can see here,
we've got a pivot table,
and this pivot table has the park team and the sales person on the road section and the
year on the columns section and the summation of sales year on the Submission of Value
Section.
And as you can see here,
this pivot table,
if we select a cell inside it,
go to design Tab and then on the report layout.
We're currently actually in the compact.
For now.
If we switch to the outline form,
you will see here that the sales person has been indented to the right,
and it is in its own column at the moment.
Now we can actually achieve something similar to that.
But actually,
in the compact form,
we've explained the different pivot table layouts reportedly outs previously on a previous
video.
So please refer back to that video.
Now,
if we switch back to the compact form,
there's an option that we can use,
which we can get to by right clicking and then clicking on pivot table options.
And then there is an option here,
it says,
when in compact form in dentro labels by one character.
It's,
Carney said at one.
But weaken.
Change that to 10 for example,
10 characters.
And then we press okay.
And as you can see here,
it's been indented easy,
cause here the sales person has been indented by 10 characters.
It looks now more like an outline form,
but actually we're currently in the compact for so it's a way to achieve a look that is
similar to the outline form,
but actually in the compact form.