in this video,
we're going to see how we can change the filter layout in pivot tables says You can see
here we've got a pivot table here we get a product name on the Rose and the Year on the
Columns section and the submission of sales on the Submission Value section,
and we get a bunch of filters year,
region sales,
person quarter and sales month.
And as you can see here,
the filters are in a single column,
but you can actually make them be in a single row or multiple worlds.
And you can set a limit on how many filters appear per column or Perot so that if you said
a limited to,
for example,
than you'd have to filters in this column and then Excel would create another column for
the other two filters.
So we'll see how we can do that.
Basically,
you can right click on any cell in your pivot table and then go to pivot table options here
,
and you can see here there is an option here,
display fuels and report filter area down than over,
so it's currently down.
Then over this means that they'll be stacked across columns like this.
And then there is report filter fields per column,
so it's currently zero.
So that means it will put all the filters in one column.
But let's say I'm gonna put a limit of two per column so we'll actually put each two
filters in a single column.
So we get here full filters,
so we'll have to columns here.
So each two filters are in a column.
You can also right click here pivot table options and then the second option here instead
of down then over.
It's over.
Then down this will make them get Start the crossroads.
I'll switch to the zero option here in you can see here it's now,
report filter fields,
Perot instead of pair column.
So press Okay,
so zero is usually the default option to see what happens here.
You can see here that now the filters are spread here in a single row is against year.
They are all in a single rope.
Now,
if we go again to the pivot table options and then we can make it to Perot.
So we've got four filters,
so we're gonna have to rose with two filters,
each press OK you can see here we get to Rose and we've got to filters per each row.
So this is how you can change the pivot table filter,
Leo.