Okay,
So the second rule for creating or pivot table is do not have any blank rows or blank
columns in our data.
Says you can see her on our data.
We've got column,
if is blank.
And we've got to blank rows here,
row 18 and row 33.
Okay,
so let's try to create a pivot table here and see what happens.
Now,
I'm gonna select my headers here.
I'm gonna hold my shift key on my keyboard and then select the rest of the headers with my
arrows on the keyboard.
And then I'm gonna press control shifting down on my keyboard and keep doing that until I
said,
like all the data here and then I'm gonna go to insert a pivot table.
I'm going to try to create a new pivot table in your worksheet.
And as you can see year,
I'm getting an error.
Pivot table field name is not valid.
This is because we have a blank column,
so I'm gonna click.
OK,
here.
I'm gonna click.
Cancel and I need to delete Molly Blank column.
So right clicked on my column and deleted it.
And now we need to also make sure not to have any blank crows in the middle off our data
set.
So imagine that you have lots of blank rows.
Not only two,
but lots.
So you don't want to select them all one by one in order to delete them.
So a better way to do it is to select all your data.
Second year plus control,
shifting down to select all your data set year on your keyboard and then go to the home tab
on the ribbon click on finding select and click on Go to special.
And then we're going to select blanks.
So this actually select only the blank cells in our selection off cells.
We're gonna click OK here,
and you can see here only the blank cells have been selected.
So I'm going to right click on the selected cells on any of the selected cells and then
click on delete here to delete my cells.
And I'm going to select entire Oh,
because I want to delete the entire row of cells.
The are blank.
So I'm gonna click OK here.
And as you can see here,
I managed to delete my blank rows case I know we can go ahead and press control and ages.
Selector data Make sure that we picked up all the rows here and then go to insert a pivot
table and insert a new pivoted.
As you can see here,
we managed to insert or pivot table,
and this is another rule that you need to follow.
When creating a pivot table.
Make sure that you do not have any blank crows in the middle of your data or blank columns
.
When you have blank rows,
either they could be missing values.
You need to fill them or if they are blank by error,
and you just need to remove them than you remove them as we demonstrated.