Sometimes you might have empty data on your pivot table.
So,
for example,
here in September 2016 we've got empty data here,
and the reason for that is that if we go back to our data,
we can see where the transactions that happened in September 2016 did not have a sales
amount.
The sales amount is blank.
This is why,
on our pivot table,
September 2016 is blank so you could change how the blank cells show on your pivot table.
You could do that by right clicking and then going to pivot table options year.
And then there's an option here for empty cells show so you can show no transactions,
for example,
or no data or anything else.
So here we've shown no transactions.
So this is how you can change how empty cells show on your pivot table.