and this video,
we're going to go through the different aggregation options that are available in pivot
tables says You can see here we get a simple pivot table where we got the year and then
it's broken down by months,
and we've got the sales amount for each year and for each month as well.
So you can see here that the aggregation that we've done is the summation.
So we summed up the sales amount,
but we can do other types of aggregation as well.
So to do another type of aggregation on the sales amount,
for example,
where you need to do is to drag your field here.
Which anarchists is gonna be the sales amount.
We're going to drag it again to the submission of Value Section,
and then we can click on the field itself and then go to value field settings and you can
see here we've got other options.
So summaries values value field by other options other than the sum weaken do count,
for example.
And if I click OK,
this gives us the count of rows for that particular item.
So here in January 2016 we've got eight rows Now,
if you check our data set and that filter for 2016 end for January,
he can see here that we've got eight rows.
I'm going to remove my filters,
you but pressing control and see twice on my keyboard.
And then I'm gonna go back to my pivot table and then let's explore mawr aggregation
options.
You can also go to the aggregation options.
Another way to do it is by right clicking here and then summarize values by Nicosia.
You've got some options and you can also more options for the full list here so we can do
average as well.
On this will give you the average sales instead of the count of number of sales.
And then we can also do the max here,
and the max will give you the amount on the transaction that contained the maximum sale.
So here in 2016 January,
we filter again here.
By 2016 and January,
he can see air that the maximum sales him out on a particular transaction was 94,605 which
is the same amount that we've got here.
You could also choose minimum instead of maximum,
which will give you the amount on the transaction that contained the minimum sale.
And if we go to more options as well,
we've got here product which will basically multiply the amounts of all the sales
transactions that happened in January.
So we select product.
It will give us a very big number,
and this number is basically the result of multiplying all these sales amounts by each
other.
So if you go back to our pivot table on,
if we explore more options that we got here to go to more options,
we've got also standard deviation for the simple and then for the population and variants
for the simple and for the population.
The other option that you need to highlight here is the count numbers and count numbers
will count on Lee the cells that contain numbers.
So,
for example,
here in January,
we've got the count numbers.
It's eight and it's equal to the count because account will count both Dexter numbers.
But count numbers will only count numbers.
But all the values here are numbers actually on the sales amount.
But if we replace one value,
for example by text here just any kind of text.
And if we remove the filters here and then refresh our pivot table.
So now we've got a value.
On January 2000 and 16 there is a text,
so the count numbers should be seven.
As you can see here,
it's become just a seven.
So this is a useful option.
If you need toe on Lee,
count the cells that contain numbers.
Okay,
guys.
So that's it.
That was a quick tour through the different aggregation options that we got here on the
value field settings.
Thank you very much watching I'll see on the next one.