and this video,
we're going to see how we can create a percentage of grand,
total calculated field in our pivot table.
So we're able to insert a calculated field on the submission of Value section that would
calculate the percentage of each of the values in our pivot table from the grand total
value here that has red borders on the bottom,
right corner of our pivot table.
So to do that,
what we need to do is to insert another field here on the submission of Value section.
But we're going to click on it and then go to value field settings and then go to show
values as and then instead of no calculation or gonna select percentage of grand total.
And we can change its name as well.
2% of grand total and we can click OK here.
And as you can see here,
we were able to insert a calculated field that calculates the percentage of grand total for
each value on our pivot table.
So basically this value is 9.9% from the grand total value.
And actually,
if we some the individual values here across the columns,
for example,
so if you some this value and this value you will see here that there summation is 15.61%
of the grand total,
which is basically the percentage of this sub total here from the grand total.
So this subtitle 1,266,446 is 15.61% off this grand total.
So basically this percentage of grant a little would insert a calculated field that would
indicate the percentage of each item over pivot table from the grand total.