in this video,
we're going to explain the percentage off calculation in pivot tables,
so the percentage off calculation displays the value of one item as a percentage of another
item.
Okay,
so let's take an example for that.
So I've got a pivot table here that shows the sales on each year here for each region.
And let's say I want to display the sales of each year as a percentage of the previous year
.
So I want to see the percentage of 2017 sales from the sales off 2016 for example.
And if there had been a 2018 year here on my data,
then I'll be able to display the percentage of the sales in 2018 from the sales in 2017.
You get the idea.
So to do that,
I'm gonna insert another field here for the sales amount so that I can edit that field to
display the sales as a percentage of the previous year.
So I've got this sum of sales amount to I'm gonna click on it,
go to value field settings here,
and then go to show values as on then for the show values as instead of no calculation,
I'm gonna select percentage off and they want to display the percentage of the previous
years.
I'm going to go to the year field here and then I'm going to select previous and then I'm
going to rename it so I can rename it percentage of previous year and then I'm gonna click
.
Okay,
here and now.
As you can see here,
I can see the percentage of the sales from the PVC ear off course because 2016 is the
earliest year on my data.
There isn't a year previous to that,
so it's showing 100% because we're getting the percentage of the sales of 2016 from the
sales of 2016 which would deal the 100%.
But here in 2017 I get the percentage of sales for 2017 from 2016.
So basically saying here that the sales for 2017 war 65 points 69% off the sales in 2016
you could also get the sales off a certain item as well.
So I'm going to go here to the stop percentage of product one.
So let's say we want to get the percentage of the sales for each product as measured from
product one.
So I want to display the percentage of the sales for product to as a percentage of the
sales for product one and percentage of the sales were product three as a percentage of
product one and so on and so forth.
Let's say that product one is our main product and we wanna get the percentage of sales for
each product with respect to product one.
So we can do that as well.
We're gonna insert another field here from the sales amount,
and then we're going to click on it,
go to value field settings,
go to show values as and then percentage of,
and we're going to select here.
The base field is going to be our product name.
So this is the field we're gonna base our sales on.
And then we're going to select here Product one.
So this field here is gonna be named percentage of product one sales,
and we're gonna click OK here.
And as you can see here,
this shows us the percentage of sales with respect to product one.
So here,
because product who has sold more than product one is showing more than 100% here on 2016.
So that means that product to was 124 percent 0.65 of product one.
This means it sold about 25% more than product one.
And this is the case for product three and for product for as well.
It shows the sales as a percentage off product one.
Okay,
so this is how you can do the percentage of calculation in pivot tables.