and this video,
we're going to speak about the percentage apparent row total calculation aint pivot tables
.
So the percentage apparent row total calculation displays the percentage of an item from
its parent row total.
So we can display,
for example,
the percentage of Q three in America sales from the total sales for America's.
So let's have an example here.
So I'm gonna drag the sales amount field again here to create another field of the sales
amount.
And then I'm going to click on it good to value field settings and then go to show values
as.
And then I'm going to select percentage your parent row total.
And then I'm gonna change its name here.
Percentage of parent trow and then I'm going to click OK,
here.
And as you can see here,
we get the percentage of the parent TRO for each item.
So here,
for example,
7.6% for key one is basically it's saying that key one is 7.6% of the total sales in the
Americas and Q two is 32 point 63% of the total sales in the Americas as well.
And here when we say that on the Americas is 21.9%.
That means that the Americas are 21.9% off their parent row.
So the parent TRO,
because the Americas heir a sub total their parent rose actually the grand total year at
the bottom.
So this means that the Americas are 21.9% of the grand total off the sales,
and Australia is 17.47% of the grand total of the sales in 2016 and so on and so forth.
So this calculation displaced the percentage of each item from its parent row.
Another example that we can have here is displaying the percentage of each month from its
parent row.
In this case,
in the case of this pivot table,
which is its year so we can do the same here,
drag another one for the sales amount and then go to value field settings here show values
as percentage of parent row total,
and then we could name this percentage of year,
for example,
and if you click OK,
here,
you can see here the it displays the percentage of each month from its parent here.
So here February under 2016 is 5.42% of the year 2016.
And actually,
the year 2016 is 52.2% of the grand total for 2016 and 2070.
I need to also add one more thing here,
which is that when we say that a field is the parent of another field,
the reason that it's apparent of another field is that it's above it here in the hierarchy
on the Rose section here.
So here the year is the parent troll of the sales month because it's above it on the
hierarchy here on the Rose section.
The same goes here on the first example where the region is the parent of the quarter,
because it's above it here on the roast section.
So actually,
if we put the quarter above the reason like this,
the quarter will be the parent of the region.
So this is what it means when you do a percentage of the parent total here,
which is that it displays the field as a percentage of its parent.
So thanks,
guys were watching and I'll see you on the next one