in this video,
we're going to explain the percentage apparent column calculation aint pivot tables.
So you could probably guess what that does since we've explained the percentage of Parent
Row total calculation.
So instead of showing the percentage based on the parent row,
it's going to show the percentage based on the parent column.
So that's insert another field here for the sales amount and then click on it.
Go to value field settings go to show values as on them percentage apparent column total
here,
and we can name that percentage of parent column.
And if you press OK here,
you can see here what we get.
The percentages that we get here are the percentages of each quarter from their parent
column,
which is the year here.
So the year here is the parent column,
since it's the one above the quarter on the columns section here in hierarchy.
So what it's saying here is that,
for example,
for key one,
it's 7.6% in 2016 off the total sales for 2016.
And for Q two it was 32.63% off the total sales in 2016 and so on and so forth.
If you add the percentages for each quarter in 2016 here for key one key to Q three and Q
four,
you'll see here that we get a submission of,
ah,
100% under 100%.
It's basically this amount of sales here for 2000 and 16 and also here for 2016.
It's 60.36% off its parent column.
So the parent column is the grand total for all the years here,
which is this amount.
So here you can see here that 2017 the percentage of it is 39.64% of the parent calm.
And the parent column is this total some off sales amount,
which is this grand total.
That represents the grand total for all the columns here.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
for the percentage of parent column total.
Thanks for watching.
I'll see on the Net