in this video,
we're going to explain the percentage apparent total calculation.
So the percentage oh parent total calculation shows the cells percentage based on a chosen
parent or base field,
and the percentage is based on that particular field instead of using each fields immediate
parent.
So the main difference between this calculation and the percentage of parent throw total
calculation,
for example,
is that the calculation is based on a field that you can choose any other field that you
can choose instead of the calculation based on the field that is thean immediate parent off
your field.
So let's actually taken example here and have created a pivot table here with three
different calculations so that we can see the difference,
and this will make it easier for us to understand the concept.
So I've got a pivot table here where I've got the region and the product name and the sales
person on the roads section here,
and I've created three different calculations.
So,
first of all,
the percentage of grand total and we've seen this calculation before.
We've explained it on a previous video.
The percentage of grand total calculation is basically the percentage of the amount here,
which is the sales,
for example,
for Ivan Davis,
for product one in the Americas.
Okay,
so this is the amount here.
38,803.
So open 48% is the percentage of this amount 30,803 from the grand total,
which is eight million,
114,925.
So this is the percentage off the grand total.
It's opening 48% and then we have the percentage of the parent row total.
So what is the parent row here?
The parent row is basically the field that is just above the sales person here.
Right?
So this amount,
the amount of the sales 38,803 is the amount of the sales for that particular sales person
.
Which is Ivan Davis.
Right?
So what is the field just above it?
Here on the hierarchy,
on the roads section here,
the parent TRO is actually the product name,
right?
So this is the sales for Ivan Davis inside product one or the sales for Ivan Davis that he
sold how much he stole product 14 so it's 38,800 freeze.
So this is 17.63% off his sales for product one.
And that is in the Americas as well.
So 38,008.
So basically 38,803 is 17.63% of 220 1001 127 which is the sales for product one in the
Americas.
So it's basically dividing the amount by its parent row,
and the parent troll here is the product one.
And how can we determine the parent row?
It's the one just above it.
Here on the roads section.
This is the parent rope,
and we've explained the percentage of the parent row total on a previous video.
But I'm having here on the comparison so that you can easily understand the difference
between it and the percentage of parent total.
So all we've covered so far our calculations that we've covered on previous videos,
but where including them here so that you can easily understand the new calculation here.
So what is the new calculation?
It's the percentage of parent total,
so because you can choose the parent by yourself.
So I've chosen the parent here to be the region.
So how can I do that?
I'll actually remove this third calculation and reinserted again so that I can show you how
have done it.
So I'm gonna insert again another instance of the sales amount here.
I'm going to click on it,
go to value field settings here,
and then go to show values as.
And then instead of no calculation,
I'm going to select percentage apparent total calculation.
I'm going to select my parent as the region so that we would have the percentage of Ivan
Davis from the sales of the Americas,
for example.
So I'm going to change the name here.
2% of region total.
I'm gonna click.
OK,
Ok,
so what does this number represent?
2.63%.
This is the percentage of 38,803 from the region which is the Americas in this case
1,474,967.
So this number here represents stooping 63% off the percentage of sales in the Americas.
Where is actually this number which is the percentage of parent row totals the percentage
of the parent row.
So the row immediately above the sales person,
which is not the reason it's actually the products.
So this number represents 17.63% of the percentage off sales or product one.
And that is in the Americas.
Roles was not product one in the absolute,
its product one in the Americas.
Okay,
so I hope that I've been able to illustrate the difference between the two calculations,
which is the percentage of parent wrote total on the percentage of parent total.
Through this comparison,
I know it could be sometimes confusing,
but I think the comparison here,
in my opinion,
would be the best approach to show the difference between the two calculations.
So thanks guys watching this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.