and this video,
we're going to discuss the difference from calculation.
So the difference from calculation considers the difference of one value from another.
And the other value could be the value for the sales,
for example,
on the previous month or on the previous year.
So that's illustrate that with an example,
let's say I want to create a calculation here that would get me the difference between this
sales on a particular month and the sales on the previous month.
So I'm gonna insert another instance here of the sales amount,
and then I'm going to click on it,
go to value field settings here and then go to show values as on.
Instead of no calculation here,
I'm going to select difference from.
And as I said,
I want to create a calculation that would compare the sales on a particular month to the
sales on the month just before it.
So we're going to select the base field here as the sales month,
and then we're going to select previous so that we can get the sales difference between the
current month and the previous month.
And now I'm gonna rename this to difference between this month and previous month.
I'm gonna click OK here,
and as you can see here we get.
The results we get are the differences between the sales on the current month and the
previous month.
So,
for example,
here for February 2016 the sales was 29,549 and the bump previous to it,
which was January 2016.
It's 330,000 181 because here there's a $300,000 difference between February 16 end and
January 16 and you can see what the difference is in negative because January was greater
than February.
So it's This is current month minus previous month and is because here for Marsh sales was
122,000 189 and February US 29,000.
So differences 92 thousands a positive difference because Marsh,
the sales on Marsh was greater than this sales on February 2016 and we can do a bit of
custom member formatting here.
It's a good practice.
We can select the whole call him here,
press control and one on our keyboard to go to number formatting and the formatting is a
currency,
but we can actually color the negative numbers and red.
It's always a good practice so that we can easily distinguish the months where we had a
decline in sales so that they would stand out this way.
So now we've calculated the difference between the current bond and the previous month.
We can also calculate difference between the cells on the current year and the previous
year is well.
So if we insert another instance here of the sales amount and then click on it,
go to value field settings and then go to show values as instead of no calculation,
we're going to select difference from.
And then the base field here is gonna be the year and we're going to select previous and
then difference.
Between this year and previous year,
I'm gonna click,
OK,
and as you can see here,
we get the difference between this year and the previous year,
off course in 2016 because it's the earliest year on our data.
We don't have any data because we don't have a year on our data.
That is before 2016.
But here in 2017.
On January,
for example,
it's negative.
130,000,
So what does that mean?
That means that this is the difference between January 17 here and January 16.
So in January 17 the sales was 199,301 and in January 16 330,000 181.
So there was a decline of negative 130,000 880.
And this goes for February as well.
This is the difference.
150,803.
So February 17 the sales wills 150,000 more than the sales in February 16.
We can also do the same thing here for this column.
Do some custom number formatting.
So Arkan selected press control,
run our keyboard,
and then we can select the red color for negative numbers so that they would stand out as
well.
This is a good practice.
So as you can see here,
we could do the difference between this month in the previous month or different stream
this year and previous year,
and we can do the differences well between this month and the following month.
Okay,
so you can do the same if you click on any of them.
Value field settings.
Years show values as instead of previous you select next.
You can do that as well,
and you can do the difference between a particular year and this year.
So you can select to do the difference between this year and 2016.
For example,
not the previous year,
just 2016 in particular.
If we had had more years than two years.
So if you had add three or four years of data would have been able to compare,
for example,
2016 to 2000 and 14 in particular,
and so on and so forth.
So press cancel here,
and then we're gonna have another example here for comparing to a particular item.
So as you can see here,
we've got a pivot table where we have the region,
and then it's broken down into the different products and weaken.
Compare all the regions to a particular reason so we can compare all the regions to the
Americas,
for example,
so we can insert another instance year of the submission of the sales amount,
click on it,
value fuel settings,
show values as and then we're gonna select difference from.
And then the base field here is gonna be the region,
and we're going to compare everything to the Americas.
So we're going to compare Australia to the Americas,
Europe to the Americas.
And of course,
Americans to the Americans will be a zero because they're the same thing.
So we're gonna create a field here named difference between this region and America's.
For example.
On we're going to click OK,
here says you can see here we get the difference between Australia,
for example,
and the Americas.
So in Australia the sales were 1,266,446.
And in America's they were one million,
474,967.
So we get a difference year of negative 208,521 and it goes the same as well on a product
level.
But here the sales for product one in Australia was greater than the sales for product one
in America's.
So the difference here is a positive difference.
279,554.
So we're now comparing to a particular region so you can compare to a particular item or a
particular value.
So you can compare to a particular value is well,
not on Lee two,
previous or next.
Great.
So that's it,
guys,
for the difference from calculation.
Thank you very much watching this video I'll see on the next one.