Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to see how we can create a running total in pivot tables says you can see here
we get a pivot table here.
We've got the sales month spread across the columns,
and we got the year in the region here on the road section,
and we get the submission of sales amount on this emission of value section.
And what we want to do is to create a running total here across the months so that the
value on each month would represent the value of the sales year to date.
So the value of the sales so far in that particular year.
So,
for example,
January would have the value for the sales in January,
but February would have the value for the sales in January plus February on then.
Marsh would have the value for the sales in January,
plus Ribery plus marsh.
So it's a year to date value.
So to do that,
we're actually gonna insert another instance here off the sales amount on the submission of
Value section.
We're going to click on it,
go to value field settings here and then go to show values as and then on this menu,
Instead of no calculation,
we're going to select a running total in,
and then we have to select our base field.
So the base field is the field that we're gonna base our accumulation of values on.
So the field,
actually that we want the values to accumulate on is this sales month,
right?
Because we want January to have the value for January and then February to have the value
for January plus bribery and the marsh to have the value for January plus robbery plus
marsh So we're gonna base are accumulation of values here on this sales month,
and then we're going to give it a custom name.
So we're gonna write running total and then dash months and then we're gonna click,
OK,
and now let's examine what happens.
We're gonna take this row here for Europe in 2016 as an example.
So the submission of sales amount here in January is 244,946.
The running total is the same because so far in 2016 in Europe,
we've only been through January.
But then,
if you look at February.
The value for the sales in February is 29,549 and then the running total is actually the
value for the sales in January,
plus for every 274,495.
So it's basically this value plus this value value for January plus February and then Marsh
the sales in it World's 54,556.
But the running total is 329,000 and 51 which is the value for sales for Marsh plus
February plus January and so on and so forth.
So as you can see here,
we got a running total across the months.
We can also have a running total here across the reasons,
for example,
so that we would have the sales here for America's and then here in Australia would have
sales for Australia plus America's and then in Europe would have the sails for America's
plus Australia.
Plus,
you're so to do that,
we're gonna insert another instance here of the sales amount.
Click on it,
go to value field settings here,
go to show values as instead of no calculation.
We're going to select a running total in and then we have to select our base field here as
the region because we want the values to accumulate across the regions here.
And then we're gonna name this running total region and we're going to click.
OK,
and as you can see her on the running tool region,
we have the sales accumulating across the reasons.
So because here in the Americans in 2016 cells with zero on,
then in Australia it was 85,000.
So this the accumulation so far is 85,000.
But then here in Europe,
we have the accumulation of Europe plus Australia plus America's sales in Europe where
244,946.
But the value here in the running total you can see here it's 330,000 181.
So basically you can accumulate values across any field if you selected to be your base
field here.
So that's it,
guys,
for creating a running total in pivot tables.
Thank you so much for watching this video and I'll see on the next one