Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to see how we can create a percentage running total using pivot table.
So as we've seen on the PDS video,
we managed to create a running total.
But that was a value.
Now we can create a percentage running total where actually our sales were accumulate as
percentages,
and the percentage will be the sales so far in the year divided by the total sales for that
particular year.
So let's have an example here.
We're gonna actually insert another instance of the sales amount here into the submission
of value section and there were going to click on it,
go to value field settings and then go to show values as.
And then instead of no calculation,
we're going to select percentage running total in and the base field is gonna be the sales
month because we want our sales percentage to accumulate across the months until it reaches
100% at the end of the year,
which is gonna be in December.
So you will see that the percentage running total in December is going to be 100% and then
we will give it a custom Names is going to be percentage running total dash months and then
we're gonna click.
OK,
here.
So let's examine here.
What happened?
Let's see here the totals or the sub totals for 2016.
So,
as you can see here,
the sales in January 2016 was 330,181 and this represents a 20160.63% of the sales in the
hole 2016.
This is the percentage of running tools so far now.
In February,
sales were 29,549 and then percentage running total is 9.4%.
So this 9.4% represents basically sales for January plus sales for February,
divided by total sales in 2000 and 16 in the whole 2060 on then.
As you can see here,
the percentage of running total is going to keep on accumulating until it reaches 100% in
December 2016.
Because basically the values are being accumulated month over month until December 2060 so
December 2016 represents ah 100% and you can also accumulate values across any other field
that you want by changing your base field.
And we've seen that on the previous video and this video.
So that's it,
guys,
for the percentage running totals.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see you on the next one.