Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to explain the index calculation in pivot tables.
So the index calculation shows the relative weight of each cell when compared to its row
Total column total and grand total.
So it's taken example here.
Let's say that we have some money that we can invest in extra marketing for one of our
products in a particular region,
and you want to decide which product in which region should be invest in its marketing?
Should we invest in its marketing so that we get the most bang for buck for what we invest
in marketing?
The index calculation can help make the right decision.
So,
as you can see here,
we have a pivot table that shows us the sales for each of our products in the different
regions.
Now,
an initial intuition would suggest that we check which product has the high sales in which
region.
So someone could just highlight all the sales,
were over the products and create a heat map here,
going to conditional formatting color scales and create a heat map and the highest values,
the greenest and the highest in sales.
This product to in Europe.
So that's what we should invest in.
We should invest in extra marketing for product to in your Well,
let's see what the index calculation has to say.
I'm going to copy my pivot table here and paste it below,
and I'm gonna change the calculation on my pivot table.
I'm going to click on the submission of sales here,
go to value fees,
settings,
go to show values as and for the calculation.
I'm going to change it to index.
And I'm gonna change the name here to index and I'm gonna click,
OK,
And let's check our values year.
Our values should be around one,
and they shouldn't have a currency format.
They should have a number for months.
I'm just going to change the format here to a number with two decimal places.
So,
as you can see here,
the greenest value,
the highest value,
is actually for product three in the Americas.
So that's what the index calculation is suggesting.
It is suggesting that we invest in product three in the Americas that we do extra marketing
for product three in the Americas so sickens here.
The index for product three is 2.12 and the index calculation would deal.
The number that is around the one it could be less than a one could be more than one or
could be a one,
depending on the value and the higher the value.
Basically,
the more weight this value has in the array of values that we have in the pivot tables on
the higher the value,
the more weight this value has in our pivot table.
Now let's actually see what the formula for the index is.
So the formula for the index is actually the value in the cell multiplied by the grand
total,
divided by the row total multiplied by the column.
Tal.
So,
for example,
here for product three in the Americas,
it's 2.12.
That's because the calculation here is value in the cell.
So product in America's This is the value in the cell 1,165,659 and then multiplied up by
the grand total.
What's the Grendel?
It's this value here,
6,589,000 and 66.
So this is the grand tool,
and what's the row total for product three in the Americas.
The total for the whole row is 1,474,967.
That's the road oval,
and what's the column totaled?
Column total here is two million,
452,000 and 43.
So that's the column total here for the comb containing product three in the Americas.
As you can see here,
the index is 2.12.
So this is the calculation for the index.
The calculation for the index usually yields a number that is either greater than one or
less than one.
And the higher the number,
the more weight this value has in the pivot table with respect to the other values or
compared to the other values.
And as we saw in the formula,
setting the value in the cell aside,
the index would depend on the grand total row total and column total for that particular
value.
Also,
if you think about it,
the sales for product three in the Americas So this value is actually 48% out off the
column total,
So it's 48% out of the sails for product.
Three in all,
the other regions.
So about half of the sales that we do for product three worldwide is done in the Americas
or happens in the Americas.
So it's a considerable amount.
Also,
this sales for product three in the Americas represents about 79% off this sales for all
the products in the Americas,
and the sales for product three in the Americas represents about 18% off all of our sales
worldwide,
says also in considerable amount.
So as we demonstrated here,
the index calculation can help us in decision making.
So that's it,
guys,
for the index calculation,
I hope you found this video useful.
Thank you for watching,
and I'll see on the next one.