Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to see how weaken Group by texts fields and let me show you an example here.
So we've got a private table here,
and I'm gonna put our regions here on the road section and you can see here we've got our
regions Africa,
Americas,
Australia and Europe.
And let's say I want to divide these regions into Central and East and West,
for example.
So for me,
because I live in Canada,
so my East is gonna be Africa and Europe.
So I'm gonna click on Africa and then hold the control button and click on Europe.
And then I'm going to right click here,
go to group.
And as you can see here now,
Africa and Europe have been put into Group one.
I can actually rename the group into east,
and then you can see here America's is put into a group called America's.
I can rename that into Central,
and then I'm gonna rename Australia into West since Australia is on my west as a live in
Canada.
So as you can see here,
I've been able to divide my reasons year into three categories.
East Central and West,
and a Zika is here.
There's another field that has been created on the row section here called Region to,
and we can use that field actually to use our new Divisions Year East Center on West so I
can first start by renaming that other field called Region to.
So I'm going to click on it,
go to field settings here,
and I can just rename it to my reasons,
for example,
and I'm going to click OK,
here.
So now I have the My Regions field and I can move it actually to the column section if I
want to,
and I can drag now.
My sales amount here into the value section and,
as you can see her,
have been able to slice and dice my data with my new reasons.
As you can see,
her Africa and Europe half Onley values in east because they are in the East region and
America's has only values in Central because it's on the central region on Australia has
only values in the West because it's on the West reason.
So that's it,
guys for grouping by text fields,
so you're able to create your additional custom groups here in pivot tables.
One more thing,
actually,
is that the new field that we've created,
which is Mother My reasons field is not part off.
My original data is just in the pivot cash.
So we don't have a column here called my region or a column for our new regions or new
divisions.
It's only stored in memory.
So it's like a virtual column,
basically.
So thanks,
guys,
for watching I'll see on the next one.