Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to see how we can group by time.
Using pivot tables Says you can see here.
I've got a sales data set and a spurt of the daily said we get the transaction times which
time of the day the sails transaction happened.
And let's say that we want to create a pivot table in order to some our sales by our so
that we know which hour of the day we have the most sales on.
So to do that,
I'm gonna insert a new pivot table.
Here's insert pivot table,
and I'm gonna insert it onto the pivot cheat here,
and I'm gonna click OK here to insert my pivot table.
And now I'm gonna put the transaction time here on the road section,
and I'm gonna put my sales amount on the submission of Value Section.
As you can see air because I'm using Excel 3 65 XL actually has automatically grouped my
transaction time by hours and minutes.
Usually,
this doesn't happen in earlier versions of Excel and to do the grouping.
You right click here on the transaction Time column here and then click on group here.
As you can see here,
Excel is currently grouping by hours and minutes and seconds.
But I just need to group by hours because I wouldn't be grouping by minutes or seconds.
That's too much granularity for me.
I just want a group by our and you could also tell Excel,
which starting our you need the grouping to start from and which ending our You need the
grouping to end at as well.
So if you click ok here.
As you can see here,
I managed to group by our So basically,
this is the submission of sales that happened on the first hour of the day,
which is 302,937.
Let's actually give some number formatting here to our data.
So if I go to analyze and then select entire pivot table and then select the values on a
right click and click on form,
it sells here,
I can select the currency.
So say I'm going to select the US dollars and I'm gonna click.
OK,
here.
As you can see here we have a currency.
So basically,
on the first hour of the day,
we have 302,937 2nd hour of the day,
256,853.
So,
as it is here,
we can know which our the day we had the most sales on.
So if he actually go to the data top here,
and then we could assert our data by the highest our.
So basically,
around 1 p.m. we had the most sales.
Now,
sometimes you would see the hours in a MPM format instead of a 24 hour format,
and this actually depends on the date and time settings on your computer.
So if you right click here on the clock at the bottom right corner of your screen,
I'm using Windows 10 and clean click on a just date and time to go to your date and time
settings.
You click on change date and time format and then,
actually it depends on the short time format here,
and it's a big glitchy,
actually doesn't work well all the time,
so usually this should yield an E M P M format,
but actually,
the format I have here is a 24 hour format here on the pivot table.
It's a bit glitchy,
and it doesn't always follow it correctly,
but the format of the hours on the pivot table should actually usually follow your date and
time format settings.
But it's a bit glitchy is it doesn't always work well,
so for the 24 hour format,
you should actually have this selection here,
although I'm having this election,
which should yield in a MPM format.
But anyways,
if you need to change the format between 24 hour and AM PM is actually through your date on
time settings on your operating system here on Windows.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
for grouping by time.
Thank you so much for watching this video I'll see on the next one.