this video.
We're going to see how we congrats by half years.
So as you can see here,
I've got my pivot table and I've got the sales month on the road section and I've got the
summation of value section here having this sales amount.
And let's say I want to grew by half year.
That is,
I want to put the 1st 6 months of the year in a group and then the 2nd 6 months of the year
in another group.
So to do that,
I'm just going to select my 1st 6 months right click and then click on group here.
And if you consider they've been put in a group called Group One,
I can change its name here.
So I'm gonna name it first half,
for example.
And then I can select the second group of months here the last six months of the year,
Right Click group and said that group,
too,
And then name it second half.
And now I have two groups and I can see the totals here for Group one.
So for the 1st 6 months and then the total for the 2nd 6 months,
or the for the lost six months,
and here you can see here it's a field that is only in the pivot table cash.
It's called sales month to I can remove the sales month and it could see the first half and
second half.
If I need to change the name,
I can click on it,
go to field settings and then I can rename it Year Half,
for example and click.
OK,
so now I've been able to group my data by first half and second half.
And if I need to own group my data,
I can select my group's year right click and then UN group to UN group my data.
I'm gonna press control and Z here to go back to my groupings.
So that's it,
guys on how to group by half years.