and this video,
we're going to see how to group our dates by weeks.
Starting on a certain day Says you can see here.
I've got the order date here on the road section and the submission of sales amount on the
submission of Value Section.
Unless,
say,
when a group my dates by weeks,
that start on a Monday.
So I'd want to group here my dates into seven days that start on a Monday.
So to do that,
I'm going to right click here on the dates and then click on group.
And as it is here,
the first date here on my data is actually the 10th of January if I check the 10th of
January 2016.
So if I go to my calendar here and check 10th of January 2016 as you can see here,
10th a junior 2016 is a Sunday.
But this,
according to my grouping,
or according to the grouping that I want to apply,
would belong to the week starting on Monday,
the Fourth of January.
So it actually want to change my grouping here to start on the fourth at January 2016.
Because That is the week starting on a Monday that the first date on my data belongs to,
and I want to select here to group by days,
and the number of days is going to be seven.
Of course,
if you want your weeks to start on a different day other than a Monday,
then you could choose the Tuesday or Wednesday.
So if you want our weeks to start on Tuesday,
then would choose the fifth of January in this case.
And if you want them to start on Wednesdays,
then would choose the sixth of January and so on and so forth.
So after selecting days here and number of days seven days,
I'll click.
OK,
and as you can see here,
I managed to group my dates into weeks starting on Monday's.
So That's it,
guys for grouping by dates starting on a certain day.
Thank you so much Watching this video also on the next one