in this video,
we're going to show you some issues that you might face when trying to group dates on your
pivot table.
Says because here,
I've got this pivot table and I've got the order date here on the world section and a sum
of sales amount on the Submission of Value Section.
And I'm gonna try to group my dates here it or so right click and then group.
And as you can see here,
I get an error.
Cannot group that seduction.
And the reason for that is that I've got some inappropriate data arm Lee date column.
So if I check my order date column here,
for example,
this value here,
this is actually a text value of the date.
So this looks like a date,
but it's actually not a date.
If I check here the number formatting Eakins here,
it's actually giving me the same formatting for all because it's actually a text.
And there is no number because,
you know,
if it is actually a date,
it will give me the value of that date under this number here.
So this is not a date.
This is just a text.
I could even test it with the is text function here.
That gives me a true if this is a text and sure enough,
I get a troop.
So this is a text naughty date,
so I can actually fix it by just typing in the date like this.
And this one is fixed Now,
now,
some other issues here,
for example,
this is an error value and you could Sierra's Well,
I've got here instead of a date of got pull.
So as you can see here,
these air some of the issues that you might face because you've got inappropriate data on
the order Date column This column supposed to have only dates.
So in order to detect these values,
an easy way to do it is to highlight the whole column and press control and g on your
keyboard for go to and then click on Special here,
go to special and then you could check for constants Are numbers or texts or logical or
errors.
Actually,
we don't want to check for numbers because our dates are actually numbers,
so we don't want to check for that.
We want to check for text,
logic,
ALS and errors.
And if we click OK here,
because here we managed to select these values.
The are not axity numbers.
We could highlight thumb by filling the color here and his guys here.
We managed to highlight them by yellow and we could start changing them.
So this one,
for example,
is the date in July 2016.
So I'm just gonna write any day tear.
So,
for example,
six of July,
2000 and 60.
And this one is well here.
So this is a date in January 2017.
So I could just write the seventh of January 2017 for example,
and so on and so forth.
And then I could just remove the filling here and no Phil and no Phil here as well.
And we don't have any other values,
and it could do move.
The Phil here is well on the header off the column.
So as you can see here,
I'm trying to show you the issues that you might face when trying to group dates.
It's mainly because of inappropriate data types on that particular date column.
So that's it,
guys,
for this video.
Thank you so much watching.
I'll see on the next one