We've got this pivot table here where we have the order date on the world section and we
get the summer sales amount on the submission of Value Section.
And let's say that we group these dates here by 70.
So we right click,
go to group and then we select a zier and we select the number of these to be seven,
and we click.
OK,
so you will notice here that there are some weeks the are missing.
So,
for example,
here the week from 27th of March 2016 up until the second of April,
2016 it's missing.
And the reason that it's missing is that we don't have any transactions happening on the
dates of this particular week.
So in order to show missing data here,
we can actually go to our field here.
So click on it,
go to feel settings,
and then we can go to layout and print,
and then we take here,
show items with no data,
and we click.
OK,
here.
So now we're gonna be able to show the items with no data.
Another way to get to that.
You can right click here and then go to feel settings Goto Leo in print and we get to the
same option here.
So we managed now to show the items with no data.
We could also show zeros on these items since they don't have any sales.
So we might as well display them a zero.
We could right click here,
go to pivot table options and that for empty cells show a zero and click.
OK,
so there you go.
This is how you can show items on a field with no data.
So there you go.
This is how you can show items on a field with the data and also replace the missing values
with zeros,
for example,
or any other value that you would like.