So let's speak about sorting in pivot tables.
So to do your basic sorting and pivot tables in ascending or descending order,
there are multiple ways to achieve that.
So the first way is that if you need to start a certain field,
you could go here to the pivot table fields and click on this arrow here and then sort,
for example,
a to Z or Z two A's so by ascending or descending orders.
So if you click A to Z here,
you're going to sort in ascending order,
and you could look Z to a You're gonna sort in descending order or searching the product
names so you can see your product for Comes first.
Now when sorting in descending order and then product three,
etcetera,
etcetera.
Another way to do it is to make sure you select a cell in the field that you need to sort,
and then you can right click and click on sort here and sort eight z or Z to a.
So put it back to an A to Z sort here and 1/3 way to do it,
as well as to go to the data time on the ribbon well,
selecting a cell inside the field that you need to sort and then you consort using thes two
buttons here,
so a to Z or Z to a You can also certainly aggregated field here the submission of sales
amount.
But you can't sort it.
Using the pivot table feels here using this arrow here.
He won't give you the option to sort.
But you can use the other two ways.
Right?
Click sort,
so largest to smallest,
for example,
or you consort using the data time on the ribbon A to Z.
This is smallest to largest as well as you can see here.
We're now sorting by the values in our aggregated field,
which is the submission of sales amount.
You could also sort to subtitles the same way,
right?
Click sort.
And you could also use data time on the ribbon to sort in ascending or descending order.
So if I sort for example,
but in descending order here,
you can see her.
We're sorting now by our sub total on the quarter says you can see here we have the high
scooter in terms of sales at the top and then the next one and then the next one,
etcetera,
etcetera.
Okay,
guys.
So that's it for the basic sorting in pivot tables will be discussing Mawr advanced sorting
in the upcoming videos.
Thank you so much for watching I'll see on the next one.