another way of sorting is sorting an item role from left to right.
So here we've got a pivot table where I have the product name here on the road section.
We've got the year on the columns section and we've got the summer sales amount on the
submission of Value Section and let's say when a sort the pivot table from left to right
according to product four in a descending order.
So what I want to do is to have the whole pivot table sorted in descending order according
to the submission of sales amounts in product for So if we do that and so it from left to
right in descending order,
we should expect the value for 2017 to come here on the left and then the value for 2016 to
go here on the right.
And of course,
this will happen toe only other values.
But everything is sorted in a left to right fashion in a descending order according to the
row for product for So let's see that in action.
If I right click here,
go to sort and then more sort options,
I'm going to sort largest to smallest and left to right.
So here,
as you can see her on the summary,
it says sort year by some of sales amount in descending order using values in this row.
What is the role I'm going to sort on its product?
Four.
So it's the role on product for that is going to be the center of my sorting basically for
the whole pivot table.
Now let's click OK and see what happens here.
As you can see here,
I sorted everything according to product four in a descending order left to right.
So as you can see her,
it moved 2017 to the left and 2016 to the right because of sorting on product four left to
right.
So this is how you consort according to UN items row