He could also sort your pivot tables according to a custom list.
So here I've got my pivot table here where I have the region on the road section and we get
the submission sales amount here on submission of value section.
Now,
as you can see here,
the region field is sorted in ascending order alphabetically.
So America's comes first Australia and then Europe.
Now let's say I want to change the order here so that I'd have America's first and then
Europe and then Australia.
So to do this,
I need to create a custom list.
And to do that,
I'm just gonna put the names of my regions here in a list.
Just gonna copy and then paste values like this greater list.
So Australia is gonna be in the third position here,
and Europe is going to be in this second position.
So this is my custom list that is not sorted in ascending order alphabetically,
it's just sorted according to my liking.
Now,
I need to create a custom list out of this list.
So to do that,
I'm gonna go to file,
I'm going to go to options,
and then I'm gonna go to advanced here,
and I'm going to scroll down to the general section under advance.
So here's the general section.
I'm going to click on Edit Custom lists here,
and then I'm going to create a new list and my new list is gonna be from the cells,
and then I'm going to click on import to import menu list.
Here is my new list.
My custom list.
I'm gonna click,
Okay?
And then I'm gonna click OK,
again.
So now I have my customer list created now to apply this custom missed.
You can just right click here on a pivot table and then click on refresh.
And if it still doesn't get applied,
you can right click again and then sort a to Z.
And you can see here that the custom list has been applied here.
So as you can see here,
we've got the Americas and the In Europe and in Australia,
the items here on the region field are sorted according to my custom list that I created.
Now what happens if I sort in a descending order instead of an ascending order?
So right Click Sort sort Z to a he concedes it's sorted.
According to my custom list,
but in a descending order.
So I have Australia here.
That was the bottom.
I got it.
I got it at the top.
And then America's years at the bottom in Europe is still in the middle,
so it basically inverted my custom list here.
Now,
if you refresh your pivot table and you've done sorting in ascending or descending order,
and you still find that your custom list is still not applied,
then what do you need to do is to right click here and then go to sort goto more sort
options and then click on more options here and make sure that this odor sort is sticked.
So make sure that this older sort check boxes checked sort automatically every time the
report is updated and click.
OK,
so that's it,
guys,
for sorting,
according to a custom list that you would great,
Thank you so much for watching this video I'll see on the next one