Okay,
so that's speak a bit about the layout and structure of a pivot table.
So as we agreed before,
the best thing to do when creating a pivot table is to first grade a table from our data.
So with greater the table here from our data and to insert a pivot table,
we've seen that multiple times on the course.
But let's do it one more time here so you can actually go to the insert and then pivot
table here,
or you can go to design.
And there is another option,
actually,
for inserting a pivot table,
which is summaries with pivot table.
So either of those would work says you can see here Excel managed to highlight all of our
data automatically inside the table.
So we're gonna insert a pivot table on you,
worksheet.
We're going to click.
Okay,
here and now we've created our pivot table.
Now,
as you can see here,
we've got our pivot table tools at the top while we are inside our pivot table.
But if we step outside our pivot table,
you can see here that the two tops under the pivot table tools have disappeared.
So in order to view these two tubs,
which are the analyzing designed top you need to be inside your pivot table.
You can actually also change the name of your pivot table.
So here are Pivot Table has a name pivot table one.
We can actually change its name.
I'd like to give my pivot tables a prefects,
which is PVT so PVT.
We can call it PVT.
Sales,
for example.
And now with changed the name of our pivot table on the right hand side with our pivot
table field Spain.
And this is where we get to manipulate and play with the fields of our pivot table.
And you can actually show or hide the pivot table fields by stepping inside your pivot
table.
First,
they need to select a cell inside your pivot table and then here under the analyze tab on
the ribbon.
There is a few list button here so you can toggle between the pivot table fields,
appearing and disappearing using that button.
Now let's explain the anatomy or the structure of a pivot table.
So on a pivot table,
we've got four areas that weaken drag fields into them.
So we've got the filter's area we've got the columns area,
We got the rails area and we've got the submission of values area or the values area.
So basically,
any feels that we drag into the filter's area will be on the top left corner of our pivot
table,
and any feels we dragged to the columns area will be on the horizontal area over pivot
table at the top.
They will be laid out horizontally,
and any feels that we put in the Rose area will be on the left hand side of our pivot table
,
and any feels that we put in the values area will be in the middle off the pivot table.
Now,
let's create a quick pivot table here out of our data.
So I'm gonna put the customer field here on the filters and I'm gonna put the year on the
columns.
I'm gonna put this sales person field in the row section and I'm gonna put the sales
amounts in the submission of value section.
So there you go.
We've created our first pivot table,
and in future videos,
we're gonna learn more about manipulating our pivot tables