in this video,
we're going to discuss label filters or text filters.
So here we've got a pivot table of get the salesperson on the road section and the sum of
sales amount on the submission of value section.
And we can apply some label filters or text filters here,
and the label filters air basically gonna be applied to the rule labels.
So the sales person field here.
So if you go here level filters,
we can see your first filters equals and equals means that you've got to put the exact
value they need to filter for,
so I can filter,
for example,
for our first sales person here are doing Burton,
and the filter is actually not case sensitive.
And so,
if I type it here as lower case letters press OK,
you can see here we're able to filter a press control and see here to a moment filter.
There's also under the filter here,
which is does not equal to so filter for everything except add GN Burton sofa press.
Okay,
Here it will filter off Adrian Burton and it will keep that the other sales persons all
press control Z here to remove my filter.
And then our next filter here is begins with So begins with is a filter where you could
filter with a value that begins with this value they're gonna put so I can filter for all
people beginning with an A,
for example.
So here it will give me Adrianne and Alison and so on and so forth.
So this filters here with a value that begins with the value that you put into the filter.
And also there is does not begin with.
So people not beginning within a so anyone whose name does not begin within a press.
Okay,
here.
So,
as you consider we filtered off the people who begin within a and the other people are the
ones here who appear on our filter press control Z here.
And then the next filter here is ends with so ends with a certain value so I can end with t
o.
And for example,
and this will give me Burton and Newton's because these people's names and with a t o n a
press concerns e here and then our next filter here is does not end with so does not end
with is basically the reverse off ended with costo and all people know ending with a t o n
.
Chris controls here to remove the filter and then we've got contains.
So the contains filter is basically a filter for values that contain the value that I'm
gonna enter here.
So,
for example,
people who have a y e n in their name press okay,
here it's only Bobby going.
He's the only one who has a Y E and in his name and then does not contain is people who do
not contain,
for example,
this value so do not contain T.
O n.
So anyone who doesn't continue to you and so all these people press control NZ here.
So basically,
this is how you can filter text values on pivot tables.
Now there are also more options here which are basically greater than or equal to unless
then in between or not between.
So these options were going to use when we have values the r e mix of numerical on text
values,
and we'll see that on the next video