in this video,
we're going to discuss the filtration of numerical text values or alpha numeric values.
So here on our data set,
we've got a column.
They school the item number,
and this column consists of a mix of numbers and text.
So here you can see the item number.
For example,
101 Tripoli and the force of from four DF.
So this is basically a mix of numbers and alphabets,
so this could be an item number.
It could be a barcode.
It could be anything.
So I'm gonna go here to my pivot tab and you could see her.
We've got a pivot table,
get the item number on the world section and the summer sales amount on this emission of
value section.
And to filter that,
we're gonna filter using the label fitters.
And we're going to use these options here greater than grid unequal to less than less than
or equal to between and not between.
So that's sorry,
the greater than option,
for example here.
So I'm gonna filter for anything greater than 10 to triple A and let's see what we get.
In the result,
click OK here and is it sincere.
We got all the item numbers that start with numbers greater than 102 But we also got 102
triple Z.
So why is that?
This is because it filters for numbers,
and it also filters using the alphabet.
So because the Triple Z's in the alphabet are considered higher values in the alphabet,
right,
because Z letter is a later letter than the A letter,
so it's considered of a higher value.
So it's filtered for that as well,
on the greater that.
So it filters for both numbers and texts.
So this is a great way to filter Alfa and numerical values.
And of course,
the same applies to all the other options year.
So this is gonna be greater than or equal to say will include the window to Triple A.
They use that less than less than or equal to between between two values and not between
two values.
So as you can see her,
the idea here is that if filters using both numbers and alphabets,
so it considers both the numbers and the letters in its filters,
that's it.
Guys for alpha and numeric filters or numerical text value filters.
Thank you so much for watching this video I'll see on the next one