and this video,
we're going to speak about filtering values in pivot tables.
Cizikas here.
We've got a pivot table here.
We got the order date on the road section and some sails around on the submission of value
section.
And here we can filter the values on the submission of sales amounts.
So if you press here too,
go to our filters and then go to value filters.
And as you can see here,
we've got equals is not equal to greater than greater than equal to less than less than or
equal to between,
not between and top.
Then So,
for example,
we could do greater than 100,000.
So we'll see the days when we had orders that were greater than ah,
100,000 Click.
OK,
here you can see here we get the days where we had sales greater than 100,000.
We could do as well less than so less than 30,000 for example.
So these are the days where we had less than 30,000 and we consort,
of course,
after doing the filter so we consort smallest to largest,
largest to smallest.
Any gun to sort that we would like we could also do between and not between.
So between 50,000 for example and 100,000 press.
Okay,
here.
So these air the orders between 50,000 and 100,000.
Now,
on the next video,
we're gonna discuss the top 10 option.