and this video,
we're going to see how we can filter for the top or bottom percentage in a pivot table.
So here we've got a pivot table and we've got the retailer column on the road section and
get this summer sales amount on this submission of value section.
And if you click here to do a filter on going,
go to value filters,
go to top,
then we can actually filter by the top or bottom 10 items or percent or some.
In this case,
we're going to choose percent,
and we're going to choose your bottom,
and we're gonna filter for,
Let's say,
the bottom 25% off our retailers to determine the worst performing retailers and take
appropriate action with them.
So if repress okay,
here were able to filter for the bottom 25% in terms of performance here in terms of sales
,
and we can even sort that so we'd know the smallest,
for example.
So we consort smallest the largest,
so it no,
the lowest performing one here would have at the top,
and this way we can take the necessary action with them in order to improve their
performance