in this video,
we're going to discuss the top or bottom some filter for filtering pivot tables.
So here we've got a pivot table.
We have the retailer on the world section and the sum of sales amount on the submission of
Value section.
And if you click on this button here and go to value filters and then go to top,
then you could see her.
We've got our top time filter and we can select some here,
and this will actually give us the top items in our role labels that have a certain
summation.
So if we select top from here and then we can select,
for example,
the top retailers who have a sales amount that some up to three million,
So 3123456 So three million red press.
Okay,
here and here.
It will give us the top 10 retailers that have sales that some up to three million off
course,
because here we have retailers that some up to three million the are less than 10 so they
shouldn't necessarily be 10.
If the pivot table finds that we can achieve three million with less than 10 retailers,
then it will only show you these retainers the are less than 10.
So here is only showing us seven retailers because it managed to get up to the some off
three million with less than 10 retailers.
And,
of course,
you could do the bottom retailers that sum up to a certain amount as well.
And this is how this filtration feature work.