in this video,
we're going to discuss faltering boy Report filters in pivot tables so you can actually
filter your pivot table using the report Filter's area here.
So you simply drag a certain field toe.
The report filter,
and that means that you can filter by that particular field.
So when you drag a field to the airport filter.
So,
for example,
if I dragged the product name here,
you can see her that it's appeared at the filter's area at the top here.
So when you drag a field to this area,
it appears at the top of the pivot table and using that you can actually filter your pivot
table.
So here,
if I click on this arrow here beside product,
you can see I can filter by product one click.
OK,
so that means that the information or the results here shown on the pivot table are for
only product one.
And this way I can filter for only product one.
I can also select multiple items.
If I check this check box and select part one and product to,
for example,
I can select all the products using this old check box,
I can uncheck all on that select product one and product to Onley impress.
Okay,
this means now that the results here are for product one I'm product to and you can build
upon these filters.
You can select one or more customers,
for example,
because elect one customer here only Millennium Inc and press.
OK,
so that means that the results here showed on a pivot table offer products on a product to
and for millennium.
So now you've excluded Oh,
the other customers.
And if excluded,
product three.
You can also filter using this search part,
but you need to make sure to select multiple items before you use the filter.
And here this is a sales month.
So it contains my months stacks.
So,
for example,
filter for months ending U A r y So in this case is gonna be January and February.
So here I've got a check box.
Select old search results.
Yes,
I need these two months to be selected.
Press okay,
and I will see the results for only January and February.
But in my case here,
there is no data for January and February for Millennium Inc.
But maybe if I select another company here.
So at to life,
I don't have results.
Visionary,
I do have results for January and February.
I could also add more items to my filters here.
So for example,
I currently have January and February selected.
I can add the months the end in e.
R,
for example.
So select e r.
And then you can see her.
I will have September,
October,
November,
December in the search results.
I can actually add the current selection to filter and select all search results.
So I want to select all these search results and I want to add them to the current
selection as well.
So press OK.
And now if we check off filters here,
you can see her.
I've got January and February,
and I've got these months here that ended in e r.
Number October,
November December.
Add it to my filters.
So these results here are for September,
October,
November and December and Virginia in February.
And for product one and two.
And for all the customers,
older regions,
all the service persons,
of course,
that I can apply filters for any other field that I would have here in the filter's area.
So the filter's area and in older Excel versions as well you'd see called Report Filter
contains the fields that I need to filter mike pivot table with.
OK,
so that's it,
guys for the report filters.
Thank you so much watching,
I'll see on the next.