in this video,
we're going to show different ways or shortcuts to apply filters to your pivot tables.
So the first way is using the pivot table feels,
and you can show or unshowy Oh,
the pivot table fields,
talk of them on and off.
If you click on the analyze time on the ribbon here and then this button here feel list,
I can show or hide the field this on the pivot tables.
So if you click on any arrow here on the pivot table fields,
you can see here that you're able to do filters and the filter options you will see here
are going to depend on the type of values here that we have on the field.
So on the sales amount,
we've got some numbers,
right?
But if you click here on the order date,
which is a field that contained states,
you can see here we've got date filters instead of label food.
So the type of filters that you're gonna be able to apply are gonna be dependent on the
data type of that particular field.
The second way to create filters is to right click on a pivot table field here on the pivot
table.
So I'm bright clicking on the retailer field and you can see her.
We've gets infiltration options,
and I want to show you these two options here.
Keep on Lee selected items and height selected items.
So,
for example,
if I highlight the 1st 3 supermarkets here and right click and then go to Filter,
I can keep on Lee the selected items so I can keep only these three supermarkets press
control NZ to undo my filter.
Annika.
Also right click go to Filter and then hide the selected items so I'll keep all the other
supermarkets and hide these items says you can see here these air some extra filtration
options that we had not discussed before my first control NZ here again to undo all my
filters.
And then the third way is the way that we were easing before using the pivot table headers
here.
So this header here you click on it and you can start applying your filters.
And if you can't see this header for any reason you go to the inner life,
stop here and because here it we've got a button here for tumbling on and off the field
headers.
So if you click on that button,
it doubles it off.
Click on it again.
It doubles on.
Okay,
so these were different ways that we can apply filters to our pivot tables.