and this video,
we're going to discuss filtering using Walt cards in pivot tables.
So we will be discussing three wild cards here.
The asterisk and question mark and the tilde.
So the first wall card here,
the Astra's.
It's basically a placeholder for any number of characters.
So if we filter using Jell O and then Astra's this so foot filter with begins with yellow
and then asterisk,
this will give us all the companies that begin with a Jell O and then any number of
characters.
So if you go to a pivot table here and they go to label Filters begins with G.
L O Astra's and Notice here that I'm writing Jello in lower case letters.
Although the companies would have upper case letters because searching with wild cards is
not case sensitive.
And if we press okay here,
you can see here that we get the companies that start with the Jell O and then a number of
characters.
We could also do a filter that is contains Astra Stack.
So this will give us the company's having their name containing any number of words before
deck.
So for go here,
too,
our label footers and then Duke contains.
And then ask stressed Tech and click OK,
here,
you can see here we get the companies that contain the word tech with any number of
characters before them.
And the were tech here because we use the contains filter does not have to be at the end of
the company's name.
So because here advanced that company has the word tech in the middle,
and it has company after,
so it doesn't have to be at the end off the company name.
We could also do a filter that is equals.
And then Asterisk Inc asked us so we could also do a filter that is equals Asterisk Inc
asterisk.
So this will give us the companies that their name contains I N.
C in any position anywhere.
So if we do that label filters here and then equals Astra's I N C.
Astra's and click OK,
here you can see here we get the companies that their name contains i N.
C.
In any position.
So Capstan Inc cutting edge ink.
So the 1st 4 companies here contain Inc at the end.
But this one here incorporated ABC company.
This one has i n C at the beginning,
So this will give us the company's having their names containing i n.
C.
At any position.
Now let's check the question mark Placeholder.
So the question mark placeholder is a placeholder for one character or variable.
So the presence of the question mark means that it would replace Onley.
One character and this character could be any letter or number,
and it could be even a space.
So if we filter for contains a question mark,
see,
we would get the companies that contain the combination of A and that any character or
letter or space and then seek Sophie Do that here contains a question mark C and click OK,
here we get the companies that the names contained A and then any letter or number or space
and see.
So as you can see your ABC Telecom Arc Telecom,
these do contain be on our respectively.
Instead of the question mark here in the position of the question Mark and then
incorporated ABC company,
we got ABC there on mantra and on this mentor company notice here it's a and then space and
then see between the two parts of the company name mantra and company would get a and then
space and then seek and then on advanced that company.
We've got the A N.
C part here on Advanced.
This is what made it appear in the filter.
Now let's speak about the asterisk,
and while you probably wouldn't use it a lot,
it's useful to know what it does.
The asterisk is an escape character,
so that means that you can use it to put a literal asterisk as well or search for a literal
asterisk in the company's name.
So here,
if we search with contains Astra's Tilda Astra's,
this means that we're actually searching for a literal asterisk in the company's name.
So there is a company here that is named asterisk and that a literal asterisk.
So if I search with that label,
filters contains and then asters Tilda asterisk and click OK here.
So this means that I'm searching for any number of characters before a literal asterisk,
and you probably wouldn't use that a lot,
but it's just useful to know that.
So that's it,
guys for filtering using Walt cards.
Thanks so much watching.
I'll see on the next one