and pivot tables,
you're able to apply filters using multiple fields.
So on this pivot table here we have the region and the product name on the road section and
the summer sales of On the Submission of Value Section.
Now we can apply filters using the region and using the product name at the same time.
So,
for example,
here I can click on this field header.
And then,
as you can see here,
I've got the selected field as the product name.
I'll just switch that to the region,
and then I can apply a value filter toe filter for regions that had values and that that
means the sales.
So it that had some of sales amount greater than 1.5 million.
So if I click OK,
here,
you can see here.
The date on the pivot table has been filtered for regions that had sales greater than 1.5
million,
and in this case,
it was only Europe that had sales greater than 1.5 million.
I could also go ahead and click on the field headers again and apply another filter using
the product name so I can go here.
Value filters greater than or equal to.
And I can apply filters for products to have sales greater than one million.
So I can do that here greater than or equal to one million and click OK here and is the
cause here.
I've been able to filter for products afterwards that had sales greater than or equal to
one million,
and in this case,
it filtered off product.
Three under year says he can see where we're able to apply value filters using multiple
fields in pivot tables.
Now,
if you need to clear these filters,
you can clear them one by one by clicking on the field header and make sure you select the
field that you need to clear the filter from and then click on clear filter.
And if you need to clear all filters at once,
you can select your pivot table,
go to the data time on the ribbon and then click on this clear button here to clear all the
filters on your pivot table.
OK,
so that's it,
guys,
for applying filters,
using multiple fields in pivot tables at the same time.
I think it's so much watching this video I'll see on the next one