Okay,
so that's speak a bit more about the field list.
So another way to show on hide your field list is to actually right.
Click on your pivot table here and then click on Hyatt Field List,
and you can also right click again and then show your field lists and us another way to
show on high.
Do you feel list?
In addition to using the fuel list button here under the anal,
I stab on the ribbon.
If you need to move your field list,
you can actually click on this arrow here and then click on move,
and then you can start dragging and dropping your field list anywhere on the screen.
If you need to dock it back to the right hand side of the screen,
you can just click and drag the field list year to the very right Hindsight and then Excel
will dock it automatically for you.
Another way to docket after you move it.
So start moving again is to actually double click on it,
and this will also docket back to the right and site.
If you need to resize your field list,
you can click on this arrow here and then click on size and you can start re sizing it.
You can also move your mouse cursor to the edge of the fuel list,
and you will be converted to these two opposing arrows so you can just click and drag to
resize your field lists.
Also on our field list,
we've got different views that we can choose from.
So here you can click on this gear icon here that says Tools.
And then you have different views for you feel list.
So we're currently on a view called Fuels Section in Areas Section Stack.
There's another view that says Feel section in areas section side by sides.
Another one that says Fuel section on Lee and There's Areas section on Lee two by two.
And there is Area section on Lee won by four.
However,
I personally prefer the first view.