in this video,
we're going to show how we can apply multiple filters to the same field.
So here we've got our pivot table where we have the years and the sales month on the rose
section.
And we got the summer sales amount of this emission of value section.
And what we need to do is to apply to filters at the same time to the sales month feel.
So the first filter we're gonna apply here,
I'm gonna click on the field headers and make sure that you select the sales month here as
the field of genital play filter to.
And then we're gonna go to label filters and my filter will be for months containing e r.
So if I click OK,
here it is here that I filtered for Onley months containing e r.
Now let's say I want to apply another filter through the values on the sales month field,
so I'm gonna filter for months having sales greater than or equal to 200,000.
So I'm going to click again here on the field header.
Make sure I select the sales month as the feel they need to filter and then go to value
filters and then greater than or equal to.
And then 200,000 and click OK,
and as you can see here,
we now have months that don't contain E.
R.
So,
actually,
the second filter has replaced our first filter,
and it's not been applied simultaneously on the sales month field.
So now we don't have the ER filter.
We only have the sales amount filter for the months.
So as you can see here,
we were not able to apply to two filters at the same time on the sales month field.
And the reason for that is that there is an option that we need to enable or turn on on our
pivot table in order to be able to apply to filters to the same field at the same time.
So to do that,
we're going to right click and then click on pivot table options and then go to tools and
filters,
and we need to make sure to allow multiple filled filters per field.
So make sure to check this check box here and click OK,
and now we're able to apply multiple filters through the same field,
so I'm gonna clear older filters,
and I'm gonna start applying my filters again.
So make sure I select sales month.
I'm gonna apply label filters.
First of all,
contains e r.
Click OK here of going to go again and make sure I select the field is the sales month.
Go to value filters greater than or equal to 200,000 and click.
OK,
and,
as you can see here,
have been able to filter for months containing E R.
And then four months,
having sales greater than or equal to 200,000 at the same time on the same field,
which is the sales month,
says you consider,
we've been able to apply two filters to the same field at the same time,
but we need to make sure to enable this option first.
Allow multiple filters on the same field.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
for applying multiple filters to the same field in pivot tables.
Thanks so much watching this video I'll see on the next one