in this video,
we're going to see how we can choose the value field to filter with in case we have
multiple value fields.
So here I've got my pivot table where we have the region on the road section and we get the
soda sales amount on this emission of value section.
And let's say that in addition to the sum of sales amount value Field,
I would also add the average off sales.
So to do that,
I'm just going to drag here the sales amount field again to this emission value section and
then click on a good to value field settings and choose the summarized value fueled by twos
average here.
And then I'm gonna give this a custom name of average sales,
and I'm going to click OK,
here.
So as you can see here now,
I have my data aggregated by the summation of sales amount and also the average of sales
about now,
in order to choose which value feels to filter with when you click here on the field
headers and then click on value filters and then go to greater than or equal to,
for example,
you can choose here from this drop down menu,
which value field you need to filter with.
So here I'm gonna choose tea filter with the average sales,
and I'm gonna filter for average sales greater than 60,000 for example.
And I'm going to click OK,
here says you can see her now.
I only have one reason remaining,
which is Australia,
because it's average sales is greater than or equal to 60,000.
Now,
unfortunately,
I'm not able to apply another filter with this summer sales amount simultaneously.
So if we go again here,
value filters and then greater than or equal to and go to some of sales amount.
If we apply a filter,
for example,
for sales amount greater than 1,300,000 and click OK here because here that the second
filter has overridden the first filter.
So now the two filters is not being applied simultaneously.
Actually,
the second filter now is has overridden the first filter.
So,
unfortunately,
I'm not able to apply both filters at the same time.
So this is how you can choose which value field to filter with in pivot table