and this video,
we're going to see how we can apply filters to column field values.
So here we've got our pivot table and we have the sales person of the Rose section,
and we've got the year on the columns section and the summer sales about on the submission
of Value Section.
And let's say I want to filter the sales in the year 2018 by a certain value So,
for example,
greater than 200,000 now.
I can't click here on the Header 2018 and then go to data and then click on Filter.
You can see her Excel is not allowing me to do so.
So in order to apply filters to column field values year,
we need to click on just a cell beside the column field headers here.
So click here and then either click on this filter button on the data tab on the ribbon,
or you could also press control shift out.
So control shift al toggles a filter here on our off.
So as you can see her now,
I have some field headers and I can click on them and start filtering.
So,
for example,
I'm gonna filter the numbers for 2018 greater than or equal to 200,000 and click OK here
and the second tier of applied a filter just to the values of 2018.
And,
of course,
2017 has been filtered with it as well.
And if you consider,
I've been able to apply a filter to the values of 2018.
So this is how you can apply filters to column field values.