and this video,
we're going to speak about a feature in pivot tables that's going to allow us to filter our
data in a more interactive and user friendly wait.
This feature is called slicers,
so slicers are basically more user friendly filters.
I'm filtering your pivot table.
Using slicers is more user friendly than clicking on a field header and then starting to
apply your filters this way And slicers are a relatively new feature in Excel.
They've been introduced since Excel 2000 ton.
And to insert a slicer,
all you need to do is to select a cell inside your pivot table and then go to the insert
tab on the ribbon and then click on slicer.
As you can see here,
you will get a list of the fields the are available in your pivot table,
and this list will be identical to the Pivot Table fields list.
Here and now I can start selecting feels to use on my slicers,
so I'm going to select the customer,
the product name,
reason and the year and the sales person as well,
and I'm gonna click OK here.
And as you can see here,
I managed to insert five slicers for these five feels and slicers actually allow me to
filter my pivot table with fields that are not present on my pivot table.
So,
for example,
I'm able to filter this pivot table here with the reason so I can click on the Americas to
filter my pivot table with the Americas.
Although the reason field is not available anywhere on my pivot table,
it's not inserted here on my pivot table and to remove filters or to clear the filters.
Here.
You can click on this button here to clear the filters applied on any slicer.
And now I'm gonna filter,
for example,
with product.
One says he can see her after filming with product one.
I have some sales people who don't have data in some years.
So,
for example,
Billy here doesn't have any sales data in 2019.
That is because Billy has not sold any product one in 2019.
I can also apply filters for multiple items so I can apply a filter for product one end
product to at the same time.
So currently I have product one filter applied.
I can press and hold the control by Norma Keyboard and then click on product to.
And now I've applied my filter using product one and product to.
So now my pivot table is filtered for product.
One end product to I could also apply filters for multiple consecutive items on a certain
field.
So,
for example,
here on the sales person slicer or field,
I can click on one sales person,
and I can apply a filter for all the sales people from Adrianne until Madeline,
for example.
So I'm gonna press and hold my shift button and then click on Madeleine.
As you can see here,
I've applied my filters for all the salespeople between Adrian and Madeline.
Now I'm gonna select to apply a filter for the Americas only here on my pivot table.
As you can see here,
you can see that some items on some slicers.
So,
for example,
on the customer slicer here,
some items were two companies,
millennium and visionary are dimmed on this slicer currently after selecting the Americas.
And that means that we don't have any data on our data set for Millennium and visionary
after applying these filters here so often are playing the Americas.
We have only the sales people that sold in the Americas.
And we have these two products as well that we had filtered initially and to verify that on
our data.
I'm gonna actually insert another window here.
So I'm gonna go to the view tab and then go to a new window and is because here I have
another window open off the same workbook on I can go to the data worksheet and it can
start applying these filters.
So I'm gonna first of all filter with these sales people here Adrianne,
Alison,
Billy,
Ivan and Jamie and Katrina and click OK,
here.
I'm gonna filter with the Americas Onley because this is the region that we had the filters
applied for,
and I'm gonna filter with product one and product to because these are the products that we
had filtered with.
And as you can see here,
we have only one customer to life.
The other two customers are not appearing on our data after applying these filters,
and this is why they are dimmed on the customer slicer.
Okay,
so any deem dimmed fields are basically feels that don't have any data after you applied
filters using these slicers.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
for the basic usage off slicers in the upcoming videos,
we're going to speak more about slicers and customizing them.
Thank you so much for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.