If you need to copy a custom slicer style from one workbook to another,
there is no direct way of doing it in excel.
However,
there is a work around to do it.
So I've got this workbook here where I don't have the custom slicer style.
I've got the workbook that we had created on the PVS lesson where we created our custom
slicer style that you can see here and in order to copy the custom slicer style from this
workbook here to the new workbook,
I can just get any slicer from that workbook and then just copy it so control and see to
copy.
And then I'm just gonna paste this new slicer here to my new workbook.
And then I'm just gonna paste my slicer here to the new workbook.
And then if you just click on any slicer here options,
you will see that the new customs slicer style is there and it can be applied on any slicer
here so you can apply to all the slicers if you want here and then you can just delete the
slicer that you had copied from the old workbook.
OK,
this is how you can transfer or copy a custom slicer style from one workbook to another.
So thank you so much for watching this video.
I'll see you on the next one.