in this video,
we're going to speak about the different settings that weaken adjust on our Sisler's so
first of old to view this settings for slicers.
You could just select any slicer here and then go to the slicer tab here on the ribbon,
and it could be also named options on older Excel versions and then click on slicer
settings as an alternative.
You could also right click on the slicer here and then click on slicer settings.
And here you've got some settings that you can adjust for your slicer.
So the first setting here is the slicer name,
so we can change the name of the slicer as an object.
So here the name of the slicer,
its product name,
I could change it to just product and then click.
OK,
and then I can see the name of the slicer here on the upper left corner of the screen.
When you select the slicer,
you will see the name of the slicer here in the name box.
So,
as you can see here,
we managed to change the name of the slicer from product name to product.
Now the name of the slicer is actually different from the slicer title,
so the title here is product name.
We could also change that.
Now let's right.
Click on the slicer and then go to slicer settings.
And then here is the header of the slicer.
So you could first of all,
choose to either display the head or hide it.
So if I uncheck this and click OK,
the header gets hidden or you could also display the header and change its names a year.
I can change the name of the header of the slicer toe product.
So if I click OK here,
you can see here that now the head of the Sizer,
it says product instead of product name.
Another option that you can change on your slices is the sorting on your slicer items.
So I'm going to right click on my reason slicer here and then go to slicer settings.
And as you can see here,
I've got some sorting and filtering options.
So I consort the slicer items to these regions here eight Z or Z to a on.
It could also use custom,
this one Sertic.
So we've explained custom lists on a previous video,
but it's basically a way of doing a customize sorting for your slicer items.
So,
for example,
if I need to do a custom,
I sorting for my reasons here so that I would have America's and in Europe and then
Australia.
So that's a customer asserting That's not an eight easy and not a Z to A.
I will need to use this option,
but I will also need to create a custom list.
So to do that too great a custom list.
I'll click OK here for now,
and then I'll go to file and then goto options and then go to advanced.
And then if I scroll down here under general,
I will have it.
It custom this.
So if I click on that,
I can create a custom list here for sorting so I can create a list that is America's and
then Europe and then Australia.
And then I'll click on add and then I'll click on OK,
here and click OK again,
and now I can apply my custom list.
So if I right click here on the slicer,
go to slicer settings and make sure that this option is sticked here,
use custom lists.
Consorting,
click OK,
and I need to make sure as well to refresh my pivot tables or right click and then refresh
.
You can see here that might custom list Sorting has been applied.
So now I have my reasons sorted as America's Europe and then Australia,
which is not an agency and not a Z to a let's speak about more options that we have on our
slicer settings.
So if I right click here on my customer slicer and then go to slicer settings,
you can see here that I've got some options on the right hindsight here.
So the first option is to hide items with no data.
So if I have any of my customers here that doesn't have data on my source data set,
then this customer would be hidden.
If I check this check box on,
then there is visually indicate items with no data.
So if I have on item with no data,
one of my customers that doesn't have data,
it would be visually indicated so that it would actually have a bit of a lighter shade of
yellow here on the slicer.
And then you could also show items with no data last so that this customer here,
if it doesn't have data on my source data set will be shown last at the bottom and show
items deleted from the data source.
So if it is deleted from the data source,
it would still show it on the list here if this check box is checked.
So that's actually have an example.
So click okay,
here and now I'll actually go to my source data set and I'll delete one of my customers
entirely.
So,
for example,
I'll delete to life here.
I'll just delete the data for this customer from my source data set.
And then oh,
I'm filter here and then go to pivot and then I'll refresh my pivot table.
And as you can see here,
I've deleted to life and is taken seriously moved to the bottom.
And it's been indicated visually that this item doesn't have data on the dais.
It it has a bit of a lighter yellow or more transparent yellow color here,
as you can see now,
if we right,
click here on the slicer settings and then check this height items with no data check box
and click OK,
here.
You can see here that true life now does not exist on my slicer because there's no data for
it.
However,
if you go to our pivot table and click on this filter button here,
you can see that it's still on my list here,
off the data or of the customers that I can filter for true life is still there.
So to remove it from that list,
a swell I can right click here and then go to pivot table options and then go to data and
then here,
under retained items deleted from the data source number of items to retain per field.
I can select non and click OK here and then I will need to right click and refresh my pivot
table and then check here and music is here.
It has gone,
and this option that we changed on the pivot table options it.
I will also affects the slicers.
So if you change it before you delete the item on your data and then refresh you pivot
table,
it will also be removed from your slicers.
So that's eight guys today for the slicer settings.
Thanks so much watching this video,
and I'll see on the next one