Now we're going to speak about the settings for moving or resizing are slicer.
So if you work,
click here on a slicer and they go to size and properties.
You will see here some options for formatting the size and position of the site,
sir,
so you could change the height here or the width using these options.
Or you could also scale the height and the width.
And you could also lock the aspect ratio so that when you change one,
the other one changes as well.
And here on their properties,
you could move un size with cells.
So that means that if you change the site of the cells,
your slicer would move and get resized accordingly.
Or here you could move but do not size with cells.
So here,
when he changed the size with cells,
the slicer would only move,
but it would not get resized.
Or you can choose not to move or size with cells so that when you change the side of the
cells,
your social does not get affected at all,
and you could choose to print it when you do a print and you could choose to lock your
slicer and looking your slicer means that unlocking your slicer means that it does not get
affected whatsoever when you protect your sheet.
So this option here does not work,
except when you protect your sheet.
When you click on your slicer as well here and then go to slice a tab,
you will see some more options here,
so there is the option to have multiple columns on your slicer.
So,
for example,
I will select this slicer here of the sales persons,
and I'll increase the number of columns so that I would have multiple columns here.
I would have My name's basically distributed on multiple columns,
and you could also change the height and the width here using these dial up buttons.
And you could also align your slicer.
So you've got some alignment options year where you can align your slicers with each other
here,
and it's basically the same alignment options that are available in Excel for any object so
you could align the middle of the two slices,
for example.
So now the product and the reason slices are aligned,
their middles are aligned,
as you can see here.
So you've got your usual Align end grouping options year that are available for pretty much
any object in Excel.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
for the slicer size and position options.
Thank you so much watching this video and I'll see on the next one.