Hey, welcome, welcome, welcome.
So we're finally in the next module where we're going to learn about Java's Streams API and how they
work with lambdas.
Now I've already introduced you a little bit to the concept of lambdas, but in this module we'll start
really learning more about how we can use lambdas and especially how we can use them with the Streams
API.
So in this intro, I'm just going to attempt to tell you very quickly what the Streams API is kind of
all about relative to what you already have learned so far.
I will say this.
The streams API marginally can be thought of as a more streamlined and more advanced way to do a lot
of the same techniques that we've been doing with collections and loops.
So, for example, if we want to build a collection of employees, we might have some type of loop that
loops over things and then creates that collection.
You know, we create a collection of employees and then we pass out our employee text string, for example,
and we create new instances of employee objects within a loop.
And then we can add up salaries and things of that sort.
The Streams API lets us accomplish the same types of things, but in a streamlined way where we don't
have to explicitly create a loop to do it.
And it's almost like magic, and it really allows us to engage in a more functional style of programming.
So rather than keep talking about it, let's go ahead and jump in to the next lesson where we will do
a little bit of work and you'll get to see firsthand what we're doing.
So I'll see you there.