OK, so up until now, we've been writing little snippets of programs in code and things and to test
them out.
We just keep running the actual program and we have to go all the way through all the various scenarios.
Now, one of the keys to being a really great developer is knowing all of your techniques really well.
And one of the best techniques to know as a software developer is automated testing.
That's where you're able to actually test your code in an automatic way where you yourself don't have
to keep manually trying everything out from beginning to end repeatedly over and over and over again.
As your programs get larger, you won't be able to scale doing that type of testing, which is just
manual testing.
I'm not saying you'll never manually test, you're probably never going to get completely away from
it.
But the more you know how to write tests that can run automatically, the more work you can get done.
So in this module or chapter, we're going to learn about automated testing in Java.
So Java has a few different what are called frameworks for writing automated tests.
These frameworks, especially the most popular ones, are all developed by third party organizations.
And in general, as far as I'm aware, they are all what are called open source projects, meaning they
are non-profit projects usually maintained by volunteers, and they make the code that they write for
these frameworks freely available.
And so these frameworks are generally implemented as add on libraries that we can use with Java.
So up until now, we have not explicitly been making use of any add on libraries at all.
But now we will.
And the testing framework that we're going to be looking at in this course is called Jane Unit.
And I would say that is by far the most popular testing framework for Java, though by no means is it
the only one.
There are a few others that are fairly popular as well, but I wouldn't say they're anywhere near G-Unit
and to get a job as a professional Java developer.
Most companies, if they care about your ability to write tests at all, if you only know one testing
framework, it had better be a unit that is basically the the de facto standard of testing in the Java
world.
So without further ado, let's jump in and take a look at how that works.