Hey, there, welcome back.
So in this module, we are going to revisit more of the concepts around object orientation classes,
models, things of that sort.
I did not try to teach everything that there was to learn about this topic in the original module where
we first got into it with classes and objects.
There's just too much.
And I thought you might want to have some fun writing, some cool little programs like the guessing
game and things of that sort, which you don't need to know these concepts to any real degree to to
do what we've done so far.
But going forward, we will need to learn a bit more.
And so that's what this module is for.
The techniques you will learn in this module will really unlock a lot more of the power of object oriented
programming, for sure.
And I want to share with you the fact that I've worked with a number of Java developers over the years
who definitely know the language of Java, but they never really learned how to use the most powerful
aspects of Java to model concepts effectively and really just unlock all of the power that really exists
in Java.
And so it is my hope that by teaching you the remaining concepts in this module, you'll really have
the foundational skills you need to take your Java development skills to the next level.
So let's jump on in.