All right.
Welcome back, we are finally on to a new chapter, and this chapter is all about a topic called control
flow.
So let's find out a little bit about what is control flow control flow has to do with how our programs
execute and in what order that execution flows, if you will, to understand this.
Let me give you a small imaginary scenario.
So turning to some of the code that we've been working on here.
If you can imagine whenever we start a program, especially a program like the ones that we've been
writing so far in this course that have a public static void main method.
What happens when we start these programs, when we tell Java to execute a class is that Java creates
what you can imagine as being a little guy called thread, and this little guy's job is to visit methods
and execute the lines of code within those methods and to flow, if you will, to flow through those
lines of code in a particular order, usually from top to bottom.
But there can be certain statements that the thread will try to execute, which will cause the thread
to jump to other lines out of the regular flow from top to bottom.
OK, so Thread is a little guy who executes lines of code basically, and in executing those lines of
code, he can be directed as to where he should go next.
OK.
So in a program like this one, when Java creates thread and thread is told to go execute code in this
class in this case, compound interest calc.
The first thing thread is going to do is to look for a public static void main method matching this
signature.
And if he finds one and hasn't been told any other method to execute, this is the default method that
he's going to execute.
I mean, that is how he will enter the program.
And then from there, he's going to start executing lines of code from top to bottom in general, right?
So he's going to request that Java create a new decimal format object in this case.
And then that object will be or a reference to that object will be stored in De'ath.
Then same thing for the second decimal format, which will be stored here.
Then thread would see that we are calling the calculate method.
And so what would actually happen here is that thread himself.
It's a thing, right?
But Thread would then jump into this calculate method, which means that thread after executing Line
27, he'd get to Line 28.
He'd see that he has to jump to the calculate method, which happens to be up here.
And so then thread would actually jump up to Line 13 and then start executing the lines of code in this
method here.
And when thread jumps up here, he would take with him each of these parameters.
Here are arguments that we're passing in to this method, OK?
So he takes those with him and then those get populated or passed in rather to the calculate method.
OK.
And then Thread would start executing each of these lines of code.
Now, for every method that's referenced, thread actually jumps into those lines of code.
So here we are using percent formatter dot pass.
So Thread would actually jump into this method also.
OK.
And Thread would take the value of rate with him, and that would get passed into the pass method.
OK, I'm not going to jump in there because it's not the code that we wrote.
And then when, when, when the pass method returns, this method returns a number, right?
So then this whole thing here would become a number of of a class called number, and then thread would
jump into the two string method of that number object.
OK.
And then he would return from this to string method with a string which would then get stored or reference
to it would get stored here.
So that's actually how threads work, OK?
So I'm not going to go into too much more detail on thread flow right now in this intro, but I just
wanted to make sure that you had a little bit more understanding of what's actually happening when we
are running these programs, because in this chapter, we're going to learn more about controlling that
flow.
And so I hope it helps to actually understand like, well, flow of what?
What flow are we even talking about?
So now you kind of know what the flow is.
One of the thing I will mention, though, this is kind of just maybe coincidental.
I find this kind of interesting.
So in modern times now when you buy a computer, those of you who pay attention to these types of computer
specs may be aware.
One of the specs that is associated with computers these days is how many cores are in the CPU.
You probably hear this term like I have an intel, whatever eight core processor or four core processor
or whatever, right?
Essentially, these cores are actually little processors themselves.
So the thing that we think of as the processor is actually more of a housing for these cores and the
cores themselves are actual processors, micro processors.
And so, you know, some processors processors might have eight cores, some server processors might
have 16, 32, 64 cores.
Crazy numbers, of course, anyway.
One of the characteristics of these cores, though, is that cores enable these little guys, these
little thread guys, to execute simultaneously.
And so in general, the more cores a computer has, the more threads that.
Computer can run simultaneously.
And how that plays out is that in some programs that are written to take advantage of having multiple
threads running simultaneously.
You can imagine that this little thread guy here is going through executing each of these lines.
But if this program were written in such a way to take advantage of multiple threads, you could have
multiple threads executing these lines of code individually or separately, but all at the same time.
Right.
So they don't necessarily know about each other, but they are all able to carry out their instructions
in parallel with each other.
And so there are some kinds of programs that are really good at taking advantage of that fact.
OK.
So I just wanted to kind of help make you aware of the relationship between the control flow, the threads
and your cause and the processor cores or CPU cores in your computer and how they all kind of work with
each other to get things done faster in the computer.
So having said that, let's go ahead and jump in to learning about control flow.
So I'll see you in the next one.