Congratulations for making it this far through the course.
This is the module where you're going to learn about collections.
So what are collections?
I'm just going to give you a brief intro before we dive into the lessons and code.
So in general, collections are structures that Java provides that allow us to store objects.
One of the easiest ways for me to explain this based on what you've already seen in this course so far
is arrays.
We learned about arrays earlier in the course, and we've used them here and there.
We can create an array to hold instances of of things like primitives so we could have an array of integers.
But we can also use arrays to hold on to instances of objects as well, like person class, for example,
when we create an array.
We have to initialize it with either the number of elements that we're going to put in to the array
or the actual elements at the time of initialization.
In this respect, collections are very similar to arrays.
Generally speaking, they both are structures that allow us to hold on to data of some sort with arrays.
The data can be primitives or objects with collections.
They can only be objects, though there are some basic workarounds for certain primitives, particularly
numbers, because we have the wrapper classes.
So then you should be wondering, OK, well, if both arrays and collections allow us to hold on to
objects, why do we need collections?
And one of the biggest differences between arrays and collections is the fact that arrays cannot be
allocated dynamically.
That is to say, when we create an array, we have to initialize it either with the actual objects that
we're going to put into it or with the size that that array is going to be.
And once we've initialized that array, you can't change its size, but collections are dynamic.
We can create a collection at one point and add objects to it at any point after its creation, typically.
So this means that collections tend to be very flexible for us to use.
And in addition to being able to dynamically allocate and add objects to collections, collections tend
to have a wide array of super useful methods on them.
Whereas arrays do not have methods.
They have a property or two that we commonly will use like to get the length.
But there are no methods directly on arrays, but collections have numerous methods for doing a lot
of things, like adding and removing objects to and from the collection.
Additionally, there are a lot of powerful techniques we can use with collections to do all sorts of
things that we're going to see coming up.
One last thing I want to mention about collections I waited until now to introduce them to you because
I wanted you to know about loops, because collections are frequently used extensively with loops.
And I also wanted you to learn about interfaces because the entire Collections API of Java is heavily
predicated on the use and knowledge of interfaces.
And so I didn't want you learning to use these things without really understanding.
OK?
Why do we instantiate it this way, what we stored in this other way?
Let me take one step back and explain a tiny bit more about the Java Collections framework in general.
So the Java Collections framework consists of a hierarchy of interfaces and then a set of classes that
implement those interfaces.
At the top of that interface hierarchy is the main interface called collection.
And then there are several other interfaces that actually extend from collection, such as list, set
queue and deck off to the side.
There's another top level interface called Map.
So Map doesn't actually extend from collection, but it is still part of the Java Collections framework
and definitely is a collection in the English sense of the word, if not the interface, sense of the
word from the second level interfaces such as set and list.
There are concrete implementing classes that is, classes that implement those interfaces will be starting
off learning what is probably the most commonly used pair of collections, interface and implementation,
which is called the list.
So without further ado, let's jump in and start learning about collections.