Guess what, you have finally reached the final section of this course.
Congratulations, if you've made it this far.
We're almost done now.
I think this section will likely be the most fun for the majority of you because we will finally be
building a full application with a proper graphical user interface, and that'll be a web application
that we will be building in this entire section.
OK, so we'll be using what is arguably the most popular framework for doing this type of work, which
is called the spring framework.
So in this intro, I just want to let you know a little bit about the spring framework and let you know
a little more about what we're going to be building and how we will be using it and what to expect.
So the spring framework is the most popular framework used by Java developers, especially in the enterprise
space and enterprise really just means large corporation, for the most part.
So it is the most popular add on framework for enterprise java development when it comes to building
web applications, web services, microservices and applications of that sort.
And I would say the reason that it has become so popular is because it's been around nearly 20 years.
As of the time of this recording, it was first released back in 2002, and it's been going strong ever
since.
And it made it significantly easier to write so-called enterprise level applications than any of the
technologies that existed before then.
And it's done a great job of keeping enterprise Java development relatively easy ever since.
Now there was at least one major competitor that existed.
I consider it a competitor, at least that existed before the spring framework came out, and there
have been some that have come out since then.
But the spring framework has definitely become the de facto standard among corporations, at least in
the U.S. I have not worked as a Java developer in other parts of the world, but I'm guessing it's pretty
much the standard everywhere for corporate enterprise development.
So let's talk a little bit more about what is it, actually?
So the spring framework is a collection of sub projects.
OK.
And I'm actually on the spring frameworks website right here, which is spring that i o.
That's how you can get to a spring that i o.
OK.
And so right here on the main page, you can even get a sense of what you can use the spring framework
for microservices, reactive applications, cloud applications, web apps and a lot of other things
too.
OK.
So then we can even dig into some of the projects here, and you can see a few of the main ones Spring
Boot Framework, Cloud, et etc. And then there's even more if I click on this and you can scroll through
here.
There are plenty that are actively in development right now.
And then even more that may not actively be under development at this time.
So it's a very productive framework where they're really creating a lot of functionality.
So let me just tell you a little bit about a few of these modules, especially the ones that we're going
to be using primarily in this section.
OK, we'll be using spring boot.
I will explain a little bit more about that later.
When we start getting into it will be using obviously the core spring framework.
So I would say this represents kind of the original thing that the spring framework was, and that's
why it still gets the name spring framework.
And then a lot of these other sub projects kind of sprung out of the spring framework.
And so they kind of formalized them into their own projects.
But this one right here was pretty much the original thing that was called the spring framework.
It will be a little difficult for me to explain much of what it does without showing you.
So I'm going to hold off on that for right now.
Spring data is a great one, though, so in our last section, we spent the entire section learning
how to write Java code that interacts with a database using the JBC framework.
So spring data is a framework that makes it way easier than what we did in the last section to write
code that works with a lot of different kinds of databases and database technology.
So in the last section, we used JTBC to work with one particular database, which is H2 and H2 is a
relational database.
OK.
But there are other types of databases besides relational databases, and the spring data framework
can enable us to interact with lots of different kinds besides just relational or object databases.
You can interact with pretty much all of the most popular types of databases there are and write very,
very little code in many cases to have a lot of functionality.
So the spring?
ADA Project is kind of magical, in my opinion, it just does amazing things.
But what we did in that last section on GDC and databases will give you deeper insight into some of
the magic that's happening with spring data.
OK.
And then if we dig in to the spring framework itself, we will see that one of the breakout projects
or sub projects of the spring framework is spring in the sea, and we will be making heavy use of this
framework.
So Spring in the Sea is the sub framework for building both web applications and web services.
So one way of thinking of a web application is basically it's a type of website, but it's frequently
one that is intended to be more interactive, like in both directions.
So if you think of a website like CNN or a web news website and you're mostly just consuming content
from the website and you don't do a whole lot of interacting with it.
But in many web applications, maybe not all, but in many of them, you may be doing various forms
of entering lots of data and consuming lots of data back out of that website.
And when we make websites of that type, especially when they're purpose built within a corporation
or something like that, they're usually referred to as web applications.
A few examples that most people might be familiar with would be Google Docs, where they've implemented
basically competing applications to Microsoft Office.
So you've got the ability to make spreadsheets and type documents and Duke slide deck presentations,
those kinds of things.
And then even Microsoft has their own Microsoft Office implementation in the web as well.
So those are fully functional web applications on steroids.
Now, usually, most of the typical types of web applications that you'll be building in the Java enterprise
space won't be nearly as advanced as Microsoft Office running in a browser, but it could be.
But my point here is that those are applications where you're very much interacting and creating content
within the browser rather than just consuming it.
So if I had to summarize what the spring framework really is, I would just say it's a collection of
APIs, frameworks, projects that make it easier to develop enterprise applications in Java.
Now let me also remind you this section is only meant to be an introduction to the spring framework.
The spring framework is massive, like truly.
I mean, you can see right here there are many, many modules of the spring framework, and there are
many, many books that focus just on one of these modules, okay, let alone the whole entire thing.
So we won't be going really, really deeply into all of the aspects of this of the spring framework.
I will offer additional courses in the future that will go into those topics in more depth.
My purpose in this section is to primarily accomplish two things.
First off, I want you to be able to get a sense for how we can put a lot of what you've learned throughout
this course all together to build something more realistic.
OK?
And there's nothing like building a fully functional web application where you can actually interact
and see things visually instead of having to work on the command line.
Secondly, I want to cover some of the most common use cases that a lot of enterprise Java developers
will encounter when making basic web applications.
Just as we implemented a crud application in the last section, from the databases perspective in this
section will be creating an even more fully functional crud application in the web browser.
OK.
And we will cover enough common cases that many of you will be able to take what we are going to learn
in this section and kind of treat the techniques in the code that will be implementing here as a template
for how to make basic crud applications.
So we will be solving a number of problems that you are very, very likely to encounter as a professional
developer without you having to learn the entire spring framework.
So even if you don't go any further with me, with any of my future courses, you will leave this course
with an incredibly practical set of skills that will enable you to be able to build useful applications
immediately.
All right.
So without further ado, let's get started.