In this lesson, we're going to talk about what Java is all about.
Java is called an object oriented programming language.
Basically, what that means is that Java is a language that was designed to make object oriented programming
easier.
Now what is object orientation or object oriented programming?
Basically, object orientation is a way of programming where we try to model either the real world or
concepts within whatever problem we're trying to write software for.
I understand that may not mean much to you.
So let me just go ahead and show you some code, and maybe this will help to make more sense.
So let's say that we want to write an application that allows us to enter information into a computer
about people, basically a people database, if you will.
So you can enter their first name, last name, maybe date of birth, maybe you have other information
about people as well.
So if we wanted to write that kind of application in Java in an object oriented way, it might make
sense for us to model some of the concepts that we recognize exist within this problem domain that we
are writing code for.
In this case, the problem domain is how do we store and retrieve information about people?
So here's what I would do in that case.
Turning to the idea here, I would start off by creating what's called a class.
Now we saw a class here in our Hello World program, and I didn't really explain much about it, but
I'm going to create another one now.
And like I said, maybe this will start to get a little clearer to you.
So what I'm going to do?
You don't need to follow along with me in this particular lesson.
I'm just going to give you a quick example of object orientation.
OK, so I'm going to open up the project browser here, and I'm going to create some new files.
I guess I'm going to go ahead and do this somewhat similarly to how I would do it in real life.
So I'm going to go a little fast, but hopefully you'll see what I'm doing here now.
I'll explain it.
OK, so first thing I'm going to do is to create a package, and that's just a folder where I can group
up or organize my classes and my my code, and we'll get into why I would want to do that in a later
lesson.
But let's see, and I'd probably call this model.
And then I'd create a class and I'd create a class for the concept of person because my program is all
about me being able to enter information about people.
So I'd create a class.
I'd call it person and then I'd identify what properties or attributes of a person I might want to track
with my program.
So I'd probably want to track a person's first name and their last name.
Their date of birth.
Things of that sort you might want to track their gender or addresses is a very typical one, right?
This is enough for right now.
OK.
And then I typically create a bunch of boilerplate code and boilerplate.
Is this standard code that you almost always end up having in your program and it's so common that most
ideas can generated for you.
So I'd probably go through something like creating a constructor to let me in through all that information
easily.
And and then I'd also probably produce what are called getters and setters for all of these attributes,
and I'm intentionally not explaining all of this.
I just want you to kind of see, you know, a professional programmer doing fairly realistic ish type
coding for a moment here.
And then I'm going to backtrack and we'll break this down in and look at the bits and pieces of it.
All right.
So I have modeled a person here.
I have said that I'm writing a program that lets me enter and retrieve information about people.
And so I need a bit of Java code that lets me represent or model a person.
And specifically, I want to model the idea that a person can have a first name or last name and a date
of birth.
OK, so that's what I'm doing here.
I could model other concepts for other types of programs or if I had an expanded set of things that
I might want to do with this program for attracting people or whatever, I can do that.
So in fact, I will.
Let's say that a person has an address, right?
So I could model that as well.
I could say a person has an address and I will call that an address.
Now, this concept of an address, unlike the concepts of string and local date, string and local date
are concepts that come with Java.
But the concept of this address does not come with Java, so I would have to create the concept of an
address.
Just as Java doesn't come with the concept of a person I am creating, I'm defining what a person is
for my purposes.
If I want a person to have an address, I need to define what is an address for a person, and I can
do that here.
So right now, I'm telling Java that a person can have a first name or last name and date of birth,
and they can have an address.
But the idea is saying, I don't know what an address is.
I knew it.
I know what strings are for first name, and I know what a local data is for the date of birth, but
I don't know what it addresses, so I'm going to teach it now what is an address?
And I'm going to do that by letting the A.D. recognize that since I referred to a class or a concept
that does not exist yet, it's going to give me the opportunity to create that class.
And I can do that by using a keyboard shortcut here, and I will create the class called address.
And yeah, I'll let it go into this model package, which is just the folder.
OK, so now I it has created a the skeleton of a new class for me called address, and now I can define
some attributes of an address.
OK, so an address might have, I don't know, for lack of better terms here.
I'm just going to say it might have an address one field.
All right.
And then we might have an address to field for like the apartment or whatever.
And we might have, well, we will have a city.
And I'm assuming we're in the U.S., U.S. or Canada.
I'm just going to have a field called state.
And yeah, since I'm just going to assume that all these people are in the U.S. for right now, I won't
bother with a country, but I could put that in there as well.
All right.
And then I, yeah, I can do the same thing that he did before.
I can generate a constructor for this class and I will generate getters and setters as well.
All right.
And then I'll go back to my person class, and now the read on address has gone away.
And now I will want to add in the fact that I can get and sit and address again.
I understand I haven't explained any of these things to you.
That's OK.
I will.
I just want you to get a sense for the tempo and the rhythm and and what it is that a professional developer
might do.
So, yeah, I'll I'll generate a I'll generate a veteran setter for my address field.
All right, there we go.
Typically, I wouldn't want those to be whips.
Typically, I wouldn't want those to be in this location, though probably want those to be more towards
the bottom of the of the file.
And class.
Yeah, that's that's a little better for me.
Let's see what else might a person have that I might care about for the purposes of this application?
I don't know.
So a person could have a spouse.
So here we get into a question of, OK, how do we model the spouse of a person?
My object oriented brain automatically says, Well, a spouse is a person.
And so my inclination would be to model a spouse as a person just like that.
And now some of your brains may have just gone because you may have recognized that I'm getting a little
recursive here if you're under if you know the meaning of that term, right?
It's like inception, right?
A dream within a dream.
I have a person within a person and I'm I'm saying that the definition of a person contains a person.
You can do that in an object oriented language like Java.
And that's one of the many things that can make such a language so powerful.
The idea that we can create new concepts, well, new concepts that are new to the language, right?
You could almost say in a way, we're extending the language sort of the right kind of.
So, yeah, we can we can create new concepts, and those concepts can be based on themselves to a certain
degree, as I am doing right here.
OK.
So yeah, I just added a spouse to this person and the spouse is a person and I can do the same thing
I did a minute ago, and I can create a getter and setter for the spouse.
OK, so now that I have modeled a Oh, hold on, yeah, let's let's let's introduce maybe at least one
more class here.
A person can have a pet, right?
Let's see.
So what might be some good characteristics of a pet?
Well, OK, let's do this.
All right, so similarly to the address, I just referred to another concept that we haven't defined
yet, just a pet.
I'm going to get a little fancier here.
You know, so let this just be like the sneak preview into what we will be learning down the road a
little bit, OK?
But hopefully this kind of what's your appetite for some of the power of what we can do with an object
oriented language like Java?
OK, so what I'm going to do here is I'm going to go ahead and tell the I.D., Yes, I want to create
pet, and for now, I won't get overly fancy with it.
So I'm going to go out and just create a class.
And yeah, that's fine.
Now what are some generic characteristics of a pet?
They usually have a name, right?
So I can say that, yes, a pet has a name.
Is there anything else a pet can have a date of birth?
Date of birth, and I don't know.
I'm going to leave it at that for right now, for for that part, and again, I will generate a constructor
for this and I'll generate some getters and setters as well.
All right, now, one more kind of cool thing that we can do.
I didn't say what kind of pet?
Right?
People have all kinds of pets.
So let us say that, yes, we have this class for pet, but we want to get a little more specific with.
Well, what kind of pet?
So what we can do is we can create more classes and we can do something pretty cool here.
Let's say that we want to be able to represent a dog so I can create a new class called dog.
But I know what you're thinking.
You're saying, Well, why did you create something called a pet?
And now you're going to create something called a dog?
I will show you why I did that, because I can tell Java that I want this concept of dog.
To be a pet, in other words, I can say that a dog is a type of pet.
By typing a line just like this public class dog extends pet.
Now the idea and Java, in turn, is complaining because I am missing something that I need on the pet.
If I'm going to do this and let me go back there real quick and just fix that.
In fact, it already knows what the problem is.
And it's the idea, not Java.
The idea is offering to make it easy for me to fix that problem.
Probably.
Let's see here.
So, yeah, let me let me fix that real quick.
And what I need to do here is I need to generate one more constructor, one that doesn't have any inputs
there, and I think that will make this happy.
Let's see if I go back over here.
Yep, yep, it's happy now.
OK.
Again, you'll understand all of this in time.
So I'm saying that a dog is a type of pet.
And what's cool is, I don't have to say that a dog has a name or date of birth because my concept of
dog, my class dog, is going to inherit that fact from the pet itself.
Oh, it still doesn't like something.
What's it not liking their?
I don't know.
I'm not going to read about it right now.
It might be the idea, just not being happy with me or something.
Anyway, so yeah, dog extends pet and therefore Dog has a name and any date of birth.
In other words, if I go back to dog.
Dog will inherit the properties of pet because dog extends pet.
OK.
And so this is a powerful, powerful concept in object orientation, the concept of inheritance.
One concept can inherit the attributes and behaviors, behaviors that we haven't talked about that yet.
And behaviors of another concept.
OK.
And in Java concepts are classes and in many other, most other object oriented language as well.
Really?
OK, so we've got a dog now.
Is there any attribute that might be unique to a dog that we'd want to actually capture in our definition
of a dog in this class here?
Let's see.
So.
So I can't think at the moment of any attributes that I care about in this discussion that are specific
to a dog, but I can't think of behavior that is different between different types of pets, potentially.
And so we can model behavior as well.
So far, we've just been modeling attributes.
You know, the fact that a person has a name, the fact that a dog has a name, the fact that a person
can have an address and a date of birth, et cetera, et cetera.
But we haven't talked about behaviors and behavior is the other big concept in object orientation.
OK, so let's model some behaviors for a couple of pets.
All right.
So one behavior of a dog is the fact that it can bark, right?
So we could create what is called a method.
We won't return anything, and we'll have a method on here called bark, and this method will simply
spit out on the screen.
Ruff.
OK, so we'll do that system that out that print line and we'll say, Ruff, ruff.
All right.
So a dog can bark.
So now let's go create a cat.
Cat.
And we're going to have it extend pet.
And we're going to say that a cat can meow, meow.
And when we tell a cat to meow, that will result in our program in the the words meow being printed
on the screen.
All right.
OK, so I think you're getting the point.
But now that we've modeled a person and a spouse and an address and all these things, what can we actually
do with all of this?
So here's what we're going to do for now, just to give you a little bit of an idea of how this maybe
could be utilized to a certain degree.
If we go back over to our hello world class, we're just going to use this because it's already here.
We will now create a person or two.
And the way we will do that is by creating what is called a variable, which is just a holding tank,
something that can hold onto our objects.
OK, so we can create objects.
Objects are created from our classes, so we've just created several classes here.
But these classes are really just a blueprint for how to make something.
OK?
Our person class is a blueprint for how to make a person and what a person can do.
Right?
The dog class is a blueprint for how a dog might behave and what it can do, what kind of information
it can hold, etc. But we can make what are called instances of these things within our code so that
we can actually use them.
OK, so here's how we can do that.
If I want to create a person, I must first tell Java that I want to hold on to something that is a
person, and I will have to tell it that I am dealing with the class of person.
So it had to kind of important stuff.
You'll learn that later as well.
So let's make a person and I don't know, let's say that I can name.
In fact, I need to name this variable, this thing that's going to hold on to the person that I'm about
to create.
I can name it something now.
I could name it generically like P. one.
I'm not a big fan of using names like that if I don't have to.
I usually prefer to do something a little better than that.
But I don't know.
For now, we'll say we're going to create a person called Tom.
And so then I'll use this keyword new and I'm going to tell Java I want to create a new person.
And I created this thing called a constructor, which allows me to initialize information about the
new person that I am creating.
You saw me generating things.
One of the things that I generated was something called a constructor.
You are now seeing me use that constructor.
So I was basically just telling Java, whenever I create a person, I want to be forced essentially
to have to specify in this case, their first name, their last name and date of birth.
That's the only way that I can create a person.
And so here I will do that.
So I'm going to name them Tom Smith, and I will give him a date of birth.
Of here, let me give myself a little more room.
A date of birth of, I don't know, 1984.
On June.
15TH, just a random date.
All right, so I have now created a person called Tom, and let's let's create another person.
Janet.
New person Janet Jackson.
Oh yeah.
Local date and maybe not the singer Janet Jackson.
I wasn't thinking that necessarily because I don't know what her date of birth is.
So this Janet Jackson will have been born in 1985.
December.
Third.
All right, so there's Janet.
And now I can get a little fancy.
I want to say that Janet is Tom's spouse.
I can do that, so I can I can say Tom, not set spouse.
Now this set spouse is a method, and I haven't explained what methods are, but just know this is something
that I generated when I created Tom.
When I created a constructor which allowed me to create a Tom with the first name and last name and
a date of birth.
And after I created the constructor, I also created a bunch of getters and setters.
And what that really did was it just generated things that I could call like.
This thing here set spouse based on whatever attributes I was defining on my person class.
So I have an attribute on the class called spouse.
And so when I generated getters and setters, the ADP generated what's called a method.
In fact, that generated two methods a method called set spouse and a method called get spouse.
OK, so that generated all of this for me, so I can use that method now.
And this method said spouse is wanting me to give it a person as an input.
In other words, it's asking me, OK, you want to tell me who Tom's spouse is?
So tell me who is Tom's spouse?
That's what the ADP is asking me right now, essentially.
So I'm going to tell it, Well, Tom, spouse, is this lady right here, Janet?
And I tell it that by simply typing in this variable name here, Janet.
So I created Janet Jackson, born at this time.
And when I created her, I stored a reference to her something that I can refer to her with in this
variable called Janet, which is a person.
And now, when I refer back to Tom and I say I want to set Tom's spouse, I can say I want to set Tom's
spouse to Janet, and that's what I just did right there.
OK, then I can create Tom's pet.
So let's create a dog.
And I guess I'll have to tell it where to get dog from.
And we'll name this dog, Fido.
And so just like the person will create a new dog.
Now, I did not create a useful constructor for dog.
I can so I can jump over here into the dog class and I can create a constructor.
And the idea is smart enough to know that since dog extends pet, I might want to generate a constructor
that simply calls the constructor for PET.
Well, one of the constructors for PET and in fact, that is exactly what I want.
So first of all, generate this constructor that takes no inputs and then don't generate a second constructor
that does take the inputs.
There we go.
All right.
And then if I jump back over here and tell it, show me what you got.
Yeah, now I have the option to create a dog with a name.
And so I will say, yes, Fido is his name.
Oh, and let's see, his date of birth can be, I don't know, two thousand.
I don't know.
2018.
January the first.
All right.
And now I can say, Tom, not set.
Oh, did I not?
OK, so here I forgot to generate a veteran center for a person's pet so I can jump over into the person
class.
And I can do that.
I can.
I'll go down to the bottom here.
And I'll say I want to generate some getters and setters for the pet.
There we go.
Then if I jump back over here.
Now, now I can specify a pet.
Fido.
Fido is his pet.
Now, in this particular model, for a person, a person can only have one pet.
If I wanted to get fancier in my program, I could absolutely make it so that a person could have multiple
pets, and we might even do that as an exercise down the road.
But I just wanted you to just get the bigger picture of, oh, hold on a minute.
Sorry.
So I've I've created all this stuff, but I still haven't actually like done anything with it, right?
So one thing that I could do with this is to simply teach Java how to let me print out a person in totality,
right?
So I could do something like, let's see, I could do something like this print, Tom.
So here you haven't seen this before.
But if I do a system that out that print line and then no quotes and I just refer to a variable of some
type, by default, Java will do its best to try to figure out what to do with it.
So let's see what job is going to do with this.
I'm going to run this program.
OK, so it printed.
Hello, world.
Nice to meet you, and then it printed some gobbledygook looking stuff, model that person at blah blah
blah.
Basically, this is just printing out the location in java's memory where the person object exists.
And if that doesn't mean anything to you, don't worry about it for now.
So not very useful, but we can teach Java to do something more useful.
And so the way we can do that is to jump over here into the person class and we can add a method.
Or actually we're not going to add a method.
We're going to override a method that is already kind of there, but we just can't see it.
It's a method that all Java objects have by default.
Let's see here.
So we're going to generate a two string method and we'll take the default for now, even though I'm
not a huge fan of exactly how it does it.
But that's OK.
All right.
So we just had the idea to generate what is called a two string method.
This is a standard method that comes automatically with Java.
But what we're doing is we're overwriting the standard method.
The standard method prints out what we just saw a minute ago.
Let me see if I can bring that back up.
Yeah.
So the standard implementation of the two string method will just print out the memory location of the
object itself.
But we can override that method and teach each other to do something different when we want to print
an object.
And so the A.D. just was kind enough to generate this so-so boilerplate code for us that knows how to
just look at each of the properties of our person class and then print a little something about that
property.
OK.
Yeah.
So in fact, let's jump back over to hello world and let's run it again.
And now let's see what it does.
OK, so now there's something a little different, it's this person, first name, Tom, last name Smith.
Date of birth 1984 June 15 addresses no spouse is another person.
Look at that.
So it's even it's even drilling in and running the two string that we just wrote for the spouse.
And that's another one of these powerful concepts with Java.
The fact that since we did this kind of a recursive definition of a person to say that a person has
a spouse who is also a person, the spouse benefits from the two string method that we just overrode
so that we don't have to teach Java explicitly how to represent or print out the spouse.
It already knows that because the spouse is a person.
So the spouses, Janet and here's her birth date.
And interestingly, we didn't teach the code to say that, Hey, Janet is Tom's spouse, then probably
Tom is Janet's spouse.
Also, we could do that, but we won't right now.
Maybe not ever.
And then look here, the pet is still printing out in this weird way.
And that makes sense because we didn't teach Java how to print out the pet in a more meaningful way.
But we can, and we'll do that really, really quickly here as we wrap this up.
So if we go back to the pet class.
And let me close this, oops, let's close that we can do the same thing again, we'll come down here
to the bottom.
And the reason I'm putting this on the bottom, I mean, you could put these methods anywhere.
I just like the general standard that our what are called fields.
These are the attributes, if you will, or the properties of the class.
They go at the top and then our constructors go next and then non boilerplate methods I would typically
start putting next.
And then towards the bottom, I'd have all of my generated boilerplate getters and setters and even
my two string method, which is pretty much boilerplate and generated.
OK.
So we'll do the same thing here.
I will generate a two string and yeah, I will use both of those fields and cool.
All right.
And then we'll pop back over to the hello world and we'll run this guy again, and let's see what we
get this time.
All right, so now if we jump over to Tom's pet, yeah, we get a pet whose name is Fido with a date
of birth of whatever.
All right, cool.
So now in a real program, I really might very well have started off with most of the modeling that
you just saw me do here if I needed to write a program that let me track these kinds of concepts.
This was all pretty real.
What you're not seeing is like more realistic examples of what I might do with this in all likelihood,
because I think I said that the let's imagine that we wanted an application where we could create people
and then track them and stuff like that.
So then what you're not seeing here is I'd probably have a database which is a another program that
I won't have to write where I can store information, and then I'd write some code that would let me
take this information.
These people and dogs and all of this and store them into the database for for long term storage and
safekeeping.
And then I could I could shut down my computer and shut down this program and come back later and and
start up the program again and retrieve all this information about people and stuff.
And the other thing that's probably not very realistic or useful is the fact that in this program,
I'm I'm hard coding.
As we say, I'm I'm explicitly creating these people.
And every time I run this program, these are the only people who are ever going to exist.
That's not a very useful program.
A real program would be one where it might like prompt me as a user of the program and say, like,
do you want to enter information about a person?
And I'd say, Yeah, let me enter somebody with a first name of this and the last name of that.
And then it would just store that information somewhere and then come back and ask me, Do you wanna
enter more information?
Right?
And then I could say, show me a list of all the people.
So obviously, I'm not getting into any of that because that'd be a way long video, though we will
almost certainly get into something along those lines a little bit later.
OK, so this this video was already plenty long, and I'm going to go and shut it here.
But again, just to recap.
So we've created a lot of classes, and these classes are simply modeling concepts, and the concepts
that we're modeling can be both well in object orientation terms.
We can model data and behavior.
The data that we can model would be things like the first name, last name, date of birth, address,
spouse, pet in this particular example.
OK, those are the the data.
The behaviors oh, could be the the dog's ability to to bark.
OK, which you didn't see me run this, but that's OK.
You can imagine what it's going to do.
You know, just for grins, I'll run that real quick.
So we created a dog here, so I can I can do this.
I can do Fido dog bark.
And then if we run this program before it prints out time, it's going to print out those bark.
There we go.
Hello, world.
Nice to meet you, then rough, rough and then the information about Tom.
OK, so all right, so that's an example of a little bit of behavior there, and we could get super
fancy and super involved with how we handled all the behaviors and things in ways that will blow your
minds when we get to it.
OK, so back to the recap, though.
So yeah, we modeled we modeled data.
So you've heard me refer to these things as attributes.
I'm saying that word in a non computer programming sense.
I'm saying it more in a real world sense, like just attributes of objects, attributes of concepts,
right?
But in in Java and in object orientation, these things here, these attributes would actually be referred
to as fields of the class.
OK.
They also are variables.
And yeah, they they go by a lot of different names, depending on the context in how you're talking
about them.
OK.
And then, yeah, the dog has a a has some, some fields and some attributes that it's inheriting from
the pet.
OK.
Because this dog extends pet.
And then we also have a cat that extends pet.
OK.
And the cat has a different behavior of Meow.
So that's also really cool that you can have two or more classes that extend the same class.
But then those two subclasses as we would call them dog and cat.
Those two subclasses can have their own different behaviors, and they can also add in additional data.
I'm not showing that here, but we'll get into that as well.
I could add unique fields, fields that are only unique to a cat and fields that are unique to a dog
that have nothing to do specifically with pet.
Right?
They're too specific.
We could.
We could do that as well.
So when we say that Java is an object oriented language, this is exactly what we mean.
We mean that java's bread and butter is that it makes it really easy to model concepts in it.
All right.
That's going to wrap up everything that I want to say for right now about Java object orientation and
classes and objects.
We covered a whole lot of concepts.
So in the subsequent lesson, we'll do a deeper dive into a lot of these concepts, and I will make
sure that you understand every single thing, so I will see you in the next one.