Hello and welcome to my course, professional Java developer career starter, Java Edition, I know
I know the title is a mouthful.
It's a course teaching the foundations of Java.
It's for people who want to start a new career doing Java and becoming professionals.
So there you go, the long title.
Anyway, I'm so happy and pleased that you've chosen to take my course to learn Java.
I think you're going to get a lot out of it, and I hope that I can bring a slightly unique perspective
to teaching Java based on both my background and my way of thinking in terms of background.
I have an extensive career as a professional software developer.
The majority of which has been specifically with Java and I've worked with tons and tons of developers
as a co-worker, manager, mentor, consultant, architect, etc. So I've seen a very wide range of
skill sets among all of the different Java developers that I've worked with over the years.
Some were amazing.
Some were maybe not so much.
And I've made a lot of notes over the years of some of the same patterns that I've seen in terms of
weaknesses among a lot of developers.
Now, these are not universally true weaknesses for everybody.
But I've been a little startled from time to time to see some of these weaknesses pop up over and over
again among a large number of developers.
I'm talking about skills like pattern matching for text or using some of the latest APIs of Java that
help to modernize the language and keep it fresh and current in today's climate of functional programming
and other paradigms.
So it is my goal in this course to give you an incredible foundation as a Java programmer so that you
feel confident and capable to go toe to toe with even a lot of seasoned Java developers, and that won't
be as hard as you may think.
You see, even a lot of seasoned Java developers haven't kept up with some of the latest APIs introduced
into Java to keep it both relevant and effective as a modern programming language.
And I'm teaching a lot of those APIs in this course.
So if you learn them, there's a good shot that when you're working with more seasoned Java developers,
you'll be able to show them a thing or two, whether it's the streams and lambdas API or even an old
technology that a lot of Java developers just don't tend to be very good at regular expressions or test
driven development.
Also known as TDD using J Unit.
So I've put a lot into this course so that you can get a lot out of it.
But I'm also open to your feedback.
This is my first course of this magnitude, and I know there are going to be a lot of things that I
didn't think of.
So I want you to reach out to me and give me a chance to address any issues that you may encounter while
you're taking this course.
I'll be constantly updating this course to make it even better with more images, additional resources
and additional lectures as time goes on.
You can help drive what direction this course takes with your feedback.
So without further ado, let's get going.