All right, so next up, let's consider another scenario with this guessing game.
What if we wanted to limit the number of guests as we allow the user to have?
Right?
Normally guessing games won't let you just keep guessing forever.
They will.
They will limit you somehow.
So let us consider some ways in which we could prevent the user from just constantly guessing forever.
Let's say that we only want to allow them to have four guesses, and you can change that number to whatever
you want.
Five guesses.
Three guesses, whatever.
It does not matter.
OK?
So let's say we wanted to limit them, though, to whatever four guesses, I would like you to pause
the lesson and really put some thought into some ways that you might do this, or you're welcome to
actually even try implementing it yourself first.
OK.
And then when you think you've got it or you give up, come back and we'll try to figure this out together.
All right.
So let's see how we could do that.
So if we wanted to limit the user to only getting like four guesses.
So we already have this wrong guest count variable here.
So that's going to probably be pretty useful to use.
Right?
So what I'm kind of thinking is we already are incrementing this counter down here when yet whenever
you get a guess wrong?
So I can see a couple of possibilities here and I'm telling you now, I haven't worked this out as I'm
recording this.
I have not worked this out myself.
So I'm going to try to keep this video honest and show you my thought process as I work through this.
The problem with me sometimes trying to work through these things live, so to speak in the recording
is I may start to go down one road and then decide, I don't like that.
And since you're learning, I know that that can sometimes be kind of confusing for you.
If you see me going one way and then I back up and then I go down another path.
So I want to try to limit how often I do that kind of live thinking in front of you.
But I also want you to see how the thought processes go when we are figuring out how to write code,
because that's very real, right?
All right.
So so I have two thoughts kind of going through my mind in addition to using the wrong guest count.
I'm kind of gravitating towards either doing some kind of conditional thing down here in the last block
or potentially doing some conditional thing down here, because the criteria here in this wild clause
already is here to determine when we should stop looping, right?
So currently, we stop looping when the user enters a queue, but we could additionally stop looping
if the wrong guest count exceeds four or is four or something like that right?
We could do something along those lines.
Now, the only other thing I'm thinking, though, is that if we simply put in here, something like
wild queue is not equal to guest number or wrong guest count is less than four.
That would allow the loop to continue to go.
But when wrong guest count is four, then as the program is written currently, the program would simply
end and that wouldn't give any feedback.
We'd probably want something like if you have four guesses for incorrect guesses, then we want to present
a message saying you had four tries and you didn't get it.
And here was the heroes, the number or something, something like that.
However, if the user simply hits cue, we don't need to show that message, right?
So we have.
So in other words, there's going to be some kind of conditional thing happening, even some kind of
additional conditional text output happening, either here where we're going to say if the wrong guest
count is four or more, then in addition to telling them they didn't get it.
Also, let them know that, hey, we're killing the program now or something like that.
I'm inclined to do both, actually.
What I'm thinking is we can.
Well, let's just see here.
All right.
So maybe I'm going to make a new line right here.
And we can say if the wrong guest count is greater than or equal to four, then output.
I'm going to use a system out that print f you've had percent the guesses percentage in correct guesses.
The random number is percent, the ending program now and then we will bind our numbers.
So you've had wrong guest count and the random number.
OK, so that would show our message, if you guessed.
More than four times.
However, that alone doesn't end the program, so if we want to end the program, the easiest way to
do that probably would be just to return, just like we're doing up here.
OK, so let's build this and try it out and see what we get.
All right.
I'm going to clear.
And then let's rerun.
All right.
So our random number is six.
So let's just guess wrong a bunch.
Two.
You didn't get it.
One.
Three.
All right.
Two, one three.
Was that correct?
Now let's see here.
I feel a little off with the counting here, so we made one guess of a two one guests of a one one guess
of a three.
Ah, OK.
So our counting is off here, right?
We only made three guesses and then we got this message, and that is because we are incrementing the
counter here.
So what we might want to do is either increment the counter after this or change this logic to say wrong
guest count greater than for either one.
I don't know that there's much of a difference between either of those.
Let's let's try just moving this.
Here, let's rebuild.
Let's clear and try it again.
All right, random numbers three.
So let's do one two four five.
That feels better.
You didn't get it, you've had four incorrect guesses the random number is three ending program now.
Let me fix the little message there for the ending program now percent in.
There we go.
That feels about right to me.
That looks good right now.
It's always a good idea when you're making changes like this to do what's called regression testing,
and that's where you just retest the functionality that was working before.
So I've only tested this one scenario where I have four incorrect guesses, but I haven't tested what
happens when I get it right, when I get it right after a couple of incorrect guesses, etc. So let's
let's test those scenarios also.
So I'm going to rerun the numbers.
Five.
So let's test getting it correct on the very first try.
Random number was five.
You got it in one try.
OK, that looks good.
Let's try it again.
Let's see what happens when we get it correct.
After two guesses, two incorrect guesses.
So let's do a one and a two and now eight.
The random number was eight.
You got it in three tries, so that's still looking good now.
I did mention that we also could have put some additional logic down here just to show what that might
have looked like.
Let's let's go down that road a little bit.
So let's see here.
Currently, we're exiting the entire program because of this return statement here.
But let's see what it looks like if we were to change this logic or add to it and say while guest Nintex
is not Q or and to do or inside of a criteria like this, we use these two pipe symbols to say or so
this allows us to test a couple of different Boolean expressions or wrong guess count.
Is less than five, I believe.
Sometimes you have to really think about these, these these scenarios where you're counting up to a
number, but you do or don't want to include it, right?
I think we want wrong guest count less than five rather than run guest count less than four.
Especially because we moved this variable down here, but we'll see in a moment.
All right.
So while as as long as you aren't hitting Q and or the now, let's think about this or also do we want
an order or do we want an end while Q is not pressed?
So let's say they did not hit Q, but wrong gas count is five, so that would.
So if you did not, it would be true.
Ah, OK.
So we have a problem in our logic here because if you did not hit Q, then this expression would evaluate
to being true and with an or only one of these has to be true to allow the loop to continue.
And that's not what we want.
We want it so that this loop will not continue if you hit Q or if the wrong guest count is is greater
than or equal to five.
So I think what we want here is actually we want this logic to be and and now let's let's analyze this.
So if you didn't hit Q, this will evaluate to true because this is if Q if guest number is not Q,
which it won't be most of the time, then this would be true.
But with this and here, that means that not only this has to be true, this one has to be true also.
So if you didn't hit Q, that's fine.
That'll be true.
However, also the wrong guest count has to be less than five, and as long as it's less than five,
then this would be true, too.
So both of these have to be true in order for this loop to continue in the event that you didn't press.
Q But you had four or more wrong guesses this would evaluate to false.
So you'd have a true and a false.
And because of this and here when you're doing a logical and what happens is that both parts have to
be true in order for the whole thing to evaluate to true.
Okay, so here I want to.
I want to be really clear about that because I know this can be kind of confusing.
OK.
So what I have created here is basically a truth table or a logic table, if you will.
And what you can glean from it is that there's only one scenario in which the loop can continue.
And that's the scenario where you didn't press Q and you have fewer than four or five.
Whatever it is, I guess this really should be a five.
Actually, you have fewer than five.
But then like, that's a five wrong guesses.
OK, that's the only scenario in which the Loop will continue.
All other scenarios result in the loop stopping, and the reason for that is because that's how a logical
end works for a logical and to evaluate to true, both clauses have to be true.
So here this is a true right.
You didn't press Q and the number of guesses the wrong number of guesses is is less than whatever the
magic number is, four or five.
It doesn't matter.
OK.
That's the only way that the Loop can continue any other scenario.
The loop will stop because of this and.
OK.
So saying like, you have to have this true and this true.
In order for the whole thing to be true, that's what you get with a logical end.
OK, now a couple of things.
It's generally considered bad to hard code numbers like this in your code.
These are called magic numbers, and the reason it's bad is because you can forget what those numbers
are and they're embedded deep in your code.
And what's the relationship between this number here and this number here?
These numbers are related, actually, and I'm still kind of guessing exactly how I need to, which
no, I really want to use here, but I can tell you that there's a relationship between these two.
Ideally, my logic should be consistent enough that these numbers should actually be the same number,
in fact.
So what we can consider doing here, if wrong guest count is greater than or equal to five, if wrong
guest count is greater than or equal to four.
OK.
Actually, I'm pretty sure this logic should say it's simply four.
And now what I'm inclined to do is to actually extract a constant out of this number.
So I'm going to select that number and then I can right click on it and I can refactor and I can introduce
a constant.
And now it's ask me, what do I want to name this constant?
And I'm going to name it in all caps because that's how we named constants.
Max allowed tries, right?
So the maximum number of tries that we will allow.
OK.
And then I hit return, and now I'm going to take this variable, copy it and then replace this for
with that as well, because that's duplication.
And now I can change the number of Macs allowed tries all in one place, which is at the top of the
program right here.
So it put that constant right here and set it equal to four.
OK.
And so you really want to avoid having magic numbers.
Now I have magic numbers in a number of places in this program, really.
Now I probably have.
Let's see where else do I have the magic number wrong?
Guest count equals one.
So technically this would be a magic number two, but I'm less worried about that one.
This one was fairly egregious, though, so I really wanted to make sure I got that one.
So now that we have the ability to end this loop with a couple of different ways.
I'm curious to see if we still need this return here because this return is how we were ending the loop.
So I'm going, I'm going to comment that out for right now, and let's just rebuild and run this again
and see if this bit right here is sufficient to kill the program when we guess too many times incorrectly.
Let's see what happens.
So I will rebuild.
All right, and then let's open our terminal and I'm going to clear whips and let's rerun it.
All right.
So let's guess incorrectly four times.
So the magic number is four.
So one to three are all right.
So it only gave us three tries and we didn't get our message.
And that is because of that's because of this logic here.
So it let us keep guessing as long as we are wrong.
Guesses were less than the magic number, which is four.
And that was three.
We can fix that without having to change this by simply saying less than or equal to.
Does that make sense while less?
While the wrong guest count is less than or equal to in this case for that would allow us to have the
four tries which would match up with the logic that we have here.
I believe the other way we could do this is to say while is to say wrong guest count less than max allowed
tried plus one, but that feels a little less elegant to me.
So let's try it this way.
All right.
So let's rebuild.
OK, and I'm going to clear.
And let's run it again.
All right.
Magic number is 10, so let's do one two three four.
Let's see here.
You've had four incorrect guesses.
The random number is 10 ending program now, so that worked, OK?
So that's another way that we could kill the loop, right?
Simply by testing whether or not we had too many wrong guesses right here using and and here.
So that's allowing us to test for multiple things.
Both of these have to be true in order for this loop to be allowed to run again.
And now with this approach, we don't have to exit out of the entire program explicitly here, though
I may somewhat prefer this approach because it's a little more clear, I think, but there are pros
and cons.
One of the things that I don't like that I have going on here now is all of the nesting.
Let's see.
So what I mean by that is basically all the levels of indentation that are going on here that starts
to be a lot for your brain to track and process in general, right?
I'm already in an if else block here and now I'm putting another if in there as well.
I don't like doing that.
If I can avoid it without making the code messy, I usually will prefer to avoid such things.
But in order to just get something working, according to the specifications that I made up, I decided
to just go this way, right?
But again, I will reiterate we really want to be careful about how many levels of nesting we put.
So I'm a little shy to go quite as far as to say you should only you should limit your levels of nesting
to X number of, you know, levels because there are always exceptions to everything.
Sometimes you can't avoid it.
Sometimes it's inappropriate to try to avoid that.
But as a general rule of thumb, I can just say that if I were doing this totally professionally, I
would probably want to spend a little more time rethinking this whole approach and seeing if there was
an elegant way for me to reduce the number of levels of nesting that I have going on here.
It's a bit much for my liking, but I guess I can get rid of that.
So actually, I can think of a way to simplify the level of nesting a little bit.
What we could do is we probably actually could just grab this if block here, cut it and just move it
right here.
I think we can do that.
And the reason why this is a little better is because now this additional if block here is no longer
nested inside of another if block, now it's at least on its own level by itself.
Let's see if this works.
So let's rebuild.
Let's clear.
Let's run it again.
Random number is eight.
Let's do four incorrect guesses one two three four.
OK, let's see, you've had five incorrect guesses.
Now this number is wrong, but everything else is working just fine.
And the reason that this number is wrong is because the last thing we're doing here is incrementing.
That number again, whereas before we had this if block right above this, and so that number had not
yet been incremented.
But this is easy enough to fix what we can do is simply say wrong.
Guess count.
Let's see.
So this is, we could say, wrong guest count minus one.
It's a slightly hacky thing that we can do, but it gets the job done.
So I would consider this to be a bit of an improvement over what we had before.
It simplifies the code a little bit more, in my opinion, because you've got one less nesting of if
statement or if block in here.
All right.
So I know that this may have been a little complicated.
Like I said at the start of it, though, I wanted to intentionally show you a little bit more of how
I might think through some of these problems.
And you really were seeing me think through these problems in real time.
I may end up editing a little bit, just some of the long pauses where I'm thinking I may edit out some
of my thinking time a little bit there because you don't want to sit there watching me just think,
Hmm, should I do it this way or that way?
But for the most part, you're seeing this very minimally edited.
So let's just recap.
So one of the main reasons why I went through this line of thinking is because I wanted you to see a
couple of alternative approaches to solving some of these problems.
Number one, I wanted you to see that we can put more complex logic as in the criteria places here for
the loops.
And, you know, just to overall get a better sense for how a professional programmer actually thinks
through these kinds of problems.
It's not magic.
Sometimes it's trial and error, and even I, with my decades of experience, just need to try some
things out occasionally.
Now, I could have done a little bit more static analysis where before I actually run the code, I sit
there and I kind of become the computer and I think through, OK, what are these variables going to
be?
Sometimes that's a good thing to do.
Sometimes it's a waste of time because it may be quicker just to run the darn program and see what happens,
right?
You'll have to be the judge of that.
All right.
So with that being said, let's in this lesson and I'll see you in the next one.