All right.
So let's pick back up where we left off.
So we had just finished implementing a little bit of logic to pass the details field of a programmer.
And now let's go ahead and finish up by passing the details field of the manager, analyst and CEO,
which will be easy because the Rig X will pretty much be the same.
The only difference will be the number of subfields within the detailed field and then the names of
those fields.
So down here is where we created the programmer.
So let's create one now for the manager.
OK, so I think we can even just start off by copying the programmer bits.
Come down here.
Do this.
Let's rename this to Manager Rig X and Manager Pattern, and then we'll just change this pattern here.
Let's see.
So the fields are org size and direct reports.
D.R.
All right.
So.
Org.
Is that how I called it?
Org org size and D.R..
And then we can get rid of everything else.
Like so.
Let me make sure I got that right.
Words equals org size, comma words equals direct reports.
Yep.
Oh, by the way, now when I was troubleshooting what my issue was earlier when this programmer regex
wasn't working.
You may recall I put in a number of additional things just to make sure that it wasn't an issue like
the equals sign had some special meaning or whatever.
I'm pretty sure I we don't really need these escaped things here.
And in fact, you know, I will.
I'll take them out here and confirm that.
So, yeah, we'll get rid of these.
I think that's it.
And then if this works, then I'll come back and clean this one up as well.
All right.
And then in the case of the manager will do similar things as what we did for programmers.
So let's see here.
We extracted out the details.
We can just duplicate that line and bring it down to the manager.
And then we created our matchers, who will do that matter?
This is the manager matcher equals manager pattern matcher and then we'll match on details.
And then we'll test if we have a match.
So if manager, match or find, then we'll do some stuff, so we'll set up a variable to grab the salary.
Salary equals zero.
And then inside of here, let's see now what are these?
These values are all numeric and they are all integers.
So we can we can use the integer wrapper again, integer dot pass and see manager Matt.
Sure.
Dot Group.
And I've already forgotten the names of the fields.
Org size and direct reports.
Org size.
And I guess I can just duplicate this.
Direct reports, I'm writing it out, spelling it out, and then we'll just call that dear.
All right.
So now we'll have that data.
And for now, I think we'll just do the same basic math.
Let's see.
Salary equals 3500 plus or size times.
Direct reports.
And again, this is just, you know, some random formula, I'm just making this up something simple,
it could it could be way more complex than this.
If we wanted to wanted it to be right, the square root of something times whatever it could be anything.
All right.
And then we'll set up our else block.
Else salary equals just 3500 on its own.
And then we will yield salary.
And let's comment out this system that out here, and let's run this, see what we've got now.
Wow, that really blew up into a larger number, didn't it?
And we're not even done yet, so seven million.
OK, that makes sense, though, because we're doing a lot of multiplication.
And then let's set up the Reg X for the analyst, right?
So, again, copy.
Paste.
Analyst.
And last.
And then the fields here, there's only one and it's project count, so I will just put it right here.
Project count and then I will get rid of all of that because that's the part with the comma and there
is no comma here.
Oh my bad.
I forgot to update where these what the pattern was supposed to be compiling the pattern here.
The manager pattern should be compiling.
The manager rejects my bad.
Yeah.
See how easy it is to make little dumb mistakes like this.
And then the yeah, we want this rejects here.
Some of you probably saw that and were yelling at your screen.
All right.
Out of curiosity, let me run that again and see what the number will change to.
Hmm.
Not much, not different or not much different, I don't remember it was seven million something before.
Well, whatever.
And I'm going to get rid of that.
All right.
And same as before, I will copy this line.
Paste it right there.
Then create a new, mature, mature analyst.
Matt Equals Analyst.
Pat Matcher.
Details.
Then.
Set up our variable here, then.
If analyst matcher, find if it finds anything, then we will do some stuff here.
So we will.
Let's see.
I mean, double check.
I think the data here is also numerical, right?
This is the analyst.
Yep.
So integer pass and
analyst matcher Dot Group and the name of the field was project count, I think.
Project count.
Then capture that into a variable called Project Count, and then we will do some formula here, salary
equals.
Let's see, what do we want to do here?
It was based off of 2500, 25 000 plus just do something like project count times to maybe project count
times two.
All right.
Else?
Salary equals 2500.
And then just return the salary.
All right.
And then the last one is the CEO.
All right, let's set that up.
This time, I'll use the.
Little trick here of multiple cursors, so I can.
Take care of this all at once, c e o, and then I'll grab that name that rejects there and put it here.
All right.
And now we'll set up this last block new line.
Copy this again, paste it right there.
Create a new matter.
CEO Matt Equal, CEO Pat Matcher details.
Set up our salary variable.
If CEO matcher Dot find then.
Let's pass out.
Integer percent.
CEO matcher Scott Group.
And the group name there was a project.
No.
Average stock price, so I forgot to update that, didn't I?
Average stock price.
Make sure I was updating this, so the analyzer has a project account.
The manager has organized and direct reports that were good.
OK.
Average stock price for the CEO.
A veggie stock price, is that how I wrote it?
A big stock price, yes.
And capture that.
There we go.
Salary equals 5000.
And for this, let's do Time's average stock price otherwise.
Salary equals just the base 5000 and then yield the salary.
All right.
Let's run all of this.
Eight million.
Now, let's let's print out, let's print a little output here just to kind of double check that this
is actually correct.
Let's see.
So what we can do is maybe we'll just print out the salary and a formatted way.
Percent Skogland percent this.
In the first person, deaths will be, oh, let's see, I guess, their name.
People matter, not group.
Last name.
All right, so hold on, maybe then.
Last name, comma, first name.
First name, and let's I guess let's extract these two, so it's a little easier to read.
Turn that into a.
String do the same thing for this one here.
First name.
And.
Duplicate that line and then this bit here, will you actually I guess that's all.
And then the last bit will be the salary, and let's let's format that salary.
Let's see if we can do this all in one.
I don't know if it's going to look too messy or not, but let's see.
So we'll use a number formatter.
Does it get currency instance dot format?
Salary.
Yeah, it fits.
All right, then we're going to grab all of this.
And duplicate that in in each of these cases.
Now the reason we kind of need to do it this way, I'd prefer to do it one time in this whole entire
block of code here.
But the salary is unique to each case, and I want that all printed on one line.
And so for right now, without me thinking about it too deeply, I think we need to do it this way.
Now I can think of some smarter things to do that we might actually do later.
Well, there's lots of smarter things we can do.
In fact, just so you know, I'm intentionally doing this semi painful, long, protracted implementation
so that you can have a better appreciation for some of the alternative ways that we could do this.
OK, so I'm doing it in this way on purpose, and I will point out a few facts about the way that that
this is being done, in fact.
All right.
So there's that.
So we'll just pop that code right above every place where we yield the salary, I guess.
So here.
And here.
All right, let's run that and see if we get some, some output here.
I forgot to forgot to put new lines in.
Here will do it all in one.
So cursor there.
Cursor here.
And cursor here, and then we'll do percent in in all of those places all at once.
All right, see what I did there, I just put the percent in in all of these spots all at once with
an option shift and then a click to put the cursor in all those places at once.
All right, and then we'll rerun this control.
Shift our.
All right.
Let's see what we've got here, Fred Flintstone.
2.8 mil, one point eight.
So that's almost three, that's almost two, that's five, six seven.
Seven point five.
Hmm.
Yeah, okay, I guess this number is correct.
That was the main reason that I wanted to point these out.
I was trying to gauge whether or not the salaries made sense.
But yeah, I see it now.
It's because Programmer had three three detail properties and I'm multiplying those by each other.
And so that makes this number quite a bit larger.
And then these other roles, I think all only had two details, right?
So I'm talking about.
Here, just two numbers, although that's not a small number, but I guess that ends up being 3000 vs.
oh yeah, here we are.
Yeah.
These numbers are all in the thousands generally to begin with.
Times 10 times numbers in the 100.
So that's why those values those.
Yeah, that's why these these amounts get pretty big, pretty quickly.
Yeah.
OK, so that number makes sense to me.
That's all.
I just wanted to double check if that number actually was making sense.
I think it does.
All right.
So I'm going to assume that this is all correct.
Let's see here now what can we say about this implementation?
So yeah, let's let's look at this now.
So I have no doubt that some of you, some of you will be looking at this and are struggling to understand
what's going on here.
And that's partially the point.
Now some of you may be right there with me, but it'll be kind of hit or miss.
So let me tell you my own sense of looking at this and working on it.
It's getting to be kind of scary looking for me.
I don't typically write code like this.
This is not my natural way of writing code.
And what do I mean by that?
Well, let's see here.
So we've got one.
For me, this is one monster method.
OK.
It's one.
It's a whole entire program implemented in one method.
I haven't coded this way since I was a young kid who didn't know how to code better than this.
I don't normally code this way anymore, but I'm intentionally doing it for you.
Now I want to point out something I know lots and lots and lots and lots of programmers who probably
don't really see anything wrong with this code as long as it works.
They think they're done.
And let me tell you, just getting the code to work doesn't really mean you're done.
Maybe it's a start, but you're not really done.
So the problem with writing code like this?
First off, this is completely procedural.
OK, Java is an object oriented language, which simply means that it lends itself towards somewhat
easily writing object oriented code.
It does not mean that all of your code that you write in Java is truly object oriented.
This code here is not object oriented at all.
You could have written equivalent code like this or very similar to this in any procedural language,
such as the language of C, which was invented in like 1970 or something, right?
This is very procedural code.
Furthermore, there are lots of duplicated blocks within here.
I mean, the fact that I was able to copy and paste bits and pieces all over the place is a strong indication
that there's a lot of duplication there.
OK.
So we're not taking advantage of hardly any of the benefits of Java's object oriented capabilities with
this implementation and just looking at it.
And in even while I was working on it, it started to get really easy for me to lose track of what I
was doing and where I was.
So I kind of, you know, stuck with this approach on purpose, and I kind of wanted you to feel the
pain of me hunting and looking out, OK, where am I now?
Because that's what it feels like to write overly procedural code that isn't very good.
And by the way, notice I said overly procedural code that isn't very good, which means, I mean,
it is possible to write good procedural code, but very few developers that I've ever known who who
tend to write procedural code, write good procedural code and by good, I mean code, that's relatively
easy to maintain.
Let me also state that if you are a if you are relatively new to programming, as I assume the majority
of you who are taking this course will be, you may have the misconception that writing complicated
looking code and perhaps this looks somewhat complex to you.
It's, you know, it's not it's not fun for me to look at.
I can tell you that, you know, I'm having to use a little bit more brainpower than I'd like to now
on the scale of complexity of code that I've worked on.
This isn't at the top of my list for sure.
I've worked on way harder stuff than this, but particularly for what it's doing, which is something
relatively simple, which is just basically applying some dumb, you know, formula to these numbers,
parsing them out and then just adding up some values, right?
It's unfortunately more complex than I would like it to be.
So anyway, my point was going to be, I think there are a lot of particularly novel.
Or new programmers who may write code like this and like their code to be this way because it makes
them feel smart as if they've done something intelligent by writing this type of code.
Let me tell you something right here and right now you're not all that smart to write this, OK?
This is a bit of a mess.
The smartest programmers that I have worked with could take this and make it look so simple that no
one would be impressed by it at all.
It would look really obvious in terms of, Oh yeah, obviously, you know, you wrote the code to to
be very simple such that anyone can understand it.
But the the irony here is that taking something like this and rewriting it to be really, really trivial
looking and very, very simple oftentimes is actually quite difficult to do.
OK?
The easiest thing a programmer can do is make a big mess like this.
Because think about it to make a big mess like this, you don't have to put a lot of forethought into
it.
You just start kind of writing code stream of consciousness until you get it to do whatever it is that
you were setting out to do.
And as soon as it does that bare minimum thing, then you just kind of stop right there.
OK.
So I think that's the main thing that I want to convey with this approach is that this isn't great at
all.
This should not be what you're aiming for.
OK.
You should be striving to do way, way better than this.
Now, within a procedural approach, there are some things that I could have done to be better, such
as I could have extracted this block here, which is duplicated.
What is it?
Four times or so I could have extracted a method out of that and then just had one line, which is the
call to that method.
And in that method, we'd just be passing in the salary and everything else.
Well, we'd be passing in the salary.
And I don't know, maybe the the match or the people match or I guess, just passing in maybe two inputs.
And then it would print this stuff out, and that would have made this code a little better.
And there might be other opportunities to extract methods out.
If I did, if I took the time to do a little more analysis here.
And that's one thing.
Like a lot of programmers who naturally write code like lists, they don't take the time to really think
it through and analyze.
OK.
So in the next few lessons, that's what we're going to be doing now.
We're going to be kind of analyzing this and trying out a number of different approaches to improve
this code using more of Java's object oriented capabilities.
OK.
All right.
So yeah, let's let's jump into that in the next lesson.