Hey, there.
This will be a quick lesson to go into a little bit more detail on some of the fundamentals of class
hierarchy in Java.
To get into this conversation, we're going to jump back over to the original Hello World project.
And I'm going to go over to the person class.
And if you recall when we were working on this person class, you may not remember this.
I know it might feel like it was a million years ago, but you may recall that on the person class,
we implemented a method called two string, which taught Java how to print essentially a representation
of the data that is contained inside of a person object.
OK, and we had the idea to generate this method for us.
It's OK.
If you don't fully remember this, you can go back and watch that part of that video.
But don't worry, we're going to again.
As with many things, I want to repeat a number of concepts a number of times.
So anyway, one of the things that I sort of glossed over was the fact that in order to implement this
method, we were technically overriding and I didn't explain a whole lot about what that meant.
But I want to touch on it a little bit more here.
So in that lesson, we actually implemented a class hierarchy.
We had a class called pet, and then we created a couple more classes that extended the pet class.
So we had cat and dog.
In fact, they'll just open them up real quick.
So cat extends pet, which is to say that cat is a type of pet.
And in just a quick reminder, the reason we'd want to do that is because the pet class might have some
useful properties, some fields and some and or some behaviors, some methods that are very useful to
us, but not enough.
And we may want to further extend the capabilities of what a pet object can do.
And so we could create a cat class and then add some additional behaviors and or fields or data that
might be more specific to a cat that pet doesn't have.
But we still want cat to have all of the capabilities that the pet had.
Also, right, so extends allows us to do this, and this is a class hierarchy.
OK?
And this is getting into a lot of the essence of what it is to program in an object oriented way.
Same thing here for dog.
OK, so we had a method called Bark Person Class does not explicitly extend anything.
So I want to explain what it means to override a method, though.
So basically overriding a method is when you have a class that extends another class.
So I'll go back over to cat.
So in other words, cat extends pet.
And if we go take a look at the pet class, pet has a few methods on it.
It's got these illustrative methods protected method and package protected method here.
And then it's got to get name and set name, get date of birth, et cetera, et cetera.
Right.
In fact, here we go.
It even has a two string method it overrode.
So by default, our cat class would inherit the two string method of the pet class.
And therefore, any time we wanted to print a cat, we would get this output.
And in fact, you know what?
Let's let's just do that real quick.
Tell you what.
For now, I'm just going to introduce a public static void main method right here.
And we will create an instance of a cat cat one equals new cat, and then we will print cat one system
that out that print line cat one.
So this will cause the two string method of the pet class to be called.
It will spit out a string and then that string will be printed on the screen here.
We'll take another look at that.
So we're in the pet class.
This is the two string method.
It returns a string.
And here's the string, it returns.
So it's a string that's going to say Pat and then a curly brace and then name and date of birth.
OK.
So because that two string method is public, whenever we pass an object into a method that is expecting
a string, Java will automatically call the two string method of that object.
OK, so let's run this real quick.
And by the way, notice I just put a public static void main method on some random class cat.
You can put a public static void main method on any class and run run code from within it.
All right.
So here's our output pet, blah blah blah, right?
So that did what we expected it to do.
Now here's the thing.
What if we don't want the word pet to be printed out when we pass a cat into a print line statement?
What if we want something that's more specific to a cat?
Well, we can override the two string method, and in the one way we can do that is to simply put our
cursor on an empty line inside of the class and then use on Mac Control Zero.
And we can look for the method we want to override.
So what this is showing me is all of the methods and constructors that are on the pet class that I want
to override.
So I want to override the two string method so I can select that and click, OK.
And now I get this.
What's called annotation will learn about annotations later, but I get this special annotation, and
it's just like a clue which just tells us this method exists in a super class of the class we're currently
in, and the superclass of Cat would be pet.
So it's telling us there's already a two string method in pet and you're about to replace it.
And by default, if we do nothing, this method is simply going to turn around and call the pet that
two string method.
Remember, this super word here means the class or the class hierarchy above wherever we currently are.
So we're currently in cat.
So the class above cat would be pet.
So this is basically saying call pet that to string.
OK, but we have to use the word super here.
If we were to have the word pet, that would not be valid because that would imply that two string is
a static method, which it is not.
And so the only way we can access the two string method of pet from within cat is to use the super keyword.
All right.
So if we just do this well here, we'll run this again.
We get the same thing, and that makes sense because we haven't actually changed anything.
We're.
Yes, we are overwriting this, but then we're turning right around and then just still calling the
pet dot to string.
What we really want to do is to completely change this and get rid of that.
And we can do that.
Just like this.
And all we need to do is make our own string with whatever we want.
So let's say that we want this to say.
Cat hyphen name, Tony.
And that's it.
Now this isn't very useful because we're actually hard coding what's called hard coding the name here.
And what I mean by that is no matter what we name this cat, the name Tony is always going to print
out because we didn't turn this into a variable here.
We've hardcoded it, but let's just see what happens here if we run this now.
OK, so look at that now we get different output cat name Tony.
So we have literally overridden the two string method that we are inheriting from PET.
We've told Java forget about the two string method in the pet class.
I want to implement my own two string method.
And here it is.
And so that's what we've just done here.
Now.
That's not the main thing I wanted to convey in this lesson.
What I really want to convey is this If we go over here to pet, I mean, come down here.
So Pet has its own two string method.
Let me let me close this window.
All right.
So Pet has its own two string method.
And notice it also is being overridden, which means that this method to string on the pet class is
coming from a parent class.
OK, and and in the pet class, we're overriding it right?
So just like Cat was overriding pets to string, Method Pet is overriding some other classes to string
method.
However.
If we go up here, look at that pet isn't extending anything, in other words.
There is no parent class of pet, at least not explicitly, there isn't.
So how is it that we're overriding a two string method?
What class are we overriding for this method?
Because there's nothing shown here.
And that is what I want to talk about.
OK, so short answer for every single class in Java.
If that class is not already extending a class explicitly, there is a default parent class that it
will extend.
Let me say that again.
Basically, I'm saying.
All classes extend from one standard parent class if they're not already explicitly extending something.
So in the case here, PET is not explicitly extending anything but it, but it is implicitly extending
something, and the thing that it is extending is a class called object.
So.
What you see here.
Public class pet.
Is equivalent to.
To that, and I have not changed the behavior of this class at all because this is implied.
OK, I've made it explicit now, but this is what was already there.
We just weren't seeing it.
So there is a class above all other classes called object and every other class in all of Java extends
object, either directly or indirectly.
It might be its great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great, great parent.
But one way or another, every class extends from the original class of object, and this object class
actually has a few methods on it.
And one of those methods is the two string method here.
Now we can see what other methods are on object pretty easily, at least on object, for us to extend
by simply going to some white space and then doing another control.
Oh, control, oh, by the way, stands for override.
So we can tell the ABC we want to override one or more methods that are inherited.
And so by doing control of this comes up, and it shows me what other methods are available for me to
override.
There's something called hash code, which returns an end integer.
There's a method called equals that takes an object and returns what's called a boolean.
I don't recall if I explain Boolean, but that basically just means a true or false yes or no on or
off.
There's a method called Clone.
And then there's a method here that is being phased out called finalize, so we don't really want to
be looking at that.
It's going to be phased out or it is being phased out.
OK.
And then the other method that isn't showing up here is the two string method.
The reason it's not showing up is because the ATP knows we're already overriding that.
So it's not showing it here, but that would be another method.
OK, so in conclusion, this explains how a method like print line is able to accept any object, no
matter what type it is.
Cat dog, space ship, whatever.
Even though the print line method wasn't explicitly written to know about any of these specific methods
that you might write in the future, it still knows how to print a string representation of any of those
objects.
And that's because no matter what their class type is, they all extend from a common ancestor of type.
Object and object has a two string method on it.
And so the print line method simply knows that it can always count on that two string method existing.
There is no object in Java that doesn't have a two string method.
Now you can override that method, if you like, but if you don't, they're still going to be a default
implementation of that method.
And of course, as I stated before, not only is there a two string method, but there are several other
methods.
And as we saw, some of those other methods on the object class were methods like equals and hash code.
So this has just been a quick introduction to the fact that all classes in Java ultimately extend either
directly or indirectly from the original parent class of object, and therefore they inherit a few methods
from that class.
We will explore the implications of this further in subsequent lessons, and I will see you in the next
one.