All right, so now we're getting ready to put everything we've learned together into a small program
that is getting to a little bit more of a realistic set of scenarios now.
So for this next lesson, we're going to run through an actual scenario.
So let's imagine that you are a programmer working at some office.
And in fact, let's say you're a programmer working for a school district.
And let's say that this school district has transcripts that are on paper that they've printed out,
let's say, from decades ago before they used computerized records.
And they want to somehow scan these transcripts, these these printed out transcripts and get the data
that is contained in the transcripts loaded into a computer database so that it can be searched and
manipulated further in a computer.
OK, now one step for them to do this is that they can take these printed out transcripts and scan them
with a computer and perform what is called OCR or optical character recognition, so that the end result
would be text files.
OK.
However, just having those documents scanned with text files are to produce text files is not enough
to get the data into a database in the way that they wanted.
And so a programmer is going to be needed to further parse those text files and parse out all the little
fields of it, like the first name and the last name and things of that sort.
OK.
And so that's what we're going to do.
So on the website, for my course where you're currently watching this specific video, there will be
a file for you to download and let me show you what that will look something like.
OK, so right down here, you should have a file called transcript example that text.
If you click on that, you can download it.
OK.
And once it has been downloaded, you can open it.
And so here's the contents of it.
So it's not a full transcript, it's just kind of like the header part of a transcript.
By the way, I did base this on a real transcript.
So we've just got a simple text file here.
So you've got several field student number colon and then a student number and then a grade and birthdate
gender things of this sort.
OK, so now we're not going to do this 100 percent real, but we're going to do it about 85 to 90 percent
real.
You haven't learned yet how to use Java to read a file and grab the text or data out of the file.
So we're going to skip that part for right now, and we're going to do it the easier way.
Well, for for a one off, and that is simply to copy and paste.
So we're going to select all of that.
You can either do on Mac Command A to select everything or control a on Windows and Linux, I believe.
And then a control C or Command C to copy.
And then we're going to come back over to the ADC here.
And actually, you know, let's make a new class for this.
So again, I'm going to right click on the SIRC or source folder here.
New Java class.
And let's call this something like.
Transcript parser no spaces.
And again, you're free to call this class whatever you like, but you probably want to name it something
meaningful and useful in real life.
You would.
All right.
Transcript parser.
And then I'll make a new line and we'll want a public static void.
Main method SVM All lowercase hit return.
And there we go.
OK, now one thing we can do just kind of easily here is we can create a string and we can name this
something like transcript, and I would go ahead and make a text block string or a multi line string.
And do you remember how to do that with three quotes, right?
And then the ADC automatically puts us pretty much where we want to be here.
Now, I prefer to have one extra line before the closing three quotes there and put a semicolon there
as well.
Then I'm going to go back up to my line for here and now I can just paste right here, right?
Because we copied that, that text file.
OK, so this would be kind of equivalent to if we had written file IO code.
That's what it's called the kind of code that would know how to open up a file and then load the text
in that file into memory or something.
We're going to kind of simulate we're going to skip that step and simulate that we already got everything
loaded into a variable.
OK.
And so this approach will only work one time each.
But if we did this with file IO, then we could have a bunch of transcript files or text files in a
folder, let's say.
And we could have our code open up each and every one of those files and then pass it right.
But in our case, we're just going to pass one for now.
All right.
So here's our transcript.
And what we want to do here is we want to pass out.
All of these fields right into their own variables, or at least print them out or something like that,
right?
We want to see to each of these fields.
In fact, on this date one here, we might even want to just get the individual parts right.
The day, month and year, the gender character code, their state I.D. and then the actual waited and
unweighted GPAs.
Right.
So that's the goal.
That's what we want to do.
All right.
So.
We now know just about everything we need to know to be able to pull this off.
All right, so where to begin?
Well, we probably want to do some setup here for using regular expressions.
Do you remember the basic pattern for doing nontrivial regular expressions?
We need a a pattern and we need a match, right?
So I'm going to go ahead and and start typing Patty.
And then the ADP gives me what I'm looking for, which is this class pattern under Java Util Rig X and
I can just hit return.
And by hitting return, I'm not just telling it what I want.
I'm going to cause the ADP to import this class for me.
So that's one reason why it's kind of let me show you something here.
If you if you just start typing the whole thing out and you hit space and you were to just keep going
like this, I see some programmers oops.
I see some programmers code this way where they just kind of ignore the errors and stuff.
Oftentimes, when I see programmers who code this way, they actually get themselves into trouble a
little bit, it seems, because they forget to import these things later on.
And somehow they're just like oblivious to the read errors and stuff.
So I actually prefer not to code that way.
I like to address the errors beforehand or even not have the errors to begin with.
So if you just type a few letters here until you get that pattern there and then you just hit, enter
bam, you're not going to get any errors because immediately it imports this and it finishes typing
this out for you anyway.
So it's actually less less work and less error prone.
All right.
And again, I'm just going to call this patty and then we don't do new for pattern.
We do pattern dot compile.
Right?
OK.
And it's red now because I need to give it some input here.
So for right now, let's see.
I'm going to just give it empty strings and we'll come back and fill that in.
All right.
So we'll just stop right there for four right now, and then we're going to need a matcher, so I'll
do the same thing.
I'll just type enough to get the aid to show me what I'm looking for class wise, which is this Java
util rig x matcher.
So I'll hit return on that and I'll call this an eighty equals.
And then to get an actual instance of the matter again, we don't do new.
We also don't do this.
Instead, we use the pattern that we just created dot matcher.
And then as input into this, we give it the text or the string that we want to do some matching on.
And so that in this case would be the transcript variable.
And then I can close that.
Next, we need to trigger the regular expression engine to actually go do a match or find some matches
or whatever.
And as we did before, I would typically put that inside of a and a conditional block and if statement
like this, if and then parentheses.
And then you can do math that matches.
And then close that parentheses there and then an opening curly brace, and then when you hit return,
you'll get a closing curly brace automatically on line 18.
OK.
And so this is kind of like the boilerplate or one type of boilerplate for using the Java Rejects engine,
and this should be this kind of review for you now.
All right.
So assuming you had any match, whatever code we put in between these curly braces is going to get executed,
otherwise nothing is going to get executed.
OK?
So what is the first thing we want to be able to do here?
I think the first thing is we want to be able to grab that right there.
So I think what I'll do here is I'm going to extract the variable for the regular expression.
So I just put my cursor right in between these two quotes here, and I'm going to do an option up arrow
or control W to select all of that.
And then I will do an option command V or control alt v and extract a variable from that.
And I will take the default variable name here or the suggested variable name of Rig X and just hit
return.
OK, so now we got that, and then if I put the cursor here, so now I can start writing an actual regular
expression that will match this whole entire multi-line text.
And let me do some captcha groups to grab these key fields of data, right?
All right.
So what do we need to do here?
Do you want to have a thought?
First, you want to pause and think about how you might start this off and then catch back up with me
and see.
OK.
So I think the first thing I would do is start with this bit here, and I would treat this as a string
literal.
It's a good idea here is we're looking for anchor points places where we can say you're kind of wanting
to leapfrog from things that you do know to things that you don't know.
So this would be something you wouldn't know.
But this part here is not likely ever to change within the format or within the report, right?
The transcript.
So you know that you can tell the computer of the regex engine, look for the words student number colon
and then maybe look for a space and then look for so many digits and remember that, right?
So that's that's a a strategy.
OK, so let's try something like that.
So student number.
Colon space.
And then we want so many digits now.
Honestly, I don't know if the format of this in real life is such that the this number of digits is
always going to be the exact same on every report.
How many do you have?
One two three four five six seven eight nine 10.
Let's pretend like it's always going to be 10 digits exactly, though.
All right, so how do we represent a digit?
Baghdadi, right, is a digit and we want 10 of them, exactly.
So how can we do that with the curly brace?
10.
Right.
Just like that.
Now we want to capture that, though, so we can encapsulate that inside of parentheses.
And as you know, I'm fond of using named capture groups.
And so to create a named capture group, we can use.
Question mark.
And then less than and greater than symbol.
And then put the cursor here and then give it a name.
So this would be a student number, and I'll just abbreviate that to student numb.
Now again, you can call it whatever you like.
And I'm going to give myself a little room here also includes that the project pane there on the on
the left.
OK.
So we've got that now.
Let's see here if we come down here and go ahead and print this out.
Even so, we can get that capture group from the matcher object here, right?
So we can say Matt for matcher group Colon Quest are quote quotes and then student numbe just like that.
All right.
Let's run that and see what we get.
Hmm.
Nothing matches.
We didn't get a match.
Why would that be?
Well, there's a few reasons for that.
First off, so we created a rig that supposedly will match up to hear a lot about all the rest of this
string, right?
We didn't tell the Rig X engine what to do with the rest of this.
Right?
OK, so this is where we get into a few of those additional character classes and symbols that we learned
recently.
And so one of the easiest things we might try is to tell the regular expression engine.
For now, we don't care about the rest of this stuff at all.
We don't really care about it.
And so we could do something like use the the the dot that we learned and tell it that the rest of this
string will just be zero or more characters that we don't care about.
And we could could possibly do that with Dot and then an asterisk, right?
Because zero or more?
Right.
So that should gobble up all of the rest of this string.
Presumably.
So let's see if that works.
So we'll run this again.
OK.
So, nope, that still doesn't work.
Now I'm kind of taking you through the flow of how you might actually figure out how to get something
like this working.
I obviously already know what this is, but I just kind of want to show you so that if I jumped to the
exact approach, you wouldn't appreciate why we had to do what we had to do to make this work.
So that's why I'm kind of going piecemeal here.
All right.
So that still doesn't work.
OK.
So part of the problem here is that the Java rejects engine by default won't allow the DOT symbol here
to match just a couple of characters.
And those couple of characters are the new line character and the carriage return that we looked at
a little bit ago on the ASCII table.
So any place in this string where there may be new lines and carriage returns, such as at the ends
here won't match this period, and therefore the entire string doesn't match with this expression.
But we can change that by changing the mode that the regex engine is running in.
And if you'll recall, we can change the mode of the are the options of the Rejects engine down here
when we compile it.
So if we add a second parameter here?
We can pass in another parameter, which will be a toggle, if you will, of a mode with.
And that's a constant that is under the pattern class.
So if we type Pattern Dot now, we get to see all these capitalized things here.
These are all constants called constants because they won't change of of additional modes, if you will,
that we can enable.
And the mode that we need here is called Dot all.
So what this does is it tells the regular expression engine to allow the DOT to match not only on all
the characters that you would normally expect it to, but also on carriage returns and new lines or
form feeds.
OK.
So just makes that period match a few more things than it normally would.
All right.
And so let's see what we get now.
So we've enabled the Dot Hall.
All right.
Still not matching.
So the next issue we may want to be careful of here, seeing as how we're not getting a match yet is
in the use of these literal spaces contained within our regular expression in more complex or advanced
rag axes.
You probably want to be a little more explicit about what you're really expecting here, rather than
just depending on or relying on these literals here.
So I would actually get rid of these at this point and replace them with explicit spaces.
Now, for now, I'm going to just hard code that I'm only expecting one space because I wouldn't expect
that that would ever change in this part of the transcript, right?
Because that's probably a static field there.
Maybe the same goes for this space here.
So I will just encode one static space for each of those.
Let's see what we get now.
Hey, there we go.
And now we're getting a match.
OK.
So, yeah, so like I said, I kind of want to take you through the evolution of creating one of these
regular expressions so that you can see the all the little kinds of things to look out for.
Typical typical things.
All right.
So, yeah, so we're able to match that field now.
And next thing we will want to grab is the grade.
Now, let's also try to make our regex more readable, right from the right from the get go.
And so we learned that we could comment right.
We could enable comments on our regular expressions on the engine itself.
In the way to do that is to add another flag here.
These are called flags, flags in computer programming or just things that you can toggle on or off,
right?
So the way we can do this is to add in another flag and we do that by I'm going to put a space here
and then I'm going to use what's called the pipe character, which is this tall thing.
It's on the same key as the backslash, so that's probably looking that way for you.
Maybe I'm not sure this is a backslash.
So whatever key you're using to make that press that width shift and then you'll get a pipe.
OK?
And in this case, that pipe character really means.
Or maybe in another lesson, I'll explain the ways operations a little bit, just so you have a slightly
better understanding of why this works the way that it does.
But for now, just memorize that I'm showing you to do it this way.
All right.
So we'll grab another one of these flags, which is the comments which we've seen before.
So now we're enabling comments as well.
All right.
And now that we've been able, we might want to go out and just run this again, make sure we didn't
break anything.
OK, cool.
So that's still working.
We're still pulling that student number out.
OK, so now we can make our regex a little start getting it ready to be a little nicer.
And the way that I like to do that is to make it a multi string.
So I'm going to add two more quotes there and two more here as well, and then put this on its own line
like so and maybe I'm going to end this little bit.
OK.
And I think I'll also put this on its own line, too.
All right, so first, let's just run it again, make sure we didn't break anything.
Cool still works very good.
OK, so now we can comment a little bit.
So I will put a comment here.
Grab Student Number.
All right.
And now we can go for the grade.
So now the way we ended this expression was to capture that student number and then we told it pretty
much to ignore all.
Well, we sort of told it to not care about all the rest of this string here.
So that's from this point, right?
Because we we captured that student number and then from this point on.
All of all of this here is represented by the DOT star, right?
The Dot means any character.
And then the star means zero or more of them, so as many as you can grab, which ends up grabbing the
entire thing.
So now we don't quite want that because we want to go up to this grade here.
So let's try one or two techniques and see which ones will work for us to get that grade.
So what I would be inclined to do is pretty much follow this same pattern here.
So in fact, I'm going to just duplicate that line, for starters.
OK.
And then we'll put the word grade here.
I'm going to get rid of no, because we don't have that, but I'm going to keep the colon because we
do have a colon here.
And then we have a space, however, now here we only had one space, but here we can clearly see there
are more than one space is there.
So how can we do more than one space?
We could say plus, right?
That means one or more spaces.
Right?
OK.
And then we've got our capture group here.
Now here, we're saying we're expecting 10 digits, but here I'm going to assume this could be maybe
one or two.
I'm not sure what it would say if it were a nine.
I don't know if it would have a leading zero, like zero nine like here zero nine.
I don't know if it would be that way or if it would just show a nine.
So two to play it safe.
I'm just going to allow this to be one or two characters long.
OK.
So how do we say one or two characters or between one and two characters?
Well, we can come here and we can do a one.
Comma, too.
Just like that.
And so now this could be one character, long or two characters long.
And then we need to change the name of this unnamed capture group, and I'm going to just use the name
of that field there because that makes the most sense grade.
Notice again, though, I'm using all lowercase here just as a Java convention, even though technically
in this project's here, I'm not coding in Java now.
I'm coding in regular expressions, but from my named CAPTCHA groups, the I'm going to stick with the
typical Java naming conventions for the most part.
Treat these as if they were variables.
OK, and then at the end, we still have the Dot star to grab all the rest of it.
So let's see if this works.
Oh, well, hold on.
Now we want to do something with it also.
So I'm going to duplicate that line and change this to grade.
And then let's run it and see if that works.
Looks like that worked.
So, yeah, we've got the student number and then we've got the grade there.
This is starting to look like it's probably going to be relatively easy to do.
Don't you think?
All right.
So let's continue on, Will.
I'm going to I think I'm going to just duplicate this again.
And this time, I will anchor my rejects on the word birth date.
Just like that.
Now here, I might want each of these fields separately.
And I can do that pretty easily with separate capture groups.
Right?
So let's see what we have here.
We've got birthday, Colin and then more than one space, which we have here, more than one space.
And then we've got a two digit number, and that is the month.
So in the U.S. where we're, you know, we do everything differently from the rest of the world.
For those of you who are not in the U.S., in the U.S., standard dates usually start with the month,
then the day of the month and then the year.
I know, like pretty much the whole rest of the world does the the day of the month and then the month
and then the year.
And honestly, as a programmer in a supposedly logical thinker that does make more sense.
You're kind of going from the what is it, from the most specific to the most general or so?
But in the U.S., that's just not how we roll.
So I'm going to assume that this is the month here in the U.S..
All right.
And as such, I'm going to name this named CAPTCHA Group Month just like that.
However, now I want to grab the other two bits as well, and they are separated by forward slash.
So I'm going to put a forward slash here.
And in fact, I'm going to just grab all of that and I'm going to paste that again, and then I'm going
to put one more forward slash and paste again, just like that.
And now I'm just going to change these names.
So that was a month.
Then the next one is day.
If you're in the U.S. and we're kind of backward sometimes.
And then this last one will be easier now.
The year appears to be four digits long, and I'm going to guess it's always going to be exactly four
digits long.
In fact, you know, we can clean up the other ones as well.
So that's exactly four, and it looks like these other two are exactly two.
So I don't think we need to be so flexible there.
It doesn't look like it because we've got leading zeros in this format.
So that's why I just went in and said it's going to be exactly two, two and four.
OK.
All right.
Now one other thing too, I just realized probably it would be a little better because this isn't just
some any old date, this is the birth date.
Right?
So I think I actually prefer to call this field birth and then capital and birth month.
Earth Day.
And birth year using camel case, though.
All right.
And so then down here we can print these out.
I'm going to duplicate this line to three.
And we'll see.
Birth month.
Let's.
Earth looks day.
And birth year.
Let's see what we get.
I'm going to run this now.
Looks like we got it.
11:00, is that is that correct?
Oh, 11 was the grade and then, yep, January the 2nd, 2000 looks like we got it.
Yeah, this is really kind of looking pretty easy.
Oh, by the way, we forgot to update the the comments here, right?
Grab the grade.
Grab birth date, OK, next, we can grab the gender.
Let me see here, I think I actually want to copy this line for that because the grade line, I think
it's more similar to what we have for the gender.
So I'm going to duplicate that and then I'm going to move this line down.
And to do that?
I'm going to just do.
I'm holding down on option shift and down Arrow, which on Windows is alt shift down arrow.
OK, so that's how I move that up and down with alt shift or option shift and up or down arrow like
that?
OK.
All right.
And then we'll change the name of this to gender.
And will change this literal here to gender as well with a colon.
And then we've got one or more spaces in this case.
There's only one space, but that won't hurt anything.
And then it's one.
Character long.
Right, it's one word character, I'm going to assume that that's how it always will be.
It'll probably probably be an M or an F..
Well, now I think I better be a little bit careful here.
These days we have, you know, many organizations and such are acknowledging the existence of more
than just two genders.
And I don't know how they might encode those.
I don't know if they will do them with one letter or maybe a few letters, maybe even three.
I don't know.
So I might want to be a little bit careful how I express this in my regular expression.
So it's definitely not a digit, though, that's for sure.
Someone, I'm going to tell it.
It's going to be a word character.
And I think to be safe, what I can do is I'm going to get rid of this part here, and I'm just going
to tell it one or more word characters, followed by a word boundary.
So there's a place where we can kind of use that word boundary thing.
And the reason I'm saying this here is because I just want to be really careful that you can have some
word characters here and now I might have been able to say followed by space.
Right?
That probably would have been fine.
But what if there's a new line character right here, right at the end of this, and then it goes to
the next line as opposed to in fact, you know, it looks like there is a new line character because
I can't select anything more after that.
Right?
So I just wanted to be extra careful here by putting that word boundary character here, followed by
whatever comes next.
All right.
So let's see.
Let's see if this will work.
So that's gender.
So then we'll duplicate this and then we'll say gender here.
All right.
Let's see if that works.
Yeah, looks like that works.
There's our team.
OK, so that's that's a maybe a pretty decent reject so far, and let's update this as well.
Grab the gender.
All right.
And then we want the state I.D. So I'm going to go and grab the rest of these now without stopping to
run every single thing because I think the pattern is going to be pretty much the same at this point.
So let's see.
We've got state and then a space and then I.D. colon and then one or more spaces and then our name here,
which I will call state I.D. You'll see some people, by the way, do camel case for something like
an acronym.
You'll see them do the first letter and capitalized and then the second letter lowercase.
Again, I used to hate that back in the day.
These days, I've been beaten over the head, working on so many teams where that's where they tend
to do that.
I guess I'm mostly OK with it, but I think my personal preference is to do all caps in most cases,
although there are a few cases where to look weird, but here it's probably fine.
So do whatever you like there or whatever your team that you're working with tells you to do.
All right.
So state I.D. and this is going to be digits, and I could leave this plus here if I wasn't sure how
many digits this will always be.
I could just do the same thing that I did here in, you know, I guess I will just to just to mix it
up a little bit.
OK.
All right.
And I think I'll even leave the rest of this as well.
All right, so he grabbed the state I.D..
All right.
And then let's grab the cumulative GPA.
Now this is an interesting one because we've got the same text here on these two lines, but the only
thing that differentiates is what's in these parentheses weighted.
So that's what I think I'm going to kind of keep on.
Here is the word weighted EIA, DHT D, and then I will put this closing parentheses here.
Now, remember, parentheses are special characters and rejects those, so we want to escape that.
That's an easy thing to forget, but luckily, I think the I.D. C, I think it was kind of, well,
yeah, it was warning us here with the squiggly lines, right?
Because it thinks that that's probably supposed to be part of a captured group.
So we wanted to know that's just we want the literal closing parentheses there.
So that's an easy thing to to to mess up on.
All right.
Well, let's see.
And then OK, so we don't need the ID stuff here, so we get rid of all of that.
So we're at this closing parentheses and then one or more spaces, which we have here one or more spaces,
followed by three point eighty two.
Hmm.
So how do we want to represent that in rig?
Well, first, let's name it, I'm going to name it weighted GPA.
All right.
So it's not just digits now, right?
It's digits and a decimal.
I could tell it to start off with digits.
There's a lot of ways we could do this, we could tell it one or more digits, followed by a period,
and again, I have to escape that period because period in regex is the is a dot right?
And that means one character of any kind.
And here we want.
No, no, no, no.
We want literally to match a period.
So I have to escape that, that dot to tell the rejects.
And you know, I literally mean, I what?
I expect a period to be there.
So maybe we could do this, but I don't know, and I don't know if someone could have a GPA that is
less than, you know, like a point something.
And I don't know if that would start off with a zero or if it would not start with a zero and it would
just start with the period.
So I don't know.
I may not like that approach.
It probably certainly would work here for the example that I'm seeing, but I'm also kind of projecting
into the future of what if I had a thousand of these reports?
What variations in data might I encounter?
So maybe I wouldn't do it this way?
Let's see.
Another way that I might do it, though, is to possibly say something like expect word characters,
maybe expect one or more word characters, followed by a boundary.
I think that would work.
Actually, that would work pretty well.
Now it's a little wide in that if there were letters here that would also match, and maybe I wouldn't
totally like that.
An alternative that I could do that might be a little better than that would be to use a bracket expression,
actually, so I could tell it to allow for.
Numbers or.
A period.
OK, so we could do something like this and then we can tell it.
We will allow for one or more of those, followed by a boundary.
And so now you can't put letters in here, right?
It's a little more.
Well, it's a lot more constrained, actually.
OK.
Let's see.
And this is the weighted GPA.
Grab the loops, grab the weighted GPA now because I did a little bit of speculative things here.
I think I am going to go ahead and run this now.
I just want to make sure that this actually works because if I go too far without running it, it'll
be harder for me to figure out, where did I go wrong?
Was it on this bit here or was it on this bed or whatever?
So let's go ahead and oh, well, hold on.
We have to try printing that out also.
So let's give us a couple more here, gender and then state I.D. and then
weighted GPA.
Okay.
Let's see what we've got.
Three point eighty two.
It looks like that worked.
There it is, three point eighty two.
And the other one was the state I.D..
Yeah, looks like that worked just fine.
OK, cool.
So yeah, you got to see a little bit of my thought process on how I decided what regular expression
would maybe work best for parsing that bit out.
Now, the nice thing at this point is now I can just duplicate this line.
And do almost exactly the same thing for the unweighted unweighted right, because there's pretty much
no difference here on weighted GPA grabbed the.
In one way, weighted GPA there.
Yeah, I think that's pretty much it.
And then duplicate this line on, let's run it and see what we got.
Cool.
Looks like we're parsing everything out that we want.
Right?
So here here was our input, starting from the bottom three point four six three point eight two eight
nine two blah blah blah gender is m birth date.
We broke that out into the individual components of the year, the day of the month and then the month,
which is right there.
And then the grade was 11 and then the student number was this.
So yeah, I mean, we just did a nice job here of parsing out this whole entire thing.
We kind of put together a lot of what we've learned in this section on regular expressions, right?
Put some comments in here as well.
Broke it out so that it's a lot easier to read.
Can you imagine how terrible this would look if we had this all in one massive line?
In fact, we got the dot all in the comments and all of this good stuff.
OK, so let's go ahead and end this lesson here, and I will see you in the next one.