All right, so in this lesson, we're going to just do a deeper dive into how I am making this test
random number generation method work.
What was my thinking behind it?
I just want to make sure that everyone really follows the logic here and and how I came up with this.
If you already understand this or you feel you do, feel free to skip right over this lesson.
So this is really just meant to be a deeper dive for those who still are a little confused or are not
real sure exactly what all is going on here.
So I'm going to try to explain it in a in another way.
OK.
All right.
So first off, let's just make sure we understand right from the start.
What are we even trying to do?
The basic idea is this, you know, for any guessing game where you're having to guess the number between,
let's say, one in 10.
That game isn't any good if the number that were supposed to be guessing never changes in between games,
right?
So if every time you play the game, the random number is three.
Well, first off, it's not very random, and that game is not going to be much fun to play beyond one
or two times when everybody starts to realize, oh, the number is always three.
So we need a different number each time we play the game.
And if we're saying that we want that random number to be between, for example, one and 10, then
you'd want to make sure that if you played it enough times, let's say 20, 30, 40 times the game should
be picking random numbers in that range and not just picking two, three and four, for example, right?
If you played it 50 times, you would expect that it would have randomly chosen numbers between one
and 10, somewhat equally.
Now, I don't expect a random number generating algorithm that we have easy access to in a language
like Java to be like perfectly even.
But hopefully it's, you know, going to deliver a pretty good spread.
So this whole method here is trying to force us to write code that will generate such such random numbers.
OK?
And then we can verify that those random numbers are being generated.
So let's look real quick first at what it would look like if we had good random number generation.
So let's say, for example, every time we run the game, it generates the following random numbers
each time we play it, let's say we get a three and a five and a two and a seven and a nine and then
another three, then another nine and then another two.
OK, now these are just my own random numbers, OK?
And that's for one two three four five six seven, eight times that we run this game, right?
Those are the numbers that we might get.
OK?
How could we test whether or not we eventually hit all numbers between one and 10 inclusive?
If we ran this game enough times, how could we do that?
Well, my idea for tracking this and this is just, you know, my own idea, right?
Although I'm sure lots of people have done something similar for similar reasons.
So my thinking was, OK, well, let's imagine that we have a list of every possible number between
one and 10, so I'll make that list now one two three four five six, seven, eight, nine and 10.
OK, now let's see here, I'll change the color.
So now let's just imagine that the first time we play this game, we get a three, and somehow I keep
track of the fact that I got a three, right?
So maybe I use something kind of like a tally mark, although I'm not going to keep multiple tallies
for the same number.
If I already have a tally mark on a number.
Then then I don't need to put another one there.
I'm just trying to track, was that number ever used or never used, right?
So I got a three and then I got a five, and then I got it to write, I'm just following these numbers
up here, and then I got a seven.
So I put a tally mark there and then I got a nine, so put a tally mark there.
Then I got a three already have a tally mark there.
Then I got a nine, already have a tally mark there and then I got a two and I already have a tally
mark there.
OK, great now.
If I add up all of my tally marks, I get one two three four five.
Right now, let's also imagine in a perfect world, I ran this game 50 times and eventually I get a
tally mark for every single number like so.
And when I tally all of those up, I get 10.
OK, now would you agree that a really good random number generator would be one in which in this case,
if my range of possible numbers was one through 10, I got a tally mark on all 10 numbers.
Would you agree that that's a good random number generator as opposed to a random number generator that
just generates to every single time?
Right?
That's not going to be a fun game that just generates two, right?
So the more tally marks we have across each of these numbers, I would say, the better.
The random number generation is right, because the tally marks indicate that the random number generator
is capable of generating each of those numbers, right?
So the numbers in red that indicates a random number generator that is not great.
Now, of course, I'm not factoring in, you know, how many times did we allow it to generate a number?
But let's say that each of these rows, each of these rows, represents having run the random generator
50 times.
OK, let's just say that.
So if you ran it 50 times and this first column in red or I'm sorry, this first row in red.
Results in only getting five out of the 10 numbers, right?
That's not a very good random number generator, considering that you only had 10 options there, right?
A perfect random number generator would be one where you would get all 10 numbers selected for only
having run the random generation 10 times, right?
So in other words, each time you run it, you get a new number and it's always random.
That would be ideal and ideal does not exist in this case, but getting five out of the 10 after running
at 50 times is not good, right?
RDC or 50 times?
All right.
Getting all 10 numbers to come up by the random number generator after having run it 50 times?
That's good.
That's, you know, that's pretty.
That's that's reasonable.
OK.
All right now.
So so that's what we're trying to get to.
We're trying to keep track of how many times each of the random numbers.
Here so.
These.
Are.
The random.
Numbers.
Right.
Each of these one two, three four five, two, one through 10 there in black.
All right.
So we need to figure out a way in code to be able to do this, this tally mark thing that I that I'm
showing here.
How can we do that in code?
Well, the approach that we ended up doing in the code, in the test here, test random number generation
was to use an array.
OK.
So let me just show you if we think of each of these boxes.
As an array element.
And.
Well, first, let me just remind you, so Anna Ray is really just a collection of items, objects,
primitives, numbers, whatever, OK?
It's just a way to have a list or a collection of numbers all grouped together.
OK.
So I will show you an example, a visual example here.
All right.
So let's say we have an array of one, two, three, four five elements.
OK, so we could have element zero, element one, element two, three and four.
OK.
And then we could store something in these elements.
So if this is an array, if this whole entire thing is an array of, let's say.
Integers.
Then the thing that I could store in each of these elements would be integers.
OK?
So I could store a three in element zero.
OK.
And I could store a whatever a five.
And I could store a negative seven and a two and another three.
It doesn't matter that I can put anything in these elements, right?
And the way that I could create this array, this is an array.
This is an integer.
Array right now, the way that I could create this in code is to simply say something like.
And.
And then this square brackets symbol and then a name for the array, like my numbers.
Equals.
Now I can initialize this array, or I can just create it if I just want to create it, then I can see
new.
And.
And then in this case, I have five elements, so this is an array of five element array.
OK, so I could create this array in this way, or I could initialize this array with some actual values.
My numbs equals.
And then I could use curly braces and then put some numbers here so I could do three, five negative
seven, two and three like sir.
OK, so those are two different ways that I could create an IRA.
OK, that looks like this.
All right.
So I could I could use an array to kind of do this tally mark stuff that I have here, right?
So the way I could do that is I could create the array show you what that would look like.
Well, actually, it would pretty much look like, I guess.
OK, so you're actually here.
Let's just go to the actual code.
So right here on Line 41.
You see me creating an integer array called Random NUM Count.
I named it R&amp;D, and I'm just saying that this is an array of 11 elements.
OK.
So each of these is one element of an array.
So, so on line forty one, I'm saying make an array of integers with 11 elements.
All right.
And then let's see here.
Let me undo a few things to clean this up a bit.
All right.
So if our array is, is this thing here?
This whole entire.
But here.
If that's an array.
And its elements are.
Each of these spots.
Here.
Then what we're able to do is we're able to store a one or a zero or nothing, which ends up becoming
a zero in each of these elements, right?
So if we don't put a one in there, then by default you're going to have a zero.
And the reason for that is because this is an integer array.
Let me say that this is an integer.
Array.
And the and each element defaults to a zero.
OK.
That's just the default of integer arrays.
All right.
So imagine now, as I said at the beginning, if we had a random number generator that was generating
these numbers here.
These ones in this order.
And each time we got one of these numbers, we just put a tally mark, right?
So we got a three and a five and a two, whatever, and then we added all of those up.
You'd get some value, right, five or 10 or whatever.
So here on Line 41, we create this array then online's 42 through 45 or so or 46 lines, 42 to 46.
We create a for loop and we do this because we want to create the game 50 times.
OK.
And by creating the game 50 times, we should be getting a chance to generate 50 random numbers.
OK, now this is just in the test, so we're not going to go look right now at how it's generating that,
although you should know that already using the Java, you tell that random class.
OK, so we're generating 50 random numbers, hopefully by creating the game 50 times right here on Line
43.
And then if we are generating a good spread of random numbers, then every time we call a game not get
random number and store that number in this variable here, we will then access that particular element
of the array.
So in other words, if again, looking back here, if we if the first random number we generated was
a three, then we will go to the third index, which technically is the fourth index because arrays
start with a zero.
But I don't want to be overly confusing here, so I'll just say index three.
We go to index three of the array, which would be this guy here, right?
And then we store tally mark in it, which is this one underneath it?
OK.
And then the loop starts over again.
We create a new guessing game.
We get a new, hopefully a new random number.
And this time it's a five, for example.
Now I'm just using this as an example, since these should be random numbers.
I don't know what the numbers are at the time when I'm just talking about this, right?
But let's pretend like the next time we run it, it's a five.
And so now we're on this element here.
OK.
And so we access Element five and we store Italian mark and and so that's what we're doing online 45.
This is how we access an element.
We refer to the array name which we created up here, random name count and then a square bracket and
then the index.
OK, the index or the element.
So in this case, it would be Element five if the random number generator had generated a five, which
we won't.
You know, again, we don't know what it's going to be, and it doesn't matter, really.
OK?
And so then we store a one in element five.
OK, so that's what you see happening here.
OK.
We're storing a one in Element five and then the loop starts over again.
We create a new guessing game with hopefully a new random number and we get that number.
And let's say this time it's a two per hour.
Fake random numbers here.
Right, so it's a two.
So then we go to Element two, which is this guy here, and we started telling Mark inside of it, Oh,
one, we store a one in it and so you get it right.
We we do this 50 times.
And now every number that was ever generated should have a one in its box, right?
And its holding tank, if you will.
OK.
And every number that we did not visit should have a zero in it.
And so now down here online 48, we create a new variable and a new integer called sum.
I guess we could have called it total.
Maybe that would have been better, and we initialize it to zero.
And then we create another loop, which will only count from zero to 11, while actually from zero to
11.
But the 11 will not be included, right, because we're using counter less than 11.
So 11 itself won't be used.
So it's really zero through 10, and we use this sum plus equals, which is equivalent to saying it's.
OK.
So these are equivalent to each other.
This is just the shorthand which we learned in the numbers module.
All right.
And so this is just saying people running total of the sum of the tally marks that are in this array.
OK.
So what we're literally doing here is we're starting on element zero.
OK, now I don't depict an element zero down here, so let's pretend like we got to element one, which
is this element right here.
OK?
And we set some equal to zero.
OK.
Well, actually, and then we add this value of zero.
To the sum, right?
So if the sum.
Started off being zero.
Then we add this zero here, and we have still zero.
Then we go on to the next element element too.
And we have a one.
So now we add zero plus one, which is one.
Then we go on to Element three and we have a one.
And so one plus one is two.
Then we go to Element four, we have a zero, so sum equals two.
Still, then we go to Element five, which has a one.
So two plus one is three.
OK.
Then six is zero.
So we have a still have three, then element seven has a one.
So now we do three plus one, which is four.
Then we go to Element eight, which has a zero, so sum is still four.
Then we go to Element nine, which has a one two four plus one is five.
And that's how we end up with this five here.
That is the total sum.
That's what this loop is doing.
That's exactly what this loop is doing.
It just keeps a running total of each number that's in this array.
And we're literally just visiting every element in the array, starting with zero going to 10 because
this is less than 11 right, which would mean 10.
So zero through 10, we're going to just find out was there a zero or a one, basically?
Now this isn't binary.
These are real integers.
We just I just didn't want to keep track of anything more than whether or not it had a zero or one in
it.
Right.
And then all we have to do is this tally everything up, which is what this is doing here.
It's tallying up all of the zeros and ones, getting a total sum, which we store here.
Now I also mentioned that we declared this some variable outside of the loop, because when we get here,
which is outside of the loop, we want to refer to the Sun and remember about scope variable scope.
If I had declared this some variable inside of the loop like this, then I'm no longer able to refer
to the some variable outside of the loop because it's outside of the scope, right?
Any variable that you declare inside of a loop only has scope inside of that loop.
And what do I mean by inside of the loop?
I mean, all of the code between this curly brace for the for loop and this curly brace for the for
loop, OK?
So any code, any variables that are defined inside of here can only be used inside of here.
And that's why this is now red, because I moved the declaration for this variable inside of the loop.
OK, so I'm going to move that back.
Outside of the loop.
And now I can use it in the loop, just fine.
But I can also use it outside of the loop.
OK, so now it has a wider scope, if you will.
All right.
So I would say that if you're still feeling a little groggy or a little confused by any of this, you
probably need to go back and watch the lesson on arrays.
OK, and then also watch one of the previous lessons on the for loop or maybe on all of the loops,
but especially the for loop, where I talk again about the scope and how the loop is actually working,
OK?
But hopefully this lesson or this lesson, combined with revisiting arrays and loops, will make this
super clear for you.
Now, one last thing I will mention if you're wondering how did I think of doing it this way?
So that's one of the interesting things about programming.
I've heard some people who are definitely not programmers who have the misconception that programming
is not a creative endeavor, right?
I think those people couldn't possibly be more wrong.
I think it is possible to be a programmer who is not very creative.
I definitely think that's possible and met programmers who need to be told exactly what to do.
They can code it, but they can't think of, you know, creative solutions for problems.
But I think many of the best programmers are actually very creative.
And so I would say that thinking of this approach to determining whether or not our game is actually
producing a good set of random numbers, this is just something I purely made up.
I didn't read this in a book somewhere, not specifically for this, right?
This is where you have to draw on the bits and pieces, the building blocks of programming and figure
out how to apply them to solve a problem, right?
And unfortunately, I don't know if I can directly teach you how to do that.
All I can teach you is the building blocks and show you a number of examples of how to apply those building
blocks and hopefully creative ways to solve real world problems, right?
And maybe eventually you start to get, Oh, I could use one of these things, plus one of these things
here put them together and solve this problem.
Right?
So unfortunately, like I said, that's one thing that I cannot directly teach you.
I read this solution in such and such a book.
No, I didn't.
And in fact, I did actually have to think about this before I taught this lesson.
I had to think about how would I go about proving that the random number generation is good, right?
Is giving us a good spread.
And, you know, I don't know how long it took me to think of more than five minutes.
In fact, initially I thought of another approach.
I don't know if I should share that approach or not.
Maybe I'll talk about it in another lesson if I have time to come back to it.
But there are multiple ways to solve this, and this is just one way.
The one of the other ways that I thought of.
I'm not going to go into great detail had nothing to do with adding things up.
I decided on using this approach because I thought it might be probably the most elegant overall, and
it lets us utilize a number of little techniques that you've already learned throughout this course.
But I thought of, you know, one or two other approaches that didn't necessarily involve doing any
summing or adding up of a total or anything like that at all.
So there are multiple ways that we could have achieved this.
This is just the way that I came up with for now, and I thought it was probably one of the better ways.
All right, I'm going to go ahead.
And this lesson, hopefully this helped you to to put it all together, and I will see you in the next
one.