OK.
I mentioned that the math, that random method is fine for simple random number generation.
However, if you need a little bit better randomness and by better, I mean, let's say that if you
were to call math a random one million times, you might be able to discern certain patterns.
Or you might notice that certain numbers are coming up a little more frequently than you would expect
with a perfect random generator that has what is called an even distribution across all of its range.
So there are a few additional ways to generate numbers.
I won't go through all of them, but I will show you one other one that is at least a little bit better
than math that random in that it is a bit more random, a little less predictable.
So let's take a look at that, and I'm going to clear this out.
All right.
And so what we can do is there is a class called random on on the package called Java Dot Util.
And we can import this class.
And create an instance of it, new random like so and then to actually use this guy, we can let's say
we want to print out some random numbers so we can do a system that out that print line and then reference
the random object we just created.
And now this object has a number of methods on it that are quite convenient.
So we could do something like next event like so and let's say we want numbers up to 10 so we can give
it an upper bound and just put the number 10 in here like so.
And let's say we're going to call this a few times.
So now if I run this?
There we go.
Two, five, eight seven.
Nice and easy, right?
So in some ways, you may you may really prefer this for a number of reasons over the math random.
Four.
Really, really short, quick things Though a lot of people, especially beginners, may consider math
random to be a little easier because you don't have to create an instance of anything first, but then
you miss out on these nice little convenient methods here.
Now, internally, when I am creating this random object in this random instance, here it creates what
is called a seed, and that is kind of like a starting point number to kind of initialize the whole
process of generating random numbers.
So if you don't supply a seed as I am not doing so here, it will do its best to just make one for you.
However, you can supply a seed and it will take a number of type long.
So I can just provided a number here and now I'm supplying the seed myself.
OK.
So sometimes you may want that.
Sometimes you may not.
It just depends on what you're what, what you're needing to do.
Also, now I'm going to remove that.
Now also, you don't have to supply the bound, but you may find this method is considerably, yes,
considerably less useful to you if you don't supply a bound.
So.
Let me just show what you get by default.
OK.
So, yeah, so it's pretty big, pretty big range of values if you don't supply any bound at all.
And if you'll notice there are a number of additional methods on here, so you can ask it for an integer
or a Boolean or a double float.
A number of things here bytes.
OK.
So I encourage you to just explore and see what you can do with this.
But you may find yourself preferring to use this approach for at least relatively simple random number
generation.
Now, I will say that even this random generation approach isn't considered to be suitable for highly
secure things like encryption and things of that sort.
Actually, though, if you want to do that, there is another class you can use.
There is a secure random.
And it also can take a seed notice, though this seed is a byte array.
Let's take a little look at this.
All right, so this message, let me see if I can pull this out a bit more.
OK, there we go.
This class has a number of interesting methods on it, some that look somewhat similar to what we just
saw on the regular random class.
I think that's by design.
So we'll just take take a look at the next event or the next into method here, and we'll pass in an
upper bounds of 10.
And let's call it a few times.
OK, now if we take a look at the Java doc by selecting the method, putting the cursor on the method
and then pressing F1 or control you, I think for Windows, it says that this returns a pseudo random,
uniformly distributed and value between zero inclusive and the specified value exclusive, meaning it
will not include the 10.
So it will include zero up to, but not including the 10, so up to nine in this case, since it's four
integers.
All right.
So I will leave it to you to, you know, read the Java doc here.
But this approach is meant to generate a better, more even distribution of random numbers such that
it could be utilized for certain secure functions that you may be implementing.
All right.
So that's going to cover this.
I just wanted to follow up and show you a couple of other ways that you could generate random numbers,
by the way.
One other thing to point out as a difference between the math that random and then these two approaches
are the math that random versus just the regular random class math that random is actually less efficient
than using the random class.
So random wins out over math that random in basically every way other than maybe just efficiency for
you, the developer.
You know, you have to make a couple extra lines, perhaps to use the random class or secure random.
So just wanted to point that out, and I'll see you in the next one.