All right.
So in the last lesson, we did a little bit of cleaning up of our previously written code where we implemented
the ability to save a person in this lesson will jump to another one of the standard crud operations.
And if you'll recall, crud stands for create, read, update and delete.
So in this lesson, we're going to implement the ability to find a person by their ID.
And again, we'll start with our test in the interest of test driven development or TDD.
All right.
So here we are back in the people repository tests class and we're going to go ahead and start with
another test here.
So like I said, we're going to be implementing the ability to find a person by ID.
So let's create a test.
We'll start with the annotation for Test.
Public void as all J unit test methods have to be and I don't know, let's just call this can find person
by ID.
And I think I've stated this before, but I try not to get too hung up on what I'm going to name these
test methods initially, even though I know what I'm going for.
I don't always want to take a lot of time to come up with the perfect name for the methods.
Usually, I find that as I implement the test method a little bit further, then a better name comes
to me, although I think this name is probably going to be fine.
So if this test is going to test our ability to find a person by an ID, we'd have to first know an
idea of a person that we want to find.
Now some of you may be tempted to just go pop over to the database and see what records are out there
and take an idea of one of those records and then use that.
And that certainly would work for right now.
However, in order to have our tests be as robust as possible, the ideal situation in most cases is
to have your test methods set up whatever data they are depending on, and then test against that data
and then likely have those test methods clear out that data as well.
So in other words, it would be better to assume that people with IDs that might happen to be in the
database right now won't be there in the future, because if those records get cleared out for whatever
reason, the records that are already out there in the database right now, that test, that's depending
on those records existing there will fail.
And it won't be because your code doesn't work.
It'll be because your test made assumptions as to whether or not those particular records were there.
So a better technique in most cases is to actually have this test method insert data that it knows is
there.
Then it will test whether or not it can find a person by a certain I.D. and then it can just clear it
all out.
So let me show you how we can do that.
Now there's at least a couple of ways that we could go about inserting known data into our test data
into the database.
The easiest way that I can think of at the moment would be to go ahead and just rely on our save method
that we've already implemented, so we could actually just create a person and then call Repo Dot Save
to save that person from within this test method here and now, we'd have a person that we know is there,
and then we can turn right back around and find that person by ID.
Another approach would be to actually write the sequel insert code in our test method using this connection.
So in other words, we could do a, you know, connection that prepared statement insert into people
blah blah blah blah blah, right?
Insert a whole person in there and all of that.
So there can be pros and cons to either of these approaches with the approach of creating a prepared
statement within this test method and then doing the insert in everything, we remove ourselves from
any assumptions that are repo.
That save method works right.
So we just get away from that completely, and we insert our test data that we need for our test purposes
independently of the system under test and the system under test is the repo repository.
However, that means that we'd have to do a little more work number one by, you know, creating this
connection, that prepared statement and all of that.
And very likely, we'd be duplicating a fair amount of the code that already exists in the repo class
itself.
So like I said, there's kind of pros and cons to that approach.
In this particular case, I'm fairly comfortable not to go this route and instead to simply call Repo
Dot Save to save our test data within the confined person by ID test method because I feel fairly comfortable
that we've done enough testing on the safe person.
And by the way, there's certainly more that we could test with this repo.
Don't save.
But I do feel that we've got enough that I'm confident that repo, that save is doing its job right.
And so I'm inclined to go ahead and just use the repo that save method to insert a test person into
the database.
But these are certainly questions and thoughts that you should have things that you should be thinking
about when you're writing these kinds of tests, especially when you're dealing with a database.
Where's my test data going to come from?
Am I just assuming that the test data that I need is already in the database, which is almost always
a bad assumption?
Or do I have a way that I can get test data into the database?
All right, so let's go ahead and get a person, a test person into the database, someone going delete
that line.
And so we will call repo that save and then we can just create a new person in line, perhaps, and
we don't really care about this person too much.
So I'm just going to call this person test.
Jackson, and they'll need a date of birth, and we'll do a zone date time and the date of birth doesn't
really even matter either, so I'm going to do now.
Because that's like the easiest way for me to create a zone.
Date time.
All right.
So there's that person.
So the idea here is that we're going to create this person, save them into the database, then we're
going to turn around and try to find that person by their I.D., which means we need their ID.
So that means I need to capture the output of this save method because the save method is going to return
back the person with their ID filled in, right?
So.
We can do this, and I will call this saved person.
All right.
So there's that that saved person.
So then we're going to turn around and call Repo Dot, find buy it.
Now keep in mind, this method does not exist yet.
This is us doing TDD.
We are writing the code for the Future State that we want the repo to behave in.
So we want to have a method called find by ID.
And that method is going to take as an input an ID.
So I can reference save the person, not get ID like so.
And this method will be expected to return a person and I will call this person found person.
OK.
So we're going to have a method called Find a B ID, find ID that will take an ID as an input and then
return back the person that it found.
OK.
All right, so let's go ahead and satisfy the idea here with that red fine by IDs, I'm putting my cursor
right there on the find my ID and I'm going to do an option return and I'm going to let the I.D. create
this method in the people repository class.
All right.
So yeah, it's suggesting that it will create this method fine by ID that will return a person one hit
enter and it will take an input of a long ID.
That's fine.
I'm good with all of that for now.
OK.
And so then I will do a command shift to jump back over or control shift for Windows and Linux and jump
back over to the test class.
And now the fine by ID method reference there is no longer read.
All right.
And now I need an assertion, so I will assert that the found persons I.D..
Is equal to the saved person's Heidi.
Right.
That's pretty straightforward, right?
All right, so let's run this and see it fell.
And keep in mind, in TDD, you write a test, you satisfy enough of the code to not have red marks
and things like that.
Then you run the test.
It should fail because you won't have implemented any of the necessary logic yet.
Then you go implement just enough logic to make the test pass.
Then you flesh out some more and you keep repeating this cycle until eventually you have enough working
functionality.
And sometimes that will require you to write multiple tests to force yourself to write all of the code
that's needed.
All right, so let's run this.
OK, so it's failing.
I'm going to click here on the failed test method and see what it's failing on.
So it's saying cannot invoke the person that get ID method because the found person is null and that
makes sense, right?
All right.
So we know that it's not all because that's what the ADA implemented will jump over here into the repo.
That fine by ID method here.
And there you go.
There's the null right there.
So perhaps the first and easiest thing we can do is just to create a very simple person instance right
here.
So let's see what that will look like, new person.
And I'm going to keep it really simple and not even put any information in your hardly at all.
So zoned datetime.
I don't know.
Let's see if we can get away with a null.
Yeah, we can.
So I probably could have done that for the first and last names, too.
But that's all right.
OK, let's jump back over here to the test.
Run it again.
OK, still failing.
So I'm going to click on can find person by ID here so we can see what the failure is now.
So the test was expecting a 61 for the equality of the found person versus the saved person, but the
ID was actually null.
All right.
So that makes sense as well because the person that we're creating in the new find by ID method of the
repository class doesn't even have an ID.
We didn't set any ID on it.
So now we've got to consider what we want to do here.
Do we want to just, I don't know, hard code a 61 as an ID into the person that we are returning from
the repository.
We could do that, in fact.
Yeah, let's go ahead and do that.
And see what that does, and I think you can anticipate what that's going to do.
But all right, so the way we'll need to do that then I think, is to capture this person.
So I'm going to put my cursor right here and then do an option command v or control all the and there's
our personal hit enter.
And then I will make the new line right above their on line thirty eight.
And then we will just, I guess, hard code, maybe.
And now we can just put an I.D. on here.
Now, actually, what we could do is set the I.D. to ID.
Right?
Yeah.
So this idea that we're passing and just set that ID right there, right?
All right.
So let's jump back over here to the test.
And let's run this again.
I think that's going to pass now.
Yeah, there you go.
So we're done right now.
Of course we're not done.
This isn't really doing anything that we really want, but this is the cat and mouse game that you can
play with TDD.
So we know that we haven't really forced ourselves to implement the real true find by ID code.
So what would it take to force ourselves to implement the true, you know, querying of the database
by ID?
Well, I think one thing we could force ourselves to do is to also assert that the first name and last
name are what they are supposed to be.
Right now, we could add that as additional assertions in this test method, or we could create another
test.
Oftentimes, I'm actually not that crazy about having multiple assertions and a test method.
However, in this particular case, we'd be asserting that a number of properties of the person class
are what we think they should be.
And so in this particular case, I might be OK with it.
And there are actually a couple of ways that we could do this.
So we could have these these individual assertions where we assert that the idea is the same and then
we assert that the first name is the same and we assert that the last name is the same, right?
We could do it that way explicitly or another thought that I'm having is that we could rely on having
a decent equals method implemented on the person class, maybe one that just compares all of the properties
of a person.
And I'm kind of leaning towards that approach because with that approach, we might not need multiple
assertions anymore.
And instead, we might just be able to to assert that found person is equal to save the person or something
along those or is the same as the saved person.
Something along those lines.
But for that to work, we would need to implement a proper equals method.
So I'm thinking, let's go with that approach.
So I'm going to jump into the person class here and I'm going to go down to the bottom.
And so we could go ahead and have the ADP just generate an equal method for us.
Now there's a couple of things to consider if you're going to do this.
Oftentimes when I have written code along these lines and I'm creating what's called an entity, an
entity, by the way, is generally speaking a domain class, a domain class that is designed to be stored
in the database.
So an entity.
And frequently, when you've got these entities or or database domain classes, they will have an ID
filled like this one, and that ID field is mostly there for database purposes.
Frequently, when I'm implementing an equals method, I often don't want to include that ID filled there
because it is possible to have an instance of a person before you saved them to the database and after
you save them to the database.
And there's still the same person, according to all of their properties, except for that idea.
Right?
In this case, though, I'm considering including the ID because I want that ID to be taken into account
when I'm testing for equality.
So there's some tradeoffs there in how I'm deciding to do this right now.
I don't want to overthink this too much, though, so I'm going to do what simplest for me for right
now, and that would be to just include the ID.
OK, now if we're going to create this equals method for the person class, then ideally we should strongly
consider having a unit test class for the person class where we would test the equality as well.
So sorry for the sidetrack, but I kind of want to show you a little bit more of the right way to do
things, even if we don't go like super in-depth with it.
OK, so what I'm going to do here, I'm on this person class right now.
I'm going to do a command shift T. And that's going to allow me to create a new test for the person
class.
I will select create new test and J Unit already is saying, OK, well, I'm going to assume you want
this new test class to be called person test, which is fine.
It's going to put it in the correct package.
That's cool as well.
And I'm not going to let it generate any of this stuff for me here that it's offering.
Let me let me move this up so you can see what's going on there.
OK, so I could select methods here that I that it would kind of give me some scaffolding for test methods,
but I'm not going to select any of those and I'm going to click, OK.
All right.
So here we've just created a new test class called Person Test, and I'm going to just do that test.
Public void tests for equality.
All right.
And so what I'm going to do here, I guess, is just create two people.
Person P1 equals new person, and I don't know, I'll just call him P1, comma Smith, and we'll give
this person his own date time.
Of two thousand.
September 1st.
12 12 p.m..
And in a zone I.D. of zero.
Oops!
All right.
And then I'm going to duplicate that person because I don't want to type all of that completely.
And so I guess we'll start off with the happy path and just.
Have everything be the same, right?
All right.
And then we will assert that.
And I'm going to move my cursor over here to the that and then do an option return to import that,
assert that method.
Remember the assert that methods are not from the J Unit framework that we're using in general for testing.
This is an add on from a third party called Assert J.
OK, that's where the assert that methods are coming from.
So if you end up at a company where they want you to unit test and you just jump in and start trying
to use assert that there's a possibility that the assert that methods won't be there for you if that
company or that team hasn't already imported.
The Assert J Library and some teams might not be OK with you using it.
OK.
These are not standard assertions from J Unit.
These are third party.
Add on assertions that make our assertions a little more fluent if you speak English.
All right.
So assert that import static and I'm going to come down here to the simplest looking one assertions
that assert that from the or a search eight core API.
All right.
Assert that p one.
So then we will do is equal to P two.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and run this.
OK.
And we get our failure, as we would expect.
OK, so now let's go and implement an equals method here.
So we'll just jump back over to the person class.
I'm going to jump to the bottom of this method here, because that's where I like to put my boilerplate
in generated methods and things like like equals and to string and all of that.
All right.
And so we can have the idea generate an equals method for us.
I will do a command in for Mac users and for Windows and Linux users.
You'll have to right click, you know, like here and go down to generate.
Sorry, you can't see generate on my on my screen here, but it's there and here.
I'll do it up here.
Generate right?
OK.
So command in generate and equals.
Now remember also that when you do an equals method, the idea is going to offer to implement both the
equals and the hash code method for you, because those two methods really tend to go hand in hand with
each other.
And again, I apologize.
You can't see it on my screen because it's kind of running off the screen, but I'm choosing the equals
and hash code option there, and then it's asking me if I want to use Java 7's built in template capability
to generate these, which I'm good with and click next.
All right.
Now here is where we actually specify what fields we want to take into account.
And like I already said earlier, frequently in the past for like real business applications, I may
very well have left out this ID field, but in this case, I'm keeping it simple.
And I really want to be able to compare these objects, including their IDs.
So I'm going to leave all of these fields selected here ID, first name, last name and date of birth.
So that's just ask me which fields should be taken into account when we are comparing for equality.
In other words, all of those fields should be the same in order for the entire person to be the same.
All right, so click next.
And same thing here for the hash code.
Same same deal.
And which fields should not be null?
Now, this is a little tricky because when we first create a person, there's not going to be an ID.
So technically I have to leave the ID off for now, so I'm going to do it that way.
OK, so there we go, we've got a nice generated equals n hash code method.
And now I'm going to jump back over to the test and just run it again.
There we go, and so that's passing now.
Very good.
OK, and then let's make a negative test.
So.
Public void test for any quality.
And I suppose I'll start off by duplicating one of these people here, and then I'm going to just bring
him down by doing an option shift down Arrow.
Or all shift down Arrow on Windows and Linux.
OK.
And then I guess I'm going to duplicate him again and change this name to P2.
But now I will change something here, and technically I only need to change one small thing, so I
will change the name to P2.
So keep in mind up here, they're both exactly identical other than the names of the variables down
here, though I'm changing the first name subtly right to P2.
All right.
And then I will assert that.
P1 is not equal to P2, and then let's run both tests.
There we go, looking good.
OK, so we've got an equals method implemented now.
All right.
So now we can jump all the way back over to our repository tests.
So I'm going to do a command.
Oh, which will let me search for classes and I happened already.
Have the people repository tests class kind of showing up here.
So I'm just selecting that.
But if you don't have that, you can just type PCR tests.
It may be PR tech.
Yeah, see, there you go and then hit, enter and jump back over here and then I'm going to make some
room for myself.
OK, so now can find person by ID?
And where were we so?
Yes.
So now, instead of testing for equality, according to the IDs, only now I can actually just get rid
of that and get rid of that.
And so now I'm just saying assert that the found person is equal to the saved person.
Right?
Because now I have an equals method that will dig in to the ID and the first name in the last name in
the date of birth and all of those, all of those properties have to be identical in order for these
two people to be considered to be identical or the same right equal.
All right.
So now if I run this test test, it fails.
Because now the first names are not the same, the last name is not the same, the date of birth is
not the same, et cetera, et cetera, right?
So obviously now I could go in and hard code, the person that we're returning from the find my ID method
to match these specific parameters here.
But then as soon as I wrote one more test that had a differently named person then want at least one
of them would fail and so on and so forth.
So I'm not going to bother to do that for in the interest of time, but you get it right.
OK, so now let's go ahead and actually implement something here like really implement something.
So let's jump in to the find bad method here.
OK, so now we're going to write some real code, so I'm going to start off by maybe just making a new
line here so we can use a little bit of what we did up here as a template, but I don't think I need
it.
So what we'll do here is we're going to start off with the connection like we did before, and we'll
go ahead and use a prepared statement again.
And we're going to need some sequel.
So what we're going to be doing here is we're going to try to find the person by idea.
OK, so the way to do that would be select.
Now we could do a couple of things, or we could do select star from people where ID equals, and then
I can just use a question mark here and then I will pass in that parameter later.
OK.
So that's one thing that we could do.
Now you oftentimes it is considered a better practice to be a little more explicit in what columns you're
actually querying for, though.
And so I think that's what I'm going to do in this particular case.
So I'm going to query for ID, comma, first name, comma, last name, comma, date of birth, OK,
like that.
And then I'm going to close that off with a semicolon notice.
I have the red marks here, and that is because if I hover over it, I have an unhindered exception
here.
So to handle that exception with my cursor on this line, I'm going to do an option command T and then
I can let the ID surround that line of code with a try catch block by choosing number six.
OK, I could have written that out myself to, by the way, obviously, but I'm lazy.
OK.
So there's that line, and I'm going to make a new line inside of the try catch block here.
Oh, so the other thing I need to do now is to capture this prepared statement, because we're just
telling the connection to create a prepared statement for us.
OK.
So I have my cursor at the end here and I'm going to do an option Command V. And I'm going to call this
prepared statement piece what's not uppercase lowercase piece?
All right, there we go.
So now the next thing we'll want to do is to bind a value in this case, this ID bind this ID to this
question mark here.
OK, so in other words, we're going to plug that question mark in so that when we execute this query,
it will know what ID to actually plug in to the query there, right?
So we can do that by typing piece set long, because that's the data type.
And then it's going to take as an input, a parameter index.
And I only have one parameter in this query, which is that one right there.
So its index is going to be one.
So one comma and then I can pass in the ID there.
OK, so this ID here?
Is this it here, right?
So what we're saying is select all these fields from the people table where the ID equals whatever ID
we passed in here.
That's what we're that's what we're doing here.
OK.
All right.
And then I think we can go ahead and execute this now.
In the previous save method, we did an execute update because we were updating the database.
In this case, we're going to be executing a query because we're querying for some data out of the database,
right?
So I'm going to type execute query or you could really just type IQ, right and then return.
And now the execute query method is going to return a result set.
So I want to capture that result said this will be the results, right that we get from this query.
So I'm going to capture that with my cursor on the Line 43 and do an option Command V..
And there's my results set, and I'm just going to call it IRS out of laziness.
And I want you to remember again the results set.
You should think of it in your mind as a spreadsheet with rows and columns, right?
And so if there was a match for a person with the idea that we pass in here, then you can envision
that's going to look like a spreadsheet with one row.
OK, now to get the data out of there, we will need to use a while loop.
Typically, that's traditionally the way it's done.
While asked next.
OK, so we're telling the results set to go to the next line or the next row.
OK.
And so you can imagine that when you first get the results set, there's a little cursor or a pointer
or something like that, and it's initially starting off up above any rows at all.
OK.
And so by calling RSA next year now telling it to jump to the first row, if there is any data now,
it's possible to not have any data because we passed in an ID for a row that doesn't exist, and we'll
write some tests to test that scenario out.
But right now, we'll just do the happy path.
OK.
So presumably, if it found anything, we are now on the very first row.
And so next, we'll want to start pulling the data out.
So the way I'm going to do this is let's first grab the ID so we can reference the results set that
get along because the ID is going to be a type long and we can actually use a couple different approaches
to do that to doing this now.
We could specify a column index.
And so the ID was the first column that we specified in our query so we could see for getting the ID.
That's column one first name is column two.
Last name is column three and so on and so forth.
Or we could use the actual column names that we specified as well.
So I'm actually going to go for the column names because I think it'll be a little more readable.
OK, so I'm going to say I'd.
OK.
And then I need to capture that.
And I don't know, I will just call it person ID so that it doesn't conflict with this variable of ID
up here.
All right, then rest get string and we'll grab the first name, first underscore name.
And then we'll capture that, and we'll just call it first name.
Now notice the ABC is offering some is actually suggesting some names for this variable.
And so I can actually just choose that one.
Why am I not going for the underscore name?
Well, because now these are Java variables, and the tradition in Java variable naming is to use camel
case not underscores unless it's a constant which is all uppercase, and then you have to use underscores.
OK, so I'm going for this one.
All right.
And then our state gets string again and we'll grab the last name, last name.
Be careful about your case sensitivity as well and capture that.
Last name, and then we're going to need the date of birth, what's the date of birth?
Now this is a timestamp in the database timestamp, right?
But we're going to need it to be a zoned date time, so we're going to have to do some translating here,
as you've seen before.
Right?
So first off, we'll call this Dobey.
All right.
So now this is going to return a timestamp.
Now, the nice thing is we can go to a local daytime really easily right off of the timestamps, so
we're more than halfway there already with that.
But now we want this guy to be wrapped inside of the zoned daytime, right?
So what I'm going to do here is type ARG for argument.
And that just wrapped this whole entire thing in opening and closing parentheses for me very quickly.
And then I'm going to do a zone date time dot of like so that him and jump back over to the end.
Go inside of here comma, because I believe there's a version of the zone date time of method that takes
a local date time as one input and then a zone ID for the second input.
Now why do I need that Zone ID?
Well, because this local date time that I'm getting from the time stamp in the database doesn't have
time zone information built into it.
And so but a zone date time, which is what our person class requires, needs a time zone right now.
What time zone will I actually use?
This is actually an interesting thing to consider.
When we create our people, our person instances ourselves.
We can specify a time zone for the dates of birth, right?
And it can be any time zone in the world.
But when we get them from the database, they're all going to be normalized to a time zone of GMT zero.
And so with what I have here, I can't know what time zone this person originally was born in.
So with what I have here, I don't know where this person lives, right or where they were born or whatever.
I just know that the moment in time in the world when they were born is whatever it is, relative to
GMT zero.
And so what I'm going to have to do here in setting the Zone I.D. by clicking on that is just to specify
GMT zero, because that's what it is coming out of the database, OK?
So + zero.
And that's actually great, because now that I have a zone date time for their date of birth relative
to GMT zero, if and when I ever do find out what their preferred time zone is, it's easy to just warp
the time of this date of birth to whatever their preferred time zone would be.
All right, and then let's capture that as date of birth.
There we go.
And so now I can just set all these fields on a brand new person instance and return that person.
Now you might be thinking to do something like this creative person found person equals new person and
then start plugging in all of the variables here first name, last name, date of birth, like so and
then even set that ID, said Heidi.
To what did I call it, person ID?
Right?
Like that?
However, you're going to run into a problem if you do it this way.
So here's this found person.
And so we need to return that person here.
So let's see what happens if we try to do this.
It's red.
Now, do you want to take a guess as to why I am not able to return this person here?
OK, so the issue is that I'm creating this person inside of this while loop here.
OK?
And any objects that I create inside of this loop will only exist within the lifetime of that one loop.
OK, so once this code is done executing and the thread leaves this while loop.
In fact, once the thread leaves this one and only iteration of the wire loop, all of the variables
that got created locally inside of this loop ceased to exist, and real quickly they'll get garbage
collected by the JVM, in fact.
And so I cannot refer to this person down here because this person here is out of scope.
OK.
So pretty much any time we're creating objects within code blocks and you know, a code block is pretty
much any code in between.
Curly braces, those objects are local to that block of code, and they will cease to exist once the
thread has left that code block.
OK, so what's the solution for this?
Well, it's actually pretty simple.
All you need to do is to declare the variable outside of that block somewhere where you have a wider
scope.
OK.
So for example, a pier, we're creating this person so I could actually just hijack this person.
I'm going to select all of that and delete that and then set this to null.
OK.
So I'm not creating the person yet, but I am declaring the person up here in the widest scope possible
for this method.
OK?
Any local variables that I declare appear in the outermost level of the find by ID method will be visible
throughout this method.
OK.
And so then down here, I can just set this new person to this person variable.
OK, let me copy that and then paste this here.
OK.
So this person has scope throughout the entire method, whereas any objects that are created down here
only have scope within this loop.
All right.
And so then down here, I can return.
I can return.
That person.
All right, so then let's jump back over to the test now, and let's run it again.
OK, so it's still failed.
Let me click on that and see what's going on now.
OK, so.
The IDs are 64, the first names are Test, last name is Jackson.
Ah, but we've got an issue with our time zone.
Yeah, because the original person that we created the test person here had a time zone of GMT minus
six, but the person were getting out of the database as a time zone or GMT zero in effect, right?
And so that that's not matching.
All right.
So what do we want to do about that?
Well, I can think of one or two approaches here.
One thing I'm wondering about is jumping over here to the person class and coming down to the equals
method and looking at where we're doing the comparisons of the date of birth.
And we could consider normalizing the date of birth to always be something like GMT zero, right, at
least when we're comparing.
So let's see what that might look like.
I'm going to actually drop this down to a new line, so I have a little more space here.
So data birth dot.
So what we could do is something like with zone.
Same instant, which we've seen before with zone.
Same instant.
And then use a zone I.D..
Of.
Loops of zero.
Dot.
And then do the same thing over here, so in other words, we're just normalizing these two dates relative
to GMT zero, we're not changing the the the moment in time when these events occurred.
We're just saying when we want to compare them, we want to compare them as if they were relative to
GMT zero so that you're comparing apples to apples completely, OK?
So same thing here the be with zone.
Same instant.
Zone Edy of.
Plus zero.
OK.
OK, so now let's jump back over to our repository tests and now let's run this again.
There we go, and now it's all matching up.
OK, so that zone daytime stuff through a through a little bit of a wrench in the works there, but
it wasn't too difficult to address.
So in the next less and less flesh out the find by IED use cases a little bit more.
We can do negative cases and perhaps a few other things.
So see in the next one.