OK, so I almost debated whether or not I needed to explicitly make a lesson for this next topic because
I am hoping that it will be very, very short.
We're just going to look at the links method.
I think we've already touched on this in some of the other lessons, but I may not have been super explicit
about it.
So it certainly is a method that you will use a lot when dealing with strings in Java.
And so it's probably worthwhile just to touch on it very quickly, explicitly.
All right.
So back here again, we've got our class emptied out with our main method.
And again, I will create a string my text equals and four score and seven years ago.
All right.
And this one super super simple.
Well, let's just set ourselves up to output some text, but we'll reference the my text variable.
And then we will use the dot linked method.
And it does exactly what it probably implies.
It does.
It tells us the length of the string in terms of characters.
OK.
So if we run this?
We get 29.
I'm not going to sit here and count all of those help, but I trust it for an easier scenario.
The Why don't I just make that three characters long and then we'll run this again.
There we go.
Three.
So it does what it looks like it should do.
It tells us the length of the string.
So let's just talk briefly why we would ever need that.
As we've already seen, there are times when we might do something like break out a string into an array.
Right?
In fact, I will do that real quick.
So we might do something like two character array and then capture that.
And then let's say we want to print that print out.
One of the characters, like the third character in that array.
So we'll run that.
OK, so there's the R in the word for right?
Because that's the third character, which is index two, because indexes are zero based.
So the F is index zero.
The O is index one and then the R is index two.
OK.
That's how that works.
Now here I'm hard coding this number, but in real code, you probably you might not be hard coding
a number like that.
You might be figuring out that number through some programmatic means.
However, you'd want to safeguard that you don't exceed the length of that string, right?
Because we've seen what happens when we do that.
If you exceed the length of a of an array, for example, here I'll put a big number in here like 100.
There definitely is not a a index 100 character in here because the string itself is only three characters
long, right?
So if we run this, let's just see.
OK, so we get a predictable exception index 100 out of bounds for length three, right?
And so one place where you might want to use the length is simply to safeguard against something dumb
happening like this.
So let's say that we had determined the number of the index that we wanted to retrieve out of this string
through some programmatic means and that that number was stored in a variable.
So I will select this number just to simulate this scenario, and I'll do an option command V to select
that and put it into a variable.
And I'm going to call it index.
OK.
So.
So then I could protect myself from having my program blow up by putting an if statement in here, and
we will learn about if statements in the future, so I could say something like if index is less than
my text length.
Then.
I'm going to indent that because I want that to be inside of this f block or conditional block.
Then I will allow this.
Statement to execute.
So this is basically putting some protection around my program a little bit here, I'm saying only execute
this line of code if.
The index that I'm trying to pull out of this character's array, this index here is less than the length
of my string.
So if let's say that instead of 100, we make this three.
OK.
So if Index three is less than the length of this text, which in this case is three.
So that would be false.
So this would not execute.
Now, if this were.
To which would be the R.
If two is less than three, write my text that length, the length of this string is three.
So if two, because that's what this evaluates to is less than three, which is true, then go ahead
and print this.
So let me do that again.
However, if Index's three.
Is if three is less than three, which is not true, three is not less than three.
Then this will not be permitted to execute.
So if we run this now.
It is no longer possible to cause the program to blow up because we have a safeguard in place with this
if statement here.
So even if I put an excessively large number in there, like 1000.
Everything's good.
But if I put a number that fits like two.
Now we get the AH printing out, because that's safe.
OK.
So there's one example and then another example that we saw earlier.
Let's see here.
I'm going to delete all of that.
And I'm going to make another string.
Second text.
Score.
Then I'm going to make a string builder.
And maybe you'll recall that string builders allow us to concatenate lots of strings together into one
string.
And it is possible to use the string builder to do this in a highly efficient way by telling the string
builder at the time that we initialize it and create it.
What is the final length of the final string that we are going to make out of all of these smaller strings?
So if I wanted to combine these two strings together and I wanted to do that really, really, really
efficiently, though this isn't super necessary to do.
But if I wanted it to be totally efficient, I could tell the string builder the total length of the
final string that I want, but I don't have to sit there and count it.
I could just let the computer figure that out for me by simply doing something like my text that length
plus second text length, and let me give myself some some room here.
Just like that, then I can append.
My text and I can append.
Second, text, OK, so I just built the string builder that is going to concatenate these two strings,
but it's going to do it very efficiently, and I'll just remind you if I did not initialize the capacity
of the final string, in fact, here let's go ahead and that's print out the final string so I can do
builder dot to string.
OK.
So we'll run this.
OK, so the final string is one two three four five six seven eight characters long.
So if if I did not initialize this builder to know that the final string was going to be eight characters
long, what the string builder would do by default is it would have to just guess what it considered
to be a reasonable amount of space to allocate in the memory of the computer.
And honestly, I don't even know what that amount would be, but I'm sure it would be larger than eight,
OK, which means that we'd be temporarily wasting some of the space in the memory of the computer just
to append these two small strings together.
Or conversely, if I had an excessively long resulting string longer than what the string builder would
normally try to allocate by default, then that would cause the string builder to be a little less efficient
because it would have to go and reallocate even more space after the fact, rather than just getting
it right the first time.
So by me, supplying it with the exact length that I need, it can be more efficient, more efficient
in allocating exactly the right amount of space.
But like I said, in a case like this with just two strings or three strings or whatever, and they're
pretty short, you're not going to notice any change in speed or optimization at all.
This will matter more, though, if you were going to be appending tens or hundreds or thousands of
strings together, somehow you might really want to be able to specify exactly how much space you'll
need for that.
But anyway, so there's the link method being used again, and we had seen this before, and that's
it for length.
So see in the next one.