All right.
Welcome back to another exciting video in this lesson, we're going to learn about the MapReduce pattern.
Now the MapReduce pattern is a very commonly used pattern in functional programming to allow developers
to take large amounts of data and sift through it and and reduce it down to its essence or to a summary.
An example of this would be something that we've actually already done before, where in fact, we've
already kind of seen the MapReduce pattern in action a few lessons ago when we wrote a stream pipeline
to process all of our employees and total up their salaries.
The total of the salaries at the end was the was an example of a reduced function.
The sum function that we used, in fact, was the reduced function.
OK, so there are many other things that we can do with the MapReduce pattern, though.
Besides just summing up a grand total of objects, we could count the number of objects we could get
an average.
We could find the max, the max value, a minimum value and also MapReduce doesn't necessarily only
have to apply to numerical summaries, either.
We can do things with other types of data as long as the end goal is to kind of summarize or condense
the data down.
All right, so let's turn to the ADP and play around with MapReduce.
Oh, by the way, the map part of MapReduce is the mapping that we've already used before, where we
use the map function to convert one data type to another or one, or to convert one object or item to
another type.
So for example, in our existing application, here we are using map to do things like convert from
the text form of those lines that represent an employee into an actual employee.
And in fact, we first convert to an AI employee, right?
And then we do another mapping to convert from an employee to just a regular employee.
So we use map in a lot of different ways.
We even use Map again, I believe, to extract out the salary from the employee, right?
So then we don't even care about the employee anymore.
We're just focused on just the salary.
So there are a lot of uses of the map function there.
And now we'll learn more of the uses of of the of how we can reduce from a stream.
All right, so turning to the ABC, let's just take a quick look again at some of the things I was just
talking about.
So here's a map here where we're taking the a stream of strings and then converting them into a stream
of an employee.
Then we're taking that stream and converting it into a stream of employee.
Let's see.
And then down here on line forty nine, we're even converting the employees after we've sorted and filtered
them a bit.
We're converting those employees into just their salaries.
Now we're doing that here with a method reference.
This is just a very quick review.
And in here, we're just using this method reference so that we could get a print out to the terminal
in addition to returning or extracting the salary, right?
So we're doing all of those things.
And then finally, we're pumping all of that into this some function here that we already learned about.
So this some function is one of our reduced functions, right, because it takes all that data and reduces
it down to a sum total.
However, there are a number of additional methods that we can use besides just these some, and now
we'll play around with some of those.
All right.
Oh, by the way, I did delete what we were previously working on.
We don't need that anymore.
So that's where that went.
Sorry, I didn't show that on screen, and it looks like it looks like I may have deleted a bit too
much because I think we were also printing out that some weren't we.
So let's let me let me just add that back in real quick.
OK.
And I think I'm going to rename this variable sum because now we're about to use it to do a lot more
things than just something as we experiment with additional reduced functions.
So maybe I will just rename this variable to result or something for for now.
OK, so let me just run this.
Make sure that that all still works.
OK, there we go.
Yes, so was that 1.5 million or so?
OK, that looks good.
OK, so there's a sum.
So let's just see what else can we do within the realm of the reduced functions?
So there's a sum we can take an average.
Now, the average method, if we hover over it, as you notice here, we as soon as I change that sum
to average, we got squiggly lines here.
So if we hover over this, we will see, OK.
Now the problem here is that the average method does not return an integer, as the sum method was.
This method is returning something called an optional double.
Now we just learned in the last lesson what an optional is, but we didn't talk about an optional double.
But it's it's pretty.
It's pretty straightforward.
It's really just a hybrid data type of an optional that can only hold doubles.
The regular optional class can hold on to any type of class, but the optional double can only hold
doubles.
It's just being more specific, essentially, so that it can help to protect us from making stupid mistakes,
since we already know that we're working with numbers here.
So, so the main point of the optional double is the fact that if you're going to take an average,
we know that the average that is calculated may not be an integer.
In fact, that there's a high probability that it won't be an integer, right?
Because how do you find an average?
You take the grand total of summing up a bunch of numbers, right, divided by how many numbers or how
many items were in that list, right?
And so if the numerator is not evenly divisible by the denominator, then you're going to have fractional
components to the to the result, right?
And those cannot be conveyed via integer.
You're going to need a data type with higher precision, such as a double.
And so you need a double.
Now why?
Why are they making it optional while they're making it optional in case the average cannot be calculated
for some reason?
The most obvious reason would be that there are no items in the stream to even calculate on right.
You could have an empty stream.
And so what should you return there?
And so rather than returning a zero, which may, you know, they could do that, they decided to be
technically even more accurate and just make it an optional double right.
And that way, if there are no items in the stream at all rather than return to zero, just return an
empty, optional essentially right, and then the programmer can decide how they want to handle that.
Maybe they want to convert an empty optional to a zero, or maybe they just want to test for whether
or not the optional is empty and then say some string like, you know, no data found or something like
that.
All right.
So that's the reason for the optional so to fix this.
Now all we need to do is come down here and just click on this change.
Variable result type two optional double and watch what will happen when I do this bam.
The return data type switch from end to optional double right now down here.
To make good use of that, I could just print this and it would give us something.
In fact, you know, let's go ahead and just run this and see what we get if I just leave that result
alone as it is.
OK, so we get this thing here where it's saying like optional double and then it's kind of enclosing
it in brackets there and then we get the actual average coming out of it right now.
If we don't want it to be presented like that, which we don't, because that's like showing the raw
data type.
Essentially, it's calling the two string on the optional double data class data type.
What we would probably prefer to do is to call one of the methods on the optional class and interpret
this in some meaningful way.
If we're certain that there is a value there, we could simply call the get as double method, which
returns the actual double.
However, if there is nothing in there, that's a bad idea.
So in general, it's not well recommended that you use optional in that way where you call the get method
right or in this case, the get as double method.
A better approach would be to either call something like the or else method, which will return the
value in the optional if it exists.
But if it does not exist, then it will return a default or alternative value, right?
And that's a pretty easy one to use.
So we could say like, OK or else zero.
So this is saying if result is not empty, then return.
It's double value or else meaning if it is empty, then return in this case, a zero.
So let's let's try running that.
Here we go, and so now it just stripped off the optional double that they're right and we're getting
the the true value.
All right.
So there's how to do an average very easily and straightforward.
So keep in mind now, what does that actually doing?
That's doing a couple of things that is determining the number of items, which in this case would be
the number of integers that are coming out of this map to end this stream here.
OK.
Because it needs to know the count, right?
The number, and then it's also taking, and then it's also determining the sum.
So it's actually doing a little bit of what we were already doing previously with the sum, right?
And then it's dividing those to get the to calculate the average.
All right.
But we can do more.
We can find out the max salary.
And that's pretty straightforward.
We can just call the max method.
Now, look at this as soon as I put this.
As soon as I change that to Max, we get errors again if I hover over.
Now it's returning an optional end short for optional integer.
The max method here in this particular case knows that it's taking as an input a stream of integers,
and it's going to sum up those integers.
And so logically, it knows that the sum of integers is going to be another integer.
However, just as with the average method, it is possible that that stream could be empty and therefore
it models the result as an optional integer rather than just an integer, so that we can decide what
we want to do in the event that it is in fact empty, rather than just assuming that it should just
model empty as zero.
OK.
So, yeah, so we can change this by again, just clicking on this little thing here.
That's the idea that's doing that for us, by the way.
And so bam, now it changes that to an optional end.
So let's find out what the max value is for our data set.
Now, keep in mind, we're doing some filtering here.
Let's see what else we doing and we're doing some skipping as well, right?
So we're not really dealing with the entire dataset.
We could remove some of these and maybe we'll play around with that, but it doesn't really matter right
now.
Anyway, let's go ahead and run this and see what the max salary is for the given filtered data set
that we have at this time.
OK.
It looks like it's 1.5 million even.
Yeah, one point five million.
And if there's a max function, then you know there's going to be a mean function as well, right?
To find the minimum salary in this stream, right?
Thankfully, Max and men do essentially the opposite of the same thing, and so I don't need to change
the return type there.
All right.
So let's run that and see what the minimum is.
Cool.
6500.
All right.
Now, if I put my cursor after the period and do a control space, we can take a look at a few more
of the of the reduced methods that exist here because there are a number of them.
So we've done max average men.
Let's see.
There's count.
That's that's sometimes quite useful, right?
Let's try that one out.
All right, and again and again, we we get an error here, so if I hover over what's this going to
return, OK, now this one returns along.
Now if you're wondering, OK, what's up with this one?
Well, the thing here is we're asking it to count, right?
So even if the stream that precedes this step is empty, that should return a number, right, that
should return a zero.
If you're asking someone to count the number of things and there are and there is nothing to count.
You should still say, well, there are zero.
Right?
And so we don't need to model this with an optional we can return an actual value.
Now, if you're wondering, why is it a long instead of an end?
Well, think about way back in.
Was it Module two or whatever where we learned about number systems and things, right?
You know that a long data type allows for a greater range of values than an end.
Right.
In fact, a long is twice the number of bits as an end right, an integer is 32 bits as long as 64 bits,
and therefore we can represent much larger numbers when you're counting things in Java.
Typically, you will want to model them with a long.
Now, we don't usually model just counting things generically with big decimal, which could go even
further or a big or a big integer, because that's a very heavy weight data type.
Usually, we allow the long data type to suffice for most day to day Typekit counting.
OK, so at any rate, that's why we're getting along.
So again, we'll just click here and have that data type change.
Now here I get an error because now that I'm no longer getting an optional of some sort back, there
are no methods on long.
Long is a primitive data type, and therefore it does not implement any methods, right?
So I need to delete that there.
And let's run this and see how many records or how many employees it's counting.
What really technically it's how many integers it's counting.
OK, so we're only getting back four.
All right.
So there's count, and that's probably going to cover these convenience, reduce functions and by convenience,
I mean, like, they're all, you know, wrapped up in a nice, pretty bow and ready for us to just
use just like this.
However, there there is one more reduced function that I want to take a look at, and it's kind of
like the granddaddy of all of what we've seen here.
It's a it's a lower level function and it's actually just called reduce.
So let's take a look at that now.
So if we select this word here and then put in Reduce and we'll first play around with with the first
version of this here.
So this first overloaded version of the reduced function takes two inputs.
It takes something called an identity, which in this case will be of type entry, and then it takes
something called an end binary operator.
Don't be frightened by these names.
So into binary operator, that just means this is one of our functional interfaces, OK?
And this is an interface that defines one functional method on it that takes two integer inputs.
OK.
And then it returns one integer value out.
This reduced function allows us to actually implement a lot of the reduced functions that we just were
playing with before, like the sum marksmen.
So in fact, let's go ahead and try re implementing some of those so that you can see what that would
look like.
OK.
So let me go ahead and just type it out first, and then I'll I'll circle back around and explain in
detail how it's working.
So if we wanted to do a sum right, the sum function using this lower level reduce, what we would do
is we would set the identity to zero, which I will explain why in just a moment, and then we would
supply it with a lambda or a method or a method reference, if you like.
But a lambda sufficient here and our lambda expression will need to essentially sum up two numbers.
OK.
So it's a lambda expression that describes a method that will take two inputs that need to be summed
together.
OK, so two inputs.
So we'll call them A and B, and then we've got our Arrow operator here, and then we're going to simply
say a plus b.
That's it.
All right.
So let's run that and see if it works.
There we go.
OK.
One point five million, I believe that is what we got originally when we did just our basic thumb before.
All right.
So now let me explain how this is working.
It's less it's not as complicated as it might be looking to explain this.
I'm going to turn to a spreadsheet.
All right, so here we are in a spreadsheet.
Let's pretend like we have our integer stream with the values 10, nine, seven, five and two in it.
And here are our A and B.
So let me show you what the the reduced function is doing currently.
Basically, what it's going to do is it's going to start off by taking this.
This first value, which is called an identity, and it's going to plug that in to this a here, then
it's going to take the first number in the stream and plug that in to B, then it's going to take these
two values and call our lambda, which in this case would say zero plus 10.
And it's going to take the result of that, which would be a 10.
Then it takes that result and it calls the lambda expression again.
But this time it passes in the result of the previous iteration, which is 10, and it plugs that into
a then it grabs the next value in the stream, which is a nine, and then it does the lambda and executes
lambda expression, which is to add those which would be 19.
Then it just comes down to the next iteration takes that previous value of 19 in this case.
And then it plugs in the next value from the stream, which is a seven.
And then it adds those up, which will be twenty six.
And then so on and so forth, so I think you get the pattern right.
It just keeps taking the result of the previous iteration and bringing it down into the A.
Then it gets the next value and puts that in B and then it does whatever the operation is.
So the key thing here is to understand that
the operation that we're doing is is pluggable, right?
That's the part that we supply.
If we jump back over here, we are supplying this.
And really, out of all of this, what we're really supplying when you get right down to it is just
this bit here.
In fact, it's even smaller than that.
It's really just the operation, literally like the the plus in this particular case, right?
That's what we're really supplying.
Like, what is it that we should do with a and B, right?
All the rest of this is can can be thought of as boilerplate.
The fact that you're always going to be given two numbers or two values rather and you're going to do
something with those two values.
And the result of that is going to be plugged back in as one of the two values for the next cycle.
OK.
So that is the essence of a reduced function, and that is how it works.
The reason for the identity should hopefully be kind of obvious.
It is simply so that when you're starting the iteration process, you're starting with a value that
serves as an identity for the type of operation you're doing.
And by identity, I mean, for a given operation and identity will give you whatever value you're plugging
in.
So in this case, we're plugging in a 10 and we're doing addition.
So what value can we use with 10 and addition that will return a 10 back?
That would be zero, right?
If you want to get out of this addition operation the value that you're plugging in, which in this
case is just the 10, you need to use a zero.
If we're doing multiplication and you're passing in a 10, what value can you combine with that?
10 for multiplication to get back out a 10?
That would be a one, right?
Because ten times one gives you whatever.
In fact, that's the identity, right?
So we are supplying the identity value that will allow us to get back out what we put in for that very
first iteration, right?
So that you're kind of like initializing the iteration, if you will.
OK.
All right.
So let's try a slightly more complex one now.
What if we wanted to implement our own max function here, right?
Max function using the reduced function here?
How could we do that?
Do you want to try to take a stab at trying this out yourself first?
Why don't you?
And then I'll show you how I would do this.
All right.
Did you get it?
So here's the thing if we want to find the MAX, let's just speak in English and figure out what are
we trying to do here?
So we've got a list of numbers, right?
And we want to find out what is the largest number there.
So what we're likely going to do is we're just going to be comparing the previous number to the next
number and just keep going.
And if one wins, then we then we keep that one.
So in in this case, here would actually be nicer, I suppose.
So since we want to do the Max, let me it might be actually a little nicer if we flip this around.
Let me let me do that.
Let me put these around to 15 percent.
OK, so if we had this stream of integers and we wanted to find the max, right?
Well, we know that we'd have some reduced function that was going to start off with a zero and a two,
presumably, right?
So we'll even just plug those in real quick here.
All right.
So what do we want to do?
What operation do we want to do that, should we?
That should result in us getting a two out of this right now?
Obviously, we could do in addition, in this particular case for this one iteration, and that would
give us a two.
But as soon as we came down here, in fact, here we'll just do it.
We'll think this through a little bit.
Oops.
Two and five right now, as soon as we get down here to two and five, obviously we we don't want to
do addition because that would yield to seven.
What we would want instead is to get a five.
So what operation is there, in fact, here?
Let's do one more.
So then we'd want the five here and we'd want the seven here.
OK.
In fact, let me show what what the what the winning results should be in each of these two should win
here, right?
Then five should win and then seven should win.
OK, so now the question is simply what operation can we do that would give us these results, given
these two inputs right?
That's what we need to figure out.
So what we could use here is a simple, conditional check really combined with like a greater than or
something like that, greater than or less than however you want to look at it.
So, for example, we could say something like if zero is greater than to then return zero.
Otherwise or else return to or stated more algebraically, I suppose if A is greater than B, then return
a ealth return B and then you would get it to and then you'd bring the two down here.
Well, you wouldn't bring the two down here.
The reduced function would bring the two down and then it would do it all over again.
If A is greater than B, then return a alth return B and then you'd get a five, right?
So I think we figured out our logic in general.
We just want to implement a conditional that says if A is greater than B, then return a Else. return
B, right?
Or you could flip flip it around and say if A is less, then B then return B else return.
You could flip it around, but that feels a little less straightforward somehow.
Now what's the most concise way that we could do that, right?
There's a way that we could do that in one line, can you think?
Did you think of what that was already?
All right.
So we can simply use a ternary?
Right?
So let's go ahead and implement this now.
So we want to say for a and B, if A is greater than B, now, here's where the IFF comes from.
If you remember how to use the ternary, there's there's kind of like you're if at least that's how
I think of it, the question mark, I think of that as being the if if a is greater than B, then return
a l.
S Return B.
There you go.
Right now, it's not the most readable thing here, but that's how Turner's always look right.
So you just got to get used to reading a ternary like this.
If A is greater than B, then return a else, return B.
Right?
So that should give us the max value out of this entire list.
So let's run it and see.
There it is.
And I remember that from when we actually just used the max method directly, we got a one point five
million.
So that is working right now.
Let's do the opposite and do a men, right?
So here, let's see if we can just flip that around.
If A is less than B, then return a otherwise return B, I think that's all we need there, right?
We just flip that operation around.
Let's run that and I think we got a 6500, if I recall correctly.
Now this is a fun one.
We got a zero.
Does anyone know why we got a zero here?
It's because the minimum value out of all of this is going to be the zero again, turning back over
here.
There's the zero there, right?
So zero is going to win every single time.
How can we prevent that?
I can think of two ways, one of which I haven't taught you yet.
Still using the reduced function.
So maybe one thing we could do is just initialize that to a really large number, right?
Let's let's see what happens if we do that.
So actually, to be honest with you, it doesn't even need to be all that large.
So maybe if we just set it to the max value that we already saw was at one point five one to three,
right?
So now let's run this.
There we go.
There's our 6500.
So having seen this now, I would I would suggest that probably if you wanted to use the reduced function
to find a men, which I don't even know why you would want to do that, though, instead of just calling
the men function itself.
Right?
That's probably what you really should do.
But if for some reason you're looking for the minimum or something or a pattern similar to this, you
need to be really careful and aware about this identity business here.
OK?
For exactly this reason, that identity that you are supplying could could cause you problems, basically.
Now that being said, I want to go ahead and show you the other overloaded version of the reduce function
because there's another version that doesn't require us to supply an identity at all.
But watch what happens when I use this one.
Bam, everything blows up again.
So let's see why if I hover over any of the red squiggly lines.
So the other version of Reduce is the same, except it doesn't take the identity and it returns an optional
end.
In this case, it returns an optional for whatever the stream data type is.
So in our case, we're passing in it.
We're working previously with an end to end stream.
And so all of the values will be integers.
If we were using doubles or whatever, then it would be optional double right?
It's Typekit, all right.
So it returns an optional end, and it does so for the same reasons as we learned with some of those
other reduced functions that we looked at earlier.
It could be that there are no values in the stream, and it doesn't want to just assume that it should
return a zero.
Now, the reason that the other version of Reduced doesn't go ahead and just return an optional of some
sort is because of that identity because we're passing in that identity.
It should not be possible to not have some value at all, basically turning back over here again, even
if this list were empty because we had to pass in that identity and we were passing in, for example,
a zero, you'd at least have a zero.
Right?
That's that's the basic idea behind the other version of Reduce.
And so the versions of reduce that, take the identity don't need to consider the case where there's
nothing at all in the in the stream, right, that where the stream is empty.
All right.
So coming back over here, so again, we'll just hover over this and then click on this to change that
data type.
There we go.
And then we'll come down here to the result and we'll do something a little better than whatever.
And I don't know, I'll make this negative one.
All right.
So now if we run this, let's see what we get.
OK, so cool.
Now we get our 6500.
So this this reduced function that doesn't take the identity is reasonably smart.
Now you may be wondering, well, how is it figuring out what to do if we're not passing in the identity?
So let's jump over to the spreadsheet and we'll take a look at what it's doing.
OK, so what this version of Reduced does, since we're not supplying it with an identity to start with,
what it does is it simply takes the first value in the list and returns it.
OK?
And then each subsequent iteration then picks up where that left off.
OK, so it's just going to say, OK, two, well, I'm just going to bring that two over and then just
keep going that way.
That's all it's doing.
Now we'll see in a moment here that that will have some interesting.
I don't know if you want to call it a side effect, but an interesting effect, particularly if you're
not working with numbers.
Well, let's see, even if you are working with numbers.
Hey, and I got one more thing.
I want to show you really quickly that we can do with the reduced method here.
So here we're passing in this lambda expression to implement, you know, the ability to find the minimum
and we've looked.
At How to do Maxson and sums and things of that sort.
And obviously, you also could just not use the reduce and use some of the built in streams API or in
this case, the entire stream API methods that also let us some and find the men and find the MAX.
One more way that I want to show you, though, just so you just for complete completeness.
We could also do this.
You can use them a method reference, and there are some methods that that are given to us for free
to do these same things.
OK, so on the integer class, for example, look at that there's a min max and some right there.
So you can just pass that in and that's going to do what you think it should write.
Just like we could use Max, I'll run that real quick.
OK.
So I think you get the idea.
Just remember, pretty much any method that will take a lambda expression will also take a method reference
as long as they both are adhering to the expected interface.
So that's all I wanted to show you there.
All right.
So I mentioned at the beginning of this lesson that these reduce functions can be used for more than
just numbers.
So let's see one or two examples of that.
So I think what I will do here is just just make a few lines.
This will just be some quick thing.
So let's use some words.
Let's create a stream of words.
And I think what we can do is simply start off by typing the word stream of and then we can pass in
whatever we like.
Now, I need to import that.
So let's pass.
In some words, let's pass the names, Tom.
Terry.
Mary.
And Sam.
All right.
So here's a stream, and then let's do some things with this stream, so let's call the reduced function
and we'll use the second.
We'll use the version of the reduced function that does not require an identity.
And well, here let me first tell you what we're actually trying to do here.
So let's let's let's start off by making this reduce function that will take these names and maybe just
concatenate them essentially something like Tom underscore Jerry underscore Mary underscore Sam.
OK, let's just spit that out.
So think about that.
You've got this stream of individual names, right?
And all we're wanting to do is to reduce them down to one string, one concatenated string, right?
So that's an example of how we can use a reduced function on non numeric data, right?
As long as we're essentially just taking the list of things or the stream of things and then spitting
out one one combined or summarized output, that's basically what the reduced function is for.
So how can we do this?
Do you want to take a stab at thinking of how you can implement a reduced function to do this?
Why don't you try that?
All right.
Did you get it?
OK, so now let me try.
So let's see here.
So we're going to have a a lambda expression that we know is going to take two values A and B.
Right?
So here's our a comma B and then our arrow here.
And so what we're going to want to do, I think, is something like a dog can cat.
Underscore.
Dot can cat.
Be.
I think that is.
I think that's all we need there.
And then we'll want to capture that.
Output, I'll just call it, and then we'll print that.
Output.
All right.
Let's run that and see if that does what what we're looking for.
Yeah, it does what we're looking for, except for it, I forgot to.
I forgot to extract out the actual raw value from the optional because this is returning an optional
right.
It's an optional of a string.
And that's because we're not using any identity, you know, initializing identity, right?
So yeah, let's let's extract that out or else.
I don't know.
We'll just do A. quotes for that for now.
All right.
So at any rate, that works the way that we expected it to.
Now, let me show you something kind of interesting here.
Let's modify this to uppercase everything, OK?
So if we wanted this to uppercase everything.
And so now that's the output, by the way, I just uppercase that selection by doing a command shift.
You and I can toggle it up and down with that same command shift you which or control shift you for
Windows and Linux.
So, yeah, that's sometimes really convenient.
So that's the output that we want.
So again, you want to take a moment to figure out how to do that.
All right.
So let's see.
Now, here's how I might do that.
A dot to uppercase.
I'll take this version here and then concatenate an underscore and then concatenate a b.
To upper case.
All right.
Let's let's run that and see what we get.
Yeah.
Cool.
Tom, Jerry, Mary, Sam.
Very good.
Now here's the thing I want to show you what happens if there's only one item in this list, right?
So let's I'm just going to delete these guys and just leave just Tom.
Watch this.
Now, what do you?
First off, what do you think is going to happen?
All right.
So let's see.
Oh, look at that.
We just got Tom all by himself, right?
Nothing else.
Is that what you were expecting for some of you may be?
Yes.
I bet for some of you, maybe no.
So this proves that when we don't supply an identity, if we jump back over here to the spreadsheet,
this proves that when we don't supply an identity, that very first iteration that the reduced function
is going to do simply takes whatever you passed in and then just like spits it back out without trying
to do anything else on it because there is nothing else it can do right?
Let me be a little more explicit here.
So if Tom was what we passed, then then on that very first iteration, A is going to kind of be left
blank, essentially.
And Tom's going to get dropped in there.
And the logic of the reduced function itself is going to say, if I only have one item in the stream,
then don't even bother applying that item to the lambda.
Just spit that same item right back out again, which would be this one right here.
And in this particular case, you're done right?
And so it didn't get processed.
And we're seeing the proof of that right here by the fact that it didn't uppercase or our concatenate
an underscore or anything, you would need at least two items in the stream for that to happen.
And so if I add back in one more Brady, I'm not a sports guy.
That's just the name that popped up in my head.
I mean, I guess I know enough sports to know that there's a sports guy named Tom Brady, and that's
about all I know.
There you go.
And now you get a Tom underscore Brady.
All caps.
Right?
All right.
So this was a little bit long.
But I think a very important lesson because the MapReduce pattern can be highly effective when needing
to process large amounts of data.
Now one last thing I want to say about that pattern is one of the reasons why it's so darn popular is
because when you get into these functional techniques like MapReduce, one of their benefits is that
they can easily be parallel.
And what that means is you can implement these techniques in such a way that you can process lots of
data across multiple processes.
We've already touched on this in previous lessons.
But the MapReduce pattern together lends itself exceedingly well to being parallel lysed or or implemented
across multiple processors.
So let's say again to use some of my previous examples that we've got a list, if you will, of one
billion items, right?
One billion employees, one billion, whatever, right?
And we need to determine something like the grand total sum of some property of all of those items,
right?
Well, basically, what can be done in that case is that that large list of one billion can be segmented
into groupings, right, depending on how many processors you have.
For example, let's say you have 10 processors, so one billion divided by 10.
So then in that case, the computer might choose to segment out 10 groups of a billion.
So you'd get 100 million items per grouping, right?
And then those hundred million each would be fed into their own processor.
And then that processor could could sift through that data and sum up whatever the property is that
you're looking for there.
And then it would spit out the result of all of that, right?
Just that result.
So you've just done a map reduce.
Although in this case, I'm not really talking too much about the map part, right?
But you've reduced the hundred million on that one processor down to just one value and the other and
the other nine processors would presumably do the same thing.
And then all of their values can get summed up together as well.
And bam, now you've got the grand total and you were able to arrive at it, presumably in one tenth
the time, roughly minus the overhead of doing the segmentation and all of that.
We won't get into that.
But you know, hypothetically, theoretically, roughly, you know, one tenth the time that it would
have taken if you only had one processor sifting through all one billion of those records all at once.
Right.
So the MapReduce pattern is extremely important to get familiar with when you do more of these types
of parallel processing for large amounts of data and things of that sort.
All right, so let's wrap this up.
And I will see you in the next one.