Welcome back in this lesson, we're going to learn about something called class member visibility that
might sound kind of complicated, but it's actually a pretty simple concept.
So in order to learn about this concept, we first need to define what is a class member.
So if we go back to our person class first, I will point out what the class members are here, and
then we'll have a look at the concept in another way.
So here we have our class person.
And the person class has a number of items that are directly contained within it.
This variable here middle name that is a class member because it is an item that is directly underneath
the class.
So is this method?
Say hello and say something and get middle initial and add.
So really, a class member is really just any item, especially a variable or a method that is directly
underneath the class.
And when we refer to class member visibility, all we're really talking about is the accessibility of
those members based on the keywords of private or public or protected or no keyword at all, which also
means something in terms of access.
OK.
So let's take a look at this in another way.
I have prepared a graphical representation of classes, packages, methods, et cetera.
So here we have two different packages, this default package has one class in it, which just has a
generic name of class.
And then over here we've got another package called Carm that example dot model.
And in it, it has multiple classes, but this largest class here is labeled person.
And then within sight of this person class, we have several methods do stuff speak, get age, greet
plus a constructor turned to the side, and then we also have some variables in particular this one
labeled name and another one labeled Dobby.
And then there's one off to the side that looks a little weird, called greeting.
In fact, they'll zoom in a bit.
There we go.
OK.
So in this person class, the class members would be these variables named job in greeting, as well
as the methods such as do stuff, speak at age, etc. Those would be the class members.
Now some of these methods, such as speak, have variables.
And by the way, I'm representing variables in this diagram as hexagons.
OK, so let me zoom in a bit more here.
Some of these methods have variables inside of them as well.
These variables inside of the methods are not class members because they are not directly underneath
the class.
OK.
All right.
So let's talk about the significance of the color coding here.
What I'm doing here is simply color coding, the different items within a class so that I can convey
what level of accessibility or visibility the items have.
So we'll start with the simplest one, which is green in this diagram.
Green means public, and we already discussed in a previous lesson the visibility rules for classes.
But as you can see here, I have the person class itself in green, which means that it is a public
class and that means it can be seen from everywhere.
So if we were to jump over here to this, in fact, let me zoom out a little.
So if we were to jump over here to this generic class, which is in a different package, in fact,
it's in the default package, but that is still a package.
Any code within this generic class would be able to access the person class because the person class
is public.
OK, so that's kind of a little review.
What we want to focus on here, though, is the rules for visibility of the class members themselves.
And so we will continue with the conversation of the meaning of public.
And we will apply it first to some of the public methods that are on the person class.
And this won't be a real long discussion at all as far as public methods, because it's pretty simple.
Any method that is public can be accessed from anywhere as long as its class is accessible.
Now notice I didn't say as long as its class is public because there are ways that a class can be accessible
from outside of itself without being public.
But as long as the method is public, it can be accessed from anywhere that its class is accessible.
So in this diagram code that is over here in this generic class would be able to access any of these
green methods.
And we have two green methods the constructor and the speak method.
So let's just review a little example of what that might look like in code.
So if we go back over to the ADC and I'm going to open up the Project Explorer.
And I'm going to just create two packages, and I'm going to give them very generic names.
OK, so package one, I'm going to call it package one.
And then I'm going to create another package.
And I will call this one package, too.
And then I'm going to create two classes, one in each package.
Class A.
And I will create another class and package to.
Class B.
All right.
And so let's see here in Class B, let's just create a very simple method.
And we're going to make it public.
And I'll let it be void, and I'm going to call this method public method.
It will take no inputs and it will return no output.
And this method can just print something to the screen.
This is.
A public method.
All right.
So that's in Class B.
So now if we jump over to Class A, let's write a little code where we're going to access the method
in Class B.
So I will create a public static void main method so that I can actually run this thing.
And what we'll do is we'll create an instance of Class B.
We'll call it Class B.
OK.
And please note that when I reference Class B, I allowed the ID e to automatically import it from Package
two, if you may recall classes that are in packages other than the where you're coding have to be imported.
So I'm coding in Class A, which lives in Package one.
And so if I want Class eight to be able to access Class B or use anything from Class B, I must first
import Class B, but I allowed the ID e to do that for me.
Don't worry, we'll do plenty more of this.
If you didn't quite track all of that.
All right.
So now we have an instance of Class B because we've created a new instance of Class B from package to.
And we're storing that new instance, or we're referencing that new instance inside of this variable,
which I am calling Class B with a lowercase C.
And so now, because there is a public method on Class B, we should be able to call it Class B dot
public method.
There we go.
And if we run this, let's see what we get.
OK, great.
This is a public method, actually.
Let's make this a little clearer.
If we jump over here to this method, let's even say this is.
This is the public method.
Of Class B.
And maybe I shouldn't have a space there, Class B.
All right.
And then we'll jump back over here to Class AA and A..
I'll run that one more time.
Great.
This is the public method of Class B, so we can see that class is able to run a public method on Class
B.
All right.
So let's jump back over to Class B and now let's introduce probably the next easiest level of visibility
to understand, and that would be private.
So we'll make a private message now public.
Void, private method.
And we'll make this output something as well.
This is the private method of Class B, OK?
Now one thing this is supposed to be a private method, so we need to go to this keyword here and make
it private.
All right.
So now we have a private method.
OK, so then if we jump back over to Class A.
And we try to call the private method on Class B, let's see what happens.
Class B Dot where is it?
Well, it's not even showing up.
Private method.
All right, that's what it should be called, but it's not even showing up for us because it's private.
So the idea isn't even bothering to let us try this if I want to bulldoze my way through the private
method.
And type it anyway.
The idea is going to warn me and I get all kinds of this, so it's just really not happy with me even
trying to go there.
Let's see what happens if I try to run this anyway.
OK, I get an error in the error private method has private access in package to that Class B, so yeah,
just nothing's going to let me access this method or run it.
So if we go back over to our diagram, I'll just try to show a little bit of what that might look like.
So if this class over here in the default package was Class A, just, you know, some class in a different
package and then this class over here was Class B, this red structure here, this red method, that
would be our private method.
And so what we're seeing is that code over here in Class A, if you imagine this is class is not able
to see or access a private method in a different class, in a different package.
OK.
All right.
Let's jump back over to the code.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to comment that out, and I did that with a command forward slash,
by the way.
And let's let's see what else we can and cannot do with a private method.
So I'm going to go back over here to Class B.
So now private methods can be accessed from other methods within the same class.
And to prove that I will add another line into the public method of Class B and here I will call the
private method and look at that.
The ADP lets me do that.
No problems, right?
So this public method of Class B is more than welcome to call the private method of Class B.
But it gets even more interesting.
Since the public method of Class B is able to call the private method of Class B and the public method
of Class B is able to be called from Class A.
That should mean I'm going to go and just delete this commented thing here.
So Class B, that public method, so what happens if we run this now?
So let's see.
I'm going to run class.
Look at that.
So now we get this is the public method of Class B.
This is the private method of Class B.
So what does happen there?
Well, we created an instance of Class B, then we called the public method, which is the only method
on Class B. that that class can actually call.
We're calling the public method and there's no problem there.
And then in turn, the public method prints out its first message.
This is the public method of Class B, but then it calls the private method the the.
The public method of Class B is calling the private method of Class B, so it's like a daisy chain,
if you will.
OK.
And then the private method prints, it prints out its message.
So this is perfectly permissible because Class A isn't calling this method directly.
Class is only calling the public method and then the public method in turn is calling the private method.
And this indeed is the typical pattern for use of private methods.
Private methods can be called from other members of their own class.
They just can't be called from outside of their own class.
Now, you may be wondering, why would you ever want to make anything private?
One of the reasons can be that you need to implement a lot of logic and functionality in your program
in order to get things done.
But that logic and functionality is not needed outside of the class.
And so you are generally encouraged in object oriented programming to reduce the visibility and accessibility
of class members as much as reasonably possible, so that you can protect your code from unintentional
consequences, essentially unintended accessing and accidentally or potentially manipulating or changing
data in ways that were possibly unforeseen.
So really, a private method in this case could serve as a helper, if you will, to the public methods
on the class.
If you want to think of it that way.
OK, so now let's introduce an additional class to package to.
So I'm going to create another class.
And I'm going to call this other class.
Because sometimes I don't have much imagination.
All right.
And here's what I want to test now, can other class in package to access the private method of Class
B in Package two?
So in other words, two classes of the same package?
Can one see the others private methods?
Let's find out.
So I'm going to jump over here to other class, and I will just create a simple public method.
I will call it method one.
All right.
So in method one of other class of Package two, we will create an instance of Class B and we'll call
it Class B, so we'll create that new instance just like that.
And now let's see if we can access Class B dot.
Private method and look at that.
No, we cannot.
It's not available to us.
All right.
So we now see that a private method here.
Let's jump back over to Class B, so a private method can only be accessed from other members of its
own class period.
Now let's introduce another method to Class B.
Let's introduce a protected method.
Protected void.
And we'll name this protected method.
And then we'll say we'll have it output.
This is the protected method of Class B.
All right.
So let's well, actually first, we need to clean this up in the other class because the I.D. and Java
are not happy someone to just delete that.
All right.
So jumping back over to Class B, so now Class B has one public method, one private method and one
protected method.
So let's see if the protected method is accessible from Class A.
So here we are in Class A of Package one.
And let's see if we can access the protected method Class B protected method and look at that it doesn't
show up.
So no, we cannot access be protected method of Class B from a class in another package.
All right, now, let's jump into the other class of package to.
And try the same thing.
Class B Dot.
Oh, look at that protected method is accessible from a different class in the same package.
OK, so we're we're kind of piecing together the rules of visibility here.
OK, so just restating that a protected method of a class is accessible from other classes in the same
package.
However, it is not accessible from classes outside of that same package.
Now why might we want that kind of capability?
Well, to answer that, I'll jump back over to our diagram again, and let's focus a little bit on this
combat example package here.
So we've got this class here, person, and then we have several other classes as well.
Now what these other classes are meant to model is not important at all for this discussion.
But one concept that you can take away from this lesson is the idea that we can designate certain classes
within a package to be the key classes that for that package such that other code outside of that package
can only interact with designated classes within this combat example, that model package, for example.
It's kind of like setting up gatekeepers.
OK.
So it could be a situation where there's super useful functionality in some of these other classes,
and that functionality is very useful to this main class here in this package.
And so this there might be code in the person class that calls a lot of different code in these other
classes here.
But you generally don't want these other classes being accessed from code over here.
Outside of the combat example, that model package, for example.
OK.
Or to get a little more complex, maybe there are some methods on some of these classes that you do
want to allow to be accessed, but not all of them.
Right?
So in that case, you might have some of these other classes being public and some of their methods
being public, but some other methods being protected.
And that would mean that code over here is able to call some of these green met or all of these green
methods, but maybe not able to call the orange methods definitely not able to call the red methods
if I zoom in here.
Right, so we've got a red method here, we've got an orange method, a white method.
Only the green methods might be the ones that we want to permit to be called from over here from outside
of this package, but this class.
Person class would be allowed to call.
For example, this do stuff method.
Let's assume that this orange color here, if you can see that if you're not colorblind, this orange
method here orange orange can signify that that method is protected.
OK, so let's say that green signifies public, orange signifies protected, red signifies private and
white.
I haven't introduced yet.
All right, so let's jump back over to our I.D..
All right.
And again, don't worry if this isn't all completely meaningful to you.
We will be writing so much code in this course.
We will have other opportunities to see how these concepts can actually be used in real life.
OK, so let's introduce one more level of visibility and that is called package protected.
And to do that, we just don't put anything for visibility, so we'll just say void package protected.
And we'll have this printout a message.
This is the package protected method of Class B.
All right.
So let's find out what the rules are for this one.
So let's jump back over to Class A.
And let's see if this new package protected method is visible Class B Dot.
Nope.
It is not.
All right.
So that that keeps things actually pretty simple.
The only thing that a class outside of the package in question can access is a public method or a public
member.
OK.
So let me be careful here.
These rules of accessibility are not only for methods, they are also for variables, and I will show
that in just a few moments.
All right.
So then let's see what the other class can do.
Class B Dot.
OK, so a package protected method is accessible from another class in the same package.
So then in that case, what's the difference between a protected method and a package protected method?
Well, the only difference has to do with a concept called subclass thing, and I don't want to get
too much into that right now.
But if we jump over to the Hello World Program.
And I opened up the project thinking here.
I want to refresh your memory on one thing.
Over here, we modeled several concepts, we modeled addresses in cats and dogs and persons and pets.
If you recall, the classes for cat and dog actually extended a higher level concept of pet.
And by doing so, the class for cat and dog became subclasses of the pet class.
So there are special rules for the visibility of methods within subclasses.
In other words?
I could decide to make certain methods of this parent class of pet visible or accessible to its subclasses
or not.
This also has to do with whether or not the subclasses are in the same package.
If the subclasses are within the same package, they're going to be able to see everything other than
private methods.
OK, so let's actually see a quick example of this because it's not too difficult.
So I'm going to introduce a throwaway method here.
Just a little example method.
And let's see, we will.
In fact, I will introduce two methods I will introduce one that is protected.
And we'll call it protected method.
And we'll have it print out.
This is.
The.
Protected method of PET.
And then I'll make another method that will just be package protected so I won't put any visibility
keyword here void.
Package protected.
This is the package protected method of PET.
All right.
Now.
I'm going to create another package.
And I'm going to call this specific.
That animals.
It's not a great package name, by the way, but it will suffice.
OK, specific animals.
And then I'm going to take cat and dog and I'm going to move them into specific animals package.
All right.
So now if I open up specific animals and jump in here.
Let's see if those other methods that we just added to pet are accessible here.
And way I will do that is I'll just jump in here into this existing method and let's see if we can call
either of those other methods.
So the way that we can refer to methods that are on this parent class with this super class is by using
a special keyword of Java called super.
Super lets us access whatever may be on the parent class or parent hierarchy so I can type super and
then dot, and now I can see what methods are available to me from up above, right?
Because Cat extends pet.
So these are the methods that are on the pet class.
And indeed, I do see that there's the protected method there.
Do we also have the package?
No, but we don't have the the the package protected method.
And I can double check that by trying to type a little bit of that method name.
And no, it doesn't give me that, but I can get to the protected method.
So that's kind of interesting.
OK, so I can call the protected method.
And if you'll recall, in fact, here you don't have to recall it will jump back over to the other project.
And we will recall together that we had class say and package one in Class B and Package two and in
Class A.
If we tried to access the protected method of Class B, which is in a different package, we weren't
able to do it.
I'll just show that again.
Class B that.
No, no protected methods.
Are accessible here, and that's because Class A does not extend Class B and Class C is also not in
the same package as Class B.
OK.
But over here in the Hello World project.
Cat is able to access protected methods of the pet class, even while Cat is in a different package
from PET.
And the reason Cat is able to access the protected method of PET is because it extends pet.
And that's what the protected methods allow for, however.
If we jump over here to pet.
Pat also has a package protected method, and that method is not accessible.
To the cat class.
Now I'm going to create one more animal that extends Pet, but I'm going to put that animal in the model
package, so it'll be in the same package with Pet, so I'll create another animal.
I don't know Turtle.
Turtle.
Turtle extends pet.
All right.
Let's create a.
A method that is unique to Turtle.
It will be turned void.
I'm going to create a hide method, as in, you know, the turtle can hide in its shell.
OK.
So Turtle has a hide method, and now we want Turtle to be able to access the well, we want to see
what methods off of pet can we access from within the turtle?
So again, we'll call Super Dot.
And now look at what we have access to.
We now have access to both the package protected and the protected methods.
So we can do either.
In fact, I'll go ahead and call both Super Dot.
So there we go.
We can access both of those methods from the turtle class because not only turtle extends pet, which
is one of the reasons why it's able to get to the protected method, but it's also in the same package
as PET, and therefore it has access to the package protected method as well.
So again, don't feel too bad if you don't feel like you're quite getting this.
I'm a big believer in repetition to really start to get the hang of things.
So this will just be the first time I'm mentioning this concept, but we'll review it again when we
learn more specifically about class hierarchy.
So don't worry about it.
Just kind of take in what you can, and we'll get to the class hierarchy section and we'll go into this
some more and we'll see more examples.