All right, so now that we've learned a little bit about the basics of what a set and a harsh threat
are and how harsh that is using a harsh code to make it quick to access items within it.
Now let's find out a little bit more about where these hash codes are actually coming from.
So if we turn back to the A.D. here and I'm back in the main class, I'm going to jump in to the employee
class.
So if you want to find a line that refers to the employee class, you can hold down on command and click,
or you can put your cursor there and do a command B to jump right to it or control B for Windows and
Linux.
All right.
So now we're in the base class of employee.
And if you'll recall, we generated a few methods on this class towards the bottom of the class.
So I'm going to scroll down pretty much to the bottom here.
And one of the methods we generated quite some time ago was the equals method.
And if you may recall, though, when we generated this equals method, the I.D. also generated one
other method for us at that time, which is the hash code method.
In fact, I don't even know that it's possible to generate one without the other within the idea if
you allowing the idea to do it.
I think it's just one menu item here.
And just a reminder the way that we even did that was we just went to an empty line somewhere within
the class, then did a command in or for Windows Linux users.
You would need to just right click and go to generate.
OK, so we did.
We did that.
And then one of your options here is equals and hash code.
So the ADC doesn't even give you the option of generating one without the other, and that is actually
a very good thing.
One strong piece of advice?
Well, my first piece of advice is whenever you're creating a class, it's always a great idea in general
to go ahead and generate an equals and hash code and even a two string method as well.
This is this is advice that actually comes straight from one of the godfathers of all things Java programming.
Joshua Block in his book Effective Java, which I have mentioned previously.
And one of the other suggestions that he makes in the book is make sure that if you're if you're going
to have an equals method, go ahead and create a hash code method.
At the same time, make sure that they play well with each other.
And so that's one of the reasons why we're seeing the equals and hash code as one option in the generate
menu item here.
All right, so.
So, yeah, let me clear out these empty spaces here.
So here's our generated hash code method.
Now, honestly, it's not all that necessary to understand in low level how this hash method is working,
but we will go ahead and just jump into it just so you can get a gist of it, OK?
First off, though, one thing to note is when we used the ideas generate hash code and equals method
option, it asked us to specify what what properties of the class we wanted to include in the equals
and hash code method.
OK.
And so what that's basically saying is what underlying properties of this class do you want me to use
to generate a hash code in this case?
That's really important to note because what we're trying to do with this hash code is to effectively
create a number in this case, an integer that will hopefully be very, very unique for any combination
of properties on an instance of this class.
Let me say that in another way.
In this particular case, we're modeling an employee and the employee class has a number of properties
on it.
But chief among them are the last name, first name and date of birth.
Right now, we could have other other properties that are meaningful to what an employee model is.
But in this case, these are the ones that that are most important to us for our purposes.
So in the real world, what would it take to hopefully ensure that any given employee is truly unique
and differentiated from other employees of a company?
Well, generally speaking, you're not likely to have a high level of collisions.
If you take into account an employee's last name, first name and their date of birth, right, there
shouldn't be a lot of collisions, might not be any at all.
And so these become great properties on this particular class to use for for generating a hash code.
So ideally, what we want our hash code method to do is that for the combination of properties that
we care about, that we think that we think will ensure a level of uniqueness for various instances
of our class that the hash code method would return a unique number.
OK.
So if we had Jerry Jackson born on January 1st, 2000?
That should return a number different from Jerry Jackson, born January 2nd, 2000, right?
Just that one little change should result in a significant enough difference in the hash code coming
out.
And you would hope that there would be very little possibility for collisions.
That is to say very little possibility that two different employee instances with different last name,
first name and date of birth would result in the same hash code or integer being generated.
You would hope that your hash code implementation would be strong enough or good enough that that should
be highly unlikely to occur.
Conversely, though, if you did have two instances of an employee that do happen to have the same last
name, first name and date of birth, then definitely the hash code for those two instances should match
it very well, should match.
Otherwise, we've got we've got problems.
So going back to our spreadsheet example here, here are some example hash codes.
Now I happen to be showing these hash codes as hexadecimal numbers just to keep them a little compressed
to fit here.
But the important thing to note is that they should each be unique as long as the last name, first
name and date of birth are unique.
OK.
And then as you learned in the previous lesson, that hash code can then be converted into an integer.
And again, the process or algorithm that is converting these hash codes to indexes in and of itself
isn't that important.
The important thing, though, is to know that there is some process or technique that is trying to
convert these guys into indexes, and hopefully that process also results in a unique number, though
that can be a little challenging to do.
OK, so turning back to the ADC now, let's jump in to how this hash code method is actually being implemented
by the AIDS auto generated code.
So you'll notice that we're using the this utility class called objects that comes with Java and the
fact that it has a method on it called hash.
And this method takes as input a VAR, ARG or variable number of arguments, which are references to
the to whatever properties of the class we want to use for defining uniqueness essentially, right?
So in this case, last name, first name and date of birth.
So if we jump into this hash method, we will see that it in turn, is just using another utility method,
which is erase that hash code, which takes again a VAR args.
And just as a reminder, VAR args is really just a special form of an array, essentially.
OK.
So here we are defining a VAR ARG named values of type object, and the way we do that is by just mentioning
the word object.
This is pretty much equivalent to just defining an array called values of type object.
Almost the same thing.
Just a little more convenient to call a method with this approach, rather than forcing callers of the
method to pass in an actual array.
All right.
So if we jump into the hash code method, we'll see what this guy's doing.
And here what we basically have is some boilerplate code.
And if I'm not mistaken, this code is, I think, almost verbatim taken from Joshua Block's book Effective
Java.
OK.
So if you want to know more of the thinking behind this code here and how it is trying its best to generate
a unique hash code integer, you can pick up that book and just read the section on hash code and equals
handling.
But the basic thing that it's doing after doing some really quick checks to make sure, hey, is it
null or whatever is, it's just iterating over the elements in our VAR ARG, which is really just an
array.
And in fact, here you can even see that it is modeled as an array right here.
So it's it's iterating over the elements of that array, and for each one, if the element isn't null,
then it calls that elements own hash code method.
And then adds that to a running total, which is stored in this result and then multiply that times
thirty one and it just keeps doing that for each element.
So it would.
So in our case, we're passing in the last name, first name and date of birth.
So this for loop would first hit the last name.
Presumably, it would call the hash code method on the first name.
First name is of type string.
So what's really going to happen is that the hash code and method of the string class is going to get
called.
That will take into account all of the letters in whatever that last name is.
And then those will get added to the result.
So if it's the first time we're doing this, then that will be added to one because this is being initialized.
That one?
OK?
And then whatever that resulting number is, that would be multiplied times 31 stored in back into the
result variable again.
Then we would go to the first name, get the hash code for the first name.
Add that to our running total of the result.
Multiply it by thirty one and just keep going.
And the last thing that would have to be done here would take the date of birth, which would also have
a hash code and just do the same thing again and then return.
That result, which will be presumably a fairly large number because we just kept multiplying some number
of times.
Thirty one, right?
And so that is the implementation that they are giving us for the hash code.
Now there could be other implementations of the hash code method that one might want to use for some
reason.
But I would say, well, I will say this in my entire career, I've never felt the need to implement
my own hash code method from scratch.
I've always just depended either on the idea to generate one for me, or I got a well respected implementation
of a hash code method from something like a book like Joshua Block's effect of Java.
So in other words, there are some fairly smart people who have already figured out fairly effective
ways of generating a hash code where they can try to ensure to the best of their abilities that that
hash code will be unique for the given set of inputs, and therefore you will minimize the number of
collisions that might occur.
All right.
So jumping back now to the employee class?
Let us consider what might happen if we were to comment out the hash code method.
All right.
So before we analyze that, let's just run the the program again and see what happens here, so I'm
going to jump back over to the main class and just going to run it.
OK.
And so what we find is we're back up to a count of 22.
So even though we're using the hash set to store our employees, it's behaving as the code behaved when
we were just using a list reminding you that please be reminded that we did duplicate the first programmer.
Five additional times.
Right.
And so this is now behaving as though we weren't using a hash set at all, even though we are now.
Let's consider what's happening here.
Some of you might assume that because we got rid of the hash code method on the employee class, that
there may not be any hash code being generated for any of our employees.
But that is actually not the case.
We are still generating a hash code for our employees.
However, we're now using the default implementation of the hash code method.
And so as I've mentioned a number of times throughout this course, all classes derive ultimately from
the object class.
And the object class gives us default implementations of two string equals and hash code, to name a
few.
Now, the default implementation of the hash code method actually generates its hash code in modern
versions of Java in a particular way that is pretty much beyond the scope of this course.
The main point that I will make, though, with the current implementation of hash code, is that it
attempts to ensure as much as it can that the hash code method should ideally return a unique value
for each object.
Now, in the earliest versions of Java, the default hash code method did something very similar as
the default to string method.
If you recall, we have learned that the default implementation of two string even now is to essentially
just show a memory location for the object in question.
The default hash code implementation in earlier versions of Java did something very similar to that
by utilizing the uniqueness or the supposed uniqueness of memory locations.
Now, there were some issues with that implementation because the hash code method is supposed to return
the same hash code for a given object with a given set of properties.
And in fact, what can happen in Java is that if an object gets garbage collected or reallocated or
shuffled around, its memory address could actually change.
And technically, the hash code method isn't supposed to change, right?
I suspect that's one of the reasons why that particular method of implementing implementing the hash
code method actually changed.
And I think inversion maybe seven or eight or so, they changed the implementation.
It is my understanding that they changed it to use something more like a random, randomly generated
number or something along those lines.
And these days, they're doing something even more complex, from my perspective, dealing with threads
and things.
So the bottom line, though, is that the default implementation is still trying to give a unique value
back from the hash code method.
And perhaps a simplistic way of thinking about this is to simply assume that the default hash code method
is essentially generating a random number.
OK.
So if we were to assume that that's what it's doing, that it's simply generating a random number,
then I think that can help us to understand why we're getting a 22 back.
So if you know that the default hash code method isn't looking at any properties, because why would
it?
It wouldn't know what properties are meaningful and which ones should be ignored.
So if we just consider what would happen if the default hash code method instead simply returned a randomly
generated number of sufficient length to minimize the number of collisions that could occur?
Well, then it's going to generate a unique number for each and every one of these records, even the
duplicates.
Right.
And if each and every one of them are unique, then none of them will get filtered out, and therefore
you will end up with a count of 22.
Right.
So that's what you get with the default implementation.
It's arguably not all that useful, especially, you know, here where we actually want to filter out.
And that goes all the way back to what I was saying in the previous lesson that a set and specifically
a hash set is only as good at filtering duplicates out as your code allows it to be right.
So when I remove a meaningful hash code implementation from our employee class, the hash set is no
longer able to meaningfully filter out duplicates.
So if you think about that, there's a problem here.
If we look at our data here, what we would want our hash code method to do considering that we've duplicated
the first line five more times.
We would expect with a good implementation of hash code that we would get the same hash code value for
each of these first few items in this list.
And if we did get the same value for each of them, then the hash set would know to filter out the duplicates
because it would see, Oh, we already have this object here, and this is where the hash code method
and the equals method need to work well together.
Which again, is why the A.D., by default, is just making it so that when you generate the equals,
you're generating the hash code they need to.
They need to play well with each other.
They need to ideally be using the same concepts of uniqueness or, in our case, the same properties.
In fact, here's the reason why if each of these duplicates results in having the same hash code with
a good hash code implementation, then once one of them is stored in the hash set, then when the hash
set encounters one of these duplicates, it will take that duplicates hash code.
It will determine if that hash code already exists in its hash table.
Right.
As we discussed in the previous lesson, and when it finds that there is a match, it's not done yet.
It will then call the equals method to compare the duplicate object to the object that's already in
the hash table.
And if they are equal, then it is at that point that the harsh set knows it does not need to store
this duplicate, it can just ignore the duplicate.
So that should help to explain why it's so important for the hash code and equals methods to be implemented
essentially in tandem.
And for those two methods to be using the same philosophy, right?
If you're equals, method cares about first name, last name and date of birth, then your hash code
method had better.
Also, be caring about those three fields specifically so that the concept that makes these objects
unique is consistent right across the hash code and the equals methods.
All right.
So in the next lesson, we're going to take a look at another implementation of the set interface because
as I mentioned in the previous lesson, there are actually three popular implementations of the set
interface that come with Java, and we're currently only looking at one of them, which is the fastest.
By the way, Hash said.
But there are two others the tree set and the linked hash set.
So we'll be taking a look at those as well.
I'll see you in the next one.