All right, so now that we have worked out all of the parsing in the most procedural way possible,
let's now explore some object oriented solutions.
We can maybe try applying to this and see what the various approaches in the object oriented realm may
look like.
So looking at our data here, so we've got all these people right, all these employees of different
types, right?
And so one of the first approaches that I can think of that we could try doing to make this a little
more object oriented is to actually introduce some classes in here.
I can think of a couple of approaches with classes right off the bat, but one I think I'm going to
skip right over.
So one is that we could just create a class called employee and then somehow create and initialize a
bunch of employees for each of these lines.
But I'm not confident that that's going to bring us all that much value.
And so I'm sort of inclined to skip past that and do one step beyond that, which would be to actually
introduce one two three four, I guess four classes, one class per role, essentially.
Now let me explain some of my thinking here when we did the first implementation of this program, where
all we were doing was just determining a salary based on the role and nothing else.
Right.
We didn't have we didn't have all of this.
We only had the role in that case.
I'm not even sure that doing much of an object oriented approach would have would have paid us much
at that point.
Things were so simple, right?
And all we were doing was basically saying, if it's a programmer, it's this much.
If it's a manager, it's this much right now.
When we introduced these details here and the fact that the details can be different per role and the
fact that the algorithm for D for calculating salary with the details is different per role.
That's when it maybe starts to make more sense to look at having different classes per role because
we've got different behavior.
Well, because we have different implementation details in some of the behavior, right?
And in other words, the way that we calculate salary for a programmer is totally different from the
way that we calculate salary for a manager or an analyst or a CEO.
OK.
And those are some, some clues that maybe at least we should explore what doing this in an object oriented
approach might look like.
OK, so let's let's try that.
So let's just create four classes, and we'll just call them programmer, manager, analyst and CEO.
All right.
So I'm opening up my project pain here, and I'm going to throw those classes, I guess just in here
in the calm neutrino SIS employees package.
Java class programmer.
And maybe I'll go ahead and just create them all all at once here.
So programmer and then we need a manager, Java class manager.
And we need a an analyst, Java class analyst.
And then we need a CEO.
Now you'll see some programmers call this class like, which is an acronym.
Maybe they'll do that.
That doesn't feel good to me.
I think that feels a little better to me.
All caps.
I'm not telling you you have to do it that way.
You'll see programmers do it both ways.
But maybe this feels a little better to me, at least in this case.
So I'm going for all caps with my acronym.
All right.
All right, so there's our CEO, OK, now that we have these classes, what are we going to do with
them?
Well, so the first thing I'm thinking is I want code to create instances of these new four data types
that we have these new four classes that we have and initialize them with all of the pertinent information,
right?
All of the pertinent data.
So, you know, we've got the the first name, last name, the date of birth and and now we won't we
won't even really need a field for the role because that is inherent in the actual data type itself,
right?
So let's see here.
So here's our code where we loop over each of the people, right and we do a bunch of stuff.
Right.
Who?
A whole bunch of stuff.
A lot of stuff there.
So maybe what we can do first off is simply instantiate each of these data types according to whatever
the role is.
So maybe something like this inside of the case statement there.
Maybe we do something like programmer.
Equals new.
Programmer.
Now here's the big question, what do we what do we do with the constructor for it?
What I'm kind of leaning towards is maybe we simply pass in the entire string for one employee and then
we maybe allow code inside of the class to do its own parsing.
And what I like about this is that once we do this, maybe this main program here doesn't need to know
the internal details of how to properly pass a person anymore.
And therefore, maybe the code can get a little simpler.
So let me show you what I mean by that.
So here we are pretending like we've got this constructor, which we have not created yet, and I think
I just want to pass in that whole entire line.
So let's see here.
So we could access the entire line of text for the one employee with people.
Matt Dot Group.
So calling a matchers group with no input there that should access the entire line.
OK, the whole entire thing.
Now we're getting the Red Squiggly Line because we haven't actually created this constructor yet, a
constructor that essentially takes a string, right?
So if I put my cursor right here and do an option return, then the ID gives me the option to create
the constructor, which I am good with.
Yes, I want that to be a string and I don't know what I'm going to call this.
Maybe just person text for now.
Yep, there we go.
All right.
Now what do we do with that?
Well, let's come up here and see.
So we know we've got a last name, first name, date of birth roll is implied.
Then we've got all this.
So let's start with these fields here.
Let's just model these fields with these first three fields, at least on the programmer.
OK.
All right.
So let's throw the private string last name.
And then a private string first name, and then we had a date of birth.
Now many of you might have been inclined and I know many programs.
In fact, I don't know if I'll say most programmers, but a heck of a lot, at least 40 percent, if
not 50 or more.
Let's go back over to the main thing here would possibly without even thinking.
Think of modeling this date of birth as a string.
So I don't remember if I've already said this, but when we are modeling, it is highly advisable that
you use data types that most closely resemble the actual type of data that you are modeling.
So in this case, we'd be modeling a field that represents a date of birth.
The key word there is date.
OK.
So while we certainly could just grab that as a string and store it as a string and model it as a string,
we would be missing out on a lot of power that we can have when we actually convert this string into
a proper date by converting it into an actual date field of some sort.
We then can do date math on it.
You know, if we need to calculate or determine how old this person is, that's trivial to do with the
date types that are built into Java.
Whereas if we leave this as a string, it's a big headache and a big hassle and you miss out on a lot
of the semantic meaning of these data.
OK.
So let's model the date of birth as an actual proper date.
All right.
So we'll come over here and we'll say private and we'll make this a local date.
Notice I just type L.D in my I.D. figures.
You must be talking about some class that it starts with an L. A..
Yes, I am local date.
I can just hit return and that gets imported automatically.
And for now, I'll just call that filled Yobe.
And we've done this pattern before.
So you're familiar with it.
All right.
Now, do we need to go ahead and implement something here?
I'm thinking, Yeah, we do.
We probably want to go ahead and pass this out.
So if we jump back over to the main class here.
So we're already parsing this right.
We're already doing that.
Let's see.
We've got this regex right here.
And let's see.
We're compiling it here and we've got a matter here.
So what I'm contemplating is just exactly how do I want to be able to reuse a lot of the code that's
already here?
I'm just trying to decide what's the what's a nice approach to doing that?
What I'm inclined to try first off, is to just copy all of this.
So let's copy this.
Go over here to the programmer class, and I'm going to throw those copied lines in as fields.
First off, mostly, let's see.
So we've got a match here.
Oh yeah, so OK.
So we don't have the.
Yeah, okay.
So this matter doesn't make sense because to use a matter, you need the string that you're actually
going to be matching on, right?
And we don't have that.
So let's see for now, just comment that out.
While I think for a minute here and I'm going to close the project pain.
All right.
So I think it may be appropriate to grab that line and bring it into the constructor.
And maybe we can just take this text which should match this rejects.
It should just be one line of it, right?
But it should perfectly match this rejects.
So if we take this and throw it right there, I think we've got something there.
And then from here, as long as that's a match, we should be able to say something like if people matched
Dot we can use, find or matches here.
Then now I could have used I could have used while, but I already know I'm only passing in one person
here, right?
So at most I'd only have looped once, and so I'm just as good to just use one if.
Does that make sense?
All right.
So now I can start extracting these fields right so I can extract the last name so people match the
group last name.
And I can set that this last name equals just like that, and then maybe I'm just going to duplicate
that once and then say, here I'll be fancy again and use my dual cursors here.
First name and then escape to stop with the dual cursor business.
And then I want the date of birth.
Now let's see two to pass this date of birth.
I'm going to do something that I don't think I've shown you yet, and we will have a module where we
get into dates.
But I guess you're going to get a quick little sneak preview on a little bit more of the date handling
stuff.
So if you think back to the module on numbers at the end of that module, we learned about the number
format, right?
And you may recall, although you may have forgotten it now.
So we've been using no format or to take big decimals and numbers and to format them into formatted
strings, right?
So going from a number to a formatted string, well, we can also go the opposite way.
And we did that in one of our lessons in the number module where we went from a formatted string to
a number, right?
Well, Java has a date format that does pretty much the same kind of thing, and it can go both ways
as well.
And so what we're going to have here if we jump back over to the main class.
We're going to have this formatted date string here, and we're going to want to go from that to an
actual local date.
Right.
So we need to pass this somehow.
And so we can actually use a date format to do that.
So I will show you how we can do that.
Jump back over here.
So let's see here.
Let's create a date format.
Now, these format guys oftentimes are good to have as fields because oftentimes you only need one instance
of them.
So let's see what that will look like.
So Java has a class called date time format.
There it is.
Well, all right.
Daytime format.
And I'll just call it dirty.
Format or.
Now, there are a bunch of basic ones already in existence here, and if our date format already happens
to match one of these, then we could just use it.
So what we can do here is take a quick look at the Java doc.
And see if there is a format that already matches what we want here, so there's only.
All right, so I'm not sure that I see one there, but it's easy enough to just create one ourselves
anyway, so what we can do is simply say of.
Pattern.
And then we can pass in a date pattern if you need to know what the symbols are for the patterns.
This is very similar to what we did with the no format.
Click on of pattern and then pull up the Java dock with an F1 or just hover over it.
And let's see here.
If you notice in this Java dock here, it talks about pattern of letters and symbols.
So if you click on that article, it will tell you what all of the patterns and symbols are.
So we're going to want the month, the day in the year.
So month is specified with a capital M and depending on if you do one or two, that tells it whether
or not it's a it's a two decimal month with a leading zero or just like we're doing it currently with
no leading zero.
So a capital M and lowercase D for the month and then the year is Capital Y.
All right.
So let's try that out.
So capital M.
Forward slash lowercase D forward slash one two, three four.
Because I think that's our format, right?
Let's just double check.
Yeah.
One digit, one digit, four digits.
Yep, that's it.
OK.
All right.
So there's our formatter.
So now when we get ready to grab.
The date group.
T0 be like, so then we should be able to pass it to dty Formatter Dot Pass.
So it even looks just about like the no format method did.
Now this past method is going to return something called a temporal access survey, which we're not
going to talk about right now.
But what we can do next is simply create a local date.
Local date.
From now, a local date class now we've used the local date sort of many times already.
But now we're going to use another method on the local date, which is from.
And this takes something called a temporal accessory, which is what this pass method is returning.
And then it will give us back a local date.
So we'll just use this from method here.
Local date dot from.
Pass that all in.
And now we can just capture all of this.
And there's our date of birth.
OK.
Don't worry, this isn't something you need to, you know, master right here about the local date business.
Like I said, we'll have a whole entire unit where we'll learn about date, stuff, date and time stuff.
So you're getting a little bit more of a sneak preview here.
But this is how we can pass the string representation of a date in a particular format into an actual
date object.
And you know what I did wrong here, I created a new one and I actually meant to just say this that
oops, this state job.
That's that's what I meant to do.
All right.
So we now have all of those fields passed.
Presumably.
Let's jump back over to Main.
And now let's let's let's think about what we're going to do with with these bits here.
So I think we're going to probably just do the same basic approach.
Let's see here.
So we've got yeah, we've got this regex here.
So let's let's grab all of that.
Also.
Jump back over here.
Let's see, by the way, let's make this let's make this people rejects private and let's also make
it final because it's not ever going to need to be changed by making it final, by the way.
Not only do we protect ourselves from inadvertently changing it later on in the program, but we also
allow the Java compiler that converts our readable Java code into machine language.
Essentially, we allow the compiler to have opportunities to make optimizations.
Now, there's no guarantee that it can optimize in every single case, but we're kind of flagging it
like, Hey, this is never going to change, so it may be able to do certain optimal things with that.
All right.
Let's see.
And same thing goes for the pattern as well.
Private final.
And then let's go ahead and paste these other two bits and do the same thing here.
Private final for the programmer Reg X and for the pattern as well.
All right.
And so now we want to be able to parse the lines of code and the years of experience in the IQ.
So let's create fields for those.
Private.
Let's call this lines of code.
Oh, forgot my type.
I guess this will be an integer.
We'll initialize it to zero.
And what else did we have years of experience, private and years of experience, I'll just call it
exp equals zero and private and.
IQ equals zero.
We'll just default them all to zero.
All right, so now we need to parse out those bits.
And so we will use this or pattern, I just realized that I called the program, I called the Rejects
program or rejects, but then I called the pattern coder Oh, well, all right, so we'll use this code
or pattern, so we'll use it inside of the block.
Because if this fifth block isn't true, then surely you won't be able to parse out the rest of the
programmer bits, either.
That wouldn't make sense.
So it has to be done inside of the f block here.
OK.
All right.
So let's see.
We'll we'll work with this code or pattern.
So let's see what this might look like.
Maybe we can do something like code or pattern.
So first thing we'll need is to make a matcher again, write code or pattern that matter.
Now we will pass in one particular field, which should be the People Match or Dot Group.
Details, but details.
And then let's capture that, and we'll call it, I don't know, programmer matter.
And I guess I'll be more consistent here and call this.
Well, I'll leave it for now because we called it code or pattern in the other thing, some being a
little inconsistent.
Forgive me for that.
Well, you know, so let's go ahead and change this to be programmers.
Since the class is now called programmer, let's make all references to programmers be use the word
program at least, so I will do a shift.
Six.
And change the word coder to Prague.
All right, now, at least, I'm a little more consistent inside of this class.
OK, so now that we've got the matter here, we'll have to tell it to actually find things right, so
we'll see if.
Prague matcher Dot find.
So if it finds anything, then we can extract its bits, right?
So will do pretty much the same pattern that we have here.
So we can say this the lines of code equals integer dot pass.
And.
Prague matcher that group.
And the field is called l'Eau Sepedi.
Just like that, then I'll duplicate this line two more times, and now the other two fields were years
of experience, years of experience equals and then this bit is why Zoe and then the next bit is IQ
and this is IQ.
All right.
So now when we create a new programmer and pass in one line of text that's representing an entire person.
All of this should get passed into the person in a nice, usable way.
All right.
So now let's jump back over.
By the way, I'm jumping around with command.
Oh.
Main.
All right, so let's jump down here and see now what was I, how was I doing this up until now?
So.
Most of this code is just a lot of parsing.
The only part that's actually doing any calculating is this one line right here.
So let's implement this one line in our program or let's in our programmer class.
So let's in fact, you know, let's just grab this whole line.
Let's jump back over to our programmer now that one line can become a method all by itself, maybe a
method called get salary.
Let's see what that'll look like.
So let's see here.
Here's our constructor.
So I'm going to make a new method.
It'll be public.
It'll return.
Hmm.
Debating on whether or not it should return an integer or a string because it would be formatted, I
guess it'll return an integer.
Get salary.
All right.
So now for the implementation of it.
Well, you know, I was going to paste well here, I'll do this, I'll paste a reference to it.
But you know, we've got different fields and things now.
So the way we want to do this, I suppose, is let's just return 3000 plus.
Lines of code.
Times.
Years of experience Times IQ.
Oops!
IQ.
Now, if you recall in the main program here, we have this health block to say, like somehow like
if we weren't able to pass anything, then just returned three thousand.
I'm not inclined to do that in the new program or class.
And the reason is because we're defaulting all of these to zero anyway.
And so if any of that is zero or can't be read, then these are all going to end up just being zero
and this will just be 3000 anyway.
And probably if I had thought about that a little more deeply, that's probably true even in the other
in the other implementation, too.
But I can see it a little more clearly here.
All right.
And I don't need this reference anymore.
Jump back over to Maine again.
And now what I'm really wondering is if I can get rid of a whole bunch of this code and more like just
depend on this programmer here, and I sort of think I possibly can.
I'm kind of wondering if I can do something like.
Comment out.
All of that.
And then maybe just do programmer get salary.
Oh, now you see where we're getting here now, really, I mean, we haven't saved ourselves a lot of
lines of code, but we have saved ourselves some a little bit of simplification in two different classes
now, right?
So whereas this class has all of this code that our brain has to kind of track when we're done with
all of this, each of these cases may become just like two lines of code.
Right.
And actually, I can see we could even boil it down to maybe one line of code per case, possibly.
And the equivalent of what all of this code is doing will now be kind of moved into those classes.
And so it will be a little more manageable in our heads.
Do you see where this is going?
All right.
So let's see here.
Let's rerun this and see if we're still getting what was it, around eight million or so?
So let's just rerun this.
Hmm.
OK, let's see, unable to obtain local data from.
Oh, maybe I used the wrong format character for the year.
I was feeling like that was looking a little weird to me, let's see here.
Let's see.
So if you see here the the issue, it says unable to obtain local data from temporal access, sir,
which was right here, local date, blah blah blah.
So this formatter here?
Y y y y let me look at this.
I mean, look at the Java doc for this again.
Pattern of letters and symbols.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Lower case y, I don't know why I had that that way command shift to you.
There we go.
So you see that command shift, you toggle the text of your selection or control, shift you for Windows
and Linux.
All right.
Let's jump back over to main and run that again and see if that was the issue.
Hey.
Yeah, we're still getting eight point six million, I'm pretty sure that was the number before now.
We're not printing out any more, though, but I think we can fix that, right?
So we're not printing out for the programmers now.
Let's fix that.
All right.
So let's jump over to the programmer class.
So here's where we're getting the salary so we could do one or two things.
So I think what we can do here is to simply override the two string method.
So let's see what that looks like.
I'll do a control o to override.
I will choose to string.
And so in this, we will return string dot format because this will be equivalent to what we were doing
to print out these names and amounts here.
So we'll pretty much do the exact same code just about.
So we'll do a percent Ask.com percent as Kolan percent s.
And then we will do.
Let's see.
Last name, come up, first name.
Now we are formatting this amount though, right?
So we will want a format again, and I guess I'm going to make that format or as a field here.
All right.
So let's make a no format final.
No format.
Let's see money.
I'm just going to call it money for a minute.
Equals no format, get currency instance.
And then we will use it down in here.
Oh, look at I call it money format.
Money format that.
Format and then we'll just pass in the get salary.
Like so now, if we jump back over to the main we can call system out the print line and then call programmer,
oops.
Pro Grammar.
Talked to string.
Which technically, we probably don't need the two string, but I'll be more explicit here.
All right.
So let's see.
Let's run this now.
All right.
Let's see if we got those hey, yet looking good.
Got all the values there.
So now from this class's perspective, we now.
Don't need any of this.
Look, how much nicer that just got, right?
The code's a lot more manageable.
All right.
So I think we have accomplished what we set out to do for the programmer.
And so in the next lesson, let's just do it again for the manager and the analyst and CEO.
All right.
And I'm just letting you know we're just getting started, OK?
There's a lot more that we can do to make this much more object oriented and you'll see that as we proceed,
but we're off to a nice little start here.
OK, so I'll see you in the next one.