All right, so in the last lesson we played around with making the database actually retain our data
by using an actual file, and that meant that we had to take over some of the settings.
So I showed you how to do that in the application that properties file.
And and then we played around a little bit with some of the cosmetic layout issues, I guess.
And you learn a little bit about bootstraps responsiveness, which is kind of a cool thing.
All right.
So now here's what I want to show you.
Let's say that we are on this page here and we haven't put any information in the form and we just click,
Save, what's going to happen?
I'll look at that.
It just lets us do that and let me do it again.
And there's a fourth record and a fifth record that looks like a bit of a problem, doesn't it?
We don't have any way of validating the data that's coming in here, so we're just allowing any and
all random, you know, button presses to put fake data or erroneous, useless data into our database.
We probably don't want that to happen.
So now I'm going to show you how we can stop that by using validation.
OK.
So there are a couple of parts to this.
There is the cosmetic aspects of the validation.
So where we can actually convey to the user of our form that they did something wrong and maybe even
tell them what they did wrong and maybe even prevent them from being able to successfully submit their
wrong data to us?
And then there's the back end where we actually control all the wrongness in this particular implementation.
Now, a lot of modern web application development would would actually prevent the user from even being
able to submit anything at all to the back end.
But in order to keep this whole section simple and not have to introduce you to any more stuff like
JavaScript or some cool JavaScript framework where we would do a lot of checking on the front end,
I don't want to introduce you to that because that's a different language entirely, and you're already
learning HTML a little bit now and a little tiny bit of CSS with bootstrap.
I just don't want to hit you with everything all at once.
OK.
So we're going to do all of our validation on the backend.
And besides that, there are fantastic capabilities of doing validation on the back end, which you
will see in just a moment, OK?
So that's what we're going to do.
All right.
So let's jump in to the I.D. and I guess we'll start with our domain model of all places.
OK.
So we'll go to the person class right here.
And one of the dependencies that we added into our start that spring that i o page when we built the
original zip file that started off our project.
One of those dependencies that we added in was a dependency called something validation.
And in fact, let's even take a quick peek at that build Gradle.
There it is.
Yes, spring boot starter validation.
OK, so this package we're going to actually make use of now.
All right.
And basically what we can do and I think this is actually pretty cool is we can put annotations on various
fields to specify what kind of data is allowed in those fields.
OK.
And we're using a validation framework to do this, OK?
And the framework is actually a two part framework.
But but at the lowest level, it's actually the hibernate framework.
So that's the same framework that is actually talking to the database, although in this case, we're
not going to use it so much for database stuff.
We're going to use it now just in general to validate that that data that is trying to get entered into
these fields matches up with what we want it to.
OK.
So let me show you how to do that.
So I'm going to put a couple of spaces above the first name.
And let's say that at the very least, we don't want the first name and last name to be blank.
They're not allowed to be blank.
OK.
So there are a number of rules that we can use to do this via annotation.
And one of them is called not empty.
OK, so we can specify, not empty.
And we can also specify a message to be relayed.
If if it is empty, in fact, I forgot their never go message.
And so we can say something like first name cannot be empty.
OK.
We can do that and I can put that on this field as well.
Last name cannot be empty.
And let's see the date of birth.
So we can even do some cool things for a field, for a date filled like we can say that it has to be
a date in the past.
OK.
So you can't put like future dates in there.
We can do at least that much.
So we can specify and not such and.
A date of birth must be in the past.
And then here's a good one email.
There are actually a lot of complex rules around validating emails.
Now we could have done a regular expression and in fact there is a an annotation of the validation framework
that would allow us to specify a regular expression.
However, we'd never write a good enough regular expression to capture all of the intricacies of a valid
email.
And thankfully, we don't need to.
Instead, we can simply use the email constraint right there.
And we'll specify a massage, and we can say email must be valid.
I don't know something like that.
OK, so maybe that's enough for right now.
OK, so the next thing we need to do is jump over to the controller and we need to tell spring in the
Sea to make use of our validation rules.
And this is pretty cool.
So to do this, all we need is another annotation of this annotation will be a little different than
what I think we've ever seen before, because this annotation will go inside of the parameters here.
So it's called valid.
OK.
And then let me import that.
All right.
So we're telling Spring MVC to validate any data that is coming in from the web browser that's trying
to get bound to this person instance here, OK?
We're just telling it to perform validation on all of that.
Now, if that doesn't work out, we'd also like to get some feedback and we can do that by specifying
that we also want to bring in D.C. to feed us the results of this validation attempt.
OK.
And all we have to do to get those results is to refer to this object called errors.
And we'll create an instance of that.
Well, we're not creating the American Spring in the Sea will create the instance, but it'll drop it
off in this variable here and then we can do whatever we want with that variable.
OK, so if there are any errors, we'll even if there aren't, this object will be populated and then
we can check that object to see, Hey, are there any errors or not?
OK.
And then finally, what we can do is this bit here conditionally.
OK, so we're going to say, like, do this if there aren't any errors?
OK?
And so I'm going to wrap all of that and an f block and I'm going to say errors.
So if?
Someone to flip that logic around and put a knot if there are not any errors, then go ahead and save
that person and redirect back to the people page with a clean slate and refresh the table with whatever
is in the database, right?
So that would be what we would normally want.
However, if there are errors, we don't want to redirect back to a clean version of the page.
We want to actually take you back to the page with all of that state still there and by state, I mean,
all of the fields and values that were in the form before we went.
All of that to be repopulated.
If you recall, before we were using this redirect people and we were just doing return people, things
were sort of working, but the form wasn't getting cleared out right.
It was actually retaining all the stuff that we had filled in.
We didn't want that in that case.
But if there were errors and you filled out all of this stuff and you submitted and then you got errors,
you wouldn't want the stuff that you had filled in here to go away.
You'd actually want that then, right?
So we actually can make use of that behavior that we were getting before we implemented this redirect.
OK, so that in this case, it would be a good thing to have.
So what we can do is this alternative really do a another reader return and still just specify people,
but no redirect now.
OK, so this will retain the state of everything that was in this page when it was submitted so that
it can be resubmitted with any changes that anyone might might implement.
OK.
Oh, and one more thing that would happen now is that these errors here would also be made available
to that page.
If there were any errors now, they're not going to show up by default.
We have to actually do some HTML to make those show up OK.
But but they will be put into the model for us.
OK.
All right.
So we're actually done here.
So then let's jump back over to the HTML template and let's make it so that if there are any errors,
they will show up and we'll get some nice formatting also.
OK.
All right.
So how do we do this?
Well, I don't have that memorized, and I don't need to memorize it.
What I will do is come over here to bootstrap and we can see how we can implement validation for a bootstrap
form.
All right.
Or we can get some ideas, at least.
OK, take some inspiration, if you will.
So let's see here.
All right.
So what we're going to be doing is validation on the server side as opposed to validation on the client
side, which would be in the browser using JavaScript typically.
So for that, we need to come down here to the validation area where it talks about how to do it for
the server side, which is right here.
OK.
And so we can look at some of these examples here and get a sense for the gist of what they're doing.
So basically, what they are doing is the input field here has a class and we've got let's see here.
Let's go down to our table.
I mean, at our table, but our form.
OK, so here are our fields, so there's an input field here and it's class form control.
So look at what they're doing here.
Class form control.
But then they're specifying an additional style and they have an option here of either is valid or is
invalid.
OK, so if it's invalid, then you can set that class style to is invalid or you can add that style
to the class.
OK, so we need a way to conditionally add the is invalid style to an input if there is an error.
OK.
That's what we need to do.
So how can we do this?
Well, so obviously the first thing is we need it to kind of see how to do this so that it looked nice
using, in this case, bootstrap.
OK, but then we'll also have to figure out how to do this with the time leave framework.
OK.
So first thing I'm going to do, though, is copy some of what they've got here because in addition
to setting this style for invalid, if it is invalid, they're also showing the validation error message
in a div underneath that widget.
And we probably do want to copy this and and display that optionally as well.
OK.
So I'm going to just copy that that little bit there and then I'm going to come over here and let's
see.
I will do a shift enter and then I'm going to paste that in and I need to name this something validation.
OK, I hate naming these things.
Validation first name.
All right.
Now, this text here, I think, isn't going to matter, because that's going to get replaced automatically
with whatever the error messages are that are associated with this guy.
OK.
That's that's how we're going to do this.
All right.
So now let's put that on hold for a minute and jump over to time leaf.
OK, now to find out how to use validation, we actually can't use the generic, timely documentation.
We need to look at the timely documentation for using time leaf with spring with the spring framework.
OK, because Time Leaf has special support for for being used with spring, and thankfully they've got
great documentation right here for that.
So we're going to jump into this documentation now.
So when you want to just do like kind of generic stuff with time timelines, that first documentation
page that we were on is is fine.
But when you want to find out a little bit more about how to use timely specifically with the spring
framework, then you need to jump into this version of the documentation.
Sorry that they have these two separate things, but I guess in theory, Time-Life can be used with
other technologies besides spring, and that's the reason that they have that in that way.
All right, so let's see here, we want to know how to validate.
And here we go.
Here's the validation stuff here.
Then again, I'm showing you this so that you would know have some idea of how you can find out these
things for yourself.
OK, that's the reason I'm showing these to you, rather than just putting in a bunch of stuff, which
obviously I could do.
But then you'd be wondering, how did you know to do that?
And I wouldn't be showing you every single case there is right.
I'd only be showing you use cases that are specific to what I'm doing right here.
But if you ever wanted to do something a little different from what I'm doing, well, now you'll know
where to go in the documentation to find that.
OK.
So we are going to want a way to add in an additional class on our input fields like right there, for
example, right?
So if there is an error, we want an additional class to be specified there, and I think it was called
is hyphen invalid, right?
We want that to show up there.
So how can we do that?
Well, one thing we could do is what they're showing right here.
They're overriding the class attribute with their own version of the class attribute to in class, and
then they're digging into the fields of the object in question, which would be the person.
And then they're calling.
This method has air.
So they're saying, does this particular field that we're on, which in this case would be the date
planted field?
Does that field have errors?
If it does, that's what this little ternary operator thing is essentially doing there.
If this field has errors, then render out a class called field error.
Now that would work for a lot of people, but it won't quite work for us because we want this style
here to still be here.
We want this class here, we want this class to still be here also.
So we want to add another class to this.
And with this approach, we'd be overriding what's already here in this static class.
We'd be getting rid of that completely and then just replacing it with this other thing.
And so that's not ideal for us.
OK, we want to add an additional class to the list of classes here, and thankfully there is a way
to do that as well.
And what we can do is this option down here to call an error class, OK?
So this allows us to specify a class that should be added to our list of classes if there is an error.
That's basically what that does, OK?
And that's what we want.
So let's do that.
So I'm going to just grab that and I'm going to come up here.
And I guess I'll just put it right here.
Now we want ours to say is invalid.
And remember now that's coming from bootstrap.
Right, right.
There is invalid.
OK, that's what we want.
If that field is invalid and that's what we should get.
So you see here how they have class equals form control and is invalid.
OK.
So if there is an error on the first name field, then this value is invalid will be added to this class
attribute here.
And let me explain something else real quick.
I just realized I hadn't explained this OK, and I'm sorry, but obviously I can't go infinitely deep
into all of this in this last section.
OK, I can only go so far, but I will explain this real quick this time.
Leaf attributes here.
What happens is timely, factually rewrites some of this sage html when it's executing.
So, for example, this field attribute here will rewrite the IDE attribute with whatever value matches
up to here, which in this case would be the same thing that we already have there.
It will also, I believe, render a name attribute because sometimes you need that it'll do a few things
OK.
This error attribute here will check if there are any errors and then if there are some, it will take
this value and add it on to the existing class attribute.
OK, so that's what that would do.
OK, so that's kind of how they work.
And then we also need to make this error message thing here conditional like we don't want that to render
unless there are actual errors.
And so for that, we actually do want to use this to make errors annotation right here.
OK.
And so what we need to do there is simply add that on to errors equals and then we point it at.
I always want to use the dollar sign.
I don't know why I keep doing that.
And then we pointed at the field that we are referring to, which in this case would be the first name
field.
All right.
So what this two errors attribute does is it checks if there are errors for the first name field in
the back end and spring, then.
It will allow whatever element it's on, which in this case, this terror's attribute is on the device
is on this device element here.
It will allow that to render OK.
That will render.
But if there are not any errors, then this will just disappear when we are running our application.
OK, so that will only show up if there are errors on the first page, and it will also populate this
area right here with whatever error messages are associated with this field.
OK.
Which is why I don't need to replace this with anything.
OK, that'll get replaced automatically if there are errors.
Otherwise, it just won't even show up at all.
All right.
So sorry, I know I have to explain a lot here, but man, you know, that's that's how it goes sometimes
with programming.
OK, so now that I've done all of that, I'm going to copy this and let's see, and I'm going to do
the same thing on each of these remaining fields where we're doing validations, at least.
So let's see, we'll call this one validation last name, and we'll change this to last name.
Last last name and I need to add in the.
T. H.
Oops.
H error.
Class is in invalid.
OK.
In fact, you know, let me let me just do that consistently first.
So there it is there.
And let's add it to the date of birth as well.
Paste space and email.
Paced space.
And I didn't do salary might look at that later, but this is enough for now.
OK.
And then let's do this in a few more places as well.
So we'll put this on the bottom of this input field here, and we will rename this to what is this Doby
validation, Dobby?
The lobby and email now this already has one div, but that's OK, we'll add another div.
Validation email.
And email.
All right.
And I think that is all we need.
So now let's refresh.
OK.
Presumably that it's something we'll see here in just a second, so let's just hit this button and see
what happens.
Hey, look at that.
Yeah, see, now it's complaining about these things and didn't do anything on the date of birth, and
I think that's because of the fact that we're using this weird browser provided date of birth field.
And it also didn't do anything on the email.
And I think that's because I didn't specify that the email couldn't be blank or or empty.
OK.
We'll play around with that in just a minute.
All right.
But let's satisfy these two fields.
So let's see here.
Jerry Maguire.
All right, and then let's try that again.
OK, so that allowed that to go through.
So I think what's happening here is that I didn't try to put any kind of date of birth at all, and
our date of birth validation is allowing an empty date of birth.
It's just not allowing actual dates of birth that are in the future.
OK.
And then it is allowing blank emails also.
So let's go fix that now.
So we'll go back over here to the person class.
So for email, we will say that it's an email filled and also that it cannot be empty.
All right.
P.M. must not be empty, and let's see for the date of birth.
I don't think we can do empty.
I think that's only appropriate for strings, but I think we can do not null.
Yeah, we can do, not in all.
What message?
Date of birth can't must be specified.
Let's try that.
OK, so now let's try this again.
Look at that now.
First name, last name, date of birth and email are all throwing up errors, right?
So that's looking pretty good.
So let's do a Bruce Wayne and I don't know one one, 1950.
B. Wayne at that manned calm.
And let's suppose.
Well, we won't specify a salary because I didn't put any validation on that.
OK, cool.
And then let's try.
Wonder Woman.
And let's put a date in the future, so one one, 2023, and let's do no email, so let's try that.
OK.
So it's saying so it didn't retain that date of birth, and again, that has to do, I'm pretty sure,
with the the way that the browser is rendering the date here.
I don't think I really want to play with that right now, but just know that that's because of the browser
on see the email.
Email must not be empty.
OK, so let's play around with email a little bit, though, so let's do an invalid one email address.
Ah, OK, so now what happened there is that the browser attempted to do a little bit of validation
for us, and I don't actually want that at all.
So to try to make sure that doesn't happen, what I can do is jump back over here to the form and I
can actually specify no validate.
All right.
So I can tell the browser, don't try to do any validation.
Don't don't, don't do me any favors.
All right.
So I'm going to restart.
OK, so now let's try that again.
Invalid email, email must be valid.
OK, let's try.
W woman at.
Yeah, and that's still not valid.
OK, so you've got to do the whole thing.
Wonder Woman Act.
I don't remember what island Wonder Woman is from Butt Island dot com.
All right.
So, yeah, cool.
So now that's not an error anymore.
And now the only file that's in error is this date, which won't be retained, unfortunately.
I mean, I'll look that up.
Maybe.
And maybe if I figure out how to do that, I'll teach in one of the future lessons, OK?
But for now, we'll put let's try one more time a date in the future.
Yeah.
So we got the date of birth must be in the past.
OK, cool.
So that's how that can work.
So now nobody can put stupid stuff in here and get past our validation, at least.
OK?
And yeah, let's go ahead and put some validation on the salary field now as well.
So I will copy that and paste it right below and call this salary.
And name this salary.
As well and then jump back into the person class and put some kind of a rule on the salary now, so
this will be a numeric rule.
Let's see what annotations we've got here.
So one way you could look this up kind of easily, I guess, is just to come up here to the imports
and see that all the constraints are coming from this package.
Java X validation constraints.
So if you put your cursor right there and then have control space, you can kind of get a quick peek
at a lot of what your options are.
OK, so let's see.
We've got digits and we've got decimal so we can specify a maximum decimal and a minimum decimal.
I don't know that might.
That might be useful.
We could say like, you have to put in a number that's at least, you know, over a thousand dollars
or something like that.
Well, a thousand.
Right.
So that's one quick way that you can kind of just see what some of the options are, by the way, that
if you want to do regular expressions, there's there's your there's your guy right there pattern that
would allow you to specify reggae acts.
So, yeah, let's try this decimal men.
Right.
So we'll throw that on there at decimal men.
All right, so let's see, we have to provided a value.
What?
Value equals and this will take a string, though, so I don't know, let's try.
You have to have a minimum of a thousand.
And then a message salary must be at least.
1000, OK.
So and maybe also we don't want to allow that to be empty right now again.
This is not a tax field, so I can't use not empty, but I can use not.
No.
OK, so let's do a not null.
And then we'll provide a message and we'll say sal- salary can not be empty or whatever, or it must
be specified or whatever you want to say there.
OK, so let's restart.
All right, so now if I try to save.
Hmm.
I didn't get anything there for the salary.
Let's see, did I not finish putting in?
All of the fields for the salary.
Oh yeah, I did not.
The error class.
Yeah.
T.H error class equals is invalid.
There we go.
Salary cannot be empty.
OK, and then let's try a salary that is below $1000, so let's do 900 salary must be at least 1000.
OK.
Let's do one thousand even and see if that passes.
Yeah, that does it.
But right below that, so let's do 9-9-9.
Yeah.
So that validation rule is working well.
All right.
So I think that is more than enough for this lesson.
And in the next lesson, I think we're going to probably tackle the ability to delete records from the
database.
OK.
So I will see you in the next one.