All right, welcome back.
In this lesson, I'm pretty excited because I think we're going to do something that represents an even
more real world scenario.
We're still working with lambdas and streams API, but will be actually working with an externalized
data file along the lines of what we did.
And I think the last lesson or the lesson before that I can't remember now where I showed you how to
load data from a file.
However, this file is going to be awesome because it has five million records in it, so this will
let us play around with some slightly more realistic scenarios, right?
And we'll be doing this by learning some even more advanced streams, API methods that are quite powerful.
So let's jump to it.
All right.
So what we're going to be doing here is first, we're going to go ahead and just create another class.
We'll still play in the same project, but let's create a new a new class.
So for myself, I'm going to open up my little file explorer thing here, and I guess I will just create
a new class.
Let me let me point out real quick, by the way, in a real professional setting.
I might already have started organizing my files and my classes into more packages.
I'm not very inclined to do that here because so much of this is still just kind of, you know, playing
around.
But at least I want to point out when I'm doing things that are standard for professional programming
versus when I'm doing things that are just for us to learn.
OK, so right now, for the most part, this structure is just for us to learn.
All right.
OK, so I'm going to create another Java class.
And I'm going to call this big data because we're about to work with five million records.
All right.
And return.
OK, and now let's see here.
Now I'm going to close that.
And so let's go ahead and just have our standard public static void main stream hit enter.
There we go.
OK.
And let's see.
So the first thing I think we're going to want to do is just to load up a large file and maybe print
a few records out of it.
OK, just to make sure that we're loading it, finding it and all of that, OK.
So to do that, we will use the files class just like so and I'm just typing files with no space, and
then I'm going to hit return so that I can have the ID import that for me automatically, which you
just did there on Line three.
All right.
And then dot lines, which we've already learned all of this before.
And then I'm going to again use the path class and same thing here.
No space.
I'm going to hit return so that that can get imported as well of and now quotes.
And now I need to paste in a path to a file on my file system of my computer.
Now for this lesson, if you go to the files of this lesson, you will find a zip file there and it
will be called eight r five m dot zip, apparently.
OK.
So what you're going to want to do is to first download that file the zip file.
It's a pretty big file, so depending on your internet connection, it may take a minute or whatever.
And after you've downloaded it, you'll need to unzip it.
Now, if you don't know how to unzip.
Well, I think on every modern operating system, if you simply double click the file, it should unzip
for you automatically.
So I will do that now.
Incidentally, if your operating system doesn't automatically unzip the file upon double clicking,
you might try right clicking on it and then you may have an option to unzip it or extracted or decompress
it or whatever fancy word they're going to use.
OK.
But but generally, I think you should be able to probably just double click it to to extract it.
And when it unzips properly, you'll end up with the same file name, but with an extension of CSP so
that CSP, I think I might have mentioned this once before, but that CSP stands for comma separated
values.
This is this is actually one of these standard formats that spreadsheet programs like Excel are able
to export to very commonly used in business, especially among people who are not programmers but love
to use excel to do programmer type things to play with data.
But usually what ends up happening is they need to give that data over to developers to do more meaningful
programming things around it.
And so typically they will export that data in the CSV format and all it is.
Is this a simple text file that is comma separated?
So basically what we've already been seeing up until now?
All right.
Except this one has five million records that it, by the way, I would warn against just double clicking
on this file and just opening it with any standard text editor.
You can do it.
Probably you'll be OK, but with five million records, it may take a little while to open up whether
that's with with excel or whatever.
It can be done, though, but.
You know, I don't know.
You might want to think twice, especially if you're on a slower computer.
All right.
So now on my Mac, what I'm going to do is I'm going to highlight this file and then I'm going to come
down here to the bottom where I see its name listed here now.
If you're on a Mac and you don't see this, you will need to turn on that setting.
And honestly, I always end up having a fumble around to remember how to do this.
Let's see if you.
Yeah.
View the View menu and then something like Show Pass Bar.
I think that's where it is on the Mac.
I'm sorry, Windows users, you'll have to google it if you don't know how to get the path to that file.
You may be able to just right click on it that I feel like.
I'm vaguely remembering that you may be able to right click on the file in windows and then there may
be an option there to grab the path of it or copy the path or something like that.
OK.
All right.
So did I get that yet?
Hold on a minute.
Let me make sure I actually got that myself.
So I'm going to right click on this and choose Copy as path name on a Mac.
All right.
And now I can jump back over to the ad and my cursor is already in between the quotes and I'm going
to paste the pass right there.
And then I'm going to hit enter now, if you recall, as before, we've got this red squiggly line,
and that's because.
There's always the potential for problems when you're executing commands in Java that want to work with
files, among other things.
You could, for example, refer to a file that does not exist or have a typo or whatever.
And what'll happen is the code.
The program will throw what's called an exception, which is again, kind of like an error, basically
a type of error.
And your program will just blow up or stop working.
So typically, you need to tell Java what to do when certain types of exceptions or errors occur and
different different methods are capable of generating different kinds of exceptions when things don't
work out correctly.
So the ID is actually asking me, Hey, this line's method here throws exceptions that need to be handled.
What do you want me to do about it?
So again, I'm just going to kind of hover over this and then jump over here to more and then choose
to surround with try catch.
All right.
And so now that just encapsulated this one line inside of a try catch block.
And again, you can think of this try catch block as kind of like saying if there is this type of exception,
which, by the way, is a class, we'll learn all about these shortly.
If there is this type of exception, then do whatever I have in this code block down here.
OK.
All right, so now that we've got that, I can make a new line down here.
And this line's method produces or returns a stream.
And so now we can just work with that stream.
So first thing I think we want to do is let's just print out maybe the first two lines.
We probably don't want to print out the entire thing because again, it's five million records.
Right?
But let's just get a get our eyeballs on the general format of what's in this, what's in this file?
OK.
So if we wanted to print a line, we could do a dot for each right and then a system dot out.
Print line, right?
We could do that, however, now if I run this, that's going to attempt to print out all five million
lines, I don't want that.
I only want two lines.
Now, do you remember how to do that with the Stream's API?
Why don't you pause for a second?
And if you remember, go ahead and type it in?
All right, so here is how we can do that.
I will put a new line up above here.
I got my.
Got my tabs off a little bit.
OK.
And we've got the limit.
Method here.
Right.
So we can limit the number of items in the stream, and if you'll recall, this line's method returns
a stream of strings and each string is one line in the text file in this case, right?
So we can limit the number of strings that we actually process.
And so if I simply put the number two in here that will limit the processing of this to two.
Now let me also state this.
One of the really cool things about this file that lines capability is that it is highly efficient in
some in certain types of file input output programming or file O programming.
One common pattern that wouldn't work very effectively here would be to open up the file.
Read the entire contents of the file into a variable or a buffer or an array or something like that,
and then close the file.
The problem with that approach here is that because this file has five million records, that would
mean that we'd have to load up all five million of those records, which is a lot of data into the memory
of the computer while the program is running.
And that would be very wasteful of memory if we don't absolutely need all of that data in memory all
at once.
And in this particular case, for right now, we absolutely don't need that.
So one of the cool things is that this files that lines capability to return back a string is actually
very streamlined in that it doesn't need to load the entire file into memory.
Instead, it's literally reading one line at a time and streaming those lines through for us to process.
And so they come in, get processed and then they go right back out of the memory again.
And that allows us to very efficiently work with incredibly large files if we need to without impacting
the memory of the computer significantly at all.
So, yeah, so whether we're reading two lines or five million lines, it wouldn't need to affect the
memory much.
However, if we read five million lines, it would affect the time right.
We don't want to sit there and wait for that to happen.
All right.
So let's go ahead and run this and see what we end up with.
Now, notice on my Mac before this program is even allowed to actually run fully, I'm getting presented
with a little question asking me if I'm OK allowing Intel AJ on behalf of my program really to access
a to access the documents folder of my computer.
So whether you're on Mac or Windows, you may be asked a similar type of question and in general, you
will want to allow that.
If you don't allow it, the program won't be able to access that file.
So I'm going to click OK.
And there we go, the program is done.
And so now we're seeing a couple of lines here.
Now the next thing that I'm inclined to do is to actually copy these two lines.
I'm going to select them and then I can right click and do a copy and I'm going to open up, excel on
my computer.
Now, if you don't have excel, that's OK.
You don't need to do this, but I'll show you why I'm going to do it.
All right, and I will bring that over here so that you can see what I'm doing.
And I'm going to paste.
What I just copied in this is a spreadsheet program, by the way, if you haven't used Excel, you should
get a little familiar with Excel if you plan to become a professional Java developer because like I
said, quite often, business people like to pass data to programmers to import into databases or to
do programmer things with it.
And a lot of the times you'll want to open it up in Excel to analyze the data so that you can know what
you're doing with it, which is why we're doing this here.
All right.
So so all of that data got pasted in, and it looks like each field of my data is already aligned to
the columns of this spreadsheet, which is cool.
So let me zoom in on this a bit.
Yeah.
So what I'm seeing here is that this first this first row is what we would call a hetero.
It's not meant to be actual data, it's just the names of the fields, right?
So here's the first name filled in here someone's first name.
Here's a middle initial field and there's there a middle there, middle, initial last name, gender,
et cetera, et cetera.
OK?
So that's the nature of the first row.
And then the second row is actual data.
OK, so this just allows me to kind of get a quick idea of the nature of the data and what's in it,
right?
All right.
So now that we've done that, let's do our first useful streams thing now with this data.
And the first thing we're going to do is just count how many records are in this file.
So let's jump back over to.
Until day.
Now, while we're doing this, I'm going to introduce you to another way of doing it, though.
Now there are actually two or three different ways to count the number of records in this file.
OK.
And I'm going to show you each of them.
So first, let's just review one of the ways can you think of a way to count the number of records that
are in this file?
Go ahead and take a moment to think about it.
OK.
Did you get it?
All right, so here's here's one way that you can do it that you already have learned.
I'm going to get rid of the four each and what you can do.
Is simply use the count, the count method here right now, if we if I run this right now, though,
do you know what you're going to get?
You're going to get to right because we're limiting the number of records that can even be processed
to two.
Right.
So we don't want any limits right now.
We want to actually get rid of that.
Now another thing to consider, though, is now that now that we've looked at the nature of this data,
we know that the very first record is actually a header row and.
We probably don't, and maybe we don't really want to count that.
Maybe it doesn't really matter, but you may not want to count that.
So if you wanted to skip that first row, I did show you that once.
All right.
So if you wanted to skip that first row, it's actually very straightforward.
You'll actually use the skip method and you can just give it a number telling it how many rows to skip.
And so let's say here, we only want to skip the first row because we know that that first row is the
header row.
It's not the real data, right?
All right.
So if we just do this and we know that this count method here returns a long, right, so we probably
want to capture that.
So I put my cursor here after the semicolon and do an option Command V. And that's fine for now.
Just call it count.
And then let's just do a system that out and then we'll just print out that count.
OK, so let's run this and see what we get.
Well, there we go.
Five million records.
Right.
So I wasn't lying.
It really is five million records long.
OK, so that's a little bit of review on how we can count the number of records.
But now I want to show you what we're really getting ready to learn going forward.
And that is there's another way to do pretty much everything that we've learned in the streaming API
and this other approach is actually incredibly powerful, OK?
And what it involves is us actually making a call to the dot collect.
Now we learned a little bit about this method before, when we wanted to convert the items in a stream
into some type of collection.
So, for example, if I wanted to collect all of the lines of this file into a list, I could use the
Dot collect and then reference the two list method just like that.
Now, this two list method is actually a method that lives on the collectors class, and so we're seeing
appended like that.
It is a static method, though, so I could remove that.
I could get rid of the collectors here.
In fact, I'll go ahead and do that, and then I could statically import the two list method just like
So now I'm getting these red squiggles because if I hover over this, it's going to tell me that now
that I'm using the to list inside of the collect, I'm collecting all of the strings into a list and
therefore this dot collect method is returning something of type list now.
So before I was using the dot count method and that was returning along, but now I'm using the Dot
collect with a to list and therefore it's returning a list.
And so what I'm doing up here is wrong now.
That's what it's telling me, OK?
So if I want to now?
Well, first off, I need to put a semicolon there to close that off.
All right.
So if I want to fix this, then I need to come up here and just change this to pick up a list.
Or I could delete this, and then I can just let the ID e create a capture that variable again with
my option command the and I'm just going to call this result for now.
And then I will come down here and call that result as well.
Oh, now actually, obviously, I don't actually want to do this right, but this is just a little quick
review in real life.
If I were to actually run this, that would be wasting a ton of memory because it would actually be,
you know, making a list with five million records.
OK.
All right.
Now what I actually want to do, though, is get back to counting and here's what I want to show you.
So this two list method is a static method that lives on the collector's class.
The collector's class has a zillion methods on it, though.
And if we just take a look at what other methods are on the collector's class, you will see that there
is a method called counting.
And if I select this.
Then I get red squiggles again, and if I hover over this now, it's telling me, Hey, it returns along,
so I really should have just left that long that we had before right there.
So I'm going to just delete all of that.
Put my cursor here and recapture.
And I will just call this result.
All right.
So now if I run this, this should behave just as we had before with the discount method.
Yeah, there we go.
So we've got five million again, OK, now you should be wondering, well, what's the difference between
using and I'll just show you for four sake, I'll just show you here.
What's the difference between using this count versus collect and then referring to the collectors that
counting, right?
What's the difference?
Well, in terms of, you know, the end goal, obviously there is no difference.
But in terms of how they're implemented, there is quite a bit of difference.
Basically, the dot collect method here is you can think of it as an entire framework for four, enabling
us to do some really powerful query type things with the Streams API and because it's essentially an
entire framework.
There are all kinds of capabilities that have been implemented in a fairly generic way behind an interface,
whereas the the count method here and many of the other terminal operations that we learned previously
with the Streams API, you can think of those as being more purpose built.
So in some cases, they might actually be more efficient.
A little bit sometimes.
That's that's entirely possible because they're a little more purpose built for what they do, whereas
the operations that we are able to use in the collect method here, they all adhere to the collect methods
framework for doing these kinds of operations.
So the main thing to know is that in many cases, you don't really need to worry about it.
But as we learn more of what we can do with collect, you'll see that there are some things that you
can only do with the collect method that you can't do in any other way within the Streams API.
OK.
And so while they were implementing those things, they went ahead and implemented collect versions
of some of the other operations that we've already learned before, like summing and counting and things
of that sort.
OK.
All right, so I'm going to wrap up this lesson, and when we pick back up, we're going to really dive
in on what we can do with five million records, OK, and how we can analyze the data in really awesome
ways programmatically.
So I'll see you in the next one.