All right, now, in the last lesson, we modified our guessing game to use a for loop.
I want to take a step back, though, and show you a little bit more of using the for loop to do some
really, really basic things because I initially showed you the for loop within the context of an existing
bit of code.
There may be some of you who may still be a little bit confused as to just the basic gist of the for
loop.
It may be a little harder to see the basic structure and pattern of the for loop within the context
of all that's going on here.
In other words, there may be a little too much noise.
So I want to just take a quick step back and go into a brand new clean slate and just show you what
the four loop looks like on its own.
All right, so to do this, I'm going to open up the project pane here.
All right, so let's close this folder for the output of our compiled programs is open.
Let's close that, and we're going to go down here to source.
Click on that as our see right click on it new Java class, and I'm just going to call this for loop
example.
Enter.
All right.
And so now I will create a new line public static void, main as usual, and let's just make a loop
that will count from one to 10.
OK, so the most basic way to do that would be to start off with our for loop for space.
Again, the spaces is optional parentheses.
And now in this case, like the most typical way that you would do this would be to declare a counting
loop variable, a counter variable right here.
So it would typically be an event.
And then you'll name a variable.
I'll name it counter, and then you'd initialize it as well.
Equals zero, let's say, and then a semicolon.
And so that's the first little segment of our for statement or our for loop.
Then we will give it the criteria for how long it should loop until what.
So let's say in this case, while counter is less than 10, so technically now this will count ten times,
but it will start zero up to nine.
The 10 will not be included.
Okay.
This is pretty typical pattern that you'll see where your zero based and then you count up to, but
not including whatever this number would be.
So 10 in this case.
All right.
Colon and then counter plus plus.
And usually you will see that will use the postfix version of the increment or instead of the prefix
here.
All right.
Now, if we want to just print out those numbers, we can do an so you f and then we can say something
like counter is percent the.
Percent in close quote, karma and then simply reference the counter variable just like so.
All right.
So this is one of the most basic forms of loop you could ever use.
OK.
And the most typical format for it as well.
So let's go ahead and run this.
And now that we're back in a program where we're not taking any input from console, we can go back
to just running the regular way.
We don't need to build it first and then run it outside of the ADC.
We can run everything right here.
So I'm going to go ahead and run this.
You can click on those buttons or do the control shift f 10 or whatever.
And there's our output counter is zero blah blah blah.
Up to nine.
Now I did initially say, let's make it count from one to 10, right?
Not zero through nine.
So there are a few ways we could do that.
We could just add one to this counter as we're printing the values right?
We could do that.
Let's run that.
There we go.
So now we've got one through 10 like so or I'll undo that, or we could just start it from one and then
we could tell it to count as long as it's less than 11, that would achieve the same thing, right?
There we go.
Same thing.
Or we could say, while it's less than or equal to 10.
Let's run that that also would do the exact same thing.
All right.
But I would say the most common approach that you'll usually see from most professional developers would
be to start with zero and then go up to the number that you're looking for and then you'll do something
else.
But you know, there's pros and cons to that.
This is a little clunky.
Maybe that's a little clunky having to add one to this variable here.
So it just depends on if you're going to be using that variable in other parts of the program or loop
or whatever.
And what do you need there, right?
All right now, in the previous lesson, I showed that you could initialize the variable outside of
the loop, which then increases the scope of the variable also so that now that variable can be accessed
from outside of the loop, right?
So if we wanted to do something more with it down here, we could do that because the variable lives
beyond the scope of this loop.
Right.
So we could do that now technically.
Each of these clauses, if you will, of the for loop is is optional, so I could get rid of that bit
there.
However, when I do that now, the ADP tells me that, OK, you can do that.
But now Line nine will never be reached.
And the reason Line nine will never be reachable now is because this effectively causes this loop to
simply keep incrementing forever.
Because now the for loop doesn't know when it should stop.
OK.
And if this loop is going to go forever, then this line will never be reached.
The thread will just always be going in a loop, literally here, and it will never reach this line.
So the idea can see that, and it's warning us, Hey, this doesn't look like totally legitimate code
if that's what you want to do.
So in this case, I would delete that.
Now, there's almost never going to be any reason why you would want to do this in most typical Java
programs.
However, there's one case where you might do something a little like this, although in that case you
probably would not use a for loop and that would be in video game programming.
Video games, especially graphical video games, tend to have what is called a graphics loop, where
the program just constantly is looping and repainting the screen multiple times per second.
So if any of you are gamers out there, you and I'm not a gamer, but if any of you are gamers out there,
you'll know that there's something about the frames per second that your game will operate at.
And what one of the things that limits the frames per second is how long it takes to recalculate and
then repaint the screen within one iteration.
While all of that is happening inside of one massive loop, which is called the game loop.
And in that particular loop, you probably don't want to have a limit to the number of iterations.
You probably want that loop to go forever or until someone exits out of the program somehow.
And then this bit here is also optional.
Technically, though, now the loop is even less useful.
So now what's going to happen is it's still going to run forever, but it's just going to print the
number zero forever.
In fact, I suppose we could run this.
I don't like running infinite loops, ever, but let's just see.
Well, Will will cancel out of it.
OK, so we are adding one to it, but it's going to run forever, someone who controls sea to kill it.
All right.
Now I have to scroll down to get to the Oh, it's still running.
So it's it's taken over the computer so much that I can't even easily control see out of it.
So what I can do is click this little stop button here to stop it.
So I would advise be careful if you if you decide to run code that looks like this.
Make sure you have access to a way to stop it.
All right.
And I think that's going to wrap up this little lecture.
Like I said, I just wanted to make sure you got a chance to see a little more focus on what the for
loop really looks like without all the noise of the guessing game code that we had all around it.
So in the guessing game code that the main body of that loop would have been a bunch of lines of code
kind of, you know, like here.
Right?
But this is the main structure of the for loop.
I mean, except for removed, you know, these clauses here, but you get it all right.
So with that, I will in this lesson and I'll see you in the next one.
And there's one more for loop pattern that I want to introduce you to before we close out this topic.
So for this one, I want to show you a scenario here.
It has to do with arrays.
So let's say that we have a string array called fruits, and we will initialize it with a few different
fruits.
Apple, orange, pear, plum.
That's another.
All right, now, let's say that we want to loop over these fruits and just print them out, right?
So can you think of ways that we can do this?
I mean, one thing we could do is we could use a for loop and we could declare a counter, set it to
zero, initialize it to zero.
And then we could say something like keep counting as long as the counter is less than now.
What number do we want to put here?
Well, we could actually just set it to count up to the number of items that are in the fruit array,
and this is a very common pattern.
So what we can do is to reference fruits length.
OK.
And then counter plus plus.
So that's a very, very common pattern when especially if you're looping over items in an array, you'll
just refer to the length of the array.
And now here we could do something like current fruit is.
Fruits counter, right?
Let's run that and see it.
All right, so there we go.
Apple, orange, pear, plum.
Right.
So that's fairly straightforward, kind of a nice use of the the for loop.
However, there is as of Java five, I believe it was something called the enhanced for loop.
And basically, it just cuts down on the amount of typing that we need to do to implement this exact
pattern.
And so let me show you what that looks like.
It's quite nice, I would say.
So we don't need any of this.
We can get rid of all of that.
And instead, we can simply say that we're going to have a variable of type string and we can call it
fruit, and then we use a colon and then a space.
The space is optional and then we reference our array.
So the variable for the array is fruit.
So if I just type in fruits just like that.
Now you can have a space to the left of the colon as well.
It doesn't really matter.
And now down here, instead of directly referencing the array, what's going to happen is that this
enhanced for loop is going to iterate through iterate means to step through each item in the array.
In this case, it's going to step through and it's going to take whatever the current value in that
iteration is.
Whatever the current string is in the as it's iterating over all of these strings in this array and
it's going to assign them one at a time to this variable fruit.
And so that means down here, we don't need to reference the individual values out of the array anymore.
We can simply refer to this local variable fruit.
So let's run this.
So look at that.
There's you don't see any difference in the output.
It behaves the same, right?
The output is.
But look at this much nicer, isn't it?
Is it just easier to look at?
So as long as you don't need an index or a counter, if you just want to loop over the items that are
in an array, you can use this enhanced for loop to do this.
Now this is I'm considering this to be a little bit of a sneak preview because in a later module, we
will learn about collections which are kind of like arrays on steroids, and we can use the enhanced
loop to reference the items that are in a collection as well.
OK.
But since we were already on the for loop and you've already learned about arrays might as well go ahead
and introduce you now to this specific use of the enhanced for loop.
So that's it.