All right, so in the last lesson, we implemented the first Test for implementing the find by ID method,
and we got that working in this lesson.
One of the things I want to do now is to test a negative situation in which we provide an ID of a person
that we know doesn't exist in the database and see how that should be handled.
OK, so let's create a new test.
Public void.
And let's see, test person I.D. not found.
OK, so let's set this up a little bit.
Let's say that we're going to call repo find by I.D. and we need to pass in an I.D. that we know won't
actually be found in the database.
And the easiest way I can think to do this is to use maybe like a negative number.
So negative one.
For example, I know that the H2 database isn't generating negative IDs.
And so I think this should work pretty well for our purposes.
OK.
And then I'm going to go ahead and capture the result of this found person.
Now what do I want to assert here?
I actually think this might be a great opportunity for us to return an optional person, actually.
Right?
Because it shouldn't find a person.
Right.
But we have to return something and we've learned about options, and we know that they are, generally
speaking, much better and more desirable than returning null.
And they might actually be better than throwing an exception.
Traditionally, a lot of applications back in the day that would implement a functionality like this
might have just chosen to throw some kind of an exception saying something like, you know, person
not found or invalid ID something along those lines, right?
But when you have to do all this exception, handling that code is considered kind of nasty.
And really, a lot of developers would prefer not to have to do all of this nasty trade catch stuff
all over the place.
And so here's an opportunity for us to avoid nulls and try catch stuff, I think, and simply return
it optional.
So if this were to return an optional, then that would look like.
This.
Optional of person, and I will import that.
And then down here, we could assert something.
Now do I want to go ahead and implement the assertion or do I want to address these squiggly red lines?
I think probably we want to address the red squiggly lines here to address these red squiggly lines.
Do you know why you're getting this?
Do you want to take a quick guess before I before I hover over it?
So the the issue here should be the fact that the signature for the Find My ID method currently is defined
to simply return a person and not an optional person.
So to fix this, we would need to modify the signature of the find by ID method in the repository class
to not return a person but return an optional person.
That in turn, though, is going to have ripple effects on what we're doing up here, right?
So it's forcing us to refactor our code a bit.
Let's go for it, though.
All right.
So let's jump in here to the find by ID method now.
And so I'm going to declare that this method will return and oops.
And optional loops optional person.
All right, and then I need to import the optional class there.
All right.
And so then down here, we're returning this person now.
The easiest thing I can think of doing to make this happy is probably just to say optional or optional
dot of knowable.
Person, why did I use of Nullarbor?
Well, because we're different, we're declaring this person up here in line 39 to be null.
And if we didn't get any results in this, in this result set here, then none of this code is going
to execute.
And so then when we return the person, that person is still going to be null.
Right?
And so if you know that that object is null and you do an optional dot of that will blow up with an
exception.
But if you do an of Nullarbor, then the optional will allow you to pass in a null person as well as
a non null person.
OK.
So we need the oven culpable here to avoid any potential exceptions being thrown.
All right.
So then jump back over here to the test.
So now we've got to deal with this, and now it's a little bit of whack a mole, right?
So we go fix one thing and then that breaks another.
Now go fix that break another.
OK, now this line is not happy because it returns a an optional person, but here we're just catching
a regular person.
So I've got a few options here that options no pun intended.
I could put a cursor here and then be lazy and just call it get.
And then that makes everything happy right away.
And because this is test code, I'm OK to do this actually right, because I control the circumstances
of this test entirely, right?
So I know that every single time this test runs, there should be a legitimate person here.
And therefore this optional that's coming out of the fine by ID should never be empty, and therefore
the message should always work.
And if any of these assumptions don't work, I want this test to fail, right?
So I'm very OK in this case, just calling okay and not being any fancier than that.
So again, keep in mind the difference of how you would think about handling test code versus how you
might think about handling real implementation code in your system under test, which in this case would
be the repository class.
All right.
So then down here, we'd be getting this object here.
And so then I think I can just make a really simple assertion like assert that the found person is empty.
Now, notice here how I did that I didn't call.
Sound person Dot is empty inside of these parentheses here, right, I didn't do it that way.
I referenced the optional class here, found person and then outside of the parentheses, I let a certain
DJ give me and is empty method.
Now, why did I do that?
Well, by using a certain JS is empty method, I allow a certain DJ to be aware of what my intent is
here.
And that way, a search way, along with DJ unit, can report back when my assumption isn't true, and
it can give me more detailed information about how my assertion isn't true.
OK, so a search is now aware that I am dealing with an optional that I expect to be empty.
OK.
All right.
So let's run that.
And there we go.
That works.
And I apologize to you.
One thing I actually forgot to do in the last lesson was once we got one of those tests working to go
back and just run everything.
And really, you could always just run everything, even as you're implementing one test at a at a time.
I really just was being lazy and didn't want to scroll all the way back up here again.
So let's run all the tests.
Very good.
So you do want to make sure that you're constantly rerunning all of your tests so that you can ensure
that you haven't introduced what's called a regression?
A regression is literally going backward, right?
So you had functionality that had been working.
But then when you implemented some new thing, you unintentionally broke some old functionality that
had been working, so you regressed.
So you want to rerun all of the tests frequently so that you can catch any potential regressions.
OK.
And that is called regression testing.
All right.
So it looks like we're all good here.
OK, so now that we've got this test working, let's jump back over into the find by ID method here.
And one little cleanup thing that I would like to do is to extract this SQL query here out into a constant.
So I will just select the entire thing there and then do an option command C for constant or control,
alt C for Windows and Linux.
And I'm going to name this.
Let's see.
Well, I guess I'm going to name it something like find out about just fine by Edee sequel.
It would go all right.
And so now that sequel is right up here next to the previously created constant right there.
OK.
One other thing that you may want to consider as well, though I don't think I'm going to bother with
it.
Here is these constants here for the column names and stuff.
There may be some really, really strict teams who are still using GDC to do database coding, and they
may have decided not to allow these kinds of string literals to be peppered throughout throughout the
code, and instead, they may prefer to extract those out into constants.
I, I don't know.
I'm not real crazy about doing that to that extent.
I do know of frameworks that could be utilized where the frameworks would generate a lot of constants
for you, like the framework will go out and scan the database and become aware of all the columns and
everything that are out there.
And then it'll generate classes that define these constants for you.
So that way you don't have to create them yourself.
And the idea there is to keep the constants in sync, always with what's actually out in the database.
I don't know.
I kind of maybe, maybe I kind of prefer approaches like that in real world application development.
So I don't know.
I'm just mentioning some things to think about.
But for me, in a case like this, I'd probably just leave these string literals right here as they
are, to be really honest with you.
All right.
And I think that was a pretty easy once we're going to wrap this one up and will implement some more
functionality in the upcoming lessons.
I will see you in the next one.