All right, so in our last lesson, we created a new programmer class to encapsulate most or all of
the functionality that had anything to do with the programmer records that we have here, OK?
And by doing so, we were able to greatly simplify and reduce the lines of code in our programmer case.
So we had code that looked pretty much exactly like this.
And that became these.
What is it?
Three lines of code now?
So I would say that was a nice little bit of simplification now.
Of course, mostly all we did was move code around, right?
We shuffled it around a lot of the code that was, you know, looking like this underneath this case
statement has now been moved into the programmer class.
The declarations for the rejects and everything are now fields in this class.
And the code that actually does a lot of the parsing is now inside of the constructor.
So we're passing in one string now and that string that we're passing in would be one line like these.
So let me just be clear that we haven't probably reduced the total lines of code.
We've just moved them around to make the overall application maybe more manageable in individual sections.
All right.
So having done that now, we're going to just do the same thing again for manager, analyst and CEO.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So first I will open up the project pane and let's see.
So we've already got a manager class created, but there's probably not much in it.
So let's let's take a look in here.
Now, one thought that comes to my mind is what might happen if we considered copying and pasting a
lot of code from the programmer class?
So in the programmer class, let's see here we've got we've got our fields.
Obviously, these three fields will be different, but these first three will all be the same.
So that would probably be good.
And then we could copy over our projects and our patterns and things, while maybe not from here, but
from the main class.
So yeah, let's let's start by copying these three fields.
First name, last name and date of birth.
Those are all going to be the same.
So I'm popping over here to the manager class shift into Paste Command V. or Control V to paste.
All right.
So there are those.
Fields.
Let's see what else.
OK, we're going to want the rig.
So let's jump over to the main class.
Let me make a little more room this way.
Jump over to the main class.
Let's see.
So here's the manager stuff.
So let's grab these two bits and jump back over to manager and paste those and let's make them private.
And final guess I could have done that on both lines simultaneously private and final.
And yeah, that's looking OK so far.
And let's jump back over to the programmer class.
What else?
Let's go ahead and create the manager constructor.
But I'm kind of wondering if we can start by just copying the body of the programmer constructor and
then we'll just kind of change things.
So let's see what that will look like.
Jump over here to the manager constructor shift enter to make a couple of new lines command in Generate
a constructor.
This won't use well.
We won't use any of these fields, though, so I select none.
Then in here, I will say we're going to pass in a string.
What did we call it?
In the programmer we called person text, OK.
We'll do the same here, person text shift.
Enter, then I'm going to paste.
All right.
So now let's just change a few things.
So.
All right, so here we're referring to a people pattern.
Let me see what we had in the program here.
People pattern, people pattern.
Did I not copy that?
No, I didn't.
OK, so we need to copy the people pattern, as is.
So I'm just selecting that command.
See, jump over to manager class and I'm going to paste that in.
OK, and then I'm going to need the people rig x jumping over to the programmer.
OK, I see.
So I should have just grabbed both of these lines.
That's fine.
Copy that!
Jump over to manager.
I'll pace that right above it.
There we go.
All right.
So that's happy now.
And that's allowing us to pass the last name and first name.
Then we need this format or the date, time matter.
So jump over to programmer and grab that guy command c jump over to the manager.
Paste that, and I see that I actually forgot to make that private and final.
In the programmer class.
So let me let me do that real quick.
Yeah, let's make that private and final.
OK, well, let's see back over to manager what else programmer pattern will become manager pattern,
right?
So I'm going to copy manager pattern here and then come here and just replace that name a mantra.
And then this should become manager, matcher, MDR manager matcher.
Then I'll copy that name and replace it everywhere.
I see it here now.
I guess I could have done a refactoring, but since things were kind of broken, I don't know.
I'm just doing it kind of overly manually.
Probably shouldn't.
But I've already started down this road.
So change it there and there, and they're all right.
Now these these fields, though, are all going to be different fields for the managers.
So let's jump back over here to Maine and see what what fields we are actually caring about for a manager
we've got.
Org Size and direct reports d.r.
OK, so jumping back over to manager here, in fact, I'll just copy that.
Org size jumping back over to manager.
So we're going to want private and org size equals zero, private and direct reports equals zero.
And then down here I will refer to those fields.
Org size.
And then I'll change this to organize, and then I will change this one to direct reports, and this
one will be called D.R, because that's what it's actually called here in the named Capshaw Group.
And then there were only two details that we're capturing from the manager.
So this third one here, I will just delete with the command delete looking pretty good.
All right.
Jumping back over to manager, what else do we need then, because I think that finished off the constructor.
So then we're going to need a get salary and a two strings.
So let me start off by just copying both of these and then I'll jump over here to the manager class
and paste those to there.
And I mean, let's go back to the main class and confirm the what math were we doing here?
I think we're just doing 3500 plus or size times, direct reports.
OK.
So we'll jump back over here to manager.
So here it'll be 30 500 plus org size times, direct reports and no IQ like so.
And then the two string.
OK, we need a money formatter, so let's jump over to the programmer and copy the money format business,
which is right here.
Command C..
Jump back over to the manager.
Go to the top.
And I'll make a new line and paste that right there.
And no errors there.
OK, so maybe maybe I got everything.
Now we'll jump back over to Main.
And I think I am going to comment everything first inside of the manager case that is and now at the
bottom, I'm going to follow this same pattern here.
So
manager manager equals new manager.
People match your group.
So just another reminder, People Match Report Group refers to one whole line here.
So if you just use the Match Report Group method without passing any inputs into it, it refers to the
entire to one entire line.
OK.
People Match Report Group, then I'm passing that string, this is this returns a string into the programmer
constructor or I'm sorry into the manager constructor, which is the same same basic deal.
OK.
All right, then system that out, that print line manager to string and then yield manager Typekit
get salary and semicolon.
All right, let's confirm that we still get whatever the number was 8.6 million or so.
So let's just run this whole thing now that we've kind of refactored it.
Yeah, still getting eight point six million, so I don't think we've broken anything, and let's see
some of the manager names were Barney.
So the rebels are all the managers and there are the rebels there.
Yeah.
So I think we're looking pretty good there, and now I think we can get rid of all of these commented
lines, oops!
Went too far.
I'm just going to delete these lines, command, delete or control.
Why for Windows and Linux?
All right.
So now the programmer, case and manager case are much shorter, and now I will do the same again for
analysts.
And this time, maybe I'm going to just start off by copying everything in the manager class and then
just changing.
What I need to see if I copy all of the guts of this and go into analyst and paste, then change this
constructor name to analyst the constructor name always has to match the name of the class.
Always.
All right.
Then go grab the correct rejects and pattern.
While the correct rejects really for the analyst, which I have in the main class.
So analyst?
Right there, grab all of that, jump into the analyst class.
Replace these two bits.
And make them both private and final.
I'm using my two cursor trick here.
Private final so that I can do them both at once.
Escape to get out of the double cursor business.
All right.
So there's all of that.
Now down here, I can refer to the I need a pattern.
And so I'm going to use the analyst pattern, some copying that and then I'm going to replace this manager
pattern with my analyst pattern instead.
And this time, I'll be a little smarter, and I will create this matter by simply using a rename refactoring.
So I will do a shift six and call this.
And a list and then hit return, and now the fields that I want out of here are just one, and it's
called project count.
OK, so I will change this first one to project count and I will delete this last line and I need to
store that in a field called Project Count.
So I actually can just rename this as well.
So I'll do a shift F6 and call it project count.
Then I will delete this unused field here.
Command, delete.
All right.
I think that's looking pretty good.
And then let's see now what was the math that we did for the analyst to jump over here to the main class
and for analysts, what did we do?
We did 2500 plus project count times to here.
Let's just grab that copy, jump over to analyst, select all of that and paste.
There we go.
And two string is already looking good.
So that was even quicker.
Now, jump back over to the main.
And now let's comment out all of the analyst case as it currently exists.
Command forward slash, then pop in.
Create a new instance of our new analyst analyst analyst equals new analyst.
Passing people matcher diet group.
Then you analyst Dot to string shift into yield analyst Dot, get salary, semi-colon.
Let's rerun it and make sure we still get eight point six million or so.
There it is looking like it's still the same.
And our analysts people are The Flintstones and they're, well, the other Flintstones, Wilma, all
the Wilma Flintstones.
Looking pretty good.
All right.
And one last one to do, which is the CEO.
So same same deal.
We'll start off by just yet.
I already have all of the guts of the manager class selected, so I'm just going to do a Command C again
to copy all of that.
Jump into the CEO class shift.
Enter to make a new line inside Command V to paste.
Change the constructor name to CEO and let's see, then jump back over to Main.
Find the CEO rejects and pattern, which are here.
Copy these command, see jump back over to CEO class.
Replace the manager, rejects and pattern with the CEO, rejects and pattern, jump to the beginning
of these do an option shift.
Click here and here to get to cursors type private final so that I can do them both at the same time.
Escape to finish that, then look for my patterns.
So this should be a CEO pattern, which is right here.
Select that with a double click Command C to copy double.
Click this one here Command V to paste, then select this manager matcher and rename it to CEO matcher
some selecting it or clicking on it, then shift DEF Six.
Then I will just replace the Imgur with CEO.
Enter!
All right.
And let's see here.
The named capture group that I care about is average stock price.
I'm going to just double click that to select that whole word command C to copy.
Then I will jump down here to this section for the CEO Match Report Find and I will replace org size.
I'll double click that command v paste.
Average stock price looks like we only are using one detail field, so I will delete this second line
here and then I will rename this variable to average stock price.
So I will do a shift of six with the cursor on it and then I can just paste since I already have it
in memory and then enter.
Now I will come up here and delete this line 14 for direct reports because that does not apply to the
CEO, but my cursor anywhere on Line 14 then do a command delete to get rid of that.
All right.
What else?
OK, and then the math.
Let's see how we did it.
Main.
So for the CEO, oh oh, I forgot to delete the analyst stuff.
We'll delete that in a moment for the CEO, we did 5000 times average stock price.
OK.
So jump back over to C.I., actually.
So let's just copy that command, see.
Jump back over to CEO, select all of this for the good salary and then do a command V..
There we go.
And I don't see any red marks, so I think we should be good here.
So jump back over to Main.
Let's select all of this and comment.
Commented out.
Shift into to make a new line and then let's create a new instance of a CEO.
CEO CEO equals new CEO people Matt Dot Group.
So you t CEO, get strong?
Well, I'm sorry.
CEOs to string shift into yield CEO don't get salary and let's run it all.
And again, we'll be looking for a number roughly 8.6 million.
Yet still 8.6 million, and there's Betty Rubble with 1.5 million in salary looking good.
All right, so minimize this and now let's get rid of these commented lines
there, and let's get rid of these ones also.
And now let's get a bigger look at what we've got here in this while loop, so that's way shorter and
much more manageable now.
All right.
So now we have finished our first level of refactoring for this program.
And so you can see that again, mostly all we've done is just shuffle code around.
But there's a lot of value in shuffling code around in this way if you're moving it into other classes
by having done so.
Let me close that for a moment.
So by having done the shuffling that oh oh, there's one more thing that we can do now, and we should,
I think, be able to get rid of most of these fields.
Let's let's just see what happens here if we just comment these out.
So I'm going to select all of these projects and patterns and then just comment them.
Let's see if anything breaks.
No, nothing breaks.
So therefore they're not being they weren't being used.
And so I think we can delete them, command, delete, make a little more space there.
So I always feel so good when I can reduce the lines of code in one massive class, right, like we're
doing here, this is some, you know, nice little refactoring that we're doing here.
All right.
And you know, for grins, let's just rerun it and make sure we didn't break anything, but I don't
think we did because we'd be likely seeing errors.
Yep, still getting still getting 8.6 million.
So that is still looking good.
All right.
So take a look at this class now, it's gotten a lot shorter and easier to look at, easier to discern
the big picture of what's going on here, right?
So we've got our list of people, our list of employees.
We've got a regex that knows how to pass them line by line.
Then we've got our loop, which is looping over each line.
And for each line, we're using a switch to instantiate whichever class we need based on the roll,
right?
So in other words, if the role is analyst, then this switch is is getting the word analyst and then
it's saying, OK, match the case for analyst, which would be here.
Then we end up creating a new analyst.
And then in the constructor of that analyst, we're passing in the text representation of that analyst,
which would be one of these lines like so that's getting passed into the constructor.
Then we jump into the constructor with that string.
Then we let our matcher analyze that string essentially.
Then we create a matter which is capable of analyzing that person's string, which goes right here.
And that matter is capable of extracting the last name, first name and date of birth, which is a string
when it comes out of here.
So then we use this date time format or to convert the string representation of a date date of birth
into an actual date object, a local date so that we have more semantics behind that information.
Then we create another matter that is specific to an analyst.
So this matters job is to extract the information in between the curly braces here for an analyst,
and the same is true for any other type, right?
All right.
And then back over here in the analyst class, now that we've got a matter for the analyst details,
we tell that match or to go find any of those details and as long as it does, which is what this f
block is for as long as it can find any of those details that are specific to an analyst, it can extract
them.
And in this case, there would only be one, which is the project count.
We converted into an integer and then stored in a field right there.
Then we can do math on it to get the salary, according to our arbitrary rules for how to how to determine
the salary for a role.
I want you to note now this formula that I've put here, this is completely arbitrarily made up and
we could have made this as simple or as complex as we wanted it to be.
My point with the get salary was simply to give us an excuse to have different methods of determining
the salary based on an employee's role.
OK.
So for each employee of a certain role, there would be a different way to calculate their salary.
And I will remind you, if we were calculating salary in the in an identical fashion for all roles,
we would not even probably need to bother creating all these classes and stuff.
OK, we could have just done that just with the Switch statement, as we did in the very, very first
implementation of the main class.
OK, but then we wouldn't have a justification or a reason to get into all of this object oriented stuff
that we're slowly traveling down.
And then we implemented a two string method, which is identical in all of the classes.
All right, so that's a little recap on what we did so far.
So in the subsequent lessons, we will continue traveling down this road and we will see what else we
can do with Java and its object orientation techniques to hopefully simplify the code even further or
make it more flexible or a combination of the two.
So I'll see you in the next one.