All right, so before we get on with learning some of the other implementations of the set interface.
Let's do a little bit of quick housekeeping.
Let's jump over.
Let me minimize this.
Let's jump back in to the employee class and let's uncomment the hash code method so we can get get
things working more correctly again.
So I'm coming down here to this comment about hash code method.
Make sure you select the annotation as well.
So on my idiot's line 71 through 74, but it may be different for you a little bit.
All right.
And then I'll do a command forward slash to uncomment or control forward slash for Windows and Linux.
And then we can go back over to the main class, and let's just make sure that that took effect.
So I'm going to just rerun the program again.
And yeah, okay, we're down to 17 items instead of twenty two, so I think that's looking good.
All right.
So now that we've done that little bit of housekeeping, let me present you with another scenario.
So we're using a set because we want to ensure that there are no duplicate objects.
And obviously the definition of duplicate for employees is two or more employees with the same first
name, last name and date of birth.
OK.
For our purposes, if we wanted to change that definition, we certainly could do so.
We could add in roll or something else like that, and we'd have to go into the employee class.
In fact, I'll just jump over there real quick to show you this is just a very quick review.
So if we wanted the definition of duplicate to include first name, last name, date of birth and roll,
for example, then what we could do is go over to the employee class, go down to the equals and hash
code methods which are here.
And perhaps we would have to add in something like class itself or a string representation of the class,
because in our current implementation here, the role is not a an explicit field, it is the actual
subclass of employee, right?
If you are a programmer, there is no there is no field called roll that then encodes the string of
programmer.
Instead, the entire class itself or in our case, really the subclass would be programmers.
So maybe we'd be looking to do something along these lines.
Maybe we do something like simply add in a call to get class.
OK, now note if we add this here in hash code, we need to do something equivalent in the equals method,
though, right?
Because we want the the the approach to determining uniqueness or whatever to be consistent between
both the equals method and the hash code method.
OK?
So if I if I'm adding in that uniqueness of an employee includes the class type here, then I must also
add that up here and let's see how much they do that.
So in this case, maybe I would do something like real quick first.
Let me let me clean this up a little bit so I can make it a little easier just to show you what I'm
talking about.
So maybe I would add another and here and then I would need to say something like get class.
Equals, oh, dot, get class.
OK, so there's an example of how you might do that in that particular case, and that's a little bit
of an oddball one because normally you'd be using explicit fields of the class itself rather than the
whole entire class.
But this hopefully gives you some ideas.
All right.
So let me undo that.
And I will jump back over to the main class now.
So we've we've learned that with the hash set, it is very good at filtering out duplicates as long
as we have done an adequate job of implementing our equals and hash code methods.
However, we also have learned that the hash set implementation of the set interface does not honor
the insertion order or any type of ordering that we would be able to intuitively understand.
And the reason for that is because it uses a hash code which then derives an index, and it is by that
index that the items in the hash that are effectively ordered.
So what if we did want the items in our set to be in the same order in which we inserted them so-called
insertion order, which is what the list interface gives us, right?
Well, there's actually a way to do that and to do so.
All we need to do is change the implementation of our set from a hash set to a linked hash set.
So that's actually as easy as simply coming up here.
And changing this to Linked has said like, so I got a little extra there, someone to delete the extra
bits there.
All right, there we go.
Linked hash set.
And so now let's take note real quick of the current order with the hash set, and then we'll rerun
this with the linked hash and see what the difference will be.
So with the hash set, we've got The Flintstones and then some rubbles and then some more Flintstones
and then the Nay and then some more Flintstones.
Right?
That's that's the order we happen to be getting at this time.
So now let's run it with the linked hash said and see what we get.
All right.
So we're getting Fred Flintstone in A..
And then two, three, four and five and then Barney Rubble two, three, four and five, Wilma and
Betty.
And then if we I'm going to make this come down just a little bit.
And then over here in the top, I'll come up here, so what we should be seeing now is other than having
filtered out the five duplicates or so, we should be seeing the same order between the top and the
bottom now, right?
So we've got the Fred Flintstone with no no right.
Then the next one after we skip over the duplicates is this one with a roll that doesn't match up with
any of our standard roles.
The programmers, which maps to a not applicable right the in a right here.
So that's correct.
And then let's see.
And then Fred Flintstone, two, three, four and five.
Here we go two, three, four and five.
Barney Rubble two, three, four and five.
So, yeah, so as you can see, it appears to be more or less the same behavior that we got with the
list interface, except with an added little bonus, if you will, that it's also capable of filtering
out the duplicates.
Now let me remind you, I can hear some of you already thinking because you may have forgotten or not
caught some of the points that I made earlier.
Some of you are thinking, Oh, why don't I just use the linked hash that for everything?
And I mean, for in certain cases, perhaps you could if your list isn't very long or if your application
isn't very time sensitive and you don't need to care about access times and things like that, like
in this program, where our list really isn't that long and it's not particularly time sensitive at
all, you very well may choose to prefer using a linked hash set.
However, as I've noted before, the hash that is much quicker for accessing the elements within it
because of how it works.
The linked hash that isn't bad, by the way.
It's really not too bad at all.
But it's not quite as fast as the hash set.
And so that's just something to bear in mind.
But yeah, you do get some some nice benefits here if you need the items to come out of it in order.
Now one other thing I will I will note if we go.
Let me see, let me bring this down a bit.
So here's where we are actually printing them out right in this bit of a loop here.
And we're using and we're using the enhanced for loop or the more modern for loop to do so.
So this works great because the interface that we're using here is a set.
Just note that even though the items are now being saved in this linked hash set in insertion order
and they are coming out in in the insertion order.
When we use an enhanced loop, we are not able to say things like give me the third or give me the seventh
element in this in this collection, as we could do with a list, the list interface has the get method
on it, where you can say get the 3rd or the 5th or the 10th index of the Element.
The set interface does not have those random access type methods in it.
And so that's just one thing to bear in mind.
In other words, you can get a whole set, no pun intended of items out of the linked hash set in order
in the insertion order while you're iterating over them with an iterator or an enhanced loop or whatever.
But you cannot randomly go to specific indexes, as you could with the list, OK?
If you wanted to be able to do that, even though you had been storing everything ultimately in a set,
you could create a new list temporarily and and initialize it with a set.
As I have shown once before, I'll just show you what that looks like real quick again.
So let's say you wanted to be able to get specifically the seventh element out of this out of this set
here.
What you could do if you really must do so is you could create a new array list.
And then simply initialize it with the hash set or with with the set like so and then you could even
just go ahead and say get and then pass in an index, right?
And now you're pulling out the 11th element in the set.
OK.
So that's something you could do.
Keep in mind, though, that's kind of an expensive operation to do just to get one item.
So, you know, you just want to be mindful of that, right?
You're effectively going to make a whole other copy of that employee's collection.
So in our case, where we only have whatever it is, 17, 22, whatever.
Probably not a big deal.
But if that thing had millions and millions of records, that might not be the best way to go about
doing that at all because you'd effectively be duplicating those structures, right?
So just keep that in mind, I'm going to delete this line.
I just wanted to show you and remind you of the fact that you can always create new collections and
initialize them with existing collections.
All right.
OK.
And that's going to wrap up my little discussion here on the linked hash set.
And then in the next lesson, we'll take a quick look at the remaining popular implementation of set,
which is the tree said see in the next one.