All right.
So in this lesson, let's do some more math.
So here in the browser, I have pulled up some random physics website someplace where it's teaching
how to solve some physics problem.
I don't actually care about this problem at all.
I was just looking for something a little more difficult than what we previously did.
And this looks like a halfway decent little problem because it looks like it requires us to solve three
different formulas to get the final answer.
So I want to show how we can do some maybe intermediate level, you know, math in Java or how we could
at least.
OK.
So don't worry, if you don't know physics, it doesn't matter.
We don't care about the physics of this.
We just want to find some formulas to translate into Java code.
That's that's really all we're trying to do here.
All right.
So looks like ultimately what we're wanting to solve in this particular problem is centripetal force,
and they give a formula which is ethical a which is a pretty common formula there.
OK?
And it looks like the way that they plug in the numbers for M and A is partially they are given like
this 0.2 kg is given as the mass of a ball and three point five four was calculated up here using the
formula for centripetal acceleration.
OK, so we're going to have to solve for centripetal acceleration and it looks like in order to solve
for that, we need a velocity with this one point six seven and they got the velocity by calculating
something called pass velocity using this formula here.
So we're going to just implement these formulas and then see if we get the same answers.
All right.
Let's have some fun.
So let's start off by calculating the path velocity.
Now it looks here.
So first thing we want to figure out is what are our inputs for this formula?
And I don't know if they made a mistake here because I think this three here is actually one of the
inputs.
I think it came from the word problem up above where it says that something is happening every three
seconds.
I think that's where they got that three from.
And then I was thinking usually on the left hand side, they're showing the pure formula and then to
the right of the equals, they're plugging in the values.
I think they may have made a mistake here.
So I'm going to assume that this should be a variable that we would pass in.
All right.
So let's let's make a function that solves for the path velocity, first of all.
So we'll make a new function and we'll just use doubles for everything.
Public static double.
All right, so we'll calculate path velocity and our inputs looks like our radius.
I don't think the two is part of it because you'll often see formulas that are related to circles and
things like what we had just done before, where the the formula will be something like two pi are or,
you know, something along those lines, right?
So I'm not going to make that two part of the inputs.
I think that's a given with the formula.
I think our inputs will be the radius.
And I guess this would be a period the three there.
All right.
So that's what I'm going to make it, at least.
So we'll have a double of a radius again and we'll do a double for the period as well, even though
here it is conveyed as a as an integer.
But that's all right.
Period.
All right.
And so the formula here is two pi times the radius.
So that's really similar to what we did up here for the area of a circle, except that we raised it
to the second power and and the pie isn't multiplied times two.
And then all of that divided by three.
OK, so when you want to implement formulas like this, it's really good and useful to break them down
in some way.
OK?
If you know what these terms actually are in terms of the real world, you can make variables that are
named after whatever those actually may be if you know what they are.
OK, so to Pi R, I think is the formula for the circumference of a circle.
I'm a little rusty.
Let's see here.
Circumference, loop circumference of a circle.
Form you.
To PR, yes, it is.
OK, so that's the circumference of a circle, so we could make a variable inside of our function to
first hold on to this value and call that variable circumference.
And then it would be easier to do this division afterwards.
So you see what I'm trying to do, I'm trying to figure out places to break this down.
Let me go ahead and do it, and you'll see a little more of what I mean here.
So we could create what's called a local variable.
That's a variable that only exists within the function itself and not outside of it.
Not like a field of the class.
OK.
So we'll make a variable that is a double.
We'll call it Sir Conference.
And will say that it is equal to two.
Times math, not pi times radius, OK?
That's what we have here are two times PI times radius.
All right.
So there's our circumference and then the path velocity is that circumference divided by what I assume
is a period.
Forgive me any math experts if I'm referring to these terms incorrectly.
All right.
So we will return circumference, which is the two pi times point zero eight here divided by.
The period.
OK.
Just like that, and now we can test this out.
So we'll do this out, we'll call calculate path velocity, and we will pass in a radius of zero point
eight and a period of three.
And let's run that and see what we get.
Hopefully, we get the one point sixty seven.
Hey, we do.
One point six, seven and a lot more.
OK, so I think we're we're on the right track here.
All right.
Now, the next thing we need to calculate is the centripetal acceleration using this formula.
So it looks like for this one, we take the path velocity squared divided by the radius.
OK, so let's make let's make that method now.
So another method public static double calculate spin trip.
It'll acceleration, and I'm just going to abbreviate that part.
Let's see, and our input or inputs for this will be the path velocity, which will be a double path
vehicle.
I will call it karma and our radius, which will also be a double radius.
All right.
And I don't think I need to break this one down.
This one looks a little simpler to me.
So let's try this now I could if I wanted to, but I don't think it's necessary, so I will simply return
the.
So we need to we need to have the square of the path velocity.
So to do that, we can use the masked power method and then pass in the path the ill to the second power.
Or we could have also just done Path Ville Times Path Bill.
Right?
Either one.
OK, so all of that divided by the radius.
So I just felt like this one is simple enough that we don't need an intermediate variable, but we certainly
could have created one if we wanted to, and I could even extract one out even now.
In fact, I'll just show that just for grins, right?
So I can always select this whole thing here and then do a command option v right?
And then all this, I guess velocity.
Right now, I'm not going to go through with this, but I was just showing you that I could have done
that if I wanted to.
OK, so now let's test that out.
So if we come up here?
I'll make a new line.
System that out, that print line count, calculate centripetal acceleration will pass in the one point
sixty seven and then the radius of zero point eight.
Sorry, I know you can't see that, but there's the point eight there.
All right, and so let's run this and see what we get.
Three point four eight six one two five.
Here they got three point five oh four.
Yeah, I guess close enough.
And so finally, we need to calculate the centripetal force.
And that is done with F equals may or one of the variations of that equals a super common formula.
And so now we will take a given, which is the mass of the ball point two kilograms times the centripetal
acceleration.
So this will be a very easy one.
OK.
So public static double calculate, thin tread bid or force, taking a double of the mass.
And a double of the.
Centripetal acceleration, which I'm just going to call ask because I don't feel like typing more and
then we will return mass times.
So that's a really easy one.
C So that's so easy.
I almost don't feel like we need to test it, but we will.
Calculate centripetal force with a mass of point two.
Comma and then the input of the centripetal acceleration.
So we'll give it the given here 3.5 oh four, and then let's run that, OK?
Yeah, and we got point seven zero zero eight and then a bunch of zeros there.
Now we could make this final method really smart.
Let me I'm going to move this out of the way and get back to a more reasonable size here for the HD.
OK, now there's a few things we could do if we wanted to to make this a little more powerful here,
since this is the main thing that we're really wanting anyway.
We could choose to combine these methods to make one powerful method that calculates the centripetal
force and takes a few more inputs, like takes all of the inputs that we need.
Yeah, let's let's do that.
Let's make what we can do is we can overload this centripetal force method and make another version
of it that takes more inputs.
So to do that, we'll just make another double.
We can use the same name centripetal force and we can start off with the mass.
But now what we'll do is we'll just reference all of the unique inputs of the other methods.
OK, so we can just pass in whichever inputs are unique and aren't already calculated from something
else, right?
So we need the mass.
We don't need this path velocity because that's calculated up here.
So this guy's inputs are the radius and the period.
See, is there anything else?
So I think what we need is mass radius and period.
So mass and then a double of the radius and then a double of the period.
I think that's all we need.
All right.
And then what we can do now is to call each of these methods and turn and just get everything we needed
all in one right, so we can create a local variable of type double, which will be the path velocity
and then we can call that method and pass in our radius and our period.
And then we can create a another variable local variable for these centripetal acceleration, centripetal
acceleration, and we will call that method.
And pass in our path velocity.
And radius.
And then we can finally put it all together and just return to the middle.
Now we could capture this last bit and then return what we capture.
In fact, they'll show you that.
So we could calculate the centripetal force explicitly like so and call the count centripetal force
method.
Now notice I'm in a method called calc centripetal force, but I'm calling a method called calc centripetal
force because I'm overloading this method, right?
So the idea in Java are smart enough to understand what I mean here based on what inputs I passed,
though, as long as the inputs are different, you can have the same method in terms of the naming of
it.
All right.
So calc centripetal force it once a mass, so we'll pass in the mass and then at once, the acceleration.
So centripetal acceleration.
And then we can just return the centripetal force.
Like so now this is a pretty nice method that does everything, in fact.
Hold on.
Let me just bring it back.
That does everything that all of these separate steps we're doing.
It puts it all together in one.
So that's quite nice, actually.
So what I will often do if I were breaking something down the way that I broke it down here, but then
I was putting it all back together in one nice, easy method or something.
There's a good chance that I might choose to make these other methods private now and hold on.
Now just depends on how I think this class would be used in the future.
But if I consider these methods to be intermediate methods that I only broke out just to make it easier
for my brain to handle, you know what's going on in small little bite sized pieces?
And then to kind of put it all together in this last one?
And I'm thinking I or other people who may call this class don't need to directly be calling these little
guys.
And really all that's needed or all I want to expose is just this main guy here, then yeah, I can
make these other methods private so that other callers of this class can't call these smaller bits right.
They can only call this main guy here who puts it all together.
And so that's a nice example of why you will sometimes want things.
Some methods to be private versus public or something like that.
But it all just depends on how you, the creator or author of the class, intend for that class to be
used.
OK, so now let's try out our big boy here.
So.
We will call centripetal force this version of it that takes three inputs a massive point two kilograms.
Notice also we leave off the units, right, because that won't have any meaning here.
We don't need it.
You wouldn't use that either way if you were using a calculator or something, a massive point, two
kilograms and then a radius of zero point eight.
And our last parameter i just hit command p to show all of the parameters.
Here will be the period of three.
OK?
By the way, I keep meaning to mention this throughout this course, and I don't know that I have ever
mentioned it.
You may all have wondered or noticed that we see the names of these of these arguments.
Here are these parameters, arguments and parameters.
They're kind of interchangeable, depending on whether you're from the perspective of whether you're
calling them or when you're defining the the method, you'll hear developers use the terms interchangeably.
OK.
So anyway, this is showing these these parameter names here is not a standard of Java at all.
Some languages actually do have what are called named parameters, and it's quite nice and helpful so
that you can know what are these values.
In this case, though, what's happening is that the IED is showing us the parameter names so that we
can have a clue of what these numbers are for.
Java actually doesn't do that.
Many newer languages do, though.
So anyway, I just wanted to point out that you'll likely be seeing these and these are not a standard
part of Java.
So if you were to write Java code in some other IED, maybe another IED wouldn't show you these parameter
names by default.
OK.
So anyway, let's comment about everything else now.
And one way that you can comment out, by the way, is you can select all the lines that you want to
comment and then hit command forward slash and that comments out each individual line in one fell swoop.
All right.
And then let's go ahead and run this and see if we did this correctly and we get zero point seven zero
one eight and that is close enough to what we got in the browser.
Close enough for me, at least over here, we got zero point seven zero zero eight point seven zero
one eight.
Now that difference between what we're getting here and what we're getting, what was calculated in
that website now, I don't know how the website did its calculations.
However, I will warn you that the Java data types that we are currently using of well, in this case,
double does have some issues which we will explore coming up really soon here.
And so you will want to be careful of that.
And this discrepancy that we're seeing may in fact be due to some of those issues that we will talk
about in an upcoming lesson.
So I just want to give you a little bit of warning here, but I don't know.
I mean, is this close enough for your physics physics class?
I guess it depends on your physics teacher or professor and how many significant digits they care about.
For me in this lesson right now, this is good enough.
We will I will show you, though, how you could have rock solid numbers.
And that's all assuming, by the way, that this answer here on the website is the rock solid answer.
I'm going to assume that it is OK.
So we will address how to make sure that your answers are as accurate as they possibly can be really
soon.
But this, you know, we have shown, though, my purpose here was more so to kind of show you how to
really use some of the math functions and how to translate math problems and formulas into Java code
that you can actually execute and make it maintainable and readable with nice, small, easy to understand
methods.
Now I could have written one, just one method that did all of this, by the way, I absolutely could
have done that, and that method might not have been like horrible either, because really, each of
these is pretty simple.
But I wanted to break this out a little bit so that it would be a little more readable and understandable
to you.
So that's going to wrap it up for this lesson, and I'll catch you in the next one.