OK, now let's learn about index of this is an extremely commonly used method, probably overused by
most Java developers, in fact, and later in the course, you'll learn why, although I'll probably
try to remember mention a little bit more about this towards the end of this lesson.
So the index of method is super useful, though it can tell us where inside of a string.
According to its index, a substring exists.
Now let me show you what I mean by that.
So again, I've cleared out what we had before, and I'm going to create a string here.
My text equals and let's see four score and seven years ago.
OK, so we've got some text here doing so.
You T and we'll reference that string and now we'll use the index of method.
OK.
So one way that I might use this is if I wanted to know two things.
If I want to know is the word seven in this string and where in this string does it begin?
OK, so we learned another way that we could determine whether or not the word seven or any other sub
string here is contained within this string.
We could use the contains method, right?
But if we want to know where in this string is the word seven, we could use the index of.
So it tells us the index, which is the place in the string, which character, right?
Starting from zero.
Where in this string is the word seven?
If we if I do something like that.
OK.
And so let's run this and see what we get.
So it returns the number 15.
So if we count, starting with zero zero one to three, including spaces for five six seven eight nine
10, 11 12, 13 14 15.
So the fifteenth index here is where the word seven begins.
So it's telling us where we could find that.
OK, now there are several variations of the index of method, and we'll take a look at at least some
of them.
So I'm going to change this string to something a little more a little simpler.
A B C D e f g.
OK, so there's another version of the index of method that does not take a string, but instead takes
a number an integer, actually.
And the reason it takes an integer is because, oops, I deleted too many parentheses there.
OK.
The reason this version of index of takes an integer is because this integer represents the code for
a character.
If you'll recall, I stated that all characters in Java have a numerical code associated with them,
and that is really the way that these characters in letters and things are being stored in the memory
of the computer.
As as numbers, as you may know, like everything in a computer is really comes down to numbers, right?
And so what we can do is we can ask the index of method to find the character whose encoding is this
number or any other number and then give us the index of that.
OK, now I happen to know that 65 is the character encoding the standard encoding for a capital A..
OK.
So if we run this, it should give us the index of this first A..
So let's let's run it and see what we get.
Yeah, we get zero, which means the first one there.
OK, now if I delete that first, eh, I've got another a here and it should find that one.
So let's see.
Yeah.
So let's see zero one, two, three, four, five six, that's correct.
Right.
All right.
So if I put the first aid back in.
So something to note here is the fact that the index of method stops once it finds a first match.
Now you might be wondering why would you ever want to use this particular version of the index of method
that's taking a number?
And one reason for that is because there are some characters that are not easy to type in here that
you might want to search for, especially like white space characters and things of that sort.
So, for example, a new line character or carriage return.
There are a lot of special characters that don't represent easily visually here, but you may still
want to search for them.
So if you look up their values, the values of some of those characters, you could search for them
by their numerical value.
By the way, I did mention the most common character encoding, which is used in Java by default, is
called Unicode.
You may have heard of ASCII AC III, so that's a different encoding system from Unicode.
One of the main differences is that ASCII really only supports Latin characters, whereas Unicode and
there are several sub standards within Unicode.
But in general, Unicode has encoding and values for many, many characters of many parts of the world,
if not by now, virtually the entire world.
So if there is a a known country that has its own writing system and characters, it's very likely that
those characters have been encoded and included in the Unicode encoding standard.
But all you really need to just understand from this is that there is a standard encoding for turning
characters into numbers, and that encoding that is used by default in Java is called Unicode, and
all it means is that every single character has a numerical value associated with it.
OK, so let's take a look at some of the other variations of the index of method to see what else we
could do with this.
All right.
So we've looked at the index of that takes a number.
That's this entire thing here in the states, there's just stands for character.
So they're just saying you could search for a character by its numerical value.
All right.
And then we also started off with this version here that takes a string, right?
So we searched for an entire string.
And now let's say, let's say that we asked index of to search for a character or string that isn't
contained in the source string here.
So I'm going to put a number in here that I know isn't here, like 122.
OK.
And let's see what we get now.
We get a negative one.
And this is normal behavior.
So what what index of is telling us is that there is no character in this string that matches the encoding
of 122.
So negative one means no match.
It's not in there.
OK?
And again, you'll see code all the time written by Java developers that tests to see if some string
or some characters are contained inside of a bigger string or something, and it'll explicitly look
for like a negative one or whatever.
So that's something really important to learn and be aware of.
And we can do this with a string input as well.
In fact, I guess I could have just left that as a stream, but I don't want to be confusing here,
so I'll do this instead.
Car, OK, so we'll see.
Is the combination of C.A.R. in that order contained in this string and we'll run this.
OK, and again, we get a negative one, which means no car is not contained in that string.
OK.
And by the way, this is case sensitive, so there would be a different.
So in fact, here I'll just prove that real quick.
If we do a b c all uppercase, we get a match of zero, meaning ABC starts at the beginning here.
However, if we do a b c a lower case.
And we run this.
We get a negative one, meaning there is no lower case.
ABC contained within this string.
OK, so that's enough of that.
Now let's look at another variation of the index of method.
I'm going to tell it to search for capital A..
However, we're going to use we're going to use the last index of variation here.
So this method searches for the last occurrence of whatever we're telling it to search.
So let me run it and make that a little more clear as to what I mean.
And so we're here.
We're going to have a search for the letter A.
And look at that, it returned a seven, even though this string starts with an A., which should have
been zero.
But we're telling it to find the last index of a which means find the the last time you find a match.
So this is the first time we find a match.
But if we keep going zero one two three four five six seven The seventh character in here, or the seventh
index, which is the eighth character really is another A and that happens to be the last A.
So you can use this or last index of method to find, you know, the last time there was a match in
any string.
OK, and then there's a few others that we can take a quick look at.
So we've got this one here, index of that takes two parameters.
The first one is, well, here, I like this one, so the first one again is just the numerical code
of one character.
But then it also says you can start from an index.
So what that is telling it is to start searching from a particular index.
So by default, the index of method is starting from the beginning zero.
It would be the index, but you can tell it to skip past some number of characters and then start searching
from there.
OK.
So what happens if we tell it to search for a starting on the third character, let's say.
So let's see what we get here.
So search for a starting from the third.
Character, which is an index of two.
So we're going to skip over that first a in other words.
OK.
All right.
So let's see what we get now.
OK, so this is kind of interesting.
We get a seven, which is what we got when we told when we used the last index of, but now we're using
just the index of which normally would have started at the beginning and it would have found the very
first, eh.
But we told it to skip over the first three characters or so and then start searching.
So now it's returning a seven.
So if I change this to two a zero, which will cause it to behave as if I didn't even have this second
bid here at all, because that's the default behavior.
Let's just confirm what it does.
OK.
And now it does as expected, and it returns to zero, so we are indeed just telling it start searching
from the very beginning and find the first aid you can see, and that would be the very first one.
Whereas when we had when we had the we had the two here, we were telling it start searching.
From here and then go find an A..
And when it found the A..
It then told us what was the index of that a for the entire string, not from where we started searching
from, but for the entire string.
So that might not have been entirely intuitive, but that's what it's actually doing.
OK?
And the last index of has the same variations as well, so I'm not going to show those here.
All right.
So now we can do something kind of interesting.
I've got a little bit of a challenge for you.
Now, this challenge might be a little more advanced, but technically you have learned enough that
you may be able to do this.
So what I want to challenge you to try is to write some code that can extract out parts of a phone number,
and I'm going to give you the format of that phone number.
So first off here, you know what?
I'm going to just clear this out completely.
Oops.
But.
All right.
And.
I will create a phone number.
And I'm going to use a very specific format here, I'm going to do.
Two, three, four space.
Three, three, three hyphen.
Five, five five one.
OK, so we've got the area code.
The exchange and then the line, no.
So the challenge is, can you write some code that can extract out these three parts of this phone number
in this exact format into variables?
So in other words, when you're done, you would have.
A variable that holds the area code equals.
Blah blah blah.
And you would have a variable that holds the.
Exchange.
And you would have a variable that holds the line.
No.
And then you could print those out.
Like, maybe like.
Like this?
OK, so the part that I'm not showing you is.
How did you populate each of these with code, right?
You're not going to just copy and paste these in, you're going to write code to pass this string and
extract out the bits and then put them in their right places.
OK.
Oh, and let me give you one other hint.
I would strongly recommend that to parse out these three bits.
You make three separate static methods to to parse these out.
And so here, in fact, I'm going to go ahead and even give you a starter here of what those methods
might look like in case this isn't clear to you.
This is going to be more than you've done before.
So public static.
So this is going to be a method that will return a string.
And we'll call it pass.
Area code, and it will take a string of a phone number.
Oops.
OK, so there's one.
Let me close this out of the way and then another method.
That looks real similar, but this one will be called pass exchange.
And it also will take a phone number.
And then one more.
Pass line ups line, no.
And this will take a phone number to.
So if these methods are implemented correctly, they should return, respectively, this part for this
method.
This part for this method.
And this part for this method, and in fact, they will look something like this pass area code.
Phone number.
So I'm giving you the scaffolding here.
Pass exchange, phone number.
Pass line, no phone number.
OK, so your task is to fill in the body of each of these methods to actually return what's expected
here.
Go.
All right, so let's see how you did.
Let's see how would I do this?
So phone number?
So the first thing I want to get is this two, three four here.
I know that it's in between an opening parentheses and a closing parentheses.
One thing that I could do is I could search for where does the opening parentheses start?
What's the index of that and what's the index of the closing parentheses?
So yeah, I'm going to I'm going to try it that way.
So I know that the index of these things is going to be an integer.
So I'm going to have an integer variable and I'm going to call it.
Open.
Parents equals, and I'm going to do a phone number.
That index of and I'll just put that opening thingy in there like that.
So that should be the index of where the opening parentheses begins, which should be the first one.
But who knows, maybe whatever.
All right, then I need the closing parentheses, so I'm going to do another integer variable here.
Close.
Parents, and that's just, you know, my shorthand for parentheses.
Phone number, that index of.
The close parentheses there, and I know that could look a little confusing, but hopefully you can
follow it that's saying, all right.
Now here's the trick.
Hopefully, you remember that we learned about sub strings, and that is what we want to use here.
So I'm going to now.
There's a couple of things I could do this.
I'm going to I guess I'll do it this way.
Let's see.
Area code equals phone number, dot substring.
Now here's what I want.
I want a substring that starts with a particular index and ends with a particular index.
Now, programmers get these indexes confused all the time, and I'm no exception to this.
So let's see what we get here.
So I know I want the second one.
Now the up the index of the opening parentheses is stored in this variable called open parents.
However, I don't want the actual parentheses.
I want the the two.
I want to start with that two, and I want to end with that four.
So I don't want to start with the index of this open parents here.
That would be zero here.
I want to start at one.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to do a little math and say I'm going to take the index of
the open parents plus one.
Comma, and then I have to give it the index of the last character.
And I'm going to pass that in which would be the close parents now with the substring method.
The closing are the ending index is non-inclusive.
So in other words, if I tell it to use the index of this closing character here, it's not going to
include that anyway.
And so I don't need to do any math here.
And that's just something you would need to just memorize and know.
All right.
And then finally, I need to return.
The variable that I just populated right there.
OK, now, just so that I can run this and see if I'm on the right track here, I'm going to satisfy
the compiler and the ADC because I've got these little red squiggles here because I'm not returning
anything.
So for right now, I'm just going to return empty strings just to make these methods valid.
And that way, I can go ahead and actually run this and see if I'm on the right path.
There we go, and I got what I was looking for, which is the two three four without the parentheses,
so that parsing trick worked correctly.
All right, so let me close this and now I want to grab the three three three.
So what I want to look for is some distinguishing characteristic within this string to anchor my search
with.
I mean, I can't anchor it on the actual numbers here because those are the parts that could change,
right?
I want to pretend like the format of this string will always be exactly like this, but the numbers
could be different.
So I can't tell my code to search for a three because it could be something different, right?
So what I could do is tell it to search for this space, though.
So I think I'm going to I'm going to try that.
All right.
So on this next method here, I'm going, I'm going to do pretty much the same thing, same basic approach
that I used above.
I'm going to store the index of that, that first space.
I call it space index.
And I'll just use ADX here.
So phone number, that index of and I'm going to just use a space.
Now I could have used the ASCII or the Unicode character for a space, but honestly, I don't even remember
what that is, and I don't feel like looking it up.
And I think this will be fine.
All right.
So that's where we'll start.
And then I think where we'll end is with the hyphen there.
So.
So then we'll do and.
Hyphen index equals phone number.
That index of hyphen character.
And then I will create a string variable to hold the What am I going for here?
Exchange?
Phone number, dot, substring.
And again, we'll do space index plus one comma.
Hyphen index.
So let me explain this again, because repetition is sometimes very useful.
So we're telling the substring method to start with the index of the space, which would be here, which
would be a zero one two three four five.
OK.
But we don't want to actually start here.
We want to start.
I want to start on this three here.
So that would be the space plus one, which is why you see me doing space index plus one, because I
want to start on this three here.
The character right after this space is where I want to start and then I want to grab all the characters
up until.
But not including the hyphen character, which is the hyphen index here.
OK.
And the way that substring works is that it stops short of the last index anyway.
So I don't need to do like minus one or something like that here.
All right.
And then finally, I just return.
Exchange.
All right.
And so now let's run this and see what we've got.
OK, looking good.
So we got two, three, four and then we got three, three, three looking good.
All right.
And so now we need to pass out the last bit, which is called the line number.
So let's see.
And so that starts with the hyphen and then it goes to the end.
All right.
So for that, I think this will be even a little easier.
So for that, we'll start off the same as we did before, in fact, I'm going to be a little lazy here
and I'm going to just duplicate this line and then I'm going to bring it down, by the way.
So the way that I just duplicated that I put my cursor online 24 on my on my I.D..
Your lines might be a little different if you're hitting enter in different places, but I put my cursor
on this line and then I did a Command D for duplicate or control, D for Windows and Linux.
OK, so I duplicated that line, and now I'm going to just drag that line down in the way I can do that
is with an option shift or alt shift and the down arrow key I could have copied and pasted or cut and
pasted or whatever.
If I weren't explaining this, though, the approach that I just used was probably the quickest.
All right.
So now I have that index here and I don't need a last index or closing index.
I mean, you'll see why in just a moment if you don't recall.
So string line number equals phone number, not substring.
Now for this one, I can use another version of the sub string, which just takes the beginning index
and no end index.
If you will recall, this version of the sub string method takes the beginning index and then it just
takes the rest of that string to the end anyway, which is exactly what we want.
And so I don't need to specify an end index, which is great because I don't know what I would anchor
it to anyway.
So, yeah, so we can just pass in the hyphen index just like so and then return line number.
Oh, you know what?
Sorry, almost messed up here.
Forgot to add plus one plus one.
Sorry about that.
See, even seasoned developers make simple mistakes like this all the time.
It's super easy to make this kind of mistake.
All right, so now let me explain what's going on here.
So we have the index of the hyphen plus one would be.
This first five here.
Right.
And then we use the substring method, which takes this index, and if you don't supply an end and end
index, it will just grab all of the characters to the end of the string, which is exactly what we
want.
And that's what we're doing here, substring.
So we're telling it to start at the index of the hyphen plus one, which is this first five here and
then keep going and grab all the rest of that substring substring, meaning the smaller part of this
whole entire string, right?
All right.
So let's run that.
And look what we got here, so now we've passed out all the parts of that phone number.
As long as that phone number is in this format now to double check that this is true, let's change
this to something else now.
Seven, six three.
Eight seven to.
Six, six, three three.
And let's run that.
There we go, seven, six, three eight seven two, six, six three.
So this is actually pretty much 100 percent real type of code, I'm 1000 percent certain.
Many Java developers in the world have written code that looks pretty much exactly like this, except
for maybe not the static methods, possibly not the static methods.
But yeah, many developers will have written code that passes a 10 digit phone number in this way,
or they might have had a phone number that had another hyphen in it, you know, so something like.
Like that, and we could have done this as well, but in that case, we might have used the index up
for the hyphen for this one here and then the last index for the second hyphen to differentiate those
two hyphens.
That might have been what we what we might have done.
OK.
So this is pretty cool.
If you were able to get that, then you are really coming along.
And if you weren't, hopefully my walk through here clarified what?
What was needed here?
Now I do want to point out one quick thing.
While it is true that in my experience, I've seen a probably a majority of Java developers who would
have solved this problem, and in pretty much just like this, using a combination of index of and substring,
I personally almost certainly wouldn't have done this in this way.
There's actually an easier way.
Well, there is actually a more concise way to do this, but it involves learning a more advanced technique
called regular expressions, and we will be learning that shortly.
But you will encounter as a professional Java developer, lots of code that looks very similar to this,
where there's lots of index UVs and sub strings in any time you need to parse some formatted text of
some sort.
But there is a better way to do a lot of these kinds of things, and we will see that shortly.
Anyway, this concludes this lesson, and this was a good one because we really got a chance to put
together a lot of things, by the way.
Real quick, you also might have wanted to do something like what if there could have been some spaces
here?
What if the user had been asked to enter the phone number?
Let me let me put.
Let me put this back the way it was real quick.
What if the user had been prompted to enter a phone number in this format, but you couldn't be certain
that they didn't put a few extra spaces in here with these extra spaces that would cause this whole
entire program to blow up.
In fact, let me just do that real quick.
OK, so now look at what we get.
The program isn't quite working correctly anymore.
It's very fragile, and that's because of these unexpected leading spaces here.
Now we could fix that, though, by using the strip method.
Anywhere in here so we can use it here or we could use it here or whatever, but by using the strip
method and we run this again, we're back to working again.
OK.
And so now you get a chance to see a little more real world.
Why something like the strip method could be very, very useful.
All right, now, I'm going to wrap it up.
So good lesson and I will see you in the next one.