All right, so for this next lesson, we're going to get into the last of the most popular implementations
of the set, and that is the TV set.
So the TV set is kind of interesting because what it can do is in addition to filtering out the duplicates,
like all implementations of a set, are capable of doing.
It will also order the items naturally.
So think essentially alphabetical order.
However, that order actually can be controlled by you, and we'll take a look at how to do that momentarily.
So first thing we're going to do, though, is just revise our code to use the tree set.
So I'm coming over here to where we've currently got the linked hash that and I will replace that with
tree.
There we go.
And it's as easy as that.
Now please keep in mind that every time we've changed now the implementation of the set, we again are
not having to change anything on the left side here, right, because we're coding to the interface,
so to speak.
Right?
OK.
So taking a making a quick note of the fact that with the linked hash set, all of our elements when
we iterate over them are in the same order as the original list because that's the order in which we
are inserting the items, right?
So the linked hash that retains the insert order, the hash that has the kind of a random order.
Right?
Sort of kind of random to us, at least.
So let's see now what happens with the tree set.
So I'm going to go ahead and run this.
All right, so looks like we're getting only 11 items back after the filtering then because we're only
getting 11 items back, it looks like our total payout has now lowered to seven million versus the eight
point six million that we have been generally seeing.
So obviously there's a question here why are so many more items being filtered out than we were expecting
in order to answer this question?
We need to step back a moment and consider a little bit more about how the tree set actually works.
So the tree set has the ability not only to filter items, but to keep those items in a so-called natural
ordering.
Now that ordering is actually something that we can control.
And would you like to venture a guess as to how we can control that?
So the tree said, actually can make use of objects that are in it that implement the comparable interface.
If you remember that interface, the comparable interface has a method on it, which is compare to.
So if our employee class implements the comparable interface and therefore has a compare to method on
it, we can implement that compared to method to cause the tree set to order our items.
However, we see fit.
So let's take a look at the employee class and remember what we were doing with it with regards to ordering.
So I'm going to jump into the employee class.
OK, so the first thing to recall is that it's on the face of it.
It's only implementing the AI employee interface.
But if we drill into the employee interface and this is really just review, in fact, we can kind of
see what the AI employee interface is doing right here as I'm hovering.
So we can see that it actually extends the comparable interface.
And so that is equivalent to us saying that the employee implements I employee.
Comma comparable.
OK, that's that's somewhat equivalent to that.
So if we go down to the bottom of the employee class, we should find the compare to method that we
are forced to implement because of because of the comparable interface that we are inheriting essentially.
So if we go down here towards the bottom.
There it is.
Compare to remember this.
All right, so our compared to method currently is comparing last names.
And therein lies the key to understanding why we're only getting back 11 items instead of, I think
what was it?
17.
So before I explain it fully, do you want to take a moment to try to think of, you know, figure out
if you understand what's going on here so you can pause the video and think about it for a minute.
OK, so if we jump back over to the main class and go look at our unfiltered data, let me move this
down a bit.
Let's get to a little deeper understanding of what's happening here.
So the So the tree set is both filtering and sorting our employees, according to the implementation
of the Compare two method.
And we just looked at the compare to method and saw that it is only comparing last names.
So we have three possibilities when comparing these employees using the Compare two method.
Either one employee compared to the other is going to come before it or after it, or they could be
considered equal.
So let us consider now what would cause two employees to appear to be equal with respect to the compare
to method?
Well, it would be the last name, because that's the only property that's being used in that compared
to method.
So if the compare to Method is only looking at the last name, then what do you think is going to happen
with multiple records that all share the same last name?
They're all going to look equal to each other.
So this means that while we're using the tree set with this particular implementation of Compare two,
which is only looking at the last name, the definition of a duplicate would be any employee that has
a last name that's already found in the tree set.
OK.
Of which there are many.
Right?
So if we're looking here at the last name of Flintstone, for example, presumably after this first
Fred Flintstone is added successfully to the tree, set all other employees with the last name of Flintstone,
regardless of what the first name is.
If they have the last name of Flintstone, presumably they will be filtered out because the compare
to method is only looking at the last name.
So all of these should be filtered out, but additionally.
Wilma should also be filtered out because she also has the same last name, at least this first Wilma.
Additionally, let's see who else here, we've got Barney Rubble with no no behind him, and we've got
Betty rubble, so Betty presumably would also be filtered out.
And so if we go back here to our output, like I said, we shouldn't see a Betty rubble and we should
not see a Wilma Flintstone either.
Fred, Fred, Fred, Barney, Barney, Barney.
Yes, so unfortunately the ladies are being filtered out.
That's what's happening here.
Now, one quick thing, I also want to note, just for your own edification, this isn't something I
think you really desperately need to know, but it might be helpful to just be aware.
So the tree set is called a tree set because internally it uses what is called a tree structure.
More specifically, it uses a self-balancing binary tree.
Don't worry, you don't really need to remember that.
In fact, that can be even more specific.
It uses a particular type of self-balancing binary tree, which is called a red black tree, and that
tree structure allows items.
In this case, our objects of of type employee to be arranged in a tree like structure such that individual
items in that structure can be found relatively quickly without having to necessarily iterate through
each and every individual item.
Let me show you real quick what that kind of looks like.
We'll go to the Wikipedia article for a Red Black Tree.
OK, so here we've got the Wikipedia article for the Red Black Tree up, and we're not going to read
any of this, but I will jump over to some pretty pictures so that you can get a get a sense for what's
happening here.
So if you think of each of these circles, which are usually considered to be nodes, if you think of
these as the objects or items in our tree set, right?
So in our case, these would be employees, actual individual employees.
And if you think of these numbers as the last names of the employees, OK, then what happens is when
the when we add the first employee to the structure that would be represented at the top of this tree
structure here, that's the first node that we are adding.
And then as we add subsequent nodes, the compare to method gets called.
So let's say we add the first employee to the tree.
Who would be Fred Flintstone, OK?
And then we go to add a second employee to the to the tree, who is one of the duplicated Fred Flintstone.
So same first name, same last name.
Well, what's going to happen is the compare to method is going to be called to compare the first Fred
Flintstone to the second Fred Flintstone.
And since our compare to method in this particular case, is only looking at the last name and the last
names match, thereby returning a zero from the compare to method.
Remember, compare to returns an integer negative one, zero or positive one.
If they are equal, it returns a zero.
So when the compare to method returns a zero that indicates to the tree set that this new.
Object that we're trying to add to the tree already exists in the tree, and therefore it will not be
added, the second one will not be added, it'll just be sort of filtered out.
OK.
However, if we try to add a node for which the compare to results in a negative one, meaning one comes
before the other, then that new node will be added either to the left or to the right of the existing
node.
OK?
And that's why it's called a binary node, because newly added nodes can only go to one of two positions,
either to the left or to the right.
And basically, it's just if a new node that we're trying to add would come before the existing node,
then generally speaking, it goes to the left if it would come after in some sorting order that it would
go to the right.
And again, we control that order right and the determination of it because we can right the compare
to method ourself or we can write the implementation of it ourselves.
So that's why here we are depicting that the number eight goes to the left of 13 because it's less than
13.
If you want to think of these as names, if this is Flintstone, this name over here could be Apple,
right?
So Apple would come before Flintstone alphabetically, and therefore Apple would go to the left here.
And then on the other side here, if this name were Roberts, well, that comes alphabetically after
Flintstone, and so that would go to the right.
OK, now the whole benefit of using this tree structure to order things is that, like I said earlier,
we are then able to find a given node within this structure more quickly than having to iterate through
each and every single node.
So if you wanted to find a 22, for example, if we passed in the number 22 and we wanted to find where
is 22 within this tree structure, well, we get to the 13 because that's the first node here and we
would quickly determine Will 22 is greater than 13, so therefore twenty two must be off to the right
somewhere.
Then we come down to 17 and then we ask again with the compare to where it's 22 in relation to 17.
And so we would determine that, well, it must be to the right because twenty two is greater than 17.
Then we get down to this node for twenty five and we determined that twenty two is less than twenty
five and therefore twenty two must live to the left of twenty five.
And bam, now we're here.
So we did have to traverse three nodes to get to twenty two, but we didn't have to traverse potentially
all of the nodes to get to the twenty two.
OK, so the binary tree structure does permit us to cut down significant potentially significantly on
the total number of nodes that we have to traverse in order to find the the node that we're actually
looking for.
And that is one of the primary benefits of the tree structure.
And then the other benefit, obviously, is the fact that the nodes can stay in some type of ordering.
So returning back to the A.D. now that we know this, if we want to get more than 11 nodes out of this
thing and get back up to like the eight point six million value.
Can you think of a way that we could do that with minimal changes to the code?
OK, so hopefully you may have thought of a way to do that.
I'm going to show you one way that I can think of of doing this.
So we kind of know now that the employee diet compared to method is kind of at the heart of influencing
how this tree set works.
So I think we need to jump back over to the employee class and go back down to our compare two method.
And one thing that I can think to do that would be fairly minimal is simply change the implementation
of the compare to method to not use the last name, but instead use the first names because they are
actually more unique.
So I'm going to hold down on the option shift keys while I double click the last name here and this
last name here, right?
So that way I can select both of them at the same time.
And then I will hit escape to get out of that double entry mode.
And now, if I just come over here and just click the play button to rerun the program.
Let's see what we get now.
Hey, there we go.
17 items.
And we're back to the eight point six million again, so that did the trick right there.
And just in case you're a little foggy on exactly why that's happening, let's just go look again at
the main class.
And we'll come back up here to our main data and make this a little bit smaller.
So just consider so all of these duplicates are still being filtered out, but now they're being filtered
by the first name, which is also Fred.
Right.
So all of these are being filtered.
But let's see what isn't getting filtered that was before.
So we've got Fred Flintstone.
But now we're also getting Wilma Flintstone because we're no longer looking at her last name, we're
looking at just the first name now.
And so since the employees that we weren't really meaning to filter out have a number differentiating
them in their first name, right?
Those remain right.
They're not getting filter out filtered out.
It's just the ones with the duplicated last names that are getting filtered.
And so Wilma persists.
And then for the rubble family, not only do we have all the variations of Barney rubble, we also still
are getting Betty rubble because there's only one Betty, right?
And so that's enabling our tree set to filter out.
These duplicates by first name, but not Fred and Wilma and Barney and and and Betty.
Right?
So yeah, that's that's working well.
Now there's one more little thing I would like to share with you about the tree set now with the default
no, our constructor version of the tree set that we are using here.
It expects that the objects that we're adding to it are all of type comparable, meaning they all implement
either directly or indirectly, in our case, the comparable interface so that it can call the compare
two method to determine do I put these new notes to the left or to the right of existing node right
and build that tree structure?
However, there is an alternative constructor that we could also use, especially when and if our objects
that we're wanting to store in it don't happen to implement the comparable interface.
So there is another overloaded version of the constructor that can take that can take a comparator.
So we learned in previous lessons about the comparable interface, but also a comparator.
Right.
And so this is quite nice.
Like I said, if our objects don't happen to implement comparable or if we just want to be able to sort
them according to some other approach.
And in fact, what we could do that would maybe be kind of interesting if we go back over to the employee
class one more time and basically undo this change here.
So I'm going to put this back to last name.
Last name.
And just to prove that I broke it again, I will rerun and we should go back to having only 11 items.
Here we go, OK, we're back to 11 items.
All right, now, I will jump back over to the main class.
So since the tree set has this overloaded constructor constructor that is capable of taking an actual
instance of a comparator and because the comparator interface is functional, which means that it only
defines one method on it, we could actually supply a lambda expression right here to implement our
own comparator in a fairly constrained way.
Now I'm going to get this started, but I'm not going to finish it because we're going to run into one
thing that I'm not all that inclined to get into, but I want to show you the gist of this real quick
here.
So the compare method of the comparator interface takes two inputs.
It's the two items now that are being compared against each other.
And so to make a lambda expression that would represent that, we would be able to have something that
says something like this.
If I decide to call those two objects e one and E two and putting them in parentheses, and then we'd
have our arrow operator here.
And then we could start saying some things, right like e one dot.
And here's though, where we're going to run into a little bit of trouble because currently our set
is a set of AI employee.
And as you may recall, I employee does not directly define last names and first names and things like
that, right?
And that's what we actually want to use to compare.
It only defines salary, so we would need to cast this, and I don't feel like getting into all of that.
But you can see where I'm going here.
Basically, what we would be saying is something to the effect of E one dot.
First name, Scott, compared to E to Dot first name.
That's basically that's the basic gist of what we'd be doing here, and this would let us do the same
thing and again, and just remind you, the only reason I'm not following through with this is because
we're actually dealing with an employee which does not happen to define first name.
I would have to cast these, OK?
But this is the basic gist.
And so that's quite convenient in most cases where we're using the proper interface.
At least this would be quite convenient to be able to do to arbitrarily order our objects in this set,
according to whatever individual simple property we might want to.
One thing I guess I could do for sure and this would be worthwhile, I suppose, is to use the is to
order them by salary.
So we certainly can do this.
Now, the get salary method is returning a simple integer, though, and so simple in integers are not
objects, and therefore they don't have a compare to method on them.
However, if you may recall, we did learn a way to get past that.
We can just use the wrapper integer class, and it has a compare method on it, so we can kind of flip
it inside out, if you will.
E one dot get salary, comma e two loops dot good salary so we can do this.
And to prove that now we can run this again now, the output that we're going to get is going to be
somewhat unpredictable to me because now we're not comparing by last name or first name.
We're now comparing by salary, but let's see what we get.
It'll be something different.
All right, now, we're getting 16 back.
OK, interesting, we are still getting eight point six, though.
And now they are all ordered by salary, starting with zero.
Two point five six, two point two point five, six, two point five 08 and so on and so forth.
OK, so that's kind of cool, right?
So this is actually quite powerful if and when you actually need this type of functionality to be able
to sort and order the items in your list, but also to filter out duplicates according to whatever arbitrary
definition of duplicate you come up with.
And even if you didn't bake that definition into a comparable interface on the objects that you're adding,
you can always just supply a comparator directly to the tree set.
So that's quite powerful.
And so this is pretty cool.
We've now learned how to implement three different types of the most popular implementations of the
set interface.
The hash set, which again is the fastest one but gives unpredictable ordering.
The linked hash set, which is almost as fast as the hash set, are not quite as fast but almost as
fast as the hash set.
But has the added benefit if you need it of retaining the insertion order of your objects?
And now we also have learned of the tree set, which also can filter.
But it does so according to an ordering that you can define either with your objects, implementing
the comparable interface or by supplying a comparator or a lambda that implements the compare method
of the comparator.
All right, so you've got quite a bit of flexibility here for filtering items out with sets now.
And so with that, I think we're going to wrap this one up and I'll see you in the next one.