And there's one more for loop pattern that I want to introduce you to before we close out this topic.
So for this one, I want to show you a scenario here.
It has to do with arrays.
So let's say that we have a string array called fruits, and we will initialize it with a few different
fruits.
Apple, orange, pear, plum.
That's enough.
All right.
Now let's say that we want to loop over these fruits and just print them out, right?
So can you think of ways that we can do this?
I mean, one thing we could do is we could use a for loop and we could declare a counter, set it to
zero, initialize it to zero.
And then we could say something like keep counting as long as the counter is less than now.
What number do we want to put here?
Well, we could actually just set it to count up to the number of items that are in the fruit array,
and this is a very common pattern.
So what we can do is to reference fruits length.
OK.
And then counter plus plus.
So that's a very, very common pattern when especially if you're looping over items in an array, you'll
just refer to the length of the array.
And now here we could do something like current fruit is.
Fruits counter, right?
Let's run that and see it.
All right, so there we go.
Apple, orange, pear, plum.
Right.
So that's fairly straightforward, kind of a nice use of the the for loop.
However, there is as of Java five, I believe it was something called the enhanced for loop.
And basically, it just cuts down on the amount of typing that we need to do to implement this exact
pattern.
And so let me show you what that looks like.
It's quite nice, I would say.
So we don't need any of this.
We can get rid of all of that.
And instead, we can simply say that we're going to have a variable of type string and we can call it
fruit, and then we use a colon and then a space.
The space is optional and then we reference our array.
So the variable for the array is fruit.
So if I just type in fruits just like that.
Now you can have a space to the left of the colon as well.
It doesn't really matter.
And now down here, instead of directly referencing the array, what's going to happen is that this
enhanced for loop is going to iterate through iterate means to step through each item in the array.
In this case, it's going to step through and it's going to take whatever the current value in that
iteration is.
Whatever the current string is in the as it's iterating over all of these strings in this array and
it's going to assign them one at a time to this variable fruit.
And so that means down here, we don't need to reference the individual values out of the array anymore.
We can simply refer to this local variable fruit.
So let's run this.
So look at that.
There's you don't see any difference in the output.
It behaves the same, right?
The output is.
But look at this much nicer, isn't it?
Is it just easier to look at?
So as long as you don't need an index or a counter, if you just want to loop over the items that are
in an array, you can use this enhanced for loop to do this.
Now this is I'm considering this to be a little bit of a sneak preview because in a later module, we
will learn about collections which are kind of like arrays on steroids, and we can use the enhanced
loop to reference the items that are in a collection as well.
OK.
But since we were already on the for loop and you've already learned about arrays might as well go ahead
and introduce you now to this specific use of the enhanced for loop.
So that's it.