All right.
And now let's do another one.
This time, we're going to implement the ability to delete a record from the database table.
All right.
And this should be approximately just as easy as the count.
Maybe even easier, actually, because technically with this, we don't even really have to return anything.
All right.
So let's see here we'll create another test.
Public void can delete.
All right.
And so to delete records from a test perspective, maybe what we'll do is we'll start off by inserting
one record into the database.
Then we will get a count of the total records in the database.
Then we will use our delete to delete that one record that we just added and then we'll get another
count.
And then we will assert that the end count is the start count minus one.
Something something along those lines, right?
All right.
So then let's just copy one of these lines again.
Oops.
All right.
And then we'll bring that down.
All right, so there's our new record into the database and then let's get account, and I guess we'll
just use the count method that we have now.
So we'll grab that and say start count.
And so I think we may need to capture the output of this save so that we can get an idea, maybe we'll
implement this delete method such that it takes the idea of a record and then it finds that record by
that idea and deletes it.
OK.
There are a number of ways that we could implement that, but maybe we'll go with that approach for
now.
All right.
So let's capture the output from this.
So that's going to return a person and a saved person.
There we go.
All right.
And so then we will call Repo Dot Delete.
Now, I think the way we'll do this is we will just pass in the the person, the whole entire object.
All right.
And so let's go.
Let the ABC create this delete skeleton for us, and we will let that return a void.
We don't need it to return anything, and we'll just call this person.
All right.
Jump back over to the test.
So now that's happy.
And then finally, let's get an end count, I suppose.
Repo count.
And so then we will assert that the end count?
Is equal to the start count minus one.
All right.
Let's run that.
All right, there's our failure.
Yeah, so we expect that their team, but we got 14.
OK.
And now let's go make it work.
So we're implementing delete now.
Connection prepare statement, so this will be delete from people where.
ID equals question mark.
And let's surround that with our try catch.
And then let's capture the output prepared statement.
All right, now, we do have a parameter here now, which is going to be the ID of the person that we
just passed in.
So we will need to bind that piece that set long.
And the first parameter is the index parameter index, and there's only one parameter here.
So that will be an index of one right one.
And then the value will be the ID of that person.
Person die, get I.D..
Like so and then we can execute this start execute update.
Now that will return a result that we can capture affected records.
Record count.
And we could just print that out somewhere that's really more like for debugging purposes.
But I think that's it right there.
All right.
So let's jump back over here to the tests and let's run it.
See what we get this time.
Hey, there you go.
Looks like it's passing.
And now let's go ahead and just run all the tests.
And look, we don't looks like we don't have any regressions, everything's still working for us.
Now, this one was so quick and easy, I feel inclined to make it a little more complicated.
What if we wanted to delete multiple people at the same time?
Well, I think we can do that too.
Now, I think we're going to do it with a with an additional method, though.
So one way that I could see to do that might be to have a method can delete multiple.
People, maybe.
And so let's say that we had both of these going to copy those, both come down here.
Paste them.
Okay, so we'd start off by inserting two different people into the database table, and I suppose we're
going to want to capture their outputs here.
So I'm giving myself two persons here on both of these lines by holding down on option or alt and shift
while clicking on both of those.
And then I can do person p one equals and then I'll come down here and just change that to a P two like
that.
All right.
So now I've captured both of those people.
And then let's pretend like I have another version and overloaded version of the delete method, one
that takes P one and P two like that.
All right.
Now I can do this in a lot of different ways, really.
But for right now, I'm inclined to just do it this way just to have some fun.
So watch what I'm going to do here to implement this method.
So I'm going to put my cursor there to the right of the closing parentheses and then do an option return.
Now the idea is offering to modify the one and only delete method that we currently have by adding a
second parameter or a first parameter.
I don't want either of those.
We're going to create a new additional delete method.
OK.
Create Method Delete in People repository now.
So the void return type is fine.
However, the input parameters I don't want what I'm thinking of doing here.
Well, I don't want all of them rather.
So I'm going to say yes to the data type of person, but I think I'm going to say no to everything else
here.
So I'm just going to start deleting.
In fact, now what I'm thinking of doing here is actually using barracks.
Do you remember we learned about VAR args there basically in a lot of ways, just a shorthand for passing
in an array.
So if you just put.
Three ellipses and then a variable name.
Like that that's basically equivalent to having.
An array like that, OK, except that I don't have to create an array in the code that calls this delete
method.
OK.
So it's actually makes it pretty easy for me to call this method and just pass in any arbitrary number
of people objects.
OK.
But that's what this is basically equivalent to.
All right.
And now what I can do is something like four.
Each person and people.
So I'm using the enhanced for loop here to iterate over each of the potential people that I have in
this space in this bar args, which is basically an array.
And then here I can delegate down to the other delete method, really delete person just like that.
OK.
So I didn't even have to write any SQL code down here.
Now, honestly, this isn't actually the way that I was going to go about doing this when I started,
when I thought of this idea, but I realized this was one quick way that I could do it right.
In fact, honestly, this is so easy that I think I am still going to complicate this a little more
for you because because I actually want to show you another skill technique.
In fact, OK, but this is one way that you could do it for sure, right?
So you could just iterate over these and then just delegate down to this delete method here.
That's one way you can do it.
However, from a database perspective, there's a more efficient way to handle this same use case.
And by efficient, I mean, with this approach, you'd be making separate and distinct updates to the
database for each of the people that were passed in here.
OK?
There's a more efficient way to delete them all with one call to the database.
So let me show you what that would look like.