All right, I've got another idea for a feature to implement in this guessing game that we actually
did not implement in the original version.
Sometimes it's nice when you're playing a guessing game where you have to guess a number to be given
a hint as to whether or not you're too high or too low.
Right.
So that you can at least have some idea what direction should you be guessing in?
So I was thinking it might be nice to implement that capability here.
So if we turn back to the code and go back over to our tests and I'm going to minimize that window there.
So let's start at the top here and just see.
So, yeah, like this scenario here, test one wrong negative guess situation.
So obviously here we're using a negative number.
So we might have expected that if we were to implement this hint capability, maybe it would say something
like you didn't get it and then maybe tell us that we're too low, right?
So we know too to go up something like that test one wrong positive situation.
So assuming in this case that, well, yeah, actually in this case, we would be too high by one.
So then it would say you didn't get it and maybe too low or I'm sorry, too high.
Right?
So I don't know.
Let's let's see what this would look like if we were to do this.
We'll start by just revising these existing tests to force us to make the proper code changes.
So we'll start with this one where we know we're going to be too low regardless.
And let's just say that it's going to say you didn't get it hyphen.
Maybe you're too low.
Yeah, let's let's try that.
All right.
And see here, let's run all the tests.
And so now that guy is failing as as expected, and so we'll we'll jump over to him and then we'll jump
into the actual code and do the simplest thing we can to make that work.
You're too low.
All right now, let's see.
So that message is currently here.
You didn't get it.
So let's just do the simplest thing.
Ethan.
You're too low.
And let's rerun all of the tests, and I think we can predict roughly what's going to happen here,
but let's let's see it.
All right, so let's see.
All right, we fixed that previous failing test, but now our positive situation is failing.
So what can we do to get that working again?
So currently the positive situation is expecting to just see the text.
You didn't get it.
So let's see here.
So both of those scenarios are happening inside of Line 19.
And currently we've hardcoded the message You're too low.
But now I guess we need to be more conditional and say and only put this year too low if you're actually
if your guest is actually too low.
So I mean, I guess we could just put a little embedded conditional only inside of this final clause
here because it won't apply to these two.
Do you understand why?
That's because this message only comes up in this clause.
So anything we're going to add to it needs to be code that only needs to live, probably in this clause.
So let's see what we can do here.
I'm going to make a new line and we'll start simple and just say something like if if guest number is
less than the random number.
Then now we need to decide what we want to do here.
I'm kind of liking this idea of having these formatted strings and then just tacking them on to the
end.
I'm kind of liking that approach in general, so I'm thinking to replace this with a variable right
and then use and then turn this whole thing into a formatted string and then just tack on that variable
something along those lines.
So let's see, how would this look if we had a string called something like two low text and we'll set
it to null, I suppose for now.
And then we'll say if the guest number is less than the random number, then to load text equals.
Hyphen, you're too low.
And then we can replace this string.
Now, I don't really want to, I don't want to make this line too much longer than it is.
So what I think I'm going to do is I'm going to extract this string.
I'm going to convert this string into its own variable first.
By selecting it and then doing a command option V and maybe I'll just call this loose text.
All right, then I'll come over here and we'll use a string that format again so that we can tack on
this to low tax to replace that bit there.
So we'll do another string dot format.
And then we'll select all of that and replace it with a percent s.
And then we'll just plug that in with the two low text like that.
Now I do see one issue here that I think we're going to have to address, and I think we've got the
tests to force us to address it already.
If I were to run this right now, I believe this test would still fail because this condition would
not be met because this is happening.
If you're too high and therefore too low, tax would be null.
And we'd be trying to assign a null value here.
And I think I don't know exactly how that would turn out, but I'm pretty sure it's not going to work.
Actually, we can go in, just try it and see, let's let's just run this all again.
Yeah, OK.
So yeah, now we get you didn't get it null because we're initializing this string to a null.
So we could fix this in one or two ways.
We could initialize it to empty string like.
So that's a tiny bit wasteful, though, because if this condition is true, then this little empty
string object is going to be created for for nothing, which means that it has to be garbage collected.
It won't cost us anything significant at all.
But it's a little better not to do this, I think I think a better thing to do is to leave that null
here and then just have an else block.
So if the guest number is less than the random number, then set this text to you're too low.
Now we could maybe do an else else and then otherwise we could just set the two low text equal to empty
string like so.
And I think that would get it.
So let's see.
Let's run this now.
Hmm.
Close, maybe.
Yeah, we're very close.
OK, so now now that looks like a perfect match, but I bet we're not quite matching due to some space
characters or something that we are not able to see.
So now to see what the real difference here is here, we can actually click on this, see the difference.
So if we click on that?
Yeah, look at that we we get a little green space here showing us that there's an extra space right
there, which doesn't exist here.
All right.
So how do you think we could get rid of this?
Can you think of a way that we could fix this?
All right.
I think one thing we could do that would be pretty easy.
You may not remember this method, but we learned it in the text manipulation module.
We can use a method that will strip all of the trailing spaces so we can actually use the let's see
the trim method here.
And there are actually a couple of ways we could do this.
We can use trim, which will get rid of both leading and trailing space, or we could use one of the
strip methods to strip either the leading or trailing.
In this case, we'd want to strip the trailing, so either of those would be fine.
Trim or strip trailing would probably be appropriate, I guess, since since I'm already highlighted
on the trim, I'm going to go for the trim method here.
So let's run this again and see.
There we go.
We got everything passing.
So just a quick reminder here.
The trim method simply removes any leading or trailing space characters.
And that's exactly the issue that we have here is that we end up with an extra space at the end and
we just don't want that.
So this trim method fixes that perfectly.
All right, now, let's go back over to our tests and now let's look at this because we're not done
here.
We just got this back to working again, but now we want to revise this.
So this is a scenario where we're too high, right?
Because we're adding one to the random numbers.
So we're our guest is going to technically be too high.
So in this case, we'd want it to give us some feedback and tell us you didn't get it.
You're too high, right?
So let's run all the tests again, and this should fail again now.
Yep, there we go.
All right.
So now that's failing.
Now let me just step back real quick before we go and fix this.
Make sure you're all keeping up with what we just did here.
So first, we changed the negative situation in which we were too low.
And we said, Hey, when when we're too low I want, I expect that we'll get feedback telling us that
we're too low.
Right?
So we did that.
Then we ran all the tests.
And then this test failed.
Then we did the simplest thing I could think to do to make it pass, which was to simply hard code.
This message then ran all the tests again, then this pass.
But then this one failed.
So then I refactored the implementation code, the system under test code, the code not in this class,
but the actual game class guessing game class.
I refactored it to implement this functionality in a smarter way other than just other than just hard
coding it.
And then we ran all the tests again and then this passed.
But then this failed, right?
And so then I had to fix that again, and I hadn't yet even added any of this right?
So I was just trying to get all of the tests back to a working state.
So my point here is I'm you really want to try to limit your changes in both the tests and the system
under test to one change at a time.
Right.
So all I initially did was just make this change.
Then I did everything I needed to do on the back end to get all of these tests working again.
Then, and only after I got all of these tests working did I come in here and then say, OK, now let's
make it so that we see this message about being too high, right?
And now we're having to fix this.
So one change at a time, you don't want to introduce multiple changes all at once because then you
complicate what it is that you're there to fix, right?
Or implement one change at a time, ideally.
All right.
So now we can jump over back into the system under test, which is the guessing game class.
And so now let's see.
We need it to say you didn't get it.
You're too high if in fact you are too high.
And I think this should be pretty easy to do now without breaking anything else.
We'll just add on to this, if else block here.
And I think we can just add an additional EFL's statement right on the end of here.
So like else, if.
Guest number is greater than the random number then.
And then I want to join this line 25 up to line 24, and by the way, if you ever want to join two lines
like I want to do here, get this this line.
Get this else.
And then the curly brace up on this line.
24 to join it all up just for my formatting, the way that I have an else here.
And then the curly brace, there is a keyboard shortcut to do that.
Of course, you could just hit the delete key a few times until it all joins up.
But I don't like doing that.
I like doing, you know, the keyboard shortcuts, right?
And do it all in one fell swoop.
So to do that, it is a control shift, J.
All right.
Let me do that one more time for you.
So my cursor is on the line that I want to get everything on two.
And then on Mac, I'm doing control shift j for join all right and on Windows also control shift j.
So that joins the bottom line up to the next line above it.
All right.
And now in the body here, we'll just do the opposite of this, so we'll set to low text equal to hyphen.
You're too high now that we're using the to load text for two various scenarios.
For two opposing scenarios, I want to rename this variable to something a little better.
Maybe I'll call it, I don't know, too low, high text or something.
I don't know.
So I'll just put my cursor on any one of these instances of the variable to low text that doesn't matter
which one I'm on, and then I can refactor that with a renaming with a shift f six.
All right, and look out all instances of that variable.
Get highlighted now and then I can just say to add my cursus already where I want it to be too high.
Oops.
Lost it there, too too high.
Low text enter.
And so see how that renamed all places where I'm referring to that variable now, including right here
also.
All right.
So now let's rerun all of the tests, and I think we may have this working.
Awesome.
There we go.
Cool.
So all of our tests are working, and now we've got a little extra functionality that we did not have
before, and we've got a pretty well fleshed out little game engine here.
All right.
So I think that's just about going to do it for this module for now in teaching you how to write automated
unit tests for basic tests like what we're doing here, there's really not a whole lot to it.
Now there's a lot of additional techniques that you could learn, and we may touch on a few more of
those throughout this course.
But obviously this was enough to get you going on a fair amount of testing.
So let's just review this real quick.
So we've got the before each annotation here, which allows us to run some bit of code inside of the
method before each test method runs.
If we need it, then we've got the at test annotation to indicate that a method is an actual test.
We also saw earlier on the repeated test annotation that you can use.
Alternatively, instead of the test annotation and with this one, it has parentheses so that you can
pass in the number of times that you want that test to be repeated.
So that can be quite helpful sometimes.
All right.
But after we got everything nailed down, I decided we didn't need to keep it there.
We could have, but I didn't think it was necessary.
And then we also learned, obviously about the assertions which which really finalized the test.
So I've actually seen professional software developers who claimed to know how to write unit tests with
J Unit, the framework we're using here.
And they wrote tests and didn't have a single assertion.
And let me just tell you real quick.
In fact, let me just show you real quick what happens if you don't have an assertion in a J unit test?
So we'll make a quick test here.
Public void junk test.
And I'm not going to put anything in there at all.
Now let's run this and see what happens.
And I'm only going to run just this one test.
OK, so look at what happens there if you have no assertion by default, the test passes, I've seen
a number of software developers who claimed to know how to write unit tests, write a test with no assertion
whatsoever.
And of course, they see things passing and they think, Hey, I wrote a great test.
No, you didn't.
You didn't write anything at all without an assertion.
You do not have a test because you're not telling the test what it should check to determine whether
or not it actually is working, right?
You have nothing without an assertion.
All right.
So we learned about the static method assert equals, which is generally the most common type of assertion.
But let me tell you now there are actually quite a large number of assertions that you could use, and
I will show you a few of those before I do.
Let's also talk about the fact that you can optionally supply a message to be shown in the event that
your assertion doesn't work.
And this is particularly helpful when you run into a scenario where you have one test method with multiple
loops, with multiple assertions, with multiple assertions.
OK.
Where you'd be asserting various things like you might want to assert that the number three exists in
this message, in addition to asserting that the term you got it exists, so you could do that in two
separate states.
In fact, let's do that real quick.
I'll just show you what that would could look like.
OK?
So if we wanted to verify that no, not only the number three is here separately, but also that the
message you got it is here separately, but all in this one test, we can do that.
Now we can do that in a few ways.
We could use another assertion method.
So one way that we can learn about the additional assertion methods, by the way, and this is this
one out of many ways you could actually go up to where this assert equals is being imported, which
is at the very top here, right here.
And if you put your cursor right after this period and then do a control space, we can actually pull
up all of the other static methods that exist on this assertions class here and see what else there
is.
And look, it just there's so many just of the equals there.
There's a all and assert array equals, and so many assert that assert does not throw and assert false.
That's, you know, one worth being aware of that just asserts that you have a Boolean that's false
or a Boolean expression or something that evaluates to false.
And of course, there would be an assert.
True, there's a certain lines match assert, not equal.
OK, so that's potentially useful.
Assert, not null.
Assert null, assert same throws time out.
True.
OK.
So there's quite a bit.
And then there are additional third party libraries that give us even more assertions than than these.
So there's quite a bit, but generally assert equals tends to be probably the most used and the most
useful assertion in general.
And it is often recommended to do your best to use this because I using an assert equals you get really
great feedback when the assertion fails, because then you can compare as you saw us do earlier.
You can actually compare the actual compared to the expected.
All right.
So let's go down here real quick, though, and we can show how to use multiple assertions here.
So let's say we first want to just assert that the number three will exist here.
Right?
So one way we could do that could be to change this from an assert equals two maybe and assert true
and then say something like message that contains you.
Remember, we learned this method here contains three.
So we could do that and we could even put up a little space in there if we wanted to.
Not that it matters.
Notice that this is true is in red.
That's because it needs to be imported so we can either use the red light bulb there or we can put our
cursor here on this word and then do an option return to import it like so.
And now, because we're about to have multiple assertions here, I definitely would supply a message
here to say something like, I don't know, maybe like should indicate.
Three tries, you know?
All right.
And then let's see, you got it in three tries.
Then we could do something similar here as well.
Like, maybe say true.
Message Dot contains.
You got it.
And then we can say for a message here should indicate that.
We got the right number.
And then maybe we don't need this last one, right?
So let's just run this by itself.
All right, so of course, that passes.
Now let's break it on purpose here so that we can see what this world would look like.
You don't got it.
All right.
And then let's run that.
So now we see that the expected assertion was true, but the actual was false.
And now it's telling us that we should have gotten indication and indication of three tries.
All right now, because this first assertion failed.
We don't even get to see the next assertion yet.
OK.
And so one of the nice things about supplying this message is that it helps you to pinpoint which assertion
actually failed when you have multiple assertions.
You get that.
So if we didn't have this message here, it would be less clear immediately which of these assertions
was failing.
So if we fix this one and then rerun, OK, now we see that the second assertion fails and we get that
message as well should indicate that we got the right number right.
So that's how you can pinpoint which assertion is actually failing.
But if one assertion fails within a test method, the subsequent assertions won't even run OK.
It'll just stop on the one that's failing.
So I would say definitely if you have more than one assertion in a test method which you should generally
be conservative about doing.
But if you are inclined to do it and I do do it occasionally, there's some cases where it feels like
the right thing to do.
This isn't really one of them, by the way.
I'm just showing you this as an example.
But if you are going to have multiple assertions and a test method, definitely, definitely.
You should include a message so that it can help you to pinpoint which of the assertions is actually
failing.
All right.
So you have now learned, I think enough about test driven development to go forth and conquer and write
at least simple implementations of code with decent little tests.
Now there's a lot more that can be done with writing tests, and we will likely engage in a few more
scenarios as we learn more advanced techniques not just with testing, but with writing code in general.
There's a whole other world, in fact, of writing code that can be tested.
But we'll get there in time.
So I hope this will serve you very, very well.
You will be well ahead of many people in the job market.
If you've really put the time and effort in on this module.
So with that, I will close this out and I will see you in the next one.