All right, so here we are back in the main class and, you know, in the last lesson, we did a nice
job of simplifying each of the cases of our switch, reducing them down to about three lines of code
or so.
And so that's pretty nice.
But I think we can do even more still.
Now, one thing we often want to look out for as professional programmers is duplicated.
Code duplicated code is often not a great thing because if we need to make changes to the underlying
structure of the code, there's a good chance that those changes will have to be duplicated also, and
all the same places wherever we have the duplicated code.
Whereas if we just had that duplication minimized down to hopefully just one instance of whatever the
duplicated thing was, then you'd only have the one place to go to make your changes.
And so with that in mind, as I look at these case statements, I still see a little bit of duplication
here.
We're following the same basic pattern.
We create a new whatever employee type, right?
And then we call the two string method of that employee.
And then we also call get salary of that employee.
So the question becomes, is there a way for us to reduce this duplication a little further?
And obviously the answer is yes.
Now there are actually multiple ways in which to do this, but the first way I'm going to show you is
something that we have not discussed at all, and it's an incredibly important and powerful concept
that is the concept of interfaces.
So we're going to learn about interfaces.
So the first thing is, well, what is an interface?
So let me take a quick, high level stab at trying to give you a basic definition that may or may not
be all that helpful until you see some code.
So interfaces are very much related to classes.
They are almost like hollowed out skeletons of a class.
In fact, interfaces traditionally describe some or all of the public methods of a class.
OK.
So one of the primary purposes of an interface is kind of to almost hide or abstract away the details
of one or more classes so you can have one or more classes that all have a relationship to an interface.
And generally speaking, when a class has a relationship to an interface, that class is said to implement
that interface, OK?
So you can have one or more classes that implement an interface so that when other code wants to use
those classes, that code doesn't necessarily have to know specifically what classes they are.
That code can just know about their interface.
OK, so it gives you an abstraction.
Maybe one way to think of an interface might be if you think of the electrical outlets in your home
where you plug in power cords and things right into the wall of your home, the outlet with the holes
or whatever, depending on what country you're in.
The outlet itself is an interface.
It interfaces your devices that you want to plug in to the electricity that your house is carrying.
OK.
And it gives a standard way to interface with that house electricity the little plug socket itself being
the interface, OK?
It also serves to abstract away some of the complexity of interacting with the electricity because you
certainly could just have the bare wires that are behind that outlet exposed and someone come along
and splice the wires together.
But that would be a level of implementation detail that most people would not want to get into.
All right.
So enough talk about interfaces.
Let's see how we can use an interface to help us to reduce some of the duplication that we have here.
OK.
So here's the thing.
Each of these employee classes that we have here are already implementing two of the exact same methods
that we call.
We're calling two string, which actually, in this case, all classes have a two string method that
can be overridden, and they all implement a get salary method.
Obviously, that's by design, but it actually makes good sense here, right?
Because that is a trait that all of these different types of employees have in common anyway, right?
So when you identify methods that can be in common between multiple classes, that can be a sign that
you could abstract those classes behind and.
Interface.
OK.
So let's see what that might look like.
So let's see if we can further reduce the lines that we have in these cases, and to do so, we might
even change the way we're using the switch.
What I'm what I have in mind here is instead of the switch returning the salary from each case, which
we're doing here with the yield, perhaps we'll just create an instance of a class and then collect
that class at the end of each of these case statements and then just get the salary one time.
So in other words, just call it get salary once instead of for each of these types.
If that's not making sense to you yet, don't worry, it will.
So let's see how we can do this.
So the first thing we need to do is to introduce an interface, and we do that very similarly as we
would create a class.
So I'm going to open up the project pane and let's see here.
I'm going to select our package and right click on it and and choose new Java class again.
However, this time we're not going to make the new class.
We're going to make an interface.
I'm clicking on interface now.
All right.
Now, I need a name for this interface, and for right now, I think the most logical name that I can
come up with.
It needs to be a name like you would name a class, but it needs to be a name that makes sense for all
of the different classes that you plan to hide behind this interface.
So we've got programmer analyst, CEO manager, right?
What would be a good word or a good name that would describe more generically all of those types?
Well, for right now, I think one potentially good name could be employee.
Right?
These are all employees of a company or worker worker could work as well.
Something like that.
So we're looking for a word that just describes more generally what all of these types of roles have
in common.
OK.
All right.
So I'm going to go for employee for right now.
So we're going to create an interface and call it employee.
All right.
Now we want to define the methods that all employees should have in common.
OK.
And there's really just one in this particular case and that method.
So if we go back over to the main class here, that method is get salary.
Now you might be wondering, well, we also have the two string method and they the they all have that
in common and that is true.
They do, however, be mindful of the fact that the two string method is actually being inherited and
overridden from the super super class of object, right?
And so all of these classes share the two string method in common with each other from the object super
class.
And so we're not going to define the two string method on the interface because it's already in common
to all of these classes.
OK.
All right.
So you need to get the get salary method on to the interface.
So there are actually a couple of ways to get a get salaried method on to the employee class.
So one thing we can do is to just jump into any one of these new classes that we created programmer,
manager, CEO or analyst.
I'll jump into the programmer class here, and I'm just going to copy this method here minus the curly
brace.
OK, and I'll do a command.
See, then jump over to employee.
Shift enter.
And then I'm going to paste.
And then put a semicolon now, not a curly brace, but a semicolon now, because an interface defines
all of the public methods that you might want a class to implement.
We don't need the public keyword.
It's not wrong if we have it there, but we don't need it because by default, any methods that are
defined on an interface are understood to be public.
OK, so I'm going to just remove the public key word here because it's superfluous at this point.
Now why the semicolon?
Well, because the general purpose of an interface is to simply describe what methods should be implemented
in classes of this interface.
Okay, so it's just a description for the most part.
Now, in the latest versions of Java, they have actually expanded what we can do with an interface
to the point that we actually can provide implementation details and by implementation details.
I mean, you know, curly brace and then like, do stuff, you know, write code in here, that would
be an implementation detail.
We actually can do that under certain circumstances in interfaces, but that's a really new capability.
And and it's intended mostly for a very specific set of circumstances that we don't necessarily have
right now.
So we won't be getting into that right now.
But the historical and standard use of an interface is simply to say, Hey, if you're an employee,
you're capable of giving a salary, OK, that's what this method would do.
All right.
Now how we give the salary that's going to be left as an implementation detail of the individual classes
that implement this interface.
And so we're not getting into that here.
OK, now I will make it a little more clear as to exactly why we do it in this way, if it's not clear
yet, but right now, this is all we need on the employee interface.
Now, the next thing we need to do, though, is we need to expand the definition of our employee classes
to tell Java that these classes will now be implementing the employee interface.
And so if we jump over to programmer, for example, and go up to the top.
On this line, public class programmer, if we put our cursor after the word programmer, we can now
type all lowercase implements space capital employee.
Space, just like that.
So now that is telling Java that this class not only is a programmer, but it is essentially a type
of employee.
OK.
That's kind of what we're saying, kind of.
All right.
Now this is different.
We have seen in earlier modules where I introduced you to some of the object oriented concepts of classes
and super classes and hierarchies and extensions and things of that sort.
Right.
This is related, but not quite the same thing.
OK, because this employee doesn't actually implement any actual code, right?
It's more like just a while.
It's just an interface.
It's just a template, if you will, that says employees have the ability to give their salary information.
All right.
So now we just want to do this same thing on the other employee class type.
So I'm going to copy this and implements employee and I'm going to jump over to manager.
And I'm going to put my cursor right there and paste.
And I'm going to do the same thing on CEO.
Jump up to the top.
Put my cursor right there.
Paste space and do the same thing for analyst as well, put my cursor right there.
Space are paced and space.
There we go.
OK.
So other than just pasting the implements employee onto each of these classes, I really haven't made
any other changes.
OK, now jumping back over to the main class, though, now here this class is using all of these different
types of employees now.
And so now we can start to make some changes here.
That might be kind of interesting.
So let's see here.
First, let's make a little space again.
So I think one of the first things I'm thinking of doing here is to change what the Switch statement
is returning.
So currently, the Switch statement is returning the actual salary.
I'm now thinking of having the Switch statement simply return whatever new employee type we are creating.
OK.
That's what I wanted to do.
Just return the employee type.
But if I return that type, I may want to hold it in a variable.
Now, the reason we currently are creating the employee type and then holding it in a local variable
local to the case is because in order to be able to reference the object that we're creating here twice,
like on this line and then on this line, we need we need a variable right to refer to to to make these
two different calls.
And that variable.
Up until now had to be of whatever the type is that we just created.
Okay, so if you're instantiating a programmer, then you have to create a variable of type programmer.
But now that we have an interface, we no longer have that necessity.
We can now do something pretty cool, which is we can store a reference to each of these types in a
variable of type employee.
Let me show you what that looks like, so I can actually just select each of these.
I'm going to select programmer, and in fact, I'm going to use my.
Option shift here, and I'm going to select the programmer here, and I'm going to select the manager
here by double clicking, so I'm holding down an option shift while I double click and I'm going to
select the analyst and I'm going to select the CEO.
OK, I've selected all of these, all at the same time.
And now I can actually refer to them all as type employee like so and then I will hit return and that's
going to.
Complete that and look at what happened there.
No errors.
Now, I could not have done that if these classes were not implementing the interface called employee.
All right.
Now that didn't really buy me anything yet, but it's about two in just a moment here.
So I did that mostly just to show you that I can now refer to each of these instances as an employee.
And because the employee interface defines a get salary method on it, I'm able to call get salary.
OK, now, if I didn't have a get salary method defined on employee, I couldn't do this and let me
prove that to you real quick.
So if I jump into the employee interface and I temporarily comment out that definition there, that
declaration there.
And I jump back over to the main class.
Now we get red marks for each of these calls, because this analyst is not known in this code as something
of type analyst, which has he gets salary method on it.
This analyst is known as something of type employee, and currently the employee interface does not
have a get salary method on it.
OK.
Is that making sense?
All right.
So now I will jump back over to the employee interface and I will uncomment the get salary method and
then I will jump back over to main again.
And now these methods are good.
OK, so even though the analyst class had a get salary method on it, this analyst variable is only
seen as an employee currently in this code, and the employee class didn't have the get salary method
on it when we commented it out.
OK.
So you could almost think of it as this interface is almost kind of masking all of the methods that
may actually exist on a given class.
If those methods aren't defined on the interface, then any variable whose type is that interface won't
expose all of the other methods that may exist on the underlying class.
OK, so it's kind of masking them, if you will, or at least it can.
So let's see what changes we can make here.
So what I want to do now is to actually just return the instance rather than the salary itself.
So we're going to make a couple of changes here.
One change I want to make is let's make a new line right here at the switch and let's let's prepare
for the switch to simply return the instance as an employee.
OK.
So let's see here.
What we can do is let's create another variable here of type employee and we'll just call it employee
and we'll set it to null initially, which means it hasn't been instantiated yet.
All right, then, for this switch here, what we'll do is we'll simply say employee equals like so
and I would like to an indent that also.
All right.
And then this total salaries bit here.
I'm going to delete it for now.
All right now, our yield statement is wrong, right?
So we can actually simplify what's in these case statements now to the point that we don't even need
the curly brace anymore.
The curly brace here.
This code block is here because we have multiple lines of code that we're doing.
But now all we need to do is just return a new instance of an employee.
And so what I think we can do is I'm going to copy this line here, then I'm going to select this entire
code block and I'm going to simply paste.
Like so.
And then I'm going to do the same thing here.
Copy all of that.
Then select this whole entire code block and then paste.
And same thing again.
Copy all of this.
Select the code block and paste books, and I missed the semicolon there.
All right.
And then for this last one?
Same deal.
Copy all of that, then paste.
All right.
So look what we have here, it's getting getting smaller and smaller, right?
All right now, we've got to figure out what we want to do with the default for right now.
I don't want to think about it too much.
So it needs to return something that can represent an object.
What I'm inclined to do for right now is just to return null.
OK, yes.
So looks like it's OK with that will need to be a little careful with that decision, though, in the
future.
But for right now, it makes all the errors go away and we don't have to deal with exactly the thinking
along these lines right now.
Now we're not actually calculating anything anymore, though, so we need to bring back the actual calculations.
So what we can do now is outside of our switch, which would be right here, we can still call the two
string and then get salary method, but now we only need to call them one time each instead of for each
of these types.
Watch this So we can call system that out dot employee, which is what we're capturing from any one
of these dot to string.
And then we can also call total salaries.
Plus equals.
Employees get salary.
Look at that.
Does that make sense?
And the reason we can do all of this now is because even though each of these is a different class,
they all implement the same employee interface, which defines a get salary method on it.
And that's primarily all we actually care about anyway as we get salary method.
So this code here doesn't even need to care about the distinction of a programmer or a manager or an
analyst or a CEO.
This code here only cares about two things.
It knows that all class objects have a two string method, so it's going to call that, and it knows
that all employees have a get salary method, and that's the only thing it needs to care about.
OK.
And so these details of what the underlying classes are unimportant to this code here, and that allows
us to abstract those details away and just get right down to the part that we actually care about,
which is the get salary.
So now let me prove it, and let's run this and make sure we're we're still getting 8.6 million or so.
All right, so.
Hey, looking good.
Look at that.
No difference in the output and still getting 8.6 million, and we just made our code even shorter than
it had been before, and we didn't have to do very much to get this nice benefit either.
Now this default case here is a little problematic.
If we were to add another line in here or if we had a typo, for example on one of the rolls here,
then it would not match any of these cases and it would come down to the default, which currently is
null.
And as soon as we tried to call to string on a null object, we'd get a null pointer exception.
OK, we'd get an exception because that can't be null.
So in real life, this wouldn't be quite good enough.
This would not be very robust code.
Now, a couple of things that we could do about that circumstance.
We could define one more class, which is kind of like an empty employee class, and that could be like
our default, right?
Like we could say new nobody employee or something, something along those lines.
And when you call, get salary on that class, it could just return zero.
You know, we could do something like that.
I will leave that as an exercise for you.
But basically, you know, you just create another class.
You'd call it whatever.
You'd make this new class, implement the employee interface, which would then force you to also implement
the get salary method.
And then in that get salary method, you could just return zero.
So it would be pretty trivial thing to do.
Yeah.
So like I said, I'll leave that as an exercise for you.
OK, so I think we're going to wrap up this lesson.
We have accomplished a good deal now.
So you've been introduced to interfaces.
We'll just take another quick look at the interface.
So it looks a lot like a class, except instead of the word class, we use the word interface all lowercase
than the name of the interface, which again follows the same naming conventions as classes and inhumane.
And then we can define methods in it.
We don't need to be explicit about the visibility for the most part, because by default, any methods
that we declare in an interface are presumed to be public.
That's kind of the whole point of an interface is to say, Hey, this is the the public interface of
of this class or these classes.
All right.
We give it the method name, but we don't supply an implementation of the method.
So we just put a semicolon there.
OK, so all we're really saying to code like this code here is objects of type employee have a get salary
method on them.
OK.
We're saying things like that.
Let's see.
We can have lots of methods on an interface, by the way.
I'm only showing one here, but you can have as many as you need.
However, for every method that you define on an interface, all of the classes that implement that
interface must also implement those methods if it is a concrete class.
Now we're going to learn in the future about things like abstract classes and in an abstract class.
Abstract classes don't have to implement the methods of an interface, so we will take a look at that.
So I'll try to remember to make sure to show you what that looks like.
But regular classes like these that we have created here, if they implement an interface, then they
must implement the methods of that interface.
Also, classes can implement multiple interfaces.
So if I had other interfaces, in fact, maybe yeah, if I had other interfaces here, I could actually
have a comma delimited list and mention, you know, other interfaces, interface one, an interface
two and so on and so forth.
And all of the methods that would be declared on these interfaces would have to be implemented in this
class.
What's cool about that is that I could then refer to instances of this class by any of these interfaces.
Now, if I were to refer to this class by one of these other interfaces, I'd only be able to access
the methods that are defined on that interface.
So if I created an instance of a programmer and stored it in a variable of type interface two, I would
not then be able to call the employee died get salary method because I was referring to it as an interface,
too, and not as an employee.
OK.
So again, we'll take a look at what some of these other scenarios look like in the near future.
All right.
So before I wrap this up, I want to take one more quick stab at giving you a really simple summarization
of what interfaces are for.
And here we go.
So if you have multiple classes that are not related to each other, in other words, they don't all
inherit from the same parent class.
You know, they they're just completely separate classes.
But they do all implement some version of the same function or functionality.
Like in our case with these classes here, the programmer manager, a CEO and analyst, all are capable
of calculating a salary, right?
But they're not related to each other.
They just happen to all have this ability to calculate a salary.
You can make those classes all look like they are the same type by slapping an interface on top of them,
so to speak, or by making them all quote unquote, implement that interface.
And that way, other code, such as the main class, can think that they are all the same type and and
thus make it really easy for the main class or some other class to interact with all of these other
classes, even though they're not actually related to each other.
So that's the that's the gist right there.
You want to make a bunch of different unrelated classes look like they are the same type.
All right.
This is just an initial look at what we can do with interfaces and the fact that they even exist.
So I'm going to wrap this up and I will see you in the next one.