Hey, and welcome back.
So in this lesson, we're going to talk about getters and setters, what are those?
So if we jump into our person class, we have some getters and setters that we generated that we allowed
the idea to generate for us when we created this class.
I'm going to point out which ones they are.
So we've got.
This method here get first name, which returns first name, set, first name, which takes an input
of a first name string and then sets that inside of the field here.
So we've got these getters and setters for the first name, the last name and the date of birth.
Why do we have these at all?
Because actually in this program so far, we're not even using them.
So that's what we're going to talk about.
There is a strong convention in Java that when we have fields like this, we often want to make that
information private.
OK.
First of all, because we want to, by default, protect our internal data of a class.
But we may need to allow some of that data to be accessed from outside and the way that we typically
will do that.
There are a couple of ways that we can do that.
But the way that is most standard is to expose access to this data via getter and setter methods.
Now we could make these public.
And then code from outside of this class could directly read or access, read and write this data.
But that is considered a bad pattern to do.
And I'll explain a little bit more of why in just a moment.
OK, so the default standard way of writing classes is that if if our class is going to have any fields.
We will typically let those fields be private or protected or package protected, but the default would
be to make them private, to protect them and then to expose them via getters and setters.
Now you may be wondering, well, if you're just going to make them private, but then turn around and
expose them via getters and setters, and you're going to automatically make a getter an asset or something
that can get the data and then something that can set the data back.
You're no longer protecting the data, and to a large degree, you would be right.
You're not.
However, by using getters and setters, we have the opportunity to do a level of protection if we want
to.
And the person who is calling me getter and setter doesn't need to know if we are doing any protections
or changing of the data at all.
Whereas if we did not use getters and setters and we just allowed external code to directly access these
fields, well, now we never have an opportunity to to put any good protections or ability to change
any of that data coming in or coming out at all, like you have no opportunity to do that any more.
So by putting getters and setters in front of, if you will, in front of these fields, it gives us
the future-proof ability to protect our access to that data later down the road if we want or need to,
or to even be able to translate or change in some way that data.
So let's look at what I mean here.
So what we can do is we can will write a little bit more code.
That's going to use the person class and we'll do that by going over to the Hello world class.
OK, so I'm going to go over here to this line where we created a person called Johnny, and I'm going
to create a new line here and we're going to print out Johnny's first name.
Let's start with that and we'll do that.
Now I'm going to use a slightly different method this time before I used print line.
This time I'm going to use format.
And let's see, we'll say.
The person's first name is.
And then we will plug in.
Well, we'll call the gutter for the first name, get first name just like that.
OK, now what this is meant to do is it should print the the text the person's first name is, but it
won't print this percent S. That is a format string and that is a it's a symbol basically that tells
this method.
Take.
Whatever arguments I pass in at the end of this method, which is here and plug those argument values
into any places in this string where I have percent signs in this case, I have a percent less, which
means expect a string.
So the get name method returns a string.
And so this would be an index card with the first name of this person written on it.
So take that name and plug that in wherever you see.
Well, in this place here where we see the percent s OK?
And that's just a nice way of formatting a string.
Conveniently, this approach, by the way, incidentally, comes to us from the C programming language
C as a function that does pretty much exactly this, and it uses the same symbol and everything.
So the creators of Java said, Hey, it was good enough for C back in 1970.
It's good enough for us now.
It's a very venerable capability in C.
It's not called format, but it works pretty much identically as far as the format string goes.
OK.
So let's go ahead and run this and see what we get.
So I'm going to do a control shifter or control shift of 10 for Windows and Linux.
OK?
The person's first name is Johnny.
So that worked.
Now, let's say, whenever we get a first name of a person, we want that first name to be capitalized.
OK, so here, let's do this.
In fact, I'm going to go over here where we created the first name, and I'm going to replace that
Jay with a lowercase j.
And I'll do the same for the last name, too, even though we're not working with the last name right
now.
OK.
So if I run this again, OK, the person's first name is Johnny, and now I have a lowercase j.
Now, typically in computer systems and record keeping, we want names to be capitalized.
So what if you know the person who created this code here forgot to capitalize that name for some reason,
right?
So we could protect ourselves from that a little bit.
So I'm going to command click on this method here to jump back over to that method.
And now we're about to see a little bit of the power of using getters and setters, because getters
and setters not only allow us to simply access the data that we're interested in.
And not only do they allow us to protect access to that data, they also can allow us to translate that
data to make it more friendly to the outside world and in this case, I mean, outside of this class.
So within this class, at this point, the first name field has the word, Yeah, I'll put it here.
Johnny, in lower case, OK?
But when we ask to get the first name out of this person object, we don't want that name to be lowercase.
We want to make sure it's always capitalized.
So how can we do that?
Well, we could have this get first name method to translate whatever name we have inside of that field.
We can have it capitalize it for us.
And there's a method that we can use to do that.
Strings are objects string as a class.
And when we work with strings, we have objects and therefore we have methods that were built into the
string class.
We didn't write that string class that comes as part of the Java language.
So the way to capitalize just the first letter of that name is a little bit involved with the way that
we're writing this code.
So the purpose here isn't for you to become an expert at how to capitalize, and I can show you easier
ways to do this in subsequent lessons.
The purpose here is simply to show that we can actually make these getters and setters do useful things
for us.
OK, so what we want to do is we want to grab first just the first letter of the first name field,
which in this case would be Johnny.
So we want to grab the J of Johnny, the first letter in there so we can do that by grabbing what's
called a sub string.
And we want the first letter.
So in a lot of programming, whenever you're talking about first, second, third and you're trying
to grab an index of something typically in most programming languages, the first other thing is usually
going to be zero.
If you have to refer to it by a number and index number, it'll be zero.
That is to say that many methods in many programming languages, many methods and functions are zero
based and arrays as well.
Lists of things.
So anyway, so we will say we want the zero with character in this string, which would be the the J-
in Jerry.
And we also want to tell it that we only want to go as long as one string.
So we're just saying start with the very first letter in this string and only give me one of one letter,
which would be the J.
OK.
So there's the J.
And then we want to take that and we want to uppercase it just like that.
And then we want to add on the rest of the string, minus the first character, so to do that, we can
append and we can do that in a few ways.
But for now, we'll just use a plus sign.
So when you're dealing with strings or text, the plus sign allows you to take some text here and and
tack on some more text onto it with the plus.
OK.
And so now we will basically do this again.
We'll say first name dot substring, but this time we won't start on the zero with.
We'll start on the number one index, which would be the second character.
OK.
Don't worry if this doesn't make sense to you right now, we will spend time to dig into this and we'll
make sure that it makes sense.
OK?
And that is all I need now.
Notice here.
I'm not even specifying a second value to say how long.
If I if I leave that out, it'll just grab all of the rest of the string, which is exactly what I want
to anyway.
OK, so this first part here grabs the J and then uppercase, is it?
And then this part grabs the E and Jerry all the way to the end of the word Jerry and leaves it alone.
OK, so it just strips off the J because we don't want that there now.
OK, so then if we jump back over to the hello world and run it again, now we should get a capital,
J.
In Johnny.
Look at that, and we do the person's first name is Johnny.
So here we have managed to write a letter that is translating the first name from one format to a more
desirable format by capitalizing that Jay.
OK.
And we could go the other way as well.
So let's see here we could.
Let's.
Just for thoroughness.
Let's go back over here to the get first name.
I'll tell you what.
Well, we'll do it with the with the last name here.
Let's see here.
So I'm back over in the hello world.
And yeah, OK.
So we set the last name to Smith, right?
So this time, let's be a little inconsistent, though instead of writing a getter for the last name
that translates it into capitalized name.
Let's translate it into a capitalized name with a setter in.
OK, so first, let's prove that the last name is lowercase and I'm going to just duplicate line 10,
and I did that by doing a command or on Windows and Linux, a control D. So I duplicated the line 10
and then I'm going to just change this to last name is and then I'm going to call get last name.
Here we go.
All right, and so let's run that and we should see that Smith is going to be lower case in our output.
Oh, let's see, let's all say, well, that's OK.
The person's first name is Johnny.
The person's last name is Smith, and that's lowercase, and that's not what we want.
OK.
So this time the way we're going to fix that is I'm going to put a line in the middle here and we're
going to call the center.
So here we're calling the getter, get first name, get last name, but we can call the setter also.
So we'll call Johnny that set last name to Smith.
OK.
And now if we run this.
Now we get a capital s.
OK.
So even though at the time that we created the person with our constructor and we passed in a lowercase
Smith, even though we did that, we have an opportunity to change it using the center.
OK.
Now we could make this better smart the way that we made to get her smart so we could make this lower
case, which wouldn't bias anything over what we already have here, but just to be consistent, I guess,
or to show a few other little tricks, I guess.
So if we do this, I'm not going to bother to run this, but obviously it would print with a lowercase
s.
So let's make let's change our setter now so that when we're passing information in to it, it translates
and we'll have it capitalize the pretty much the same way that we did before.
OK, so what we can do here is a variation of what we did in the letter.
So we'll take this last name here, which is right here.
By the way, the reason that we have the word this not last name here and not here is because in a method
of a class when you pretend a variable or a method with the word this, then you are referring to a
field or a method that is.
Part of that class, as opposed to this first name, which is you can think of as a field that came
from outside of the class, so there's the data that's coming from outside of the class and then there's
data that is internal to the class if it's internal to the class.
We can differentiate it with the word this and by the way, the word this here is not always necessary,
but in this case it is because there would be ambiguity as to which first name we were referring to.
Sometimes you'll see developers just slightly change the name of the field there to avoid any ambiguity.
They sometimes you'll even see that they might name the internal field with an underscore.
For example, I personally am not a fan of doing that because I think the more symbols we use like underscores
and things, I just find that in a more advanced application, seeing a lot of underscores and weird
symbols all over the place just makes my head hurt a little bit.
It makes me have to do a little extra work to parse and understand what I'm looking at.
So I prefer I personally prefer not to do it that way.
And there are a number of coding standards for various language where that is actually frowned upon
anyway.
I think for similar reasons and sometimes under scores and things are reserved symbols for internal
coding and things like that anyway.
All right, so let's translate this first name, so we're going to do pretty much exactly what we did
before, so we're going to grab a substring.
We're going to grab the zero with and we only want one character from there.
And then we're going to uppercase that and then we're going to spend the rest of that.
Oh, oh, wait, I'm sorry, I'm on the wrong one, the wrong center.
We're meant to be doing this on the last name filled, aren't we?
Sorry about that.
All right.
So last name dot substring, get the zero with instance are the zero with character, and we only want
one character from one character.
And then we will uppercase that, and then we will append the rest of the string.
So we will grab the last name again and do another substring.
But this time we will start with the second character, which would be one because the first character
is zero.
So we will start with the second character, which is one.
And then if we don't specify the range, it will assume that we want all of the rest of the string,
which is exactly what we want in this case, and that should be all we need there.
And so then if we jump back over to our hello world, let's see.
And yeah, we're calling set last name with a lowercase S..
Let's go ahead and run this.
And very good.
Yeah.
So we're getting a capital s now for Smith.
So I recognize this could be a little confusing because there are so many ways that we could have done
this right.
We could have done it in the setter.
We could have done it in the we also could have done it in the constructor.
By the way, I didn't even show that when we talked about constructors before.
Let's just jump over here real quick.
So yeah, I mean what we could have said, hey, whenever any data is passed in while we're building
this class, go ahead and just make sure that the first name and last name are uppercase.
Right?
So we could have done all of this here on both the first name and the last name to protect any data
coming in right off the bat.
We could have done that as well.
There are a lot of places where you could you could do this.
But like I said, the basic thing, though, is that getters and setters allow us to protect our data,
our fields that normally should be protected.
And I say that word in the general sense, not in the Java keyword since private or protected or whatever,
and also give us an opportunity to translate the data.
Let me also show you now if I were to make the date of birth field, I'm just picking another field
that we haven't played with much if I were to make this field public.
Like this that won't adversely affect anything in the code.
OK.
But by making it public, I just want to show that I could access that field without using a getter
or a setter now.
So I could say something like Johnny Dot.
Date of birth equals local date of 1969 comma, some random month and some random day.
Perfectly valid for me to do that, but not a good idea, because now what's happening is.
Code that is outside of Johnny, which that means, you know, in this hello world class is directly
manipulating internal data of the Johnny object.
OK.
And there's no code inside of the Johnny object that gets an opportunity to police what I'm setting
here and make sure that it's valid and it's good.
And all of that, because that's just wide open in public.
Any code anywhere could just come in here and manipulate that.
Now, granted, I will say again, changing this vote getter and setter in most cases usually isn't
much better.
But if we realized after we created a veteran setter that just was allowing us to just blindly change
things, if we realized later on that that was not right, we could go into that gutter or center and
change that code and code that calls the getter and setter doesn't even have to know that anything changed.
OK, but here, since we're directly accessing the date of birth, if if we find that this is allowing
a bug.
And we want to safeguard ourselves from it.
There wouldn't be the easiest way to change that.
We'd probably have to go find all the places in the code where where there's code that's calling Johnny
that Dobby or whatever that Dobby.
And we'd have to change that somehow probably make it start using a sweater instead of directly accessing
that.
And that's a little bit bigger of a change of a refactoring, if you will.
So it's kind of better to just make sure that all of your external code, all of your external classes,
if they need to access data within a class or an object, they should do it via a getter and setter.
OK.
All right, I think that's we've probably beat this horse to death.
So I think that's about enough for this lesson.
Join me in the next one and we'll go deep on something else.
See in the next one.