All right, so before we bring this module to a complete close, I think it's important that we actually
take what we've done in this module and put it all back together again as a as an actual working program.
So all we've seen so far is that we've been able to flesh out a new implementation of the guessing game
engine, the logic behind the guessing game using a TDD approach with unit tests.
However, we don't actually have like a workable, usable program that someone who's not a programmer
could actually use right at the end of the day.
That should still kind of be the real point.
So I thought that in this one last lesson, we'd just put this all back together again so that we can
interact with it from a user interface, which in this case will end up just being the command line
again.
Now, I had considered implementing the user interface in a separate class, but for right now, I still
want to just put this in the same class, but it will be in its own separate method.
OK, so let's let's just see what this might look like.
So we're back in the ADC here and now I'm in the actual guessing game class itself, and I think we're
done with the unit test, no more unit tests and we fleshed out everything that I think we needed to
with the unit tests and now we can just use what we have created here.
So I'm going to start off by creating a public static void main method.
And let's see here now with this implementation, we're actually making a class that maintains state.
And if you may recall, that just means that it can remember stuff.
And the way that it remembers things is with these two variables here, these two fields, these fields
are the state of the class.
And again, state really just means like the parts that can remember something, right, that store
information.
OK.
And so because this class maintains state or can store information, if we want to use it in our final
application, we will have to create an actual instance of the guessing game.
So I think that's the first thing we're going to do down here.
We're going to make a variable, a local variable that will be an instance of the guessing game.
So we'll reference it here and we can just call it game and we'll say new guessing game just like that.
All right.
So let's ease into this a little bit.
I guess let's start off by just asking a user to guess the number.
So let's see.
We can do that by calling system dot console Red Line and say something like, uh, enter a number and
then we can capture the output of that with a command option V.
And I don't know this for now.
I'm just going to call it input and then I think we need to do from this point is called Game Dot.
Guess now we'll need to convert this input, which is the string into a number.
Now I'm going to take a little bit of a shortcut here, and I'm going to do it all in one, all in one
fell swoop.
So I'm going to I know that the number that I want is needs to be an integer, so I need to convert
the string to an integer.
So I will use the integer wrapper class dot pass int and then I will pass in the input like.
So and then that's going to return some output, which for now, I guess I'm just going to call output.
Now this output could contain a number of different strings, right?
It could say something like you got it in one try in this case and then the game should be over.
Or it could say you didn't get it and you're either too low or too high, right?
So maybe what we want to do now is to set up a loop, and I think that loop maybe can start with just
taking this input here.
So let's see what this would look like if maybe we do a do while loop because I know we want to do this
bit at least the one time right?
And that's what to do.
While Loop is four.
So we can say do and then let's indent these two lines do some stuff while and now the question is,
how do we know when to end this loop?
Well, maybe what we can do is just define a variable, maybe inside of the loop and that variable will.
Help us to determine when we should stop.
So maybe we'll say while Loop should continue.
Now we haven't actually defined this yet, so I will define it here.
Luke should continue.
All right, so I'm I'm declaring that loop here, and we're going to set it using some conditional logic.
OK, so what are the circumstances where this loop should not continue?
One would be if the output contains the words, you got it, then you're done right?
So let's let's just let's see what that would look like.
If output that contains.
You got it, then loop should continue equals false.
All right, so that's one situation.
Oh, and I apologize.
Actually, I apologize.
Actually, we do need to have this loop should continue outside of the loop in order to be in scope
here.
So let's move this.
Yeah, sorry about that.
And maybe we should initialize it to true to start off with.
All right.
What's another circumstance where we should set it to false?
So if the word you got it is there?
Maybe if the words game is over or game over, are there.
So really, maybe we can just look for the word over that might be sufficient.
Now we could combine all of that here, or we could do a another conditional so we could see if output
that contains you got it.
Or output that contains over then set this to false.
We could do it that way.
What else?
Over.
That may pretty much be it.
And then one other rule that we had before was you could hit cue to stop as well.
And I suppose we could just put that right here and say something like if Q Dot equals input, then
we could just end the program immediately.
Now, we may have had a little bit more elegant ending in the previous one where we might have output
it something first and then ended.
But I don't care right now.
All right.
So now let's build this and see what happens.
Now, remember, since we are using the console redlined, we won't be able to run this from here.
We'll have to build it separately and then manually execute the program ourselves.
So we'll do a command f nine to build.
OK, and then option F12 to open a terminal prompt.
All right.
Let's see here.
So now we want to run this guy from the command line, so we'll do Java all lowercase hyphen CP for
Class Path, which again just lets us specify what folder our compiled code is in.
Now we need to be a little careful this time around, though, because we're now using a fully qualified
package name for this class, right?
This.
Com Neutrino Assist game bit.
So here's how we'll do this.
We'll do Java hyphen C.P and currently we are here in this folder.
And so we need to tell Java that our class starts off in this out dot production guessing game.
So we'll do that here with this class path bit.
So we'll say out forward slash production, forward slash guessing game.
All right.
So that's our class path and we stop right there.
The rest of this calm neutrinos cis game, that's the package structure, OK?
And that becomes part of the fully qualified class name itself.
So now the next bit here is the class name.
OK.
And so this is where we have to put in comm dot neutrinos, this dot game dot and then the actual short
name for the class guessing game.
Now how do I know that this part out production guessing game belongs in the class path and then the
rest of the folders come neutrinos.
This game belong as part of the actual class name.
Well, that's defined up here with this package.
So calm neutrinos this game that becomes the, you know, part of the fully qualified class name.
And then we just tack on the actual class itself to the end of that.
OK, so be careful there not to include this calm neutrino CEST game on the end of the class path itself.
OK.
It does not belong there.
It belongs as part of the fully qualified class name.
All right.
So once we have all of that, we can now run this and there's our prompt.
Enter a number.
All right.
First, let's just test out the qubit, the quitting queue to quit.
So let's see what happens here.
All right, cool.
Yeah, that exited out.
Very good.
All right.
Now let's run it again, and let's get the number.
I'm going to start with a five.
Oh oh, and we totally forgot to actually print out the output.
Didn't, didn't, didn't I?
I forgot to print out the output.
So let's jump down here.
Let's see.
So we prompt if the prompt is a cue, then we quit.
Otherwise, we take the output and we need to show the output right there, right?
So let's do that.
So let's just drop a line in here and say, system that out output, and let's just try that and see.
All right.
So let's quit out of the program.
And then we need to rebuild with a command F9.
All right, and then let's rerun it.
OK, I'm going to start with five again.
You didn't get it.
You're too low.
OK, I'll try.
Seven.
Still too low.
OK.
Nine.
Too high.
All right.
So maybe it's an eight.
Hey, there it is.
And we got it in four tries.
So it looks like this is working.
Let's let's try it one more time.
One more game.
All right.
Enter a number.
I'm going to start with five again.
Too low.
OK, I'll do a nine.
Oh, interesting.
Too low.
Is it 10?
Hey, got it in three tries?
You know what?
I kind of want to play this one more time.
I'm kind of having a little fun here.
Enter a number.
I'll do a five again.
Too low.
Nine.
Hey!
Got it in two tries?
All right.
So yeah, this is our game.
And I don't know, is it just me or does it seem like implementing the user interface for the rest of
the game was a little easier this time?
Now, that might be by virtue of the fact that, you know, we've already implemented it once and we
kind of knew what we were doing.
And I wasn't really teaching you much about implementing this because we've already done it before.
Probably that does have a lot to do with it, but it is quite nice to keep the game logic separate from
the user interface logic.
I would say, and we also could have just taken all of this and put it in another class and done the
exact same thing here that it would have worked just the same.
I'm just being slightly lazy in that, you know, we don't absolutely have to do that, but we absolutely
could have.
We could have just put put all of this in another class, compiled the whole thing and then run, run
everything, all all together.
All right.
So I will see you in the next one.