Hey, there, I wanted to take a real quick few moments to revisit one little lesson with regular expressions,
even though we're in the module for control flow, because now, as I mentioned in one of the last lessons
from Regular Expressions module, I would come back and show you one little thing with control flow.
So now that you've learned about loops, we can apply a loop to what we did in one of those last lessons
from Regex.
So if you recall, I know it might seem like it was a million years ago.
But if you recall we had this program where we were creating a list of people in a multi line string
of cartoon characters from The Flintstones to be more precise.
And then we created a Rig X.
But up until that point, all of the regular expressions that we had created were rag axes that were
meant to match an entire string.
But this time we created a Rig X that only matched one pattern, one sub pattern within this string.
So in other words, we have a repeating pattern here.
Last name, comma, first name, comma, date, last name, comma, first name, comma, date, etc.,
etc. right?
And that pattern is repeating.
So we didn't create projects with with this pattern four times, we just created the pattern one time.
Then I showed you how you could use that pattern with the match or Dot find method to find that pattern.
However, often it may exist within a string.
But because we had not yet learned about loops, I didn't show you the last little bit that really makes
this quite powerful.
So I'm going to take off this number.
By the way, that number, if you recall, just tells the match or find method to skip the first 35
characters before it starts trying to find a match.
So let's take that out and just tell it to start at the very beginning of the string.
So now what we can do now that we know how to create loops?
Let's do this.
Let's select all of this, and let's surround it with a loop.
Do you remember how to do that command option T..
And let's surround it with a while loop.
OK.
All right.
Now, instead of hard coding it to true, which would cause it to loop forever, which we don't want,
we will grab this line match dot find.
I'm going to just cut that and then I will delete that line and then I will paste it right over the
truth.
So this find method does two things.
It tells the regular expression engine to take this rejects and go see if you can find a match for it
anywhere in this string, which presumably would work to first find this first line of the string.
OK, and then if it does find a match, which in this case we know it will, it returns a boolean true,
which means that the while loop can keep looping, right?
And so because this fine method returns a boolean true after it has found this last line, the loop
will come back up here again and try to find another match, but it won't find one.
And so the matched find method on the last line after the last line will return a Boolean false and
the loop will end.
OK, so let's jazz this up a little bit, though let's not print all of these things out separately.
Instead, let's use a system out with the print f.
OK, and then let's do a formatted print.
So let's do something like, well, we won't make it too much different than it already is, but we'll
do maybe a first name, last name and then a date of birth.
Let's do that.
And a new line.
OK, so we can do matched group first name matched group.
Last name and match group.
Date of birth like that.
All right.
So if this all works properly, we should get four lines that look almost identical, except the names
will just be flipped.
All right.
Let's run that and see what we get.
Hey, there we go.
Fred Flintstone, here we had Flintstone Fred, Rubble, Barney.
Here we get Barney, rubble, et cetera, et cetera.
So that's really about all I wanted to show you was just the fact that now that we know about loops,
we can use this in the way that it was actually really intended to be used.
So if you recall in the original regex lesson for this, I just called matched up find multiple times,
which you can also do for sure.
But the way that it was mostly intended to be used was inside of a loop, which is why the find method
returns a boolean true or false if it does or does not find a match.
So that way you'd know you'd have a nice way to stop your loop from running, which is also the reason
why I use a while loop here instead of a fork.
Now, of course, I could have used the for loop to write.
In this case, I could have used a for loop because I knew I only have four lines.
But what if I had like 1473 lines?
I'm not going to sit there and count how many lines I have and then make a for loop for that exactly
that number, right?
A while loop would be perfect for that, and a while loop would be more appropriate in that case than
they do while loop.
Because with a do wire loop, you assume that the loop is going to occur at least one time.
But if you don't have a match, then it shouldn't occur at all, right?
So while loop is is probably your best bet.
All right.
That's all I wanted to show you in this lesson and see in the next one.