And next up, we're going to learn about the split method.
This is another method that's incredibly useful from time to time, and you'll see why in just a moment
here.
So basically, what the split method does is it takes a string and it can split that string into an
array.
We did briefly go over what an array is several lessons ago, but basically it is a list or a collection
of items.
Those could be strings or integers or objects or whatever.
It doesn't really matter, but the split method will break apart a string into an array of strings.
Now, the way that it does this is by looking for what's called a delimiter.
And that's just a character or a sub string that typically would repeat itself within the greater string
that we're trying to split up.
Now let me let me take you through a very typical and realistic example of why we might want to do this
and to talk about this, we'll go over to the computer here.
So changing things up a little bit instead of starting off looking in the A.D., I have a spreadsheet
open with excel, and what I have here is a bunch of fictitious people in the spreadsheet with last
name, first name.
Maybe that's a date of birth, a street address, a city and a state.
So as a programmer, a scenario that you may encounter from time to time is that you may find yourself
working with business people.
That is, you know, people within a company who are not programmers.
And one thing that business people seem to really love is working with Excel spreadsheets.
They love Excel spreadsheets because Excel is so flexible, you can do a lot with it.
And one of the things that you'll find business people really love to do is to store data that probably
really belongs in a database, in a spreadsheet because they don't have easy access to work with databases
themselves sometimes.
And so you may find yourself being given Excel spreadsheets and being told here, take this data and
do something magical with it in code.
Maybe take this data from this spreadsheet and then write some code that puts it into a database, like
importing it into a database or or who knows business people have no limits to what to what kinds of
things they like to request us to do with their data.
But as I said, they love working with Excel spreadsheets.
And so this data that I have here could be quite typical of some type of data that a business person
or a company might actually give you.
And you may have a task of loading that data into a database, for example.
And again, a database is just a program that usually runs on a server that is designed to house massive
amounts of data like what we're seeing here.
But instead of like whatever five records, it might be 50 million records or five billion records.
Who knows?
OK, so what I want to show you is kind of a little scenario of how you might possibly work with data
like this.
Now some aspects of what I'm going to show you are not going to be true to life, but it is certainly
based on real life scenarios.
All right.
So let's say a business person gives you a spreadsheet with data like this and your task is to load
it into some Java code so that you can do something with that data.
All right.
So one thing you'll probably need to do first is to save this data in a format that you can actually
work with.
And one of the most common formats to use for something like this, for a task like this is what's called
a CSV file that stands for comma separated values.
And so in Excel, you can go to file save as.
And you can come down here to file format and choose CSP.
OK.
Just like that.
And then you can save that file somewhere.
So I'm going to just save it on my desktop.
All right, so I've saved that file, and now I can open that file in an anthology, so on my Mac,
I can actually just come up here.
There's the file and I can right click on it and I'm actually going to open it up in.
So I can go to other.
And I can find Intel AJ.
And I can open that up now, I actually have this open already, someone to hit cancel here.
All right.
And then so as you can see, what I have here is the last name with a comma than the first name with
a comma than the date of birth comma.
So each of the columns of the spreadsheet is separated by a comma, and that is why this is called a
csb comma separated values.
OK.
So each record, if you want to think of these as records, each record has its individual values separated
by commas.
Each record itself is also separated by a new line character.
In other words, when you get to the end of the line, there's a new line.
Now, new line characters are not visual characters, but they cause a file like this to go to the next
line, OK?
And so that's how each row is being separated by a new line character.
That's an important thing to know.
All right.
So we want to be able to load this data up and pass it basically.
OK.
So I'm going to select all of this and then I'm going to do a Command C or control C to copy that.
And then we'll go over to our trusty text to learning class.
And I already have a public static void main method here from whatever I did previously.
All right.
And so first thing I want to do is I want to make a variable, a string variable that will hold the
text that we just copied.
Now maybe you'll also recall that we learned how to make a variable, a string variable that is a text
block and that is a string that is multiple lines of text instead of the typical one line.
And the way we can do that is to first say what type of variable we want, which is a string.
Then we will give it a name and I'll just call it text for now equals.
And now here's the thing instead of just doing a double quotes, we will use three quotation marks and
that tells Java and the idea that we want to create a text block or a multi line text string.
And now I'm going to make it some space here, and I just to do that.
By the way, I did a option command enter to make a new line above where I was, and I'm going to indent
a couple of times with the tab key and then I can just paste just like that.
So now I've just pasted all that text in and I'm going to go down to this last line and then closed
this statement with a semicolon.
All right, now I'm going to tell you, this isn't typically how a professional programmer would import
this type of data.
They would probably write some code or even use a library that someone else already wrote to just access
the file directly rather than copying and pasting.
But you haven't learned how to do those things yet, and I don't want to overwhelm you with a bunch
of of of all of that stuff.
So we're going to do a kind of the poor man's way and just copy and paste a few records directly into
a string for now.
All right.
So now we've got a string with all of this data, and now we want to be able to parse it and use it
somehow.
All right.
So the first thing we can do here, let's say we just want to be able to count how many records there
are.
OK.
So we could reference this text field and then we could use the split method.
Which is right here and what the split method takes as input is, it wants to know what's called a regular
expression that conveys to the split method where it should split the text or where it should split
the string.
Now we're not going to learn much about regular expressions right now.
We're going to do like the simplest regular expressions there are, which is basically just to use a
string literal as our expression.
But basically, what we want to do right now is we want to tell the split method to split this string
at the end of each line where we go to a new line.
OK.
And so the way we can do that is to create a string literal here.
And then we're going to use a special code that means new line character.
And you can think of this more or less as the end of the line.
OK.
Not quite the same thing, but effectively it's pretty much the same thing.
So there's a special character that means end of the line or new line, and that is again.
That n stands for new line.
OK, so you can't see it here, but there is a character here, which is the new line character.
And that's what we're telling the split method to find.
So we're saying go find a new line character and then split the string.
Every place that you see new line characters into an array of strings.
So what will result is this line will be inside of an array element.
This line will be in another element and so on and so forth.
All right.
And I can close this now.
The split method is going to return an array to us, so we want to capture that array in another variable.
And I can do that easily with option command the four variable or alt command V. for Windows and Linux.
I mean, let me do that one more time, by the way.
So I have my cursor at the end of Line 12 here.
OK.
And then I'm doing option command the.
All right.
And now the aid is wanting me to name this new array variable, and I'm going to name it people.
Because what's coming out of here is.
A representation of a person of a bunch of people, actually.
Now, of course, I could have name that anything.
All right.
And now.
Now that I have an array I can call methods on that array.
And the first thing I want to do is just determine how many people do I have.
And so and maybe I want to print that out so I can do it.
So you T.
And then reference the people array that links.
OK.
And this will just give me a chance to see if if I'm parsing this properly, to even be able to get
that much information, so I'm going to go ahead and run this now.
OK, and I get five.
And let's see one, two, three, four or five, so looks like that's probably working.
All right, cool.
So we just passed this big, huge string into individual rows.
And so that's one thing we can do with Split.
However, there's an even more typical thing that you'll usually see with Split, and that would be
more like splitting out the individual columns of a row.
That's like the most common thing I think you'll typically see.
So let's do that now, so we can do that by splitting out the individual rows.
So we have the individual rows in this people array already.
And if we want to access any one of these rows, we can do that.
Again, I don't know if you'll remember from the brief array lesson that we had, but if you want to
do that, you can access one row or one element of an array with the square brackets symbol just like
this.
So I'm using the square brackets not to be confused by curly braces, right?
Which is different.
We want the square brackets.
Interestingly, the square brackets and the curly braces are on the same keys, though, and then we
supply an index of which row we want or which element we want.
OK.
So if we wanted this string here, just this first row, that would be zero.
This would be one, two, three and four.
So let's take the last one.
Let's take index for George Jetson.
OK, so that would be four.
And that's four because array indexes are zero based.
So the first row is zero zero one two three four is George Jetson.
And so that's what we're referring to here.
So first, let's just print this out.
So I'm going to do an s.
So you t just like this and then hit enter and then I'll just delete a little bit here and put this
inside of the method just like that.
Let's see what this does if I just print out that whole string just like that.
OK, cool.
So we get just that one line of text just as it exists here.
Cool.
Now.
Let's say that we want to access the individual fields of George Jetson, so we could do that the same
way that we split the original text or, well, pretty much the same way so we could reference people.
Curly brace or square bracket four, OK.
And then from here we can do.
So this would return a string and then we can call the split method again on this string by just using
a period split.
And now we need to tell it, Well, what do we want to split it on?
So what we're trying to get here is the individual fields, right?
Each part that is separated by a comma, and because each part is separated by a comma, it is the comma
that we want to use to split on.
We want to split wherever there is a comma.
And so we can do that again by using a string literal so quotes and then just put a comma there just
like that.
So that will return an array of strings, and each element in that array will be each column of data.
In this one row now, again, we'll need to capture that.
So again, with my cursor at the end of this line, 15, I'm going to do an option, command the four
variable.
And then I need to name this variable and I'm going to just call it George.
OK, so I have an array variable called George.
It is an array because they have these square braces, square brackets here.
It is an array of strings, meaning it is an array that holds strings in each element.
OK.
And now let's say that I just want to print out the street address.
So what index is that?
So that would be zero one.
To.
Three index of three.
OK, so if I want to print that out, I can do it.
So you T.
Now I'm going to reference the data that is in this last array, which is here, George.
So, George, then a square brace, and I want zero one to the the index three.
All right.
And so if we run this.
And there we go, we've got 555 M.A. Street.
So now I think you can see that you could randomly extract any field from any row in this data using
the split method plus an array.
And that's one of the things that makes this so powerful.
OK, now soon we will learn how to loop through code so that we could write code that would automatically
just loop through each row and grab columns and do whatever we wanted with them.
So if we needed to put this data into a database, for example, we could write code that would loop
through each row, grab each column, put each row here into a row in a database, one column at a time
or something, something like that.
So there's a lot of powerful things that we could do with these techniques.
OK, one more thing I want to show real quick is that the split method has another variation on it as
well.
So I'm going to put my my cursor there, and I'm going to show.
So this is the version of the split method that we're currently using, but there's a second version
that takes a second parameter and that is a limit.
And all that is is it just allows us to limit how many elements there can be in the array.
I've never personally found a need to use this, but let me just show you real quick.
So here we did a split to split this text out into the rows, and we ended up with five rows because
we didn't limit anything, but I could have told it limit the number of elements that you search for
or in return to three.
OK.
Just like that.
Now this is going to do some weird things.
So let's just see what it does.
I'll run it.
OK, so we ended up with an index out of bounds error.
And the reason we did is because let's see, this says that it happened on Line 14, which is here.
We tried to access the Fifth Element in this array.
However, we limited the array to only having three elements.
And so we exceeded the bounds of this array, which is a no, no, you can't do that.
So one thing we could do here is to just change this array to not exceed the limit.
And I'll do that, by the way.
I'm going to show you another little neat kind of thing that the ADT can do if I want to change this,
for which I have in two places, there's a couple of ways I could do that, but I'm going to put my
cursor right there on that four and then I'm going to put my cursor on this other four while holding
down on option or alt and shift, and I'm going to select this right at the back of this other four.
Now what I have is two cursors at the same time.
And the reason I wanted to cursors both on the same at the end of this four is so that I could edit
them both at the same time so I can hit the backspace key once and delete both of them, some editing
in multiple places in the ad at the same time here.
And then I'm going to put a two instead.
OK.
And then when I'm done editing, I can hit escape.
And now and now things go back to normal.
So that's a nice little capability of the I.D..
All right.
So let's run this again.
I suspect they're still going to be something else a little bit weird, but let's just see.
So we'll run this again.
OK.
Let's see what we got here.
So we got three for the number of rows, which is sort of correct because we limited it.
However, the last row is actually going to be it's going to be zero hour, it's going to be one two.
And then the third row would be actually all of this now.
That's how the limit parameter works.
It doesn't stop here and then just ignore these two.
Instead, it grabs one.
And then to.
And then three, all the rest of it, that's what it does, not the most useful thing in this particular
case.
So beware of that.
And because that's how it behaves.
Let's see here when we told it to print index two, which is the third because it's zero based.
Right?
Zero one two.
When we told it to print two, it printed Flintstone Rubble, Barney Jetson, George, all all of that.
OK?
And then when we split the third element of the people array by commas and then asked it to give us
the fourth element in this array that started here because this is now the third element in people.
And and then breaking this into commas, the fourth element in here would be one to three.
Four, which is what we've got right there.
All right, so that's going to cover it for the split method.
Like I said, this is another extremely useful method that you will encounter from time to time.
Now I will let it be said, I'm just going to reiterate one thing that I think I mentioned already earlier
in real life, if we really wanted to take data from a spreadsheet and get it into our Java code somehow
so that we could manipulate it or work with it, then especially if it's like a lot of rows of data,
not just five, but it could be hundreds or thousands or we have to do it periodically.
We almost certainly wouldn't really want to do it this way.
Instead, we would probably use some third party library code, and that means code that was written
by someone else that they make available for us to use for free usually.
And we'd probably use some other person's code with methods that we can easily utilize to open up that
CSV file and then retrieve the lines of code that way.
But still, what you're seeing here are some of the building blocks of how we could do some at least
simple things on our own.
All right.
So that's going to wrap it up and I will see you in the next one.