All right, so next up on our tour to learn about the various interfaces and classes in the Java Collections
framework, we're going to learn about maps.
So what are maps?
Well, a map is an interface in the overall collections framework, and the concept that a map represents
is basically a table like I've shown before the inner workings of a hash that it's a table that allows
us to associate objects to each other.
Those objects will be in the form of what we generally refer to as a key value pair.
So one object is the key.
The other object is the value, and you use the key to look up the value.
OK, but they're both objects.
So why might we want this functionality?
Well, maps are actually very common in many, many programming circumstances.
Pretty much any time you want to do a simple lookup of some type of data, I mean, think about dictionaries
for for a moment, a dictionary has a key and a value.
The key is typically the word, and then the value will be the definition of the word.
OK, so there's one example of the functionality of a map in programming, though just about any time
we want to associate two pieces of information with each other.
And especially if we have a list of those types of associations, more often than not, a map will be
called for.
For those of you who are a little more knowledgeable about how your computer works, especially if you
work in Windows or Linux, you may be familiar with the concept of environment variables.
Perhaps where you can set these values are variables that may control how programs work or how the computer
itself functions.
Environment variables are another example of key value pairs where you will define a variable and then
it will have some value set for it.
So, for example, frequent one is setting a path variable or something like that.
You'll have a key that is like a name.
In this case, it might be called path.
And then the value will be an actual path to some directories or folders or files or whatever.
Now you may recall from the introduction video for this module that technically speaking, even though
a map interface is considered to be part of the collections framework within Java, unlike list and
set, the map interface does not extend from the collection interface.
However, because it does still store references to collections of objects, it is part of the overall
Java Collections framework.
One other thing I'll note is that the map interface has three most common implementations.
And as luck would have it, those implementations mirror very closely the implementations of the set
interface, so they will be very familiar.
We've got a hash map which uses a hash key just like the set does.
And in fact, if you'll recall, set hash set actually uses a hash map underneath it as its own implementation
anyway.
So there's a hash map, there's a tree map, and it works as you might imagine it would.
So where tree set is able to retain a natural ordering for items in it, a tree map does the same thing
for its entries, and it does it on the keys.
And then finally, there is the linked hash map, which is capable of keeping the entries of the map
and by by the way, entry is just a key value pair the pairing of those, right?
So one row, if you will.
So those are the most common implementations of the map interface.
So without further ado, let's jump in and see how to use them.