All right.
I've got another topic that I want to present to you that is closely associated with automated testing,
and that is the topic of debugging code.
So what is debugging code and how do we do it?
Well, debugging code is basically where we use capabilities of the ADC to allow us to essentially step
through code while it's executing.
And in fact, quite often we will control the pace at which the lines of code are executed so we can
actually stop on each line while the program is executing.
And then we can take the time to inspect values of variables and see what's going on in the program,
kind of like from the perspective of the computer.
So this is a very helpful technique that's been around for decades, really.
And a lot of developers at some point often will choose to use debugging to figure out what's going
wrong with the program or try to understand better.
Why is the program functioning in a way that they didn't think it would?
So that's what we're going to learn next.
OK, so turning to the ADP, we're still in our guessing game, and what I have chosen to do here is
to actually break it just a tiny bit.
I just made one tiny change to it so that we'd have an excuse to play with the debugging capabilities
of the ADP.
Now there are maybe a couple of ways that you might in real life determine that something has gone wrong
in your program one way.
And I would argue this is the less efficient way would be to actually just run the guessing game and
try out all the various scenarios.
But I think by now, you should understand that if you've done particularly TDD to develop the application,
the much quicker way to determine that something is wrong would be to just run all of the tests and
see if anything breaks, right?
So that's what we're going to do.
So I'm going to do a command shift you to jump over to our tests and go up to the top here, and I'm
just going to run all of the tests.
All right, and as you can see, we've got one failing test and that failing test is this one here test
for wrong guesses.
So if I double click on this, that'll take us straight to that particular test.
Now let's see what's going on here.
So this is where we are simulating what happens when you make four wrong guesses.
And apparently what we are expecting here is that you should we should get back a message from the guessing
game engine saying you didn't guess you didn't get it and you've had four tries game over.
But what we're actually getting now is you didn't get it.
You're too low.
All right.
So that's the problem here.
So one more time, I just want to note what we're expecting to see here is you didn't get it and you've
had four tries game over and this is presumably coming on our fourth guess.
So we make a fourth wrong.
Guess we captured the message and then we're expecting that that's what the message should be.
So how can we figure this out using debugging techniques?
Well, the first step is typically to put what we call a breakpoint on a particular line close to where
we think things may be going awry.
OK, now sometimes a developer may put a breakpoint kind of high up in the program, and then they'll
kind of step through the entire program.
That's pretty wasteful and inefficient, though, because then you've got to sit there and just like,
keep going through line by line by line.
It's usually a little better, in my opinion, to put the breakpoint somewhere close to where you think
the actual problem is going wrong.
And that way you get to skip over all the parts that are presumably fine.
And if you're wrong, you can always change the breakpoint.
Put it somewhere earlier in the in the execution and try again.
All right, so here, since the focus of this test is to see what happens when you make a fourth guess.
And that's the only time when we're actually getting a message and the message we know is wrong, I'm
inclined to put a breakpoint on this line.
64.
OK, so what that breakpoint is going to do is it's going to tell the I.D. and Java to stop at that
line before the line actually gets executed, though, and then we can decide what to do from that point.
So the way to make a break point is easy.
I'm going to move my cursor right to the right side of the line number, and I'm just going to click.
So this is usually called the gutter.
So clicking one time puts this little red dot here, and that's a breakpoint.
OK.
And so now if I run this program in a special mode called Debug Mode, the program will pause or halt
when it gets to line sixty four and then I can choose what I want to do at that point.
OK.
So the most efficient thing I can think to do at this point is actually to just run only this one test.
So I can do that in multiple ways.
I could come down here to the failing test and right click on it and choose to debug right here.
Or I could click on it up here and choose Debug Right so I can do any of these things.
Or I could run all the tests and the breakpoint would still get stopped and the program would still
stop or halt or pause when it gets to that breakpoint.
But again, that's a little less efficient.
Why run of all of the tests?
All right.
So I'm just going to choose up here for now, just randomly.
I'm going to choose the debug option here.
So that's going to run the program.
And now I'm in debug mode right now.
So the test is actually executing right now.
But at the moment it's paused.
If you will not technically pause, but it's halted.
It's waiting on me to tell it what to do.
So what has happened is it started running this test and it executed line.
Sixty one, sixty two and sixty three just fine.
Then it came to Line 64.
It saw that I have placed the breakpoint here.
And so now it's waiting for me to tell it whether what I want to do now.
I have a couple of choices here.
My first choice is I could just let the program do what we call step over, step over Line sixty four
and I've never been a big fan of that terminology step over because it feels like it's saying like Skip,
skip the line, and that's not really what it's doing at all.
What stepping over will do is it will execute everything that needs to be executed on Line 64 and then
go down to the next line.
OK.
So it doesn't skip anything, really.
It just executes that line and moves on to the next line so that.
Stepping over the other option, though, is to step in.
Now I have the option of stepping in when there is a method that is going to be called on the line of
my break point.
So here there is a method that is able to be called it is Gamecock.
Guess this method here?
So if I step in, if I choose to step in, that will take me into this method, which is pretty much
the same thing that the thread would do when it's executing this program, right?
It steps in to all of the methods and everything and then starts running those lines as well.
So if I choose to step over, the thread will still execute all of that, but I don't get to see it.
OK, it's stepping over it from my perspective, if I step in.
Then I'm kind of going along for the ride with the thread and jumping into this method.
So I'm going to choose to step in because if I just step over this, I already know what's going to
happen.
The Gamecock guess method is going to return a message which is wrong, and I won't know why it's wrong,
right?
I want to know why this message is wrong and to find that out.
The only way I'm going to figure that out is to is to jump into this guess method where all of the real
logic exists, right?
All right.
So how do I step over or step in?
So down here.
There are these little buttons, tiny little buttons.
And the first one is step over and I can just click it to step over.
If I wanted to do that, which I'm not going to right now, or I could step in and notice, I can also
use the function keys to do this.
So f eight four step over F7 four step into.
OK.
And keep in mind that if you want to use the function keys on Mac, the I think it was maybe the third
or fourth video that I ever made in the first module.
I made a little addendum telling you how to set your Mac up to let the function keys behave as regular
function keys so that you could use them without holding down on any additional keys, right?
So just keep that in mind.
All right.
So I'm going to step in.
I'm going to use the keyboard here because my function keys are set up correctly.
If yours are not, it may be easier for you to press the button here.
OK, so pressing this little button is going to jump us into this guess method.
All right, so I'm going to do function or F7 right now.
All right.
And so now we are along for the ride with the thread, right?
This is what the thread would have done.
Now, notice a number of things here.
It's pretty cool, actually.
We're getting a lot of insight into what various variables are set to like, what their values are.
We're seeing them in real time.
So our test passed in the No.
Negative three here, and we see that this guest no variable, its value is being shown off to the right
here.
Guest number is set to negative three.
That's what we passed in from the test.
And in fact, I can jump back over to the test just to see what that looked like.
So over here in the bottom pane, we're seeing the stack, if you will.
OK, so this is kind kind of showing us the flow of the thread, like where did the thread come from?
What was its path to getting here and the top most entry in this stack view?
Here is the most recent place that the thread has been.
OK, so we're currently highlighted in blue online.
12 inside of the guessing game class and down here we see we're in the guest method line 12 of the guessing
game class, right?
And even the package there and we can see previously we were in the test for wrong guesses method on
line 64 of the guessing game test.
And if I click on this, it actually takes us back to where the thread previously was.
This line right here where you can see we're passing in a negative three.
Now this line isn't like re re executing or anything.
This is just taking us back to what things looked like when we were here previously.
So you're almost like freezing time so that you can just kind of inspect how are things going?
For some reason, I get this picture in my mind of what was the name Neo from The Matrix.
When he's in bullet time, you know, time slows down and he's able to see individual bullets.
We're kind of in programmer bullet time right now where we're able to see what's going on at such a
slow rate of speed, right?
That, well, technically, it's nothing's going on right now.
We're just pausing, right?
So we've halted the simulation, if you will.
All right.
So I'm going to click back on this top line, though, to go back to where the threat is currently waiting
for us.
OK.
All right.
So before we step through or over any of these lines, I kind of want to get my bearings here.
So we know that what was supposed to happen in that test was that we were supposed to receive a method
saying you didn't get it and you've had four tries and that the game is over.
So I want to kind of find, where is that text and then kind of work my way backward from there to figure
out, OK, what is supposed to happen in order for that text to be output, right?
And it's kind of jumping out at me right here on Line 17.
You didn't get it and you've had X number or the number of tries, right, game over.
So this is the line that we want.
And so I think what should be happening is that this conditional on Line 16 is supposed to evaluate
to true, which would cause the thread to jump into Line 17 and execute this and then set this value
on the response.
And then that response should be returned, but that's not currently happening.
So with that in mind, as we step over these next few lines, we want to determine if, in fact, this
conditional.
Is evaluating to true or false, and if it is false, why is it false, right?
That's what we're here to figure out.
OK, so coming back up to Line 12, which is where the threat currently is, we're going to let it step
over the next few lines rather than stepping in.
Although in this particular line, there is no method call here.
So stepping over or stepping in would actually be the same thing as I have just shown here by actually
stepping in from line 12, that just took me down to Line 13.
However, you should be very mindful of the difference between stepping over versus stepping in.
Oftentimes, if you step in in the wrong places, that will take you down a wild goose chase.
And I've seen many novice developers who maybe didn't really fully understand the difference between
stepping over and stepping in, and they just step into all kinds of crazy code, which I'm going to
show you in a moment why that's just a terrible idea to do.
All right.
So we're now on this next line here.
And what are we doing here?
We're evaluating the counter variable and we're saying if the counter equals one, which it does not.
And by the way, so one other thing to notice here now the ID is even showing us the value of this evaluation
here.
Counter equals one this this equals false bit here.
That's not anything that we typed in the I.D. is is is adding that in there for us to tell us, hey,
counter equals one is false.
This expression is evaluating to false so that we don't have to figure that out on our own, even though
we could.
And I will show you that later.
All right.
So it's telling us that that's false.
And since that is false, we already know that this word try is not going to be returned from this ternary
expression.
And instead, the word tries is going to be returned from this expression and therefore set on this
try text variable here.
All right.
So I'm going to step over this line F8 and notice now that I've stepped over Line 13 and I said that
the string tries would be set on the try text variable here.
We can see that over here now.
Now that I've actually stepped over the line, the line has executed, so the line doesn't execute until
after you step over it.
OK.
So right now I'm on Line 14, but line 14 has not executed yet.
Not until I step in or step over something.
So over here, we're now seeing that the tri text variable is currently set to the word tries.
So isn't that really convenient to be able to see in real time what the program is actually doing?
Super useful.
All right.
So now we're online 14, and now I need to decide, do I want to step over or step in?
Well, so here's the thing if I step in, where do you think it's going to go?
Take take a good look at this.
All right.
So if I step in, the thread is going to jump into the format straight into the format method here.
So let me just tell you right now, that's not useful to me.
Let me let me make a little space here, by the way, I'm going to close this pain.
Here we go.
Got a little more room now.
OK, now stepping into the string, that format method is not useful to me for for a few reasons.
First off, and most importantly, the string, that format method is not code that I wrote.
You should generally assume that code that you did not write that that came with the Java or was written
by a third party library that you brought in to your code, which I'm not using here.
But if I were, you should assume that that code doesn't have any problems.
Occasionally, it might like.
I don't know.
Zero point zero zero zero one percent of the time there could be a legitimate bug in third party code
that you did not write, but don't send yourself on a wild goose chase, jumping down in every nook
and cranny of all code everywhere.
Looking for what the problem is?
You'll lose sight really quickly of and focus of what you're really here to find.
OK.
So we can just assume there's not a problem with the string that format method.
OK?
And therefore, we don't want to step in to that method.
That's a waste of our time.
So already, I know that I want to step over this line.
OK.
I don't want to jump into that into that method there.
I want to step over it.
So I'm going to do another F8.
There we go.
And now I can see the try text is still tries and I can also see winning text is said to you.
Got it in four tries and the counter is set to four.
Right?
All right.
We're not really doing anything here other than just creating an initializing the response variable
to null.
So I will step over that.
And now we can see that over here, response is null.
So now we're at the line in question, right?
So we know that for the program to function correctly, we need this conditional to evaluate to true
so that we will step into line.
17.
So let's just take a look at this and see what's going on here.
So we already can see that this first little bit of the conditional expression counter equals two,
which is to say, does the counter equal to because we're using the equals operator here, right?
Well, the ID is already telling us, since we're in debug mode, that this is going to evaluate to
false right.
And we can see that in a few different ways.
We can see that the value of counter.
Well, a couple of things here.
If I hover my cursor on the word counter or the variable counter, I can see its value right there.
It's for another way I could see it is to jump over here to the right hand side.
And again, I can see that counter is equal to four, so four does not equal to and that's why this
is false.
So this is to say that if you have made four guesses, right, that's what this part is saying.
And this two ampersand together means a logical and right, and the number that you're guessing are,
you guessed, is wrong, essentially right.
The number that you guessed, which in this case is a negative three, does not match the actual random
number.
Now that's a method call to determine that.
OK.
So we're not getting the actual value shown to us if we hover over this, but we can actually find out
what that value is going to be in a couple of ways that are very, very nice.
So if I select this method, call here, I can right click on it and I can come down here to evaluate
expression.
And what that's going to do is it's going to have the I.D. essentially create a separate thread.
OK, a temporary, separate thread that's just going to call that method and then give us the results
of it.
So I'm going to actually click this.
All right.
And it's just giving you another opportunity to see like, what am I about to do here?
And let me let me.
Resized that so you can see what's going on.
OK, so this is going to create another temporary thread to run just this method, given the current
state of this class, though.
So I'm going to click, evaluate and look at that.
I get back a three.
So get random number is currently returning the value of three.
So I can now close this and now I can come back up here and I can see, OK, so my guest number is negative
three.
But the get random number method is currently returning a positive three.
So those don't match, which means you've made a wrong guess.
And so if I just kind of revisit what is this conditional really saying, it's currently saying if we
have made two guesses and this most recent guess is wrong, then go ahead and run line 17, right?
But actually, we've made four guesses now and the last guess is wrong.
And so we're not going to end up making it into line 17.
So I think we've found out where the problem is.
This number here should be four.
So I'm going to go ahead and actually just change it right there.
All right.
So now that we've changed this value from two to four in order to try to fix this bug that we have,
we're going to need to do one thing before we can proceed with the rest of the execution of the program.
So you can't just change code in the middle of a debugging session and just expect that everything will
continue to work.
And the reason you can't do that is bear in mind, Java is a compiled programming language, right?
That means that this text that we're seeing here on the screen all has to be translated or compiled
into machine code, essentially right, which we call in Java bytecode.
It's got to be compiled.
And so when we make changes to the code here, those changes don't actually take effect until two things
happen in a in a debugging session.
One, the code has to be recompiled or the class in this case has to be recompiled and to that recompiled
code then needs to be reloaded into the memory right in, in this case, reloaded into the debugging
session itself.
So those two things must happen first.
OK.
So in order to do that, there's several ways we can do it.
We can do a command F9 to just rebuild if I come up here to the build menu.
You'll see all the options here.
Build Project, right?
We've used this before, or we can just build the guessing game.
Now, this first option will rebuild any and all classes that have changed in terms of their source
code.
So in this case, we've only made one change just in this file here.
And so this would be the only file that actually gets recompiled.
Or you could specifically tell the IDE to only recompile just this one file.
So right now, all three of these options would be more or less equivalent to each other.
OK.
But that's what we need to do first in order to get this little code change that we've made to start
to take effect.
So I'm going to do that now.
I'm just I'm just going to do a command F9 or control F9 on Windows and Linux.
And you can see down here that a rebuild took place.
And now that this class has been rebuilt, we're being prompted.
Some classes have been changed.
Reload changed classes now.
So do we want to reload those classes now?
Yes, we do want those to be reloaded now, so I'll click the reload.
Now, notice one thing in particular, since we reloaded, the variable debug data that we had is now
unavailable and and basically the debugging session is in somewhat of an unknown state, if you will.
OK.
And so we wouldn't want to just proceed with our debugging session from this point because we're not
in a well defined state at the moment.
So there's something we can do about that now.
The easiest thing we could do, of course, is to stop the debugging session and then restart everything.
But imagine if you had been in a debugging session where you were tracing through many method calls
across many classes and it took you a while to get to wherever you currently were.
You might not want to have to go through all of that again.
You might want to just make the little surgical change like what we've made here and then just pick
right back up from more or less where you left off, right?
Well, you can do that in the debugger, and I want to show you how.
So if we come down here to this lower left pane where we're basically seeing the path that we've taken
from the test for wrong guesses method in the guessing game test class to where we are now, right?
Each of these entries is actually called a frame.
OK.
And this top frame here represents the fact that we are currently in the guest method of the guessing
game class.
OK.
So what we can do is we can actually drop this frame, which will allow us to just kind of restart not
the entire debugging session, but just from the point where we were about to enter this frame.
OK.
That's what we can do.
We can kind of just restart from this one frame rather than having to restart the entire program.
Now, in our case, we only have two frames of note anyway, so it doesn't really matter.
But like I said, if you had been 10 frames deep and you only needed to reload the last frame and it
took you a while to get there, you don't want to have to go through all 10 frames again, right?
OK, so to drop this frame, all we need to do is come up here and there's a little icon right there.
Drop frame.
OK.
And so this will allow us to basically.
Restart from right before we jumped into this frame.
OK, now one thing I want to point out before we do that.
Let us take note of the value of the counter variable.
Currently counter is set to four, OK?
Keep note of that for when we get back here again.
OK, and we'll take another look at that.
All right, so let's drop this frame.
I'm going to click the drop frame button here.
And so all it did is it just dropped us back to the previous frame and that that that top frame that
we were in is gone now, so we basically deleted it.
We kind of told the debugger and the thread pretend like we never went into that into that last frame
and just drop us back into the previous frame, which is right here, right?
And so now we kind of get to start over again from this point.
And so again, I will just step into this game guess method with an S7.
So currently, now we're back in the guest's method.
And if we take a look at this counter variable, we'll see that counter currently is equal to four.
Now keep in mind, we're highlighted on line 12, so we haven't executed Line 12 yet.
We're about two, right?
So it's currently set to four.
If you may have noticed when we entered this frame or the guess method previously counter was set to
three.
OK?
So one thing of note here is that even though we have dropped this frame and come back in to it, this
counter variable has retained its value from the previous time that we entered here.
And the reason for that is because this is a field of the class and we did not restart the class or
remake the class or anything.
All we've done is just reenter this guess method here.
And so in the previous time that we entered this guess method, we had already gone past Line 12, where
we incremented the counter variable from three to four, which is why it is currently four.
And that variable is up here, right?
It's a field of this class.
So dropping a frame does not reset the values of fields in a class.
All it does at best is to reset all of the local variables in a method, right?
Because we're re-entering this method and local variables within methods lose their values when a thread
leaves that method.
And we in effect, have left the method and then come back in for a new pass.
Right.
So this is noteworthy because in order to properly simulate the scenario that we are trying to play
through here, we need counter to right now be set to three OK, so we can do one or two things.
We can either change it right now back to three, or we can move past this line and then change it from
five back to four.
So take your pick, right?
But since we're talking about it now, let's go ahead and just change it now.
And you can actually do this in two places.
You can do it here by clicking on this little dropdown there, right?
Or I'm going to click outside of there to let that go away.
Or you can come down here to this little area called variables or the minus cutoff, and you can come
down here to the same counter variable listed down here.
You can click on it at press two, and you can change it that way.
So I guess I'm going to do it that way for now, but there's no difference.
So I can press off two and then I can replace the four with a three and then hit return to set that.
And so you can see now that that value got changed up here as well, right?
So we're seeing it changed everywhere now because it's the same variable everywhere.
All right.
And so now I could proceed to step over all of these lines until I get to line 16 with an f eight or
with the step over button right there.
Or I could put my cursor down here on line 16, anywhere on line 16, and then I could choose to have
the debugger simply run all of these lines until it gets to line 16.
There's an option for that.
It is this option right here.
This little this little icon run to cursor or I could do an option F9 or alt F9, OK?
And that would tell the debugger to run down to the line where my cursor currently is.
So for now, I'll just click this button.
All right.
And so now the threat is waiting for me online 16, and now we're back to where we were right before
we recompiled and dropped the frame, right?
And then if we check counter now is equal to four, right because it got incremented, we see it down
here.
And we also see it there.
And we also see it over here, right?
And we can still change that.
Now, some of you might possibly be a little bit confused by the question of did we need to recompile
when we changed the value of counter?
And the answer is no.
We don't need to recompile when we're changing the value of a variable because that's not code that's
in memory, OK?
We only need to change.
So keep in mind, the idea is just showing us this.
This isn't part of our code.
This is just some metadata, if you will, that the I.D. is showing us for convenience sake because
we are in debug mode.
OK, it's not part of the code, right?
This over here is the code right.
So if I changed this zero to something else and I wanted that to take effect, I would need to recompile
OK if I changed any of these lines that we typed originally any of them at all, including that for
there, I would need to recompile.
But changing a value that's in a variable that we can access like these here, those values can be changed
without re compiling.
Now sometimes, though, to have them take effect, you may need to drop the frame and get back in again.
You may have to do that, but you won't need to recompile if the only change you're making is simply
to change the value of a variable.
OK.
All right.
So anyway, see, so we changed that before we dropped the frame and now we changed the counter, and
I think we're good to go here.
So I'm going to step over this line 16.
And hopefully now what should happen is we will jump into line 17.
So I will step over that with an f eight.
And there we go.
And now we're hitting Line 17, which the code clearly wasn't hitting before when we were testing whether
or not counter was equal to two, right?
But now we are.
OK.
So I'm pretty satisfied that this is now going to work.
And so if I want to, I don't have to keep stepping over or in any of these lines, I can just let the
rest of the program just run OK.
And probably the easiest way for me to do that is to come over here to this green play looking button
here and just click that to resume the program.
Assuming you have no more breakpoint set anywhere in the rest of the program, we'll just run to the
end or in this case, the rest of the test, sorry, will run until the end.
OK, so I'm going to click that now.
All right, there we go.
And then I will click on the console tab here, which is partially hidden, though we can see right
here Test Pass, right tests best one and we were only running one test.
So if I test, if I click on console, I can see that test right there.
I've got a green checkmark now, and so we're good.
And I can double click on it even.
And that's looking good there as well.
OK, now if I want to get rid of a break point, the easiest thing I can do is simply click it one time,
just as I put it there by clicking once I can toggle it off or get rid of it by clicking it again.
OK, so I'll click.
Once that puts a breakpoint there, I click again.
That removes it.