Welcome back.
So in the last lesson, we summed up the salaries using a domain model, and I stated that one of the
reasons why we were introducing the use of a domain model the person class or record was for some future
techniques that we would be learning, and we're about to jump into some of those now.
So let me just tell you high level what we're going to be doing now.
We're going to learn some more advanced techniques that we can use on the collect method.
And one of those advanced techniques is the ability not only to sum up data of a column or field, but
to actually be able to group data by a field or, in other words, to categorize data.
OK, if that's not clear what I mean, I'm about to make it pretty clear here.
So before we learn how to do these additional techniques in Java, I thought it would be helpful to
see what the results of these techniques would look like visually using a spreadsheet.
So the first thing I'm going to do is to prepare some additional data to be opened up with a spreadsheet.
You don't need to follow along with me on these first few steps, though, because I'll be going in
to the Unix command prompt and issuing some Unix commands.
And this is not a Unix course, but I thought it might be helpful for you to get a little glimpse of
some real world techniques that a software developer might use in their day to day job.
Now there's lots of Java developers who won't be comfortable or even know how to do some of what I'm
about to do, so don't worry about that.
All right.
So what I want to do is I want to take our five million record file and I want to make a shorter copy
of it by shorter I mean fewer than five million records, just so that I have something that will open
up reasonably quickly with the spreadsheet.
Also, I'm going to use a different spreadsheet program now because it's pretty basically and I'm on
a Mac.
So here I am in a command prompt on my computer, and I'm in a folder that contains the data file that
we've been working with.
It's this one right here.
H.R. H.R. 5:00 a.m. Dot CSB.
OK.
And so what I'm going to do is issue some Unix commands to make a short copy of this file, basically
by truncating it down to maybe like, I don't know, 100 lines or something like that.
So to do that, I can use the head command dash in and then tell it how many lines out of that original
file.
I want to bring over essentially or copy.
And I don't know.
I think maybe I'll take one hundred and one the one for the header and then the hundred for the data.
OK, then I'll specify the file itself, CSP and then I'm going to direct the output of this command
into a new file, which I'm going to just call people dot csb for now.
All right.
And it's that quick.
So the reason I'm doing this in this way is because it's just really quick and easy to do.
I could have done this programmatically as well.
You've seen me actually copy some records out of the file.
Like we wrote a little code that printed out the first 10 records or so, and then I copied those records
out of the console of the ID, and then I pasted them into a spreadsheet, right?
You've seen me do it that way.
This is just another way to do that without me having to write any code.
And in fact, this head hyphen in 101, this is pretty much equivalent.
Let me jump over to the real quick.
This is kind of equivalent to something like files, lines of files, dot lines, dot limit 101, right?
If I were to do the dot limit one to one and then a A for each with a system out dot print line or something
like that.
This is pretty equivalent to that.
The only additional thing that I'm doing here is I'm redirecting the output into a new file and I could
do that in Java, too, but this is just quicker.
All right.
So now that I've created this new file, I can open that file up.
And with the open command, and this will by default open up that file in the native default spreadsheet
program for MAX, which is called numbers, it's kind of apples, cheap, cheap competitor to XL.
All right.
So here we are in the spreadsheet.
And let's see here.
Yeah, so I think that looks like around a hundred lines.
Notice it did a few neat things for.
I said it recognized it went ahead and took that first row, which is our header row, and it represents
that row as a header row, right?
So that's why it's in darker, grey and bolded and everything.
And then we've got our data rows here.
All right.
So just for a quick review.
So what our program is currently doing is it's just currently adding up all of the salaries, right?
And so I'll just show you very quickly as a review what that looks like in a spreadsheet for those of
you who are not super familiar with the spreadsheet program.
So if I find the salary column, then let me also zoom in on that.
Sorry about that.
So you can see it more clearly.
Where is the salary?
There it is.
There's the salary column, right?
OK, so if I come down here to the bottom of this?
Of this column, and I will right click on that and I'll add a new row below.
Here we go.
And now the selected data cell is this new one here and then I can come up here to insert some.
And so that has automatically summed up our totaled up all of the data in this salary column.
Now it's not formatted nicely, and if I want to do that, I can come over here to the format and choose
sell and let's change the format type to currency.
So the reason I'm showing you these things is just to show you that the things that we've been doing
programmatically have a very strong analog in this particular case in in a spreadsheet program, OK?
And so this is just another way of seeing what we've been doing programmatically.
We can do those same types of things in a spreadsheet in this particular case.
All right.
So there now that's formatted as money, and I can even throw the comma separator in there and then
let's get this wider so that we can actually see everything there.
So there you go eleven million eight hundred fifty five thousand for these hundred rows.
So if I wanted to, I could also format all of these numbers, but I'm not going to bother with that.
You get the gist.
OK, so that's what we've been doing programmatically now.
We just did it in a spreadsheet.
OK, now the next thing I want to do, though, in fact, let me I'm going to delete this row now.
I just was showing you that kind of for kind of an analog to what we've done so far.
All right.
Now the next thing I want to do, though, is show you what it would look like to group up these records
by some category.
So let's say that we wanted to group these records by state.
OK, so if I find the state column there, there it is.
OK.
So what I can do is I can come up here to the ad category button and it lets me choose a state.
So what it's basically asking me is what?
What field do you want to categorize these records by?
And I'm going to tell it.
I want to categorize these records by state.
And now look what it did.
Very, very quickly, almost instantaneously, it just grouped these up by the states, right?
So here they are.
And so we're seeing all of the people in that in this total data set from New Mexico, from Pennsylvania,
Minnesota, et cetera.
Right.
Now, if I wanted to alphabetize this, have these states alphabetized, I could go over here to the
state column.
There it is.
And come up here to the header, the the main header for it and select this and then choose to sort
state groups ascending.
All right, so now if I come over here, now we've got Alabama, Arkansas, California, so now it's
all, it's all alphabetized, right?
Then I can collapse these.
Right.
And I can expand them all as well.
All right.
So let me close this format bit here.
OK, so the reason I wanted to show you this is so that you would see visually what it looks like and
what it means to group records to group a two dimensional table of records by some category or by some
field, right?
So in this case, we've grouped all of these records by the state field.
And so what you end up with is kind of like an indented kind of a deal where the first level is the
state and then the indented bits after that are all of the records in this case that come after that
state.
Right.
All right.
So now that we've seen what this looks like, let's jump over to the Edee and do the same thing there
or the equivalent there.
All right.
OK, so here we are back in the I.D. and we were dealing with the collect method, which I was telling
you earlier, is going to be our gateway into a lot more advanced capabilities like grouping data.
All right.
And so currently we're just summing up all of the salaries, but we're not going to do that anymore.
So now we want to emulate what we just did in the spreadsheet.
And so we're going to use another function that goes inside of the collect method and that function
is called grouping by.
So if I just start typing here, there it is our grouping by now.
If you don't get this auto completion, you may need to type out collectors' dot grouping by.
You may need to do that and then you can statically import the grouping by method.
And then that would allow you to delete the collectors.
So if you don't get the auto completion by default, you can always just prepend with the collector's
class name.
All right, so let me get rid of that.
Grouping by now.
This is super easy to use.
So think about what we did in the spreadsheet when we told the spreadsheet that we wanted to categorize
our group by.
It asked us to pick a column, right?
Same thing here.
And we can and and because we have now stored our pertinent bits of information, namely the state as
a field in a domain model of person of class person, we can use a method reference to the getter method
for the state field.
So in other words, we can simply type person colon, colon state like so.
Now notice as soon as I did that, I got read errors all over the place.
And if I hover over this, it's going to say that we've got to require type of lung.
But what was provided was a map.
And all it's saying is that now that we're using the grouping by method, we are no longer returning
a result of type long.
We are now returning a result of type map of string to a list of person, which sounds kind of complicated.
But let's just go back over to the spreadsheet and and I'll make it make sense really easily.
So it's going to return a map now and what its mapping is the the states to the people.
OK, so the the keys, if you remember a map is basically just a list of key value pairs, right keys
and then values, right?
So in this spreadsheet?
So in terms of what we see here in this spreadsheet, the keys would be these state codes.
Al RCA.
OK.
Those are the keys.
And then the values would be all of these rows.
OK.
Underneath that state and these rows currently are represented in our Java code as the by the person
class.
OK.
But we've got a list of them, literally.
We've got a list of them.
So what we're getting over here in the E is also a mapping of strings, which are our state codes.
Mapping those state codes to a list of people.
So I know this is a little difficult to read, especially if you're kind of new to looking at all of
this because it looks kind of messy.
Let me see if I can stretch that out and make it at least show up a little nicer.
Yes, so maybe that's maybe that looks a little easier to read, at least.
OK, but what we're seeing here is a map of string to a list of person.
And that's exactly what we're seeing here.
Strings text of the state to a list of people.
Right.
So this is visually the equivalent of what the grouping by method is currently going to return us.
OK.
And that's again, why I wanted to use this spreadsheet so that you could visualize and see conceptually
what is actually happening with this grouping by because otherwise it can be a little intimidating and
confusing, especially as we proceed to do even fancier things with the data set because we can go a
lot further than this.
All right.
So back over here.
So to get rid of the red marks, we can actually just put our cursor here and then do an option return
and have the ID.
Just fix it for us, right?
So all it's going to do is just change the the data type of the result from a long that we had before
to a map of string to list person, meaning mapping strings the states to the list of people.
Right.
So is that pretty?
So does that make sense?
All right.
And then down here before we run it.
This result, now that it is a map, it won't make sense to try to use the print statement with this
format string and all of this.
The formatter wouldn't know what to do with a map.
OK, so we're going to just comment that out for now.
And I will replace it with a new system out, and for now, I'm not going to get fancy.
I'm just going to use the default two string method of the map class to allow it to be printed in whatever
way it sees fit.
It probably won't be pretty, but it's a start.
OK.
OK, so now that we've got these few changes here, let's go ahead and run this and see what it.
And see what it outputs.
OK.
And I totally forgot to limit the results here because we we just printed out all five million records
sorted out by state.
And that's going to be a little difficult to parse out something meaningful here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to throw back on the limit real quick and let's just run that again.
Sorry about that.
There we go.
And that's a lot quicker and a lot shorter.
So now what we are seeing is taxes.
And then we're seeing a person, Imogene Hagopian and Louisiana Walker Warlick, something or other
and Ohio Lizbeth.
And let's see and.
OK, so Ohio as this person, Elizabeth and another person, Foust, though, these are all people in
Ohio, apparently, and Vonda.
And then we've got New Jersey, right?
So we can see a few different.
So some states have multiple people associated with that state like here's New Jersey with destiny and
E. The California has Damien and Jason Cita.
I guess ASU, CTA D.C. has one person out of our current data set, at least.
OK, so we can see that now again.
If I hadn't shown you the spreadsheet and I had just run this program for you, some of you might have
been fairly confused by how to make heads or tails of this.
But what we're really seeing here now is here's Texas, right?
And then here's someone named Imogene.
Let's see if if Imogene happens to show up in our data set in the spreadsheet here, do we have Texas?
Let's see, Texas.
There's Imogene right there.
So in this dataset, we've got one two three four five six seven eight people in Texas, and I don't
think we had eight here.
That's because here we constrained our dataset to just about 10 records, right?
Really?
Nine records.
So we didn't get everyone.
But yeah, so we've only got Imogene here, but that's the taxes bit, and then else Louisiana, I almost
said L.A., Louisiana.
There's there's Louisiana.
So we had four people in the original data set there, right?
So there's your L.A. And then here are the actual people over here.
We've got Louisiana, and we're only showing the one person Walker.
Here's Walker, right?
And let's look at maybe one more here, Ohio, and we had a couple of people for Ohio, Liz, Beth and
Fausto.
Let's find Ohio.
There's Ohio, so there's Liz F and there's foul stuff.
All right.
So, yeah, now the other thing that we could do.
Is we in our spreadsheet, we did alphabetize these right, and we can do that fairly easily with our
code as well.
So one of the easiest ways that we could get these alphabetized by state would be to use another overloaded
version of the grouping by function here.
So if I put my cursor right here after the first parentheses and do a command p to show me parameters,
I get to see different versions or overloaded versions of this method or function and what those different
versions take.
Currently, we're using this first version that just takes a classifier.
OK?
And another version that takes two arguments a classifier again and then a something and then something
called a downstream.
We'll get into some of these options.
But and then there's another one here that can take a classifier, a map factory and the downstream.
So let's see how we can do this.
So the one that we're kind of interested in is this one that takes a so-called map factory, OK?
And all that is is a method in the form of a lambda or a method reference or something of that sort,
or it could be in or it could be an anonymous class.
Even that will supply some type of map.
And so this allows us to return a specific instance of a map, OK?
So currently, these entries are out of order by state because it is using a hash map.
OK.
But we can make it use some other instance of a map.
So if we wanted these entries, the keys really to be alphabetized.
Can you remember what implementation of the map interface might be best for getting alphabetized entries
by key?
OK, so we could use a tree map, right, because tree maps alphabetized by key by default.
Right.
And so what we need to do here is inside of our grouping grouping by method.
After we specify this first field here, the state, the field that we want to order by or grouped by,
I'll put a comma here and then I can supply a map factory.
Now that sounds fancy, but all it is, it's just another lambda or a method reference.
And really, the simplest thing I could do here is probably just refer to tree map as a method as a
method reference with new.
This is another way of just saying new tree map.
OK, but doing it in a method reference type of way like so.
All right.
And now I need to do one thing that we weren't doing before.
So when we're using the version of grouping by that only takes one input, which is basically the field
that we want to group by.
By default, it will take all of the records that got grouped and it will throw them into a list and
return that.
So if this is all you want, then you don't need to specify the rest of it.
But now that I want to use one of the alternative versions of the grouping by method where we're going
to additionally specify a custom implementation of the map, I now have to also tell it what to do with
the records.
OK.
Not much to do there, but you'll see.
So, all right, so we're going to tell it to use a tree map instead of the default of hash map.
And now we need to tell it what to do with our actual records and what it was doing previously was it
was just taking those records that got grouped and it was throwing them into a list.
We can have it, keep doing that and we can just tell it explicitly to do that.
There's another collectors' method to list, and we've actually used this before back when we originally
learned how to use the collect method.
We learned that we could take the output of the dot collect and throw it into different collections,
right?
And probably, I think the very first collection we learned how to use in that example was a list by
using the two lists.
This is the same to list, so you're not even learning anything new here.
All right.
And so notice that we don't have any red marks or anything, we didn't need to change the data type
for the result because we're still returning a map of strings to a list of person, right?
But now this map, instead of being a hash map, it is now a tree map.
All right.
And so now if we run this again, let's see what we'll get.
There we go.
And so now we've got California as the starting state, and let's see as we scroll through, then we've
got D.C. So that's looking alphabetical so far and then Louisiana and then New Jersey.
Ohio.
Texas, yeah.
So there you go.
Now that's alphabetized, right?
So again, we've just done the equivalent of what we had done over here where I had what did I do?
I selected the the state header and then I told it to sort by an ascending order or whatever, right?
And so we've done the same thing here.
All right.
So we're going to wrap up this lesson.
And in the next lesson, we'll continue to learn some more techniques that we can do with the collect
method and grouping by.
So stay tuned.
See in the next one.