Another thing I can do with break points, though, is sometimes you'll have many break points throughout
the code because you're trying to really figure out, Okay, what happens when I'm in this area of the
code versus that area of the code, right?
In fact, I'll do that.
I'll put a breakpoint here, and then I will jump back into the guest's method and I'll put a breakpoint
here and I will put one down here as well.
OK, so now I've got break three break points.
OK, if I go back over here, let's say that I decide, you know what?
I don't need this particular break point now.
I know that this isn't probably doing much for me, but I don't want to get rid of it for whatever reason.
I just want to temporarily not stop here while I'm in my debug session.
So what I can do, I can pull up a list of all of the break points that I have, which is actually quite
helpful to do.
Sometimes, especially sometimes you'll be in a you'll be in a debugging session where you've set so
many break points that you starting to lose track of where they all are.
OK, and you kind of want to see the big picture of where are all of the break points?
So for that, you can actually click on this little icon here.
View Break Points, So I'll click on that.
OK, so now if I expand this top thing here, Java line break points, those are your standard break
points.
I can expand that and there are my three break points.
OK, so one on line 21 and guessing Game Line 14 and guessing game and then in the test on line 64.
And from here I can actually uncheck any of these to kind of just temporarily ignore or turn them off.
So I'm not the leading them.
I'm just turning it off, right?
So if I wanted to get rid of this one, that's in the test, I can just.
Uncheck that right.
And it's nice that I can kind of see a little snippet of the code right there so that I don't have to
remember now which one was this and what is it doing?
I can just click on it, not on the checkmark, but on the actual name itself.
And I get to see a little snippet of that code right there so that I have more context as to what that
particular breakpoint was.
And same thing here.
OK.
So that's kind of nice.
So.
You've got all kinds of little options here while you're highlighted on a break point.
Just as I can check and uncheck the check marks here, I can also do the same thing here.
OK, so this is more like a detailed view.
This check mark here for enabled is the same as this check mark there, right?
You see that I'm I'm toggling it here, but it's changing here also.
So, yeah, so you can do that.
And let's see, I can also specify what should happen when that breakpoint is hit, right?
When the thread gets to that line with that particular break point, should it suspend, which is pretty
much almost always what you'll want.
You can tell it to just suspend the thread.
Now here, I'm actually telling it to suspend all threads, which doesn't really apply too much for
what I'm currently doing.
There's really only one thread, but if I were somehow testing an application that has multiple threads,
I could cause all of the threads to be suspended any time that particular breakpoint was hit.
For the most part, I don't think you really need to be too concerned with this right now.
And then there's another really cool feature that I sometimes really like, and that is to make a conditional
break point.
So this is kind of like having a breakpoint with an if statement where you can say, don't just stop
because I have a breakpoint only stop at this breakpoint if a certain condition is met.
And typically that condition will be some expression similar to an expression that you might have inside
of an if statement.
Let me show you what that would look like.
Real quick, I'm going to close this for a moment.
So let's see here if we go back into the guessing game code, and I think what I will do is I will make
a change right here.
I'm going to change this from a one.
To a two.
OK, so I'm intentionally kind of slightly breaking the application again.
All right.
And while I'm at it, I'm going to go ahead and get rid of these particular break points.
I'm going to go back into the break point view here, and what I can do is just select them all like
that.
I just held down on shift.
Well, here, let me show you.
So I had this last one selected.
So if I hold down on shift and then select the top one, then that will select everything in between
right inclusively.
And then from here, I can delete these by clicking the minus button here or remove, right?
OK, so now I got rid of those break points and then I can click done.
All right.
Now, if I jump back over to the tests and just run all the tests, not in debug mode, but just regular
run, because I want to just verify that I have broken at least one other test.
All right.
So we've got one failed test now, and it's a different one.
Let's see.
This is the test.
I mean, double click on it.
This is the test random number generation test.
And what we're getting here is an array index out of bounds exception index 11 out of bounds for links
11 and that's happening at one at line 49.
So we're now trying to access.
And Index 11 on this array, and there is no index 11, because Index 11 would be the 12th element in
the array, and this array only has 11 elements.
OK, so that's the bug we're trying to access.
One element beyond the number of elements that are actually allocated in this array.
OK, and that's all because I added, I changed that one to a two.
So now we're going a little too far.
OK.
So here's the kind of neat thing.
What if I wanted to make a breakpoint that stops right here, but it only does so if random NUM equals
11, right?
So normally to create a breakpoint, I can just click here, bam.
Now I have a breakpoint.
But here's the here's the reason I wouldn't.
I might not want to just do a regular old breakpoint here.
I'm inside of a loop.
And that means I'd have to sit here and let the debugger stop on this line 10 times before 10 or 11
times before I finally got to the scenario that I actually care about.
Huge waste of my time.
What if it wasn't an array with 12 elements?
What if it was an array with a thousand elements?
I don't want to sit there waiting on that right?
And I don't have to.
What I can do is just tell it only stop here when random numb equals 11.
So the way I can do that is I can actually right click on this break point.
And bam, right here, I get a little condensed version of what we were seeing in the bigger break point
view, I don't have it available right now, but you know what I'm talking about.
And so right here I can just type in a little a little expression random numb.
Equals 11.
So in other words, you can read this as if it were saying if random numb equals 11, then.
Suspend the the debugger when you get to this line, that's that's pretty much what it's saying.
Someone to click done.
And then I can come up here and just run.
Just this one test in debug mode, though, so we'll click on it and then choose Debug.
And now I'm stopped here, but random numb equals 11, so that means it didn't stop here until it had
iterated over this enough times for random numb to get to the value of 11, right?
And now I can jump in if I want to or do whatever I want to do here.
OK, so at any rate, that just shows you how a conditional breakpoint can be used quite effectively
to prevent you from having to sit there and wait for some rare circumstance to occur.
Right?
By the way, this might also come in very handy in conjunction with the at repeat annotation that we
learned earlier, right?
So if you're waiting for some circumstance, that doesn't happen very often, you might want to set
that repeat there to have it repeat many, many times so that you get more opportunities in conjunction
with a conditional breakpoint, right?
So that you don't have to sit there and manually keep clicking things until you get to wherever you're
looking for.
So that's a neat little technique that you can use.
Let's see.
Oh, now if you want to stop the debugger prematurely because you figured it out before you already
figured it out or you don't care, or you need to go to lunch or whatever, or it's the end of the day,
you can just click this little stop button right here to stop your current debug session.
And now that session is is done, and I'm going to go ahead and get rid of that.
Now if we jump back over to the guessing game code itself and scroll down here, and here's our main
method where we can actually run this thing, right, like in real life.
Now let me point out, you don't have to use the debugger with automated tests.
You can use the debugger anywhere if you have lines of code that you can execute somehow, whether it's
by hitting the play button on a main method or hitting the play button on a test method or wherever
else, you can hit a play button or execute some code.
You can put breakpoint.
All you have to do is make sure that when you tell the ad to run that code that you tell it to run it
in debug mode.
That's the only way the weak points will be honored is if you're in debug mode.
OK, and I just want to mention a couple final thoughts before I wrap up this lesson on debugging.
One of the things that I notice novice developers do quite often is when they are stepping through code
in debug mode, they have a tendency sometimes to just indiscriminately step into third party library
code.
I kind of touched on this a little bit ago, but I just want to finalize the point here.
When you're stepping through code and especially when you're stepping into code in debug mode, you
pretty much never want to step into third party libraries.
So any line of code that contains method calls and those are method calls that you didn't write and
they're not your code.
You don't want to step into those lines.
OK.
Period.
You just you don't want to step into those.
OK, so don't use step into.
So if we were on this line right here, for example, I do not.
In fact, here I will actually do it.
Debug.
OK, so here I am now, if I were to step into this line, the I.D. would ask me which of these methods
I want to step into, which is actually a nice touch in older versions of most I.D. ease.
They wouldn't even give you the option.
They would just start from the outer, from the innermost call and then work their way out from there.
Kind of annoying.
However, the main thing to note here is I didn't write any of this code, so I don't want to step into
any of it.
That's a waste of my time.
It's going to be a fruitless endeavor for me.
The appropriate thing to do here would be to step over this line and get to the next one.
Now, in this particular case, I'm not actually going to be able to do that because I can't technically
run this code that is trying to access the console from within the ADF for reasons that I've explained
already before.
So that's going to blow up with an exception being thrown or an error being thrown.
OK.
I was just using this as a as a quick example.
So keep that in mind.
Don't ever willy nilly just step into a line of code if that line of code contains third party methods
that you did not write OK unless you actually mean to do that, and you will almost never mean to do
that.
Now I have done it a few times in the past, but usually on purpose.
OK, so just pay attention, OK, if it's this kind of line, just step over it.
One thing that I have noticed when I'm working with some developers, especially either novice developers
or developers who frankly just aren't very good.
I noticed that once they learned how to use the debugger just a little bit, they have a tendency to
overuse the debugger like they use it to find out everything all the time.
In my experience, the debugger can be a fantastic tool, especially when you just can't figure out
what's going wrong, right?
You can step through the code methodically until you figure out, OK, this this variable is actually
set to this value, and I thought it was set to some other value, right?
Probably almost nothing beats being able to simply step through the code while it's running and actually
verify what is happening line by line.
However, that process does take time.
So what I like to do is a combination of things.
I like to use automated tests, and the more strictly you're using TDD, the less likely it is that
you're going to have many unexpected bugs.
And in fact, technically speaking, the only bugs you should be able to have in a program that was
written via TDD are bugs that weren't discovered because you didn't think of those testing scenarios,
right?
So you didn't write a test to test that scenario.
And that's the scenario where where the bugs are.
And that would make sense, right?
And so in that case, what you'd want to do is as soon as you encounter a bug, you want to first write
a test that reproduces that bug, and you should see that that test will indeed fail, right?
Because you have that bug, do that first, then go and fix the bug, OK?
And then to fix the bug, you may need to use the debugger and step through your code and figure out
what is going on and analyze it right.
And then once you figure that out, you can fix it.
And hopefully, once you've fixed it, your newly written test will now pass.
And now having that passing test, that passing test along with all of the other tests there, serves
as a safety net to ensure that hopefully that particular bug never comes back.
And if it does come back, you'll get an early warning system because that particular test will now
fail.
So you should understand that in most professional programming environments, there are servers that
are set up to build and compile code that is written by the team automatically.
So team members will write code and then they will kind of like check that code into a central code
repository, which we will talk about a little bit more in detail in a future lesson.
But after that code is built, any tests that exist for that code should ideally be run automatically
by this build server.
And if any of those tests fail, then a notification will be sent out to the entire team, letting them
know right away, Hey, one of your tests or some of your tests have just failed.
You need to go check this out.
And ideally, that code can't proceed any further down the pipeline to moving into production use by
customers or whomever until those tests are all passing.
OK.
So there's a lot more value to writing these tests than just to help you as an individual developer
to write clean code write.
These tests serve.
As a an early warning system to let you know when someone might not even be, you might be another developer
has inadvertently broken the the code, right?
OK, so at any rate, you now have learned the basics of how to use a debugger.
It's really not that complicated, right?
And I encourage you to just play with the debugger right on working code, on broken code, whatever
both sets and break points, run some code.
Let it stop their step through the code.
Step over the code.
All right.
So I think that's going to wrap it up for this lesson and I will see you in the next one.