Hey, welcome back.
So we've implemented a fair amount of database functionality so far in our people repository class.
But what if we wanted to implement additional repositories for other types of concepts besides people,
right?
We'd essentially end up having to replicate a fair amount of the code that we have here in the people
repository class.
So I was thinking it sure would be nice if we could reuse a lot of the boilerplate style code that exists
in this repository class to implement additional repositories more easily and also to cut down on some
of the visual noise that I see here in this class, especially with the use of the try catch blocks
here, which we have in every single crud method here.
So in this lesson, I want us to do a little experiment to see if it's possible for us to reduce that
boilerplate code and end up with something that we can reuse so that we can make additional repositories
a bit more easily than this.
So here's what I have in mind.
Let's start by just trying to re implement the save method in some kind of more reusable fashion.
And the way I'm envisioning this is that it would end up being another class that our repositories could
extend and that class would kind of temple.
It ties most of the boilerplate style code that we have here.
And then classes like this people repository would simply extend this super class that takes care of
all that boilerplate.
OK.
So this would give us an opportunity also to revisit some of the other things that we've learned about
object orientation as well.
OK, so let's jump in here and see what we can do.
All right.
So let's focus on this save method first.
And what I kind of have in mind, first and foremost, is maybe just let's just copy this whole entire
method and then let's go create a new class.
And really, I think we can kind of do this in almost a 2D style where we'll just pretend like the class
exists and then let the ADP create it for us.
OK, so let's pretend like this, people.
Well, I guess we're not going to pretend let's have this people repository class extend a new class.
And I don't know.
I think I'm going to call it crud repository.
We might have already made one of these once, but in a different way.
Maybe so.
OK, so we've got a create repository, or at least we will have one.
And let's just let the ADP create that for us.
And yeah, I think all of those settings are fine.
So I'm just going to click, OK.
All right.
So here's our Creed repository.
OK.
So I'm going to make a couple of new lines here, and then I'm just going to paste that save method
verbatim right here, just as a starting point.
OK.
All right.
So now I want to see what parts of this method are the parts that would be unique to a class that might
extend this?
And what parts would be kind of boilerplate, right?
You know, like the stuff that would be the same any time you had to create a repository class?
Right?
So the first thing I'm taking note of is the fact that obviously, since I copied and pasted this in
here, we've got it hardcoded for a specific data type, which is person.
So we learned about generics, right?
So we could look at making this repository class generic so that we don't have to explicitly refer to
a particular data type, right?
So let's just see what that might look like.
So we can simply say that this takes something of type T, right?
And then we can replace the word person with T everywhere.
All right, so where else do we refer to capital person?
I think that's it.
Actually, those are the only two places that I see at the moment.
OK, so let's go back.
And now let's pass in a tight right, so it's going to be a person, right?
Just like that.
OK.
And then let's jump back in here again and I will clean up my imports now.
OK, so next, I'm kind of analyzing what's going on in here.
OK, so the first bit is this first line here, and that actually fills mostly like boilerplate to me,
with the exception of the fact that we've got this sequel constant that that we're using here.
So next, let's see what other red marks can we get rid of.
So we've got this connection here.
That's an easy one.
I think we can go ahead and just redefine a connection, I think.
In fact, let's see here.
Let's make that protected.
Connection connect, what's connection like, so and we will import that.
All right now, to get that connection into here, we're probably going to just need a constructor just
like we did before, so I'm just going to do a command in and generate that constructor.
All right.
So there's a little bit of red gone now.
The next bit of red that we've got here is this sequel.
Now this is currently a constant that we define in the subclass, but maybe we want to try to figure
out a way to get this sequel string into here.
And honestly, if we could just get our hands on this sequel right here, the rest of this line could
really be reused.
So I want to show you a trick that we can use to get around this kind of issue.
What we can do is actually just replace this with a call to a method, and I'll show you what I mean
here.
Let's see what this would look like if we did something like get save.
Sequel.
OK.
And then I'll put my cursor right there and let the idea generate this method for us.
Like so.
Now, here's the thing.
What I'm thinking is our subclass, which is now the person repository class, I would like to have
our subclass be kind of like forced to implement this method so that it will return whatever sequel
we want this to, you know, return.
But I want it to be forced to do it.
Can you remember a way that we can define a method like this one on a super class and then force its
subclasses to have to implement this method or any other method that we want?
Can you think of a way to do that?
We've learned this.
OK, so a way that we could do that would be to make this method abstract.
So when you have an abstract method defined on a class, it means that subclasses of that class must
implement that method and that you're not going to implement it on the defining class, in fact, OK.
So we could do that.
However, if we want this method to be abstract, then the entire class actually has to be abstract.
So let's see what that would look like.
So I'm just going to replace the public here with abstract, with the abstract keyword.
And then if we come down here and replace private with abstract.
And then we when it's abstract, you don't need curly braces because you can't implement anything.
So I'm just going to select all of that and do this, OK?
And so now we will be able to let this save method get its hands on the sequel that is needed by calling
the get saved school method of a subclass.
OK?
And so now let's jump back over to the people repository and see what that might look like.
Are person people repository.
All right, so now we've got some errors, and that's because of a couple of things, we're going to
need to implement that abstract method now.
So let me put my cursor here and do a control o for override so that I can override this get saved sequel
method right there.
All right.
And so now what I'm going to do is simply return this constant right here.
OK, so return that, and so the red error that was up here went away.
Now we've got a red area here, and if I hover over that, that's complaining about the fact that because
now this people repository is extending the credit repository, I need to have this constructor call
the superclass constructor.
OK, so I'm going to go ahead and do that so we can call super.
And then pass in our connection.
And now this line here is not needed.
And in fact, this connection here is not needed because this people repository is now inheriting a
connection from here, right?
That protected connection.
OK.
So it's got one, in fact.
Maybe I'll go and just get rid of that and I will get rid of that too.
All right.
So let's jump back over here now these lines here where we are binding the fields from our person to
the prepared statement so that it can be executed.
These parts, I think, would definitely need to be different from one implementation to another.
Right.
And so I'm thinking at at the very least, these lines here also can be template ties.
OK, so here's what I think we can do.
Let's we've we've got these lines selected already and I'm thinking, let's extract the method out.
I'm going to do an option, command em or control alt them for Windows and Linux, and that'll extract
out a method.
And now I need to name this method something.
And maybe let's try naming it something like map for save.
Let's see how that a look.
OK.
Map for safe.
And so the I.D. decided to make the inputs for this new method.
The person and then the prepared statement, and that seems possibly reasonable to me.
Now let's make the name of this variable a little more generic, though, since this will be reusable,
it's not going to just be hard coded for for saving people anymore.
Okay, so I'm putting my cursor there and I'm going to do a shift of six.
And let's just call it entity.
And I mentioned this before.
Anytime you have a class that is designed to work with a database to be saved and retrieved from it
to and from a database, the generic term for that type of class or at least for those types of objects
of that class, is entity.
OK.
So that word entity actually has meaning.
It just means an object that works with databases.
Essentially, someone hit enter.
OK, so now we've renamed that.
And so now I think we will just make this abstract also.
So again, I will replace the word private with abstract, and then I will leave in the throws circle
exception.
But I will get rid of everything else and replace all that.
Oops.
Got too much.
I think.
But I will replace everything else with a semicolon just like that.
So there's that and then the rest of this, I think, is boilerplate.
You'll execute it, you'll get back the rose affected, you can get the generated keys.
Now the next thing that we do that's in error, though, is that we get that idea and then we set it
back on the person, which is soon to be just renamed, I guess, entity.
In fact, let's go ahead and rename that up here as well.
I'm going to put my cursor on the word person and then do another shift f six and rename that entity.
And I think it's just asking me, Do I want to do that everywhere?
Let's click.
OK, here we go.
OK.
All right.
So the only other thing we need to do now is to fix this bit here, said it.
And the reason that's red is because we've generic sized this entity now.
And therefore, the Aideed has no idea if there is a set ID method on a class of type T.
Right?
So one way that we could fix that and we've done a little version of this, I don't remember when maybe
back in their collections, maybe when we created our poor man's repository the first time we briefly
introduced an interface.
And I think we called it something like Idea Bill, and I'm kind of thinking we could do something along
those lines again so that basically any entity needs to be able to have and have a getter and a setter
for its IDE.
So let's let's see what that might look like.
If you're not following me, that's OK.
I think you will in just a moment here.
So let's go to the person class person.
OK, here's the person class.
So let's see what would happen if we made the person class implement and entity interface instead of
idea.
Well, let's let's let's see what it looks like if we introduce an interface called entity.
Let's see what this will be.
So implements entity.
All right.
So it's red, and now if we do an option return, let's create an interface, or let's let the ABC create
this interface called entity.
And we will allow it to be in the model package for now.
OK.
So there's that.
Now if we jump back over here.
Let's go find the getter and setter methods here.
And what I'm thinking is maybe we can have the I.D. do a little refactoring for us.
Yeah, here we go.
Pull members up.
So I just came in here, too.
So here, let me do that again.
So with my cursor on the Get ID method here, I probably could be anywhere.
Actually, I'm going to right click on empty space, go down to refactor and then I'm going to go to
this pull members up.
Now, when you click on that, so we may have done this before, I don't recall, but the idea of pull
pulling numbers up just means that if a class has a super class or in this case, an interface, you
may want to take some of the methods or fields of that class, which are the members of the class,
and pull them up into either the super class or, in this case, the interface in the case of the super.
The idea is basically going to just cut those members that you select and again, members are fields
and or methods.
It's going to cut them out of the subclass and then paste them back up into the super class.
And sometimes it will change the visibility as needed to be at least protected or something like that.
In the case of an interface that you're pulling things up into, it will basically just copy the signature
of methods and then paste them into the interface.
OK, so let's let's try this out.
So we're going to grab the Get ID and the Set ID methods here, and that's all I want.
And then let me make that a little more visible, OK, and then I'm going to click refactor.
All right.
So let's see what just happened now because you don't really see any change here, and I wouldn't expect
to other than the fact that these are now labeled override.
OK.
So let's jump over here into the entity interface.
And there we go.
So now we see that there's a Get ID and a Set ID defined on the interface.
OK.
So in and of itself, that didn't really do anything yet.
But now let's jump over into this crud repository, and now we can do something kind of cool.
I think we can redefine this generic key to not just be any random class in the world, but instead
we can define it as being a class that extends the entity interface.
OK.
So I'm going to select the entity interface that I just created under neutrino, right?
This one, not these other things.
Right?
And then hit enter.
And now look what just happened.
Like, instantly this set ID thing here.
The red marks there went away because now the system at least knows that entity is something that extends
or really implements the entity interface, and therefore it has a set ID method on it.
OK, so now we've just satisfied that error that was that was previously there.
All right.
So now let's jump back over to our person repository and see what we need to do for that map for save
method.
OK.
So we'll jump back over.
By the way, I'm doing a command.
Oh, and then I'm going to type in person repository.
Oops!
And then person repository.
There we go.
OK.
So now I've got red squiggles here because I need to implement that additional method now.
So I'm going to put my cursor, I guess, right under this Get Saved sequel there.
Make a couple of lines.
Do a control o choose map for Save.
Click OK.
And now what I think I should be able to do, hopefully, is just grab these lines here.
Just those three copy them and then paste them right there.
And now I think maybe, just maybe, possibly we don't need this save method anymore.
So I'm going to comment it out for right now.
OK.
So wouldn't that be awesome if this is all it takes now to implement a save method, just to have a
method that generates the sequel and then a method that does the mapping essentially?
So we don't have to wonder.
We've got a whole suite of tests that we can actually go rerun right now and see if this will actually
work.
I don't see any errors here whatsoever.
Let me just jump back over to the crud repository real quick.
And yeah, I don't see any errors here either.
So.
I think we are ready to go, try running our tests and see if we have inherited a working save method
now.
So jumping back over to the people repository tests, and I'm just going to rerun all the tests and
see what happens.
Oh, wow, look at that.
Everything is still working.
I think that's pretty cool, right?
OK, so let's jump back over to the repo now.
So that's pretty nice, I think.
Right.
This is all we need now in order to save a person.
And this gets us a step closer to having a reusable, generic, literally generic crud repository class
that will allow us to more quickly create additional repositories, hopefully.
OK, so now that that all seems to be working, I'm going to get rid of all of that.
There we go.
And that, my friends, is one way that we can do some nice refactoring to cut down on boilerplate code.
So in the next lesson, let's just go hit another one of these methods and do the same operations again
and see if we can eventually get this entire class condensed down really nicely.
And then we can go create another repository for another type of entity entirely.
See you in the next one.