All right.
So now that we've learned about big decimal and big integer and the wrapper classes and all of that,
let's put some of this knowledge to work and let's do something a little less trivial with money based
calculations.
So one of my favorite things to do is to play around with compound interest calculators, either online
or whatever.
So let's try making a method that can calculate compound interest for us.
And I have a formula here that I will pull up.
So this is on the website called Money Chimp Dot Com, and they have a compound interest calculator
that we can use to check our work when we're done implementing this.
But on their website, they also give the formula that they use for calculating compound interest.
Now there are a few variations on how to calculate compound interest.
The one that I think we're going to go with is one that factors in contributions.
And so that will be this formula right here where you can calculate a balance given that you have a
principal and interest rate or a rate of return and some time in years and a contribution amount.
So we're going to translate this into Java code.
All right.
Using a the decimal.
So to get started here first, let me make this window a little smaller.
And I'm going to put it somewhere where we can keep our eye on the formula there.
We'll make it a little bigger.
OK.
And then over here, what we will do is let's create a new class.
We're going to lose this window for a moment, but we'll bring it back.
So we're going to create a new class.
Let's see here, Java class.
Let's call this compound interest.
Calc, because that's what it is.
All right.
And so this class is going to have a method on it.
And because we're going to be doing compound interest calculations, the return type is going to represent
money, and we now know because I think I've put it into everyone's head that anytime we're doing money
based calculations in Java, we must use what type.
If you said big decimal, you would be right.
And so let's go ahead and make a method that's going to return a big decimal.
And let's see, we'll call this method calculate.
And let's take a look at our formula here.
So what are the inputs?
So it looks like the inputs are any of the variables that are on the right hand side because the output
is what we're going to get back.
So we've got a principle, right?
That's your starting balance.
We've got a rate of return, right?
The R we've got Y, which stands for the time in years.
And we've got see, which represents a annual contribution.
OK, so principal rate years and contributions.
So we've got four inputs here.
OK, so let's decide that we will specify these inputs as strings because we already know that when
dealing with big decimal, the most accurate way to initialize the big decimal is with strings.
So let's just start right off with the strings.
OK.
All right.
So first one up is the principle.
So let's use a string.
And we're going to call this principle.
All right.
Then we've got a rate and we'll use a string for that as well.
And we've got a period which is the amount of time in years now, honestly, I'm debating whether or
not I really want to make that a string because I think we could get away with that just being whole
numbers like an integer.
So I'm actually going to go ahead and model that one as an integer.
It doesn't matter a whole lot, but I think that'll be easy enough to to work with.
So for the period, we'll make it an integer.
And then we've got our contribution contribution, which is money.
And so that's definitely going to be a string because it's a floating point value.
So we'll do a string.
Contribution.
All right, one, two three.
We've got four inputs, I think that covers everything.
All right.
Let's get started.
First thing I think I want to do here is to copy this formula so that I don't have to keep paging back
and forth.
And for now, I'll just put that right here as a as a comment.
So notice, when I do a comment, I just do two forward splashes of space and then I can paste that
right in just like that.
All right, then I'm going to get rid of this project sidebar here so that we can have a little more
room.
So we need to translate this formula into Java code.
Now one of the things that sticks out for me right away is that we've got this term one plus are repeated
a couple of times here, so I'm inclined to let that term be represented by a variable so that it's
a little bit easier for us to put this thing together.
So let's tackle that first.
Let's make a variable that represents this term OnePlus.
Ah.
So let's let everything be a big decimal, so we'll create a big decimal.
Now, I'm not a finance major, so I don't even know if there is a an English term for what this OnePlus
R represents.
Unfortunately, I don't know what that is.
So, but, but I need to name this variable something so I could either give it an abstract name, which
I don't normally like to do, or I could name it something that reminds me of the fact that it represents
OnePlus R or if I knew what that actually represented, I would give it the real name, but I don't
know what that is.
So unfortunately, I'm inclined to simply name this something somewhat abstract and not very meaningful,
such as unfortunately a.
So I'm going to say a equals.
And now so we want to do one plus.
Ah, so I'm going to start off with a big decimal now.
I happen to know that the number one actually is a defined constant on the big decimal class, and I'll
show you that right here.
There it is, right there one.
So that's a quick way that I can create a big decimal equivalent of the number one.
Just the convenience.
And then, as you know, we can't use the regular math operators when dealing with big decimal.
We have to use methods.
And so if I put a period here, I can then get to the various methods of big decimal.
And there is an add method which takes as input, another big decimal.
And so the other big decimal that I want here is for this R R stands for the rate and I have a rate
which is of type string.
So what I can do is just create a new big decimal.
And I can use the version of the big decimal constructor that takes a string and so I can just pass
in the rate just like that.
And so now.
This a equals one plus are.
And if I want to, I can put a little comment here just reminding myself that that's what this is one
plus ah.
So next up, I think what I want to tackle is the innermost bits of this formula and then work my way
out from there.
So in other words, kind of doing loops.
So in other words, kind of starting off with we, we tackled this right?
And and then it looks like there's another thing where this times y is something and then this times
y minus one is something as well.
So I want you to kind of understand my thinking here.
And by the way, I mean, my thinking may not be 100 percent totally ideal.
I haven't worked this out before I started recording because I kind of want you to see how I'm thinking
about this now.
I have implemented compound interest calculations before, but I don't do it so often that I've got
everything memorized, right?
And it's been I don't know how long it's been since I last did this in Java, especially.
So one of the things I'm thinking now is do I want to create another variable that represents the OnePlus
hard times y and then just leave it there?
And then a third variable that would take all of this minus one, so I could just keep building on it
that way.
And that certainly would be easy to do, though, you know, I'm going to have a few lines there, not
a lot, but a few lines.
Or do I want to get a little more adventurous and try to do the OnePlus hard times y minus one, all
kind of in one fell swoop?
Maybe I could do that.
I think I'm going to keep it a little simple, though, and just do one bit at a time.
And that way, I can kind of keep myself out of trouble.
So the next bit that I'm going to go for is this because I've already got a which represents OnePlus
are.
And now all I need to do is multiply that times why and and that's easy enough.
So let's do that.
Now I need another name for that term.
And again, because I don't know what if there is a an actual, meaningful name for what this represents
mathematically.
I'm just going to have to create a generic number or a generic name for it.
And I've already used a.
So my next one, I guess, will be.
Please know I'm not a big fan of naming variables in this kind of meaningless way, but in this particular
case, because I'm not a math or finance major, I just I don't know what these terms, if these terms
even have any real world meanings.
So I don't feel that I have much choice right now.
All right, so.
Create another big desk, the moment to call this one be.
Equals and so now this one is going to be simply.
Eh, because eh, is one plus are a times y, that's it.
So that should be really easy.
So A.
Multiply.
And then why now, why is the period because why stands for years?
And so that is the period here now.
My period here as an input is an integer, and I think I'm OK to just use that integer, as is in this
particular case.
I'm not worried that an integer is going to have any issues with precision or rounding because it's
an integer.
There's no decimal point there.
It's kind of one of the reasons why Semi intuitively thought, you know, I don't think I can model
that just as an integer.
I don't need it to be a string.
All right, so multiply that now.
Again, the multiply method takes a big decimal, though, so I have to create a new big decimal.
And then here, though, I can pass in just that period, and there we go.
And then I'll use another inline comment just to remind myself of what is this?
So I think the way I'm going to remind myself of this is this by copying this bit right here and then
pasting it right there.
So one plus are times why that's what this is.
All right?
And now I'm ready to go to the next bit, which is all of this minus one.
And so that should be easy enough.
So I'll create another variable.
Again, I'm just going to name it badly.
C equals.
Be.
Because B is one plus one plus our times y right?
This whole bit.
B.
Subtract.
And then one and again, I can just use the constant of one.
Just like that.
And so now C equals.
All of this.
All right, now, we're ready to get all of this divided by, AH.
And you see what's happening here as we just slowly expand out each individual calculation is quite
simple.
All right, so create another big decimal.
I'm going to just call this one D equals C.
Divided by ARE, which is our rate, so I'll need a new big decimal and then I will pass in.
Ah, which is the rate?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Rate, not our rate.
Now if you will recall.
When using the divide method of big decimal, you can pass in optionally an additional math context,
in fact, there's a few variations of it where we can specify how many significant digits we want and
how to round off like what what strategy for rounding.
We want to use.
So you'll need we'll need to kind of decide, do we need to specify that now or can we get away without
doing that?
I usually like to live a little bit on the edge, I guess so I'm and I'm kind of lazy, so I'm inclined
not to specify that until we run the program and it blows up if it blows up.
And then I will know, OK, maybe I should do that.
So I'm going to leave that out for right now and just roll the dice and see what we get.
All right.
So now this part would be all of this.
All right, and now we're ready to multiply D or all of this times.
See our contribution.
And again, that's going to be pretty easy.
So I'm going to just call it E equals D.
Multiplied by new big decimal contribution.
There we go.
And so now.
Variable E represents all of that.
And by the way, I mean, maybe I would I may or may not always break everything down so explicitly
and then had these inline comments.
I suppose I'm partially doing that for clarity for you because you're following along.
I'm not saying that I wouldn't, though I might not do it quite so explicitly on every single line in
real life.
But it's not a bad way to go, really.
You know, it's super clear, right?
All right.
Now what I am inclined to do is tackle this side of the plus side by itself.
And then once I have all of that built up, then the last thing I will do is do this addition on both
as opposed to I mean, that's pretty much the only approach that makes any sense to me because we've
got this term already calculated in a right.
And now we need to multiply it times the P and the Y.
So the multiplication here would take precedence over anything we could do with this addition anyway.
And so in terms of the order of operations and the precedent of everything, this addition would have
to be the last thing we would do.
Right.
Because addition comes after multiplication in general, unless you got parentheses and things.
Now I think we can get away with doing this multiplication of the P in the Y in this term, a all in
one fell swoop, though let's let's see if we can.
So let's create another big decimal we'll call this f equals.
And I don't know, we can start off with the OnePlus R, which is a right right there.
OnePlus R is a.
So we can start off with a multiply times the principal p the principal.
So we'll do a new big decimal and then we can just pass in principle like so.
And then I think we can just do another multiply and then add in the the why, which is our period.
Like so, OK, so here we combined a couple of math operations, all in one line, and we kind of strung
them together a daisy chain.
This is called method chaining when you just keep calling methods like that.
I don't like to do a whole lot of it in many cases, but in this particular case, it's cool.
I mean, there may have been a way that we might have figured out how to method chain the whole entire
thing, but it would have made for a very difficult to understand and difficult to debug bit of code,
most likely.
And so that's why I opted not to do that for the whole entire formula or not to even try.
All right.
And so finally.
I think we only have one bit more to do.
We will now take F and ad. Let's see.
So this term now I got to go find it's this one right here, right, which is e so f + e well, that's
easy enough.
F + e.
And then we can return the result, which is, gee, there we go now, let's see if this actually works.
So to try this out, I will create a public static void method main here so that we have a method that
we can actually run.
And you know, actually, since this calculate method does not depend on any variables from outside
of it.
In other words, all of its input is kind of self-contained.
There's no reason why we should need to instantiate or create an instance of this calculator class.
So if we want to call this calculate method, the easiest thing we could do is just make this method
static.
And that way, we don't have to create an instance of the compound interest count, if you don't know
what I'm referring to.
I will just remind you that when a method is static, we don't need to instantiate the class that it
lives on in order to call it.
OK.
So if I had wanted to call this calculate method without making it static, I would first have had to
do something like compound interest.
Calc count equals new compound interest count like this.
Then I could call Calc Dot.
Calculate, but if I didn't want to go through all of that, I could simply make this calculate method
static.
And by doing so, we can just call it directly by doing compound interest, calc dot calculate just
like that.
And we will do so.
So now let's come up with some values, so let's start with a principle of 10000.
Dollars.
And a rate of, oh, I don't know, let's two point zero eight, so eight percent and a period of 10
years with an annual contribution of one thousand dollars and then let's capture the output of that.
And that would be our it would be our balance.
And then let's print that.
All right.
Let's run this and see what we get.
Let's see if it blows up or not.
OK does not blow up, so it says we would get 230000, $500 so in 10 years at eight percent with a thousand
dollars added per year and starting with 10 grand, you'd end up with $230000.
So now let's see if this is actually correct.
And to do that, we will go back over to our compound interest calculator here and let's actually run
it.
So I just clicked on the calculator link here, so let's plug in those same numbers which have already
kind of forgotten.
So let's see here for the current principal, we said ten thousand.
And for the annual edition, we said one thousand and for the years to grow, we said ten years.
And we said and a rate of eight percent.
Now notice here I'm entering an integer of eight because they're telling me that it's meant to be percent.
So they're going to do the math for me and we can revise our application to to do that for us as well.
But in our application right now, the way that it's written, we have to pass it in as an actual decimal
point of zero point zero eight.
All right.
And now when we hit the calculate button, let's see what we get.
Oh.
Way different.
Thirty seven thousand two hundred thirty four.
OK, so we got the wrong answer there, so let's figure out why.
So looking back at our formula, I think I already see what the problem is here.
When I copied and pasted this formula into our code right here, these y's here, these two y's turned
into terms that are being multiplied, whereas and I should have known that looked weird, whereas in
the original formula, they are actually exponents.
In fact, I kind of felt like it was a little easier than I was expecting it to have been.
And that is why.
So these y's here are an exponent.
But when I copied and pasted them, they just turned into values that looked like they were just being
multiplied times the rest of this.
So we need to just fix that.
We need.
We don't want to multiply p times one plus our times y we want one plus r to the Y power.
OK.
That's what we want.
So actually, I think this will be pretty easy.
We stored one plus R in its own term and it was the very first term that we tackled.
So I think what we can do is simply just add on this to the y power to that first term, and we're good.
So we'll come over here.
Here's that first term a right where we did one plus r here is the one plus R right here.
And I think what we can do is simply chain one more method call on here.
And so first off, in the comments here, I'm going to represent the raising of two a power with the
carrot symbol, which is a common symbol used for that and a lot of programming anyway.
So we will say that that will be raised to the Y and here Y is, period.
OK.
And so that's how we'll do that.
And so here what we'll do is we'll just chain now to raise to a power.
We use the P.O.W or power method right here and we can pass in an integer.
And that was the other reason why I chose to model the period as an integer because as I was looking
here and I saw that this was to be raised to that value.
I knew that the power method would be needed and the power method takes an integer.
And so this would be a very nice, easy, direct way to do this.
All right.
So we'll just pass in the word period right there.
And now we need to fix what we were doing with this, though, where we were multiplying right here,
one plus our times y let's see, we were doing that right here, so we no longer need to do that.
So let's see how that's going to look now if we stop doing this.
And what I'm thinking here is Liz's commented out and then see what breaks.
OK?
So we were doing b minus one, which was this one plus are supposed to be to the Y minus one.
So I think what we can do now is simply do a.
A, which would be one plus R to the Y power and then C would be all of that minus one.
So look how easy it was to fix this because we broke it down into small pieces, right?
And so, yeah, I don't think we need this metal piece.
I'm going to go ahead and delete it now.
Sometimes I'm what I might have done instead is just to run this whole program, but I'm pretty confident
that we're going down the right road.
I'm not going to promise it's all going to work perfectly just yet, but I think we're going down the
right road, so I'm comfortable to delete this line here.
All right.
And in fact, let me just fix this also, and I'm going to fix that everywhere, I suppose now.
Let's see, we did have this term one plus R to the Y.
A couple of times, though.
All right, so let's run this again and see what we get now.
Let's see, was that two hundred thirty thousand three hundred seventy nine?
Let's see what we got over here.
Nope, still completely wrong because here we're getting 37000.
Here we're getting 230000.
OK, I suspect the issue is with this this part p times one plus are to the why.
So let's find that p times one plus are.
OK, here, I think it is, and see, I already had forgotten to put the comment there.
And so that took me a little longer to find it.
So that's a good reason why I probably should have kept using the comments.
So a which is now one plus are to the period times principle are times period.
So we don't need this now.
Yeah, this is wrong time period.
We don't need that.
In fact, we don't want that.
OK, so now what we have is a which would be all of that.
Oops, forgot to comment it.
All of that.
Times.
Principal.
Which is what we have here.
P times.
A.
Let's run it again and see, hey, I think that's looking like a winner.
Thirty six thousand seventy five and eighty one cents.
Let's go back here.
Ooh, little bit off, huh?
We've got 37000 to 34.
OK.
What is that all about?
Let's see.
Thirty six thousand seventy five.
Here we've got thirty seven thousand two hundred thirty four.
Now what this may be is the difference between making annual additions at the start or at the end of
the compounding period.
Let's see what we get.
If we say at the end are that that's the difference right there.
So the formula that we were using was one that gives us the compounding at the end of each period,
which is fine.
I don't care which one we use.
We just needed to make sure we were comparing apples to apples here.
So when we switch that over, we get the exact same number 36000, 75 and 81 cents, thirty six thousand
seventy five and 81 cents.
There we go.
OK.
So we have just implemented a nice little compound interest calculator in Java, and we ran into a little
bit of trouble.
I'm going to leave that in this lesson.
Hopefully, it won't confuse you, but you'll get to see that even a professional can make dumb mistakes
sometimes in this case.
I was led astray by the fact that I, you know, copied and pasted this in here, and then that changed
the interpretation of the formula itself.
And I didn't quite catch it before it hurt us, but it was easy enough to fix right now in the next
lesson.
Let's learn how we can format these strings so that they look nice because you wouldn't want to show
this to your users of your program.
So we'll do that in the next video.