OK.
In this lesson.
Let's run through some of the more common methods that exist on the map interface and see how they work
and how we can use them.
So turning back to the A.D., we're still in the main class, and I think what I'm going to do is just
come up here to where we are printing out the the the map itself, right?
We're just passing an entire map into a system out that print line.
So what we can do here is just put the cursor right after the map reference there, the variable there
and and then a period and then we can start looking at some of the methods.
So I'm just going to run through these methods.
I may not explicitly show each and every one.
And in fact, I definitely definitely will be skipping over a few for now.
Now we will come back and look at some of the methods that I'm skipping over in later lessons or modules,
but we're not quite ready to get into every single one of these methods here.
All right.
So we've already seen the get method and as you can see, you pass in a key.
The signature here shows that it's an object, just a generic object.
And you'll recall that object is the super, super super class of all classes, and they're just being
very generic here.
That's why they're using the the class object instead of being more specific.
All right.
And and then we've also used put that's how we actually get key value pairs into a map.
We'll skip over compute for now.
Values is an interesting one, so values will actually get returned back a collection of all of the
values that we've added into the map.
So again, keep in mind that whenever we call put, we are adding essentially a new row of a key value
pair, right?
So you can think of it as a two column row.
OK.
Every time we call put, as long as the key is unique, you'll get a new row, so you're going to have
all these rows of two columns.
Right?
But if you call the values method, it will return a collection.
You can think of it as a list or set whatever you want to think of it, as it will return a collection
of just the values, right?
So just that second column.
OK.
So let's go ahead and actually just use this real quick and we'll actually see it.
So I'm just going to change line 60 to print out whatever is in whatever is returned from the map values
method call.
OK.
So if we take a quick look down here before I run it, you'll see that currently, if we are just printing
the map on its own, we see these key value pairs, right?
So each of these comma separated groupings here is what's called a key value pair.
Because we've got the key, then the equals sign and then the value.
So if we call the map that values method, what we should see are just the values themselves without
the keys and without the equals sign.
Now one thing before I run this, it might be a little clearer if we actually revert some of the changes
that we recently made, specifically the change that we made to to have the value, be the entire object,
right, as I'm doing here.
So I'm going to actually put this back to just mapping the integer and now change this change this guy's
name again to what was this salary map?
And I'll explain in a little more detail why I'm making this change in just a moment.
So here as well, get salary and then down here, we don't want to do this anymore.
In fact, they'll just get rid of this method.
OK, so let's uh, let's see here, what do we have?
OK, so now salary map values, OK, so now we're ready to run this.
There we go.
So now we've just got a collection of just the values, right?
Instead of the key value pairs.
So I think that should be pretty clear.
The order, though, is still the same as it would have been if we were printing out the entire key
value pairs, by the way.
OK, we're just not seeing the keys.
So currently we're using a linked hash map, which means that these are the values in the insert order,
right?
In other words, these values should line up with the order in which each of these rows are in, except
for excluding the duplicates, though, right?
OK, so that's what the values method does.
And sometimes sometimes you need that functionality to just only get all of the values that are in a
map, and so there you go.
That's how you can do that.
OK, so there's that.
And and while we're talking about this, we might as well look at the other side of it as well.
There's another there's another method to do kind of the opposite of that instead of getting the values,
you want to get the keys right.
So there's a method called key set.
So this specifically will return a set of keys.
So the values method returns a collection.
They're intentionally being somewhat vague as to what the underlying collection implementation will
be.
But in this case, for the method that will return a collection of the keys, they're being very specific
in saying this is a set.
The reason for that is because in a map, you've got all these key value pairs, but the keys are really
important.
They have to be unique.
Right?
I already mentioned before that with these most standard implementations of the map interface, you
cannot have duplicates any time.
You have this idea that there's no there are no duplicates being permitted.
You're thinking of a set.
OK.
And so that's why they're they're making it so that if you want just the keys out of the map, they're
going to map those keys to a set.
OK, because that's the that's the concept of no duplicates is implemented by a set.
OK, so anyway, I will select that and then we'll run this again and see what we get.
OK, so now we're getting just the first names, right?
Fred in a Fred to Fred, three, Fred four, et cetera, et cetera.
So this isn't this is not unlike what we would have gotten if we were simply printing the employees
using one of our sets, right?
It's the same thing, pretty much.
OK.
So again, sometimes you just want to extract all of the keys of a map.
So we've looked at key set values get put.
Size gives you the size.
The number of entries.
Right?
OK, so yeah, the next thing we can look at is entry set that makes a lot of sense.
So now notice here we've got this method entry said that returns also a set, but it returns a set that's
a little bit complex in terms of its generic definition.
It returns a set of something called an entry of string and integer.
In this particular case, the string an integer is easy to understand that came from us.
When we created our instance of the salary map, we declared it to be generic and to hold strings and
integers.
So that's where this bit is coming from.
So if we were to go and change that, like I had changed it earlier to mapping a string to an employee,
right?
And so if I went back and changed that again and then we came back in and looked and looked again,
this would no longer say integer.
It would say employee or whatever data type.
I set the generic to the generic to this entry thing, though I haven't spoken explicitly about it.
So the entry, that's actually a special data type that comes with Java, and you can really think of
it.
It's actually quite simple.
You can really think of it as a class with two properties a property called key and a property called
value.
That's really all it is.
OK, so it's just a class that group's key value pairs together and it is called entry.
OK.
And so what this is saying is that these key value pair thingies can be placed inside of a collection,
which is a set right?
So you've got a list of them.
Essentially, I use the word list in the English sense, not in the Java collections framework since,
but you get what I mean, right?
It's a a list or an ordered, a collection of these key value pairs that is an entry.
OK, so let's try this out.
And let me delete that and let me close this and let's see what we get here.
OK, so that actually looks identical to simply printing the salary map all by itself, right?
You don't see any difference there.
And that makes sense, really.
So why might we want to use this method entry set?
Well, sometimes you want to iterate over the entries themselves.
And this is one way that you could do it.
In fact, they will show you really quickly what that code might look like.
So you could have a for loop where you say something like entry.
Of string comma integer.
And I'll have to import that class.
And now notice here, I'm get, I'm giving, I'm given two options of which entry class I want to import.
You want the one that comes from map.
Right?
Because we're working with a map, this other one has nothing to do with that.
So you want this this one for map and notice it even pins it with map dot entry because the entry is
actually a nested interface inside of the map interface.
So that's why it's prepend it here with map port entry.
All right, so anyway, so yeah, you could have a map that entry here, and then I will just call this
entry and then a colon.
And then you could say a salary map dot entry set, and now you can iterate over the actual entries
within the map.
OK, so you could do something like
here's a formatted string, and I don't know.
I could say key equals percent s.
Comma value equals percent as percent in karma.
Entry does not get key.
Comma entry, dot get value.
Right.
Does this make sense?
In fact, I will go ahead and even run this.
There we go.
So.
Now you have, you know, an iterative way of accessing the key value pairs one pair at a time, right?
And then you can do whatever you want with those guys right off of these entry objects.
OK.
So I hope that makes sense.
You can just think of them as rows in a spreadsheet, right with the two columns and you're you're getting
one row at a time.
That row is called an entry.
All right.
So that's how you can use the entry set.
And work with entries, by the way.
One of the thing I will note about the entry, by the way, it has a few other methods on it.
Let's take a really quick look at some of those methods.
So we worked with the get value, get key and get value.
There's also a set value, though, so you could replace the value in an entry by calling the set value
method.
OK.
And then the rest of the methods are boilerplate that aren't really worth going over.
All right.
But that's how we can use the entry set method of the map interface.
OK, then we've got contains key.
So this is so this is very similar to the contains method on the other collection classes like list
and set.
So if you wanted to know if there's a Wilma in the map, assuming that the map is mapping first names
to something else, you could have the string Wilma and then call it contains key.
And then it would be turned back a boolean true or false if the name Wilma is contained as a key in
the map.
Same thing for contains value, right?
If you have a value like a number, an integer and you wanted to know, is this integer contained within
the values column of this map?
It would return a true or false.
So that should be pretty straightforward.
Get or default is a really cool method, actually.
Let me show you actually what this one is for.
So coming down here to our get salary method, have any of you wondered what would happen if we were
to pass in a name that we know isn't contained in the keys of this map, right?
What would you get back out?
So actually, let's just try that out right now and see, OK, so we've got a test that's testing out
this method.
So if I jump back over to that test and I don't know, let's just create another test to try out this
scenario
test, let's call it test bad name to salary.
So let's just do x x x x x, and let's run this and see what we get.
All right.
It fells, of course.
And if we highlight this guy and scroll down.
Cannot invoke integers into value because the return value is null, so it's returning a null.
OK, that's what we're getting back.
If you pass in a key to a map and you call it, get on that map with that key and that key is not contained
within the keys of the map, you will get back a null by default.
However, let's say that what the way we want the application to behave is that if you pass in an invalid
key, let's say that we just expect to get back a negative one.
OK, so I'm going to run this again, and it will still fail.
OK, so that's still failing.
And now let's jump back over to the system under test.
And now what we can do is change this from a get to a get or default.
And now the way that this method works is it still takes one input of the key, but it takes a second
input, which is a default value that you want the method to return.
If there is no match.
So if I now put a negative one right there, I am saying.
Try to get the value for the key that I'm passing in a first name, but if that results in a null or
if that key does not exist, then just return this default value of negative one rather than returning
a null, which isn't handled very nicely for the application.
So this is this is actually quite a nice method to use, and I would actually encourage you to strongly
consider letting this be kind of the default way that you may typically get data out of your maps.
OK, so now if we rerun this, let's see what we get.
There we go.
And now it's green.
OK, so that's a really nice one, and it saves you from having to type a bunch of code.
Now you could have done this yourself, right?
You could have we could have done something like, you know, if salary map does get first name.
Is null, then return negative one.
And then you could capture.
You could capture all of this into a variable return.
Value.
Else return value, right, you could do something like that, or you could be a little fancier, perhaps
and use a ternary, you get it right, but look at all that typing you have to do versus just using
the get or default, which does all of that for you.
OK, so that's a really cool method there that they've included.
Very, very helpful.
All right.
Let's see what else we got.
Is empty should be pretty self-explanatory.
It checks to see if the if there are any entries in the map at all, and again, an entry is equivalent
to a row of two columns, right?
So if there are no rows of data added into the map, then the is empty method will return.
True are put if absent.
This is a good one.
Now remember I was stating that generally speaking with regards to duplicates.
When we have all of these duplicates here, what's happening is that as we're putting the first name
and then the calculated value into the map, the map is accepting each new value for the same name of
Fred.
OK, so it's not allowing for duplicates, but it is allowing for overwriting each time we try to put
a new value for an existing key.
And that is why it is this last value that is actually persisting for the Fred key and not the first
value, right?
That's what it's doing.
However, there is an alternative way to change that behavior.
So if if you were to use the put, if absent method here and in fact, we can go ahead and just try
this out and see what will happen.
So currently we're using put right here, let's just run this again so we can see the the output that
we were getting.
OK, so we're getting Fred equal to one point two, six million or something like that, right?
But if we change this to a put, if absent, let's see what we get now.
I'll just rerun it.
Hey, look at that, you don't get a one point two, six million anymore.
Why is that?
Well, it's because if you use the put, if absent the what's what's happening now is the first time
the code tries to put Fred and whatever this value would be, that goes in to the map just fine the
next time it encounters a Fred, though it will now actually ignore this.
It won't even it won't actually update the value because it sees that we already have a Fred entry in
here.
And so as we try to add another Fred entry, it says, Well, I already have a Fred.
Fred is not absent.
Fred exists, and therefore I'm not going to update this value for Fred.
I'm going to stick with the original value that I had, which is this one right here.
And just to prove that we'll just change this value slightly from 2000 to maybe 2500.
OK.
So currently we're getting to eight 03, right?
So if we rerun this now, with that number having changed, this should change.
Two to three.
Yeah, now it's three, five, oh three, OK, so now we've kind of made it behave a little bit more
as a set as you might have thought of a set behaving right.
Yeah.
So it's no longer overwriting the so-called duplicates, right?
It's sticking with the first one and then ignoring the rest.
So that's a key thing to keep in mind also might come in handy sometime if you want that specific behavior
for your map.
But the default behavior is just to keep overwriting the value every time you see a duplicate or every
time it sees a duplicate.
All right, so put if absent, I think I'm going to put this back for now, no pun intended.
All right, so that's put.
What else do we have here?
You can remove an entry from the map.
Keep that in mind now.
If you call remove and you pass in a key, you're removing the entire row or the entry, right?
So you removing both the key and the value.
And that makes sense, right?
You can't have keys without values or values without keys, really.
Now you can have no in either the key or for either the key or the value or both.
So you can have that, but you can't.
But whatever you do, you're going to have an entry for each row.
OK, so the removed method will find whichever entry has that key.
If there is one and then it will remove it, and then it will return the value that was associated with
that key.
All right, and then put all is kind of a neat method.
I honestly have I don't know that I've used it very often, but let's say you have two maps.
And they both map the same data types, so they both map, for example, string to integer or whatever,
as long as they both map to the same types.
If you wanted to essentially kind of like merge the contents of one map to another, you can use put
all.
OK, so basically you would call, put all and then you would pass in the other map.
And then what?
What would effectively happen is that your your map a would now contain everything that it had before,
plus everything that was in the other map.
OK, so it's just kind of like able to merge two maps together to become one big super map.
And I think that's going to be about it for the most common methods that you're likely to encounter
or use on the map interface for now.
Now we will come back and revisit a number of the a few of the methods that I've skipped over here.
When we get more in even more in depth into lambdas and things like that, because there's some additionally
like really cool things that you can do, but we'll save that for another time.
So with that, we're going to close out this lesson and we'll see you in the next one.