All right, so now I want to present you with another scenario.
So here is the output of our current code iterates over each of the employees and presents how much
their salary is going to be right now.
What if we also wanted to calculate a bonus from the salary of the way the bonuses work at this particular
company is that they are just a simple, flat percentage, let's say, of the salary itself.
OK.
So how could we do that?
So one way we could consider doing it, I suppose, would be to go to each of the subclasses where we
currently have a get salary method right?
And we could do something like public.
Now this.
Let's see if we make this a percentage, I don't know.
It's probably going to end up being a double.
So we could do something like get bonus and then return the bonus.
And maybe it's based on the salary.
So salary time's on it.
So like, you know, plus 10 percent or something like that.
OK, now if this is the formula that we would use companywide, right?
So no matter whether you were a programmer, manager, CEO or analyst, your bonus is always just going
to be a flat 10 percent on top of your salary.
Let's say something like that, then that would mean that this code right here would simply be duplicated
across each of those subtypes.
Right?
Does that sound like a good idea now that you've learned a few things that we could do that it would
work?
Does that seem like something we should do, though?
Probably not, because that would just be blatant duplication of code with with no real benefit there.
So what's an alternative that we might be able to do?
I can.
I think I can hear you thinking and talking.
Yes.
So if you just said, well, we could just implement the get bonus method on the superclass.
You would probably be on to something.
So let's see what that would look like.
So we could go into the employee class here.
And we already have this kind of placeholder get salary method, in fact.
And so we could just maybe throw a get bonus method right here.
And now all of the subclasses will inherit this get bonus method right off the bat.
And they can all benefit from it.
And we don't duplicate this method 15000 times or in this case, four times, right?
We just put it in one nice place.
So pretty straightforward, right?
OK.
Now there's one more thing I want to lay out, though in this scenario.
So right now, we are actually implementing the get salary method, right?
So let's do a couple of things now.
Currently, our employee superclass is still implementing the employee interface, and I just left that
there just for illustrative purposes.
I'm going to go ahead and actually remove this Snellville, because we actually never really needed
it.
And as soon as I do that, my employee class gets an error and the error is a small one.
It's just saying that, hey, since you removed that interface, this get salary method was being marked
with this annotation called override, and you're no longer actually overwriting anything.
So let me explain that real quick.
When we implement an interface on a class, we are forced to make sure that we have an implementation
of the methods on that interface.
So the I employee interface defines a get salary method with this signature here.
And so any class that implements that interface must implement the get salary method.
And when we implement that method, we can flag that we are implementing it with an at override annotation.
In this case, we didn't put this annotation here.
The ADP generated that for us whenever it was that we put the interface there or pulled this up from
the previous class, OK?
It put an override here, but now we're not overwriting anything.
There is no interface or super class from this class perspective where we're, you know, getting this
get salaries.
So now this is an error.
And it just needs to be removed.
And now no more errors on the class.
So that's what that was.
All right.
Now here's the next scenario that I want to lay out, though, because we have this get salary method
defined on the superclass employee technically.
In these subclasses here, we don't even have to have a get salary method anymore.
So if I were to just comment this out like so that doesn't break anything.
Well, yeah, that doesn't cause any errors.
However, now our calculations will be wrong.
So there's nothing forcing us to implement a specific version of the get salary method that could be
good.
That could be bad.
It depends on what you're needing.
It could be that someone who wants to create another type of employee might not realize that in order
for that employee to get their salary calculated properly, they needed to implement the get salary
method themselves.
They might not realize that with this current approach because there's nothing forcing us to do it,
at least with the interface.
Back before we had the superclass here, the interface would have forced us to implement the get salary
method.
But in this case, even though this programmer is implementing the employee, there's nothing complaining
about the fact that there's no get salary.
And the reason it's not complaining is because we do how they get salary method on the superclass.
And so the interface is happy as long as somebody is implementing the get salary method in the class
hierarchy structure.
The interface really Java.
The JDK is happy.
OK.
But in reality, this isn't good, right?
We know that this would actually doesn't break our compilation of the code, but it does break the desired
outcome.
Right?
Because we're no longer conveying how to handle salaries specifically for a programmer.
So what can we do about this?
All right.
So well, there is something we can kind of do about this along the lines of what we've already started
doing here.
If we go back to the employee class.
Let us first question what if we didn't want to supply this basically default implementation of get
salary, which is kind of a placeholder?
What if we didn't want to do this?
What if we wanted to ensure that subclasses of employee do definitely implement their own implementation
of the get salary method?
How can we ensure that they will do that?
That way, we make sure that no one forgets to implement it, right?
Well, there's a way to do this.
So so far, we've learned about interfaces and we've learned a little bit here about super classes in
general and how it's nice to use a super class to pull up any potentially duplicated code into one central
place among a class hierarchy.
Right.
Well, now we're going to learn about another type of class, which is called an abstract class.
OK.
So first, I'll show you how to make one, and then we'll talk a little more about what its uses are.
So to make an abstract class, all we do is just put the word abstract in front of the keyword class.
OK, and now we've made an abstract class.
Now on its own, that's not going to change very much.
Other than one thing that I'll show you real quick now that we've declared that the employee is an abstract
class.
Remember when I showed you this trick that if we wanted to get around this null issue, one way that
we could do so is by just instantiating the employee class directly like this.
Well, now we can't do that.
And the reason is because I've just declared the employee class to be abstract, which means it's not
a class that is meant for you to create instances of it is meant only to serve as a super class for
other classes, but it is not meant to create a standalone object instances on its own.
OK.
And so now I'm in error if I tried to create this, and in fact, the message tells me employee is abstract
cannot be instantiated.
So there you go.
All right, so you can't instantiate an abstract class.
All right.
So you may be wondering, OK, then what's it?
What's it any good for?
So let me undo this real quick.
All right.
Put that back to null.
Go back to the employee class here.
So what it's good for is if I have a method that I want to make use of in my super class, for example,
but I don't want to implement it in my super class.
I want to make sure that subclasses actually provide an implementation for that method.
I first must declare that the class is abstract.
That's step one, as I've done.
And then step two, I can declare a method to be abstract as well.
Now, when I do this, the method cannot have an implementation here.
So now I need to get rid of all of this.
So it actually looks pretty much like a method defined on an interface.
It's it basically is.
In fact, it's pretty much that it's this is kind of a hybrid, if you will, of a regular super class
and an interface kind of all together.
So what this is basically saying is I have this class here that can do real work with real methods.
But here's one method that I don't want to provide provide a concrete implementation for.
I want to flag this method such that subclasses of the employee class must implement this method in
order for the class hierarchy to be valid.
OK.
So if I go down to one of these subclasses like programmer?
I'm in error now, see this red mark here, and if I hover over this, it's going to tell me the programmer
must either be declared abstract or implement abstract method, get salary.
So it's complaining that I don't have a get salary method here.
So I either have to make this class abstract, which would mean that I'm going to kind of pass the buck
down to yet another level of class hierarchy, which, by the way, be careful with that you don't want
like, you know, three, four or five levels of hierarchy when you're doing object orientation, that's
really, really bad.
Keep it pretty shallow.
OK.
One two levels is is usually good.
If you're getting two, three and four, you probably want to step back and ask yourself, Am I going
crazy with this?
And you probably are.
All right.
So now if I uncomment this, that error went away, right?
And so now I am forced to implement the get salary method on all subclasses of the employee.
And therefore, I can't accidentally forget to implement this.
So if some a new programmer comes along and decides they want to define yet another type of employee,
they can do so.
But as soon as they do, they're going to get an error message telling them, Hey, you need to make
sure that you implement the get salary method.
So armed with this knowledge, let me show you what I was actually wanting us to do with this additional
little feature here.
So we go back to the employee superclass now, where we now have declared the get salary method to be
abstract, and therefore it is not implemented here.
It must be implemented in the subclasses.
So what's cool is we can still refer to this method in other places as if it's already implemented right
because we can trust that you're not going to, you know, have subclasses of this and this method is
not going to be implemented.
So one one one, the kind of neat things we can do is down here.
Look at this two string method.
We are referring to the get salary method, which is sort of referring to this, even though it's not
actually technically implemented yet.
So we're sort of like projecting into the future.
We're saying I don't know how the get salary method is going to be implemented, but I do know that
it's supposed to return an end.
So I'm going to just trust that there will be an implementation of this method and therefore let me
continue to call it from within my two string method.
And so what'll happen now is that as was already happening before actually is that the get salary method
will actually execute from the subclasses.
Right now, we can do one more thing here.
Let's say that we want to go ahead and present the bonus also so we can add that in now percent.
Yes.
Let me make some room here.
So we'll just add another another argument on the end of here money format format and then we'll just
call get bonus like so.
And so what's cool is the get bonus method also depends on this future to be implemented on subclasses
that this class doesn't even necessarily know anything about.
But it's saying, hey.
However, it is that subclasses will implement the get salary method.
Whatever that is, take that number and multiply it times one point one zero to get the bonus right.
So this is really cool.
And actually, there's a name for doing this.
It's called the template method pattern.
What we have done here is we've created a template for a method which will be actually implemented in
the subclasses.
But this is the template for it.
And because it's a template, it's like a cut out kind of like the rest of this class can still kind
of pretend like it's implemented and make calls to it code wise, right?
But actually, it'll be implemented later.
All right.
So super useful pattern.
By the way, there are a lot of patterns like this one that are more formally called design patterns.
OK.
So a lot of smart programmers over the decades have kind of discovered and then formalized common programming
patterns that they have encountered themselves or seen.
Others do that they find to be highly advantageous to writing good code, and they have decided to name
some of those patterns.
And so this is one of those patterns.
It's called the template method pattern.
OK.
All right.
So we've added.
This so let's jump back over to the main class now, and let's just run this again.
And now we should see the bonuses coming out as well.
Hey, there we go, and yeah, I'm going to assume that the math is is good.
Pretty sure it is.
So yeah, there we go.
And we only have to go to one place to make this change, which was just the the superclass of the employee.
So that's a really cool pattern to to use.
So let's recap real quick the difference between using the abstract class and the interface and just
a regular concrete superclass.
Right?
So we'll start with the interface.
So if you've got a bunch of classes like analysts, CEO, manager and programmer, then they all implement
one or more methods that take input or spit out output of the same type.
But internally, they do something different, which is the case here.
Right?
Our get salary methods are all doing something a little bit different internally, a little bit different
there, but they all return a salary right of some sort.
And if those classes don't have anything else in common, such as behavior, implementation or data
in common, then an interface might be a good way to kind of tie them all together so that you can treat
them all as the same thing from the perspective of client code.
And when I say client code, I mean, in this case, the main class of this main class is making use
of what these classes here can do, right?
So the main class could be said to be a client of these other classes.
It uses what these other classes can provide, right?
Which in this case is they can provide a string and they can provide a salary.
OK.
So when you have that kind of situation where they don't share data and they don't share implementation
either, but they do share some general characteristic like, Hey, we all know how to provide a salary.
You can tie them all together and treat them all the same from from a third party perspective in the
main class or would be the third party perspective.
And you can do that by tying them all together with an interface.
And then just referring to all of them via that interface, which which originally was our employee
class.
And then later on, we evolved it to be I employee.
But you get it.
OK.
So that's a good use for an interface now.
On the other hand, if you have two or more classes that actually share some of the same data, or at
least they can share some of the same data and or they can also share some of the same implementation,
some of the same code.
Right.
That might be a good candidate for a super class or a class hierarchy.
OK.
So just to revisit here the employee class.
So some of the same implementation that's being shared here is like the constructor here.
In fact, the data end and some of the same data and implementation are being shared here.
All of our classes, all of our subclasses have shared these fields, the last name, first name, date
of birth.
They happen to also share quite a number of these other fields the date, format or number, formatter
and things of that sort.
I wouldn't really call these data, though in a generic, object oriented sense.
These are more like really deep internal implementation features, if you will, but definitely the
first name, last name and date of birth.
Our shared data between all of these four classes not shared in the sense that they're sharing data,
but shared in the sense that all of those subclasses have these same properties, right?
And so why duplicate the definition of those properties across four classes?
We can just consolidate them all into one class.
And then the way that we get those properties populated or initialized can all be done in one place
as well, which we're doing right here in the constructor.
And then now we also happen to have this get bonus method, which is also the same implementation across
all four classes.
OK.
So that's a good case for creating a class hierarchy with a super class, for example, as we initially
had done and then an abstract class.
OK, so with an abstract class very, very similar to just a regular superclass, except two things
we don't want to permit anyone to ever be able to instantiate the abstract class itself, maybe because
by itself, it's just not very meaningful could be a number of reasons why we might not want to allow
them to do that.
Or we may not care too much one way or the other about that, but maybe we want to make sure that we
force subgroup.
Classes to implement certain methods.
OK, like I get salary method here, we want to make sure that there's no possibility that people who
write subclasses could forget to implement that.
And so we can declare that method abstract, but we can't do that unless the whole entire class is also
abstract.
OK.
And then that opens up the possibility of using the template pattern, the template method pattern and
cool things like that.
All right.
So I'm going to wrap up this lesson on the abstract class, and we will take a look at yet another cool
thing that we can do in the next lesson.
I will see you there.