All right, so now we've got this compound interest calculator code written, and it is doing what it
needs to do more or less, it's giving us the correct answer now that we fixed it.
However, the answer's a little unwieldy.
We would never want to see a number like that, nor would we ever want to present a number like that,
especially when we're talking about money.
We wouldn't want to present that to anyone using our code, you know.
So now let's learn how we can format this so that it looks like actual money.
And I'm in North America, so I'm going to particularly want to see this formatted in the way that we
typically present sums of money when written out.
So Java has some really nice, convenient ways to do this type of formatting very easily.
And so I'm going to show you a few ways that we could do this.
So there is a class in Java called no format, and this class is almost like magic.
Not only can it format our numbers for us, in this case, it can format numbers according to all of
the rules of how numbers and money and things like that are typically shown in different countries or
regions of the world.
So we'll start off with the most simple way to use this, though, so we'll create a number format,
and that's what it's called here under the Java Dot text package.
And I just hit return so that it would get imported properly, and we're going to make a format that
can format for money.
So I'm going to call, I'm going to create a variable here.
I'm going to call it money form matter.
And now to create an instance of this, I'm not going to use the new operator and instead I'm going
to use one of its static methods.
So to do that, I will refer to number format dot and then I can call the get currency instance because
what I want to format here is money or currency, so I can get currency instance just like that.
And now I can simply use this money format or down here where where I'm printing.
I could use it in a few different ways, but I'll start with the simplest way.
I think so.
Money form, matter, dot format.
And then I can just pass in the big decimal here.
All right.
And so that's actually going to be calling this format method.
There are many overloaded versions of this dot format method here.
As you can see, there's one that takes along a double and an object, a few additional parameters as
well.
So this one that we're using right now is the one that just takes an object, which means it's simply
going to call the two string method, which is what we're getting down here.
All of that.
OK.
So let's see what we get now.
Look at that perfect for North America, at least thirty six thousand seventy five and 81 cents.
Now there's so much that you can do with this right now.
When I call the get currency instance, what's happening is this method is first determining what Cal
or what part of the world I'm in.
Or rather, what part of the world my computer is in.
And it's determining that I am in America, essentially.
And it knows that in America, we format our money typically in groupings of three with two decimal
places and with a leading dollar sign symbol.
And so what this get currency instance method did was to return an instance of a no form matter that
is configured to format numbers exactly the way that I need them in North America.
And so if I ran this exact same code on a computer in, let's say, Japan, this is not what I would
have gotten.
I would have gotten the formatting that is most prevalent in Japan with a yen symbol, presumably.
However, I can actually take charge a little bit and actually specify a local or a part of the world
that I want to get a currency instance for.
And I can do that by simply passing any local right here as an input.
So this takes a look.
How so?
To do this, I can type all look uppercase, local and there are actually a whole lot of predefined
locales right here.
Now, I don't have to use these.
I could specify what makes up these things on my own, but why would I want to do that?
I'm a programmer who wants to be lazy.
So let's say we wanted France.
OK, so now I'm passing in low Cal Dot France, and so if I run this again, let's see what we get now.
OK, so now we get a space for the grouping separator because apparently that's how they do things there.
And instead of a period for the decimal point, we get a comma because again, I guess that's what they
do and they are on the euro.
They don't use francs anymore, they use euros.
And so we get the little symbol for euro.
So thirty six thousand seventy five and eighty one.
I don't even know how to read that in English, but thirty six thousand 75 euros and 81 euro cents,
I guess.
OK, let's do one more.
Let's do I don't know.
Let's do Japan.
Cool.
Thirty six thousand seventy six.
Notice that it dropped the 81 cents here because in Japan, they use the currency called the yen.
And there isn't a denomination of money smaller than the yen, so you can't have a point eight one.
All right.
So yeah, so that's definitely the quickest and easiest way to format our answers for money right now.
There are some other interesting things that we can do with these.
Number four matters.
So first, I'm going to put my format back to the default for my locale here.
Just make sure that that gets back to normal real quick.
All right, there we are.
Now what if I wanted to be able to specify my inputs using appropriate things like money, for example?
So for this first input here, which is my starting balance and my annual contribution?
What if I want to be able to specify that using this format?
Well, I can actually do that.
So let's see a way in which we could do that.
Currently, this method is receiving a string for the principal and the contribution.
Let's see where these are used.
The principle is used just in one place here and the contribution is used in just one place as well.
So this will hopefully be pretty easy, actually.
Let's start with this principle.
So what we can do is we can actually utilize the money formatter, both to format an unformed ID number
to look like this.
And we can also go the other way.
We could pass in a number that looks like this and then get back an unformed ID, simple number like
what we have here and here, so we can go either way.
Now, when you are using these for matters, the most efficient thing to do is to only create one instance
of the formatter and then use that instance all over the place.
So now I have a situation where I'm using this number formatter, which is doing the right thing down
here, but now I want to use it up here as well.
So maybe what I want to do is first, consider converting this whole thing into a field of the class
so that I can use it in both of these methods.
However, keep in mind now these methods are both static.
And so if I want to use this as a field, it will likely need to be static as well.
So first, let's just see what options the ADP gives for converting this local variable.
And again, I will just state that a local variable is simply a variable that we create inside of a
method as opposed to a variable that is created outside of a method.
Well, all right.
So let's see what our options are here.
Someone just right click on this and go down here to refactor and let's see, we can introduce a field.
Let's see what happens when we do that.
All right.
So it asks, Where do we want to initialize this?
We've actually done this once before.
I don't know if you remember it.
So where do we want to initialize it?
So the initialization is just this bit here where we say equals blah blah blah.
Do we want to keep doing that in this method?
Or do we want to do that elsewhere?
And I'm thinking we want to do that in the declaration itself.
So let's see what that looks like.
OK.
And then we're going to hit enter.
OK, now awesome.
The I.D., which is called intelligent for a reason, was smart enough to realize that if we wanted
to move that variable up into the class as a field and keep using it as we are, then this variable
would have to become static because the method we're calling it from is static.
And if this were not made static, then we'd have to create an instance of this class in order to utilize
it.
OK.
So intelligence was smart enough to realize, Hey, just make that static.
And then it brought up the whole bit here where we're initializing it as well.
So good job there.
All right.
And now we can use this money formatter everywhere in the program.
So now what we can do is we can call a different method of the money formatter or the number format
formatter really to pass.
Whatever we pass into this contribution field here now, now that I've done this though, I'm getting
a squiggly line and when I hover over the squiggly line, I can see what what is the problem here?
And so it's telling me that, OK, now you've got an unhindered exception.
Now we haven't learned about exceptions yet, but to fix this, what you can do is put your cursor right
after the word pass like I have done here.
And then, well, there's a couple of ways to fix this, actually.
You can see this little red light bulb here.
And if you click on it, it offers to try to fix this problem for us.
You can simply click Add Exception to Method Signature, or if you like to use only keyboard shortcuts
like I do, the equivalent of that is to click on option return.
And then you get the same option there, and then you can hit enter or just select this.
OK, now we get another issue here.
Cannot resolve constructor big decimal.
OK, so now what's happening is that the pass method returns something of type.
No, if I can show you that, so put my cursor here right after the period and do a control space.
And then I just kind of move over a little bit and I can see that this pass method that's getting called
will return something of type number.
And this type number is not understood as one of the inputs for a big decimal.
So we need to convert that number into something.
And how we can do that is putting a period right here at the end of the pass call.
So on the right side of the little parentheses which is yellow there and then period and then we can
simply convert that to a string by calling two string.
And now we're back to a string again.
OK, so now let's go ahead and try this out now, I just realized I did this on the contribution field
first instead of the principle, but no, no big deal.
So what this will allow us to do now is to format this number as actual money and thereby making it
a little more readable.
Perhaps so I can put a dollar sign here and I can put a comma there.
OK?
And that's how we would typically, you know, specify money in in the US anyway.
So now let's let's see what happens when we run this.
OK, so it still works.
So we didn't break anything there.
So now let's do the same for the principle.
So we'll refer to this money formatter Matterport Pass, and we will wrap this.
Like so and then we will call to string.
There we go.
And so now if we come down here and we format this as well, and I'll put a comma in there.
Now, let's run this.
OK, very good, it still works.
Now let's try a different number just to make sure.
So let's do 25000.
Three hundred and let's do an annual contribution of seven thousand five hundred dollars.
So let's run that.
OK, so we get one hundred sixty three thousand two hundred seventy.
I'm going to go ahead and just assume that's correct.
I'm sure it is.
Now what if we don't want to specify the rate as a decimal like this and instead we just want to refer
to it as a percentage, right?
Like eight percent?
Well, we can do that, too.
So we created a money format and now we're going to need a different format or to do this because now
we're talking about a percentage.
So the way we can do that is let's just create another one following the same basic pattern.
By the way, the ADC made our number formatter final by default, which just means that it should not
be changed after it has been created.
OK, so that's kind of like a safety mechanism to make our formatter final, not just formatter, but
in general any variable, especially when that's going to be a field, it is strongly recommended that
you make them final, if at all possible.
All right.
So we'll make another instance of a number formatter.
This one will be a percent, for matter, though, and we'll do this get two percent instance.
Look at that.
There we go.
So now we've got a number for matter for percentages and so we can use this.
Now let's see where are all the places where this is used?
OK, very good.
So it's only used in one place anyway, which is right there at rate.
So to use this now, we can do the same kind of basic thing.
Percent Formatter Dot Pass will wrap this and then we'll do two string just like that.
And now we can come down here and we can change this from point zero eight to simply eight percent like
that.
And now again, that becomes more readable.
Oh, and looks like we're actually using the rate in more than one place, so.
OK.
The best thing to do here would be to grab where we're doing this correctly.
Woops, actually, I want all of that and then to convert that into a variable, a local variable with
a command option V and I don't know, I'll just call it rate as percent, maybe.
And now the move this line up.
To the very top and then this bit here, I will replace with my rate as percent.
There we go.
And so now I'm using it in two places, so notice what I did there.
I could have replicated this line in two places where I'm using rate as percent.
But one big guideline in good programming is to try not to repeat yourself.
If there's duplication in the code, you want to try to weed it out and get rid of it.
So rather than having this percent formatter thing here being used identically in two or more places
in the code, it's better that I use it one time, capture the output of that and then just refer to
that output, which is simpler in two places.
And that way, if I needed to do any other changes, I would only need to make those changes for the
foreign matter in one place on Line 14, rather than going to two or more places to make that same change.
OK.
All right.
So now that we've done that, let's run this now.
OK.
Good.
No blow ups.
And so now we're able to specify these numbers in potentially a little bit more meaningful way that's
more readable now in actual real life in my Java code where I'm calling a method like this.
I probably wouldn't want to actually be passing in these formatted strings like this because they're
highly opinionated here.
However, if I wrote a user interface for this calculator, such as what we are seeing in the website
itself, where we can, you know, type in numbers and things notice here that this number is mostly
formatted.
The only thing that isn't formatted here is that they're they're implying the dollar sign, they're
giving you the dollar sign there, but it is accepting the commas and the decimal points and things
like that.
Same thing here.
It's not expecting you to type in a zero point zero eight.
It's letting you type in a whole number and then they're implying that they'll figure it out by the
fact that they're showing this percent sign here.
So this is semi formatted, if you will.
So if I were writing a program where I had an actual user interface, I would likely want to accept
either this input or something close to it.
Maybe where I'd be leaving off the dollar sign in the percent sign, possibly.
It just kind of depends.
Or ideally, I'd make it very flexible where I could supply either or write with or without.
And my code would be smart enough to figure out what to do there for maximum flexibility.
But this is really just to show that we can both format numbers and we can pass them as well.
All right.
So we're going to look at a few more things that we can do it with no format in the next few lessons.
So I'll see you then.