All right, now, I've got another scenario for you.
What if you wanted to do some other type of operation on your data, like the salary field or the entire
person instances or whatever some other operation that doesn't come pre-packaged with the collectors?
Right?
So in other words, like here, we're doing an averaging.
Previously, we were I didn't run this, but you know, previously we were using these something long.
Right?
These are all methods that exist on the collector's class, right?
So you've got the grouping by and counting and averaging in all kinds of things that you can do here,
right?
But what if you wanted to do some other type of operation that out of the box you could not do with
the collectors in?
And I've got the perfect example here.
Let me let me get rid of that.
So bear in mind that we have been adding up salaries for the last several lessons, right?
And I've mentioned this before, but I'll bring it up again in general when we are doing math on money.
We actually don't want to be using just simple addition and subtraction capabilities that are built
into Java, right?
Like, you don't want to just take two numbers and just do this, generally speaking, and we learned
way back in the numbers module.
The reason for this is because you open yourself up to rounding errors, and those rounding errors exist
because of the way that all computer languages.
This is not a Java problem.
All computer languages and all computer systems store floating point values and by floating point values.
I'm referring to the decimal places here, right?
Point two three point three eight.
We learned way back in the numbers module that by default, computer languages and systems represent
these floating point values in binary decimal format and inherent to how that format works.
There are going to be rounding errors for all but the most straightforward values, right?
So like a point five that you won't have any rounding errors with that, but values that don't line
up perfectly with the binary bits for a decimal point values.
They're going to have to be approximations, right?
You can get closer and closer to the real value with the more bits that that can be allocated, which
is why you know you've got double types and things of that sort.
But it's always going to end up being an approximation for most decimal values, right?
And ultimately, your money math calculations are almost guaranteed to be off.
OK.
And so you can't do that.
You have to use big decimal.
Right?
We learned that.
So the rule of thumb in general is anytime you're doing many math, use big decimal.
The only reason that I didn't care about using big decimal up until now for what we've been doing here
is because.
Let me jump back over to the spreadsheet is because the data that we have here happens to be such that
it's all nice round numbers right there, all integers essentially, right?
And so we didn't need to worry about decimal places and things of that sort.
Not a big deal, but if there had been decimal places in these values and we still wanted actual accurate
answers, which I'm sure we would, we could not do what we've been doing so far.
It would not work.
We'd be getting bad answers.
So I want us to pretend as though this salary column has floating point values in it.
If I thought about this many, many, many, many lessons ago, I might have found a better data set
where we actually had floating point values for the salaries.
I mean, I do see that we've got these things here, but this is talking about age.
I could use it as numbers, but that's all right.
We'll just pretend.
All right.
So so that's what we're going to do in this lesson.
We're going to pretend like these salaries here could have floating point values in them.
And then we're going to rewrite our code a little bit to handle that situation appropriately by using
big decimals.
So the issue, though, is that there are no methods built in to the collector's class for doing math
with big decimal.
OK, so let me let me delete these guys here.
Right.
The collectors class simply does not give us any out of the box way to do that.
So we'd have to come up with our own way of using the Streams API working within this framework here.
But doing the math using big decimal.
That's what we're going to to learn here.
OK.
So the first thing we're going to need to do, though, is we're going to want to model the salary as
a big decimal.
Now, technically, there might be some ways that we could avoid doing this because we could have opportunities
to map the long to a big decimal later in the pipeline, so to speak.
But I'm inclined to go ahead and just model it more accurately right from the start.
And so that's what we're going to do first.
OK.
So instead of using a long for the salary, let's use a big decimal.
And now that's going to cause some errors like we've got this one down here now.
Let's see so long.
That part's long.
So what we were doing here is that we were taking what is going to be a string, right?
And we were converting it into a long.
Now, if you'll recall, when we learned about big decimal, you may recall that you can actually just
create a big decimal or initialize the big decimal from a string.
And in fact, quite often that is the most accurate way to create a big decimal is by using a string.
Because when you use a string, you ensure that there's no possibility for rounding errors in interpreting
that string in some intermediate number type, right?
You just go straight from the string to the big decimal.
You won't lose any precision or anything like that.
So what we can do here is actually just get rid of the long that pass long and instead we can just do
a new big decimal.
Like so.
All right.
So this is actually about the best way to convert a string to a big decimal anyway.
All right, so we've got that now.
Then down here, we've got an error now, so now we're trying to do averaging, but this is now trying
to do an averaging of along on a field that is not a long right.
It is now a big decimal.
OK, so let's go back to pretending like we wanted to sum up all of those salaries, OK?
So what can we do here?
Well, we've actually learned this technique.
Many lessons that go as one of the many methods on the collector's class and the method we're going
to make use of now is a more generic method.
It is the reduced function right of the famous map reduce pattern, right?
So we're going to look at the reduced function here.
And if you recall, when we learned Reduce previously, we learned that we could actually use reduced
to do all of these things that we're that we've been doing so far right.
You can use reduce the find the minimum value, the maximum value, you can use it to add or subtract
or whatever.
It's like this generic pattern any any time you want to do any sort of accumulation calculations, right?
And so we can use it here, and it is quite appropriate, in fact.
So the first thing I'm going to do is just replace that with reducing.
And before I even finished typing that out, I will just acknowledge that look at what we've got here
now, so we've got a few different, you know, overloaded versions of the reducing function.
We've got one version that just takes a binary operator.
And again, that's really just the lambda or a method reference to a method that can take two values,
right?
And then you're going to implement, for example, a lambda expression that will take those two values
and essentially add them, add them up, write in whatever way makes sense for those value types, though,
to be added, right?
So that's one way that you can do it.
There's another version here that can take an identity.
And if you'll recall, it's a value such that when you do whatever your operation will be, such as
adding, If you add one value to this identity value, you'll get back that original value again.
So if you're doing adding your identity value would be zero because x plus zero equals X write x plus
zero equals X is an identity type of operation, right?
If you were doing multiplication, your identity value would presumably be one right because x times
one equals X.
So it's whatever value for a given operation would result in that original value again.
OK.
And then this final overloaded version of the reducing method goes one step further.
And this is actually the version that we are going to make use of in this particular case.
So again, the first parameter is the identity.
OK.
So in our case, if we're adding up salaries, it's really going to just be zero.
But the second parameter that it takes is a function that does a mapping.
And what this is useful for is to say, all right.
In this particular case, all of our records are really of type person.
Right?
That's what we are actually dealing with.
Fundamentally, we're dealing with persons, right?
Well, we don't want to add up one person with another person.
That's that doesn't make sense, right?
We actually want to add up one field of a person to other to two other instances of that same field
of person, right?
In our case, the salary field of a person.
So we can use this function here to do that mapping right because it's going to give us by default,
people.
So we want to convert people into salaries, OK?
And so that's what we would use that function for.
You'll see what I mean in just a moment here.
And then finally, and I'm sorry, that's kind of running off the screen here, but the final parameter
to this third version of reducing would be our binary operator again, where it's going to give us to
two values and then we can do whatever thing we want to do with those two values.
Okay, so let's go ahead and try this out and see what it will look like.
OK.
All right.
So the first bit is the identity, the second bit is a mapping and the third bit is going to be for
our case, a lambda expression, OK?
So the identity?
Now we're going to be dealing on.
Sorry, I forgot to actually say reducing there.
OK, so the first bit is an identity.
Now this is ultimately going to be dealing with big decimals.
So we don't want to just say like zero.
OK?
Because that would be an integer.
And that's not what we are dealing with here.
We're dealing with big decimals.
So what we can do is we can create a big decimal version of the zero right and and nicely enough.
You may recall that the big decimal class actually has some predefined constants on it, and one of
them is zero.
So we've got a zero, a one and a 10, right?
So we can actually just do that.
OK, so there's our identity for the adding operation that we are about to do, right?
And then the second bit is our mapping function.
And look, we've already got a built in mapping function right here.
Person salary, right?
So just calling the salary method of the person class.
OK.
And so we don't even have to type anything there that's already done for us.
So we're saying that we're going to be working with the salary field of each person instance that's
going to be dropping into the pipeline here, right?
And then finally, we need our what did they call it, binary operator, right?
So a lambda expression that will take two values and then let us do some kind of operation on those
two values, right?
And so here we can assume that we're going to receive an A and a B and then we can map those to something.
So now these this and this B are going to be instances of big decimal.
And so if you want to add two big decimals together, you you can't just do this A-plus, be right.
These are not integers.
These are big decimals, right?
To add big decimals together, you have to actually, they are actual objects and therefore they inherit
methods, right?
And so there is an add method of the big decimal class, right?
And so we can do this a dot ad and then you pass in the B, OK?
And so this result now will be carried forth if you please go back and watch the the lesson where I
taught explicitly how reduce works.
I don't want to go through the whole entire thing explicitly again, but I'll say very briefly here.
The way that the reducing function generally works is for a list of values.
It will take essentially two values in that list and B, in this case, it will execute the operation,
which in this case is adding it will take that result and then it will go to the next value in the list
and then it will do that operation again with the result, plus the next value in the list, right?
So you always result in next value.
Do that operation, take that result, go down again, result in the next value and it'll just keep
doing that until it gets through the entire list.
OK.
And so that's how that would work.
And then when all of that reducing is done, you're going to end up with one big one.
One big, big decimal value.
I didn't mean for that punter to come up, but you're going to end up with one big, big decimal value.
And then this bit here, this number format, we don't even have to change anything.
It can accept that big decimals, as we also learned back in the numbers module and it can format that
big decimal.
So we don't even need to change anything there.
So look at that.
Actually, all we needed to change was the data type here and then how we're actually initializing that
field on new persons.
And then just this one line right there instead of using the collectors died something long.
We're now using collectors that reducing notice again.
I don't need to specify the word collectors here because it's being statically imported for us.
This reducing method is a static method.
OK.
But yeah, that's how this is working, so we should be able to run this and it hopefully won't blow
up, so let's try it and see.
Yeah, it didn't blow up, and I think we're getting what appeared to be real real values here, right?
So again, in fact, I remember these numbers a little bit.
The women of Arkansas were getting one point ninety three billion and the men were getting one point
nine to seven.
So yeah, we're still getting the same same values, right?
So again, I just want to point out in this particular case, because of the source data that we have,
we didn't technically have to use big decimals here, and it was actually more lightweight not to use
big decimals and to use longs in our particular case here, because we don't have floating point or
fractional values for the salaries in our source data and by source data.
I mean, you know, the spreadsheet data here, right?
We don't have that.
But if we did have that and we were doing this kind of math on salaries, this is the way to do this.
OK?
You'd want to most likely use reducing and you definitely want to use big decimals.
OK, now I also showed in the lessons where we were learning about reducing, and you can use reducing
for more than just math, right?
I think we did an example where we were appending and underscore something like that two strings, right?
So any time you're accumulating things right, you're like adding on right, whether it's numerically
or just in terms of strings or building something bigger and bigger.
That's when you can use reducing OK.
And actually, let me let me even say this doesn't have to be building things bigger and bigger, it
could be taking apart, I suppose, as well, right, if you're chipping away.
If you start with a big value and then you're working, you know, chipping away at it, you can do
reducing for that as well, right?
So anytime you're doing an operation in a kind of recursive way.
All right.
So that was a really important one.
I think please definitely make sure that if if if you didn't fully follow everything that I said here,
please slow it down and watch it again.
This is pretty important, right?
Because you're going to encounter circumstances like this where the built in operations of the collectors
class aren't going to directly give you what you need, right?
And you're going to have to figure out a way to probably use reducing to indirectly come up with the
exact operation that you're needing.
And here's a great example of that.
All right.
So I will see you in the next one.