OK, so now I want to show you one last way to format numbers.
I'm not trying to overwhelm you.
It's just that there are a lot of different scenarios where one particular approach might be better
than another.
So far, though, out of what we have worked with and done, I would say that still, you should probably
prefer to use just the no format.
Does it get currency instance or get percent instance or whatever, at least for formatting?
You know, money and percentages.
All right.
So let's look at one more way to do this.
So the other thing we can do is instead of using the print line method.
We could use the print shops print f method of system died out.
Now this method and we have touched this a little bit before, I don't know if you remember it.
That stands for print format.
And so this method can take a format string sort of along the lines of this, but it's not the same.
It's not the same format patterns at all, but kind of accomplishes similar things so it can take a
format string plus whatever it is that you're trying to format.
So the way that this can work, let's start with something simple here.
So let's first just print out the raw value that we are getting back from the big decimal.
And so we can tell it that we want to expect to format a decimal number so we can do a percent.
That's kind of like saying, here comes a format string that we're about to tell you or a pattern that
we're about to tell you about.
And then we need to give it a character that tells it to expect a floating point number, a number with
a decimal in it.
And the symbol for that is an F..
OK.
And then because we're using the print f method instead of the print line method, we if we want this
to print something and then go down to the next line, which is what the print line method automatically
does, we have to explicitly tell the print f method to do that.
And we do so now.
You've seen me in the past, actually here.
Let me first close this quote.
So you've seen me in the past.
Do this a backslash in for a new line character.
So that's saying, you know, inject a new line character to go down to the new line.
However, actually the formatting method such as print, death and its related methods actually recommend
using percent in to do the same thing, except with the percent in its smart enough to know how to handle
going to a new line across different platforms.
All right.
And then we put a comma after the closing quotation mark there, and then we pass in the object that
we are trying to format, which in this case is the balance variable right here, the one that we're
using here as well.
All right.
So now we've got that balance variable there.
So we're saying format this variable as a floating point number and then put a new line after it.
That's what this is saying.
Now so far, we're not doing any special formatting of any kind, though, with commas and all of that.
So let's just start off by seeing what this does.
OK, so that just prints out the whole entire thing.
All right.
So now let's get a little fancier with it.
So one of the first things we probably will want to do is to is to specify the level of precision or
the number of decimal places that this goes.
And we probably want that to just go to two, right?
As the other examples earlier have done.
So to do that will put our cursor right in front of the F here and after.
So between the percent sign in the f there, and we can use some character codes basically to specify
that level of precision that we want.
And the way we can do this is with a period and then to to say I want to decimal places there.
All right, so let's see what this does.
There you go.
So, so now we've got the two decimal places, so any number that you put after that period will we'll
we'll do that.
And let's also get that the prefix there of the dollar sign now to do that.
That's easy.
We can just put it right in front of the percent sign.
So in other words, this dollar sign will be taken literally.
I would not say that it's really part of the format string.
The format string is kind of everything to the right of that percent sign there, but the dollar sign
going in front of it just says literally print a dollar sign and then whatever this format string tells
you to do.
Right.
So if we run this again, here we go.
Now we've got the dollar sign.
Now let's get the grouping of commas in here, though.
Now to do that, if we go to the right of this percent sign and simply put a comma, just like that,
that's a flag.
And we've looked at flags before.
They're usually, you know, just kind of like one little thing that you can kind of check on or off.
So here we're kind of checking on the Karma flag to say, Yeah, we want grouping now.
We're unable to specify how many digits we want grouped at a time.
So with the format string here, it's just going to assume that we want it the way that it is done for
North America.
So let's run this and see.
There we go.
Awesome.
So now we're back to what we had with the other approaches, right?
This one, I would say there was less readable.
It's more cryptic than what you get from the no format or decimal format.
Now we can tell it how to handle negative numbers, though, and that is done with another flag.
And all we need is to just specify one character for that flag, and it is an opening parentheses.
So just like that.
Now, of course, to see this work, we need to negate this value.
So we'll do that here by calling the negate method again.
And so now if we run this, there we go.
So now we've got the parentheses notice now because this is a flag and not like a full a full on formatting.
We didn't have to like wrap anything in an opening and closing parentheses.
We only specified just an opening parentheses here because this is just a flag by including this.
We're simply telling the formatter turn on the ability to wrap negative numbers in parentheses.
We're not, you know, explicitly telling it where to put the parentheses.
Kind of, as we are here, here, we're actually telling it, put an opening parentheses to the left
of the number and put another closing parentheses to the right.
Here we're just saying do parentheses OK?
And so we only have to specify the one because it's a flag.
It's just kind of like you're flipping the switch on to say, Yeah, I want parentheses used for negative
numbers.
All right.
And just to make sure let's turn off the negation there, but leave the formatting there and just make
sure that that still prints the way that we would expect for a positive value without any parentheses.
Yeah, there we go.
Very good.
So I'm definitely not going to try to show an exhaustive list of every single format string that you
could supply because there's a lot we will get into.
More of this, though, when we learn about dates and how to handle date and time.
In that chapter, we'll revisit the print off because there's a lot more that you can do when it comes
to date and time as well.
Now, if you wanted to know more about you know what your options are here, you can always put your
cursor on the print f method and then do an F1 to bring up the Java Dock for it.
And then in this Java Dock article right here, it says parameters format, a format string as described
in format string syntax.
So this is actually a link and if you click on it.
That takes us to the Java doc article that tells us everything we could ever probably want to know about
how to use the format strings here because it gives us a nice table with all the special characters
that we can use here.
OK, so you don't need to memorize all of this.
You can just know that you can use the print f state or print f method and then look at the Java doc
by going to f one and then reading the Java doc.
If you ever need to know what are all the things you can do here?
Look how long this article is, by the way, it's it's quite massive.
There's a lot that you can do.
So clearly, I've only scratched the surface of what you can do with this.
Let me also point out a couple of other things, though, so I'm showing you that we can use this print
f method now this print f method.
There are actually two methods on this out object here that do the exact same thing, and in fact,
one uses the other.
So you could use this print f method or you could also do format.
Same thing, in fact.
The print f method uses format, and I'll prove that to you real quick.
So if we jump into the actual code written by the creators of Java, you'll see here that the print
f method actually just calls the format method itself.
OK.
So they are the same thing.
I think the print f method is here just for familiarity because the print f method.
And let me go back to the print f method and this general format here more or less is borrowed or heavily
inspired from a print f function that exists in the language of C.
C is a really old programming language that's still heavily utilized, especially for a lot of system
programming and things.
And so I think they just wanted to have a method with the same name as what inspired this in the first
place print death.
And that way, C programmers coming to Java could feel pretty comfortable and at home more or less with
how to do things here.
Now I want to show you one more thing you won't have to learn any more of these these format things
here, but there's one more.
Well, there's actually a couple more ways I probably won't show you all of them, but there's a couple
more ways that you could do this same thing here.
You also could create a string and capture this format with the string.
So the string class itself has a format method on it, and it's the same format that I just showed you
here.
So if we were to just use this format method here, it's the same thing.
In fact, it is so much the same thing that I could actually just grab all of that copy it.
Go right here after the word string and haste.
And look at that.
Put a semicolon there and then I can just capture the output of this.
So if I just do a an option, command the right here and I don't know what what will I call this my
string?
Actually, I guess I should have called it my money.
I got a name that my money.
All right.
So I'm calling this static method format.
I'm telling it, Hey, string, I want you to format this variable, which is a big decimal in this
particular way and then pass me back the result of that.
And I will store that in a string called my money.
Now down here, I can maybe get rid of this and I can do a system that print line instead and then just
pass my money.
OK, and then I can run this.
There you go.
Now, why do it this way versus the other way with the system got out that format or print off or whatever?
So let's say you wanted to append or concatenate a bunch of different formatted strings together or
something of that sort or do a lot more stuff.
But beyond just formatting this one value here, you know, then you might want to use something like
the string that format store the result of that and then keep going on doing other formatting and things
and then put them all together, perhaps when you're done right.
So you could do something like my money that can cat write and then do some more stuff here, you know,
concatenate another string on there or whatever it is that you're going to do.
All right.
So there could be a number of reasons why you might prefer to to do it this way.
In fact, actually in most professional programming, you are more likely if you wanted to do a format
like this, if you were locked into formatting a string in this way and as opposed to using the decimal
format or the number format or something like that, then you almost definitely would be using the string.
That format method in all likelihood, because in real professional applications, rarely are professional
Java applications just printing things out to the command line like this.
Instead, you'll be formatting some data and then showing it in a web browser or in a graphical user
interface or something like that where you would never even be using system that out that print line,
OK?
We're just using system that out and print def and all of these things out of convenience, because
I have not yet shown you how to make any other type of user interface for the applications that were
or for the code that we're writing right now.
All right.
So I think that's going to just about do it for all of the ways that we can format at least money and
basic numbers for right now, as I've shown you.
You can always go here and do an one and then drill in to some of the methods.
Or you can put an F1 on this format method here.
And then you can jump over to learn more about all of the ways that you can format something in the
Java docs.
If you want to learn a lot more about how to do this, and there's plenty of articles online as well.
This is really just meant to kind of give give you a gist of how to do it and to capture what is most
likely the most common scenario that you're going to do, which is to format money, probably.
All right.
So I'm going to wrap it up and I'll see you in the next one.