All right, so we're going to define this class at the bottom now.
I'm going to let you know there are about probably, I don't know, four different ways to create classes
within a class.
Right now, we're just going to focus on one particular way and which is one of the most recommended
ways.
OK.
All right.
So what we can do is we'll come down here.
Now we want to limit the scope of this class because we're only creating it for use right here.
Nowhere else.
OK, so we're going to make it private.
Static final.
It's going to be a class.
And we'll call it, I don't know, dummy employee.
And so it needs to extend our employee class, just like all of our other subclasses do.
All right.
OK, now we're going to need to implement some things here.
Let's see what it's telling us first off.
So class dummy employee must either be declared abstract or implement abstract method, get salary.
So here we are being forced to implement the get salary method, which is a good thing.
So I will do a control for override, which lets me override the methods that need to be implemented.
And I'm going to start with that one there the get salary method and look at that.
It gives us the exact implementation that I wanted anyway, which is simply to return to zero.
Nothing more, nothing less.
All right now, let's see what else it's complaining about.
There is no default constructor available on employee.
So the deal here is that currently we're not defining any constructor at all.
And if you don't define a constructor on a on a subclass, then that subclass, when it's when instances
of it are created, the JVM will look to call a no ARG default constructor on the superclass, of which
there is none because we didn't define one because we didn't need one up until now.
So now we kind of do.
So we're going to make one real quick.
But now let's be careful here.
We don't really need this.
No, our default constructor like for our own purposes.
And so knowing that we don't want this to be public because it doesn't need to be used outside of this
class at all.
OK.
So let's generate a new constructor.
And we will use none of the inputs there, because this will be a default no ARG constructor and let's
just make it protected so that it can be called by subclasses.
But not from outside of the class hierarchy, OK, which which makes sense anyway, because this class
is abstract, right?
So you wouldn't really wouldn't make any sense for this constructor to be called for any other reason.
Now when I created this, we got an error here.
Let's see what this is.
It's saying that variable people, matt might not have been initialized.
So the problem here is that this people matter is declared final, which means it can only be initialized
one time.
Now that I've created a second constructor, Java and the A.D. upon analysis are realizing that if some
code tried to create an instance of this employee again, which doesn't really make sense.
But if if, if an instance was attempted to be created via this constructor here, which does nothing
in its body, then that would mean that this people matter would be undefined.
And since it's final, that's unacceptable.
So we need to do something with that.
I think the easiest thing we can do here is to simply set it to null.
And voila!
That error goes away.
All right.
Let's go back down here again.
See what else we need to do.
All right.
So here's our dummy employee now.
The other employees, when they're working properly, they will be setting a first name and a last name
in all of that.
And I have none of that code here, so we probably want to do something about that as well.
So the easiest thing I think we could do is to simply use this, know our default constructor here to
initialize these fields to something.
OK, let's just see what that might look like so we could do.
Last name equals, and I'm just going to set it to empty string.
First name.
Empty string.
And date of birth
for now, I'm just going to let it be null.
And so this dummy employee will inherit all of that.
And now all we need to do is fix this bit here.
So now, instead of returning a null, let's just return a new dummy employee.
Like so and we can do the same here as well.
And now, if we go back over to the main class here now.
We don't need this check anymore, because in theory, this employee can never be null.
At worst, it'll just be a dummy employee.
So let's get rid of let's unwrap that.
And then let's onion dent, and then let's just rerun this program again, because if you recall, we've
got one invalid employee role right here, which should result now in the creation of a dummy employee.
So let's see what happens here.
OK, cool.
Same value, it didn't blow up.
And there's our second instance right there.
It's a little too empty.
We might have wanted to fix that, but it doesn't blow up, right?
We get empty values there.
Now, if we wanted to make this look a little better, we can come back over here to employee go up
to this constructor here and maybe just put something in.
I don't know, like in a in a, you know, for not applicable do something like that.
Let's run it again.
There.
There we go in a in a so.
Little bit better.
And by the way, this is proving something to this is proving that when we create a dummy employee,
even though we did not explicitly define a constructor on it, the inherited no, our default constructor
is getting called right because that's where we're setting the nnanna.
So this no, our default protected constructor is getting called here.
One other thing we could consider making this constructor protected as well because we only went outside
code to create employee instances via this factory method here.
OK, so if we wanted to force everyone to only use this factory method, then we'd want to just make
this protected like so.
So if we jump over here back to Maine one more time and just run it all again and just make sure that
that's all legit.
Yeah, looks good.
Same values, everything's looking good.
Yeah.
All right, so I'm going to wrap this up.
So you've learned a whole lot here.
Abstract classes, interfaces, that's class.
Oh yeah, by the way.
So let's see this class here is what is known as A. That class that makes sense, right?
It's a class defined inside of a class.
It's a nested class.
Now let me be clear on a couple of things.
I chose to create this class as a nested class instead of creating a class outside here because of a
few things.
First off, look how minimal it is.
It's just the bare minimum, right?
All it's really doing, in fact, is just implementing the get salary method, right?
That's pretty much it.
So I didn't want to create a whole additional class just for that, and I made it private because there's
no external code that should ever need to instantiate this.
As of now?
OK.
So instances of this class never need to be created outside of this class here.
It's static because of the way that the compiler handles nested classes, and it is strongly recommended
that when we need a nested class of this sort that we first go with it just being static.
So if you want to know more about that, I will point you to an excellent book that is one of the seminal
Bibles of Java and programming in general called Effective Java by Joshua Block by Pelosi H.
It's a fantastic book, and it will teach you so many things, like if you're going to make an nested
class for this kind of purpose, you should prefer for it to be static again.
And we're making it final because since it is a dummy class, I don't expect that this should ever need
to be extended by making a class final.
We prevent any other class from being able to extend it.
OK.
All right.
So that's going to wrap this up and I will see you in the next one.