All right, so let's jump in to these regular expressions, and to do this, let's create a new class.
I'm in the people project here, but it really doesn't matter what project you're in.
So I'm going to right click on the source folder here.
And I'm going to go to new and Java class, and it doesn't really matter what we call this, I'm going
to call it Rag X practice.
And hit return, and I've got my new class, and I'm going to close this project pain there to get a
little more space.
So the first thing we'll do, let's just experiment with some of the simplest things that we can do
with a regular expression.
So we will start off by create a new line here and let's create a public static void main method so
that we have a place to execute our code.
SVM All lowercase return.
OK.
And we'll start off with the simplest type of expression, regular expression, which would just utilize
a string literal.
So what we want to do here is we just want to ask the regular expression engine if one word matches
a pattern that we have predefined.
So let's use a simple word like cat to find out whether or not this word matches our pattern.
We'll just print that out on the screen using the system that out that print line.
So I'll do a T return.
And so I want to know if the word cat, the string cat in I'm going to do a period here matches.
And if you'll notice so the matches method takes a regular expression.
OK, and I think we saw this in the previous lessons where we did look at matches, but we didn't go
deep into what it meant to make a regular expression within here.
So now we'll start digging into this a little bit more.
OK, so this first example will really just be review.
So will choose matches, and the simplest expression that we could make is just a literal expression,
a literal string or string literal.
So we could just do all lowercase cat just like that.
OK.
And so we're really just saying, does this string match this string here?
And so if we run that?
We get true.
So, yes, that does match.
And it is case sensitive, so if we do like a Capital C and then we run that this should not match.
Indeed, we get a false here because our expression does not indicate that we will allow for a Capital
C there.
And so I mean, that's really straightforward.
Probably not the most useful thing unless you literally want to just test for the exact occurrence of
a string, which yeah, you may want to do that sometimes.
But that's not even getting close to scratching the surface of all the power that we have with regular
expressions.
So now that we've seen that, let's expand our abilities here a little bit.
So like I just showed here, this matched as long as the C here was lowercase, because that's what
our pattern was expecting.
But what if we wanted to accept upper or lower case now with the previous methods that we have learned?
I did mention that you could do something like simply lower case the whole entire word first.
Right?
So you could do you could do to lower case.
Oops.
I don't really want that version of it.
You could do to lower case and then you could do matches, and in fact, this would work.
It will.
We'll just run that little bit of review.
OK, so that's true.
So that does work, right?
But if you don't want to get into all of that, if you want to do it in a more native regular expression
way, let's look at what we could do there.
So now I'm going to introduce the concept of character classes, and these are just patterns that we
can use to represent one or more characters within a string.
So in our case here, we want to allow for either a lower case or an uppercase C.
So one way that we can do that is to use a bracket expression.
And to do that, we put some brackets here.
So I'm going to put square bracket around that, see?
And then within the brackets, any characters that I place inside of these brackets will indicate that
we want to match any of those possibilities.
So in this case, we've got a lowercase C here.
But if I also put an uppercase see what I'm now saying to the regular expression engine, the thing
that is actually testing, whether or not we have a match.
I'm saying if this word starts with a lower case C or an uppercase C, followed by lowercase a T, that's
a match.
OK, so that's what these brackets or a bracket expression is doing by default.
It's testing either or OK, a c, a lowercase or an uppercase.
So now if I run this?
OK, we get a true for that, and then if I drop this back down the sea, back down to a lowercase C
and run it again.
Still true.
OK, now what if I use a letter that isn't expected in this pattern, such as a bee?
Right?
So let's try that.
So we'll do BRT and we'll run that.
OK, and I get a false here.
So this pattern is only allowing for lower or upper Casey, followed by an A and a T lowercase A. A.
OK, so it is case sensitive.
All right now, if I did one to allow for the B in addition to the Lower and Upper Casey, what do you
think I could do here?
Give you a second to think about it.
OK.
You think you got it all right, so all you need to do is just add a B in here, so you can add I don't
know what the limit is.
I'm sure there is a limit, but for all intents and purposes, you can add as many individual characters
and symbols in here as you need to specify your your, your matching or your regular expression here.
OK, so I've got a lower Casey and uppercase and lowercase B, and while I'm at it, I might as well
throw in an uppercase B as well.
So now if we run this note, it was false.
And now it's true.
OK, so and then I can also come over here and make this a Capital B and run that.
OK, so very good, so you get the point, right?
You can play lots of characters in in here and it will accept any one of them essentially in this case.
OK, now expanding on this, what if we wanted to allow the first letter in this string to be anything
ranging from A to F all lowercase A to F.?
Well, there's a way to do that as well.
Now, obviously, you could just say A, B, C, D, E and F, right, and that certainly would work.
But there's a nicer way, more elegant way to do this and that is using a range so we can specify a
range of characters within the square bracket expression as well.
And to do that, we can simply use a hyphen so a through f all lowercase.
OK.
So if I change this to a D and run this, that works.
And if I do an F and run it, that works as well.
However, if I do a G here and run this because G is outside of our range that does not match, I get
a false right.
So I think that's pretty clear.
Now what if you wanted to allow for the range of all lowercase A through F or the range of uppercase
A through F?
So do you want to take a venture at how to do that?
I'll give you a few moments.
OK, so what you can do for that is you can simply put an uppercase a hyphen uppercase f with no space
in between the lowercase F and the uppercase A..
OK.
So just as we were able to do something like a and a and this would mean except lowercase a or uppercase
a right.
You can do two or more ranges.
And this is saying accept the range of lowercase A through F or the range of uppercase A through F.
That's what this is saying.
And by the way, you can have additional characters and ranges still, so you're not limited to just
two.
So say if I wanted to also allow for the range of lowercase W through Z and uppercase W throughs through
through Z, you can do that as well.
And you could you could keep going again.
I'm not sure if there are limits.
Well, again, I'm sure there is a limit to how far you could go with this, but I don't know what it
is.
And probably if you got anywhere near that limit, you probably shouldn't do it in that way.
All right.
So that's character ranges.
Now, one other cool thing about the square bracket expressions is that you can invert them, so to
speak.
So you can kind of make it negative.
So you could say, I'm going to delete all of that.
I want to match anything that is not starting with a B, for example.
And to do that, you will use what is called the carrot symbol, which is shift six on most Curti keyboards.
And what did I say?
We don't want to match on a on a C.
OK, so not a C.
I hope that's what I said.
I don't know if I said a, b or C, but anyway, if you want to allow every character except a lower
case C.
So if I put a C here and I run this now.
We get a false because I'm not wanting to allow this word to start with a lower case.
Now if I use an uppercase C and run this now, I get a true.
As long as this first character is not so you can kind of read this carrot symbol here as a not as long
as the first character is not a C. It's going to be a match.
OK, so let's try a non character even.
Yeah.
So even a non character like a hyphen here or let's see what we.
An ampersand.
OK, so anything that is any one character that isn't a C.
OK, now if I were to put multiple characters here that aren't c like f l, for example, right?
Let's see what happens now.
OK, now I get a false.
Now the reason I get a false on this, meaning it's not a match, is because what goes in between these
square brackets in this particular expression, it's expecting one character that isn't AC, followed
immediately by a A..
Here I have two characters that are not AC, followed by A. So that pattern does not match the expression
that I have here.
It has to be a three character string.
OK.
And currently I have four character strings, so that's not going to match.
All right.
So we can also use this negation with a range.
OK, so we can say anything that isn't.
Well, here let's let's be a little playful and give it an entire range of a through z.
OK, so now you know, I'll make this a three character string again.
OK, so l, which is in the range of a through Z.
So let's see what we get now.
We get false and that's expected because we don't want to allow the first character to be in the range
of a through Z.
So we're saying here any string whose first character is a fuzzy should not be allowed, followed by
a A..
OK, so that's fine lowercase eight through Z, by the way.
Now with that being said, if I use a capital L, that is perfectly fine with this expression, OK?
So is this making sense?
You know, so far, I think we're, you know, we're using some relatively simple examples here.