All right, so in this next lesson, we're going to learn about one of the most fundamental ways of
controlling flow, and that is with something called an if then statement.
So if then statements allow us to test for whether or not something is true or false and if it is true,
then we will execute some code.
And if it is not true, then we will execute a different block of code.
Okay, so if true, we execute one block, if not true, we execute a different block.
And this gives us the ability to kind of test things and figure out stuff.
OK.
And this really is kind of at the heart of program logic, right, where we actually start to kind of
make our programs seem like they're thinking, OK, so let's try this out.
And to do so, we will.
Let me see here first, let me open up my project view here.
And it doesn't really matter at this point what project you're in.
We're just going to make a new class.
So I'm in the people project, though if you care and I'm going to right click on the source folder
as our see and I'm going to create a new Java class.
So I think what we're going to do here is we're going to make a little bit of a guessing game.
OK.
And so I'm going to call this class guess.
I guess it gets it.
All right.
So here's my new class, and then I'm going to close the project view there.
Let's make a new line here, and let's just start off with our standard public static void.
Main method PSV enter.
And here's what I'm thinking.
So let's make a very, very, very simple program that will first generate a random number.
OK?
Just a simple random number.
And maybe we'll keep the range pretty, pretty small, and then we will test whether or not that number
is, I don't know.
Three.
OK.
And if it is three, then we will print some message.
So let's just start with that.
So, so first off, let's decide what the range of random numbers will be.
Maybe, for starters, let's keep the range between one and three inclusive.
OK, so the number could be one, two or three.
OK.
So I'm going to give you a quick challenge.
Can you think of how to do that?
How can you generate a number and store it in a variable and the number needs to be one, two or three?
Go ahead and take a moment and see if you can think of how to do that.
And then unpaused the video when you think you've got it.
All right.
So hopefully you were able to do that.
Now let me work it out.
So we've learned a few ways to generate a random number.
Actually, I think I'm going to use the Java date util random because it's a better implementation of
random.
But if you chose to use math at random, that's fine too, if you were able to get that to work.
All right.
So let's see here.
So I know that we're going to end up with an integer and I'm going to just call it NUM, and then we're
going to need a new random number.
So I'm going to do new random and I'm not going to specify a seed.
Now I'm probably doing this slightly differently than what I originally taught because I I don't think
I'm going to capture this random object I'm creating.
I'm just going to use it in line.
So you'll see what I mean here.
So instead of like storing this random object in a variable of type random and then using it, I'm just
going to create it in line and then hit period here and then use it right away.
And in so doing, I won't ever have the random object to go back to.
OK, so I will lose the random object after I have gotten a random number and the reason I'm doing it
that way is partially out of laziness.
And then secondly, because I don't anticipate needing to use this random object again in this program
for right now.
All right.
Let's see and am going to give it an upper bound someone to use the second version of the next entry
method.
Like so, and the upper bound I will give it will be three.
Now, I think we need to remember something here.
If I go look at the Java Dock for the next and method, I am reminded that this method will generate
a number between zero inclusive, which means zero is one of the values that it's capable of returning
between zero and whatever the upper bound number that I supply exclusive, which means it will never
actually return the number that I'm specifying for the upper bound.
It will go up to that number, but won't include that number.
OK.
So in this case, that would mean I could get numbers between zero and two, so zero, one and two.
Now my criteria for this program were that I want to generate numbers one, two or three, not zero
one in two.
So can you think of what I can do to ensure that I always get one, two or three and not zero, one
or two?
Why don't you take a moment to think about that?
Pause the video and then unpause when you think you've got it.
OK.
So what I would do, I think for that scenario is to simply add one like so.
Because I now know that all of this is capable of generating a number of zero, one or two, it will
never give me a three because the documentation says that it will never include the number I'm specifying,
therefore the upper bound.
So by default, this would give me zero, one or two.
So then all I need to do is just kind of shift that range of zero, one or two over by one to one two
or three.
And to do that, I just had one right.
I want to point out that is some of the thinking that you need to be able to do sometimes as a programmer,
right?
You need to be able to see those patterns and see, OK, I've got a thing that gives me data that looks
like this.
I need data that looks like this.
How can I transform this to this right from this to that?
And so in this case, zero one two, you want one two three.
So mathematically, OK, everything's off by one.
So then just add one, OK?
In this particular case, it's a simple thing, but it's that type of thinking that you need to be able
to do from time to time.
All right.
So hopefully that gives us what we want.
And so now we can make sure that that actually is going to do what we want by simply printing it out.
And I'm going to do that with a system out that print line.
So we'll print out that number, the generated random number.
You know, actually a better name for this variable would be random number.
So I'm going to rename this sentiment to do that by using a refactoring on Mac Shift F six and on windows
to shift F6.
So I'm going to call this random number.
And because I use the rename function of the ADP, it renamed that variable everywhere where I was using
it on both lines in this case.
All right.
So now we're ready to utilize a new programming construct that I have not.
Up until now really taught and that is the use of the if statement.
So let me go ahead and just type this out and then I'll come back and explain it to the extent that
it needs much explanation.
OK, so to use the if statement, it's all lowercase the word if followed by parentheses.
Notice that when I type one parentheses, the left parentheses, the ADP automatically gives me the
right parentheses because that's the only legitimate way to use that.
And then it puts the cursor right in the middle.
So the point of what we want to do with this if statement here is we want to test if the random number
equals some number that we're looking for.
And I think I specified we want to see if it's three.
And I'm just randomly picking that number.
I could make it anything and you can choose to make yours whatever you want, although it should be
in the range of one, two or three, ideally.
So we can say something like if random number equals, do you remember we learned this equals equals?
Operator That is the equals operator.
That's how we can test it in this case, if one number is equal to another number, right?
If random NUM equals three, then.
Now the way we use the if statement is typically we will use a curly brace.
And when I type that curly brace either out loud or in my head, I am always thinking then because that's
what this essentially means.
If random NUM equals three, then do something OK and that do something part is what we're about to
type next.
So as soon as I hit return after having typed that left curly brace and be careful, that is a curly
brace, same brace that we use when we're creating a method or a class, OK, which just tells Java
that here comes a block of code, so we'll hit return.
All right.
And now I'm set up to type a block of code.
So this is where I typed the code that I want to have executed.
If this thing here is true, OK, or evaluates to being true.
All right.
So in this case, if that number is three, I'm going to print out a message using system out that print
line.
Let's print out a message saying, You got it.
OK.
And that's it.
I think that's all we're going to do with this program at this moment.
All right.
So now all we need to do is run it.
So let's try this out.
I'll just click here and run.
OK.
Well, looks like we did get it, apparently, because here's the random number that was actually generated,
by the way.
Let's let's make this line six a little more informative, shall we?
And one way we can do that is let's use a formatted string.
So instead of using the print line method, let's use the print f method and then we can use a string
like so and say generated number is.
And then we can use a percent d meaning print a decimal number.
OK, and then over here is the actual number.
Do you all remember we learned a little bit about the print statement.
We've actually seen it now a few times in the numbers chapter.
We even learned how to use print to format numbers in really cool ways.
Here, we're not doing all the fancy formatting, though.
We could do some type of formatting, but we're using this just as a placeholder so that we can generate
a nice, you know, message there.
All right.
So let's run this again.
This time, I'll do it from the keyboard.
OK, so this time the generated number was one, and therefore it did not print.
You got it.
So do you, do you get it?
Do you see how the if statement works right?
It should be pretty straightforward.
So in this case, random number was one.
One is not equal to three and therefore Line nine did not execute.
So the thread starts at the beginning of the main method here.
It creates it request to have a random object created with the new random OK, which actually does jump
into the constructor, by the way.
I'm not going to.
I wasn't being very explicit about that, but it does actually jump into the constructor, which is
effectively a method that and then the constructor, you can kind of think of it as returning with a
new random object.
Then it jumps into the next into method, passing in the number three, and then it returns with a randomly
generated number between zero and two.
Then whatever that number was, it gets a one added to it.
Then that gets stored in this variable.
Then it calls the print method of the out object of the system class and passes in all of this and that
causes all of this to be printed on the console.
That's what this area is really called the console.
Then it jumps down here to this if statement and it evaluates it, saying if in this case, one equals
three, which it does not.
So this evaluates to a Boolean OK, and that boolean in this particular execution of the program turned
out to be false.
OK, so let me let me point that out.
The if statement at the end of the day, all it's going to do is if whatever is inside of the parentheses
evaluates to a Boolean true, then it executes whatever is then in between these curly braces.
If it evaluates to false, which is what happened this time, then the thread skips right over.
All of this and jumps to the very next line of execution, which in this case, that is the end of the
program, and so the next thing we see here is process finished with exit code zero.
And this just means I'm done.
And there was nothing eventful to come out of this.
OK, so that is the end of the program.
All right.
So let's run it a few more times and and see, you know what happens here if we run it a few times in
a row?
So the first time we got to three, the next time we got a one.
Let's see where we get this time.
OK, another one, a two, a two, a two.
I'm going to keep going until we get one more three.
Another two.
OK, there we go.
So we got one more.
Three.
You got it.
Oh, and then notice since I used a print off now, we didn't get a new line when it printed.
So if we wanted that new line, do you remember what to put here to get a new line?
All right.
So I would use a percent in and I'm going to just make sure that that looks good.
Oh, oops, I put it in the wrong place, didn't I percent in?
There we go.
And I happened to have gotten another randomly generated three.
Well, a randomly generated two.
And then we added one to it.
All right.
Now there's at least one thing I don't like about this implementation of the program.
It's pretty nice when we do get a match.
But what if we don't get a match?
We don't get any message telling us that it wasn't a match.
All we see is just the same thing at the end of the program, either way, which is that the process
finished.
I would like to be able to see either you got it or you didn't get it or something like that.
OK, so now let me introduce you to another version of the if statement.
This is called an if then statement, by the way.
If then I can remember when I put this curly brace here, I read it.
I read it as then.
OK.
So if then there's another version of this called the if?
Then else, though, OK?
And that allows us to specify if the if statement evaluates to true, then execute the code that is
in one block.
But if it evaluates to false, then execute another a different block of code.
OK.
And so the way we can do that is to simply type.
Else so you're basically saying otherwise.
Right?
And then you use another opening curly brace again.
So curly brace like this and then hit return.
And then again, it gives us a matching closing curly brace right there.
These two yellow guys and then this space in the middle is where we can put another block of code that
should execute if this evaluates to false.
So if it's true, do this.
If it's false, do something else.
OK.
Else so let's have it print some alternative things.
So I'll do a system that out and I'm going to say sorry.
Sorry, you didn't get it.
OK.
And now we'll get a little bit better feedback.
So now let's run this.
OK, so sorry, you didn't get it.
Let's run it a few more times, let's run it until, oh, there we go.
So now we got a three and then we got you got it.
But then when we run it again and we, OK, we got it again.
All right.
So now we didn't get it.
So you get what's going on here.
This gives us a little bit more control over things now.
If it's a match, then you get this.
If it's not a match, then you get this.
Now what you can put in between these parentheses is actually quite powerful.
You can put a lot of different things in here as long as whatever you put in here eventually evaluates
to a Boolean.
OK?
That's the key.
It needs to evaluate to a Boolean.
So let's see here we could change this logic a little bit.
Currently, it says if random NUM equals three, then do this.
We could change it.
We could flip it and say if it does not equal.
Three.
Do you remember how to say random name does not equal three?
I'll give you a moment.
OK, so to say does not equal three.
All you do is get rid of that first equal sign and put and an exclamation, which I read as not OK.
So if random num not equal to three, then do this.
So now let's see how it works.
OK, so generated number was three.
But now we got these.
Sorry, you didn't get it message because we're wanting it to not be a three, right?
We flipped the logic right?
We'll run that a few times.
OK.
So there you go.
So now, if it's not three, it says you got it.
OK, now some other things that we could do.
OK, so we could call a method inside of these parentheses to do so.
Let me just show you what that would look like.
Now this is going to be probably a little nonsensical, and I'm going to make it private because it
does not need to be public, private static.
And this method is going to return a Boolean, and I'm going to call it.
Should I go?
All right.
And I'm going to return true now if I replace all of this with it.
Oops.
With a call to my should I go method?
Let's run that.
OK, so now what's happening is we're no longer evaluating the random number, in fact, we're not even
using the random number at the moment other than just to print out what it is and instead this if statement
is testing whatever the output of this method call is.
So the thread gets to line eight.
It sees that there's a method here.
And so the thread jumps down to this line.
16 and all it says is return true.
And so then this, should I go basically becomes the boolean value of true.
And you already know now that within if statement, all it's waiting for is to see if it's true or not
true or false.
If it's true, then it executes whatever is inside of these curly braces.
Otherwise, and that's another way that you could read this else or else it executes whatever is here.
So if I changed this to false and run it again, now it's always going to run line 11.
OK.
So sorry, you didn't get it.
It's always going to run 911 as long as I leave this method here and leave this logic the way that it
is.
OK.
All right.
Now there's one more variation of the if and else blocks.
In this particular case, we're testing a very Boolean type of scenario.
It's either one way or else.
It's the other way, and those are really your only two options, OK?
But if you wanted to be able to test for a few different scenarios, you could do that as well.
And the way we can do that is, let's see here.
First, I'm going to get rid of this.
This method don't need it now, and we'll put this logic.
Well, we're going to do this logic a little differently.
So now let's say that we wanted our program to do something like if the random number is a one, then
print the color red, OK, and if it's a two, then print the color green, OK, and then for any anything
else, print blue.
All right.
And again, I'm just making random rules here, OK?
So in fact, by the time we started implementing it, I'll probably have forgotten exactly what I said.
All right.
So so if the random number is one, then let's say the color is is red.
But now how can we say also, if the random number is two, then the color is green?
How can we do that?
Well, it's actually pretty easy.
What we can do is I always have trouble deciding where to jump in here to actually do this.
What we can do is I'm going to put a closing curly brace just like that, and then I'm going to say
else space.
If so, I can put more ifs in this if I put the word else there first.
Else, if random NUM equals two, then and now, this new curly brace here is matching up with that
curly brace, which was originally there.
This curly brace here was the one on line 10 until I added a new line.
OK.
So then if I hit enter now it's waiting for me to say some more.
So if the random NUM is two, then system out the color is whatever green.
All right.
And now this else here is saying for any other possibility that we didn't explicitly mention here or
here for all other scenarios.
This is like a catchall.
Do this last thing?
OK.
So now we'll change this and say the color is blue.
So does that make sense?
If it's one, then print red.
If it's to then print green for all other possibilities other than one or two print blue.
OK.
That's what we're saying here.
Now we could be more explicit and say if random number equals three, then print blue and just leave
it like this, we could do that too.
And in this particular case, that would be OK because one, two and three are the only possibilities
that we could ever have.
Right?
But if I were to change this range to five, in fact, you know what?
I will do it.
All right.
So let's run this a few times and just see what kinds of output we get.
First, I said we'll run it several times.
All right, so oh, so right away we got something that wasn't a one two or a three, and as a result,
it didn't print any color at all because we no longer have a catchall for scenarios that don't match
anything that we were looking for, right?
So we were only looking for one, two or three.
We got a four.
We don't have a catch all for four, right?
So if we want to have that catch all still, we need another else block here, right?
Else.
Let's say the color is.
Polka dot.
OK.
All right.
So now let's run this a few times.
So we got a two was the generated color, and so that matched here, and so it ran this line.
The color is green.
And then when it finishes running this line, by the way, I wasn't very explicit about this.
It obviously doesn't execute these other lines.
It just jumps to the end of this.
If block, this whole entire thing is an Earth block.
OK, so jumps to the end of the block and then it executes whatever commands are next, which in this
case, there are no other lines of code to execute.
So let's run this a few more times right now.
The color is three, which is blue.
Three Blue.
Yep, that's right.
Run it again.
This time the color was four.
We don't have an explicit mentioning four four.
And so we get the default catchall polka dot a few more times to five.
I'm not going to stop until we get a one.
There it is.
There's one.
OK, the computer heard me and didn't want me to keep bothering it.
All right.
So I am going to end it here.
I think you hopefully get the gist now of how to use if and else and if else, if and and all of the
variations of if and else.
And there are a few other ways to do similar things here that we will learn in the subsequent lesson.
So I will see you in the next one.