All right, so the first thing we're going to do is to build a simple Hello World Web application.
OK, now normally we'd go into Intel, AJ, Intel, Intel, AJ to create a new project, yada yada.
However, with spring applications, there is actually what many may consider to be a shortcut to getting
started.
And I'm going to show you that now.
So the first thing we're going to do is to open up a browser and we're going to navigate to start dot
spring dot Io and then hit return.
And that brings us to a little Web application that the spring developers have created, which is out
on the internet.
And what this application will do is we can tell it what type of spring application we want to build
and what types of features or functionality we want to have in this application.
And then this little wizard here will generate a mostly empty project that contains all of the add on
spring framework projects that we need, according to the functionality that we said we wanted all in
one go.
And that'll be a downloadable zip file.
And then we'll download that zip file, unzip it onto our computer wherever we want, and then we can
go into intelligence and simply open that project so it will open into its own project.
OK?
So it's just a nice, convenient way that isn't tied to any specific browser that we can create a new
project from scratch.
We don't have to do it this way, but this is one of the easiest ways to get going.
OK, so the first thing we'll do here is to make our selections.
So we've played a little bit with MAVEN and Gradle I may have mentioned before.
I personally prefer Gradle a little bit over MAVEN, though MAVEN certainly came before Gradle and there
was a long period of time years, in fact, where I was a huge proponent of MAVEN.
But then Gradle came along and eventually I kind of decided I liked Gradle a little a little better,
mostly just because Gradle is able to describe what is needed for a project more concisely than can
be done with with MAVEN.
So I'm personally picking Gradle, but it doesn't matter that much.
I do encourage you, though, to follow me so that we're all on the same page.
And of course, we'll make our language Java.
Now I will point out, though, that the spring framework has fantastic support for using it with other
languages such as Kotlin and Groovy.
But we'll be sticking with Java in this Java course.
And then we also need to decide what version of spring boot we want.
We won't be using any of the experimental cutting edge features of spring, but as of the time of this
recording, so for now, I'm picking two, six three now at the time when you're watching this video.
If there are stable, newer versions of Java, such as 2.7, which is already looking like it's about
to be maybe a release candidate or something.
So if there's 2.7 here and then up here, you're seeing 2.8 m one or something like that.
Don't worry about it.
You can, you can pick 2.7.
You don't have to look for 2.6 that three.
Hopefully, by the time that they have stabilized version 3.0, I may have gone into this video or updated
it with a little note to tell you that it's OK to pick version three.
OK, and then down here, we'll have to tell it a little bit of metadata about our project.
This may look familiar to you because these are the same basic questions that we are asked when we create
a new maven or Gradle project within intelligence.
So we'll have to specify a group.
I will, as usual, use my own company name.
You could use your last name, followed by your first name, whatever you want to do, or you can use
my company name.
It doesn't matter or your own company name.
It really doesn't matter.
OK, so I will do.
Com That neutrino sis.
And then for the artifact, that's basically the name of the project that effectively.
So I think what we're going to build ultimately is going to be a UI version, a UI web application version
of our people database.
So I'm thinking, maybe I'm going to call this people D.B. hyphen web because it'll be a web application.
Now you can feel free to call it whatever you like, though.
All right.
And these other fields are optional.
I guess I'll put something in here, though a people crud application, because eventually we'll make
this to create, read update delete functions all within a browser.
OK, and then finally, we're just seeing the total the combined name of this.
Com Neutrino, says people D.B. Dash Web.
And that's fine.
Now it's also asking us, how will we want this application to be packaged when we're done with it so
that it can be executed?
I'm not going to get into a whole lot of the details here, but basically our choices are a jar file
or a war file.
If if we choose a jar file, what that will mean is when we build the final version of our project and
we are ready to run it somewhere.
If you're a Windows user, a jar file is somewhat equivalent to an XY or an executable.
OK, it's a standalone file that contains everything that's needed to make that application run.
OK.
For the most part, I mean, you do have to have Java installed on on a computer still.
But but other than that, it pretty much has everything in it.
A war file, on the other hand, is something that is meant to be deployed into what is called an application
server.
We won't be going too deep into that right now, but suffice it to say, we're going to be choosing
a jar file, which tends to be the easier, more self-contained style of packaging and then for the
version of Java.
Why not go ahead and use the latest since we've been learning how to use the latest features anyway?
So I'm going to target Java 17 as of the time of this recording, and again, if Java 18 or whatever
is out.
By the time you're watching this and that's one of your options there, you can probably feel safe to
go ahead and select whatever that latest version is.
OK, and now we get to choose what kinds of functionality we want this application to have.
OK.
So you can either click up here on this Add Dependencies button or you can click if you're on Mac Command,
be I'm guessing for Windows.
It's probably controlled by.
I don't know what you'll be seeing if you're on a Windows computer, so I'm going to do the command.
Be there.
OK.
And so now we get to choose from a long, long list of features and capable capabilities, and I'm just
going to scroll through this just so you get an idea.
I mean, there's just a ton of functionality that the spring framework supports.
And honestly, I'm certain that not everything that the spring framework fully supports or the ecosystem
of the spring framework is even added in here.
Although a whole lot of the most popular things are.
So we're going to just start at the top and just work our way down because we're going to pick a number
of things.
We'll start here with this spring boot dev tools, and I guess I'll try to explain very, very briefly
what each of these will do.
OK.
So the spring boot dev tools package will allow us to develop our application in the.
I.D. while it's running and whenever we make small changes to the application, even while it's running,
so we'll be able to see the application in a web browser, right?
That will be our finished product, but we will be able to make changes while the application is running
and those changes will take effect much more quickly than if we did not use the spring boot dev tools
add on.
OK.
So it basically just allows us to have a much quicker round trip between making a change and then seeing
that change take effect in the browser.
So to select that, I'm going to hold down on the command button and click on that.
That way, I can select additional features without having to come back into this little pop-up window
here.
OK?
The next feature we're going to select is Lombok.
So if you'll recall, we learned how we could create both classes and records and records in Java are
a relatively new feature of Java that allows us to create lighter weight classes with less boilerplate.
So we don't have to explicitly write out the setters and getters and the two string and the equals in
the hash code methods in particular, or even the constructor for that matter.
Those are all essentially just get generated for us.
Lombok is an older technology that actually implements a very similar set of capabilities for traditional
classes rather than records.
OK?
And it does this by giving us annotations that we can place on our class, usually at the top of the
class.
And then the framework itself will generate those getters and setters and constructors and all of these
kinds of things for us.
Now, one major difference between Lombok and using records, though, is that records are final.
OK.
And because they are final, we often can't utilize them in the same ways that we would want to use
a class.
So for example, if we created an instance of a class and then later on, we wanted to make changes
to properties of that, of that instance.
You can't do that with a record, but you can do that with classes.
And so by combining Lombok with classes, we kind of get the best of both worlds.
We get the ability to avoid having to write out all of that boilerplate code, like you can do with
records.
But the instances of our classes don't have to be final.
All right.
So we'll we'll I'm going to hold down on the command key and choose Lombok.
And by the way, if you forget to hold down on the command key or I guess, maybe control for Windows
and Linux users and this window goes away.
In fact, they here, I'll just show you real quick like this?
Don't worry about it.
You can just click on the Add Dependencies button again to get back in here.
OK.
All right.
The next thing we're going to grab is spring web, and that represents that spring MVC framework that
I mentioned before.
So this is what we need to select if we want to build a web application, write an application that
runs any web browser.
All right.
So we'll go ahead and select that.
OK, then we'll scroll some more.
The next thing we want is under this template engines.
We want to select time timely if is going to be a little difficult for me to explain, but it has to
do with web application development and basically making templates that represent the web pages that
we are going to be making.
So I will explain more about that when we get into it.
But we we want to use that.
So I will select Time Leaf and then scroll for more.
And now we're getting into the database related technologies.
So for this, we're going to choose spring data JPA So Spring Day to JPA is spring's framework that
will enable us to interact with a relational database without having to write much code at all.
And I mean, like, we basically almost won't write any code.
In fact, it's it's really, really magical.
So we will select that.
OK.
And we will scroll for more and we will want to use the H2 database again.
Now there again are many databases that we could use, but I want to keep this relatively simple.
If we wanted to use one of the other databases, we'd have to all.
I'd have to also teach you how to either install one of those databases or use a technology called Docker
or something like that where where you can kind of stand up a data, a proper database server.
And I really don't want to get into all of that in this course right now.
So we will keep this relatively easy, as we did in the last section, and we will just use the H2 database
again.
And at any rate, you have some familiarity with it now.
Not that you'll need to get too deep into it in this section.
All right.
So we'll choose H2 and down here under IO.
We also want the validation framework.
This will come in handy when we're making web forms, and we want those forms to be able to validate
the data that we're entering.
So if we say that someone has to enter their first name, for example, and they leave that field blank,
we don't want them to be able to submit that form.
We want them to be stopped and be forced to and give them some feedback, telling them, Hey, you can't
submit this form with a blank first name.
You have to have the first name filled, filled out.
Things of that sort.
So that's what this validation framework will will give us.
So let's select that.
And that's finally it.
OK.
So we can.
You can.
I'm just going to click over here and now we can see all of the dependencies that I have chosen.
So just to reiterate, we've got spring boot dev tools Lombok Spring Web Time, Leaf Spring Data, JPA,
H2 database and validation.
OK.
So once you've got all of that and everything filled out as I do.
Go ahead and click the Generate button.
And that is going to generate the project.
Zip it up into a zip file and then download it to our computer.
So the next step is to unzip that file.
In most cases, it will probably have downloaded into your downloads folder.
Feel free to move that to wherever you like.
So wherever you have been writing your code throughout this project, you may want to move that zip
file or the unzipped version of it into whatever that folder is.
OK, so I'm going to do that off camera.
OK, so I went ahead and copied my people db das web zip file into the idea of projects folder on my
computer.
That's where most of my projects that I've been working on with you guys live.
You can again, though, you can put yours wherever you like.
And then I went ahead and unzipped it, as well as on Mac.
At least you can just double click that zip file and unzip it, probably on Windows.
You can do that in the same way as well, so hopefully you shouldn't have any trouble with that.
OK, so now that you've gotten that done, let's meet up in the next lesson and we will write our first
application.
So I'll see you there.