Welcome back.
So in the last lesson, we did a whirlwind tour of object orientation.
We wrote some classes so that you could get an idea of how modeling works, modeling of ideas, works
and object orientation and how to do that in Java.
In this lesson, we'll take a deeper dive into the basic anatomy of a class how to and how to create
a class.
For clarity sake, we will do this in a new project.
So this is going to be another mostly lecture.
So you are welcome to follow along.
But I won't be going too slowly for you here because I'm mostly just wanting to show you a few things
about how to make a class.
Don't worry.
In some subsequent lessons, I will be going slower and you will be expected to follow along and you
will even get some homework.
OK, but you don't have to do that here.
All right.
So I'm going to create a new project.
I'm going to accept the defaults.
Let's see, I'm going to call this business.
And I will do this in a new window.
OK, so what I want to do is I want to model a little bit of a world here, a world in which there is
a business and there is a news agency and the news agency can interview the business.
Let's call it a company.
The news agency can interview the company, but there may be one or two other entities or one or two
other concepts that I don't necessarily want everybody to be able to interact with.
That will become clearer in just a moment.
So first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to model a company, so I'm going to create a new Java class.
I'm going to call this company with a Capital C.
Real quick note about naming conventions of classes real quick by convention.
Class names are always capitalized.
They do not have to be.
Java will allow you to create a class that's lowercase, but don't do that if you're taking this course
so that you can become a professional software developer, especially working in a company and you create
your classes in lowercase.
You'll be showing them that you might not know what you're doing.
So just don't do that.
Class names should be capitalized because that is the standard convention.
Class names can start with an underscore, but don't do that.
Class names cannot start with numbers or symbols other than an underscore.
So don't try to do any of those things, though the good thing is that the idea will generally stop
you from.
In fact, it will.
It will stop you from doing everything that isn't allowed by Java.
It won't stop you from doing the things that are technically allowed by Java, but shouldn't be done.
So just do yourself a favor.
Keep your class names as words that are capitalized that start with a capital letter.
OK.
Don't make the class name all caps, either, though that also goes against convention.
So those are some basic things.
You can have numbers in the middle or at the end of the class name.
There might occasionally be some good reasons to do that, but in my 20 plus years of experience as
a Java developer, there have been very few reasons why I've ever needed to put numbers at the end of
something.
But I'm sure I've done it once or twice.
OK, let's see.
So now let's look at the anatomy of this.
The first bit here is the visibility of the class.
I will explain what that means.
Very shortly in this lesson, someone to skip past that.
For now, the next part is the keyword class, which just indicates that we're creating a class.
The reason we need this keyword is because there are a few other things that you could create besides
a class, and you will learn about those in subsequent lessons.
The next bit here is the name of the class.
We've pretty much already covered the ground rules for how to name that.
And then the next two bits here are just an indication that here begins the class and here ends the
class.
And these are just curly braces.
These have to be here because these let Java know where the body of the class goes.
So if I were to do this, for example, and I could start typing, you know, code or whatever.
By the way, these forward slashes that I'm putting are two forward slash, as that means I'm just making
a comment which will be ignored by Java.
I can type pretty much whatever I want here, and it'll just be ignored.
OK, so that's what these forward slashes mean.
So I'm just showing you that this represents the body of my class where the good stuff goes right,
the definitions and code and all of that, all that kind of stuff.
All right.
OK.
Know, get rid of all of that.
So there is one piece of this skeleton of a class that is actually optional and that is this visibility
bit here.
I actually could get rid of that.
And this is a perfectly valid class.
And this is the most minimal class that you could possibly define.
Of course, it does absolutely nothing at all, but this is the most minimal that you could have.
All right.
So we've got a class.
I'm going to leave it this way, by the way, and now I'm going to create another class.
So let's say that a company can have a worker creating a class here.
I don't know.
Let's call it a factory worker.
OK.
And again, I'll get rid of the public here because I don't technically need it right now.
Then if I go back over here to company, I can even say that there is some kind of relationship between
the company and the factory worker.
So I could say factory worker and I'll just call him or her a worker.
Now in the Hello World program, when I created fields like this in a class, you may recall that I
was putting the word private there.
And that is the typical way that I would be doing things.
I'm going to maybe not put that in here for right now, only because I don't want to confuse you when
we get talking more about visibility and things, but that is typically how I would do this.
All right.
So basically, what I'm saying right now is company has some type of relationship with a worker.
OK, now not necessarily specifying what type of relationship that is, but a company has some type
of relationship with a worker.
All right.
Now I'm going to create one more class and this will be a news agency.
OK.
And again, the idea, by the way, is the thing that's throwing this public bit in here.
I don't need it as you have seen, but the idea just assumes that most of the time when you're creating
a class, you want the class to be public.
And I would say that probably might be true.
Most of the time.
But for right now, I'm going to get rid of that.
Now I'm going to say also that the news agency has some type of relationship to a company.
And I can say that by just making a field for the company and I'll call it company just like that.
All right.
So I've kind of set up this little world here.
Now, let me lay down some ground rules.
Let us assume that the purpose of a news agency is to interview companies.
Let us also assume that a news agency should not be permitted to interview factory workers of the company.
OK.
So the CEO of the company just makes a rule.
I don't want any factory workers talking with the news.
OK.
I want to stop that from happening.
Well, so right now, there's nothing stopping us from saying something like factory worker right here.
OK, so in other words, what I'm saying is the news agency has full access to factory workers.
But the company doesn't like that and doesn't want that.
OK.
Company needs factory workers to get work done.
But company doesn't want news agency to be able to interact with a factory worker.
How can this be stopped?
How can we stop?
How can we prevent the news agency from being able to access a factory worker?
Well, the first thing that we could do is to take our company and our factory worker and put them in
their own little package, if you will.
And the way that I would do that is to click on the source folder and then create a new package.
And I did this in the Hello World program as well when we created all of our models.
I created a package called Model, and that's where I put what was that person and dog and pet and all
of those things.
OK, so now I'm going to create a package and I'm going to call this business.
All right.
And now I'm going to grab my company and my factory worker, and I'm going to just move them both into
the business package and the way I'm doing that is just dragging them.
There are a couple of ways that I could do it, but that might be the easiest for me right now.
And I'm going to accept all of these default things here, and I'm going to ignore all of that for right
now.
OK, cool.
Now I'm getting some errors and we'll go take a look at what those are in just a moment.
But for right now, company and factory worker are now inside of a package, which is really just a
folder called business.
And then if I jump over here to the news agency now, look what's going on.
I'm getting all these red marks on the company and on the factory worker.
And if I hover over one of these, the ID will tell me, what's what's going on here?
Business, that company is not public in business, cannot be accessed from outside the package.
So what it's saying is that news agency is no longer allowed to see or or interact with the company
or factory worker classes.
And the reason for that is because news agency, which is this guy here he is in his own package.
I didn't create a package for him, but he is in a package.
He's in what is considered the default package.
It's the invisible package that all classes are in if you don't explicitly put them in a package.
OK, so the news agency is in his own package called the default package, and the company and factory
worker are in their own package called business and company and factory worker.
Are not public.
Their visibility is called package protected, OK?
And what that really means is that the company and factory worker can only see each other inside of
this business package.
But other classes that are outside of the business package can't see or interact with these two classes
anymore because they are both package protected.
OK.
And so that's why I'm getting these complaints here that the news agency can't see these guys anymore.
Now I do want the news agency to be able to see the company so I can fix that really easily by simply
declaring that the company class is public.
Yeah.
OK.
Right.
The company can be seen by the public, and now if I jump back over here to the news agency, the red
mark went away for the company, so news agency can now see the company because the company is public.
I did not do that for the factory worker, though the factory worker is still package protected.
And this is a pretty good relationship, according to the rules that I laid out.
I want the news agency to be able to interview the company, but not the workers, not the factory workers
of the company.
The company, however.
Can interact with the factory workers.
And that is appropriate, I want that to be the case.
OK, so this is this is all good and we'll just take another look at the factory worker.
And again, the factory worker is package protected because I do not have the word public here.
So this is pretty good.
So now I could just get rid of this reference to the factory worker because I don't want news agency
to be able to interact with a factory worker.
Right.
So I can do this and then I can also get rid of this lying to here just like that.
OK, now one more thing that I want to call attention to this first line here in the news agency class
import.
What is that all about?
So basically now that the company class is in a different package from the news agency, when I refer
to company down here, I have to tell Java, Where is this company class coming from?
OK?
By default, Java will expect to find the company class within the same package as this class, or it
will also look for it in one or two other packages.
One of them is called Java Dot Lang.
That is a default package that Java will look for things in as well.
This company class is in neither of those, though.
And so if I want to be able to refer to the company class by just its name and nothing else, just the
short name here, I have to import it into the class so that Java knows what company I'm talking about.
So basically, I'm saying, Hey, Java, anytime you see me refer to this name company like this.
Just know that that I'm really talking about business dot company.
That's the fully qualified name of this class business dot company.
OK.
Now I don't have to have this line this important here at all.
I could get rid of this.
I can comment it out, for example, or I could delete it.
And then I could come down here and just ride out.
The fully qualified name of this class business accompany the fully qualified name, right, the whole
entire name, so I could do that.
And every time I refer to company, anywhere in my program, in this, in this class or other classes
that are outside of the business package, I would have to write all of that out.
Most good programmers are a little bit lazy and wouldn't want to have to do that.
And so rather than having to do all of that, I can get rid of that and instead just import the specific
company class that I want.
Now, just to make this even slightly more clear, I'm going to create one more package here.
And I'll just call it other.
Package.
And in this other package, I could create another class and I could call this company also.
And so here's another reason why importing is important.
Well, here, if I comment this out, how does Java know which company I want?
And in fact, right here it's saying, hey, you have multiple choices for which company you're referring
to.
So if I just do it like this, Java doesn't know which company I'm referring to.
Am I talking about the company that's in the in the business package?
Or am I talking about the company that's in the other package, right?
So I again would either have to be very explicit and say, I want other package dot company.
I could do that.
Or.
Business Dot company or.
I could import business stock comp at company or.
I could import.
Or I could import other package company, and in fact, see, it's giving me the option there.
But I want the business company for now, and I'm going to get rid of this other package in the class
they're in.
OK.
So one last thing I think I want to just note here is this protection of classes and visibility is a
is another pretty powerful concept in object orientation.
If I were writing a really complex project with tens or hundreds of classes, I might very well have
some classes that I want.
For example, the company to be able to use, but I don't want other classes outside of this package
to be able to use those, those those classes.
And so in order to keep the overall structure of my program relatively simple from the perspective of
certain other classes, this whole idea of visibility and things is actually quite useful.
OK, so that wraps up this lesson.
In the next lesson, we will do a little deeper dive into methods.
So I will see you in the next one.