All right, so in this lesson, the first thing we're going to do is to set ourselves up for an introduction
into the Streams API and a bit more of lambdas.
So specifically, what we're going to do is we're going to basically re implement some of this basic
functionality that we have here in the main Java file.
We're going to implement some of this, but using primarily the Streams API, and we'll do this in another
Java class because there's kind of a lot going on here, kind of a lot of noise.
So the first thing we're going to do, if you're not already there, go ahead and go back into the main
Java file and let's copy the people text variable in all of the data inside of it, right?
So I'm just going to select and drag or you can I just let go of my drag, but I can hold down on the
ship key and then click down here to select the rest of that and then do a command C or A or a control
C to copy.
And then I'm going to open up the project view pane over here on the left, and I'm just going to create
another class and it's not really going to matter too much what this class is called.
We're kind of still just sort of playing around.
So I'm going to go to new Java class and I don't know, maybe I'll call this one streams.
Stuff you can call yours whatever you like.
And this will be a class and enter.
All right, and then I'm going to make a new line inside of the class by holding that on shift and enter,
and I will create a public static void main with IBM and hit enter.
All right.
And now the first thing I'm going to do is just go ahead and paste that variable here.
Here we go.
And then I'm going to give myself a little more room by closing the project pane on the left.
OK, so we'll start off with something relatively simple, let's just reproduce the capability of this
class to convert all of these lines of text back into instances of employee and print them out basically
as we're doing in the other class.
Now for this, I'm going to go ahead and just type this out first, and then I will come back and explain
what's going on.
So what my my purpose here is is basically just expose you to some of the basics of what can be done
with the Streams API.
All right.
So I'm my is at the bottom of this variable declaration here in hit enter a couple of times.
And so I'm going to go right ahead and reference this variable here.
Now one thing you're going to notice I won't be using any loops at all.
OK?
And that's kind of a lot of the magic of the Streams API.
All right.
So people text is the variable.
So watch this.
I can reference the people text variable and we will utilize our first new foray into the streams API
people text dot lines.
Now notice this method line's returns, something called a stream of strings.
I know that's kind of a bit of a tongue twister, huh?
A stream of strings.
So I'm not going to do a lot of explaining right now, but we will come back.
Basically, though, you can think of this as essentially breaking down this multi line string into
individual lines.
And what this stream of strings will do is to feed the individual lines of this string into what's called
a pipeline.
And that pipeline is what we will use to process the strings and do all kinds of cool things with them,
essentially all in one go.
OK.
So we will reference the lines method here, which returns the stream of strings.
All right.
Next, we will simply print each string one at a time.
Now, notice what I'm going to do here.
I'm going to just hit enter without a semicolon or anything because I'm actually not done.
I'm going to build what's called a pipeline.
So I'm going to hit enter, and I don't like this formatting that the ABC does, I'm going to hold down
on ship and tab.
You don't have to do this, but I prefer to have this be back by one indentation, if you will.
So not not there, but there, but it doesn't matter.
It's just my own personal preference.
And the next thing I will do is type, period and then for each.
All right.
Just like that.
Now notice the for each method here is expecting something called a consumer.
Now this is basically referring to a type of functional interface called a consumer.
And that is just an interface with one method defined on it that takes input but doesn't return any
output.
So it consumes.
OK.
So I can place any method or lambda expression here that accepts some type of input that is a type of
string.
That's essentially what this is saying.
A question mark superstring, meaning something that has a super class of string.
Or is a string itself, but doesn't return anything?
OK, now watch this I'm going to use something else that we haven't seen before.
OK, now I could.
I could put a lambda expression in here that satisfies this condition here, but I'm going to do something
new.
I'm going to type system that out.
Colon colon.
Print line.
OK.
And now I'm just going to read this without explaining too much, although I think it might be sort
of obvious what it's going to do.
So I'm going to run this.
All right.
So all that did is just print each of the lines from this string, but it's doing it one line at a time
instead of printing out the entire string as one string, right?
So basically, this line's method here is able to split this multi-line string into individual strings
for each line.
The definition of a line within this string is all of the text that comes before a new line character
or whatever the operating systems definition for a line.
Terminator is right.
We've kind of touched on that a little bit before backslash and represents new line.
That's one of the more common Terminators for the end of the line on some operating systems or in some
software.
It may be two characters which would be like a carriage return and a new line or something like that.
So anyway, the lines method is smart enough to understand those differences and figure out what is
what constitutes one line of text within a string.
And so it will grab each of those lines individually and then feed them into what is called a stream.
Now, because this line's method returns a type of stream and being very careful here to enunciate the
Strings API, which is what we're playing with here, has lots of methods that know how to take the
output from previous streams API method and do further processing.
So what's happening here, essentially, is that this line's method is returning a stream of strings,
which are the individual lines, and then you can think of it this way.
Each string is being fed into the next node into the next step of this pipeline, which is the dot for
each method.
OK.
And in fact, I could even break this up like this.
Maybe that makes it look even a little more like a true pipeline.
This is a simple pipeline with just two with just two steps, though the lines calling in the need for
each and then look for each method, as we've already just discussed, is expecting a method or a reference
to a method or a lambda expression that satisfies the consumer interface.
And the consumer interface simply defines one method on it that takes some type of input and and does
not return anything.
And in fact, if we go look at the consumer interface real quick, it's right here under the job that
you tilt the function package.
Let's go take a peek at it.
So this interface?
Only defines one abstract method, because functional interfaces can only be find one abstract method,
as we've learned previously.
And the method is called accept and it uses generics.
Now we haven't done a time about generics here, but you have learned a little bit that when we're utilizing
a type that defines generics, we can pass them with that Typekit.
So this T in our case would become string, which means that this consumer interface handles strings
for our for our utilization at this moment in time.
And so the word string replaces the T everywhere where you see this capital T here.
So what this is saying is that for our purposes, this accepted method would accept something that is
of type string, right?
And it returns nothing.
And that's all it's really saying.
So it's not magic, it's not really doing anything.
It's just defining a an interface and a method for us.
OK.
All right, so we jump back over here.
It just so happens that this print line method follows that exact signature.
The print line method accepts input, and I'll just show you here in parentheses, if you will recall
we could, we could have written this out like this line?
Hello.
Right.
So this is a massive print line on the out class of the system class.
That takes an input.
Of a string.
But does not return any output.
It prints the word string to the screen, but it does not return any output.
So what's new here is the way that we're referencing this method, rather than typing out this method
explicitly, as we have previously done and passing in some type of input here explicitly, we're allowing
the input to be implied using this new syntax, which is called a method reference because it refers
to an existing method and because of the rules of how method references work.
Java is able to determine that because we're referring to this method print line that takes one input.
It should take the individual strings one at a time from this stream of strings and pass them one at
a time into a call to the print line method.
And so what this for each is actually saying is that for each string in the stream that's being passed
in, call this method and pass in each string into the into the as input into the method.
OK, we'll go into this in more detail later.
I'm just giving you a high level view of what's going on here.
OK, now so you can think of this entire pipeline almost like a for loop essentially, right?
Because this lines thing here, you can think of that as sort of outputting a collection of strings.
Now that's not really what it's doing, but you can kind of think of it that way.
OK?
And then each of those strings in this imaginary collection, which in this case is is really a stream,
then is is going into this for each into this for each method.
And the very name of that method for each implies a loop.
Right.
It's a four.
In fact, in many programming languages, there is a for each loop, there's an actual type of loop
called for each, right.
And so the looping behavior is kind of implied in the name of this method, right?
So for each of the strings that are being passed into it in that stream, it's going to loop over them
kind of sort of like and call whatever method we're referring to, whether it's a lambda or an explicit
method or a method reference.
And in fact, let me go ahead and just show you that real quick.
So here we're using a method reference, but let me show you what this would look like with a lambda
expression.
OK.
So I could do something like this is a method that takes an input and doesn't return any any output,
right?
So a lambda expression for that might look like, let's see, string, I'll have a variable and then
an arrow operator.
And then I would say something like system that out.
Print line and then just reference the variable there, the s right.
So this s here is my input.
And here it is right here.
Now this is actually considered a shorthand, and I'm not going to go all into this, but I'll just
show you this real quick.
This is actually sort of a shorthand for lambda expressions.
The fuller syntax would actually be.
That right.
So here's a method that takes a string as input called s, and then it takes that input, and then it
calls this method with that same input being passed in right?
And just for quick little reminder, that's pretty equivalent to having a method like, let's see void.
Print stuff.
String as.
System died out print line as.
OK, so this being a method called Prince stuff that takes as input a string called S and then prints
that out.
All of this is equivalent to this.
The difference being that I've removed the method name, I'm not referring to a method name.
It's anonymous, right?
It's like an anonymous method.
And then as I showed you earlier, we actually don't even need to refer to the type because that can
be inferred.
OK?
Java knows that the output from this is a stream of strings, and therefore any lambda expression that
expects one input has to be a string java's smart that way, right?
It knows.
So we don't need the type.
And then we also don't need the parentheses there, either.
OK.
But as I showed you early, initially, we don't even need any of that.
We can simply system that our colon colon print line, we can use a method reference because now job
is smart enough to know that the print line method takes one input.
That input has to be the strings that are coming out of this stream, right?
All right.
So that's how you could do that.
Let me clear this out.
Now, let me show you one more thing here.
This isn't really doing much other than just printing these out, right?
Let's actually turn them into employees, as we were doing in the previous program.
So we need to take each one of these strings and call the create employee method, which exists on the
employee class, right?
So let me show you how we can do that with streams.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to kind of break into this pipeline and add another step.
So this first step lines here is breaking this string into individual lines.
Right now, I want to take each of these individual lines and convert them one at a time into an employee.
Watch how I can do this.
Let me back up there so I can use the map method on the of the Streams API.
And what the map method does is it takes one input and it returns one output and the functional interface
that is capable of doing exactly that.
Taking one input and returning one output is called function.
And so we can see right here that the map method is expecting an input of function.
So this is an interface that defines one method on it that takes one input of any type of any generic
type and returns one output of some other type.
It could be the same type also, but it allows for the for the return type to be something different.
OK.
So in our case, the input type would be string right because each line is a string and the output type,
do you want to think what would the output type be here?
So the output type could be I employee, because that's what the employee does not create employee method
returns.
So let's let's see what that could look like.
So first, I will do this a little more explicitly and then I will show you how we can do this with
a little less typing as well.
OK, so we're going to take as input a string.
So I'm going to refer to that is yes, I'm going to do this with the Lambda first, OK?
And then we're going to be calling the employee that create employee method and then just passing the
s just like that.
So we know that this create employee method, which is a static method.
That's why I can call it like this without having to create an instance of anything, right?
The Create employee method takes a string, which is one of these lines, and it returns something of
type I employee.
OK, now what's going to happen in my pipeline here is that now for each of these lines, they will
be converted in into an AI employee and then passed into the for each method here, which will then
simply print them out.
All right, so let's run this and see what we get.
It's not going to be way different.
OK, so look at that that's already looking, I think, identical to the output from our previous project.
As far as this list is concerned right now, we're not adding things up yet, but that is the output
that we were getting before and it's in the same order as what we've got here because we're not using
any collections right now, right?
We're not throwing these into an array list or a set or a map or anything like that.
We're simply letting the line's method pass this string and break it into the individual lines in the
order in which they are listed here, right?
And then we're processing each one at a time, converting from string to I employee something of the
type I employee the interface, right?
And then just printing that.
Now let me show you.
Alternatively, though, because this is a method that takes one input and returns one output.
Again, I can just simplify this to use a method reference, and I will do that by simply getting rid
of these bits here.
And then instead of the employee create employee, I will use employee colon colon and then I don't
need to specify anything here because Java is smart enough to understand what I need here.
So it knows again that the lines thing here.
The lines method is returning a stream of strings, and so it should take each string one at a time
and pass it in to the create employee method.
It should then take the output of the create employee method and pass that in to the next step in the
pipeline.
That's how the streams API works.
There are some exceptions to this.
For example, the for each method here doesn't return another stream.
In fact, if I if I hover over it, we can see here that it's return type is void.
OK.
That's because the for each method of the streams API is what we call a terminal operation, which is
printed, which is listed right there.
It's the end of the line, if you will, right?
It's kind of it can only be used at the end of a pipeline of a streams API pipeline.
All right.
So I'm going to wrap it up here.
I just wanted to give a quick overview of what the streams API kind of looks like.
So in the subsequent lessons will be digging in deeper and learning a lot more about how all of this
works, and there's so much more that we can do with this.
We will effectively just be re implementing everything that we did in the main Java class, but using
the Streams API, so I'll see you in the next one.