All right, so here I am in a browser and I'm going to search for download.
Squirrel.
Sequel client.
All right.
And I'm just going to jump right down here to the link for downloads.
All right, and we've got a big green download button there that looks like a good candidate to me,
some clicking on that.
And it's telling me that it's going to start the download in a few seconds, and there we go, so I
can click Allow.
If you're on windows, it might operate a little bit differently depending on what browser you're using,
but it should be pretty much the same.
All right, and so that is starting the download, all right, and that's done, so I'm going to go
ahead and launch this.
So now I'm getting a security message on my operating system.
I'm on macOS telling me that I can't just run this application by default because it's from an unidentified
developer and it's something that I downloaded from the internet.
So on my Mac, I'm going to have to go into my security settings and allow this program to be installed.
So let me just clear that out for a second jump up here to the system preferences, security and privacy
general.
All right.
And so down here, it knows that I tried to run this squirrel jar and it's asking me if I want to open
it anyway, and I do.
So I'm going to click on that.
All right.
So now.
I can click open.
There we go.
All right, and so now I'm in the installer and so I can click next and next again.
And it's asking me, where do I want to install it?
This is the standard location, so I'm not going to change that.
I'm going to allow that in next and it's going to create that directory.
That's fine.
Click OK.
And then it's asking me, what additional plugins do I want?
I don't have to select any at this time.
I could select them later on, since I do know, though, that we are going to be working soon here
with the H2 database.
I am inclined to go ahead and click on that right now.
And that's it.
So I'm going to click next.
And next again and done, all right.
And then I'm going to close down a couple of these little bits here.
All right.
So now you should have squirrel installed on your computer and I'm going to go ahead and launch it.
I'm just going to use the keyboard shortcut for Spotlight and I'm going to type Squirrel.
And there it is, right there under Application Squirrel sequel.
OK.
And I'm going to close that help window there.
All right, so here we are in Squirrel.
Let me make that bigger.
All right, so now that we've installed Squirrel, the next step is that we're going to have to install
a driver.
So in order to understand what drivers are, let's talk about the database that we're about to use and
how all of this stuff kind of works.
So first thing I want to state is that Squirrel is a database SQL client that is written in Java, so
this is an actual Java desktop application.
As such, it uses Java's own standardized API and mechanisms for connecting to various databases, and
it's capable of connecting to just about every relational database there is as long as there is a so-called
driver for that database for Java.
So Java has a standardized API for programming against various databases.
This API is called JDI B.C., and it stands for Java database connectivity, so you can basically think
of the ABC API as a set of interfaces.
OK.
And each company or organization that makes a database that they want to be connectable by Java has
to write classes that implement these standardized interfaces.
So this is one of those places where interfaces are being used to make code very flexible in that different
database providers can all allow their different databases to be interacted with in a standardized way
because they're all hiding behind a standardized abstraction layer, which is the JBC API interfaces.
So their drivers are really just the implementation classes for the standard ADC interfaces.
So if we want to connect to a particular database with Java, typically that database has to provide
JBC drivers for us, and this is actually a very common pattern.
Even outside of the world of Java, most programming languages and platforms have their own equivalent
to ABC.
So the database we're going to be working with in this module is called H2, and I like this database
a lot because it's very small and very easy to download and install, and it offers some very flexible
options for how we can interact with it.
I mentioned at the beginning that generally speaking, databases are programs that are installed on
a computer, and those programs usually sit and wait for other computers on the same network to connect
to them to issue SQL commands, essentially.
And the H2 database can be used pretty much in that same standard type of way.
However, H2 being that it is a very lightweight database is also able to be embedded within another
program.
OK, so it doesn't have to be installed as its own standalone program, though it can be.
It can also be embedded in other programs that we would write, and it can also access data that is
stored very simplistically in an individual file.
And so this just makes H2 really convenient for us to work with as I am teaching you the beginning basics
of databases.
You don't have to like install a whole entire application, which can usually be somewhat involved.
We can keep it relatively simple.
All right.
So now we're going to actually go download the H2 driver, someone to go back to the browser here and
type download H2.
Driver.
There we go and there's our downloads right here.
And what we can do is just grab this platform independent zip file here, so I'm going to click on that.
All right, so that's downloaded.
OK, so now I will click here to open that file.
Now, that was a zip file, by the way, my operating system automatically unzipped zip files.
If yours does not, then you'll want to download the zip file, then go to wherever it downloaded,
probably in your downloads folder.
Unzip that file, which will expand out into a folder called H2 mine, is called H2 Dash, too, because
I already had another one on the computer.
And then you can go inside of that folder and then you should see everything that I'm seeing here.
All right.
So at this point, you're going to have to make a decision as to where you want to store this folder
permanently.
Some of you may choose to just leave it in the downloads folder, and that's fine if that's how you
operate your computer.
Some of you may prefer to move this into somewhere like a home directory or something like that.
To keep this simple, I'm going to just leave this in my downloads folder for now.
But just be aware that if you were going to continue to operate with H-2 in the way that we will in
this module, you might want to consider grabbing this whole entire H-2 folder and moving it somewhere
a little more permanent.
If you don't like your downloads folder, getting cluttered up with all of the download stuff and you
occasionally like to delete a lot of that stuff, you don't want to accidentally delete this.
All right.
But like I said, I'm going to just leave mine in the downloads folder for right now.
OK, so here's the folder.
It's in my downloads.
So you're going to want to make a note of where you're leaving this H-2 folder because we're going to
have to go back to it in just a moment here.
All right.
So now I will go back to Squirrel.
So we're going to go to drivers and then.
Click on H-2 Embedded.
And then right click on it and modify driver.
Then click on extra class path.
Add.
Now, because I've already installed an to drive around here, it's opening me up right to where that
driver is installed, but now that you've downloaded and unzipped the H2 folder and you may either have
left it in your downloads folder, or you may have copied it into another folder, like in your home
directory or somewhere like that, you'll want to navigate to wherever that HS2 folder is.
So in my case, I moved the two folder into my home directory under Terry.
OK, so you'll want to go find that wherever you've unzipped it and copied it to, or if you left it
in the downloads folder, that's fine too.
And then from there.
So let's say that now you're in the H2 folder.
From here, you'll want to also go into the bin folder.
That's short for binary, and then you'll want to find the file that starts with the word H2 and ends
with J.R.R that J.R. stands for Java Archive.
It's really just a zip file that contains Java compiled code, so select that file.
Pay no attention to the numbers that I have here.
If you're watching this lesson sufficiently, some time after I've recorded it, there will likely be
a newer version of H2 at the time that you're watching this.
It might be 1.5 1.6.
It doesn't really matter.
OK.
So just make sure you select the file that starts with H two and ends with J.R.R.
Click Open.
All right, and then if you don't have anything the down here at class name, then as long as the H2,
blah blah blah, that jar file is selected.
You can click the list drivers button here, and that should populate this class name down here.
And now you can click OK.
All right, so now let's create a connection to the database.
So we're going to go up here to aliases and click on this plus button here, and then we're going to
set a name for this.
So I don't know we can call this anything we want.
It's just a name for our connection to this particular database with this particular driver.
So let's call it people test.
And now for the driver, I'm actually going to change this.
We want to choose H Embedded.
OK, so select that.
And then further, you are L..
I'm going to remove from the double forward slashes there, so I'm going to delete all of that.
So I start off with JTBC Colon, H2 colon, OK, and then the tilde symbol forward slash people test.
So that's the tilde symbol on the keyboard underneath the escape and then click on the test button and
then connect.
And connection successful.
Very good.
So click OK.
And then click Connect and connect again.
All right, so now we are actually connected to an H2 database.
Now I want to explain very briefly what is different between the way that we're connecting to H2 to
talk to this new people database versus the way that most database connections, especially in a professional
business setting, would be.
As I mentioned earlier, typically when something is connecting to a database, the database is first
an application typically that's installed on a server.
The server is on a network, and other computers on that network are making network connections to the
database server and then firing off SQL commands and things to get data back or to either insert data
into the database and or get it back out.
That's the standard way that most professional applications work with databases.
However, because we're using this very lightweight H2 database and this database supports connectivity
in a number of ways, the way that we're currently using it is not as a server per se.
In other words, it's not an application that we've installed on the computer and we've told to start
running and then it's sitting there waiting for network connections to it.
Instead, we're using it in its embedded form.
And so first off, we're connecting to H2 not via a network, but really as a programming extension
of the Squirrel database client in this case.
So Squirrel is really just calling code or methods that exist within the H2 jar file that we were pointing
to the driver and we told the H2 Jar file methods to open up a connection to a file.
Now that file did not already exist on the computer.
And so H2 saw that and created the file for us.
And so any data that we push into H2 while we're connected in this way is going to actually just be
written out to an actual file on the computer.
This is a very lightweight way of just basically playing with the database.
You would not want to use a database in this very lightweight, non server based approach with a file.
If you were writing an application that needed to support simultaneous multiple users connecting to
it.