OK, so if we go up to file new project.
We've done this a few times already.
Make sure you have Java selected, make sure you have a project SDK, which you almost certainly will
buy now and then you can click next.
And don't you don't need to select anything there and then click next again.
Now for this next project, I think we're going to make one project that's all geared towards one little
application, if you will.
And this application will just be a really, really simple calculator app.
I mean, the reason we're going to do something simple with the calculator app is because that'll be
simple to test.
So we're going to ease you into unit testing.
OK, so for that matter, let's call this project calculator and then you can click finish.
And if you have other windows open, it's up to you if you want to leave them open.
I personally will be leaving mine open because I may want to come back to some of these other windows
in the future while I'm in the middle of talking about something.
But it's up to you.
You can always get back to them by just opening the projects anyway.
So I'm going to say new window.
And then let me resize that new window.
So that you can see it.
There we go.
All right.
And I'll move that over a little bit as well.
OK, now we need to do something that we've never done before.
As I mentioned in the intro, we're going to be learning how to write automated tests with the framework
called J Unit J Unit that stands for Java unit and really it stands for Java Unit Test.
That's a type of testing that we will be focusing on unit testing.
So we need to pull in this third party library for for the J Unit framework.
Now there are a few ways to do this and we will learn in the future probably the most common way to
do this in Java development it within a company.
But for right now, baby steps.
And so we're going to do a kind of a middle of the road approach to this.
So we need to pull in this library.
Thankfully, intelligence makes it pretty easy to do this without having to become a complete expert
in a bunch of other frameworks as well.
So the first thing we will do is to right click on the project name calculator here.
And then we can go down to open module settings.
And this is an area where we can further configure our project.
Up until now, we've just been using all of the default settings and everything.
Now just know that the way my window here looks might be a little bit weird and a bit different from
how yours looks because I keep my screen blown up large so that you can read everything somewhat easier.
All right.
So what we want to do is add a new library to this project.
So we've got over here on the left.
All of these project settings.
And there's one here called libraries.
So if you click on that, you'll see that there's not really anything here because we haven't added
any libraries yet.
So what we can do is click on this plus button here to add a new library.
And we want to add a new library from MAVEN.
Now I'm going to explain very quickly and briefly what what this is.
So there is a very popular tool within the Java world called MAVEN, and this tool does a number of
things.
One of which is it standardizes how we can organize our Java projects, like what folders we put everything
into and it can also build our projects.
So we've been building our projects via intelligent right.
We tell Intelligent to build our projects for us, and then it does so.
But typically in the professional Java world, where people may be using a number of different ideas
like some people on a team might be using intelligence, others might be using eclipse.
Some may be using nothing at all, although I hope not.
But there probably are people like that as well.
And so it's problematic to assume that everyone is using the same ID and then to further assume that
everyone can build the project in the exact same way.
If everyone's using different IDs, especially so these third party tools such as may then give us an
external sizable way, if you will, to standardize how we build our projects such that it won't matter
what ID we're using anymore.
Now, one of the other things, and this is kind of the biggest point here.
One of the other things that MAVEN has done is they popularized the centralization of third party libraries
that can be used with Java projects.
So as I've already explained, we're about to use a third party library called J Unit for unit testing.
While the MAVEN project has what are called repositories all around the world, where they've gathered
up thousands of third party libraries and centralized them on these repositories.
And that makes it so easy to just say, Oh, I want to use whatever library.
Chances are that library is already in the maven repositories, so we only need to search the maven
repositories for a given library and then we can get that library very easily.
And now there are tools such as Intel, AJ and the clips and other ideas that know about those repositories
and know how to search them and pull down libraries that we want to use very, very easily.
And so what this option here is asking us is where do you want to get your library from?
And we have the option of getting it as a Java library, which generally just means we're going to supply
it ourselves.
Like we've already downloaded it from somewhere and it's a file or something on our hard drive and and
we're just going to point to it or something like that.
And then the second option, though, is the one that we care about right now, which is to say we want
to get the library from the standard maven repositories.
So that's the one you're going to select.
All right.
And so then we get this additional dialog box that opens up, and it's asking us to type in the name
of a library that we want.
So now libraries that are in the MAVEN repository have what are called coordinates, if you will, and
these coordinates or the address, if you will, are how we can specify what library we're looking for.
Now I already happen to know the maven coordinates for the day unit library that I want to use.
And so I'm going to just go ahead and paste that in here now.
Like so I will supply these coordinates for you to be able to copy and paste in the lecture for this
lesson as well.
Or you can just type it in as you see it right now.
OK.
And then once you've got that pasted in, you can click on this little hourglass button to search for
it.
And after a little while, hopefully you should get this dropdown list.
Now let me show you just briefly how these coordinates are comprised.
There can be up to three parts to these coordinates, and those three parts will be separated by a colon.
OK?
The first part refers usually to the organization that is responsible for creating that library.
OK.
The second component to the coordinate will be the designation for the actual library itself.
So, in other words, some organizations may be responsible for making lots of different libraries that
you may want to use.
And so you'd see the first part would be the same for that organization.
But then within that org, they might make lots of different tools or libraries or something that you
may want to use.
And then the third component, which I did not supply in what I pasted, but the third component would
be the version of the library that you want to use.
So since I did not specify that in this dropdown list, I am being presented with every version that
is available at this time.
All right.
Couple of other things to note are we're seeing some some version numbers, like five point eight point
zero five point seven three five point seven one, et cetera, et cetera.
And some of these have a few words after them as well, like snapshot and one snapshot rc one in general.
Unless you know that you want something for a particular reason, you'll likely one to shy away from
using anything that is labeled snapshot.
That usually implies that there may be some unfinished aspect to that version, or it is currently under
development.
The team behind it is making it freely available for you to utilize, but it is probably still actively
under development right now, and so maybe not totally stable.
So I would generally shy away from that.
I would also shy away from one.
And also, I would shy away from RC one.
Oftentimes that means that's a version that's really, really close to being totally releasable.
It might even be identical, possibly to the final release for that version in this case five seven
zero.
But they're not 100 percent done testing everything out yet.
So, so yes, so you'll probably want to shy away from RC one as well or RC anything?
OK.
So when looking for a version to use, you will probably want to usually go for the highest version
number that looks stable, and that means the highest version number that doesn't have an RC or a snapshot
or IM1 or anything like that.
So as of the time of this recording, which is in June, the highest version that I'm seeing here for
J Unit Jupiter is five point seven point two.
That's the highest stable version that I see here.
And so that's the one that I'm going to go for now.
If at the time when you're watching this, there's some better version or higher version like five point
eight point zero and there is no snapshot behind it is just five eight zero or five nine zero or five
eight point three or whatever.
Don't feel that you have to stick with the five point seven point two that I'm about to choose now.
In all likelihood, we're going to be doing such simple things with G-Unit unit overall that you should
be fine.
Now, the one caveat to that would be that as of this time of the recording, we are on G-Unit unit
version five.
If you're seeing J Unit version six or seven or something like that while you're watching this, you
might want to be a little more careful there because that means that's a major release and there very
well might be backward breaking changes that somehow might not be compatible with some of the things.
I'm going to show you that I think that's fairly unlikely, but it could be.
So, you know, you kind of go at your own risk there.
You could try out the version six or version seven.
And then if you tried things that don't work the way that I'm showing you in the video, then you'll
know, OK, maybe I should back off to something in the version five.
But within version five, if you do version five point seven five point eight five point nine, you're
likely to be just fine there.
All right, so I'm going to click on five, seven two and then I'm going to click OK.
Now, what that just did is that just pulled down from the internet, this library called Janet Jupiter
five seven two, and it's telling me it's going to be added to the calculator module as intelligent
calls it, and I'm going to click OK.
And now I can see the actual files that just got pulled down from the internet.
Now these files are actually initially going to be stored in your home directory.
This isn't something you really need to care about too much, but I'm just making aware you'll see that
these files are being referenced as being in my home directory in a directory called into.
Not a big deal.
All right.
And then I'm going to click OK.
So now these files just got pulled down and I should be able to click over here on this external libraries.
And there's that library right there.
OK, so that's another way that I can see this now in in the future, I will be teaching you actually
how to use maven and a competitor to MAVEN called Gradle to do similar things here.
But that's when we will allow MAVEN and Gradle to sort of manage the building of our projects for us.
Although intelligence can still remotely control maven and Gradle such that you won't really see any
real difference from what we're doing now other than just those tools will be responsible for managing
the libraries, which are called dependencies, by the way, in general.
So just giving you a little sneak preview of some of the things that we'll be getting into, but again,
we kind of want to take baby steps.
OK, now we'll need to do a couple of other things as well.
So I'm going to close that external libraries there.
Now, up until now, we've mostly just been putting our source code files directly in the source folder.
We're going to need a couple of folders, though, in order to properly handle unit testing and to get
more acquainted with some of the typical Java programming standards that you might see at any company
where Java development is done.
So we're actually going to go back up on this calculator project here and right click again, and we're
going to go back into the open module settings and I apologize.
You can't really see my open module settings anymore.
It has kind of fallen off the visible portion of the screen, but just look for open module settings.
Just as you did before, and you'll want to be on modules now on the left here and down here, where
it says SIRC for source.
If you click on that, then you can right click on it and we want to add a couple of new folders.
So click on New Folder and the first one we're going to create will be called Main Imay in all lowercase
and click OK.
And then we're going to do this again.
Right click on SIRC again and click New Folder again.
And this one will be called Test and then click OK.
So now you should have in here the source folder, which was already there and then under it main and
test.
All right.
So now we need to designate the purpose of these folders within intelligence.
So in other words, we're going to tell intelligence where it should by default find our test files
versus where it should find our main code.
All right.
So if you click on main, then you can click up here to this, this icon labeled sources.
Just click on at one time.
And by doing so, we have now told inteligente that this main folder is one of the folders where our
main source code can be found.
And then if you click on Test down here and then come up here and click on tests with the green icon
there one time, just click on that.
Now we're telling Intel that our source code for our tests that we will be writing, which are also
written in Java, will be living in this folder.
OK, so our main program code that would actually execute and everything would be in main.
But our test code will live in this test folder.
And I'll just say briefly, the reason for this designation here is because typically when you build
your project into a final form, you do not want the tests to be packaged up with the rest of your working
code.
Those are only there for us to just test our code while we're writing it.
But when we package things up and like, let's say, if we were going to build a program and sell it
to the world, the thing that we would sell like, you know, if you're on windows, you're probably
used to running something called ICSI an executable, right?
That's the final form of the program or something now in Java, that's not called ICSI, but there is
something like that in Java.
You would not want to package up your test.
In that final thing that you're delivering or giving to people to run your program with your tests,
stay with you.
And so we need to keep these things separate so that when we package up the final project or the final
executable or whatever it's going to be, the tests don't get packaged with it.
And so that's one of the one of the main reasons why we have this separation here.
All right.
And once you're done with all of that, you can click, OK.
So now, if you come up here and click on this little greater than symbol next to the source folder
to expand that out, now you'll have a main and a test folder.
OK?