Let's talk a little bit about Java.
What is Java?
Well, Java is a programming language that was originally created by a company that no longer exists.
Sun Microsystems and it was released in 1995.
The chief architect behind Java was James Gosling.
I sometimes like to jokingly refer to Mr. Gosling as Java God.
The language was originally targeted to be embedded in consumer electronics devices like VCRs and eventually
DVDs, where it has made some appearances.
But another key area that Sun Microsystems really heavily pushed and marketed, Java was as an early
competitor, if you can believe this to the product that eventually became Adobe Flash.
Do you remember Flash, the technology that Apple eventually killed?
It gave us animations and simple video games and things of that sort.
Running in the browser, you had to install a flash player or plug in in order to run any of these things.
Well, back in the mid to late 90s, Sun Microsystems took their Java programming language and tried
to bring it to the web via a plug in for your browser as well.
These were called Java applets.
Unfortunately, applets never caught on the way that Flash did.
And as a result, lots of people don't even realize that Java ever was able to do that.
The funny thing, though, is that it was Java's third incarnation where it really started to make its
mark, and that was as a server side application platform.
Now, I know you may not even know much of what that means, but essentially, if you think of lots
of very popular websites that you probably visit, like Amazon or eBay sites like that, many of those
sites, especially in the early days and to a large extent even today, are heavily powered by Java
applications.
A lot of the data processing that has to take place when you make orders or click on a video to watch
on Netflix.
A lot of that is being handled by Java code running on servers in the background.
And for those of you who are old enough, if you may remember going into banks or various types of businesses
where you sit down with a worker there and they'd have a green screen terminal and they'd enter things
and look up records and things like that.
A lot of that type of computer work has moved away from mainframe computers that those terminals were
connected to and into web applications that now run in a web browser but are powered by Java in many
cases.
So Java really has taken over huge parts of the application development world, particularly for business,
and so much so that, according to two of the most well-known indexes that track popularity of programming
languages the Tobie Index and the People Index.
Java has consistently been among the top three most popular programming languages for years and years.
Both of these indexes use various techniques and strategies to determine this popularity.
One relies more on Google trends.
That is to say what programming languages are people searching for the most?
This tends to give an indication of popularity or rising trends in popularity, and the other does a
lot with surveys of companies to determine what they're actually doing today.
Now, Java is what's known as an object oriented programming language, and much of this course is really
going to help define what that means.
But in a nutshell, it means that the language is strongly geared towards a particular programming paradigm
in which we are encouraged to try to think of the problem that we're trying to write code for in terms
of objects that encapsulate data and behavior.
Perhaps a small example of that would be if we were writing a program that could track companies.
For some reason, we'd almost certainly be modeling or creating objects that represent the concept of
a company.
And examples of some of the data that would pertain to a company would be the number of employees the
company name, what sector the company operates in, and perhaps some of the behaviors of a company
that we might model into our objects could be the ability for the company objects to calculate various
performance metrics or financial data or implement various H.R. activities, things of that sort.
So a lot of what we'll be learning in this course will pertain to various techniques and capabilities
within Java to allow us to model concepts effectively.
Overall.
It's a really cool language, and I think you're going to really enjoy learning what you can do with
it.