All right.
Welcome back.
So when we left off in the last lesson, we had introduced the new skill annotation and we replaced
the getter methods for saving and for updating to use our new skill annotation, right?
And so then we were about to tackle the fine by ID and the find all methods.
When I realized that those two operations find my ID and find all are both sharing one method in the
people repository class.
In fact, let's jump back over there and I will show you OK.
So both the Find All and the find by ID method are just using this method right here.
They're both using this same method.
So the current approach that I was thinking of where we would just throw in at school as a one to one
like for a method that supports a given operation like or update, you would just throw a sequel annotation
on there.
But in this particular case, we've got one method that is actually servicing the Find All and the find
by ID.
And so how do we get around that?
And what I'm sort of thinking about here is that currently, in order for our SQL annotation to even
work from the perspective of the crud repository, we're having to hard code the name of the method
that that SQL annotation is on, right?
So in other words, when our KRudd repository wants to know what's the sequel for saving, we're telling
it go find a method called map for save.
Right?
That's how it's doing that.
But I just realized maybe a different way that we could do this would be maybe to not search for the
SQL annotation by the method name, but instead, maybe we can search for the annotation by crud operation.
So maybe we can introduce another attribute on the at school annotation that lets us specify what the
operation is like saving, updating, finding all, et cetera, et cetera, right?
And then you can put that annotation anywhere, in fact, actually, to be honest with you.
You could even put that annotation right up up top on the class itself in that case.
And as long as the annotation can be found, according to the operation that you're trying to do, everything's
good, right?
All right.
So here's what I got in mind.
That's sort of one more technique in the mix here.
So what I'm thinking is let's jump into the SQL annotation here, and let's add one more attribute.
And this attribute will have a type that is that is going to be, I think, from an enum.
OK, so we're going to introduce we're going to make use of an enum here.
Also, OK, so the enum will be called crud operation.
OK, that'll be the type.
And then the attribute will just be called operation type.
Like so.
All right.
And so obviously, we've got red marks here because I'm referring to a data type that the ID doesn't
know anything about yet.
And so I'm going to do an option return here and now the idea is offering to create this, and I'm going
to tell it.
Yes, created as an enum.
All right.
Now where do I want this to go?
I think I'm going to just put it in the model class for now, I guess.
OK.
So here's the enum.
And so you may not remember how to use these names, but basically we can just declare a bunch of constants
on the enum itself, and that's all we really need or we're not going to do anything fancy.
OK?
So the constants that I have in mind would be save.
Update.
Fined by I.D. Notice, I'm using all caps and underscores because these are because these do really
represent constants, OK, fine by I.D. and find all.
And delete, and if I think to some more, we'll throw some more on there later, but that's I think
that covers all of the operations that we've actually implemented thus far.
All right.
So let's jump back over here.
Cool, so that's happy now.
All right.
And then let's jump.
Over here, and so now my usages of the SQL annotation are in error because we've got attributes that
need to be specified, OK?
All right.
So now let's specify the that operation type.
OK, and I should be able to do a control space.
There we go, and I get presented with the options.
OK, so this one is for savings so I can just select save like so and looks like that's happy now.
Notice when I did that, the I.D. went ahead and has now specified the explicit attribute name for my
value attribute as well.
OK.
So you need that if you're going to specify additional attributes.
All right.
And then we'll do that down here as well.
So operation type equals and this is for updating.
So sorry, this is running off the screen, but there it is.
OK.
Create operation that update.
So first, let's just get these two operations working now with this new approach, OK?
So I'm going to come up here to go back into the credit repository, and now I want to make a few changes.
I think we're going to jump into this get sequel by annotation method here.
And so now, instead of passing in a method name, we'll just pass in that operation.
OK.
So crud operation.
And I will call it operation type.
OK, so now let's look at this code.
So we're on the repository class.
All right.
So we're going to find all the methods of this class.
And then currently we're we're filtering those down to the methods that have a particular name and we
don't want to do it that way anymore.
Right.
So instead of finding the methods with a particular name, now we want to find the methods with a particular
annotation.
So I think let's delete that line there and actually, let's see if we can do a different filtering.
Here's our method.
OK, so I think there's a method on the method class that lets us test for whether or not a particular
annotation exists and I see it right here, is annotation present?
That's perfect.
That's I think that's exactly what we want.
So is annotation present and then we can pass in school class like so OK.
So now we're filtering methods according to whether or not they have the skill annotation on them.
Perfect.
And so then if we find those, then we want to convert the stream of methods to a stream of the SQL
annotations.
And that's what we're doing here.
But now we need to go one step further.
So now we don't just want to automatically take that annotation.
Now we need to filter those annotations.
So we're going to filter again, so this is an annotation, and now we're going to say if the annotations
operation type equals whatever this operation type is that we passed in right here, operation type.
OK.
So if the annotation that we're currently inspecting in the stream has the matching operation type,
then get its value and then return that otherwise execute this skill, get everything you hear.
Oh, and by the way, in the last lesson, I forgot to explain why using the or else get with this method
reference was better than just calling the getter method directly.
OK.
So the reason this is better is quick.
Let's see here where we're using this is because here's one place where we're actually using this OK?
So what's going to happen here is this method here, which shouldn't be needed under normal circumstances,
is never even going to get evaluated unless it's actually needed.
OK.
But on the other hand, if this was not a method reference, that method would actually get called whether
or not we needed its value.
So by using a method reference, we're able to do what's called lazy loading essentially where you don't
actually do the processing required to make that call unless you actually need to.
OK, so we're just passing around a reference to the method versus calling the method.
OK.
So that's why that is a value now.
OK, so now let's go ahead and clean this up.
All right.
So instead of that string there, this is to update, right?
So we can pass in the crud operation.
Dot update.
There we go.
Looks nice.
And let's see, do we have we have another error right here?
OK, and then this one is the save, right?
So crud, Operation Save.
All right.
Let's run the tests.
Look at that.
They all still work.
Awesome.
OK, so now let's try tackling this slightly harder thing, which I don't think is going to be that
hard though now.
So fine by it.
OK, so now we will just call our get what was it?
Get sequel by annotation and the Pride operation is a find by IED.
And then the fallback method will be this colon colon get fined by IED sequel.
There we go.
All right.
Let's go ahead and just knocked these all out now.
I'm pretty satisfied that this is all good.
All right, so here's this one get find all sequel.
So I'm going to select all of that and let's see here.
So we're going to do a get sequel by annotation and then passing a crud operation.
And this is find all there it is.
Find all.
And then our fallback will be this Colin Colon Find all sequel.
There we go.
All right.
And then, oh yeah, we've got a few more calls to, oh yeah, we've got the count.
Oh yeah, we've got a count.
OK, well, let's jump in to let's jump into here and add in.
Count and did I say one other thing?
Count.
And delete are we've got delete one and then delete many?
Yeah.
OK.
So.
Let's jump in here and and specify those, so this maybe should be delete one.
And then we can have a delete many.
OK, let's see how that works out.
I think it's going to be fine.
OK, so the count here.
Get.
Get schooled by annotation, quote, Operation Count this Colin Common count.
Very good.
And delete.
Get sequel by annotation.
Crud operation, and we're doing delete one, delete one comma.
This Colin Colin, the sequel that one right there.
OK.
And then this one here.
There it is.
OK, get sequel by annotation, crud operation and this is delete many karma.
This delete in I might want to standardize on a better naming here, but for right now, this should
suffice.
OK, so there's that.
And so I think I have modified everybody now.
So now let me find all the abstract guys, and I think I can just make them all not abstract anymore.
So I'll just do a multi cursor here so I can do an option shift and put a cursor there and there and
there, and then select all that and just delete all of that and then come over to the end.
Now I'm someone I have to get out of multi-step cursor mode and then go back into it here and here and
here again.
I'm holding down an option and shift or alt and shift, I believe, for Windows and Linux.
All right.
And then I will just do.
Return empty string semicolon and then get out of that mode.
All right, so now that, I think, is there's one more debt find by sequel yet, let's get rid of that
one also.
Return empty string.
All right.
Yeah, so let's see.
Let's move, let's move this one up because I kind of lost track of it just now.
Yeah, and let's make it protected just to be consistent, and let's move this one down.
Away from these other getters.
There we go.
OK, that looks pretty good.
All right.
And now let's jump back over to the people repository class.
And now let's just finish throwing the sequel in.
So let's see.
This is fine by IED.
OK, so for that, I can go right here.
All right.
And so we can create another sequel annotation here and paste in our sequel.
Like so and then we're going to have to specify the operation type.
And so this will be for find by idea, right?
So.
There's our find by ID.
And one of the thing I'll show you this we don't even really have to be copying and pasting the sequel.
So let me just show you the alternative way that we could be doing this.
Another SQL statement here and now, this time, instead of pasting in the sequel, though from up above,
I will actually just reference the constant.
So this will be the Find All sequel.
See, so we could actually just do that also and then the operation type.
And so this is the find all OK.
So I would say it's largely a matter of personal preference or team preference.
If you're working on a team as to which of these approaches, one may prefer to a certain degree.
I actually kind of prefer being able to see the actual sequel as close to the code that that sequel
is being used with as possible.
Although one nice thing that intelligent will do as you're seeing here is if you hover over that constant,
it will show you the value of that constant.
So actually, in that case, that's not bad at all, right?
But as you can see now, we do have an issue.
If I hover over, you can see that there are the little red squiggles underneath these two sequel statements.
And if I hover on one, we get the message here.
Duplicate annotation, right?
So currently, our at SQL annotation cannot be used multiple times on a method.
OK.
But we can fix this.
So to do so, we'll need to jump in to the annotation for sequel.
And what we'll have to do is add another annotation on here and additional annotation to say that this
annotation sequel can be repeated or it is repeatable.
OK, now that won't be the only thing we have to do, but that's one of them.
OK, so we'll put this at repeatable annotation here and now we have to provide a reference to a container
annotation for our SQL annotation.
So the basic idea is this If you're going here, let's let's jump back over here.
So the basic idea is this if you want to be able to use the same annotation multiple times on a method,
then those annotations need to be wrapped inside of a parent annotation, a container annotation.
Now the nice thing is that we don't actually have to wrap them ourselves.
Java will do that for us, but we still have to define a container annotation because when we use the
reflection API to find methods that have whatever annotations we're interested in, the existing APIs
won't let us say find all methods that have multiple at SQL annotations on them.
It's not going to do that.
So instead, we'd have to say find all methods that have the container annotation that we're going to
create in the future here.
And then once we find that, then we can dig into that and then get all the SQL annotations in this
particular methods case.
Now, for these other methods that only have one SQL annotation, that code is going to work the same
as it already was.
OK.
So we're going to have to define one more annotation, which will serve as an as a container.
So let's jump back over here.
So what we'll do is we'll go ahead and specify that annotation, even though it does not yet exist and
we can call it just about anything.
I don't know.
Maybe we'll call it multi sequel.
OK, so let's try that.
Now, normally the ADP would give us the option to create this for us.
But in this particular case, it's not directly giving us the option to create an annotation, though.
I think what we could probably do is just tell it we want it to create an interface and then we can
change it ourselves.
So let's try that.
So we'll just throw an at symbol right there and get rid of that clean up the imports and then let's
specify that the retention.
And will set the retention policy to run time.
All right, and then we need to specify the fact that this annotation can contain our at SQL annotation
and the way we do that is actually to just define a value method that returns an array of our SQL annotation
so we can do a sequel array and then value method like so and look at that, the errors went away.
So I think we've got a winner here, so we'll jump back over to our SQL annotation yet.
And this looks happy now.
And now let's jump over here, and the red squiggly went away over here as well.
So that's looking pretty, OK?
All right.
Now we need to actually use this right because this is going to be a little bit different.
OK.
So let's jump back over to our credit repository now and see what we can do here.
So we need to go down here to our get SQL by annotation method.
So currently we're finding all the methods on our class.
And then we're filtering for just the methods that have a sequel annotation on them.
And then we're getting that annotation and then we are filtering for the SQL annotations that specify
the operation type that we are interested in, right?
Then we get that value and then we return that value, right?
So that's what we're currently doing.
But now, in addition to doing this, we also need to be able to search for SQL annotations that are
embedded inside of our new multi SQL annotation.
So what I'd like to do is to somehow do both of those searches and then combine all the sequel annotations
that are found from either approach and then finish this stream off the way that we're doing now.
OK.
So I'd like to be able to combine these two things, and I think we can do that.
So what I think we'll do is I'm going to make a new line here and I'm going to go ahead and write the
code to try to find the SQL annotations that are embedded inside of our new multi sequel.
And by the way, just keep in mind, let me let me jump back over here real quick.
Just keep in mind now that although we didn't explicitly wrap these two SQL annotations inside of a
multi SQL annotation, Java will do that for us by virtue of the fact that we have made these repeatable
and that we have multiple ones on this method, OK?
So when we use the Reflection API to find these on this particular method, they won't show up directly
on this method.
Instead, this method will appear to only have one annotation on it, which will be our multi SQL annotation.
And then we'll have to grab that multi skill annotation and then dig into it to get these out.
So in other words, it would look something kind of like this multi sequel.
It would look kind of like this from the perspective of the reflection API.
OK.
That's what it's going to kind of look like when we're programmatically looking for these guys, OK?
So in addition to our existing code that says go find all methods that have SQL annotation on the method.
Like this one here?
We also have to have code that says go find all methods that has the multi SQL annotation on it.
And then if and when we find that, then we have to access that guy's value to get at this array of
sequel annotations here.
And then from that point, it'll be the same processing as what we're doing up here.
OK.
So that's what that's going to look like, but we don't explicitly need to wrap this code inside of
the multi SQL annotation.
Java will do that for us.
All right.
So let me put that back.
And jump back over to the credit repo.
All right, so I think the way we will do this then, is inside of this gets by annotation, we're going
to create another stream for that other scenario, right?
And it'll pretty much look just like this.
In fact, let's see here.
Maybe I will start off this.
Well, I'll start off with at least this much.
All right, so I'm going to paste that, and so we're saying go through all the methods, filter through
the methods that have now here we'll do multi sequel.
OK, so find all the methods that have a multi sequel annotation on them.
And if you find any, let's map the stream of methods to a stream of multi sequels.
Well, annotations, OK.
And then if there is a multi SQL annotation, we will want to convert from a stream of multi SQL annotation
to a stream of sequel annotations.
OK.
So another map?
So let's say that this is a multi sequel, I will call it that way.
And so we're going to want to do a multi SQL annotation dot value.
Now, let us consider that calling multi-skilled that value is going to return a stream of arrays of
SQL annotations.
OK, a stream of in fact, let me see if I can get it to just if I can coax it into showing us that.
Let's see here.
I'll just.
Yeah, there we go.
OK.
This is just away right here.
So I could get the idea to show us what the output of this Line 126 would be.
So it's a stream of SQL arrays, SQL annotation arrays.
That's not what we want.
We actually want a stream of sequel like we have here.
So again, can you think of how to coax the Streams API into giving us a stream of sequel annotations
and not this array?
Can you think of how to do that?
Did you get it?
OK, so it's it's a two part thing here.
So what we'll have to do is we will have to use arrays again.
This is a very indispensable class arrays that stream.
OK.
But that's not enough, because now look at what we get out of this if you do arrays that stream.
So the arrays that stream method takes an array of objects in this case, an array of SQL annotations,
and it converts to a stream of sequel annotations.
OK?
But the map method takes whatever its output is and puts it inside of a stream also.
And so now we end up with a stream of a stream of sequels, right?
We've learned about this before, right?
This double stream thing.
OK.
So do you remember what to do about that?
Did you get it?
OK.
So all we need to do is not use the map function, but use the flat map function.
So flat map is useful any time you've got a stream of streams and you want to flatten that down back
into just one stream.
OK.
So we use flat map and now we have a stream of sequel just like we've got right here.
OK?
And so now I'm going to delete this little placeholder that I put in here just to coax the ID into showing
us what was coming out of each of these steps.
All right.
So now what we can actually do is I'm going to put a semicolon here and I'm going to capture this stream
into a variable like so and so I will call this stream multi sequel stream.
OK.
Like that, and then I'm going to do a similar thing down here on this stream.
I'm going to capture this stream down to this point right here and I'm going to capture a variable out
of that.
And yeah, I guess I will just call this one single stream.
There we go.
So now we've got these two streams, and let me put a little space in here, so it's a little easier
to see some of what's going on.
OK, so we've got our multi cycle stream and then we've got our sequel stream here, OK?
And now what we can do is we can reference the stream class itself, and the stream class actually has
a method on it called concordat.
And it takes two strings as inputs, and it just concatenate the two streams together.
So this is kind of perfect.
So, Kat, and so then we can just reference both of our streams Multi-Stream Comma Sequel Stream Like
so and now the rest of this processing can take place on both streams.
OK, so basically, we're saying go find all of the sequel streams via this multi cycle approach and
then also go find all of the SQL streams with the original approach that we had.
And now we've got these two streams and then concatenate those two streams together because they both
are going to contain SQL annotations, right?
And now go process all of the rest of that.
And so now we may get exactly what we're looking for.
So, yeah, I don't remember that I had actually explicitly shown that we could assign a stream to a
variable, right?
But you can.
And the fact that we can concatenate streams as well.
We might've learned it.
I can't remember.
But.
All right.
So I think we might be ready to jump back over to the tests.
So let's jump into the people repository and let's see.
There are no errors here.
And I think now we should not need any of these methods.
Let's say fine by ID, find by all.
I think we implemented all the rest of this already.
So I'm going to go ahead and just go out on a little bit of a leap here and just comment all of those
out.
Let's see.
Yeah, there are no errors.
OK.
So let's jump over to the tests, and let's just try running it all.
See what happens?
All right, we got a few a few failures here.
Let's see two failures to be precise, count and delete.
So let's see here.
OK, so something went wrong on the delete up or on the delete test.
So let's see what this test was doing.
We were creating a person, then we were saving the person.
Then we get the count of people.
Then we delete that person and then we get the count again, ending count.
And then we assert that the end count should be should be equal to the start count minus one.
OK, so this depends on count working.
And I can see here that the test forget count fails.
So let's let's focus on that one first.
All right.
So for this one, our error says the method is only allowed for a query.
OK, so here in the stack, trace, the first line, remember, stack traces kind of go depending on
how you think of them.
Stack traces are sort of like backward.
So we want to start at the top and then start working our way down the stack trace, usually until you
see the first line of code that you can do something about, right?
So like, there's nothing I can really do about the code in H2, and there's likely nothing wrong with
that code, right?
But this first line here that I can do something about is code that I wrote in the crud repository account
method.
So I might want to start by taking a look there.
All right.
Let's see here.
So to execute the count method, we create a prepared statement.
So we call SQL, get SQL by annotation code operation that count.
And our fallback is the get count cycle.
Now I have a feeling that maybe I forgot to implement this in the people repository.
And so the code fell back on this call here, which is now just an empty string, which reminds me we
may want to.
Let me jump into that real quick.
Instead of returning empty strings, it's probably going to be better to actually throw an exception
here because we don't really expect this to ever happen anyway.
And if it does, this isn't what we really want.
What we really should want is to just throw an exception in here.
Now someone actually decides to override any of these methods, then that would be fine, right?
But if they don't override these methods, probably the better thing to do here would be not to return
a string, but instead to just throw an exception.
And in fact, just for grins.
Let's go ahead and just do that real quick and see.
And then actually, before I even try to fix anything, I want to run these tests again, and I'll bet
we will get the exceptions instead.
OK?
So maybe four right now will do I'll do all of these simultaneously with the multi cursor.
So option shift.
So I'm going to put a cursor here.
And here and here and then instead of returning something, I'm going to say, throw new runtime exception
and I'm going to embed a message in here to say something like sequel, not defined and semicolon.
All right, so then escape to get out of the multi person business there.
And now let's run this again, and I'll bet we're going to get that runtime exception.
All right.
Coming down here to the get count.
Yeah, there it is.
There it is.
Sequel not defined so that's actually a better message anyway, because now I know exactly what the
problem is, right?
So I just didn't define the sequel for the get count properly.
So let's jump over to let me close that down.
Let's jump back over to the people repository, and let's see now where should that sequel annotation
forgetting the count actually live?
Ideally.
Ah, so now I see why I failed to make a sequel annotation for the get count.
There is no map or method for that, and that's fine.
So really, truly, these sequel annotations can can be put anywhere, you know.
So for now, I will just put it on this method here.
Now, there is a little bit of potentially a design flaw in that.
I was really intending to have these annotations live on the methods that use them.
But in this case, there is no method here that is using the sequel to get the count.
Yet we do have to specify it.
So for right now, I'm just going to slap it right here on this method.
Another good place to put it, though, might have been running the class.
OK, so we'll just we'll just throw throw that right here at sequel.
And let's see.
We will reference the Count Select Count sequel.
And with an operation type of count.
There we go.
All right.
And let me open back up the tests and let's run the tests again.
Hey, look at that.
Now just the delete is failing, and for the same reason, I'm sure let's confirm it.
Yeah.
Sequel not defined.
There's no sequel defined for deleting.
OK, so let's just add that in as well at sequel.
The lead.
All right.
So the sequel now, I thought we had written separate tests for testing both the regular delete and
then the Delete Multi or whatever, but maybe we didn't so that that might be a a short sighted on my
part.
We'll check that in a minute.
All right.
Operation type.
So this will be delete one, right?
All right.
Let's run the tests.
There we go.
So now everything's working, and maybe I will go ahead and replace these explicit strings here with
just the reference to the constants.
So this is find by I.D..
All right.
So I can just select all of that and then reference find by ID sequel.
Let's run the tests.
Looks good.
All right.
And this one is update.
So.
Update sequel run the tests.
Looking good, and this one's already using it.
OK, yep, so the lead in skills, so apparently I don't have an explicit test for testing that, I
guess I'm a little surprised by that.
All right.
So we've got everything back up and running now.
And let's just jump back over to the credit repository.
Just kind of want to take another look at it?
Oh, and I got an oddball message right here.
Let me move that down to its brethren.
I guess it can just go right here.
Yeah.
So this one should be like the others.
Copy that.
And technically, this these runtime exceptions would be a little nicer if they would specify in their
error messages.
What the attempted operation was.
So that way you'd be able to pin it down even more easily than having to look at the stack trace.
I may choose to leave that as an exercise for you, though, or we may in a later lesson, go ahead
and do a better job with these exceptions, anyway.
Yeah, and we've got a couple more down here also and here, boy got a lot of them.
All right, so now one last thing, let's jump back over to our people repository, and let's just get
rid of what we aren't using anymore.
Rita forgot to do that a little bit earlier.
Right.
So all of that can go bye bye.
Who I love.
I can't tell you how much I love being able to delete code.
It's very satisfying.
And for me, being able to refactor and delete code, especially the code that I have to look at a lot,
that's what helps me to feel like I'm really on the right path and I'm doing a good job with my code.
Now, some of you may be thinking, well, really all you did was you just took all that code that was
here and you just moved it into the crud repository.
And in fact, the credit repository in some ways is even bigger than this class was.
However, where you'll really start to see the value now is when we go create another repository, which
is what this has all been leading towards.
And in fact, in preparing this module on databases and working on this people repository, I had debated
whether or not to create another repository by mostly just copying and pasting.
And I hate hate, hate copy paste coding.
Sometimes you need to do it.
Sometimes it's just a practical thing to do.
But in a case like this, there would have been quite a lot of duplicated code, and I cannot abide
that.
And so now when we get ready to create another repository, it should hopefully be a joy and a pleasure
to do.
And we shouldn't need to do very much because our credit repository from which we will extend should
do most of the heavy lifting for us.
And hopefully all we will mostly need to do is just supply the sequel statements, for the most part,
implement a few methods and supply the SQL statements.
And so with that, let's go ahead and close out this lesson, and I will see you in the next one.