All right, so in this lesson, we're going to learn about another set of numeric classes.
This will be an easy one and shouldn't be long at all.
So Java has another set of numeric classes that are cousins of the primitive data types.
Basic numerical data types in Java, such as Int and Long and Float, Double, etc. And those data types
are called primitives because they are not based on classes.
OK, they're not classes or objects.
They are just low level numbers that work very efficiently at the microprocessor level.
OK.
So when you want to do math with any of those primitive data types, you're going to get the fastest
possible processing power and calculating power that you can on your computer because they are passed
natively, if you will, down to the processor, essentially.
However, as we've already learned for the floating point types float and double, you can lose some
accuracy or some precision when using those data types.
So what you what you lack in precision you make up for in speed, maybe, or vice versa?
Sometimes, though, when programming in an object oriented way, you may need to have methods that
are capable of passing nothing but objects back and forth.
And if you want to deal with the primitive number types such as float and double in particular, sometimes
you will encounter issues where you're wanting to have the signature of a method that is, you know,
the definition of the method itself capable of taking as input or as as output instances of objects.
But when dealing with with primitives, primitives are not instances of objects.
So now you have a bit of a mismatch.
So what I'm going to introduce you to in this lecture is the concept of what are called wrapper classes.
These are classes that wrap the primitive numeric types so that we can get around some of these issues.
So first off, let me show you what I mean in code.
So let's say that we have a method.
That for right now, I'll just declare that this method is going to be void.
And let's call it store data, OK?
And what this method is supposed to do, I will I will comment here as a Java doc.
OK?
A documentation for our Java class.
Let me let me.
Let's make a little room here.
All right.
Take thin.
Any type of data and stores it.
Somewhere generically.
OK.
So I'm not saying this is a great idea for a method, but let's just say we wanted a generic method
that could take in any type of data and just store it somehow.
OK, so that data could be strings or numbers or whatever.
Well, if we wanted to make a method this generic, what would the input type be?
Because I just said, like, we want it to be able to take strings or numbers or whatever, right?
We don't even want to have to think about what the data type would be, just whatever it is, we're
going to figure out a way to store it somehow.
So the first thing you'd have to do is decide, well, what is the data type going to be for the input
of this method?
If you will recall, in Java, all classes of Java eventually extend from one primary super class called
object.
And one of the beautiful things about object oriented programming is that you can always refer to a
class by that classes super class.
OK.
So for example, if we go back to one of our previous lessons where we had created a person and a pet
and a cat and a dog, if you recall in our modeling of the cat and dog, we said that cat extends pet,
meaning that a cat is a type of pet.
And we also said that dog extends pet because we have this hierarchical relationship.
We were able to say that a person can have a pet.
And the data type for that was just pet.
We didn't have to say a person can have a dog and then another member variable saying a person can have
a cat.
We don't have to do that.
We can store either a cat or a dog in this generic data type called pet.
Because both cat and dog extend pet, they are both a type of pet.
In other words?
OK.
All right.
So here's my point.
If we want to be able to have a method that can accept any data type at all, we could define this method
as simply accepting something of type object because object is the parent type for all classes throughout
Java.
There is no such thing as a class that does not eventually inherit either directly or indirectly from
the object class.
And so we can use this generic class type always.
Now, this is not usually a real great idea to do.
You usually want to be a bit more specific about what kinds of data you can accept so that you can have
more meaning.
But in this particular case, where the whole point of the method is to be able to accept literally
anything at all, this may be the best that you can do, however.
Now let's look at a potential issue with this.
And so here we might, you know, do something with the object.
So now let's say that we Oh, let's make this static so that we can keep this a little simpler.
OK, so now let's say that we have an integer called number one equals seven.
And let's say that we want to be able to pass no one into this method store data.
So let's see what that would look like store data.
Number one.
Now this is kind of interesting.
I don't know if you're noticing this, but on first blush, this really shouldn't be happy.
Notice I'm not getting any errors here, but I maybe should be, because ENT is not a class.
It is a primitive data type and object is a class.
You, generally speaking, cannot pass a primitive data type into a method that is expecting a class.
However, I'm not getting any errors here.
Why not?
This is where we get into a trick that the creators of Java added to later versions of Java.
When Java first came out, this would not have worked.
We would have gotten an error.
But I think as of Java version five, if I recall correctly, the creators of Java did some some trickery
with the language to allow this to happen.
And what they did was they introduced another set of numeric data types, which are classes, and these
are commonly referred to as wrapper classes or numeric wrapper classes.
And so basically, for many of the most common numerical primitive types, such as Int Float Long Double,
there are classes that represent the same concepts.
And so in this case, what's happening is, even though it appears that we are trying to pass a primitive
integer into a method that accepts an object, Java is actually converting our primitive integer into
a wrapper class of type integer.
And what that kind of really looks like is this.
There's a class called integer spelled out with a capital I, because it's a class, and let's call
this number one.
Be.
And then that gets initialized, and there are a number of ways to initialize this.
But for right now, what we'll do is we will call a static method on the integer class of value of.
And then we can pass in our primitive integer.
Now what This method value of returns is a wrapper class of integer.
So we have just converted a primitive integer into a wrapper of integer.
This is not entirely unlike how we can use big decimal.
Instead of using a float or a double, very similar float and double our primitives big decimal as a
class.
So here, instead of using the primitive integer, we can now convert to a wrapper class of integer,
and Java is actually doing this automatically for us.
In the case where we're trying to pass a primitive integer into a method that takes an object, java's
doing this for us.
And when Java does this type of wrapping for us, it is called boxing or auto boxing.
I'll spell that out.
Auto boxing, because it's putting our number in a box, if you will, or a rapper.
So auto boxing and now this integer of seven is being represented as an object, which can now be passed
in to a method that expects an object.
In addition to the class of integer, there are a number of other numeric wrapper types, such as double.
And we can initialize it in much the same way.
We can use the value of.
And then we can pass in a double.
Like so.
There's a float.
And again, we can use the value of method.
Here, though, I need to put an f behind this number because we call without the F Java assumes that
your number is a double.
Right.
So now I have an error, so I have to actually put that f there if I want to make sure that it interprets
that number as a float.
There is a bite.
Same deal.
I can use value of.
However, with this value of there are a few different versions, there's one that takes a bite.
And then there is one that takes a string.
The easiest thing to do in this particular case would be to actually supply it with a string, because
if we were to just type a number that will be interpreted as a double and not a bite.
So the quickest, easiest thing to do here would would be to simply wrap this as a string and then specify
it.
So again, that's quite similar to what we would do when initializing a big decimal or a big integer.
And incidentally, we can do the same for these other data types as well.
We can wrap them as strings and pass them in that way, too.
And so now each of these boxed numeric data types can be passed into any method that is expecting an
object rather than a primitive.
And so this allows us to get around that issue of how to pass numbers that would otherwise have been
primitives into methods that are expecting objects.
Additionally, there are a number of useful methods on each of these classes, which are quite similar
to the methods that we've already seen in the math class and on the big decimal and big integer classes.
So I will not go through those exhaustively, but we'll just take a quick peek at some of those methods.
I'm not even going to really call them, though.
So let's see.
What do we have method wise on the boxed integer class so we can get a bite value?
And we saw a version of that on Big Decimal, I believe, or on big integer.
We can compare numbers we can convert to other types, which is sometimes quite useful so you can convert.
For example, this integer value to a double float or a float, or a long that's sometimes quite useful
or a short or a string, you can always convert any object to a string.
Let's see.
For my double, you'll have pretty much the same methods here as well.
You can convert it to a byte or a double a float, and you can ask if it's infinite or is it not a number?
That's what NAND means.
That means not a number.
So if the value stored inside of that object cannot be represented as a number, then this method,
if you called it, would return.
True?
OK.
There's one more really important topic that I want to show you and talk about when it comes to numbers
and converting them to different types as a professional programmer.
One thing that you are likely to find yourself having to do from time to time is taking input from users
via some type of user interface.
What I mean by a user interface, by the way, is a screen where users of your program actually interact
with the program.
So for example, if you wrote a program that asked users to enter information, it might be in a web
browser.
In that case, a form in a web browser would be your user interface.
If it's a desktop application, there would be a window with a form or something like that, and that
would be your user interface.
Or if it's a mobile app like a Java Android app and there's a form on the screen of the Android app
that would be your user interface.
So the user interface is literally the thing that the user interfaces with, right?
How do they work with your program?
So when you are asking users to enter information into your user interface, which is also called a
UI for short, typically all of the information that they enter, regardless of what that information
represents, it will come to you, the programmer, initially in the form of text, usually.
OK, so even if you asked the user to enter their age as a number, what you would initially receive
in your code will typically be a string and not a number.
So then if you wanted to proceed to do some math with that information or something like that, you'd
have to convert that text representation of a number into an actual number.
So I want to just make sure that you are aware of some of the ways that you can do this.
And having just learned about the wrapper classes, those classes are among the easiest ways to do such
conversions.
So let's see what that would look like a little bit.
OK.
So the easiest thing we could do.
Would be something like, let's say, if you did ask the user to enter their age and then you wanted
to store that in a variable of type and right, so I will make an integer and I will call it age.
Now let's pretend like that information was passed into our program as an input argument that would
be like with one of these here.
OK.
So the way that we could make sure that that number, it's converted from a string, which is what these
args are to a number one way you can do that is to simply use the integer wrapper class.
And all of these wrapper classes have a method on them called pass.
Well, they have variations of of a method called pass.
So the integer has a method called pass int and it takes as an input a string.
And so what you can do is, let's say that the user entered a string of thirty seven like so well,
all that happens here is that this string representation of thirty seven gets translated into an actual
integer.
And and then we get the the integer stored in the age here.
Let me show you a couple other things here.
Amount.
So let's say that was going to be a floating point number, a double, right?
So here we can call Double Dot Pass double.
And then you could have something like 345 and 12 cents.
Oh, and I'm sorry, and I forgot to make that an actual double.
Oops!
Here we go.
Float.
Float would be the same pass float, right, so there's a there's a pass method for float.
About bite, there's a past method for four bite.
There's even a past method for Boolean.
The way this one works, is it it it's looking for the word true or false?
In fact, here will live and we'll use it.
So.
Like so.
And then we could print that out.
Here you go, and you can set it to true.
OK.
So let me also show you a quick example of how this could actually be used.
So we'll just print, let's do a little bit of math.
Let's ask for the age of a person and then we will print out that age plus 15.
OK.
In fact, here let's be even a little cooler than that.
Let's let's use a print format and say you will be.
Percent, the age in 15 years.
New line.
OK, so see what we're doing here.
I'm going to take that age, add 15 to it.
I'm treating all of that as a variable that will be bound to this symbol here percent d.
So it will say you will be whatever age you will be age in 15 years.
Now appear instead of hard coding and age, we will want to instead retrieve a number that will be passed
in when the program is executing and it will be passed into this array of args.
So in a later chapter or module, we will learn more about arrays.
But basically, you can think of this as a list of strings.
And so whatever arguments we pass in to this program, they will be contained in this list of strings.
OK.
I know that's probably not meaning very much to you right now, but let me just show you what it will
look like.
So we will want to get.
I only planned to pass in one argument for now, and so it will be the very first argument in this array
of strings.
And the way that I can access that is by referring to this variable args and then using a square bracket
and then specifying a number of the index that I want to grab out of this array.
So I want the first argument which would be index zero.
OK.
So assuming that I pass in a no as an argument to this program, that number will be here in this args.
Zero.
However, it will be a string.
And in order to store this number in an integer, I need to convert it.
And so that's what we're doing here.
OK, so this will be args zero.
Now there are a few ways that this could be run, but maybe the easiest way right now would be to go
up here to the run menu and select run.
And then we're in the numbers, tough class, so this is ask me, what class do I want to run?
I want to run the numbers stuff.
Now, if you click directly on this word, no stuff, you won't get an opportunity to specify the arguments
that you may want to pass in.
So if you want to be able to specify the arguments, you have to click on this arrow here.
And then you have to skip down to edit.
OK.
So this will allow us to specify some more options in this case, the arguments that we want to pass
so you can click on Edit and right here there's an area called program arguments.
This is where we can pass in more arguments to the program.
So here I can type in a number, even though it's going to show up as a string.
Essentially, I'm I'm going to type in 30, OK?
And now I can simply click run.
And look what we get, you will be 45.
Age in 15 years.
OK, I guess I should have said you will be 45, maybe years of age in 15 years.
Now if I run this again, I won't have to re specify the argument because it's already configured,
so I can just click this run button here, or I could have clicked it up there as well.
Any of those would have worked.
All right, there we go.
You will be 45 years of age in 15 years.
So just to recap, I've passed in an argument that argument is a string, though.
And so I need to use the integer pass and in order to convert that string into a number.
And then once it's a number, I can do math on it, so I couldn't do that math directly on the string.
And that's the whole reason why I did this.
So just keep in mind that you are likely to encounter a number of situations where you will take some
kind of input, typically numbers.
But those numbers will be stored in strings and you will need to pass those strings into numbers.
And this is one of the most convenient ways to do that.
Now, this isn't the only way to do it, though.
There are.
There are a few other ways, but this is probably the most straightforward and the most common.
OK, so make sure you really remember this.
I'm telling you this tends to be needed.
Pretty fair amount.
All right.
So I think that's going to wrap this up.
Like I said, basically these these wrapper types are particularly useful when you need to pass a primitive
to method that is expecting objects or vice versa.
So with that, we'll close this lesson out and I'll see you in the next one.