All right.
I got another data type for you to learn about.
So the creators of Java have been super busy people over the last few years.
They're really trying to keep Java relevant in a world full of programming language competition, and
a lot of the languages that are competing with Java are doing it by being more lightweight, letting
you do more with fewer lines of code.
So I think that has really inspired Java's creators to rise to the occasion and try to keep things relevant.
So with that being said, the newest data type added to Java as of Java version 14 is called record.
And basically, it's a shorthand version of a class.
So let's create a quick class, and I will point out the things that the record type are helping us
with.
All right, so let's see here.
I'm just going to create any random class will quick.
I'll come in here to new Java class and I'm going to create a class and let's call it weirdo.
All right.
So we want to make a weirdo.
And as basically, this will be a person, right?
So I'm going to just say, like, you know, here's a private string last name and a private string
first name and a private local date, which is a date of birth.
OK.
So we've we've done this many times before, and I've mentioned that often, not always, but quite
often.
Most Java developers will, almost without thinking, just automatically generate a constructor and
getters and setters.
And so they'll they'll come in here and they'll say, Give me a constructor, and there's a good chance
they'll generate two constructors, at least one which takes no arguments at all.
So, you know, our default constructor and then they'll they might make another one that uses some
or all of the fields that they've added to the class.
OK, so something like that.
And then they'll generate the getters and setters.
And again, that'll usually be comprised of all of the fields that they've added to the class like this.
One other thing that they will often do, and I will be teaching this when we get to collections, but
I'll give you a sneak preview now.
They'll often also generate what are called equals and hash code methods.
My option for that is falling off the end of the screen, but trust me, it's there.
It's called equals in hash code, and so they'll often generate an implementation for these two methods.
And I'll just take the defaults here for now.
All right.
And they might even generated two string method, which we've done before.
I won't bother with that.
All right.
So what we have here is a lot of the standard things that a good number of classes written by professional
Java developers will often have a hash code method and equals method.
You'll learn why those are good things to have when we get to collections, getters and setters for
the fields.
At least one constructor, maybe a couple.
OK, very, very typical.
And like I said, developers will often generate all this stuff without even thinking about it.
So here's a problem.
If you're a programmer who's been using one of the competing, possibly newer, more streamlined languages
for a while, and then you come to Java, perhaps because you took a job at a company where Java is
the language used primarily, and you learn that this is what a majority of Java developers do just
automatically.
And you start looking through all of this and you're like, Why there's so much code here?
And this is all just boilerplate code, right?
Which means, you know, the code that can be generated.
So it's not considered to be code that's really adding much value to anything.
It's just like the the starting point.
So consider we haven't even added our own like actual true behaviors to model what a weirdo can do,
right?
This is just the starting point.
So a good number of developers, especially those who have experience with languages other than Java,
will look at this and just say, I don't want anything at all to do with Java if this is what I have
to do every time I, you know.
Now, granted, this didn't take any time for me to generate because, you know, the idea generated
it all for me.
But it is a lot to look at, right?
And you haven't even really done much yet.
And at this point, all this class can do is just create objects that are just.
Glorified data holders, so keep in mind, and this is a really key point.
The true value of object orientation is the combining of data with behavior together to give you to
allow you to model the real world or business concepts or whatever.
When we just use an object oriented language like Java to to just model data, which is all I'm doing
here so far, we're really missing out on a lot of the value.
Now, granted, sometimes there are programs that we need to right where there just aren't that many
opportunities to get into some really awesome modeling.
And all we really needed were just some glorified data holders.
And there you go, right?
So maybe this is fine for that.
So that's just something to keep in mind.
However, the architects of Java have over the years become increasingly aware that there is this negative
sentiment with regards to Java.
And so they've come up with a solution of sorts.
And basically, it's a new data type.
Now this data type is really just a facade on top of a class.
So let's recreate this weirdo class, but using the new data type of record.
So I'm going to delete this.
Then I'm going to come back over here again to the package, right click on it new Java class.
But this time I'm going to choose record and I will name it weirdo again.
OK.
Return.
All right.
So now notice what the differences are.
There's a couple.
First off, we have public, but not class.
Instead, it's public and then record.
And then instead of stating the name of the class and then curly braces, instead, we just start off
with the name of the class and then parentheses as if we were defining a constructor.
And in fact, basically that is what we're about to do here is to just define a constructor.
So the equivalent of what we just did with a class would look like.
This will have a string, last name, comma, string, first name, comma, local date dob.
And we're done.
This is equivalent to all of what you just saw on the previous class based version of the weirdo.
And what I mean to say here is that by just typing that little bit there, Java will essentially generate
for us the getters and setters and implementation of the hash code and equals methods and a basic body
of this constructor here.
Now let me prove that to you.
So I will come over here to the main class, and I'm going to instantiate an instance of our new weirdo.
So weirdo Larry equals new.
So you instantiate it just like you would any class.
And now I have this constructor where I can specify a last name, first name and a date of birth.
So I'll say David LeRae with a birth date of Oops.
Of.
Whatever, I don't know, nineteen, fifty one one.
There we go.
So that just created an instance of the record from from the perspective of this class man that is using
the weirdo class.
There is no real difference.
The biggest difference for us is that we didn't have to type a bunch of stuff now.
Let's see so I can access the fields now.
There are a couple of very minor differences here.
If I access any of the fields now, when we create fields on a class and use our ID e to generate getters
and setters for us, like, let's say we add a field called first name and then we generate getters
and setters for them.
The getter and setter methods will by default be named something like Get last name, set last name.
OK.
However, when we use records, actually, excuse me, I did slightly misspeak.
There won't be any setter methods.
I'll explain that in just a moment, but there are getter methods.
But the getter methods won't be prefixed with the word get.
Instead, they just match the actual name of the field.
So if I want to get the first name, I can say Larry Dot first name, but with parentheses on the end.
And that would retrieve that.
So I can I can.
I can print that out.
Like this, Larry, that first name, Larry, that last name, etc..
Now the reason that there won't be certain methods for a record is because records are final.
OK?
They are made final.
And not only the record is final.
Like the CLAT, the class essentially is final, which means it cannot be extended.
But also the fields within the record are final, which means that once they've been set by the constructor,
they can't be changed.
And since they can't be changed after creation of the object, there's no point in generating set or
methods for those fields.
Setter methods imply that you can change those fields after the object has already been created, and
you can't do that with records.
And the reason for that has to do with a concept called mutability.
Basically, more often than not, it's a great idea to keep as much of your data immutable as possible.
That means unchangeable, so you want to make it so that you can create it one time and then it can't
accidentally be changed, because that's one of the ways that lots of bugs pop pop up into code is,
you know, someone creates an object and then some other code changes data within that object.
And now you've got bugs because the data that they changed it to isn't valid in some way.
That's one of the reasons why immutability is often a sought after property of code, and so records
just build that right in.
If you need to change something about the Larry object of type weirdo.
You just create another weirdo, perhaps one that's based off of a preexisting weirdo, but it will
be a new weirdo.
So, for example, if you wanted to make a better weirdo, we'll make one right now.
Weirdo Better weirdo equals new weirdo.
And you could do something like Larry Dot, our dot last.
Last name, plus Z.Z, Karma.
You see where I'm going with this.
You know, if I wanted to make changes to this Larry object, I can't technically do that.
But what I can do is just to create another weirdo object based off of the Larry object in some way.
If I wanted to do that, or I could just, you know, make a whole new object, whatever.
And so that's how immutability works.
Sometimes it can be a pain, but it often protects us from ourselves.
All right.
So there's a few rules about records.
Records cannot extend any class.
OK.
They're final.
However, they can implement an interface.
Let me show you what that would look like.
Let me delete that will jump back over here into the weirdo.
I started to say weirdo class.
Weirdo record.
Right?
So if I want this guy to implement an interface, it's it's pretty much the same as with a class just
at the end of this constructor looking thing.
Here, I can still use implements and then I can make it implement one of my interfaces, such as the
Apple interface.
I chose that one because then I won't be forced to actually implement any any methods here because there
are no methods to find on the Apple interface.
But yeah, you can do that.
And let's see if you want to create alternative constructors, you can do that as well.
And that looks pretty much the same as with Class Constructor.
So, you know, you can set it.
Presumably, it'll be public problem.
Probably weirdo.
And then you can put other inputs in there.
So let's say that I want another constructor where I don't have to specify the date of birth, right?
So I can do something like this.
And so then what I can do is just delegate essentially up to the original constructor for the class,
which is this this guy here?
I can call that from this new constructor and it will look exactly like this.
This and then I can pass in these values.
Last name, first name now.
Though this new constructor that I'm defining does not require does not take a date of birth, if I
want to delegate up to the original constructor, I will still need to pass something.
OK, so I could pass a null.
Or some?
Date of birth.
That represents, you know, that we don't really know what their date of birth is or that it's unspecified
or something of that sort.
OK.
One one one, for example.
I don't know if that's.
I don't know what would happen with that, actually.
I guess that would be the year one.
So something along those lines, but that's how you can create your own constructors.
And then if you can create your own constructors, you also can create your own methods.
Still, so you can create a method of extreme say hello return.
Hello, world.
There we go.
And then if I jump back over to the main class, I can use my new constructor.
I'll create another weirdo.
Jake equals new weirdo.
And so what snake, Jake?
There we go.
And then I can call Jake.
Say hello.
All right.
So, yeah, these are pretty nice, pretty convenient kind of shorthand versions of classes so that
you can dispense with most of the boilerplate that we normally put into classes.
But like I said, they can't extend any other classes.
So if you become a professional Java developer and especially a business developer, what you may encounter
is that a lot of Java business development involves creating lots of shallow classes that model very
simple concepts like a person or something.
And it's rare that anyone on teams where this type of Java development takes place is trying to architect
really well thought out class hierarchies.
You know where this extends from that and implements this and all of these things, all this fanciness
that may not be super common in a lot of Java shops.
And so using a record to do really basic data carrying like go, just go out to the database, go grab
a bunch of information, plop it into some data holder, which in this case would just be this simple
Java class or record and then send it on its way to be utilized in some other way.
Maybe it will be presented to a screen or to a web page or something like that.
So that's probably one of the real intended use cases for records.
So anyway, let me finish just telling you a few of the other properties of records.
You can't declare any other instance, fields or instance variables on the record other than those fields
that you are defining in the constructor itself.
Now notice I said instance variables.
You can define static fields on on on a record and note also that since record classes themselves are
final and therefore they cannot be extended.
Then also, they cannot be abstract because the only thing you can really do with an abstract class
is to extend it.
So no abstraction for records, they can be nested inside of other classes.
So I could have defined weirdo or any other class as a basically a nested class somewhere else.
Let me let's see here.
Let me show you what that might have looked like.
Let's say we decide to add another employee type.
Well, except that we can't really, because that would imply that it would extend from employee and
records can't extend.
But let me show you anyway what it would look like to create and a record as a nested class, essentially
so we can just create just as we did before instead of public class.
It will be a public record.
And let's call it, I don't know, jumper.
And because I don't feel like thinking I'll use, you know, first name.
Last name.
There you go.
So there's our new jumper record.
All right, so I think that's going to pretty much complete what I wanted to cover on records.
They're basically just streamlined versions of classes with a few restrictions added on them, such
as the fact that they can't extend anything and they themselves can't be extended either, but they
can implement interfaces.
And now that we know that interfaces can have default methods.
You know, you got some you got some options there, for sure.
There's something in my soul that makes me want to caution you about running out and just like making
all models records by default.
But you know what I mean?
You're young, you're new to Java.
Have that it?
If you get a job working somewhere and you start trying to do this, keep in mind, this only works
in some of the most recent versions of Java.
I think it was a preview, in fact, in Java version 14 14, if I'm not mistaken.
So it hasn't been out all that long.
So there may not be a lot of teams in the US as of 2021 who even know about records for all I know.
But yeah, have fun.
Go knock yourselves out.
All right, I'll see you in the next one.