All right, so in this lesson, I want to wrap up the final loose end and that final Lucentis is something
that I had actually sort of promised to get back to a while back.
So if you will recall in the collections module, I was going through a lot of the methods on the various
collections interfaces, and there were some methods that I was skipping over.
And the reason I was skipping over those is because I knew that we weren't quite ready to learn how
to use those yet.
But now that you've learned about the Stream's API and lambda expressions and method references as well,
we are now ready to go back and revisit some of those methods that we skipped over before.
OK.
And so that's all we're going to do now is just take a look at a few of the methods on the collections,
classes or interfaces that pertain to doing streams and lambda expression type things.
And we've already been playing with a few of them anyway.
For example, let's see, do we have I don't remember if I still have any here, but at one point we
did something where we captured the map and then we did some things on the map.
And so in fact, here we can do just do that again right now.
Let me make some room here.
So for example, we were capturing, we're capturing this map result, right?
And it's a map of string string to long at at the moment.
That's what it is.
And so if I just refer to the result map and hit a period here, now we can start looking at all the
methods that exist on this class, right?
And one of them that I know we used before was the for each.
Right?
Yeah.
In fact, I remember we we stuck a dot for each ride at the end of the dot collect method.
That's I think that's what we did.
So, yeah, we could do a for each here.
So let me just go ahead and hit that real quick.
So what does this guy take as input?
It takes a by consumer, right?
So we now know that a by consumer is going to be a functional interface that is expecting two inputs
and returns.
Nothing.
Right?
And so, for example, if we wanted to print out the key value pairs for each entry in our map, we
could use this function now.
Now, one thing that isn't obvious here, the fact that this is taking a by consumer is cool, but you
don't necessarily know just from looking at this that the two inputs that this buy consumer are expecting
are the key and the value, right?
How do I know that?
Well, the way that you could learn that would be by just looking at the Java Dock for the for each
method itself.
So if I just go to the Java Dock here, I can see that I'd have to read it a little bit, but it performs
the given action for each entry in this map.
So right here, entry, I know that entries are key value pairs of a map, right?
So it performs the given action for each entry in this map until all entries have been processed or
the action throws an exception.
And if I skip around a little more down here now, one nice thing about a lot of these functional methods
are about a lot of these functional methods on the collections classes is that they will often give
you this implementation requirements type thing here, which shows you kind of in a more procedural
format, what the expectation would be or how how you can think of using or kind of how you can think
of using whatever it is that it's expecting here, like this by consumer.
So down here, it says the default implementation is equivalent to this is equivalent to for this map.
So for.
So what they're showing here is a for loop that is looping over the set of entries in this map.
So again, a map can be thought of as a list of key value pairs and a key value pair is also called
an entry.
And so a set of entries of the map is just that list or set, I'm using less than the English fence,
not in the programming sense.
It's just a list of key value pairs or entries.
And so we're setting up a for loop using the enhanced for loop, we're setting up a for loop that will
loop over those entries.
And here's your entry there, right?
And then it is going to call the by consumer that you are going to supply to it.
So that could be a lambda expression or a method reference as long as it refers to a method that can
take two inputs.
And so now we can see what are the two inputs that it's going to pass us.
It's showing us right here, it's going to pass in the key from the entry and the value from the entry.
OK.
So all of this stuff here.
That's kind of like internal code of the for each method itself.
OK.
But that lets us see what how it is going to use what we are supplying it.
Essentially, that's kind of how you can think of it at least, right?
So that's how I know that this takes a key and a value.
All right.
So we've done that many times.
I'm not going to I'm not going to do that again.
Let's see what else we've got here.
Let's see.
Oh, replace all.
All right.
That's what.
Replace all.
So this one also now this one takes a buy function, meaning it's going to be a function that takes
two inputs and returns an output.
Right?
So again, I can click on the method here and do an F1 to bring up the Java dock to get a little better
sense of exactly what is this thing trying to do or what is its intent.
Right.
And so I can come down here to the implementation requirements and see.
So what is this guy doing?
So again, it's iterating over the set of entries and it's going to intricate set value, so I can see
now that it really does mean to replace something, right?
Because it's going to replace the value of each entry.
Let's see.
And it's going to call the apply method of our supplied function, whatever.
Let me take a quick side note here to make sure I explain what the function data pie is.
So the word function here is referring to our lambda expression.
OK.
Or a method reference?
And you know that we are looking at using the in this case to replace all method, but it could be any
of these functional methods.
OK.
And the replace all method is taking as an input.
A bi function by function is an interface.
As all of these functional interfaces are, it's it's an interface.
So when we supply a lambda expression or a method reference, what's really happening is that Java is
going to take our lambda and plug it into an object that it's going to create for us.
And that object will look like whatever the functional interface is that we're that is being expected.
So for replace all, it's going to create an object that looks like a bi function object.
OK.
And then it's going to take our our lambda expression and plug that in as a method of that by function
object.
And then in order to actually call our supplied lambda expression, it will be mapped to the apply method.
And generally speaking, all of these functional interfaces have an apply method, OK?
And so that's why we're seeing here function that apply.
So basically, you can just take it to mean when it says function that applied, it means call the lambda
expression or method reference that we are supplying.
I hope that helps clear up a few things we're supplying to it.
What was it?
A bi function that we're going to supply?
It's going to pass in as input for our function, the key and the value.
So, OK, so it's going to give us the key and a value, and then it's going to take whatever we return
from our lambda expression and replace the value of the current entry with whatever we're supplying
it.
So let me think real quick off hand, why might you want that?
So in this particular case, let's say that since we have currently a mapping of states to what we're
doing here counts, I think, yeah, we're counting, right?
We're counting the number of people in each state.
Currently, I'm looking up here to see that right here, the dot collect grouping by state and then
counting, right?
So we're counting the number of people by state, right?
So maybe now I don't have a real great reason why we would want to do what I'm about to say.
But let's say we wanted to double all of the counts for each state, right?
Maybe that's something we'd want to do.
OK.
So in that case, we could do that by supplying a bi function.
That would be a lambda that would take two inputs.
And I know that those inputs are going to be the key in the value.
So I'm going to just call them Canva, which is a common convention.
And and then what I'm going to do is return maybe v times to write.
And so that would double all of the counts of the populations in this particular case.
Now I could get fans here with this notice.
I didn't use the K for my actual, you know, calculation I could have, right?
I could have said something like if K, which I know is going to be a state code rights of K Dot, I
don't know starts with, I don't know, Z.
I'm just making up something silly here.
If Kay starts with Z and I can use a ternary here to make it kind of concise.
If Kay starts with Z, then returned the value times to otherwise just return the original value that
was already there before, right?
So that's just a random example of something that I could yeah, of of a way that I could use the replaceable.
All right.
So there's that.
What else we got?
Let's see.
We've got merge.
I'm going to skip.
Merge will come back to it, though.
Yeah, I guess let's do compute.
All right.
So now let's take a look at the compute method.
So first off, we can take a quick look at what it takes for inputs, so it takes a key and then it
takes a bi function.
And so we now know that a bi function is a function that takes two inputs and returns one output.
Right?
But that doesn't really tell us how to use this thing.
So if I put my cursor on the compute method itself and do an f one to bring up the Java Dock for it,
I can now kind of take a look so it attempts to compute a mapping for the specified key that was that
first parameter that it takes compute, a mapping for the key and it's current mapped value or null.
If there is no current mapping, for example, to either create or append a string message to a value
mapping.
OK.
So we can jump down here to the implementation requirements.
And as you can kind of see here, it's a little more involved than on the.
The other method that we took a look at earlier was that the replace all.
So let's see what this guy is doing.
So it's getting the value for the given key that we have passed into it.
So again, keep in mind, we're going to pass the key into this thing as the first parameter.
OK.
You're going to pass in a key and then it's going to call your lambda expression.
Let's just assume we're using a lambda.
It's going to call your lambda expression and it's going to pass in the key and an old value so that
old values the value that it got for the key.
So let's say, for example, that we used it here where we're counting populations, and so we passed
into the compute method.
I don't know M for Missouri.
And so then this implementation is going to look up Missouri in the map and get the current value for
Missouri, which will presumably be some population.
Let's say it's whatever, I don't know, a million.
And so then your lambda expression is going to be passed M0 and 1000000, and then you can do whatever
you want with those two values.
You just need to return something back.
OK?
And it will need to be of type long, because that's what this particular map is dealing with in this
case, right?
So it needs to be another value that you're going to return.
So now here's the thing I can't really think of a great reason to use compute in this program.
So I've actually prepared another smaller program with a very specific scenario so that we have a good
reason or a better reason, at least to use compute.
So let me let's jump over into that and I will show you a good use case, a potentially good use case
for using compute.
All right.
So let me just delete that.
And then.
And then we'll jump over here to my state counter.
Now this isn't something you need to write.
I just wrote this just so we'd have a little a little scaffolding to play around with some things here.
All right, so let me lay out a quick scenario for us here.
And actually, this will be kind of real world.
As a professional programmer, I've run into the following scenario a few times in my career.
So basically, here's the scenario I'm going to iterate through the five million records of people,
and I just want to tally up each time I find a person from a particular state so that by the time I'm
done going through it all, I have the total counts of population per state.
OK?
It's just a more procedural way of getting counts by state.
Right.
Obviously, we know that we can do this quite efficiently using the Streams API, but let's say that
maybe we don't have all of this data all at once.
Maybe this is a program that's running over the course of a month.
And different people go online and fill out something, and every time they fill something out, one
of the things that they're filling out is what state they live in.
And so at that moment, when they submit their form, we're just tallying up.
Oh, here's one for Missouri.
Add another one.
Here's one for California.
Add one to the California stack or stash, right?
So maybe we're keeping track of all of this in a map.
OK.
So the problem is that by default, if you just use the very simple, straightforward methods of a map
which are basically put and get, you end up having to write some.
Really, I don't like writing this code at all.
And in fact, maybe I can show you what that code would look like real quick here.
So right here, I have a map, right?
Already called state count.
OK.
And so what I'd normally be end up doing is every time somebody from a particular state submits their
form, I might end up doing something like this state counts that get and then I'm going to pass in
whatever state they're from.
Right.
So let's say it's CIA.
Now, that would have been a variable, really, because I would have received that as an input somehow,
right?
But so just pretend like that's a variable that came through some form of metal or something like that
and not not a not a static and not a constant like I'm doing here.
But anyway, so we're going to need to get the current value for that particular person state, right?
And.
And we'll call that current population.
And then.
I might need to say something like if current population is null, because like, this is the first
time we're ever running this program and we've not encountered anyone from California before, then
that could be not right.
So if if it's null, then then maybe we want to do something like State Council that put
K again pretend like that's a variable one.
All right.
So consider that to be our first tally mark.
Right?
On the other hand, if it was not known, then we'll need to do something like state counts that put
see a comma current population plus one.
Or I suppose maybe I also could have done I maybe could also have done that right, incriminate.
Right.
Notice I'm using the prefixed interim increment here, though, because I want to make sure that that
happens at the time that I'm putting in, not after I'm putting right.
And for that reason, maybe you'd be better off just doing the plus one because it's more obvious and
explicit.
So here's the thing.
That's, you know, that's a bit of code that you have to write just to do that one stupid thing, right?
So this is like one of the classic scenarios, though, for using something like this compute method.
So now let's see how to do it with with compute.
And I don't know.
We'll I'll just I'll leave this here for reference.
All right.
So what we could do instead is now I'm going to cheat a little bit here and I'm going to still use the
Stream's API just to read in a bunch of data, OK?
And I'm even going to use the for each here.
All right.
Just to simulate my scenario here.
But inside of the four, each is where I will actually make use of the compute.
OK, so here's our state counts.
So what I'm going to do now is do this with compute.
And the way I can do that might be something like this.
Let's see here.
So we'll refer to the state counts dot compute.
And then it once a key.
So our key would be now here.
In this case, we've got this array.
So I need to refer to the element of the array that holds the state.
And I think that's thirty two.
All right.
So there's our key.
And then it takes a buy function.
And so this by function.
Let's go look one more time.
I'm going to do a pull up the Java docs, so if I come down here so our buy function is being referred
right here, it's going to pass in the key and the old value.
OK, so we will put in here key comma value like that and then we can do whatever we want with those
values.
So the key is going to be using our other example here, whatever was passed in here, which is the
state and then the old value would be this guy right here, the current population, as I called it,
right down here.
So what we could do is something like the.
If he is null and I'll do this as a ternary, if this is null.
Then return a one, otherwise return the plus one.
OK, now here's the gist.
What I'm doing just in this bit right here, just this little bit, it looks a little cryptic, but
what I'm doing here is equivalent to all of this.
That's the whole point here, right?
This compute method lets me more concisely say potentially slightly complex things.
I mean, it's not that complex, but let me say all of this kind of scenario much more straightforwardly,
and some of the astute ones of you might even be noticing that this feels a lot like the reduce function
of the MapReduce pattern.
It's very, very similar to that.
OK.
Because what it's really going to do is it's going to let us iterate well, not this part, this part
of here because of the fact that we're using this loop, right?
This, Fareed.
It's going to iterate over all of the entries, essentially.
Basically, that's what it's going to iterate over each record.
OK.
And for each record, we're going to pull the current state, which is going to be like us doing this
bit here.
And then we're going to get the value that's associated with that state in the map.
And if this is the first time we're encountering that particular state, then the value is going to
be null.
And so we're going to initialize it to one.
OK.
But the next time we encounter someone from that same state now we will equal one.
And now we're simply going to add one plus one, which will be to right.
We're going to increment whatever we had in there before.
And each time we encounter someone from that particular state, we're just going to keep incrementing
the count for that state.
And by the time we get to the end, we will have the full count of people from that state.
And let me prove that by running this real quick.
All right, so let's just yeah, let's just run this.
All right, and so we've got our output and I don't have all these numbers memorized, but I do recognize
this number right here.
Sixteen thousand two hundred eighty eight.
So I'm quite comfortable that we're on the right track here.
So that's that's what the compute method does.
Sorry that it takes a little while to kind of explain it because I wanted to give you a kind of a real
world example of how to use this.
Now you could do this.
You can use the compute method for doing more than just this type of like tallying up, you know, values
and summing up things, right?
You could use it.
Maybe if the values that we were tracking in some other use case, in some other example were words
or something, you might want to append something to the words or whatever.
I mean, you could go crazy with all of the scenarios that you might be able to think of, but I think
this is a fairly classic scenario to cover with with the use of the compute method here.
All right.
So that's compute.
And while we're here, we might as well just take a look at a few other variations of this because there
are other variations, but they're all going to let us do very similar things.
So let's get rid of that.
And let's see.
So we looked at compute and there's compute if absent.
So let's see what that guy does.
So he also takes a key and takes a function.
Now, the compute method was taking a bi function, which was passing in the key in the value.
This one is just taking a function, so let's see why that's a little different.
We'll jump in to the Java doc here.
All right.
So the Java doc says that if the specified key is not already associated with a value or is mapped to
null, this one attempts to compute its value using the given mapping function and enters it into the
map unless null.
I'm not going to read the whole thing there, but if we jump down to the implementation, we can see
here what it's kind of expecting.
So it's going to first try to get the value for the given key.
If that value is null, then and only then will it call our supplied function right and it's only going
to pass in one input.
And that's why it does not use a bi function.
It's just using a regular function.
The difference being that a bi function takes two inputs, whereas the regular function just takes one
input, which will be the key in this case.
And then it's expecting our function to take that key and do whatever it wants with it.
OK, now if our function returns a null value, then that won't be stored into the map, right?
So it'll only store whatever value we we we return from our function if that value that we return from
our function is not null.
So this would not work for what we just previously did, where we were kind of just tallying up things
because once you put one value into it, it's not going to give us another callback with that same key.
This will only call our supplied function if there wasn't already a value in the map associated with
that key.
OK.
So I don't know, like if we wanted to just initialize the map with something right, that might be
an example where we might want to use this.
So let's say here we could do again the a thirty two and then we're going to supply a function which
is going to be a key.
And I don't know, maybe we'll just initialize it with the length of the key.
I'm just saying something.
I'm just doing something kind of random here now.
I'm getting an error there because the value that comes back from this needs to be of type long because
those are what the values of this particular map are.
So I could satisfy that by doing an option.
Enter here and have the ID convert my convert, the integer that's coming out of the court length to
a long right by using long that value of OK, that's not a real useful thing to do, obviously, but
that's an example of how to use the compute if absent.
OK.
All right.
And then let's see, what else do we have here?
So we've got compute.
Let's see.
I think there's one more.
Yeah, there's compute if present.
So let's take a look at this guy.
So it also takes the key and it takes the bi function again.
So this one, if the value of the for the specified key is present and non null, it will attempt to
compute a new mapping.
Given the key and it's current map the value.
I'm not going to show an example of this because it'll look just like the compute one did.
The difference being the compute was calling our lambda, regardless of whether or not there was a value
already associated with the key compute of absent was only calling our lambda if there was not already
a value associated with the key.
And this one is the opposite of that.
It's only going to call our lambda if there was already a value associated with the key.
So again, doing the counting thing, probably not real great fit for this method because we would for
the counting that we did, we would need a method that will call our lambda, whether or not there's
a value already associated because presumably when you first start, you won't have any tally marks
at all.
I'm saying tally marks conceptually, right?
And so you'll want to initialize with some tally marks.
And then from there, you'll want to keep adding up as you encounter the same key over and over and
over again.
OK.
But that's what this compute, if present, would be for.
All right.
Moving on.
Let's see, let's do merge, which is actually for this use case of tallying up stuff.
Merge is actually my favorite.
This is even more concise, so we're going to use this again to do the tallying thing OK, so again,
it takes a key.
It also takes a long value and then it takes a buy function.
So it looks almost identical to the compute method, except that it has this extra second parameter
here of a long.
And if we go take a look at its Java dock, let's see.
So if the specified key is not already associated with a value or is associated with null, it associates
it with the given non null value.
Otherwise, it replaces the associated value with the results of the give and remapping function, or
removes if the result is null.
So that's pretty much identical to what Compute said.
This method may be of use when combining multiple map values for a key.
So going down here to the to the requirements here, so it's going to first look up a value for the
given key and stored in old value.
And then if all value is null, then it's going to return the value that you supplied, which was the
second parameter, OK?
It's going to return to the old, but it's going to return the value that you supplied as an input.
Otherwise, that's what this two columns here is, because this is a ternary operator.
Otherwise, if the old value was not null, then it's going to actually call our supplied lambda expression
passing in the old value and the new value, and then we can do with those what we want.
All right.
So let's see how to use this.
This will be kind of cool, I think.
All right, so we're going to pass them the key again, a thirty two, then we get to pass in a value.
Now I'm going to pass in a one here and you'll see why in just a moment.
All right.
And then we will have our function here by function.
That's going to take the old value in the new value.
So I don't know.
I'll call them X and Y.
And then I'm going to do here is this ad those two guys up?
Oh, and I just need to put an L here because that should be a long right so I can just put an L there
and there we go.
So this is also going to sum up everything.
And what it's going to do is essentially it's going to it's going to look up this key in the in the
map.
And if this key did not already exist in the map, then it's going to create a new entry in the map
with this key.
And it's going to populated with this value of one.
So that's like kind of just the initializing the first tally mark for that given key or if the key was
already in the map but its value was null, it's going to replace the null with this value here of the
one.
OK.
And that's what's going to happen the first time it encounters this particular key.
So it could be California, for example.
OK.
Like I have down here now, the second time it encounters someone from California, it's going to do
a look up and it's going to see, Oh, I already have a value there for California and it's one.
So then it's going to call my lambda expression where it's going to pass in the one that was previously
stored here.
And it's also going to pass in this value here for the X and Y.
OK.
I think this will be the old value which was associated here and then it'll be the new value, which
is this guy here.
So it's going to pass these two values in which would be one and one, and then I'm adding them up,
which is two.
And then that two is going to be placed inside of back inside of the entry for that given key of, let's
say, California.
And so the next time California is encountered again, we're going to go through the same steps again.
It's going to extract the current value that is set in the entry for California, which by now would
be too.
And so it's going to pass in to here and it's going to pass in the one here.
And then I'm going to get to do the addition here.
Two plus one is three and then it's going to put the three back in here and then you see how it's tallying
things up, but it's doing it by and by key, right?
And so the end result is going to be the same thing that we did with the original compute, except even
more concise.
Because if you recall with the previous version of this where I was doing the compute, I had to have
a little bit of a ternary operator there that said, like, if the value is null, then return to one,
otherwise return the new value plus one or something like that, right?
So now I don't even have to do that anymore because this has that logic built into it.
Right?
And again, I can't emphasize enough these this merge method doesn't have to just be used with numbers,
though again, this is probably one of the quintessential use cases for it, for sure.
And like I said before, I've had to do this kind of code so many times in my career, and I always
sort of hate it, even though it's not hard to do, but I kind of just don't like having to write it
all out.
And now, bam, you can do it so much more concisely, right?
So that's what these methods are for.
All right.
And so I think that's going to cover all of the methods of map that were kind of functional, right,
that were that were working with any of this kind of functional business, right?
And so now you know how to use these.
And now you also know I skipped over them when we were actually learning collections before.
And let's take a real, real quick look at the list and set interfaces as well, though we may not go
in quite as much detail, but let's just create a list here of some words.
Maybe.
It's important that interface there.
And let's see here.
So if we've got a list, let's just look at the.
Any of the functional methods for list.
So we've got to replace all that takes a unitary operator of type string because that's what we're passing
in here, right?
So the replace all method here, let's just do this.
So we'll take a look at its Java doc and we can look at the implementation for it.
All right.
So this replaces each element of the list with the result of applying the operator to that element.
So basically, if you wanted to replace the values of a list in some kind of way, you can use the replace
all method to do it.
And here's how you can expect that it would actually be working.
So it would iterate over the elements in the list.
And for each one, it would simply call your supplied gunnery operator passing in whatever the current
element was.
So in this particular case, it would get called twice, once for the cat, once for the dog, and then
you'd have an opportunity to do something with that.
So for example, if you wanted to uppercase everything in that list, right, you could do that really,
really easily.
Let's say you could just do something like a start to uppercase.
Right.
So you could do that.
And in fact, I think we could even do that more concisely, though, with a method reference, so we
could do string to upper case.
Right?
Yeah.
So we could do that, bam.
Now you just uppercase every single thing in there, right?
All right.
So that's an example of the replace all.
So taking a look at it, maybe a couple more, and I think that's all that's about left anyway.
There's a big move within a Ford each.
I think you should be really comfortable with the Ford each by now.
This for each is one that just takes a consumer.
So we just know that that's going to take one input and no outputs, right?
And then you can do whatever you want with it.
So typically we'd be using that to print to print things.
That's how we have been using it.
And then the removal is maybe an interesting one, so it takes a predicate.
So we now know that a predicate is a function that takes one input and returns a true or false.
So that true or false, presumably is going to be used to tell the remove this, whether or not it should
remove something.
So one way that we could use that in this case would be if we wanted to wanted to remove all entries
that start with the letter S., for example, right?
So let's see what that would look like.
So we'd get a word as an input, right?
And then we could say something like, Oh W, it starts with C, right?
So that would remove the word cad.
One thing to note, by the way, I did this list thought up, and then I'm showing these examples here.
In real life, this wouldn't quite work because list that of will return and UN modifiable list, which
means it can't be changed in all of these methods here would be trying to change it.
And so we'd actually get errors if we were to try this.
The way to make this work in real life would be to maybe do something like create a new array list and
wrap wrap this on modifiable list.
Inside of that, and I did show that technique in the in the collections module before.
So yeah, we'll import that.
And so now you could you could do this.
However, now it's complaining that it doesn't know that W is a string anymore.
So really, you kind of need to you'd need to actually assign it to a variable and go through all of
that.
I'm not going to do all of that here, but hopefully you get what I'm getting.
Hopefully, you understand what I'm saying here.
I'm just showing this bit here just for illustrative purposes, so we can wrap this up.
All right.
And then you're going to see very similar things for the set, right?
So I hope now you'll feel very much empowered and not intimidated by the various functional methods
that exist on the collections class.
And so I now have wrapped up the odds and ends that I wanted to.
And with that, I will close out this lesson.