All right, folks, I want to make one more custom annotation with you, and then I'm pretty sure we're
going to be done with this, OK, but I think we can do this pretty quickly.
So I'm back here in the credit repository and I wanted to show you something, OK?
We're going to implement an alternative to one of the techniques that we're currently using here.
Some on the delete method here and online.
90, you see here that we've got this entity that get IDs.
So let's see here.
What we were doing was we were creating our prepared statement to delete one item by its I.D..
And here's the item we're calling it entity of type T, right?
Because it's generic sized.
And then we're getting the ID from that entity so that we can bind it to one of the parameters of our
prepared statement.
OK, and then we execute the prepared statement here.
Well, do you recall that the reason why we were able to call this get ID method on this object, even
though we don't know its specific data type, right?
Because it's generic?
The reason we're able to get at that get ID is because at the very top here, when we generic sized
this crud repository, we constrained the generic Typekit a little bit to say that we don't know exactly
what it is, but we do know that it should be something that implements or extends.
But really, it's implementing the entity interface, right?
That's what we did.
And then we defined a Get ID and a Set ID method on the entity interface just so that we'd be able to
do what we're doing down here in the elite method, right?
So that means, though, that any of our entity classes must implement the entity interface.
OK.
We can do a little better than that, though.
So let's actually jump into the person class and I will show you what I mean here.
So I'm going to jump into person.
OK.
So here we've got our person class and it implements entity.
And the only reason we did this was just so that we could call the Get ID and maybe the set ID methods
from within our credit repository and ensure that they'd be there, OK?
But now that we know how to make custom annotations, there's actually an arguably better way to do
this.
So this entity annotation is really just the way of marking where we can get the ID from on this class.
But we could alternatively make a custom annotation to mark which property is our ID property.
OK.
So that's what we're going to do in this lesson.
All right.
So here's how we're going to do this.
So let's start off by just introducing a new custom annotation on this field of ID.
Now, this will be the first time that we're introducing an annotation to a field instead of a method.
But the process will be very similar.
OK, so right before the private word here, I'm going to just put an ad I.D. just like that, and then
we'll let the ID create this annotation for us by putting the cursor on the word ID.
And then I will do an option return and there's our option create annotation ID.
So I will select that and we will put this in the annotation package.
Like so and click, OK, all right, and then we'll need to set the retention policy.
To run time like so and then let's jump back over to the person class again.
All right.
And for whatever reason, the idea decided to reformat the code a little bit here, but that's fine.
So I will maybe just put a space here because if I wanted to put other annotations which we don't,
we're not going to be doing.
But if we were to do so, I would prefer to have a space between each grouping of field and annotation.
All right.
So now we've got that annotation there.
So now we can jump back over to our crud repository and add some code that will actually read this thing
and do something with it.
OK?
By the way, I've been jumping between classes so frequently, and because I'm in presentation mode,
I don't get the benefit of having the tabs show up here, which you may have in your ideas.
Hopefully you do, which is a nicer way to kind of jump between classes that you're frequently getting
in and out of.
But I don't have that.
So I'll just show you this another way that you can jump quickly between files that you frequently are
working in is on Mac Command E or on Windows and Linux Control E!
And then I get a nice little list here of all the most recent classes or files that I've been working
in.
So that's kind of nice for me because, like I said, I've been jumping around a lot lately.
All right, so I'm going to jump back over to the Creed repository class here.
And so what I want to do now is I want to replace the way that I'm getting this idea to make use of
that annotation.
So basically currently I'm just calling entity that get ID that works the way that you know it would.
But I'd rather have some code that would dig into this entity using Reflexion API and find a field that
is annotated with our new ID annotation.
And if it finds one, then this code should get the value that is on that field and return that value
here.
So that's what we're going to do.
We're going to write another annotation finding method that can do the equivalent of what this is doing,
but it will do it via annotation and therefore we will no longer require this class to implement that
interface.
OK.
All right.
So this method can be private because I don't think it will need to be used by any subclasses and definitely
not from classes that are outside of its hierarchy.
OK, so private, and I think it's going to return along, although I do have some comments about that
that I will mention later.
OK, so it will return along.
And I don't know.
Let's say it's find I thee by annotation.
And so it's going to take an input of type T and it's going to be an entity.
All right.
Because that's what we're dealing with up here.
All right, so the first thing I think we'll do is we will need to get our hands on the class into T
get class right now from here from this point, instead of asking for all of the methods on the class.
I think what we'll want to do instead is to ask for the fields.
So let's see what we've got here.
So we've got methods for accessing the declared fields.
I think we were accessing the declared methods before.
So here's one to get declared fields, which returns an array of fields.
All right.
And then just as before, now that we've got this array of fields, I want to use the Streams API to
iterate over the fields in that array and then do some lambda streamy stuff, right?
So, all right, so I'm going to do a dot arg so that I can surround this whole entire line with parentheses
and then do arrays dot stream.
Like so.
All right.
And so that just converted our array of fields into a stream of fields.
And then for each of those fields, let's do a filter so that we can find the field that is annotated
with an at ID annotation, right?
So for a field f, let's do something like f dot is annotation present, and then we can specify our
new ID annotation ID class.
OK.
So if there is a field that is annotated with this new ID annotation, that will find it right there.
OK, so now if that field is found, we will want to read its value.
So really, what that means is we'd be converting from the field to the fields value.
And anytime we're talking about converting from one thing to another in the streams API, we're talking
about doing a map, right?
All right.
So we'll be doing a mapping here.
And so we're going to have a field right now.
Let me show you real quick here.
There is a method on the field class to get a value because that's what we want to do.
In fact, let me jump back over here to the person class real quick and just show you so.
Here's the field in question, right?
It's annotated with ID, and presumably it's going to have a value set on this field.
So all we're trying to do with the Reflection API is to say, Hey, for this given field right here,
give me its value, but we're going to run into a problem and the problem that we're going to run into
if we just try to get the value directly without doing one little step first is that this field is private
and our external code, our code that is external to the person class won't be allowed to just willy
nilly.
Go read this value off of a private field without us doing a little bit of a sidestep first.
OK?
And so jumping back over.
OK, so if we were to try to do this f dot get OK and this would be the method that we would have tried
and then we could pass in our entity like so this won't work as is because we won't have permission
to read that field.
OK.
So what we would have to do is a couple of intermediate steps.
So what I'm thinking here is we're actually going to put this inside of a code block, right?
So step one, it's actually only it's only like one extra step.
The step one is that we will have to first call F Dot set accessible to true.
OK, so that's going to basically allow us to tell Java.
Yeah, I know that this field is marked as private, but let's override that so that we can actually
read this value out of here.
OK, so that's basically us saying, let's override the stated level of access on that field.
OK.
So that's one thing we have to do.
And so once we've done that now, we can access the field itself.
OK, now let me explain why I'm having a pass in this entity here.
This f is a field of the class.
OK, so remember, now we're in object oriented programming, we're dealing with classes and we're dealing
with objects, right?
And they're kind of two sides of the same coin.
So this field f is a field of the class.
Right?
But to read a value from that field, we're talking about the object, right?
And so we have to pass in the object that actually has the value.
The class doesn't have the value, it's the object that has the value, right?
And so that's why we're having a pass in the object, which is this entity variable here.
OK, now one other issue is if I hover over this red squiggly here, you see that our attempt to call
the get method can result in an illegal access exception, and we're going to have to do something about
that.
So what we can try to do here is simply wrap this call in a try catch block.
Now that's getting a little nasty looking, but that's about the best we can do, although we could
extract this whole thing out into its own method, we might take a look at that.
So anyway, though, here's our call to get this value and then we need to capture it.
Now, if we capture it like this and just call it IED, we could try to somehow return that IED out
of all of this.
However, a slightly better thing to do probably would be to declare this object outside of the try
catch.
So I'll just make it null and then set that value like so now notice here that this call to get is actually
returning something of just type object.
OK?
It doesn't know what the actual type is.
There are actually other versions of this get method.
Like we could explicitly say, get long.
OK.
We could do that.
And then this type could be long.
And that's perfectly fine, too.
As long as you know that that really is going to be a long in this case.
So then what would be coming out of this map function would be a stream of longs now?
OK.
And so then we can just return.
This I'd like so and so then what would be coming out of this map would be a map of lungs.
We also could have used the map to long method.
We could have done that as well.
And then that would have yielded a long stream, right?
So in this case, either way is fine since we're not needing to do any math or anything like that on
the lungs.
I don't know that I really need the map to long in this particular case, but that that might have been
fine too.
All right.
So now we're going to have a stream of lungs coming out of the map, and now we just need to decide
what to do with it.
So so I'm thinking we can just do a find first.
And as you'll recall now, the find first method is going to return an optional though, OK?
But I've declared here that this method will return an actual long.
So the question is what should happen if our entity was not annotated with an ID annotation?
What should happen here?
I'm thinking, if that's the case, we should probably just throw some type of runtime exception.
And the optional class has the ability for us to do exactly that.
So we can call.
I'm going to type the word through or I'm going to start to type it in.
And you see here that we've got a couple versions of an oral through method.
Now this first one will throw a no such element exception.
And, you know, I mean, it doesn't matter a whole lot for what we're doing right now, but maybe that.
But to my thinking, that might not be quite the best approach because I think I feel like that implies
that it's dealing with some type of a collection of things that it where it couldn't find something.
This other version, though, that takes a supplier as an input, allows us to control what exception
is being thrown, and I'm kind of leaning a little bit more towards that one.
So this takes a supplier, and the supplier is one of the functional interfaces that does not take an
input.
It just supplies things.
So it just outputs stuff, but it doesn't take any input.
OK.
So what we could do here is just supply a basic lambda that takes no input.
Like so and then does something like a new run time exception, and then we can supply a nice message
here, like no I.D. annotated field found something like that.
Now do recall, though, and I've mentioned this a couple of times in real life.
What we really should be doing is actually creating our own custom runtime exception in this case,
and we could make one called no ID found exception.
OK, something like that.
And then that's what we be returning here.
But in the interest of time, I don't really want to bother doing that right now.
OK, but that's what we really should be doing, so that if we needed to catch that exception for any
reason, we'd have a specific exception that we knew to look for by using just the generic runtime exception.
That makes it harder for us to test what exactly went wrong and what we want to do about it, because
everything is just looking generic, OK?
And so then I think we can just come back up here to the top and just say return and let me clean up
my formatting a little bit here.
OK?
So this code should try to find that ID and return it in effect.
So with that being said, now we can come up here and instead of doing entity that get I.D., we should
be able to now do find ID by annotation and then pass in the entity that way.
All right.
So now let's just rerun our test and see if this actually works.
All right, so I'm just opening up all of the tests, and I'm just going to run them all.
Oh, OK, not quite.
So let's click on the can delete and let's see what's going on here.
Attempt to get field person that ID with illegal data type conversion too long.
OK, so it says something here was an illegal attempt.
And let's see where are we?
Credit repository line one.
Oh, six.
OK, right here.
Ah, OK, so it just doesn't like the fact that I explicitly tried to call.
Get long here.
OK, so it doesn't like that.
So let's see what happens if we just change that back to just the plain old get method instead.
But then we just cast it to a along.
Let's see if that works.
Hey, there we go.
So that was pretty easy.
All right.
Awesome.
So now that we know that this basic approach works, I think we've got a few other places in here where
we're doing this like, I think right here.
T. Colin Cohen get I.D..
So this is one that will also need to replace and any place where we're calling get ID on the entity.
Now this one, the way we're doing it now is that we're streaming over the entities and then we're converting
the entities into their IDs by calling the entities own Get ID method.
And now we won't do it that way.
Instead, we pass in the entity and then call this method here.
So we're going to have to change this into a more traditional lambda expression.
OK, so the input type would be an entity.
So I'm going to just call that E.
And then I'm going to say that will map to a call to the Find ID by annotation where we will pass in
the E like that.
Now, unfortunately, we know now that we don't actually have an explicit test to test this out at this
time, but I'm pretty comfortable that that is going to work.
All right.
And here's another one where we're calling Get it.
And so this will be the same bill.
So I'm just going to replace that with find my I.D. and then pass in the entity like so and now I'm
just going to search for all other places.
I'm doing a command F. Get I.D. and looks like there are no more references to the Get ID method.
Call within this class, so we might be good there.
And so now let's go ahead and just run all the tests again and see, Hey, looks like everything's good.
So now one perhaps final thing we can do is to come up here and now we no longer need to constrain this
generic type as some form of entity.
I think we can actually get rid of that.
Let's see if we break any code when we do it.
Oh, we do.
OK, so OK.
So we do explicitly set an I.D. on one of these objects as well.
So we're going to need a setter method as well that uses the annotation approach to do so.
So let's go find our find by annotation method here, and let's create another version of this.
Maybe like a set ID by annotation.
OK.
All right.
So we'll make another method.
It'll be private, but this one will be void because we're not asking for any information now, right?
We're just setting information on the ID annotated field, right?
And so I will call this set ID by annotation and the input.
Now for this, I think, will just be of type long, right?
It will be the actual it'll be the actual value that we want to set on that field.
So I will call it ID.
And then this makes me realize now, since I'm calling the Set ID by annotation, it probably would
be better to call this method down here.
Get ID by annotation rather than find Okay.
So I'm going to put my cursor on there and do a shift of six and just rename that method from find to
get.
All right.
So now we've got our set ID by annotation, and then I think we're going to do some of the same basic
beginning steps I'm going to copy down to about here.
OK, from this get ID by annotation method as a starting point.
Copy that command, see or control C and then paste.
OK, now some differences here, though, OK, well, actually first off, I see now that we also need
the entity, so we need not just the value, but we also need the actual object that we're setting the
value on so we can pass that in as another object.
Now the data type for entity is generic, right?
So it's going to be type T, right?
So there we go.
OK.
So we're passing in the value and then the thing that we want to set that value on the object that we
want to set that value on.
OK.
All right.
So here we are finding the declared fields and then filtering through just the fields that are annotated
with I.D. And now here we were doing a mapping down here.
But up here, since we're not returning anything, so map doesn't quite make sense.
I think instead of four each would make more sense.
Does that make sense to you?
Mapping is when you're converting from one thing to another and then presumably that other thing that
you're going to get out of the mapping, you're going to keep doing something else with.
Right?
But in this case, we want to find this field and we're not going to convert the field to anything.
Once we find that field, we just want to do something with that field, right?
And so for each which is a terminating operation in the Streams API is, I think, more appropriate
here.
OK.
So we're going to do a for each.
I don't know why that just happened.
Hold on a second here.
All right.
So we'll do a for each instead.
And once we find this field, we do want to make it accessible.
And then once it's accessible, I think we can just call F Dot set.
There we go.
And the setter method here set takes the object that we want to set something on, which would be this
entity and then the value, which would be the ID, right?
So entity comma idea.
Let's see if it will be happy with that.
And now it's probably going to want us to handle an exception, though.
So we will wrap this call in a try catch as we did before.
There we go.
And if this does not work, I think what we can do here is actually just turn around and throw a new
runtime exception.
And then give a nice message here.
Unable to set I.D. filled value.
OK.
Something like that.
All right.
And so then we can close off our for each and then I think we can close off the entire method as well.
And let's see here.
Yeah, I don't see any errors here.
All right.
So let's jump up to this guy now.
OK, so set it.
So now, instead of calling Set I.D., I think we can just call our set ID by annotation, which will
take our ID and then our entity.
There we go.
And I don't see any other errors and notice now.
When I'm looking for errors, I'm looking for red marks over in this gutter over here on the right,
and I don't see any.
So I think we're good there.
So now I think we're ready to run our tests again.
Look at that, everything's still working for us, and I don't know.
You know, sometimes I don't 100 percent want to trust my own tests.
So just for grins, if we comment out this whole setting business temporarily right there and then run
this again, we should get a failure.
Yeah, yeah, we got lots of failures.
So by doing this kind of thing, this is just further helping me to trust that my tests are testing
adequately because it is entirely possible to write inadequate tests.
And you may not even fully realize it because they're just not very well written, right?
And so they pass under very easy circumstances.
So I feel pretty good with that.
And so now I will come back up here and uncomment that and then run this one more time.
Looking good?
All right.
And so now we can jump back over to the person class and get rid of this.
And now we don't need these overrides here, either.
Very good.
And in fact, I could even delete the entity class are the entity interface itself.
Gone, bye bye.
And because of that surgery, let's just run all the tests again.
Looking good.
All right.
So that's really all I wanted to do was to show you that now we didn't really even need to keep implementing
that interface.
Let me step back real quick and just tell you a little bit more here.
What's informing my decisions to do these kinds of changes, by the way?
I'm not so creative that I'm making up all these techniques myself.
I mean, I am making up all the code myself.
But the idea of sticking an ID on here instead of using an interface or whatever.
This is informed by the fact that there are well known frameworks in Java for doing this kind of stuff.
And basically, what I'm showing you here is a little bit of how those future frameworks that you will
be learning are actually working.
OK?
And so some of those future frameworks have annotations that are actually named exactly this, in fact,
and they work similarly to this.
Now, a couple of differences are that our ID annotation is currently only written to work on the field
itself.
But more robust frameworks that do this kind of thing would also work if you put the Ad ID annotation
on a method, so you could put it on the getter or setter method or whatever, right?
Things like that.
We're not going quite that far.
Another thing I want to mention as well is that our credit repository framework now is just assuming
that all entities will have an idea of type long, but more robust frameworks would actually not make
that assumption at all.
And we could have written ours to not make that assumption, except that I think it would have caused
us to write a little bit extra code that I don't really want to write.
And let me show you what that code would look like, by the way.
So we'll jump back over to the credit repository wherever we're working with IDs like right here, start
get long.
If we had decided to generate size the ID type so that it could be any type and not just long.
That would mean that we would have to have some type of conditional code right here.
That would say if the generic ID type is long, then do it this way.
If it's a string, then then, you know, do then do string ID equals restart that string blah blah
blah, right?
So we'd have to write an R-Sport that get method for each of the different data types that we supported.
OK.
And I didn't want to get into all of that, but it would be pretty straightforward.
The other thing we would have done is right here, where we have generic sized the entity type.
We would have added one more generic type for the ID.
OK, right here.
And you will see in the future with one of the most popular database frameworks these days for Java,
which is called spring data, it works exactly like that.
OK, so you could actually specify both the entity type and then the ID type as well past those both
in.
And that's almost certainly what they're doing in their own code.
Implementation is they've probably extracted this out into a method with a conditional block that says
if the ID type is long, then do it this way.
If it's a string to it this way, if it's a date, do it another way and so on and so forth.
So that was all I wanted to show you.
So I think we're done now with the annotations and credit repository reflection stuff.
We may still come in here and tweak it here and there, but the main focus going forward won't be on
further revisions to this credit repository.
I think instead, we'll focus more on the rest of all of the database, things that I still want to
teach you.
So with that, I'll see you in the next one.