All right, so we left off in the last lesson with learning probably the most concise way to implement
this default case, which was to implement an anonymous class, which is all of this bit here.
Right?
So just a very brief recap.
An anonymous class is just a class definition where you don't actually even mention a name.
You just mentioned the type for the class, either by interface or by super class.
So here we have new employee.
Right?
So this would result in a new class being created with no name that extends employee in this case,
because employee is a class and not an interface, it happens to be a class and not an interface, but
we could have used an interface as well.
So this would result in a new class that extends employee that doesn't have a name that implements the
get salary method and returns a hardcoded zero.
OK.
And then it also creates the instance to it doesn't just create the class, it also creates one instance
and returns that instance if this particular default case of this switch statement is called.
All right.
So I did mention, though, that there's yet an even more concise way to do this.
And that's what we're going to learn now.
So the even more concise technique is to use what's called a lambda and lambdas are somewhat newish
to Java as of Java version eight.
So I mean, we're on 16 now, so it's not that new, but I'd say that in many ways, in many respects,
lambda lambdas are still somewhat new ish in Java because there are so many Java developers who still
haven't really fully embraced using lambdas.
And I think one of the reasons for that is because lambdas are really part of a completely different
programming paradigm than that which Java was mostly based on.
So Java is an object oriented language.
Any time we want to pass data and or behavior together around in code, we traditionally have had to
do that via object.
So here we're creating this class with no name.
But the end result is going to be an object that looks like an employee because it will be an object
that extends employee and has this method get salary that returns to zero.
OK, so the end result of this is an object.
Each of these lines here with the new operator are going to result in the creation of an object, right?
Even though in the end, pretty much the only thing we're going to use that object for is to call it
get salary and get a number out of it.
So anyway, Java is an object oriented language.
Lambdas, on the other hand, are a concept that became probably most popularized by languages that
typically follow a different programming paradigm, which is called functional programming.
So in object oriented languages like Java, objects are the lingua franca, if you will, right?
They are the main currency of the language in functional languages, though functions which you may
know here more as methods sort of functions are the primary currency.
OK.
And so in functional languages, functions can exist on their own in Java.
Generally speaking, prior to Java eight especially methods which are essentially functions that live
inside of an object, methods could not live on their own.
They they had little to no meaning outside of an object or a class, right?
So in a functional language, if this get salary is really the thing that we're after and that we're
wanting to do in a functional language.
You might be able to just define a get salary method or reference a get salary method on its own without
an object, without a class.
And just say, Hey, just call this get salary because that's really the thing we care about.
So with the inclusion of lambdas, we now have the ability to actually do this in a pretty cool way.
And that, in turn, allows our code to get much more concise.
So let's just remember really quickly how this default case is actually being used and in fact, how
each of these cases are actually being used.
So we have this method create employee that takes a string of text, and this is an example of one of
those strings of tax write.
It's just one of those lines of an employee.
And then we create a matter for that text and then we test to make sure that that text matches the regular
expression that is described by this, by this matter.
So we're just making sure that this text is in is in this format, that's all we're saying.
OK, so if this text is in this format, last name, first name, date of birth role and then some extra
stuff there, if it's in that exact format, then we proceed with the rest of this code, right?
And so we set up a switch statement.
We extract whatever word is in the role field of this text, which would be this bit right here.
We extract that.
So in this particular case, if this comment that string was the input into this method call, then
the people Matt Dart group role would result in the word analyst coming out of this switch statement
here, OK?
And then the Switch statement would simply say This Programmer Match Analyst is manager of a Match Analyst
is analyst, match analyst, which the answer would be yes.
And so then it would call this line to create a new analyst and then pass in that same string here.
And then that would create that object.
Now, in the event, though, that nothing matches, let's say, because the word is not any of these
words, then it would call this default case, in which case it would now create a new object that extends
employee that has a method called get salary that returns a zero.
OK, so that was our behavior.
I'm just doing a very quick reminder of what this logic was doing.
So then if we go over here to the code, that's actually using that, here's where we're calling Create
Employee the method we were just looking at.
Here's where we're passing in one line at a time of this text up here.
And then this method will return an object of type employee and then we're able to call print line on
it, which under normal circumstances will just print the last name, first name and and the amount,
right?
And then we take that amount, the salary and then we add it to our total right.
So that's what we're doing here.
All right.
So you might have wondered or you might start to wonder, how come this default couldn't just return
the number zero?
And the reason would be because if we go back over to main again, if we just directly returned zero,
yes, we could do the total salaries, which is arguably the most important part.
But we had this secondary bit here that was trying to print a first name in the last name as well.
So in other words, if you want to be able to interact with more than one piece of data from that object
or from these objects that would be here, then you're going to have to typically deal with the entire
object and not just one piece of data that was in the object, right?
And that was kind of the whole point of why I contrived this in this way.
All right.
So that means if we go back to the employee class again, we kind of sort of do need to be returning
an object still sort of kind of right.
But let us be clear that really, out of all of this anonymous class here, the only bits that really
matter to us are, most importantly, returning to zero.
And secondarily to that, just having this method here, the rest of it is just a bunch of what I call
boilerplate code, which is just, you know, a lot of noise, really.
This piece we shouldn't really need to say and a lot of this, you know, curly braces and all that
stuff, that's just noise.
So having said all of that, I will now show you how we can do this using a lambda.
So what we really care about is a method that takes no input and returns a zero.
Right?
So we can express that as a lambda very easily.
And all we have to say is this a method is a method that takes no input is expressed as opening and
closing curly braces, and it returns a zero.
So to see returns, a method that takes the input that returns zero, we would use an arrow.
And then zero.
And then semicolon.
And that's a lambda expression.
This is a lambda expression for a method that takes no inputs and returns a zero.
Now you'll notice I'm getting a squiggly red line.
If I hover my cursor, I'm getting an error saying target type of lambda conversion must be an interface.
So what's happening here is that Java is still fundamentally an object oriented language.
So even when we can work with lambdas, what basically ends up happening underneath the hood is that
Java will try to take this lambda expression and it will try to inspect what is the data type that is
expected to be returned here.
And so it will look and see that this is a switch expression that is returning something.
And it will see that ultimately this return from this switch expression is part of a method whose return
type is employee.
So Java smart enough to kind of trace up this tree, if you will, and see, OK, this switch is supposed
to return employees and therefore this default case here should return something that looks like an
employee.
So then Java will look at this class at this data type employee and try to determine, is there one
method on this data type that I can match to this signature and a signature again, is just the the
description of the method.
So in this case, a method that takes no inputs and returns an integer.
OK, now in this particular case, Java is unable to make that determination with this data type.
But if I were to use an interface here that declares one method on it that matches this signature,
then Java would be able to do that.
Now do we have an interface like that anywhere?
Yeah, we do we have this interface right here, I employee.
Let's go take a look at it.
I employee defines exactly one method.
It defines a method that takes no inputs and returns one integer.
That's exactly the method signature we're looking for.
And so if we jump back over here to employee, what we can do is if we were to change this signature
of create employee to return, not an employee, but to return an AI employee instead.
Like, so look at that.
That error goes away.
Now that does create another error, though.
And if we come up here and click, we can see, OK, so now the next error is that this method is returning
an employee.
But what was expected here is an employee, not an AI employee.
And so one easy thing we could do quickly to fix that is to switch this from employee to AI employee
because they're compatible, right?
All right.
And so that error went away.
Then we jump back over to the employee class again.
We've got one more issue to deal with, and that is the fact that we've got another creation of of a
class instance from the dummy employee.
Now we could handle this in a couple of ways.
We could just replace it with this same lambda or we could fix this dummy employee.
Maybe I'll do both.
So we've got this dummy employee that extends employee so we can fix this in a couple of ways.
Also, one way is that I could go up to the definition of the employee class, which is at the very
top here.
And I could just say employee implements I employee, which we had done once before.
Woops, I missed my --.
There we go.
And I prefer to have a space there.
And now all the errors have gone away.
So that's one way I could do that.
I'm going to show you a couple of others just to remind you or.
I could come down here and say that this dummy employee extends employee and also implements I employee.
And then when I come up here, no problem here anymore, right, so I could do that or I could just
replace this with another lambda expression.
In fact, the same lambda expression right there, or I could use a different one, I could return a
different number if I wanted to.
OK.
So either way.
So what ends up happening here is that Java sees this expression, which is describing a method that
takes no inputs and returns an integer.
It sees that the return type as I am employee, it goes and looks at an employee and says, Does this
interface have just one method on it?
Because if this interface had multiple methods on it, that would be problematic, especially if it
had multiple methods on it with the same signature.
So different names, but the same signature.
That would be a problem.
So to keep it easy, Java's expecting that we're referring to an interface that only defines one method
on it.
And then that one method had better have the same signature as our lambda expression.
And in this case, it does.
And so it says, Ah, OK, so here's what I'm going to do, then I'm going to create an object.
So Java does this.
Java creates an object that implements the I employee interface and has a method on it called get salary
and then it.
For the body of that, new objects get salary method.
It simply returns zero in this particular case.
OK, so it takes whatever we put here on the right side of this arrow and makes that become the body
of that method.
What's nice for us is that we don't have to type all that boilerplate new class, blah, blah blah,
you know, all of these things and describe and mention the name of a method and all of that.
We can just get right down to pretty much the most minimal bit of information we need to provide.
And then Java will kind of wrap this inside of a brand new object of whatever type it can infer, and
it figures that out by looking at the return type.
OK, so I know that's a lot of words to describe that, but I just wanted to make this not so magical
for you so that in order to make sure you're actually getting it, OK?
So look at that.
That's pretty awesome, isn't it?
And you know, let's go ahead and run this real quick because there is one tiny little bit that you
might be a little less crazy about.
But I think in this case, it's not a big deal.
So if we run this now.
All right.
Yeah, well, we're still getting eight point six mil if we come up here, though, you'll notice that
the second person or employee.
And if you remember in our data list here, we made the second one have a role that doesn't match any
of the other roles so that we would know that it would result in that default case.
Getting called, I put a bunch of Z's on the end of a programmer, right?
So for the other, more normal employee types, employees, we, you know, pronounce their last name,
first name, et cetera, et cetera.
But for this lambda one now that has been built from a dynamically defined object, essentially, the
two string method on it isn't a two string method that we have written because we didn't supply one
for it.
And so the default behavior now is just to do a bunch of this.
OK.
So in this particular case, that's the best that I think Java's going to do for us because we can't
supply with our lambda a description, a definition for both the two string method and the get salary.
OK?
We can only supply one method, if you will.
OK.
And that was our get salary.
So Java does its best to say OK, well, objects that are created to enclose a lambda.
If you call the two string method on them, this is what you're going to get the class name of the type.
And then the fact that it's a lambda and maybe I don't know, maybe this is a memory location or something.
I'm not even sure what all of that is, but that's what you get from it.
But I think that's pretty cool.
Let's go look at it one last time.
Super concise.
So we're going to learn more about lambdas and quite a few other cool constructs with newer versions
of Java and another module.
But I wanted to go ahead and give you a sneak preview of this concept here because it works so perfectly
in line with all of these other techniques that I've been leading up to this with nested classes and
inner classes and anonymous classes.
And the most logical conclusion of all of that, in many cases, is a lambda, which we just didn't
have access to those before Java.
Eight.
All right.
So this is going to wrap this one up and I'll see you in the next one.