Hey, welcome back.
So in the last lesson, we loaded up all five million records of our test data file into a real database,
and we allowed them to persist by committing them via a test.
Now that test method that we wrote wasn't a real test because we made no assertions.
We were really just using the mechanisms of a test class as a convenient place for us to execute some
code that is basically meant to only be run probably once.
So now that we've got those five million records loaded into the database, I want to focus on a topic
that I don't think enough beginner and maybe even intermediate developers focus on, and that is database
optimization.
Now, don't worry, we're not going to go very deep into this.
They're really just one or two really basic things that we can do when working with a database to vastly
improve the performance of that database.
So let's take a look at some of those options now.
All right.
So turning back into Squirrel, I'm going to go back in to our people test database and connect to it.
So the first thing I want to do is to find some records in this database that are kind of towards the
end of the database.
OK, so we loaded five million records in and we already had like 11 records in there before.
So I want to query the database for at least one record.
That's kind of towards the end of those five million records.
And the way that we can do that is with a select query, so we can do select star from people.
But now what we want to do is we want to skip past a lot of records.
In fact, I'm thinking basically, we want to skip past around five million records or so.
So just as in Java, where we can use the skip function of the streams, API databases have a similar
capability as well.
Now again, each database engine may have a slightly different version of sequel that they used to be
able to specify this, so you'll have to consult whatever database you're using.
But with H2 database, we can use the offset keyword.
OK.
And then we can just provided a number to tell it how many records we want it to offset or skip over,
essentially.
So I'm going to tell it to skip over five million records.
Six zeros.
OK.
And then from here, we can tell it once you get to that point.
Just fetch like one record.
So then we can say fetch first one row only.
OK, so let me jump into the idea real quick, because I just want you to understand that a lot of these
concepts that we're going to see in the database have analogs to the streams API or various other things
that we do in Java in general, OK?
So this offset five million here would be equivalent to us here in Java code doing skip five million
like so OK.
And then this fetch first one row is equivalent to saying limit one.
Right?
So there are analogs to a lot of these concepts.
All right.
Let me on do that, though.
I'm just showing you that for illustrative purposes.
OK, so let's go ahead and run this and see what we get.
And I want you to pay attention to how long it takes for this to execute as well.
And I'm going to go now.
OK, so now that we found this record.
The reason I had to do this is because I really wanted to get at one of the IDs of a record that's toward
the bottom of this table.
OK, so now I want to do something very similar to this.
Let's query for this record by its I.D. So we'll do a select star from people where ID equals, and
then I can come down here and click on that ID value and copy and then I can paste it.
OK.
And let's run that with a control return, or don't forget, you can also click the little thing there,
but keyboard shortcuts are your friend.
They make you go faster.
All right.
So let's run that.
And again, let's note how long that took.
OK, so that took two and a half seconds.
So pretty much the same, in fact, took a little bit longer in this particular case.
All right.
So basically the same amount of time as the previous query.
So here's the problem.
Two and a half seconds might seem like it's pretty fast considering that we're iterating over five million
rows.
But in actuality, that is really quite slow for a database.
If this database with these five million records were being used in an application or on the web or
something like that, and we had lots of users who were all trying to do the equivalent of this more
or less simultaneously, those two and a half second start to add up pretty quickly.
And keep in mind every time the computer has to take two and a half seconds to go find one record,
that's time that the processor in that computer isn't available to do other things right.
So this is actually pretty bad.
Now let me help you to get an understanding of why this is so slow.
We've got a sample of our rows here, and when we tell the database to go find a record with some ID,
let's pretend like this employee ID is our ID card.
Even though it's not, we didn't actually bring that data over, but let's pretend like we did.
And until we tell the computer, go find record four one eight three nine zero.
In this particular case, the database had to actually scan over every single row checking to see if
the ID matched what we passed in as a parameter until it finds a match.
And because we chose a record that's almost near the very bottom of the table, the database essentially
had to perform what's called a full table scan, meaning just that it had to scan through every single
record in the table in order to find that record.
Now, some of you may be thinking, Well, isn't that what a database would have to do anyway?
How else could it find that record other than to scan through the entire table looking for it?
Well, we actually learned some techniques back in our collections module that would help us to understand
how a database could potentially find that record a lot faster than what it just did now.
If you recall, back in the collections module, we learned about hashes and sets and hash maps.
And one of the things that we learned about the hash map or even just maps in general, is the fact
that when we store a key and a value pair in a map, the hash map implementation of the map interface
has the ability to analyze the key that we're inserting into that key value pair entry and generate
a hash code for that key.
The hash map will then use that hash code to determine where in a table that entry should go.
So the next time you try to retrieve a value out of the hash map using that key, the hash map doesn't
have to iterate over every single entry in that map.
Instead, it takes your key that you provided.
It regenerates a hash code for it, and then it uses that hash code to determine an index into a table
where your record exists or where your entry exists.
And then it can much more efficiently go straight to that entry.
Or at least it can get super super close if there happened to be collisions where other entries yield
the same index.
But it can cut down a lot on the amount of scanning that has to be done to find your entry.
And in this example, entry and record are essentially the same thing.
Well, it just so happens that databases can use very similar types of tricks, and they are optimized
to do so if you help them out.
So databases have an ability to generate what is called an index, and you can basically just think
of the creation of an index on a table.
Very similarly to a hash map generating hash codes that lead to indexes for records and a hash maps
internal table very similar concepts.
I wouldn't be surprised if a lot of databases essentially use almost the exact same mechanisms, in
fact.
So the key here is that if you want to be able to look up records in a database more quickly, you need
to consider generating what is called an index for the particular column that you're going to be searching
by.
So in our case, we just searched for one record by ID.
But the problem is that currently we do not have an index on the ID column.
And in fact, in this people table, we don't have any indexes defined at all.
Now, when we created this table, I intentionally left out any possibility for an index to be generated
for a couple of reasons.
Number one, I wanted to be able to teach this concept and show you what happens when you don't have
indexes.
Things are slow.
And there's another reason that I'll get to a little bit later in this lesson.
OK.
So first off, I want to just show you the lack of index on this people table.
So if we jump over here?
Who the objects tab and then jump into the people test icon here, I'm just double clicking on that
and then double clicking on public and then double clicking on table and then clicking on people here.
So this represents the people table, and then we can click on this Indexes tab here.
And what you'll see is there are no rows in here at all.
So that's just letting us know that the people table currently has no index as defined on it.
OK.
All right.
So now we'll jump back over to the school tab.
So let's go ahead now and actually create an index for the ID column and see if that has any effect
on how the database is performing some of our queries.
All right.
So to create an index, I will go down to a new line and we can use this command, create index and
then we need to provide a name for the index and I'm inclined to call this index.
I'd underscore index, meaning it's the index for the ID column.
Then we have to specify what column we are applying this index to.
So we'll say on people table idea column like that.
And then we'll execute this.
Now, notice this is taking a little while.
All right.
So that actually took six point six seconds.
I want you to make note of the fact that that took six point six seconds.
The reason that took so long is because when we create an index on a column and a database with five
million records, what's happening is that the database is having to go through the ID column values
on all five million of those records to generate its index.
OK, so it has to do some analysis in order to be able to do this.
So you can imagine again going back to the hash map example where the hash map itself has to generate
a hash code and then figure out what index to generate from that hash code so that subsequent lookups
into the hash table will be fast, right?
Because it can just jump straight from a key to a hash map to an index and then go straight to that
row, right?
The database, again, is doing very similar types of things here, but that does take a little while
to generate on five million records initially.
All right.
So now that we've created this index, let's jump back over to the Objects tab.
And then if we right click on this people table and we can refresh item?
There we go.
And so now we have one record under the Indexes tab.
And you may have to put your cursor in between these headers here to make room if you can't see everything
there.
But we're in the people test database, and it's just saying that we created an index that is called
ID underscore ADX, and it is for the first column.
Column one, which is the ID column.
That's the column name.
OK, so the main point I want to show here is that now we have an index created for the people table.
All right.
So now going back over to the sequel tab, let's try querying for this record now.
OK, so I'm going to just put my cursor right back here and then just rerun this.
And now you might have noticed that that came back pretty much instantaneously, and in fact, if we
come down here, we see that that took point zero zero one seconds, right?
What is that 10, 100 hundred one one thousandth of a second, which I think is one millisecond now
to make sure that this is really working and not just like some kind of cached data caching means once
you've retrieved one record, it's kind of stored for faster retrieval than the next time.
So let's make sure we're not just benefiting from that type of caching trick.
So we can actually just increase this number on here from from ending in a seven to ending in an eight.
Like so.
So we'll get a fresh new record and then let's run that.
And that also took one one thousandth of a second.
And we're going to find now that in general, everything is going to be really, really fast.
In fact, that one showed up as only having taken zero seconds.
So I guess it was so fast that it didn't even register as a millisecond.
So just by creating that index on the ID column, we were able to vastly increase the speed at which
we're able to query for a specific row by ID.
Now, having shown you that?
Let me show you this, though.
So down here in the data, we have retrieved a record with that ID and the last name of Durkee.
Let's try selecting the same record, but instead of searching by ID, let's search by the email address
and see how that performs.
So I'll do a select everything from people where email equals, and then I'll come down here and right
click and copy that and then come up here and paste that.
And remember, now in most databases, we surround strings with single ticks, not double ticks.
OK.
All right.
So now let's run this.
Oh, look at that.
We're back to it being slow again.
How long did that take two and a half seconds, just like it was before we created an index?
Are any of you confused about this?
You shouldn't be.
But, but it's OK if you are all right.
So why did that take so much longer, even though we've created this index?
The reason is because our index is specifically for the ID column, and now we're not querying by ID
anymore.
Now we just queried by email address.
So this is an important point for you to understand when we create an index on a table.
That index is typically specific for a column.
Now, some databases may support complex indexes that are based on a combination of columns.
We won't be getting into that, but here we are no longer querying by ID.
We're querying by email address.
And so if we want this to perform fast, we need to create another index specifically for the email
column.
So let's go ahead and do that just to prove it.
So create index, and I will call this one email underscore IDEX on people.
Parentheses, email, close parentheses and then return, and let's pay attention to how long this may
take.
Wow, look at that that took almost 15 seconds to generate the index on the email column.
Why did that take so much longer, by the way?
Now I'm not a database expert, but I'm pretty sure it has a lot to do with the fact that the email
addresses are somewhat complex strings with more characters in them than an ID column that is really
just numbers.
OK.
So I think you may find in many database engines that the more complex the data of a column is, the
longer it may take to initially create the index on that column.
OK, but now that we've got that, let's go try this again.
So I'm putting my cursor back here on this query and I'm on a search and I'm going to execute this.
And now that came back in one one thousandth of a second.
And again, now, just to make sure that's not some fluke of caching, let's query the database for
a few records so that we can get a few unique email addresses for them.
OK, so I'm going to go back up here to this first line, and instead of retrieving just one row, let's
retrieve 10 rows.
So let's run that.
OK, so now we've got our ten rows here, and we've got lots of e-mail addresses to work with, right?
And there's Jeff Durkee there, so we will avoid him.
So let's try this second to last one, Merl Rufus.
Someone to grab that copy.
Come up here and replace Jeff with Merle.
All right.
And now let's run that look at that essentially instantaneous.
So these indexes are invaluable.
Now you may be thinking, OK, well then we should probably just generate indexes on every single column,
in every database table every time.
Right?
Well, not so quick.
With great power comes great responsibility.
And these indexes come at a cost.
So we don't necessarily just want to automatically generate indexes on every single column in every
single table.
The key to figuring this out is to understand how our database applications will be utilized.
So we have to ask ourselves questions like in what ways are our users most likely to search for and
query data?
For example, if we have an application that allows people to enter an ID to look up some kind of data
or record, well, then you know, you're certainly going to have to be querying the database by ID
for those particular records.
And since you know that for certain, you'll definitely want to have an index generated on that particular
column and any other columns that users are likely to specifically search by or grouping by.
Remember, when we learned in the Streams API how we could group by a particular column?
Databases can allow us to do group buys as well.
So any of these key types of columns where you're going to search by or group by or sorting on any of
those types of columns, you will likely want to have an index generated on them.
But here's the cost.
When you have indexes generated on columns in a table and then you insert records into the table, inserts
and updates can take longer now because now every time you do an insert or potentially even an update,
the database will certainly have to do its analysis and re indexing, potentially on inserts.
And it may have to do it on updates, particularly if you modified a column that has an index on it.
OK.
So consider how we initially created the people table in the first place, and then we programmatically
loaded all five million records in on my computer that took around 35 seconds with no index is there.
If I had had indexes on the people table prior to us trying to load the five million records, it would
have taken longer.
Now I don't know how long it would have taken.
I haven't actually tried it, but I can tell you now it would have taken longer.
So that's another thing to keep in mind.
If you're working on a project where, you know, right off the bat, you're going to need to load up
an enormous number of records.
And this is like brand new code and brand new database and everything.
It may be worth considering to not have things like indexes defined and generated on that table initially,
just so that you can quickly load up all of your data into the table.
You can always come back later and then generate those indexes and certain other optimization objects
on the table afterwards.
So that's something definitely worth considering if you know you're going to have to turn around and
load millions or billions of records into a database.
All right.
So maybe the last thing I want to say on this topic is I just want to point out I devised this course
based largely on my observations over the years of some of the problem areas and weaknesses that I've
seen in a lot of developers over the years.
One of those key problems that I've noticed far too often when working with some other developers,
particularly beginners and intermediate developers, is their lack of very, very basic, fundamental
knowledge of things like databases.
Now I am by no means a database expert, nor do I aspire to be one.
There are a lot of different databases in the world.
I don't care to become an expert at even one of them to a great degree.
But there are some ADCs of databases that every developer really does need to understand.
And this is definitely one of them.
It's so basic.
I can't tell you the number of times that I've worked with developers on projects.
They've built an entire application and the people who use the application or the business.
People who determine how the application should function complain about how slow it is every time they
need to retrieve data or work with data in any in any way.
And after just doing a few minutes of looking at the code and how things are working, I have multiple
times asked developers, Did you guys create any indexes on any of the columns that are most commonly
queried by and quite frequently?
I'm not sure they even know what I'm talking about.
That's not good.
You just saw how easy it is to create an index for a particular row and how drastic the timing is when
you don't have an index versus when you do.
It's not a lot of effort to get a huge speed up in performance by simply creating an index.
Right?
So I'm just reiterating the fact that it is my hope and my desire that by taking this course, you will
learn enough of the basics heads and shoulders over a lot of other developers, some of whom may have
been working in the field for several years already.
So, you know, this is a good example of where a little bit of knowledge can go a really long way.
All right, so we're going to end.
A lesson here and in the next lesson, we'll get into some other interesting things with the database.
I'll see you in the next one.