All right, so in this lesson, I want to present you with an interesting scenario.
Let's say that a CEO is, you know, an employee as we have him here, but let's say that a CEO can
also be a pilot.
OK?
And let's say that pilots have various behaviors and and data that they can capture or that they can
track.
OK, so obviously, pilots can fly.
They have a certain number of hours that they have ever flown.
They have certain certifications or ratings to determine, you know, if they're allowed to fly in bad
weather or whatever, right?
So let's let's do this.
Let's let's create another class.
Let's make a class that models a pilot a little bit.
All right.
So I'm going to come over here to the I.D., and I guess I'm going to right click on the package and
create a new Java class, and I will just call this pilot.
All right.
So let's model a few characteristics of a pilot.
We don't have to go real crazy with this.
Let's say that a pilot has a, I don't know, a number of hours that they have flown.
So let's just say this is an integer and it's hours flown and we'll initialize it to zero, I suppose.
And let's also say that a pilot can be rated for and I'm not a pilot.
I don't know much about flying, but I do know that there's something called instrument flight rating.
And I think that basically is a rating that pilots can get certified for.
That allows them to fly in conditions where they might not be able to see very well with their eyes,
and so they have to rely more on the instrumentation.
OK, so let's call this a Boolean, and let's just call it IFR instrument flight rated, and we'll defaulted
to false.
All right.
And then let's generate a constructor and we will use those two fields.
And then let's create some getters and setters.
Notice I just type genes there to narrow down to getters and setters and will create getters and setters
for all of the fields.
And I don't know.
Let's also say that a pilot can fly.
So this will be a void method and if someone were to call the fly method.
Now I happen to live very close to a to a regional airport in my town, and there are airplanes flying
by all the time.
And just as I'm, you know, talking about pilots and things, one one flies right over.
So anyway, let's say that if someone calls the fly method, we'll just print out a message and prepare
for takeoff.
I don't know if off is one word or two takeoff.
I don't know.
OK.
All right, so that's that's enough modeling of a pilot, right?
So let's say that a pilot can do all of these things.
OK, now let's go back over to the CEO class.
So how could we model a CEO so that the CEO is an employee, but the CEO is also a pilot?
If you'll recall from a previous lesson, I stated that Java, though it is an object oriented language,
Java does not permit what is called multiple inheritance.
That is a concept in object orientation where a class can actually inherit from or in this case, extend
from more than one other class.
So here we've got CEO inheriting from the employee class, OK, by using the extends word, but I cannot
do something like put a comma.
Behind employee and then say, also CEO can extend pilot, I can't do that.
And the reason, as I mentioned before, is that the creators of Java were very familiar with object
oriented languages that do permit multiple inheritance, such as C++, and they were well aware of the
headaches that can ensue when you allow for multiple inheritance, and they chose not to get into any
of that at all, at least not in the ways that C++ handles it.
So we can't do this.
But there is a way for us to sue, to take it out.
OK.
And what that is is that although we cannot have CEO inherit from two or more classes, CEO or any class
for that matter, can be composed of multiple classes.
OK.
So let me just show you what that looks like rather than trying to explain it.
So what we can do?
So first, let me get rid of that, which will never work in Java.
And what we can do, though, is we can actually create a new field on the CEO class of type pilot.
And we'll call it pilot, and we can go ahead and just instantiate that in line if we like.
OK, so we'll create a new pilot and now he's got a constructor where we can set the number of hours
phone, let's say a thousand hours.
And let's say yes, he is IFR.
He is instrument flight rated.
All right, so there's our new pilot.
Now, this isn't really doing anything for us yet when we extend a class.
We inherit all of that class's methods and all of its non private members as well.
OK.
And so we can utilize those as if they were written directly on the class.
Just creating a new instance of a pilot as a field doesn't give us any of that.
However, we can create what are called delegate methods on the CEO and what those would be are methods
that mirror the public methods of the pilot class, such that CEO then has essentially has those same
methods, and we didn't have to write all of what's in those methods.
OK, we're just passing through.
So let me show you a really cool way that we can do that using intelligence.
So what we can do now that we have this field of type pilot, I'm going to move my cursor down to the
bottom of this class and then I'm going to generate some new methods.
So again, if your Windows Linux, you'll have to right click here.
If your Mac, you can do a command in.
All right, so that you can actually see what's in here.
I'm going to scroll up a little more and see if I can get it to squeeze into the to the view of your
your into your view.
So I'll do a command in there.
It is just barely making it and we've got this option here, delegate method.
So I'm going to choose that.
So what it's doing now is it's presenting me with the fields of this class, and it's going to allow
me to generate methods that mirror the public methods of any of these classes.
So I already have pilots selected here.
So if I click, OK, watch what happens?
It now sees the methods, the public methods of the pilot class.
And it highlights them automatically for me because it's assuming I want to make delicate methods for
all of these public methods on pilot.
And so if I click, OK, look at that, it generated the delegate methods for all of those and I didn't
have to do anything, really.
And so I now have a method on SEO class called fly, which delegates down to the pilot classes fly method,
get hours flown, delegates down to pilots get hours flown, et cetera, et cetera.
It even handles the setter methods, which require a little extra step, right, because they take input.
So now pilot that said, hours flown and it passes the input over all of that.
And so this is a really cool technique for being able to expand the capabilities of my class, somewhat
similarly, as I can do when I extend or inherit from another class.
But I don't have to use up my one and only inheritance shot.
Now I can do something even cooler than this, though.
What if I want my CEO to look like a pilot?
OK, and what I mean by that is when I use objects of type CEO in other classes like Maine, I don't
have to store an instance of a CEO in a CEO variable.
I can store it in a variable of type employee or even in a variable of type I employee, right?
Because of the way that interfaces and inheritance work.
What if I wanted to be able to do something similar with pilot?
So, you know, if I wanted to store an instance here, let me just show you what I mean.
So we come up, come over here to Maine.
And let's say that just for sake of argument here, let's just say that we want to create a new instance
of a CEO.
And for right now, just use empty text, OK?
But let's say that I want to store this CEO instance in a variable of type pilot.
I can't do that right.
It's not going to let me do that.
They're just two completely unrelated types.
Even though CEO has delegate methods that delegate down to the methods of pilot, CEO is not a pilot.
It's just fundamentally not a pilot.
But let me show you this cool trick if I go to the pilot class.
And we can ignore this, that's just because of what I just did in the main here.
If I go to the pilot class and I right click on the pilot class name and then I come down here to refactor
extract interface.
So what this is going to do, and I think you've seen me do this once before now.
Well, here, let's just try it.
Extract interface.
All right.
So now it's going to create a new interface based on whatever methods I choose that are already on the
pilot class.
OK, so I need to give this new interface a name.
I'm not going to call it pilot because that would be confusing.
So I'll create another name that means someone who can fly.
So why don't I just say fly or?
Right?
The beauty of English sometimes just stick an air on the end of of of any verb, and suddenly that becomes
a person who can do that.
All right.
So fly air is going to be my interface.
Obviously, I could have name this anything.
And then I'm going to select, I guess, all of the methods of flyer.
Of Pilot.
All right, then I'm going to select Refactor.
And this is just asking me, do I want to replace all the places where I'm referring to a pilot as a
as a variable type with this new interface?
I think, yes, I do want that.
And so now it's saying, well, here are a couple of places that I have found where you're currently
referring to a pilot.
Do I'm going to change these to now refer to a flyer?
I guess so.
Sure.
Why not?
All right.
And let me read let me resize this window so that you can see what you're not seeing here.
So if I highlight if I select either of these instances, it's just showing me what's going to change
there.
So here's a place where I'm creating a CEO and trying to store it in a pilot.
And it's going to change this word pilot to this type, pilot to to two flyer instead.
All right.
So I'm going to click OK to allow that.
And then I have to also tell it to go ahead and do the refactoring.
So.
All right.
So now if I go back over here to Maine now, what was a pilot variable of type pilot is now flyer a
flyer variable of type flyer.
OK, so you can kind of see what it did there.
Now it's still in error because CEO has nothing to do with pilots or flyers yet.
OK, we're getting to that.
All right.
So now if I jump back over to the CEO.
Now I can do something pretty cool.
So you'll recall again that while it is true that Java does not allow a class to inherit or extend more
than one class, Java does allow a class to implement more than one interface.
And we just extracted a new interface called flyer from the pilot class.
So now if I come over here to my list of interfaces and I still have this, you know, this example
interface, Apple that is doing nothing for us, I should probably get rid of that, but I'm going to
add now another comma.
And now I will say that CEO also implements the flyer interface.
Just like that and now look at what just happened there.
All of those delegate methods that were added from the pilot class are now being shown with this little
icon here, and that icon just means that the I.D. recognizes these methods.
Satisfy the contract, if you will, of the flyer interface, that is to say, hey, whenever a class
implements an interface, that class must implement the methods of that interface.
And the idea is recognizing, I already have methods that satisfy that contract, right?
Those methods are right here.
And so now the CEO not only looks like an employee, it also looks like a a flyer, which is a pilot,
right?
So now if I go back over here to the main method, look at that.
That error just went away now because I'm storing this instance of a CEO in a variable of type flyer.
By default, I'm only allowed to call methods that are defined on fliers so I could call Flyer Dot Fly.
And now the CEO will know how to fly.
So if I were to call this method, it would execute whatever we coded here, which I think was to print
out, prepare for takeoff or something.
By the way, if I want to jump in to the actual implementation of this method, like the final implementation
of this method.
I can put my cursor here and on Mac.
I can do a command Option B, which is control alt b on Windows and Linux.
And then the ADC will actually let me choose which implementation do I want to look at?
The CEO one which really doesn't do anything but delegate down to the pilot one or the pilot one, which
is the real implementation so I can actually see.
Let me let me see the pilot implementation of the fly method.
And here we are.
So now I can see.
Yes, indeed, the fly method prints out that message there.
OK.
So I will jump back over to the CEO class now.
So let me recap what's so awesome about this if I want a class to be able to implement and pseudo inherit?
Functionality from multiple other classes that are otherwise unrelated.
I can still do that with this technique of composition.
So let me be a little clearer here.
So this technique is called composition because now my CEO class is composed from a pilot instance.
OK?
And I could have a thousand other classes and I could compose CEO of those other thousand classes as
well.
Now, the only thing that sucks a little bit for me, at least, is the fact that you do need to explicitly
add all of these delegate methods here.
OK.
But the good thing is the A.D. can do that for you automatically.
You don't have to do it on your own right, so it's no sweat off your back other than just a couple
of key clicks or whatever to tell the aide to do your bidding for you.
Right?
But this gets us around the problem if you want to consider it to be a problem of the lack of multiple
inheritance.
Now you will actually hear a lot of Java developers say that we should actually prefer composition over
And what they typically mean by that is they consider it to be better generally to imbue your classes
with more functionality from other classes.
Using this technique of composition rather than just extending a class now a lot of developers just
stop right there.
I'm going to put a bit more nuance in it and be a little clearer.
I'm going to say in general, if you wrote this super class and you also are writing the potential subclass
and you want your subclass to extend your superclass and you wrote both of them, go for it.
Generally speaking, go for it.
OK, now I have stated, don't do that.
Like you know, many levels deep, though don't don't go three four five six levels deep.
That's going to that's a recipe for disaster in most cases.
OK.
Keep it relatively shallow to maybe three levels that most OK.
If you feel the strong need to go deeper than that.
Rethink your entire strategy.
OK.
But if you wrote everything involved in that hierarchy and you wrote it intending to have a hierarchy,
pretty much as we have done here with the employee and then the other, the various types of employee,
you're you're fine, you're fine, OK?
Where this favoring of composition over inheritance really comes into play is in a different scenario
where you did not write the class that you're considering extending.
OK, the class might be from another developer on another team or in another department, or in another
company or in another organization.
And you don't necessarily know whether or not the author of that potential class intended for that class
to be extended.
OK, now sometimes there are frameworks that create classes that are intended to be extended.
And generally speaking, there, you're fine because those were intended for that purpose.
But if someone wrote an employee class and they weren't explicitly planning for you or anyone else to
extend that class, you should tread very carefully when doing that.
And the reason is because you may be making assumptions of how the methods in that class are operating.
And at any time, the author of that class could decide to change those implementations.
And you may receive those updates and suddenly your assumptions cause your code to be broken.
OK, so it can lead to very fragile code.
It is actually for this reason that it is often recommended, in fact, that if you yourself are the
author of a class and you don't intend for that class to be inherited by yourself or anyone else, you
may explicitly declare your own class to be final.
That prevents others from extending your class OK to protect them from themselves, essentially.
However, you can still consider endowing your class with the functionality that you're liking from
some other class by using composition.
It's a little bit better because you have more control over what's going on.
You have to explicitly call in your delegate methods.
The other classes method, right?
And so you get a chance to override what it's doing a little more easily.
I mean, you could do that with inherited within.
Here it is as well, of course, but it's even more explicit when you're using these delegate methods.
OK.
And then obviously, it lets you also get around the fact that Java is not going to allow you to inherit
from more than one class.
And so sometimes you see it, you'll see Java developers say you have to pick wisely what class you
want to spend on your one and only inheritance shot.
Right?
But with composition, it doesn't matter.
Now you can compose your class of as many other classes as possible.
All right.
So I think this is going to wrap up this lesson.
It's a super powerful technique, and I hear so many developers who have read maybe like one book ever,
and they've learned a little bit more than maybe the average developer to know that we shouldn't use
inheritance and inheritance is a powerful technique that you should not be afraid to use.
So if someone tells you just in a blanket statement that you should not use inheritance?
Well, you know what?
You're missing out on a lot of what an object oriented language can can give you, so you shouldn't
just blindly decide never to utilize inheritance.
Instead, you should know when is it a good idea to use inheritance and when is it a bad idea, right?
And what are the pros and cons and then weigh those?
Most people want to be overly simplistic, and they want to go way too far in one direction and use
inheritance everywhere where it's not necessary and go to levels deep with their hierarchy.
And that's a terrible idea, always.
Or they don't want to use any inheritance ever.
And therefore they just miss out on all the beauty and awesomeness of object oriented programming and
the power of it.
And then I sometimes question, Well, why are you even using Java if you're not going to use a lot
of the object oriented techniques that it allows?
Right?
And so there's a there's a middle of the road there where we use these techniques, but we don't abuse
them and we can also use composition and other features as well to really bring our applications together
in the most efficient and effective ways.
All right.
So that's enough for this lesson, and I will see you in the next one.