All right, in this lesson, I've got another scenario for you.
Still, with our employee project, so when we run this employee project, we get this output that we've
seen many times already.
So we basically are looping over each of the employees that we have up here, right?
And as we're looping through them, we tally up the salaries and then we print each person in their
salary and their bonus out right here, right?
And we're doing that just by calling the two string method of the given employee.
And that's all well and good.
Well, let's pretend like we want more information or we want different kinds of information, depending
on the type of employee it is.
If it's a programmer, we want to see the programmer specific information, like the lines of code in
the IQ and stuff.
Now, obviously, if we're the ones who have written the code, which in this case we are the ones who
have written the code, the most likely thing we do here is simply to go back into these subclasses
and revise their two string methods to do something a little more unique.
Right now, they're all inheriting the two string method from the employee class.
Right here.
Which is nice because we didn't have to implement anything so we could go into the subclasses and override
this method and then implement specific testing methods.
However, in this scenario, I want to pretend like we didn't write those classes.
We didn't write the classes for the hierarchy of employees.
Let's pretend like those are coming from some third party library or framework, or at least from another
team, and that team won't share their code with us.
Maybe they made the classes final also, so we can't extend them and then override those methods ourselves,
right?
But we still want to be able to revise what information we're printing as we're looping over each of
those employees in this while loop.
So how can we handle that?
That's the scenario that I want to run through so that I can use it as an excuse to to to yet another
technique relating to classes and object orientation.
So basically, I think what we're wanting to do here is we're going to get a new employee and then we
we'd have to find out externally from the classes.
So somewhere in this loop, presumably we'd have to find out what is the class type of that employee.
And then if it's a programmer, then we print out the programmer style of output.
And if it's a manager, then we print out another style of output, right?
That's basically what we're talking about.
So let's see what that could look like.
So maybe we'd literally just have an if block and we could say something like.
If the employee now here's the thing, we haven't really I don't think I've shown you thus far in this
course how you can determine what the class type is of an object.
But there are a few ways to do this.
So first, we'll start with the way that we're not going to end with.
And so one thing you could do is to do something like this employee that get class.
So all objects have a an inherited method called get class.
And it's pretty straightforward.
So you can call get class and then you can even call equals to test if it's equal to some other class.
And so we could say something like if employee Typekit class equals programmer.
Now here's the thing you can refer to a class as I'm doing here.
But then if you want to compare it to what comes out of the get class method, then you'll do a period
class.
So programmer talked class, so you can say employee that get class equals program or class.
Now I will just point out, as I've done before, when I showed you about you comparing string constants
to variables, if there was any possibility that this variable employee could be null, you'd want to
be careful here, though in our case, there should not be any possibility for that because of the way
that we implemented create employee.
So I just wanted to remind you of that fact.
Always be careful about these nails.
A little bit later, we'll learn how to never have to worry about Noelle's again with a technique called
optional.
All right.
So yes, so you could compare and say like if the employee class is programmer class, then whatever,
you know, maybe output, whatever unique type of output you want for that scenario.
And then we could just keep going else if.
Employee get class equals manager talked class.
Then do something else and so on and so forth, right?
And then finally, you could say for all other scenarios.
Default output of some sort, you know, to say that the value is zero.
All right.
So I think you get that.
All right, so that's one way you could do this, however, this is probably not the most typical way
or idiomatic way that seasoned Java developers would probably handle this kind of scenario.
So one issue with using the get class method and equals here is the fact that it is exact.
And that might be what you want.
It might be.
But let me show you now an alternative approach to this.
So in many cases, the more idiomatic way that Java developers would do this type of situation is with
a special Java keyword called instance of.
So let me show you what that would look like.
You could say if employee instance of.
Programmer like so now in this particular case, this is pretty much equivalent to what we had before.
However, instance of actually can check for hierarchy.
So if I were to say if employee instance of an employee with a big E.
This would also be true because this instance of employee will be a subclass of the employee class.
That is, unless it's an instance of our lambda expression.
I'll just remind you, we'll jump into the create method here.
We've got this last default bit here that just creates a lambda expression, which is basically an anonymous
function which you can almost think of as a method.
It's an anonymous function that in this case is returning zero.
This anonymous function will essentially get wrapped inside of a shell of an interface.
That interface will be I employee.
So technically, the object that will eventually be returned from this switch expression won't be a
subclass of employee.
It will be an implementation of I employee, though.
OK.
So that's one thing to keep in mind in this particular case.
So the object that gets generated by that lambda expression would not be an instance of employee.
But in general, the biggest difference between the use of instance of versus comparing with get class
is the fact that instance of is aware of class hierarchies and it honors the class hierarchy.
OK, class is precise.
You can only compare one class to that same class to say that they are both equivalent.
So let me go ahead and update the other clauses here if we enter one if.
Lest.
All right, so there we have it.
So that's our basic template for how we could do this now.
Oh, and I just realize.
Let me put this back to programmer.
Here we go.
All right.
So now if I wanted to get specific information about the programmer to print out here right now, I
can't do something.
Well, first, let's go take a look at the programmer class.
And let's see, so we've got lines of code.
Years of experience in IQ, and I didn't generate any getter setter methods for those fields, but let
me go ahead and generate some real quick.
I guess I'll just put them at the bottom here.
So I'm going to do a command in and getter setter enter and then I'm going to select those three fields,
just those three.
I don't want these other two here and click, OK.
And there we go.
So we've got our getters and setters for four these three fields.
So now jump back over to the main class and now I can access those fields.
So I'm not going to do anything fancy or special here.
I just want to show.
So if I wanted to just print out one of those fields, you might think that I would just be able to
say something like employee died.
Get IQ.
Now watch what happens, though, when I do this.
The I.D. casts my employee object into a programmer, and the reason it does this is because this employee
object in this context of code right now is not actually known to be a programmer.
It's only known to be an AI employee.
This interface here, because that's what we created here, that's the variable type for employee as
I employee.
So in order for me to be able to access the methods that are you new unique to a programmer, this employee
object has to first be cast into a programmer.
And if you recall about casting, we learned about it.
I think in the module on numbers in particular, we put the type that we're casting to in parentheses.
Now that's not enough here because we're also trying to access a method on the programmer class.
So not only do we have to first put the word programmer in parentheses, let me put a little space here
so you can see more clearly.
OK, so this this that I have highlighted is casting the employee variable to a programmer.
But if I want to access programmer methods, that is methods that are specific to the programmer class.
I must surround all of this blew in parentheses again first in order to get at those methods.
And so the ADP also surrounded this whole entire thing here in blue in an additional set of parentheses.
So I'll.
Like so so you can think of these parentheses as grouping up and making one one object of type programmer,
and now it is that object which I can then get get to those methods like get IQ.
OK, so the idea did that for me automatically because it's smart enough to see that that's what I was
trying to get to.
OK, now if you happen to be coding in an I.D. that isn't intelligence such as Eclipse or NetBeans,
I don't know if the latest versions of those IDs are that smart that they'd be able to do that for you.
So under normal circumstances, if an I.D. wasn't doing that for you, let me show you what you would
have gotten here.
I'm going to get rid of all of this casting stuff.
That's what you would have seen is just red for the method because there is no Get IQ method defined
on the I employee interface.
OK.
So typically, if your ID doesn't do nice tricks for you like intelligence, does you typically see
a pattern like this, something like this?
We'd create another variable of the exact type that we care about, and then we do a cast programmer
employee.
So here I'm taking this employee variable.
I'm casting it to a programmer, then I'm storing that into a new local variable of the specific type
programmer.
Then I can come down here and refer to it with this new name of the proper type that I want.
OK, so I'm saying basically, if employee is an instance of the programmer class, then cast employee
to a variable of type programmers so that I can then get at the programmer specific methods and capabilities.
Right now, this is the old school way of handling the instance of pattern that you see here.
Check for the type.
If it is that type, then cast the variable to a specific variable of that type.
And now you can access the data and methods of that specific type.
That's the original pattern.
However, as of Java version 16, which is the version that we're on right now, Java has finalized
a more modern use of instance, of which is called pattern matching.
And what it allows us to do now is we can do this bit here, as you already see, but we can put a variable
name right after the type.
So we could put Prague just like this, and now I can come down here on this line and just get rid of
that line.
So basically, they've given us a nice little shortcut to cast this variable into the specific type
that we want and give us a variable to use it right there.
OK.
And so now we can just refer to it in this way so I can do that again.
Employee instance of manager and then I can call it whatever, man.
And now I can access whatever methods may be specific to the manager class.
I don't think I've generated any here, but you get the point.
Now, as I just stated, let me restate this.
This capability, called pattern matching, is only available officially with Java version 16.
It does exist as a preview in Java 14, which just means that you have to enable that in order to use
it in previous versions of Java.
But it has official support in Java version 16, and that's quite nice.
So a lot of the a lot of the new language features that Java keeps adding are features that allow us
to type less.
That's that's pretty much what it comes down to.
They give us nicer ways to say more with less.
Now, one more thing that you might be wondering about.
We've been using switch statements and expressions quite extensively for a number of projects in this
course.
And you might have been wondering why did I suddenly switch over no pun intended switch over to using
a more traditional, if else, block?
Well, let me show you what happens if we try to do this with Switch, so I will just add a switch here,
Switch employee.
And right away, it starts complaining.
Incompatible types found neutrinos, this employees I employee required character byte short and character
byte short integer string or an enum.
Basically, what it's saying is switches only work for primitives, wrappers of primitives and enemies.
So right now, switches cannot even be used for other data types.
In this case, an interface or a class instance, and that is something that lots of people have complained
about with Java for years and years.
The fact that switches are seemingly so limited in their capabilities.
Now I will just let you know that in upcoming versions of Java, there is a possibility that the Switch
statement will be expanded where we could say something like Switch employee here, and then we could
define a case.
And we could even say something like programmer Prague.
And then use the arrow notation, or we could do the or we could do the colon notation as well.
So that is something that is very much being debated in the Java architecture community right now,
and I'm hopeful that something like this will make its way into Java in the not too distant future,
because I think that would be really nice and cut down on even more of this kind of boilerplate that
we have here.
All right.
So you now have seen so let me get rid of that.
So I'm going to leave it as an exercise for you.
If you want to go ahead and complete this, this approach and make the output say something different
for each data type.
And then in that case, you wouldn't need what is currently Line 47 any longer.
Right.
This more generic standard output for all types might not be necessary anymore.
All right.
So with that, I'm going to bring it to a close and I will see you in the next one.