All right, so in the last lesson, we created an address table in our database.
And so in this lesson, we're going to start modeling that address concept in Java.
Now to do this, we're going to try to stick with the TDD approach to a fair degree.
And so with that being said, we need to think of a scenario that would force us to have to model and
address concept in Java code.
And what I'm thinking here is we could go ahead and create an additional test for saving people.
But this time, let's imagine that in our save person test, we not only create a person, but we also
create an address.
And then we set the address on the person and then we save the person, and then we confirm that the
address ends up in the database.
OK.
So we're going to create a person, create an address, associate the address with the person and then
save it all so that something along those lines.
OK.
All right.
So to do that, let's jump in to our people repository test as a as a starting point here.
Now, before we go and create that test, let's do one quick thing here.
Remember, we created this load data test that isn't really a test.
It's just like a utility method that allows us to fire up the database and our code and then stuff five
million records out into the database quickly, relatively quickly, at least quickly for me.
I don't know how long.
I don't know how long it's taking for you, taking 35 seconds or so for me anyway.
We don't ever want this method to just accidentally run, but I might want to keep it around for a while.
So let me show you something real quick here.
If you want to write a test that you don't always want to have, run whenever you run all the tests
in a test class.
One thing you can do besides just commenting it out, which is kind of messy looking, is you can actually
stick another annotation on the test method, which is called disabled, and that will just disable
that test from ever running.
Pretty easy thing to do.
I mean, I guess another thing you could possibly do also would be to just comment out or delete the
at test annotation, too.
But yeah, yeah, whatever.
OK, so now let's jump up to the area where we have our save tests here, so say it can save one person
can save two people.
So I'm thinking, let's see what it'll look like if we add a third save method in this neighborhood
here.
So at Test Public Void and maybe we can say, can save person with address something like that?
All right.
And so maybe we start off by just duplicating one of these people.
So I just did a command to copy that guy or control D for Windows and Linux.
And then I'm going to do an option shift or alt shift down arrow to bring that line down.
All right.
So there's a person and then I'm thinking, let's go ahead and create an instance of an address, so
I'm going to make a new line.
And in in true TDD fashion, I'm going to just start coding as if the address concept already exists
in this code.
And the idea will complain and scream and yell, and I will let the I.D. make it all come into existence,
right?
So I'm going to pretend like we have a class called address and I'm going to call it address.
And then I'm going to make a new instance of this address as I would like to be able to make it.
So I'm going to imagine that I can specify a street address one two three Beale Street, and I can also
specify an address to field like Apartment one A.
And I can specify a city, Walla Walla.
And a state like Washington and a zip code or postal code like nine 00 to one 00, which I know that's
in Beverly Hills, that's not in Washington, but that's Beverly Hills, California, but that's OK.
And a country United States.
And then let me go jump over to the database and remember what the other fields were.
So in addition to those common fields, we also have county and region, so county.
Fulton County and then region, and I don't remember what an example of a region was, let's jump into
the spreadsheet.
OK, so OK, so like Midwest, but whatever.
OK, so we'll say West West.
And actually, now let me let me show you something real quick here.
Actually, this region business here, if we're limiting ourselves just to the United States, then
this region business here actually might be a good opportunity to make use of an enum here because it
looks like the options here are pretty few.
It's not like these region areas are ever going to change, right?
As long as we're only talking about the U.S. So just to mix it up a little more and show you a few other
techniques that you could consider using when modeling classes that may map to a database.
In a situation like this, where you have a limited number of possibilities for a region sometimes in
in-room could be useful here.
So let's make this as an interim.
So to do that?
Let me scroll over and get myself a little more room.
What I'm going to do here is instead of hard coding a string like that, I'm going to pretend like there's
an enum called a region with a constant called West.
OK.
And now that's red.
Let me scroll up a bit.
OK.
And I'm actually going to tell it that we wanted to create an enum and I will have it create that in
whom, I guess, in the model package.
All right.
So now if I jump back over here again, well, now it seems that I referred to a constant of West.
And so if I put my cursor there, it should offer to add that constant.
And there it is, the very first thing it's offering to do create enum constant.
Less sure do that.
All right.
Very good.
And now if I jump over there, there it is.
And so then I can put a comma here and I can add the other constants as well.
So I'm I guess we have a north and south and east and northeast and the west east to the west.
The funny thing here in the Midwest also and hopefully that's all of them.
If not, we'll see.
All right.
So jumping back over now to the test?
OK, so let me close that off with a semicolon, and now we can let the A.D. create this address class
for us, some going to do an option return.
Now I'm also thinking of mixing things up a little bit more.
And how about we create this as a record rather than as a class?
As you may recall, records and classes are quite similar.
They're essentially the same thing, except records have a few conveniences for us.
We don't need to create our own getters and setters, and creating the record or defining the record
rather is kind of a hybrid mix up between creating a class and creating a constructor for the class.
OK, so records are trying to get rid of a lot of the common boilerplate code that we often end up generating
or writing for typical classes such as getters and setters constructor.
Slightly more useful to string methods and things of that sort.
All right.
So yeah, let's try that.
Honestly, I haven't tried this out before, so we may run into something that makes me realize that
this won't work the way that I was hoping it would.
But let's see.
All right.
So we'll have this put into the model package also.
And let's see.
So this first parameter is street address and then string is good.
And then the second one was address two and then the next one is city and then state and then postcode
and then country.
And then county.
And then region and then I can hit enter.
All right.
So that looks pretty OK, except for one thing now, since objects of this new address, class or record
are destined for their own dedicated table in the database, they're going to need an I.D. also.
And so let me add that on here, and that'll be of type long, and I will just call it I.D..
All right.
And now let's jump back over here.
And so now we're going to have an error because I haven't specified that I.D. and this is going to be
kind of interesting because I don't have an ID.
The database is going to generate that for us.
So what I'm going to see here is let's see if I can just provide a null.
OK.
So it is taking that.
So that's one thing I'm not super crazy about in this case of using a record is that as far as I can
tell, I maybe need to explicitly specify a null rather than just having a constructor that doesn't
take an I.D. But I can still have an ID field on the class, which is something I could do if we were
using a traditional class like the person here where I'm not specifying an I.D., but I can live with
that being null for now.
OK.
All right.
So now we've got an address for John and now we need to associate the address with John.
And we haven't done a whole lot of this kind of stuff so far in this course where we've associated different
instances of different types with each other.
But when you start getting into these database applications, this is where you may start to really
make these types of associations.
It's a very common thing to do, which is why have contrived this scenario?
All right.
So so what we can do is say something like John.
That said, I don't know, primary address to address.
Now the reason I'm referring to this property as primary address is because I'm kind of thinking we
might have a couple of address fields on the person class, maybe a primary, maybe a secondary or or
we could have home and business, you know, we could do something like that, in fact.
Yeah, maybe, maybe let's do that.
Let's do home.
Let's do home address.
OK.
Not that there's any difference.
There's no difference here.
But my point is that we could have multiple fields on the person class pointing back to one or more
addresses in the address table.
And this again gets into this whole relational thing that I was talking about in the last lesson.
OK, so we're we are relating one instance in Java now, in addition to the database in Java to another
instance and in Java.
All right.
So there's that.
So I'm going to do an option return to prompt the E to let me do something with this and I'm thinking
I'm going to go with the second option here, create property.
And I haven't really explained this super well.
Maybe you gleaned it.
Maybe it was obvious from the other times when I've done this.
So the difference between create method versus create property.
If I choose create method, the idea is going to be really dumb and it's just going to create one method
called set home address.
And that's it.
If I choose create property, though, the idea is going to understand that there should be a property
on the person class called home address and that most likely, that property should probably also have
both a getter and setter methods, right?
So the property option is the smarter option in this case where I'm kind of doing a TDD style and I'm
going backward, I'm kind of starting kind of towards the end and then working my way upfront, so to
speak, right?
So that's why I'm going to choose create property.
All right.
And so that puts me in the person class, and it has generated a set home address method that takes
an address as an input.
Now it hasn't imported it fully.
It's showing me the fully qualified class name at the moment, but that's OK.
And so I will accept OK on that.
And it's going to call this home address, and that's fine.
And then the field is this that home address and all of that is good.
And then it also created a get home address.
Right now, it's not happy with something.
Here are, I think the address record probably was created in the test package.
Let me see real quick here.
That's probably why this is red.
I should have been looking a little more closely.
Let me open up the package stuff here, and I bet, yeah, there it is, got created in the test folder
instead of the main folder.
All right, that's fine.
So I can literally just pick that up and move it.
If I just put my cursor on an address here, I can drag it right into the model package right there
and refactor.
And I'm sorry that you can't see my options here, but under this.
Question, do you wish to ignore them and continue, I'm going to click Continue.
OK, so just saying like, Hey, do I do I care that there are issues that are being found?
Yeah, I'm OK with it.
I'm going to click Continue.
Ah, oh.
And so now I also need to move.
Yeah, I wasn't paying close enough attention.
I also need to move the region.
All right.
So I'm going to grab that and move that into model also.
Yes.
Refactor that.
OK.
And so now if I jump back over to the person class, yeah, everything's happy.
All right.
And now, actually, I don't like having all of this package here.
So again, this is how you have to refer to classes if you don't import them, right?
So there's no import for this address at the moment.
So I'm going to just get rid of all of the the package part there, because now I don't need it anymore
and it makes the code look messy.
All right.
And now let's come up to the very top to make sure that we've got an address field here.
And yes, we do.
So this is all looking pretty good.
All right.
And so I will close the package pane there so I can have a little more room.
And now I can jump back over to the test.
Very good and no more red there.
OK, so then I guess let's just pretend like we take our repo and call save on John.
And let's say that we captured John saved person.
So now we need to somehow confirm that that address actually made it into the database as part of our
test, right?
We want to assert something.
So what I'm thinking of doing for now is let's just assert that this saved person will have an address
and then that address will have an ID that isn't null.
OK.
So we can assert that Saved Person Dot Get Home Address I.D. is greater than zero.
Let's start with that.
All right, so let's run this and make sure that it does, in fact, fail.
Okay.
They did fail, and it failed because the ID is actually null as it should be.
OK, very good.
And so now we can proceed to make this work.
Now I'm not going to play the cat and mouse game like we started off doing, because hopefully you understand
that that is the proper way to do TDD.
But in the interest of time, let's just get this going here.
All right.
So now there are at least two or three different ways that I can think of to implement this functionality.
But the first approach that I think we should attempt here is to start off by creating a repository
class specifically for the address.
So just as we have a people repository, which, by the way, I probably should have actually named
person repository, I think I should have made it plural.
We actually could rename that.
Maybe we will.
We should now also create an address repository.
OK.
So let's actually go ahead and just do that.
So I'm going to open up my Heyn over here and down here in repository.
I'm just going to go ahead and create a new one.
Now I have to be a little honest with you.
I'm not doing this as strictly with TDD as I could.
I'm going a little a few steps removed because I could justify in some ways just creating a test class
for this new address repository and going that way.
But I wanted to force myself to see how these addresses might actually be used in interacting with the
person instance.
And so I just had to kind of decide they're OK, well, where am I going to drive that?
Maybe it wouldn't be quite as appropriate for me to create a person and then save the person from within
an address repository test?
Maybe it would.
Maybe it wouldn't be.
But I already have a repository test here that deals with people and addresses don't really mean much
without a person.
So that's kind of my thinking here.
But you know, let's never spend so much time overthinking these concepts more than just getting actual
working code, right?
And let's have some tests, right, that are driving some coding somehow.
Right?
All right.
So over here in the repository, so I'm going to do a command in to create a new Java class, and this
class will be called address repository.
All right.
And so I'm creating that and now we get to really test out our credit repository because I'm going to
go ahead and extend the crud repository, and I'm going to have to specify a generic type of address
like so and then I need to import that.
There we go.
All right.
And so I've got red squiggles here.
Let me make some room here.
And the reason I have red squiggles is because some methods need to be implemented.
And so let me go ahead and just click on this.
And there are three methods, according to this, that need to be implemented.
And so I will click OK.
And there they are, so now the aide is telling me what I need to do now.
It looks like there's some more things here that I will need to do as well.
Oh yeah.
So also, I need to do something about the constructor.
All right.
So the idea is offering to create a constructor that matches the super.
So let's just let it do that.
Very nice.
So now we didn't need to write any code.
So that's just the constructor that takes the connection as an input and then it's going to pass it
up to the crud repository.
And you know what?
This has been bothering me for a while.
Just the fact that this is crud, all uppercase.
I thought I would like that, but now I'm not liking it as much.
So let me see what that looks like.
I'm going to refactor this.
You don't have to if you don't want to.
But let me see what this looks like if I make it just more whatever.
Yeah, you know what?
I think I kind of like the way that looks a little better.
I guess over the years, I've been exposed so much to people who take their acronyms in these names
and just make only the first letter uppercase.
And somehow the all caps crud incredibly positive was just a little too much for me.
Like I said, you don't have to do that if you don't want to just personal taste or whatever your team
tells you to do.
All right.
So now we need to actually implement these methods, and we're also going to have to specify some annotations
that actually do the work right.
So the one that we're going to care about for right now is mapping for save, right?
So here we're going to be given an address as an input and a prepared statement, and our job is to
set the various data of the address on that prepared statement.
OK.
So maybe first off, we may need to start off with creating our sequel to do an insert into the address
table.
So let's see what that might look like at school and by the way, the operation type I can specified
anywhere.
So we were putting it at the end, I'll put it at the beginning.
It doesn't really matter.
Since they're named, they can go anywhere.
Operation type will be saved.
All right.
And then the value will be, and I'm just going to type it out right here explicitly.
In fact, you know what?
I'm going to use a tax block to do it because I didn't show that before either insert into addresses
and let me go back over to the database.
And I'm just going to drill into the address table this way and then look at the column names by clicking
on columns here and then expanding that.
OK, so I got street address and address to so.
Street address, comma.
Address to city, state postcode, county region and country.
All right.
And then I think on a new line, I'm going to say values and then this is just going to be a bunch of
question marks, right?
One two three four five six is it C?
One two three four five six seven eight one two three four, five, six, seven and eight.
All right, so there's our insert statement.
So now that we know what we're dealing with now, we can come down here and start mapping.
So I'm going to do a prepared statement piece set string and the first parameter will be parameter one,
which is the street address.
So then Entity Dot Street.
Oops.
Street address.
Like so and then start such a string to entity and that is addressed to address to every girl.
And that search string.
For three, which is the city entity, the city.
Piece that said string four parameter for which is the state.
Search string parameter five, which is post code.
Yes, search string parameters six.
Entity, which is county passed that search string parameter seven, which is Entity Dot region.
Now, this won't be quite as straightforward as the other fields because the other fields are strings
and region is actually an enum.
But never fear this is actually pretty easy to do.
All we need to do is then call the two string method, and you may recall that within rooms by default,
when you call the two string method on an enum constant, all you get is the constant and string form.
And when we have to reconstitute the enum from a string, which we will need to do when we start loading
the addresses back from the database, enum classes have a method where we can go in that direction,
too.
All right, so not a problem.
There we go.
And so now we've got the string representation of the Enum.
And if you don't know what I mean, let me just show you explicitly here.
OK, so if we jump into the region, basically these constants here will just be turned into strings
and that's what we're going to actually store in the database.
And so oh, and then one more one more piece that string parameter eight entity dot country, right?
There we go.
All right.
So we've got this much created.
Now we need to consider, OK, what are we actually going to do with this new address repository?
Right now, it's just sitting out here kind of orphaned.
There's no class anywhere else.
That's instantiating this repository so that it can actually be utilized, right?
So what I have in mind here is let's jump over to the people repository.
And let's take a look at where we're saving people right now, so this is how we're currently saving
a person.
We take that person as an input and then we map all their fields, right?
So here's some things that we need to consider now.
So if you recall from our last lesson where we created the address table and we had to deal with the
foreign key and the exported key and all of that stuff, right?
And I said that the way we were modeling this relationship in the in the database for now, at least
because there are multiple ways to model this, but the way we're doing it for now is that a person's
primary address and by the way, that reminds me we did call that primary address in the database so
we can change that name.
The person's primary address field will contain the idea of an address.
OK, so the primary address field of the person table will point to an address record in the address
table.
OK.
That's important for us to keep in mind, because that means we will need to save an address to the
database and get its ID.
It's generated ID before we save a person.
OK?
And so that's where all of this is basically happening right here.
OK.
So that means if there is an address on a person instance like here, we will need to save that address
first.
Then we should hopefully be able to get our hands on the idea of that address.
And then we can associate that address his ID with another field here.
OK.
Does that make sense?
So first things first, though, let's go rename the address column in the database.
All right.
So here we are back in the database and let's see here we will jump into the sequel here, and we will
just rename that column.
So if you know that's what you need to do, but you don't quite remember how to do it, I will show
you how to find it again in here.
So let's jump up to the top here.
We want to go to reference commands.
I'm in the H2 documentation here commands, and now you're going to need to remember a few things you
know that you're wanting to change a column name, right?
So typically that's that's often going to relate to altering something.
OK.
So if we look through this list here, you can see that there's Altar Table Altar column.
So that's a good bet that that's kind of along the lines of where we want to be.
So I'm going to click on that Altar Table Altar column, and before we dig all the way into this, we
can just take a quick look here and make sure that we're on the right track, right?
So we're altering a table and then we're specifying a column name, and there we go.
Right there there's a rename option.
So this is this is the right path.
All right.
So we want to do an altar table altar column.
So over here we'll say altar table and the table name is people, then altar column and then the column
name is currently what was it, primary address?
Right.
So let's make sure that's right.
Altar table table name.
Altar Table People.
Then Altar column column name.
Altar column.
And then there's our column name, primary address and then any one of these.
So we want rename to.
Rename two and then just decide on a name.
And so we'll say home address.
Let's try that and see if it just works.
Looks like it works.
All right.
And so now we can jump back over here to the objects, and now we're going to jump over here to the
people table.
And let's just we're already on columns to show the column names.
And there we go.
Home address is now the name of that field.
So we're good there.
All right.
So now jump into the idea here.
So the first thing we're going to want to do here is let's get our hands on this new address, assuming
that it has actually been set on the entity.
So we would say entity that get home address.
There it is.
And I think what we're going to want to do here is simply save it using the address repository.
So that means now that we need to get our hands on the address repository somehow.
Now there are a couple of ways that we could go about doing this.
The really, really simple way is that we could just create an instance of the address repository right
here in the people repository, right?
In fact, here I'll just do it.
So we could say something like private address repo repository.
Right?
Like so and I could just instantiated in line right here, although that's going to be problematic a
bit if we tried to do it in line because it's constructor requires a connection, so that's probably
not the best place that we'd be able to do that.
So maybe we'd just set that to null another place that we could do it and this would be better would
be right here in the constructor.
Right?
So we could say address repository equals new address, repository instance and then pass in our connection.
We absolutely can do this.
Now there is a bit of a philosophical problem with doing this, and I might as well go ahead and introduce
it to you now because you're never going to hear the end of this in the Java development world.
If we do this in live production code like what we're writing here.
We are very tightly coupling these two repository classes and tightly coupling means what it sounds
like.
It means we're really intrinsically linking these two classes now in real life.
They need to be linked, right?
I want to have this relationship because really, what I want to do at the end of the day is come down
here and say something like address repository, dot save.
That's what I want to do, right, and and in fact, I just did it right.
So that's exactly what I want.
And in fact, I'll even finish this bit here, and I even want to capture that address as a saved address
so that I can make sure that I can pull the ID out of it.
So let's go ahead and finish this code.
And then I'll come back to telling you why the way I'm doing it right now is not the best way.
OK.
All right.
So now what I'm going to want to do here is I'm going to need to modify the Save sequel here.
So currently we're inserting into people first name, last name, date of birth, salary and email,
and now we have also this.
Home address, right?
So I'm going to add one more question mark now, like so and so that's now a sixth, right?
One two three four five six.
Yes, that's a sixth parameter.
And so now down here, I can do that set.
Now this is going to be a long because it's going to be the ID of the address that just got saved,
right?
So set long and this is going to be parameter six.
And now, instead of referring to entity, I'm going to refer to saved address Dot ID.
That's what we want.
Does that make sense?
So we need to save the address first and the act of saving the address.
Hopefully, if all of our code works correctly, which we'll find out shortly, if that all works correctly
will get a saved address back out of it, which will eventually have an ID, though I think we're going
to run into a problem.
I'm anticipating it, but I know what that problem will be.
All right.
But in theory, when everything is working correctly to saved address will now have an I.D. on it,
and then we will just pull that ID out, which will be along and then associate it with the home address
column of the person instance that we are saving.
That's what we want to do.
All right.
Now you know what, in fact, I think what I'm going to do, we're going to just leave this like it
is right here where I'm just instantiating this address repository for right now, because I know I'm
already hitting you with a lot of things.
So let's just leave that as it is for right now, but we're going to come back to that.
All right.
Now we're not going to bother with loading and all of that right now.
We'll do that in other lessons, OK?
Let's just see if we can just get this much to work.
All right.
So let's jump back over to the test and let's run this and see what happened so far.
Still fails.
And let's see what we're getting here.
Cannot invoke long value because the return value of ID is null.
Now let's see where this is happening, and this is kind of what I was anticipating.
All right.
In the map for Save Method Online 40.
So let me click on that.
OK?
All right.
So this is simply complaining that I cannot bind this ID to type long because the ID is null, which
it shouldn't be if our code were working correctly.
This, this should not actually be null.
Right?
But I was anticipating that it would be.
Now I was thinking that we'd get an error earlier in the process, though that would tell us a little
bit more about the fact that that was null.
But apparently, we're not getting that.
So let me just cut to the chase and say what I think is actually happening here.
This is null because we actually need to place an at ID annotation in our address class record to designate
which property is for IDs.
Let me show you what I mean, if you may have forgotten so if we jump into the person entity class.
Remember this guy right here?
We need the sanitation in order to let our crud repository framework know that this field right here
is our ID field, right?
And that way, the framework knows what field to go and set the I.D. on when it retrieves it from the
database and all of that good stuff, right?
But currently, our new address record doesn't have one of these.
And so now we're going to run into an interesting question, which is can we somehow annotate this on
a record which doesn't have explicit fields and will reflection work the same way even if we could?
So I honestly don't know.
Let's go find out.
So let's jump over to the address class.
Sorry.
Address record, and what I'm thinking to try here is just putting in at ID annotation right here and
see if that works, OK, so nothing's complaining about it here.
Let's see what happens.
Let's just try running this again.
All right.
Still got a failure?
Let's see if it's the same failure unable to set it filled.
They are.
So that's the error that I was originally expecting to get.
Unable to set it filled value set, I'd by annotation.
So if we jump into the credit repository line 101, here we go.
So here we're iterating over all of the fields looking for any fields that are annotated with our ID
annotation.
And if we find one, we set our value on it.
But if we don't find one, then we actually do throw a runtime exception to tell us that we were unable
to do so and we are unable to do so because records are immutable.
I've mentioned this before, but basically immutability means that an object can't be changed after
it has been created.
So when we create a record, we call it the constructor and we pass in all the necessary properties
after those properties have been set.
They can't be changed afterwards.
And if you notice here in our code online 104, we're actually trying to access the ID field or the
field that was annotated with an ID annotation and set a new value on that that is not permitted, even
with the set accessible call on line one or two.
So that's the reason why this isn't going to work and so probably going to have to implement this in
a different way.
So I think in order to get around this for right now, what I think we're going to do is just convert
this record back into a regular class.
And thankfully, we can do that really easily because we don't have to do anything.
The 80 can do it for us.
So what we can actually do here is just click on the address name here and then we get the little light
bulb right and I can click on this little light bulb and look at that right there.
Convert record to class, and I'm just going to click on it right here on the words and look at that
and look at the fact that in the expansion here, it even went ahead and put the ID annotation properly
on the field.
So we tried a little record experiment.
I do want to try that again, but we'll need to figure out what we need to do to make that work.
And I don't want to hold this up right now.
OK.
So let's try running that test again.
Hey, look at that.
It's green, right?
Someone to jump into this test here.
Honestly, I'm kind of curious what the ID actually is, and I'd love to actually see it in the database.
So in fact, I'll tell you what, I'm going to go ahead and commit this.
We'll do a connection commit and we'll have to address the exception that can be thrown here.
So I'll just add that to the signature there.
And let's run that one more time, and this will allow a new address and the new person to actually
be permanently saved now so that I can find this record more easily.
The let me call it something distinctive.
All right.
So I'm putting four Z's on the end of the first name there, and let's run that again.
So now I'm going to go ahead and get rid of that commit because I don't want to accidentally keep doing
that or forget to remove it later.
And now let's jump in to squirrel, and let's just confirm what we see here.
All right.
So first, let's just take a quick peek in the address table, select everything from addresses.
And right now, there shouldn't be, but I think there should only be like one record in here.
So I think I'm OK to just do a select everything.
There it is, one to three, Bill.
Yeah, that's that's looking legit.
And so then let's see the record in the people table.
So select everything from people where and now what we could do is something like where home address
equals four, because the ID here is four.
Right?
So let's try that.
There he is, John.
So that worked wonderfully.
Didn't it?
Totally worked.
All right.
So that is more than enough for this lesson.
In the next lesson, we're going to continue working on this.
There's so many things that we could do.
Don't worry, we're not going to do them all.
But I just want you to really have a decent understanding of these relationships that can exist between
tables and how we can map them to and from our Java code.
So with that, I will see you in the next one.