All right, so in the last lesson, we were able to save and address as part of a person, so we saved
the person who had an address and the saving of the address got cascaded with the saving of the person,
which was pretty cool.
But now it's time to rain on our parade a little bit because we're now going to run all of the tests
and let's see what happens when we do that.
All right.
So here we are back in the people repository tests and I'm coming up here to the very top and and we're
just going to run all of these tests.
Let's see.
Ouch.
Let's see here, seven failed and two passed, so not great.
So let's click on any one of these failed tests and see if we can figure out what what happened here
cannot invoke the address that street address because entity is null.
And that is happening in the address repository in the map for safe method.
So the address repository?
OK, so and OK.
So this method got called and it was passed an entity of an address.
And then the various properties of this entity were trying to be bound to the prepared statement and
they couldn't be bound because this entity was null.
That's what this is saying, because entity is null.
Right?
Let's see what method was calling that.
So the code repository that save, which is just our kind of generic method there in the in the parent
class.
So I don't think that's going to tell us much.
But look here now the people repository map for save.
Now let's see that one.
Ah, OK, so this is the new code that we added to first save an address before we go and try to save
an actual person.
And so, yeah, of course, in most in all of these other tests, there is no address, even existing,
right?
We never created an address and associated it with the person and therefore the call to get home address
would result in a null.
And then we get the error that we're getting here, right?
Because you can't do this.
So the question is, what do we want to do about this?
Right?
So one thing that we could do is just check if the get home address returns a null and if it is null,
then don't do any of this at all.
Right?
And then if we don't do any of that, then we'd have to also come down here and I guess maybe not do
any of that either.
Something along those lines, right?
So let's see what that would look like if we were to do it that way.
All right.
So I think what we can do then is do an option command T or control alt T.
And we can surround this block of this line with an if statement, which is number one in our surround
with options here.
So we can do that and then we can say maybe if entity.
That was it.
Get out, get home address is not equal to null, then it can proceed to do all of that.
And let me make some room here.
So that should prevent any attempt at saving a home address if there is no home address.
Right.
But then we're also going to have to address this line down here where we're trying to extract the I.D.
from the home address to associated with the person.
Now, one thing that we could possibly do here would be to just consolidate all of this conditional
stuff about the home address altogether.
And what I mean by that is even though I have all of these parameter bindings in order one, two, three,
four, five and six, we could conceivably just move this line up like so that's one thing we could
do, or we could even grab all of this and move all of this down, which might be a little better because
if we do have an address, then the saving only has to happen before we try to associate the address
as a ID with the person, as we're doing here on Line forty two now, the rest of this is fine, as
is.
So this approach should work, actually.
Let's go ahead and try it out and see.
So let me open back up our tests here, and I'm just going to rerun everything and let's see what happens
now.
OK, well, all right.
OK, well, we got one more than we had before.
OK, so not much better.
Let's click on this one.
And so now what is our issue?
Parameter number six is Ah.
OK, so now we've got an issue.
So I was actually a little bit wrong.
I had forgotten that this sixth parameter is lining up with the six hardcoded parameters that our insert
statement is expecting.
So we cannot just conditionally set this value.
It has to be set to something with the way we're doing things right now.
So one thing we could do in that case is maybe provide an else and then call an alternative set method
here.
Now I think we're going to have to be a little careful here because let me show you this if we just
try to do that set long.
Obviously, the question is will set it to what right?
What can we set this to?
We don't have an ID of a saved address at this point, right?
And under some circumstances, we might have just made up an address like, for example, a negative
one.
A lot of the times you'll see programmers use negative one or some value like that to indicate that
I don't have a legitimate value, so I'm just going to put a negative value in here.
You'll see programmers do that from time to time.
And while I think that should work fine from the code's perspective, the database isn't going to like
that because if you recall, we created a foreign key constraint on the people table.
And what that foreign key constraint tells the database is that if you do supply an ID here, so we
don't have to supply an ID in the database for this column on the people table.
But if we do that, it had better be a legitimate ID of a legitimate address in the addresses table.
That's what the foreign key constraint is constraining us to.
And so negative one would not be a valid address in the address table.
It will never be a valid address unless we were to go in there and manually put one in because we just
wanted to make this work.
So that's not going to work as is.
So what I'm wondering about, though, is maybe instead of calling set long here, perhaps we could
call set object, which is more generic.
And then instead of trying to set this value as an integer, perhaps we could get away with just setting
it to null, which is what it already is in the database anyway, when we don't actually have a foreign
key pointing to an actual object.
So in other words, we would essentially just let it continue being null, which is what it would default
to being anyway.
So let's try that and see if this will help.
OK.
OK, so that looks much, much better, and, you know, I just realized something, by the way, while
all of these tests were running.
We have a we have a can find all test here, and it literally calls Repot find all.
And as you know, we now have loaded in all five million records into the database.
So this test looks like it got ignored, and I'm guessing it probably got ignored because it was running
too long.
So that's something else that we're going to want to reconsider here now that we've got five million
records in the database.
And in fact, I think what we may want to go ahead and do for right now is just to disable this test
until we may choose to come back at a later date and see what we want to do with this.
And very likely we may not do anything with it.
I mean, you get what it's doing.
We know how it does work, but yeah, maybe we don't want to be calling that anymore with five million
records.
All right.
But other than that, everything is working now, right?
So let's jump back over here now to our system under test, which is the people repository class.
All right.
So we were able to make that work now.
However, now I want to raise a question for you.
You know, we learned about optional, right?
And I mentioned that options exist in large part because doing these kinds of null checks is often not
considered cool.
It's not what the cool kids do anymore.
So now I think I want to challenge you.
Can you think of a way to revise our project a little bit so that we don't have to do these explicit
null checks?
Maybe by using optional do you want to take up that challenge?
If so, then go ahead and parse the lesson and see what you can do.
You know, it's nice to try to combine a lot of our techniques that we've learned throughout this course
to see how we can write real code.
And by the way, I mean, this is getting into some real code in many ways.
Now I will say this, I don't think there are too many teams in the world today that are writing this
much low level JTBC code anymore.
I'm sure there are a few for sure, but there are honestly frameworks that do what we're doing here
in a much more sophisticated way than what we're doing here.
And let me just remind you the reason that we're writing this little poor man's framework and doing
all of this JBC stuff is so that in later courses where you will encounter these very popular frameworks
for working with the database more efficiently and even more easily than this, you'll have a better
understanding of what those frameworks are doing.
OK.
All right.
So anyway, with that being said, if you want to take up this challenge, go ahead and parse the lesson
and try changing this over to use optional so that you can get away from having to do this type of explicit
null check and then join back with me and see how I will do it.
All right.
So hopefully, you tried that and hopefully you even got it.
So now let me try.
All right.
So the first thing I would do is I would go in and change list.
See, where am I going here?
I would go into the person class, which is here, and I would change our address field to no longer
be an address field, but instead to be an optional address.
That's the first thing I would do.
All right.
So if we come down to this field and you right click on the type of address here, you right click on
that and then come down here to refactor.
You can actually migrate or change that data type right here.
Or you could do a shift command F6.
So there's a keyboard shortcut that even I hadn't memorized.
All right.
So I'm going to select type migration.
And what this is going to allow me to do is to change this data type from address to an optional other
address.
So migrate type of filled home address, address two.
So the way I'm going to do this, I think, is just to type right over this.
I'm going to type optional.
Address like, sir and I'm going to go ahead and import that.
Just like I would in the regular Ed, OK, and then I'm going to click Refactor and now it's asking
me, where do I want this to this change to occur, by the way, and I am telling it in all places.
OK, so I'm going to go ahead and click Refactor here.
So, OK, so now I'm getting an error where it's just telling me the various places within the project
where it where it no longer will make sense to deal with an optional where it had been expecting an
address.
That's OK.
I want it to break so that I can see where I need to go, so I'm going to come down here to the button
that you can't see that says ignore.
I'm going to tell it simply to ignore these errors for right now.
I will address them one at a time.
OK, so I'm going to click Ignore.
OK, so now I've got my optional address and I can scroll down here towards the bottom and just double
check that yes, indeed, I am now returning an optional address and I am taking an optional address
now.
I actually don't think I want that.
I think I actually want to take on this set home address, just the regular address, and then I will
deal with it internally.
OK, and now now you get to see one of those places where having the getter and setter, especially
here, the center can actually bring some value in that I can have the setter accept the regular address
and then inside of its implementation, we will convert that to an optional just as a convenience,
if you will.
So we will let that be a regular address, and then here we can do an optional of Nullarbor because
I don't know what people would actually be passing in here.
They might pass in a legit address.
Somebody might call this code at some point and pass in a null.
And I don't want the whole entire program to blow up because of that.
So I'm going to let this method be kind of Nullarbor like so.
All right.
And so that makes that a little more convenient to use.
And so now I've got an error here because the ad got a little overzealous.
And so now I need to fix that.
So I'm just going to get rid of that and make this back into just a regular address here.
All right.
And then we've got an area down here because now when we call saved the person that get home address
this is returning an optional of an address.
And so there is no date that ID on an optional.
And so if I want the Real ID, I will have to dig in one level deeper and I am going to go ahead and
just call get.
Because again, I'm in a test and I control all of the parameters here.
And so I know that within this test, there should always be an address.
And if there isn't one, then this should break and blow up badly because my assumptions of of everything
would be completely wrong in that case.
So I'm good with calling get here so that it can get at that ID.
All right now to go find all of the other places that are having problems, I can actually rebuild the
projects.
I'm going to do a command F9.
All right.
And that went ahead and opened up an error right here.
Let's see now.
Where is this?
This is in the people repository.
OK, so we're right here in this code.
All right.
So now we're trying to save the address.
And of course, we're calling in to T Get Home address, which is now returning an optional of an address
instead of a regular address now.
OK, so maybe one easy thing we could do here would be to first change what we're checking for because
we're no longer going to be checking for Noel, right?
Instead, we can check something like.
Is present right, if home address is present, then we can come down here and now we can safely call
get right because we're doing this check for is present first.
We can then come down here and just call again.
This is a pattern where it's safe to call just again because you did this check first, right?
And this may actually be about the most straightforward thing that we can do in this particular case.
Now, I would have preferred honestly to have done one of the more fancy optional things like a stream
or a map, or if present or something like that.
However, we would have run into a problem, which is that when we tried to call pass, that set long
set, long throws an exception and it's a checked exception and checked exceptions don't play nicely
within streams or optional stream stream like API calls and all of that.
So we would have had to then wrap this stuff here, or at least or at least this call here within another
try catch, which is already within its own try catch, which starts to look kind of ugly because really,
truly, this entire map for save is kind of happening within its own try catch, which we don't see
here.
It's inside of the method that calls Map for Save, which lives up in the superclass right up in the
crud repository class itself.
So that would have been a few too many embedded try catches for my taste.
And this is OK.
It's not my favorite, but this is OK.
All right, so I'm going to do another build here just to make sure I got everything.
So another command f nine or control f nine.
All right.
So that all looks good there.
So now let me open back up the tests and run them all again and see if everything is still happy.
Even with that, switch over to using optional.
And no, it's not happy at all.
All right, so let's see what we've got now.
Can't invoke optional.
That is present because the return value of person that get home address is null.
Ah, oh yes.
Yes, yes.
OK, so now the problem is that although we have changed the home address field of the person class
to be of type optional, optional itself is an object and therefore it still has to exist even if it
doesn't have anything in it.
Let me show you what I mean here.
So we'll jump back over here to the person class.
OK, so home address.
OK.
So if we were to just create a person right now and do nothing else, this field would be null.
It wouldn't be optional.
It would just be null because we didn't set anything on it at all.
Right.
And that's what this is complaining about.
Person I get home address is still null right now, and it's going to be null for all of the methods
for all of the tests where we don't explicitly try to create an address.
So one thing that we can do really easily to resolve this issue is really just to initialize this field
to an empty optional so we can do optional dot empty.
And so that gives us literally an empty optional of an address.
OK.
There won't be an actual address in there.
It just won't be null anymore.
It'll be empty now.
OK.
So let's run all of these tests again.
There we go.
And so now everything is passing and we're using optional instead of null.
And so one more time, let's jump back over into the people repository and take another look at this
code one more time.
OK, so we're now checking first if we've got an address present.
Then go ahead and save it.
Get that I.D. and now use that I.D. over here.
Otherwise, just set the sixth parameter, which which corresponds to the home address column in the
people table just set that foreign key to null, as that makes sense.
All right.
So that's going to wrap up this lesson and we will do some more things with this address field because
we're eventually going to have to also retrieve addresses.
So we've got more to look forward to and some really neat techniques that I want to show you when it
comes to retrieving as well.
So I'll see you in the next one.