Hello and welcome back.
This is going to be a little bit of a different kind of a lesson, if you will.
I didn't plan for it to be a lesson at all and in fact, I wasn't even planning to make this type of
video.
I was actually working on the exercises for section eight of the course.
And when I started working specifically on exercise eight of the course, I started going down a path
of creating basically a miniature project just for that exercise.
And I realized that it was so involved that I should probably step back and actually make at least one
full video explaining all of my solutions for exercise.
Eight.
And all of these sub exercises under it, of which there are quite a large number of.
So this lesson will be more of a walk through my solutions for exercise aid of Section eight.
As such, I would say that if you are planning to actually do those exercises yourself and you have
not done them yet, I would encourage you probably to stop watching this video right now and go attempt
to those exercises first and then come back to this video after you've either completed them or given
up because you weren't sure how to how to go about them.
Now that being said, I'm going to try first in this in this video to just explain a little bit of the
background on chess and how it works.
So you could stick around for that part.
But when I start jumping into the code and the solutions for the code, like I said, if you're planning
to actually do these exercises yourself, then I would strongly recommend that you not watch this video
until you've tried the exercises.
And you know, one big reason I'm saying that is is for your benefit.
You will learn best if you attempt to do these exercises independently on your own first.
And even if you don't accomplish them, even if you get stuck.
The thought process of struggling through how to implement those exercises will help you to understand
my explanations better when you see how I did it.
So you won't get as much out of out of the exercises if you just watch this.
And in fact, if you just watch what I'm about to show now, that won't really be any different from
you watching how I've been doing all of the other coding throughout the entire course up until this
point.
All right.
So let me give you a quick little background.
Then I chose to use chess as a domain to create these exercises around because chess is a very world
famous game.
A lot of people know at least a little bit about how to play it, though many people are not experts,
including myself.
And it is a game that is that has what I call a rich domain.
That means that there are a good number of pieces, a good number of nouns associated in the chess domain,
and there's a lot of business logic.
Now, since we're talking about a game, usually we won't call that business logic.
We might call it game logic, but those are the rules of the game.
So it has a pretty rich set of game rules or business logic.
And one problem that I've seen in a lot of books that try to teach technical things like programming
or in online courses is that their examples are usually either way too simple so that they don't really
fully prepare you for work in the real world.
Or they're way too complicated, in which case they go right over everybody's head.
And a lot of beginners like you presumably are don't really understand what's going on.
So I was hoping that this domain of chess would be a good middle of the road.
Perhaps where the rules are not super simplistic, they can get a little bit involved, but not to the
point of being rocket science.
So you'll have to be the judge of whether or not I hit the mark in getting a domain that's kind of somewhere
in the middle.
Not too easy, not too hard.
So I will let you know that in creating the solutions for these exercises, even I had to think a bit
on how I thought it would be best to solve some of these exercises.
OK.
So if you're thinking that you're meant to get through all of these exercises under exercise eight quickly,
like in an hour or something?
I doubt that that's realistic at all.
I suspect that for many of you, these exercises could take a week, maybe even take a couple of weeks
for some of you.
Some of you may be able to do them in a day or two.
I don't know.
It just depends on how you go about doing it and what your desired end goal is.
My desired end goal is usually to create.
Code that is concise and relatively easy to understand, but but still relatively simple looking at
the same time.
And that's actually not a very easy thing to do when you're dealing with a non-trivial domain like chess.
So I myself have worked on these solutions actually over the course of two or three days, and I will
even admit that at one point I didn't like my approach, and so I actually deleted everything and recreated
it all from scratch.
Now, when I recreated it, I recreated it pretty quickly because I had already worked out a lot of
what I wanted there.
But my point here is that even I, a seasoned Java developer, had to put some serious thought into
how I wanted to model this chess domain for these exercises.
It was not just elementary school for me, OK?
I really did put some thought into it.
And so I presume you two will need to put some significant thought into your domain and how your modeling
classes and implementing some of the methods here.
All right.
So the first thing we're going to do, though, is just to make sure we're all on the same page.
I'm going to just do a very quick review of some of the basics of how chess works so that I can just
make sure that we're all on the same page with this.
OK, so here I have a little chess board open up and this is actually from Wikipedia.
So if you just you go to Wikipedia and look up chess, and I think I included a link, in fact, to
a part of the chess article on Wikipedia that tells you some of the basic rules and how some of the
main pieces that we're going to be modeling actually move on on the board.
OK.
So anyway, here is a typical chess board.
We've got the black pieces now.
They're not showing the white pieces, but if you can imagine that this is a mirror here, then down
here in these rows, one in two, you'd have white chess pieces that mirror the black pieces that we're
seeing up here.
OK.
And on this particular board, we've got these letters going down here along the x axis and then we've
got numbers going along the y axis here.
And by using these letters and numbers, we are able to label all of the squares on the chess board.
So we see here that this square is a one.
This is B because there's B and there's two there, right?
D four, D and four.
So anyone who's been through probably middle school should understand how that is working.
This is part of what is called chess notation.
And it is simply a way for us to specify what square on the board we may be talking about.
OK.
All right.
Now there are several pieces in chess.
We're not going to get into all of them now and in the exercises of exercise.
Eight, I'm really only focused on two of the pieces Pons, which are these pieces here on Row seven
and Knights, which are which is this horse looking piece right here at the G8 and there's another one
here at G8.
OK.
The reason I chose these two pieces is because to me, they represent a little bit of a range in complexity.
Pons might arguably be the simplest piece on the chessboard.
They are certainly worth the least in terms of points, and they have fairly simplistic movements that
they can make.
Most of the time, they can only move one square at a time forward, except for on their initial move
at the very beginning of the game.
If the player chooses to, the player can choose to move upon two squares forward just on the very first
move.
It's up to the player, though it can move one square forward or two squares forward after that initial
movement, though, all subsequent moves have to be one square forward unless the pawn is capturing
an enemy and really quickly, I will just say, let us pretend that there is a white piece right here
on Square D6 six in that case.
This pawn on C7 or this pawn on E7 could choose to move diagonally one square to here and take or capture
that white piece.
OK, that is the one time when pawns can move diagonally.
However, even then, they are only allowed to move one square diagonally.
Pons cannot capture an enemy piece that is directly in front of them.
They can only capture diagonally.
All right.
And then the night.
I chose for us to also work on modeling the night because the night has perhaps the strangest type of
movement nights do not move just simplistically forward or sideways or sideways or diagonally.
They actually move in a pattern of two squares and then one square so they can move two squares forward
and then one square to the right, two squares forward, or one square to the left or two squares sideways
and one square forward, two squares sideways and one square backward or one square, and then two squares
forward.
So as long as their movement is some combination of one and two or two and one in any direction other
than diagonal, they are generally allowed to make that movement and they make the same movement, whether
they're just traveling or capturing a piece, OK?
Unlike pawn, when pawns are just simply traveling, they can only move forward when they're capturing.
They can only move diagonally.
However, knights can move in this to slash one configuration or one slash two configuration for both
movement and for capturing.
OK, one other thing I should note, I think, is that pawns cannot move backward, generally speaking.
So once upon has moved forward, he cannot then back up.
So he has to just keep moving forward or diagonally to capture an enemy.
Knights, on the other hand, can move all over the place.
They can go backward and forward and sideways as long as it's in their two squares and then one square
or one square and then two square type of L pattern.
OK, so I think that might be about enough for us to jump in to these exercises.
All right.
So let's jump into the code now.
So again, fair warning.
If you are planning to do these exercises, then you haven't done them yet.
You should probably stop now.
Go do the exercises and then come back here after you've done them, and I'll see you in a week or a
month or a year, and hopefully it won't take you that long.
All right.
OK, so I'm going to actually start off here in the exercise guide here.
And you see the same picture, in fact, that we were just looking at.
So here we are in exercise eight and you'll see that I've broken it up into these sub exercises.
So 8.1, 8.2, et cetera, et cetera.
OK.
So what we're going to do, I think, is just go through these exercises one at a time and see how I
solution them.
So starting here with exercise one, you'll need to create classes for a chessboard and a pawn, per
the J Unit test can add PON Method Write Code to allow an instance of the -- class to be added to
an instance of the chess board.
Add a square on the board using chess notation such as A1, C three, etc. then assert that the PON
is actually at that location on the board by calling a method on the board to retrieve a piece by location.
So what I'm basically saying is write some code that lets you model a chessboard and a pawn and then
programmatically place an instance of a pawn somewhere on the board.
So like at D7, for example, and then ask the board, What piece is that B7?
That way, you can make sure that you actually place the piece there.
OK, so I know it might seem kind of trivial, but in order to do this correctly, you actually have
to implement a number of things.
All right.
So that's what that exercise is asking you to do.
So let's go see how I did this.
OK, so here we are in my test and I used TDD for this, though I will admit that I wasn't 120 percent
strict in how I did TDD, but I did generally start off with a test, created classes only as I needed
to.
Where I wasn't so strict was that I didn't always do the cat and mouse game extensively throughout throughout
my TDD exercise because I have a lot of coding that I have to do for you guys, and I just don't have
the time to sit there and go through all of that while nobody's watching.
So just being honest.
OK.
But you should do it correctly.
All right.
So here's my first test can add punch.
So I just wrote this test and then I said, OK, I'm going to need something that represents a chessboard
and I'm going to need something that represents upon.
So as you know, by now, when we are dealing with modeling concepts in Java, generally speaking,
the nouns of the domain that we are modeling for which in this case would be chess typically will become
classes.
So I.
Third to a class called chessboard.
I could have named this anything, but I thought chess board would be a good logical name.
I could have called it bored or anything, really.
And then I decided to name the instance of my chess board simply bored because I didn't want to have
to type out the whole world chess board.
And so here I am, creating that new instance.
OK, now when I first did this, there was no real functionality here.
All I did was simply create a class called chess board that initially at this point had nothing in it.
Then I did the same thing for another class of pawn.
Right?
So this is me modeling this chess piece right here called a pawn.
All right.
Now, actually, a little bit later on, I didn't do this initially, but a little later on I realized
that I would need to be able to describe what color the piece was.
So I'm not going to talk about this too much right now, and we'll come back to that a little bit later
when it actually comes up.
OK.
But I'm just pointing that out.
All right.
And then I envisioned that, OK, if I've got this thing called a chess board and I've got a pawn,
I want to somehow place a pawn somewhere on this board.
And so what I imagined was that I would have an add method where I could say, Hey, board, hey, chess
board, let me add a pawn to you at some coordinates, OK?
And so this is me doing that.
I'm I referred to a method called Add, and then I passed in my pawn with a comma.
And then a string representing the chess notation or the location on the chess board.
So here I'm referring to Square a two, which would be here a to sit right there.
So this would be a pawn placed right here, which would be the mirror of this pawn right here, by the
way.
All right.
So I'm I'm trying to place a piece at a to a pawn at a.
Then I turn around and I want to basically ask the board, Hey, chess board, what piece?
What chess piece do I have at coordinates a two?
So I imagined that I could have a method called get peace at coordinates, and I just shortened that
to co-ords.
Right?
But that stands for coordinates where I could pass in some coordinates and then it would give me back
a chess piece.
And if I got that chess piece back, I could capture it in a variable like I'm doing here for right
now, I'm going to ignore the fact that I'm casting it.
We'll talk about that a little bit later as well.
All right.
So if there is a piece of a, I would be capturing it into this variable.
And then finally, I would assert that the pond that I started with is equal to the pond that I got
back right.
So in other words, I placed upon at eight two, and then I asked the chess board, Give me whatever
piece is that a two?
And then I'm testing that this thing that I put at a two is the same thing that I got back from the
chess board at a two.
They should be equal.
I think that should make a lot of sense, right?
So it was easy to write the test a little bit more work to actually make it pass properly.
So now let's dig in on that.
We'll start here with the add method.
So I'm going to jump into the add method now.
So this method is taking something called a chess piece and then returning chess coordinates.
Now you might have thought that I would be passing in something called a pawn.
And if I recall correctly, when I actually wrote that first test, I may have actually modeled this
to just take a pawn.
However, I'm going to go ahead and give you a little bit of insight into something now.
Later on, I am also going to want to call add to add in other types of pieces, namely a night.
And if I had made this first parameter of type pawn specifically, then I wouldn't be able to use this
same add method to also add in a night.
I would have had to create a second add method that takes a night, and that wouldn't have been the
most efficient way to make good use of a lot of the concepts that you should have learned in object
orientation now, because that would mean that I'd have to create an overloaded add method for every
different type of chess piece there is right.
And that would.
And honestly, that's just not necessary to do so.
This is one of the first lessons that I wanted to force you to learn from or implement the fact that
in order to make one method, such as ad, that could be used for different types.
Have chess pieces.
You probably would need to make those different chess pieces.
All have the same interface or all have the same superclass.
So what I did was I chose to introduce a super class called chess piece.
This is a more generic class than pawn or as you'll see in a moment here the night.
OK, now I'm not going to talk too much more about that right now, but I did want to go ahead and just
explain why you're seeing this thing called chess piece and not pawn.
OK, so you can infer from what I've just told you that my pawn class actually ends up extending another
class called chess piece.
OK.
And then here we've got the chess coordinates, which are just a simple string.
All right.
Now, the very first thing I do in the body of this method is I take those chess coordinates and I create
something called a coordinate or coordinates from that string.
Now why do I do that?
Well, if we keep going here, you'll see why in just a minute.
So let's let's put that aside for just a minute and go to the next part.
So the next thing I do is I say piece that set coordinates and then I pass in this coordinates thing
here.
So what you need to know, first off, is that this class coordinates is really just a class implementation
of the concept of coordinates.
OK.
And one of the reasons I created this class was because I needed a lot of convenience.
Over here, the most convenient way for me to refer to coordinates is really just by typing the chest
coordinates as a string.
That's really, really convenient.
However, in my internal code, I sometimes need these broken apart.
Sometimes I need to know what is the letter here?
And by the way, I forgot to mention these rows here numbered one to three through eight one through
eight.
These are called ranks in chess, so these are ranks.
Each row is a rank and then the columns a through h are called files.
OK, so this would be file a, file B, File C and so on.
OK.
Files and ranks.
So sometimes I may need to be able to determine easily in my code.
What file are we on or what rank are we on?
And I don't want to have to write low level code every single time.
I need to know that where I can split the eh, apart from the three or the C, apart from the from the
from the two or something like that.
OK.
And so one of the reasons that I introduced this class called coordinates is so that I would have a
convenient place to have additional methods that that make it easy for me to split out the file from
the rank.
OK, so that's one of the reasons.
All right.
So the next thing I do on line 14, though, is that I set the coordinates on the piece.
That is to simply say that when I'm placing a piece, when I'm adding a piece onto a particular square
of the board, not only do I want the board to know that I put that piece on that square, I may want
that piece to know where it is on the board as well.
That just seems like a good intrinsic thing for the piece to know.
And you'll see a little bit later how we actually make really good use of that knowledge, in fact being
added into the piece itself.
All right.
And then finally, here and this is really, really important now I've got this thing here called internal
board.
And if you'll notice now this internal board is a two dimensional array.
So what this is, is this is the internal representation that I chose to utilize for representing the
chess board.
I thought a good way to represent this chess board in code ultimately was to just create a two dimensional
array because we've got here a board in two dimensions, right X and Y files and ranks.
And it has eight.
It's an eight by eight square matrix.
So I chose to create an array that is eight by eight.
And that way, I could just let each of the elements of this two dimensional array be represent each
of the squares on the chessboard.
So in that case, this first square here could be zero zero one zero two zero three zero zero one one
one two one three one, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
OK, now if we're going to use an internal array to actually represent what's on this chessboard and
that array has numbers zero zero zero one, etc., etc. That would mean that we would need a way to
translate between the chess notation, such as D four or a eight into the array coordinates, right?
In other words, we need to have a way to translate that, for example.
Square eight becomes location zero zero in our array, and that's another thing that we're able to do
with this coordinate class.
This coordinates class is containing or encapsulating the ability to do that kind of translation.
So we're able to encapsulate that.
So then down here, in fact, the act of me adding a chess piece to the board is actually me simply
placing that piece at a particular element in this two dimensional array.
And I'm able to use the coordinates class that get X method here to determine where on the x axis that
piece would belong, according to its chess coordinates, right?
Hopefully, this is making sense to most of you, but for the few for whom it may not be.
Let me just say this in another way.
If I go back over here again, so in this particular case, replacing this -- at Area A2?
Right?
So a two would be right here.
However, in the array, that would be.
Coordinates zero six zero on the x axis, because zero is the first is the first column and then the
sixth row from the top right.
Zero one two three four five six.
So zero six So something needs to translate a two into zero six, and that's something is this coordinates
here.
And so when I call cords that get X, that in this particular case would return a zero.
And then when I call co-ords, I get why that would return a sixth in this case.
So let's dig in here now and see how that's working.
So first, we'll take a look at the constructor for the coordinates.
All right.
So the first thing we do is just take that string of chest coordinates, which in this case would be
a two, and we just store it in an internal field right here.
OK, chest coordinates.
And I just decided to do that just in case I wanted to be able to get that back out for some reason.
Then the next thing I'm doing, though, is I get the first part of that coordinate.
So just for reference here, let's just remember we've got in this one case and a and a two a two,
so I can use the string method care at zero to get the very first character in this, which is the file.
OK.
And so I actually store that in a character called file.
And then the next thing I do is to get the rank now to do that.
That's a number.
And it's always going to be a number.
OK?
And so the first thing I can do starting on the inside here is I can get the second character, which
is character set at one because it's zero based.
I get the second character, which would be a two.
Now this care at method by default will return a character, OK, a primitive character.
And so I want to translate that primitive character into a string, and I can do that easily by referencing
the character class asked to string.
OK.
And so I'm turning this character of a two into a string of two.
At this point.
And then I can turn that string of a two into an actual number or an integer two by using integer that
pass int.
And then I can store that inside of this variable called rank of type integer, so now I've got the
file and I've got the rank.
Then finally, here I'm able to translate the file into an Array X coordinate and the rank into an Array
Y coordinate.
And I do that using these two methods here get X for file, get y for rank.
And so let's jump into this method get X for file and see what I'm doing here.
Now, this should look familiar to you because these are somewhat based on some of the earlier exercises
that I had you doing here.
Right?
Let me see, where are those exercises?
Yeah, this one right here exercise for, I think, right?
A method that takes an input of one lowercase letter.
Only one letter like a through A, B, C or Z, et cetera, and returns that letters ordinal position
in the alphabet, i.e. a one or a two or three.
OK.
So basic.
And I asked you to try to do this without using any conditionals because you can do it mathematically
and without using an array, which would also not be necessary here.
So if you were able to do this, then you should have a pretty good idea of how you can generally translate
a character into a number of any kind.
As long as the numerical pattern is sequential as the character patterns are OK.
And then we had a similar problem down here as well, where I said Translate an aide into a zero and
a seven and to a one, I was preparing you for all of the basic skills that you would need to be able
to do what we're doing now on the chessboard.
OK.
So quick reminder there.
OK, so down here.
Get X for file.
So we get a file, which in this case is an A.
And to turn that into what it should be, let's look at this here.
So we want an a to give us a zero because that is the first column into our array.
OK, so we want an a to give us a zero.
So the way we can do that is simply to take the character of file and subtract 97 from it.
Now, if you remember from the numbers, section or module in this course, you learned that primitive
characters are really the same thing as an integer, except that integers have negative and positive
numbers, whereas characters are all positive because negative numbers don't make any sense for a character.
That's pretty much the only difference in Java.
And so we can actually do math on characters, and I think we did that in the numbers section, in fact.
So I happen to know that a lowercase a has a numerical value of ninety seven.
And therefore, if I take that lowercase a minus 97, then that will give me a zero, and that's exactly
what I want.
And then if I pass in a B, which would have a sequential logical value of ninety eight, lowercase
B would have a value of ninety eight, then ninety eight minus ninety seven would give me a one.
And that's exactly the pattern that I would want here, right?
Zero one two three.
So on and so forth.
So that works out perfectly.
All right.
So that's how we can translate the file into an X coordinate for our array look up and then for getting
the Y coordinate for our array.
That's similarly easy as well.
In that case, we just take eight minus whatever the rank is, and that gives us the value that we want.
Then again, this should have been something that you may have worked out in the exercises prior to
exercise eight.
So that's how we are able to get our array coordinates.
All right.
So now we can jump back over to the chessboard implementation for the add method.
And so now, armed with our actual array coordinates of zero and six, we are now able to simply put
this chess piece inside of that particular element of this two dimensional array.
And that's what I'm doing right here.
OK.
And now we're done with the add method.
OK, so then we simply need to turn around and then look up.
Whatever piece we have at chess coordinates a two with this method, get peace at coordinates.
So let's see how this method is implemented.
So again, we take an input of a string of chess coordinates, and the very first thing I do now is
I just convert that string back into actual coordinates because this coordinate method does a lot of
really useful things like giving us these X and Y coordinates from the chest, from the chest notation.
OK.
And so now you see me just using this same approach again that I just used up here, except instead
of putting something inside of an element of this two dimensional array.
Now I'm simply reading whatever may be in that two dimensional array at that element instead.
OK, so it's the same code just used kind of in the other direction, essentially.
And so that will return whatever object I placed in that element, which in this case would be the pawn
that we had up here.
And then I simply return it.
Now, if we had not placed any object in this array at that location, I would have just gotten back
a null, by the way.
OK, and now note that this method is coded to return something of type chess piece.
And so if I want this piece to be treated as an actual pawn, I need to cast it now.
Honestly, I didn't actually need to do this at all.
This method, a third equals this assertion would have worked even without the cast that I did here.
I did this originally because I didn't want anyone who was looking at this code to be overly confused
by seeing something of Typekit chess piece coming out of here directly.
But now that I'm explaining it to you in real time, it's a lot less important that I'm casting this.
So this casting is not necessary whatsoever.
I just did it just to make things a little more straightforward so that so that it would be more symmetrical.
You know, we're creating a pawn up here.
I thought it would be nice for you to see a pawn coming out of here and then the equals is being applied,
in which case these are the same object in memory, and therefore they absolutely will be equal to each
other.
All right.
So that's a full explanation for this first exercise or first sub exercise.
And honestly, like I said, I didn't know how long it was going to take me to explain all of these
things.
I thought I might have gotten through a few more exercises than this, but apparently not.
So I'm going to go ahead and stop right here, and we'll pick back up with the next exercise, which
should go quicker because it's pretty much the same thing.
OK, so I'll see you in the next lesson.