All right, there's one more scenario that I want to talk a little bit about.
If you'll recall back in the chapter on numbers and things, we had a lesson on equalities and inequalities.
So we've already seen a couple of examples of that here with the equals and the not equals.
But just to be a little more thorough, let's also make sure that we recall from that previous lesson.
In fact, they said in that lesson that we revisit equalities when we got to right here where we're
learning about conditionals and things.
These are conditionals, by the way, these these if then else type constructs are sometimes referred
to as conditionals.
So anyway, let's see.
Another thing that we could do is something like, let me see here.
Let's let's simplify this a lot.
So let's say if random number is less than or equal to two else, if random number is greater, greater
than or equal to four.
Then we'll make the color blue.
Else the color is green.
OK, so.
Let's see what this would would really do then.
So what we're saying is one two three four five six seven eight.
All right.
So what we're saying is if the random number is two or less, then the color will be red.
If the number is four or more than the number will be blue.
Otherwise, if it's three, then it's going to be green.
That's really what this logic is saying now.
I just randomly picked some numbers here, so I didn't even consciously think that we were leaving three
as the left over right.
But that's what we're saying.
OK.
Anything two or less?
Anything four or greater.
And then three is on its own.
OK.
So I just wanted to show that we can also use these inequalities.
And of course, you know, you don't have to have equal sign there.
You could just say if the random number is less than two, which would mean one in this case, right?
If it's greater than four, then that would mean five and up and then anything else would mean three
or four.
So, you know, that's another way of doing some logic.
All right.
Let's see.
And then one other thing that I would like to show is you can actually build compound statements within
the if blocks as well.
So using using logic, and what I mean by that is, let's say.
So we could say something now I'm just making up a really random scenario here.
If the number is, let's say, greater than four and some other criteria.
So the way that you can say and here is with two ampersand.
OK.
And this comes from logic.
So we can say if the random number is greater than four and let's say it's an even number.
OK, so how could we say an even number?
Can you think of a way to say and random number is an even number?
Give you a moment to think about that.
Why don't you pause the video?
OK, so if we wanted to say greater than four and an even number, what we could do is something like
random number.
Now do you know what the key is here modulo?
Do you remember that modulo so random num modulo two equals zero?
Now I could leave it like this, but personally, there's a kind of a lot going on in here, and I would
prefer I would feel better.
I would sleep better at night if this bit here was grouped in its own parentheses.
And so what I just did there?
Let me do that again.
I was talking while I was doing it, so what I can do or what you can do is you can select all of this
in intelligence.
This may not work in all Ides.
Select all of that.
And then if you enter a opening parentheses until a j, modern versions of it will automatically give
you the closing parentheses, then assume you're trying to surround that selected text with parentheses.
Now, I don't absolutely have to have that there, but I think that makes it a little more obvious that
we're saying if the random number is greater than four and the random number is an even number now,
why would this mean an even number?
Do you recall the reason this means in even numbers?
Because if you may recall modulo this operator here returns the remainder of division between this number
and this number, the number to the left of the modulo in the number to the right of the modulo.
So if the number is six, then this will be six divided by two, which would be three with the remainder
of zero, which means that this is an even number.
OK.
Whereas if this were seven, which is, you know, greater than four.
But if this were seven seven divided by two gives a remainder of one.
Right.
And so this would not be true.
And so the way that this will evaluate is that this entire thing won't be true because with this and
here, what we're saying is both of these clauses have to be true.
In order for the whole entire thing to be true.
So not only does random number have to be greater than four also or and random number modulo two equals
zero.
Basically, this all comes out to say random number has to be an even number.
OK.
That's what this whole thing is saying.
And so you can string together clauses like this and you could put more, although I would not recommend
doing it because you don't want the bits that are inside of the if clause to become like a big, huge
monstrosity of code.
I wouldn't usually go to much more than around this in most cases, right?
But you could keep stringing together more stuff if you wanted to.
And then you can also use other logic, though the really, I'd say, probably the only other logic
construct that you may see from time to time within an f block like this would be an order clause,
and that would be like this to pipe symbols.
OK.
So then this would say if random number is greater than four or it is evenly divisible by two or an
even number right, then this whole thing will evaluate to true and then we can proceed to the next
line.
So constructs like this really make these conditionals or these f blocks.
And if patterns really powerful, obviously now you could put this kind of construct on inside of any
of these f blocks.
By the way, I just randomly chose this middle one here, so which one I put it on doesn't really matter.
All right.
So that's going to wrap this up, and I will see you in the next one.