All right, so next in our journey of the loose ends of Java.
We're going to take a slightly deeper dive into generics.
Again, this is one of the topics that we've already touched on a little bit, but I intentionally didn't
go very deep into it.
I still don't plan to go too deep into it, but enough to kind of let you dip your toes a bit and understand
a little more of what's going on there.
And this will also be a sneak preview preview preview for deeper lessons that you will learn in one
of my upcoming courses for the spring framework.
All right.
So generics, first off, let's just talk again a little bit about what they really are.
So generics, you will find them most commonly with collections, although they can be used with more
than just collections, and we will see that in the code that we're getting ready to right in this lesson.
Typically, though, when they're used with classes like collections, they allow us to constrain the
types of data that can be associated with the class that we are using the generics on.
If that was a lot of words that didn't mean much to you, don't worry about it.
You'll see what I mean, although I can give you a quick example going back to our collection.
So for example, if we were to create a new instance of a list, we can just create that new list and
leave it at that and then we can store any type of object in it.
But we can also use generics and say what types of objects we want to store in that list, right?
So we can create a list of strings or a list of employees.
And then after we've created that list with the generic type associated to it, if we then try to add
objects that are not of that generic type, the I.D. and the compiler and Java and everything else will
complain and yell and scream and tell us, No, you can't do that.
So we've seen that before.
So in general, generics allow us to kind of constrain what types of data we can associate with a with
a class.
Additionally, because they allow us to specify those data types, more specifically, they also enable
us to avoid, in many cases, needing to cast types any more.
Now, that might not be as obvious with the examples that we've seen so far from using collections,
but we can use generics on methods and things that return data types as well.
And in that case, if you use a generic for those methods that can return something, then you have
a better shot at not needing to cast whatever the data type was that comes off of those methods.
So we'll see a little bit of that as well.
And then finally, they can protect us from certain types of runtime errors because if you're not using
generics, but you've but you're working with code that is expecting to work with certain data types,
but we don't have a really strong way of enforcing that.
Then you're likely going to be casting data into the assumed types that you need to work with.
And if the objects that you're casting aren't actually cast the ball into the data type that you're
expecting, you're going to get errors.
All right.
So those are just a few of the characteristics and benefits of using generics.
So in order to explore this a little bit more, we're going to create a class that is strongly influenced
by a very popular framework that I will be teaching in one of my upcoming courses.
This is going to be a class that will model our ability to store objects like in a data store of some
sort like a database or something of that sort.
OK.
And this is an extremely common pattern that you will encounter as a professional software developer,
especially in business domains.
All right.
So turning to the ADP, I am going to first create a new package to store this code in.
So I'm going to come up here to source and do a command in for new and then I'll type for package and
click enter.
And I don't know, I will just call this data store.
All right.
And then I will create a new class in the data stored package and I will call this repository.
And this is a common name for for what you're about to learn, by the way.
Though normally with the upcoming framework, it's called the spring framework that I will teach in
another course.
You wouldn't even need to create this.
It would, it would.
They would give you this.
So we're going to make our own poor man's version of a repository just so we can kind of play around
with generics and you'll get a little taste of what this type of functionality kind of looks like.
All right.
And I'm going to give myself some space now and close that down.
So here's what we're going to do.
This repository is going to be a class that will model a repository of objects, OK, and we will be
able to interact with this repository to save objects into it and retrieve objects out of it, essentially
and delete objects as well.
Now, since this is going to be a poor man's implementation of a repository, real repositories, especially
in the spring framework, are most commonly connecting to databases.
And if you don't know what the database is, real quick.
A database is simply a program usually running on a server that usually is connected to via a network
kind of like the internet, and our programs can make connections to these databases to store data in
them and to get data out.
So think about our previous little projects with the employees and the people like the five million
people records that we've been working with.
We've been iterating through those five million records by opening up a file with five million people
records in them.
But in real life, particularly in business contexts, it would be much more common that that data that
we've been working with would actually be stored on a database, and we'd be writing code that would
be connecting to that database over a network.
And it would be querying that database to get that data out.
And a lot of the functionality that we were learning with lambdas to parse through and sift through
and calculate and all that stuff can actually be done on a database as well.
And we will be learning that in an upcoming module, too.
So that's just a little context for you.
But anyway, the repository class would be our gateway into talking to that database would be an easy
and easier gateway into talking to that database.
And so it would give us a nice, easy methods to retrieve records out of it and put records into it
and things of that sort.
All right.
So having said that, the first iteration of our creation of this repository class is going to simply
start off by letting us add strings to it and then get strings out of it, essentially.
OK.
So let's see what that might look like.
So we've got this class here repository.
And let's just say that internally, it's going to store these strings inside of a list.
Let's just keep it real simple.
OK.
So we'll go ahead and create a list.
We'll have a list and we'll use a generic here.
So we'll say it's going to be a list of strings, OK, for now.
All right, let's import that, and let's just call this, I don't know records, and I'm going to go
ahead and just initialize it in the declaration.
Just do something quick and dirty here.
Here we go.
So there's our records holder.
All right.
And now we're going to have some methods that allow a user of this repository class to do things like
getting records out and things of that sort.
So let's let's first have a method that's just that just returns all of the records.
And I'm going to use standard method names that are commonly seen with this pattern called the repository
pattern.
By the way, I think I've mentioned in a previous lesson that that there are these so-called design
patterns and they're just common snippets of code and techniques, coding techniques that have become
very popularized over decades because they really kind of condense down.
Oftentimes the most efficient or well proven way of doing certain kinds of things.
And so this is one of those patterns is called the repository pattern.
All right.
So we'll have a method here and it's going to return back our list of strings.
It's really just going to be a getter method.
In fact, I could pretty much generated except that I want it to be called something very specific.
And let's see, it's going to be called find all OK.
And so like I said, that method name, there is a very common method name that you will find frequently
on the repository pattern.
All right.
And so this guy is just going to return our records.
There we go.
OK.
And let's see, let's also have a method for storing records in our repository.
OK, now keep in mind right now our records aren't really records per se.
They're just strings, OK?
We're just going to start kind of small here.
So typically a save method in this type of pattern would be one that takes an input, and it will return
the same object that was entered into it typically.
All right.
So knowing that we know that we're working with strings, so this method is going to return a string
and it's going to be called save and it will take a string and we'll just call that record.
And then it's going to call the record's class and add the record just like that.
And then it can loops and then it can return that same record.
All right.
I know that looks a little pointless here in real life, it wouldn't it would be slightly less pointless
because the code that would be doing the saving would also be getting an ID for that record and then
saving that I.D. on the record and then returning the records.
So you'd be getting something for your trouble.
You'd be getting the new I.D. of this record that you just saved in our code.
For right now, we're not getting that fancy.
All right.
And let's also have a method that allows us to look up a record by some like ID or something, okay?
So for this one, this will also return a string and we'll call this find my I.D..
I know some developers, by the way, they like when they are doing these acronym parts of a of a name
like ID, they will typically do ID.
Yeah, whatever.
All right.
So this method is going to take as an input, an idea of a record and then return the record that it
found.
So since we're talking about records, which is a list of things, remember that I've said in the past
that when we have lists of things with that are numbered, typically we are counted.
We will typically want to use a long for that number system because that because the long data type
is is considered to be long enough, usually to actually be capable of numbering however many records
you might actually have in your data store as opposed to an integer.
All right, so we'll use a long term I.D. We'll call it, and let's see.
So for right now, the way we will implement this is just to return records that get right.
So we'll just use the get method of the list itself, which takes an index.
Now notice the record stock that actually takes an integer, not a long.
OK.
So there is a little bit of a mismatch there, but that's all right.
We'll work around it.
Can you think of how to convert our long into an end, by the way?
All right, so what we can do is we can use the rapper long class and then do a value of passenger I.D.
And then and now we've got a rapper long or a class of type long because up here we're just using a
primitive long.
And then now that we've got the class of long, we can use a method on it into value so we can convert
that into an integer really easily.
OK.
And so what this is basically saying is take that ID converted into an integer and now find that index
the integer index in this collection and return whatever object you find, right?
That's what we're doing there.
All right.
And I think that's enough of those methods for our repository.
And now let's create a public static void main method so that we can play with this class a little bit.
OK.
So let's create an instance of it, and I will call it repo.
All right.
And let's see here, let's just add some records to it so we can save.
House.
And I just will duplicate a couple more lines there, tree and boat.
All right.
And then let's do a system that out, and then let's call Oops, let's call Repo Dot, find all.
And so that should retrieve our house tree boat and let us like print them out or something, right?
So let's run that and see.
There we go.
Okay.
So there we have our collection of house, tree and boat.
Very good.
All right.
So that's working just fine.
So now here's the deal.
What if we wanted this repository to be capable of working with virtually any data type there is right
now?
It can only store strings.
But what if we had employees and person class and car and boat or whatever, right?
Like all these different types of classes?
But we wanted this very nice functionality of being able to save these objects to this repository,
right?
How could we do that?
So I mean, one way that we could do it would be to remove the string here and maybe either just not
have any generic type at all.
Or similarly, just change string to object, right?
So we could have a just be object.
I think those two approaches would be functionally similar to each other, if not identical.
So what would be the pros and cons to doing that?
Well, one potential con of that approach would be that when we retrieve items using the Find My I.D.
in particular, we would then have to cast them to whatever their actual data type was right, not the
end of the world.
But again, that kind of opens us up to some runtime errors if we are making assumptions as to what
data type we stored in there.
Just imagine if over here we're saving a string and then we saved a new person, you know, which I
haven't created that class in this module here.
But you know what I mean?
Right?
New person.
And then we created a new employee or a new house or whatever, right?
And then we did a find by ID and we retrieved one of those items.
And then we wanted to call some methods that only exist on whatever the data type is, right?
Well, you know, we'd have to be really careful that the methods that we're calling actually exist
on whatever that object was, that we were getting out.
And so we'd need to cast and then if we happen to be trying to cast something to type person, but it's
actually a string, then at runtime it's going to blow up.
So the idea would not be able to protect us from that.
While we're writing the code, we would only find that out while we're running the application when
it blows up on us.
Okay.
And it would give us probably like a class cast exception.
And now we know what exceptions really are.
Right.
So that's one of those runtime exceptions.
OK, so anyway, there's a better way.
Obviously, right?
That's why I'm saying all of this.
So the better thing to do would be to just as they have generic sized the collections framework itself.
We can make our own classes generic, too, so we can actually make this repository class generic pretty
much exactly the way that the list is here.
OK.
And so we can make it to that for a given instance of the repository.
Now this is key for a given instance of the repository.
We can only use one data type.
So if you want to use another data type you have to use, you have to create another instance of the
repository.
So let's see what that would look like.
The way we do this is we introduce the greater than less than symbol here, right?
Which we've seen before.
And then we use a letter typically to refer to our generic, our generic data type.
And the most common letter that you will find when doing this is T standing for type.
OK.
So by doing this, we are telling Java that this class is generic.
OK, now just doing this doesn't really do anything for us, though.
We must use this Ti in various key places now and so we can start using this tea to replace where we
were kind of hard coding the string data type.
So in other words, we're now going to say we don't want our repository class to just know how to store
and work with strings.
We want it to be able to store and work with whatever data type we specify later on.
And I'll show you where we'll get to that later on in a minute here.
So here we're doing a list of strings.
So now instead of a list of string, let's just do a list of Ti and we can do that.
And now that's this is kind of interesting because list itself is generic.
So now it's kind of like we're going to levels deep into the generics, if you will, right where we're
delaying telling the generic for list what it's data type is actually going to be when it's all said
and done.
But we can we can do that.
All right.
And I get an error here because I actually forgot up here to address this.
So even our collection here is current.
Hardcoded as a list of strings, we want this to be a list of T, right, because we don't know what
it is yet.
Right?
So we'll do that.
And now that error down here went away because now everything's matching up.
I'm saying that we have a list of T and I'm saying down here to return that list of T with type list
of T.
So it's all matching up now.
OK.
And remember, over here, we don't have to explicitly say what the generic type is that is being inferred.
This is a type inference, though we could if we wanted to.
I could put that in there explicitly, but it is unnecessary to do so as of I think Java version eight,
I think don't don't hold me to that.
But.
All right.
And then down here, let's see.
We're saving OK, so we're going to save now, not a string, but something of type T, and that means
we're going to return something of type T as well.
All right.
And we're good there.
And then down here, we're going to return something of type T as well.
So look at that, that all got happy all of a sudden and now down here.
Now notice something kind of interesting.
I haven't made any changes down here and there are no errors.
So let's go ahead and just run this and see what's going to happen first.
All right, so nothing broke, right?
That is by design, not my design.
The design of the creators of Java.
So this generic functionality actually was added into Java a little later in java's life.
It came about in version five of Java and Java had been plenty used in business and everywhere else
prior to version five.
In fact, I do remember quite distinctly when version five came out and because Java had been so heavily
in use prior to this whole generics functionality even being created, the creators knew that if they
were going to add this type of powerful functionality, it needed to be implemented in such a way that
it would not break existing code.
OK.
And so we're seeing a little hint of that functionality here in that, even though I have now generic
sized this class to work with type T right down here, I'm allowed to instantiate it still without any
generic mentioning anywhere here.
And this code that was working previously is still working right now.
Now, for those of you who are curious, one of the reasons why this can work is because for all of
its interesting coolness at the end of the day, believe it or not, Java is essentially just racing
this information.
And in this particular case, replacing it with object.
That's basically what what's going on there.
So this becomes a list of object essentially for right now.
Now, if we want this repository instance to be truly generic, however, we can go ahead and do that.
And the way we can do that is by using the less than and greater than symbols again, so we can create
a repository of string like so and then I can come over here and do one of these as well, right?
And this is the same pattern that you see right up here, right when where we're creating the the list,
in fact.
OK, so now we're creating a repository of string.
Obviously, this isn't bringing a whole lot of value in this particular example where we were already
working with string, right?
But yeah, all right.
It's a start.
OK.
So now, though, here's where we get kind of cool.
Next thing we're going to do is let's create a record.
Class A record that models a person.
OK.
And I'm going to just do it in line here.
So we're going to create a record of person and you will have a first name.
And a last name, and that's enough for now.
All right, so we've got this class, this record of type person.
OK, now watch this.
I can create another instance of a repository now, but this one will work for person instances and
I'll call it.
I don't know.
P. Repo four person repo new repository.
There we go.
Now if I try to.
Save.
A string in here.
Look at that.
I'm getting an error now, and if I hover over this, it's basically just telling me that, hey, you're
trying to supply a string, but I'm really expecting a person.
And the reason it's expecting a person is because we said right here when we created this instance of
the repo class that it only works with person.
Right?
And so now that's being enforced even here in this method.
And again, if we go to the save method, we say that save method takes instances of type T, whatever
he may be.
And here he is of type person.
So therefore, whatever I pass in here has to be a person.
So if I change this now?
To a new person.
Jake Johnson.
Everything's happy, right?
And so I will go ahead and create a couple more of these people that save new person marry.
Johnson.
And maybe one more people don't save new person.
Jerry?
Johnson.
All right.
And so now I can.
Recall.
Oops, wrong, repo.
Got to be careful there.
Find all.
OK, so now let's see what this does.
All right, cool.
So here's our first three people spitting out house three boat, which are all strings.
And here's our second repo printing out the two string implementation of the default to string implementation
of our person record class, right?
And so we're now seeing Jake and Mary and Gerri, right?
So that's working as expected.
And isn't that kind of nice?
It's kind of cool.
Like we didn't really have to change the underlying class of repo other than to just make it generic.
That's kind of one of the beautiful aspects of working with generics.
All right.
So now that we have the ability to pass in more complex objects like this person class, a very common
thing that we will encounter as professional developers using frameworks that implement the repository
pattern is that our objects that will interact with the repository typically will have an I.D. associated
with them.
OK.
And that's so that you can look them up quickly by ID like we have.
What is it here in this find by ID method, right?
So let's add an ID property to the person class, OK?
And as you already know, by now, IDs are traditionally going to be of data type long, typically.
So let's do that.
Let's make a long I.D..
OK.
So, OK.
Now, having done that, I see down here, I've got three read errors, and that's because I've now
changed the constructor of this record to require that ID.
Right?
So I'm going to have to come down here now and specify IDs for each of these.
So I will just do that.
To tell.
3L, I remember the is because it's long.
All right, so now those errors have gone away.
Now what do I want to do with with that right?
Well.
I could.
Do a pre-IPO dot find by IED and then I could pass in an IED like three L, for example, and let's
capture that.
Found person and then let's print that found person like, sir.
OK, now here's the thing.
Actually, in fact, you know, let's do this instead of one to three, let's do 10.
20 and 30.
OK.
All right, and then and then let's actually try to retrieve throw the person with ID of 30.
Let's run that and see what we get.
OK, there we go.
And look at where we got there.
The.
Now what should now be quite familiar?
The index out of bounds exception because we ask for Item 30 and there's only three items in here.
And the way that we implemented defined by ID was very simplistic in that it simply is looking for not
an ID per se, but just the index into the collection, right?
So if there's three items, then there should be an item with an idea of, like to write something like
that.
But that's that's how we implemented this.
But that's not how this code is expecting to to work, right?
So we need to change our implementation now to actually make use of these ideas that are associated
with these objects here.
OK.
And that's actually easy enough to do and actually so that we can reuse a lot of what we've learned.
Let's use lambdas to do this.