All right, next up, let's talk about another number system, which is hexadecimal.
Let's find out a little bit about this numbering system, why it exists and how it works.
So let's do a quick review, though first.
So we all grew up probably learning the decimal number system, and that is a system that is based on
10.
So it is based 10.
And the reason it's considered base 10 is because each place in this number system, like the ones tens,
hundreds or whatever, can hold digits between zero and nine.
So 10 values in binary binary is called a base two system because each place in this case here, here,
here and here, each place can hold only two different values a zero or a one.
OK.
So hexadecimal is a number system, which is base 16.
So for each place, you can have 16 different values.
Now, the way that those 16 values are implemented is that the first 10 values just use the same numbers
as exist in the decimal system based 10 zero through nine.
But after we run out of numbers, then we start using letters as the additional symbols for base 16.
So a through F, ABCD, E and F and combined that gives us our 16 values.
Now you should probably be wondering why on earth would we ever need this?
And the short answer is that it's actually a very convenient number system that allows us to compress
base 10 and binary numbers.
So as you can see with binary numbers, it takes a lot more space, so to speak, to encode decimal
numbers, right?
So for example, here, decimal number 15 requires four bits to encode that same number.
OK.
In decimal, you need two places to encode the number 15.
The one a one in the tens place and a five in the ones place.
However, in hexadecimal, you can encode up to 15 with just one place and f.
So hexadecimal allows us to have a compressed representation of numbers from base 10 or base two.
Also, hexadecimal numbers line up really, really well with bytes.
So if you were to take a bite eight bits and break it into two sets of four bits, by the way, Four
Bits has a name as well.
It's called a nibble.
You don't hear that term very often, but because computers tend to be more like based on eight.
But yeah, four bits is a nibble.
All right.
So one hexadecimal digit can very nicely represent one nibble or four bits.
And let me show you what that looks like, so we'll come down here.
I have here one hexadecimal number three E8.
I know it looks weird, and I know it sounds weird to refer to something that has letters as a number,
but it is a hexadecimal number three, eight and up above it.
We've got the actual binary number.
And what I've done here is I've broken this binary number into groups of four or nibbles, right?
So the first grouping of four has a value of eight by itself.
OK.
And so I have an hexadecimal eight here.
So what I'm doing is I'm converting this binary number into a hexadecimal equivalent.
OK, so all you have to do is this break up the binary number into groupings of four and then you translate
that individual binary number of four digits into the hexadecimal equivalent.
So here, the first grouping of four would be an eight.
And so I have an eight here.
The next number here is a 14 because we've got zero one one one right one two four eight.
So this first one here on the left is eight plus four is 12, plus two is 14 and then zero zero.
And so that is 14 14, and hexadecimal is an E.
We can go over here and see that 14 is E!
And we even have the binary one one one zero.
So if you come over here one one one zero, right, so that's an E.
And then the last grouping of four is a three two plus one three.
Right.
So three eight, this is the hexadecimal conversion of this binary number.
Let's look at one more here.
We've got a hexadecimal number that spells out the word face and to convert this one from binary, what
we've got is the first grouping of four in the binary is eight plus four plus two, which again is 14.
There's that same e, then we've got 12 eight plus four and that is a C, and then we've got 10, eight
plus two, which is an a in Hex.
And then we've got a 15, which is one one one one, which is an f f a c e.
OK.
So like I said, hexadecimal is really convenient at compressing the amount of space visually and in
writing required to represent decimal and binary numbers.
And it also lines up really, really conveniently with every four bits of a binary number.
Now, it's not overly important for you to really, really deeply understand this.
However, you will encounter this from time to time, and we have seen this already hexadecimal numbers
in Java, and I will show you what I mean.
So we'll jump back over to the ADP.
And if we were to create an instance of this, no class which doesn't do anything, by the way, but
if we create an instance of the no class.
My instance equals new.
No stuff.
OK, so there we've created an instance of the number of stuff.
And then if we print out in this instance, do you recall what's going to happen if we do this?
I'm going to comment out this one here, and let's just run this.
Look at what we get here, do you remember this week this happened a long time ago when we were working,
I think in the person class and we created a person and we tried to print that person before we overrode
the two string method.
So so what's happening here is that when you pass a reference to an object into the method, a method
like print line which is expecting a string by default, the two string method of that object will be
called.
Now we haven't written our own two string method on this class.
And so the inherited default two string method, which is inherited from the superclass object, is
getting called.
And the default implementation of that two string method is to simply print the name of the class itself
and then the address of that object in memory.
This is the address of the object in memory here.
Notice it has a combination of numbers and letters.
This is, in fact a hexadecimal number.
This is simply a compressed way for Java to tell us where in memory does this object reside going back
to the spreadsheet?
Again, if we kind of imagine that every object in Java takes up some amount of space in the form of
some number of bytes, right?
Every bite in memory has an address.
And so this is showing us the address where all the bytes that comprise this particular object reside
in memory.
OK.
All right.
And I think that's probably about all I need to say about Hex Hexadecimal.
I just didn't want this to be some ongoing mystery to you as to what exactly is this and why is it this
way?
If the creators of Java had not chosen to use hexadecimal here, they could have used decimal.
But then it would have taken up more space visually for us to see.
They could have used binary, but then it would be really long and taken up even more visual space.
And so hexadecimal is just a really convenient way to convey the address of this object in memory.
All right.
And that's going to wrap up this little short lesson on hexadecimal.