All right, in this lesson, I'm going to show you how to install the latest version of Java on a Windows
machine.
The latest version as of this recording is Java version 17.
So in any web browser, I like to start with Google and what we will do is we'll just Google for install
Java 17.
And from here, we can go down here to this Java C17 archive downloads, so I'm going to click on that
and then scroll up.
And as you can see here, there are downloads for installing Java 17 on various operating systems,
from Linux to Mac to Windows.
This video will be for Windows, and the particular one that we're going to go for is the Windows x64
installer.
OK.
And the reason for that is because this other one up here, the compressed archive, doesn't give us
a nice, easy to use installer, so that may be a little bit more problematic for some people to figure
out.
I think probably the easiest thing to use, though, is this installer here.
So just make sure you're clicking on Windows x64 installer and what you're actually going to click on.
Sorry, is this link over here on the right?
So I'm going to click on that, and that started the download, and it's coming down pretty quickly.
All right, there we go, and it's done, and now I can go ahead and click to open the file and it's
asking me, do I verify?
So I'm going to click, Yes.
And that should launch the actual install program.
All right.
And so when that's done, installing it may not be super obvious, it will just stop doing things.
So now we can test to see or verify whether or not it's been properly installed, and my preferred way
to do this is at the command line.
So what we can do is go down to the little windows start button there, and I like to type in a command
as in command prompt.
And you can see here there's an app for that command prompt and I will click on that that opens up the
command line.
It's kind of like the old school dos command line, and if Java installed properly, we will be able
to issue a command with it.
And so the command we can type out is Java all lowercase space.
Dash Dash like two minus signs version.
Enter.
And as you can see here, it says Java, seventeen point zero point one.
And so that is confirming that we have indeed successfully installed Java version 17 on this computer.
And that's the end of this lesson.