All right, so in the last lesson, we learned how to use the illicit interface and make an instance
of an ArrayList.
And we also learned how to add objects to the collection or the list and to iterate over them using
the enhanced for loop.
So in this lesson, we're going to continue learning more of these patterns with the collections.
And the first thing we're going to do, if you recall from the last lesson or two, I mentioned the
fact that we should prefer to store instances of objects in their interfaces when there is an applicable
interface to use.
And I said that I would show in more detail why that is.
So that time is now.
So turning back to the code here, let's go where we actually created our array list, which is here
on line 36.
So we're creating a new ArrayList and we're storing the instance of that array list in the employee's
variable here.
So on the left side, though, we declare that this employees variable is not of type array list.
It's a list of I employee, OK?
Rather than an array list of I employee.
So what's cool about this is the fact that since I left the variable declaration somewhat generic and
I don't mean generic in the sense that I'm using these, this less than greater than symbol, which
this functionality here is called generics, where we can specify a type for our collection.
But I mean, generic in the sense that I wasn't so specific as to say that this is an array list right
now since I did that in this way.
I now have a little bit of flexibility.
I can come over here and actually change this data type that we're using to some other implementation
of a list.
Do you get it by using interfaces to store our variables?
It gives us the flexibility to to swap in and out different implementations of that interface.
So, for example, at one point in time, it may make sense for us to use an array list to get our work
done.
But we could.
We could realize later on because maybe there's more data than we were expecting or something that it
might make more sense not to use an array list, but to use a linked list instead.
So watch what happens when I change this implementation from a ArrayList to a linked list, and all
I need to do is just remove the word array and put in the word linked and it's already imported.
I don't know why.
I guess I must have done it earlier or something, but no errors.
And so instantly, I get all of the diff deferring benefits of a linked list versus an array list without
having to change any code because I used a more generic interface type for the variable.
And that is, the power of coding to interface is rather than implementation types.
OK, so this program will work just the same, and I'll prove that by running it.
There we go.
So no difference there, no difference that we can see.
It just implements the list differently internally.
So I don't want to go into too much detail, but I'll try to outline basically the difference between
the ArrayList and the linked list.
The array list, as I mentioned earlier, uses an array internally and you know that when we create
an array, we have to initialize it with a size or with actual data.
And after it has been initialized, it cannot be changed.
So if we realized that the array was not big enough, we would have to create a new array with a bigger
size.
Linked list does not use an array internally.
Instead, it requests individual pockets of memory for each element that we add to it.
And as it requests additional memory locations, it stores the address of the new memory locations in
the previous memory location.
So it forms a linked list, right?
So if we've got memory location A and then linked lists requests from the computer, additional memory
for memory, location B memory location B might be given an address of T and memory.
Location A might have an address of 10.
And so the linked list will take the address of B, which is 20, and store that address of 20 in a
special little pocket of storage in location A..
And that way, when the linked list has to traverse the elements in the linked list, it can do so by
simply following the trail of addresses one at a time.
If you're an Element A and you need to get to Element B, it can look inside of Element A and C that
the next address of B is 20 in this case, and then it can jump to address location 20 to find B and
so on and so forth.
However, and additionally, linked list goes the other way as well.
So not only does it store the next location in the previous location, it also stores the previous location
in the next location.
So it's what we call a doubly linked list that makes it easy and fast to be able to traverse forward
and backward either way.
So that's how a linked list works.
One of the advantages of using a linked list is the fact that it can grow with a constant amount of
time.
Unlike an array list, which uses an array to store its data when the internal array of an array list
gets full.
The array list has to create a new, bigger array, then copy all the data from its original array into
the new array, then let that original array get garbage collected and proceed.
As you can imagine, if we're dealing with thousands or millions of objects that could take some time
to do, the length list is more efficient in that regard.
However, a potential downside to the linked list is the fact that every single time you add a new item
to the linked list, it may need to take a hit of requesting new memory allocation from the computer.
Now, honestly, I don't know if it does that each time or if it allocates a few in advance and then
uses them, but it's not going to go as far in advance as an array would go.
And so there is going to be more of a time hit each and every time we request more memory or the linked
list requests more memory from the computer and requesting memory from the computer and allocating objects
and things of that sort is considered, generally speaking, to be an expensive operation.
So it's kind of like picking, you know, which which of those scenarios do you want to take the hit
on?
All right.
But at any rate, now you can see a little bit more firsthand some more of the power of coding to interfaces
whenever possible.
This this truism of coding to interface is being a good thing isn't just true for working with collections
in general, it's true everywhere.
We saw it here as well where we were creating employees, and we chose to store them inside of a variable
of Type II employee instead of being more specific in saying it's a manager or a programmer or whatever
right now.
There's something else I want to show you.
So in the last lesson, we saw how we could iterate over a collections elements using the enhanced for
loop.
And this is the primary and preferred or recommended way of iterating.
However, I want to give you a small scenario here now.
Imagine that after having populated the employees collection with all of these employees here, the
program receives a little bit of extra data, telling it that a few employees should be actually removed
from the collection.
OK.
And so we need to get rid of those somehow.
And imagine that for whatever reason, it makes sense to do to remove those from the collection in this
loop down here, the secondary loop.
So imagine again that these two loops are happening in two very, completely different parts of the
program at different times.
Unlike in this program here, where we're doing them back to back, just imagine that we populate in
one part of the program and then maybe hours later, days later, another part of the program is looping
over that populated list.
OK.
So we would want to remove.
So let me show you something here.
So in order to know which elements to remove?
Let us pretend that we have another collection.
So I'm going to create another list, but this list will be of strings, and the strings will be the
names of people who should be removed.
OK.
So I will call this variable removal names and I will create an array list like so and then I'm going
to add a few names to this list.
So I'm going to remove all names that add.
So let's see.
Let's do Wilma.
Five.
And I'll duplicate this a couple more times, and we'll pick a couple more names, Barney four, and
I'm just randomly picking these names.
And Fred to.
OK, so the idea now is as we're iterating over these employees or these workers, I want to remove
these three from the list.
So perhaps I could do something like this if Worker Dot get in right here, I have a small problem because
I'm working with the interface of I employee.
It does not actually expose the gutter methods for getting the first or last name right now.
I'm not going to change the data type that I'm working with here, but maybe what I'll do instead is
just cast the worker to another data type that does expose the methods for getting the name.
So maybe what I can do is just cast this to an employee like so.
Then I'm going to have to embed this now in several parentheses, right?
So this first parentheses here lets me put the casting of the employee in this second one.
Here I will use to close off the entire worker object so that I can basically convert the worker into
an employee.
And then the third is for the if statement itself.
So now if I come over here and do a control space now I can get at the actual name on the employee.
And let's see, do I have a.
All right, so I will grab the first name, and it looks like I didn't, I guess I did not generate
getters and setters for the name, but it looks like it's available to me anyway.
All right.
So this will give me the workers first name.
But now what I want to do is I want to say is this first name contained within this list here.
Right.
That's what I want to do.
And luckily, I can do exactly that because the list interface does indeed have a contained method on
it.
So first, let me fix my formatting here.
I only put those spaces in just so you could see what was going on a little more easily.
So what I'm going to do is I go to the beginning of this statement here and I'm going to reference the
removal names variable here or the collection removal names.
And then I can access a method on this, which is contains.
So what I'm asking here is, does the list of names to remove called remove all names contain this first
name for this current worker that I happen to be iterating over now?
By doing this, I need to put one more parentheses here.
And then one more here as well, there we go.
There we go.
All right.
So that's a little that's a little difficult to look at, isn't it, because of all the parentheses
here?
So you'll have to just be careful to group these up nicely, right?
Because of the casting that I'm doing here, I need this parentheses pair here.
Then I need this next one to actually treat the worker as an employee so that the period works and then
I can get the first name out of it.
Then the next parentheses is for the contains call and then the final parentheses is for the entire
if statement.
Now, we could simplify that a little bit.
I could extract another local variable for the worker that has been cast to an employee so I can select
all of that and then do an option command V..
And maybe I'll call it temp worker.
And that makes this more readable now, so don't ever be afraid to extract variables or method names
to make things easier to read and to see.
Look at that.
That's a lot easier to look at, in fact.
All right.
So if the removal names contains the current temporary workers first name, then we'd want to remove
that worker from the employee's list.
So again, this is the list of the employees and we want to remove this current worker from the employee's
list.
So what that might look like is employee's employees dot and there is a remove method right here.
Remove.
And now I can just tell it to remove the worker.
Now I'm going to actually reference the worker here and not this temp worker because the temp worker
is of type employee and I just want to keep things really straight and that not so confusing.
And so since this employee's collection is a collection of I employees and worker here and here is also
of type I employee, I'd rather just stick with that.
So I'm just going to put the word worker right there.
OK.
Now, this is what you might have thought to do, but I'm going to go ahead and tell you right now this
actually isn't going to work, and this is a very common mistake for developers to make, especially
new developers.
And that's why I'm just starting right off telling you and showing you all of this just so I can tell
you this won't work.
So let's go ahead and run it and see what happens.
All right, so let's see what we got here, we got a class cast exception, blah blah blah lambda.
That's a key thing to make note of cannot be cast to employee.
I think that's probably all we need to know right there.
OK.
Lambda cannot be cast to employee.
What do you think that saying?
And why do you think we're getting that?
Lambda cannot be cast to employee.
All right, so what's happening here?
If you recall from several lessons ago.
Our code is written in such a way that this create employee method tries to convert each of these text
lines into an actual employee object.
However, when it encounters a text line with a with a role that it does not actually recognize or know
anything about.
We created a lambda expression, which results in the creation of basically like an anonymous type of
class.
And let's go, let's go remind ourselves of what that code looks like.
Someone to jump into the employee class here and go up to the create employee method.
And right here, if the role of the text line that we're on a line that will look something like this.
And here's the roll part right there.
If that roll isn't one of these roles here, then we go to this default switch block here and we have
this lambda expression, which just represents a method that takes no input and returns a zero.
And this lambda expression maps to the I employee interface.
OK.
So this what ends up happening is Java will create an object that looks more or less like an I employee,
even though I employee isn't a class, it's just an interface.
But it will make a fake object that looks like it is of type I employee.
And then for that, objects get salary method.
It will map this lambda expression, OK, which will just return to zero.
That's really all we were trying to get out of.
It was just an implementation for the get salary method that returns a zero.
But here's the crucial point here.
This is resulting in the creation of an object that has nothing to do with employee with the data type
of employee.
It's not related to an employee at all.
It's just an interface of Type I employee.
And so it is impossible to cast this object or the thing that will become an object based on this,
it's impossible to cast that to an employee because you can't go from an AI employee to an employee
if you never had an employee to begin with.
This thing was never an employee.
These are these are all fine because these are all sub types of employee that additionally implement
the AI employee interface.
OK, does that make sense?
And so that's why these can be mapped.
So what can we do about this?
And now we're getting into kind of a real type of problem that you might encounter as a professional
developer.
So do you want to take a moment to try to think of a of a minimalistic way to get around this problem?
And I'm I'm going to give you a small hint as to what I think I would do.
I don't think I would change anything here at all.
And I would look to change the most minimal amount of code possible.
All right, so here's what I think I would do.
Going back over here to the main class.
And go down to our problem code here.
So what I think I would try doing here is to test whether or not the current worker is actually an instance
of employee before I try to cast it, OK?
And I think it's as simple as that.
So maybe I could do something like if.
Worker instance of employee, then you can proceed with all this other stuff.
Now there is a little bit that I don't like about this.
Let me let me proceed with it, though, and show you what I mean.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to indent all of this and then do this.
In other words, I don't want to do any of this business here.
If the current worker is not an instance of employee.
Right.
Because I want to be able to cast the worker to some, to something of type employee first so that I
can get it its first thing because if it's that lambda expression object, it's not even going to have
a first name, right?
So I can't do any of this stuff on objects that are not a subtype of employee.
All of that would just be completely invalid, so we only want to be doing the casting if the current
worker instance is an instance of employee, also recall that we learned that we could do something
similar to this by calling workers get class right worker that get class.
And then we could say something like if that equals employee class.
However, I didn't do this because if you may recall, the get class method here is very specific.
We want to use instance of because it honors the entire class hierarchy.
So in other words, this worker instance let me undo this.
So this worker instance, even if it's an instance of a programmer, this will be true because programmer
is a subclass of employee manager, is a subclass of employee, whereas get classes specific, it just
gets the actual type.
So if it was a programmer, it would say programmer.
So it would say programmer is not equal to employee.
And therefore that's false, right?
That's not what we want here.
We actually want to honor the class hierarchy.
All right.
Let's see.
So we're going to run this again.
But I'm going to warn you now, this still isn't the final solution that we need.
You'll see that in just a moment here.
So let me run this.
All right, so now we get an air concurrent modification exception.
And that's another error that I was expecting to see.
Now this is an extremely common error that Java developers get all the time, especially novice Java
developers.
And so let me explain to you what is going on here.
So basically, in a nutshell, we are trying to remove something from the list while we're looping over
the list.
Imagine it's kind of like you're trying to change a tire in a car while the car is moving right.
It just doesn't make sense.
You can't do that sort of like that.
A little more specifically, another way of looking at it is that the JDK that is Java, the Java development
kit, it senses, if you will, that there is the possibility that two threads, two or more threads
we remember the threads are the little guys who actually go line by line, executing each line right,
jumping into the methods and doing whatever those methods say.
Up until now, we've been just imagining that there's always just one thread that's going line by line
and executing our code.
But in this particular case, what you can kind of imagine is happening is that two threads come into
existence.
One thread has the job of looping over this employee's collection here, right?
So he's just looping through the collection.
But when we say remove.
You can imagine that another thread is trying to grab one of the employees out of that collection while
the first thread is looping over the collection.
So imagine that some guy has the has the job of counting items in a list and another guy comes along
and tries to steal items out of that list at the same time that would cause chaos and Java, or the
JDK senses that something like that looks like it could be happening here.
And so it throws this exception to warn us to tell us, Hey, this doesn't look kosher, what you're
trying to do here.
So the proper thing to do would be to use my analogy again of these two threads here, and one thread
is looping over items or counting items or something.
The proper thing to do would be to ask that guy the one guy, the thread, Hey, when you get a chance,
could you remove this item from your own list?
Let him do it that way.
He doesn't get off track or anything.
And so we can do that, however, to do it.
We're going to have to implement a different type of loop.
OK.
And I'm going to introduce that to you in the next lesson.