All right, so in this lesson, I want to switch gears a little bit and give you a bit of a mental model
to help you understand how the Streams API is working.
So we'll do a little bit of analysis on just this little bit of of a program here that we've got.
OK.
And we're going to I'm going to just, you know, kind of draw some doodles here.
So we've got the people text variable here, which has all of these lines of, you know, all of these
text lines here, right?
So I'm going to depict those like this.
Let's see here just a bunch of lines, right?
So these are kind of like your whatever Flintstone, Fred.
And then some date or whatever and then other stuff.
OK, so we've got all of these lines here.
All right.
So the first thing that's happening here is that the people text the variable, which is which is a
string.
We're calling the lines method on it.
So I'm going to depict that here.
So let's kind of imagine that that that people, people text variable is kind of feeding itself into
the lines method, if you will.
So here's our lines method.
And what we can kind of imagine.
Is kind of coming out of this line's method.
Now this is this is not to be taken literally OK, but this this is just a mental model that I'm kind
of giving you for how you maybe can think about it.
OK, so it's not necessarily exactly what's really happening inside the computer.
It's just a way of thinking about it.
OK?
So this line's method here, you could kind of imagine that it is spitting out one line at a time from
our text.
Are people text variable here?
And so what that might look like is one line of text write a string.
So let's say it spits out Flintstone, Fred and a date.
And then other stuff, right of the other fields.
Close quote So this quotation marks just are there to imply that this is a string, right?
It's a string of text.
OK.
So that's what's coming out of the lines method one at a time.
That's how you can think of it.
It's actually it's not that at all.
It's a stream of strings, right?
We saw that earlier.
But this is kind of how you can sort of think about it.
All right.
And then that that text is feeding into the map function.
A map function.
OK, now that map function is calling employee create employee.
So I'm going to skip the employee bit and just and just kind of render the create employee bit.
So let's see what that might kind of look like.
So here's our create employee method.
And now that's going to take as an input the text, the string that just came out of here.
OK.
So.
You can imagine that's going to look like this, Flintstone.
Fred.
One, one, one or whatever.
And then a bunch of text, right?
OK, and then I'll draw that inside of a nice, pretty box.
OK, now coming out of that map method.
Will then be an actual object of type I employee, because the create employee method returns objects
of type I employee, you can see it right there, create employee.
The output of that is something of type I employee, which is an interface.
OK, so the way I will depict that is by writing the name of this interface, I employee.
And then I'm going to draw a picture of a person that's just how I'm doing it.
This isn't like some standard documentation technique or anything.
This is just me making up something to convey to you some concepts here, and I'll label this employee
as Fred.
Flintstone.
And then I will enclose this person in a box and hold on a second here, I forgot to.
Forget something kind of important, so let me move that down a bit.
And forgot the era there.
OK, so.
The map function takes as an input.
That's that one string at a time.
Well, you can kind of imagine that it's taking one string at a time again.
In reality, it's taking as input a stream.
That's what it's actually taking.
OK.
But you can imagine for this case that essentially one line of text at a time is coming into this map
function.
The map function is then passing that text into the Create employee method.
The Create employee method is in turn returning an object of Type I employee.
Which is.
Which is this guy here, right?
And now we're ready to move on to the next step in our pipeline, which is the four each, so draw another
arrow here and we'll scroll up a little or can't scroll anymore.
OK, that's all right.
So now we're at the four each for each.
And the for each method is calling the print line system that out print line, and I will only depict
the print line there.
So again, I'll just do something like this print line.
Now, as the input into that, actually, I want to draw this a little bigger as the input into the
print line method.
What you can kind of envision is that we're not passing in text because we're not we're passing in that
entire I employee object, which I will depict here as this whole entire person inside of my parentheses,
right?
So these are the parentheses of the print line function or method, right?
And then I will encapsulate the four each in its own box.
Now the for each function here in our pipeline is a terminal operation, which means that it's kind
of the end of the line.
It's the end of the pipeline.
So it will not have any output for itself.
However, since we are calling, since it is calling the print line method, what we can do is kind
of envision off to the side here.
I'm going to draw an old style TV and I am not.
And artist, as you may have already realized, many of you may be too young to even recognize that
this little picture represents a TV at all because TV's don't have antenna anymore, but whatever.
And and so what's going to basically happen here is.
We can kind of imagine that this this print line call is going to result in one line of text being drawn
here, and I don't know, I'll make this super small for a minute and then we'll just do our.
Flintstone.
Fred.
One one one.
Blah blah blah.
Right.
In fact, I guess I could put that in in quotes, so you get the picture right.
And then here's more lines that will eventually be rendered.
All right.
So that's one iteration of this pipeline.
Now what's going to kind of happen here is you can imagine that each of these lines appear.
Let's label them one, two, three, four five like that.
So basically, each of these lines in the in the.
In the people text, the variable is kind of going to run through this pipeline one at a time.
You can again, that's not exactly really how it works, but that's functionally how you can imagine
it's working OK.
I think that will help you to wrap your head around this.
OK, so what you effectively have here is a loop without actually making a loop.
That's that's kind of what you basically have.
OK.
And so you can even imagine that, you know, this kind of non loop is going to come back up to the
second item in the list and then that's going to run through the pipeline.
And then and then we're going to go for a third iteration, right?
And then a fourth iteration.
And a fifth iteration and so on and so forth until the until the until we've run out of all the lines
to process in our stream.
OK, so maybe that'll that'll help to give you a little bit more firm understanding of, generally speaking,
how these how the streams API is kind of sort of working or at least how you can imagine that it might
be working so that you can kind of apply your reasoning to what you see here in code.
So I'm going to wrap up this lesson and in the next one will dig in more on some more cool tricks that
we can do with the Streams API and continue to implement some of the functionality that we had over
in the other class.
So I'll see you in the next one.