All right, so picking up where we left off, we are now going to take a look at exercise 8.4.
So this one is pond can move too forward on first move.
And this represents an interesting little rule of chess that perhaps many of you are familiar with.
And that is the fact that generally speaking, at the beginning of a chess game, you can actually choose
to move upon one step forward or two steps forward, but only at the beginning of the game if that pond
had not moved before.
So just quickly, here I will show you this.
And again, I'm on Wikipedia here taking a look at their article on chess, and it nicely depicts this
fact.
So we've got a pond here on Square two, and these two axes actually represent the two legal or valid
moves that this pond could make from this position at this point in time.
So we've already covered this one here, where the pond could simply move one square forward, but there's
also this additional square, which is two squares forward.
All right, so let's see how I implemented this capability.
We'll start off here in the test and let me make some room.
So here's my test.
Pond can move two forward on first move, so it's important to note that this is only valid on the first
move.
And that obviously is assuming that your pond is starting in the in the proper starting position, which
it has to in a proper chess game.
So I create a pond, it will be a white pond.
I decide to place that pond at Square A2, so that would be here on this board.
In fact, let me let me zoom in a little bit.
So that would be a pond right here at eight two.
And then I get the valid moves for that pond and then I create a coordinate representing Square A four,
so that would be here a fourth.
So we started at eight two and now I'm making a square coordinate that represents square a four.
And then I will assert that one of the valid moves that we got back from this method call, which returns
an array of of moves, is in fact the a four square.
All right.
So then let's go see how I implemented this, and it's actually pretty easy.
So I'm jumping into this get valid moves method here.
Now, we already took a look at how I implemented the move one forward use case where I just used this
offset mechanism here for the coordinates class.
And so it became very easy for me to implement additional use cases using basically this same mechanism.
However, there was one additional criterion that I had to consider.
This ability to move two squares forward is only permitted on the first move.
OK, so we need a way to write code to track.
Has this pond moved before?
And if it hasn't, then you're allowed to do this move, otherwise you cannot do it right.
And so what I opted to do was to implement a field on the pond class called has moved.
And the basic idea here is whenever we ask the pond to move, we will make sure that we set this field
to true, OK.
And so with that field there, I went ahead and made use of the offset capability of our coordinates
to simply state one of your legal moves is to move forward by not one, but two squares.
And of course, no change to the x axis right.
So don't move left or right.
That would be zero, but you can move forward by two squares.
So I create that offset coordinate added to the valid moves.
However, I only do this if the pond has never moved.
So this field here is right up here in the pond.
Now, notice a couple of things.
I do not put this field in the chess piece class because this is specific behavior specific, rule specific
data that is tied only to the Pon class, OK.
And so this belongs only on the pond class.
And so I initialize this field to fall, OK, because at the beginning of the game, that would be the
case, right?
It has not yet moved.
And so the rest is pretty straightforward as long as it hasn't moved.
We can add the ability to move forward by two and then we simply return the valid moves.
And so then if we return to the unit test, that means we will end up with a valid move to a four and
we will find that and everything else makes sense, right?
So that's pretty straightforward.
Now one thing I also want to show you real quick here that I was thinking about as I was reviewing my
last video, I'm going to go back into the get valid.
Moves method here.
I realized one thing I could actually make this code probably a little bit clearer, just a tiny bit
clearer if I actually just made it so that moving forward is conveyed using positive integers instead
of negative integers, this is a little counterintuitive.
And the reason it's this way is because when I initially implemented this move forward capability by
one square, I had not yet implemented the solution to work for both the black and the white chess pieces.
And so all I was thinking about initially was just what number do I need this to be in order to make
a white piece move forward by one?
And we already looked in the last lesson that you need to decrement the y axis value by one.
Because white pieces are moving negatively on the y axis, right?
Because I'm using an array where it's zero one two three four five six seven, right?
And so I was going from like six to five or whatever it was.
But I realized as I was reviewing the last lesson that I could actually just flip these signs and then
flip what I'm doing inside of this method.
So let's do that real quick.
I'm just going to get rid of the negatives here.
I'm going to multi select with an option, shift all of my negatives there, and then I'm just going
to get rid of those.
And so then I can jump in to this calculate y method here.
And then all I need to do is just flip these two signs.
So I'm just flipping everything around, OK?
And so now if I go back into the test for the pine and just rerun everything, hopefully I didn't break
anything.
So let's see.
Very good.
OK, so cool.
I didn't break anything there.
So let's just take one more look at that.
Just to make it clear, right?
So now whether we're talking about black pieces or white pieces, if we want them to move forward with
respect to whatever side of the board they're from, we can always convey that with positive numbers,
which intuitively makes more sense.
And so this just goes to show that sometimes when you're writing code, the first idea or the first
thoughts that will come to your mind may be sufficient to get things going.
But as you work with the code further, you may start to realize, Oh, you know, I could make this
code more intuitive if I made this minor tweak, and now my brain has to do a little bit less translating,
you know?
And so now, yeah, moving forward, it feels more natural to say that moving forward should have something
to do with a positive number rather than a negative number.
So that's a nice little update there.
All right.
So let's jump back over to the test, and I think we're ready to move on to the next one.
OK, so let's see.
The next use case was get test cannot move to after 1st move passing.
So that's the thing.
Make this test pass cannot move to after the first move.
So now we want to kind of test the opposite case of this eighth floor, right?
We said that if the Pine hasn't moved before, then one of its valid moves is the ability to move too
forward.
What if it has moved before?
Is one of its valid moves still that it can move forward two squares?
It should not be right.
And so we want to test that negative case, essentially.
OK, so let's take a look at how I implemented that.
All right.
So here's the test cannot move to after 1st move.
So the way I decided to do this was to create a pun and then set its coordinates to eight two.
Then I immediately set its coordinates to a three.
Now, why do I do that?
Well, basically, I'm just trying to roughly simulate the idea that the pond started off on a two and
then maybe the game started, and then maybe the pond was moved to a three.
And then we ask the pond, What are your valid moves now that you're on a three and not a two anymore?
That's really all I'm trying to do with this test.
So let's just take a look at how I implemented that.
And I think a good place to start here is actually to take a look at the pond set coordinates method
itself.
So a couple of things to note here.
So now I'm in the set coordinates method of the pond class, but I want to show you something here that
you may not have realized or you may have forgotten this method on the pond.
Class set coordinates is actually an overridden method, which means that a superclass of the pond class
actually is already defining.
This set coordinates method, and we can jump into that method by clicking on this little icon here
with the up arrow to kind of go up the hierarchy chain.
So here we are on the chess piece class and there's that set coordinates method.
And so this method is literally just setting the coordinates and the coordinates are an internal field
of the chess piece.
So basically, just as a quick reminder here, any fields that should be generally common to all chess
pieces should be on the chess piece class.
OK?
We don't want to duplicate these fields on the pond class and the night class, et cetera, et cetera.
These should just be consolidated on the chess piece class, since these are properties that are common
to all chess pieces.
Likewise, the set coordinates method should be common to all chess pieces as well.
But if we are dealing with a pawn, we want to know when the coordinates of a pawn have changed so that
we have an opportunity to specify that this internal pawn field has moved should now be changed from
false to true.
And so by overriding the set coordinates method, that gives us an opportunity to do a little extra
behavior that is specific to a pawn, but not necessarily specific to the other chess pieces.
Does that make sense?
And again, this is a nice little example of making use of some of the standard object oriented capabilities
and techniques.
So under normal circumstances, set coordinates can just do what it normally would do for all chess
pieces.
But in this one case, a pawn needs to do a little bit more than what a.
Right or wrong or king or Bishop might have to do.
We want to be able to track whether or not that -- has ever been moved subsequently.
The other thing I want you to notice, though, is that I don't just set this flag to true.
I actually check something here.
If this dot coordinates is not null, then I set this to true.
Now, why do I do that?
Well, let's go take a look at the coordinates.
So as you'll see here, when we first create a chess piece that chess pieces coordinates are not being
initialized in the declaration, nor are they being initialized in a constructor.
OK, so by default, the coordinates will start off being null.
So when we first place the horn at Square A2, which was the first line of code in the test, the coordinates
will be null.
And so if the coordinates are null, then we're not going to do any of this will simply set the coordinates
as they would normally have been done and move on with our life.
But the next time we set the coordinates to a three, well, now the coordinates are not null.
And so now we can specify that this pine has moved.
Does that make sense?
So that's just the way that again, I'm able to track whether or not this is the first time this pine
is being placed at a coordinate, which is A2.
So like the initial time or has it moved subsequently?
OK.
Because if I did not do this check, then the has moved field would be set to true.
And then I would not be getting this ability to move twice on the first movement when I call the get
valid moves method right.
So I need this here at the very beginning of the game, but not after the Pine has been moved.
So that's just the way that I chose to code that check.
And then everything else I think is pretty straightforward after that.
All right.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next one.
So the next one is the fact that we want to get the can move one diagonally, right?
Test passing.
All right.
So what this use case is simply saying is that one of the valid moves of a pond.
Generally speaking, under under certain circumstances, which we are not yet coding specifically,
is that a pun could potentially move diagonally to the right or diagonally to the left.
If it is trying to capture an enemy piece, OK, now if there is no enemy peace on one of those two
squares, the pun actually is not permitted to move there.
We're not going to implement that part of the rule at this time.
But in general, one of the valid moves could be that the pond could go diagonally to the right or left
if it was capturing a piece.
OK.
So I wanted to just have us write code to calculate where those two squares would be, and I stay here
on eight six, though this is only permitted when the pond can capture a piece.
We won't factor that in for now.
OK.
So first one I do is can move one diagonally, right?
And so let's just go take a look at how I did that.
So I implemented another offset here, where the x axis offset is plus one, meaning that the pun is
going to move to the right and also forward by one.
So one forward and one to the right, which would be like moving one forward and one to the right.
Right.
So this pun would end up here where this night is.
And so I think that's pretty straightforward.
And then I'm going to go ahead and jump to the next use case where I also implemented the ability to
move diagonally to the left.
And so that's the same as this, except with a negative one.
OK, so that would be negative one on the x axis or x offset and then forward by one as well.
So that would put this upon where the rook is.
OK.
And so that's how he can calculate these two moves now.
Like I said, for now, we're not taking into account whether or not there actually is a piece here.
We may go ahead and do that too, because I think that would actually be a pretty fun, little additional
bit of logic that we could put in because presumably in order to do that, the pawn would need to know,
Is there an enemy piece on this square or that square?
And only if there is one, then the pawn is allowed to add that square into it's possible.
Valid moves, right?
So that would be kind of cool to teach the python how to determine that, I think.
All right.
So let's jump back to the tests.
So that pretty much covers all of those standard movements of upon moving forward by one square, moving
forward by two squares and then being able to sometimes move diagonally to the right or to the left.
Though again, we're not considering whether or not there's an enemy occupying those diagonal squares
at this time.
The additional tests that I have here now are just making sure that that basic functionality also should
work well for black pieces, since the logic is a little bit opposite in terms of what it means to move
forward, right?
And so here I'm just testing black pieces ability to move forward by one and then black piece can move
forward by two, and I didn't bother doing black pieces moving diagonally and all of that because in
this case, I was very satisfied that if these two tests were passing that the diagonal moves would
would work just fine since we didn't write explicit additional code to cover black piece movement anyway.
Once I saw that these two tests were working, then I was comfortable that everything was working and
like I already showed earlier, I'll just show very, very briefly again.
The main magic of what allows these black pieces to move is this method here.
Calculate why with direction factor where we simply basically say, if the piece is white, then multiply
this number of times negative one.
And if the piece is black, then multiply this number times positive one.
That's basically all we needed to do to make black pieces and white pieces.
Both work.
Oh, and I have one other little update that I was thinking about as I was reviewing my past videos.
So we've got the ability here to set this offset, right?
And then the result of this method get offset is to return a new coordinate object.
OK.
So really, the coordinate objects here are meant to be immutable, meaning that after we create an
instance of a coordinate, we cannot change the X and Y values of that coordinate object to any further.
If we want to get another coordinate related to a particular instance, we'd have to do something like
call this get offset method.
And so one minor change that I was thinking about here is that typically when we are dealing with a
class that is immutable, but it has methods on it like this one that which can give us new instances
of that class based off of the existing instance, right?
So this get offset method here is giving us a new instance that is based off of the existing coordinates,
right?
Typically, a pattern that you'll see quite often in a number of programming languages that that deal
with immutable object instances is that a method like this might actually be called something like with
offset rather than get offset.
Naming this get offset might imply that we're not getting a coordinate, but we're actually getting
some kind of offsets.
And that's not quite what we're doing here.
We're we're passing in the offsets.
And then we want to get another coordinate.
So I propose actually just changing the name of this method from get offset to with offset.
So I'm going to just put my cursor right there and do a shift f six and then I'm just going to select
the words Get Whoops.
Yet and I'm just going to change that to with Offset, that's just a naming pattern that you will see
more often when you're dealing with these immutable object types.
And then I will hit return.
OK.
And in fact, I think we will see this naming pattern a little bit when you learn more about the date
and time classes in Java, because the revised date and time classes of modern versions of Java are
all immutable.
And so you can get new dates and times based on existing date time objects using methods that look a
lot like this with offset in time, offset and things of that sort.
OK, so I just want to be a little more consistent here.
And so I think that is all we're going to do with the pond for right now.
And so we'll keep going through the rest of these use cases in the in the next lesson.
So I will see you there.