All right, so continuing on now, we're going to take a look at the exercises from number 10 on, so
these tests are focused on the movements of the night.
And I included them because the night moves in particularly interesting and perhaps strange ways, which
I think I had already kind of mentioned earlier.
So the first test here, number 10, switching to the night test that Java file, the first Test to
get passing is Knight can move northeast.
Now let me show you what I meant with all of these different directions.
These are just my own nomenclature for how to describe the movements.
These are not like standard chess terms or anything.
OK, so by Northeast, what I simply meant was that one of the movements that the pond could make would
be two steps north or forward and then east, which would be one step to the right.
OK, so northeast two steps forward, one step to the right.
OK, northeast.
So we just want to write some code that checks that this square here relative to where the night is,
is one of all of these potentially valid squares that the pond could move to.
OK.
So let's see how I did that.
All right.
So I'm going to jump into the night test.
Here we go.
And here's the very first one night can move northeast.
So I create a new instance of a white knight, and then I set the coordinates to see one.
So see, one would be right here.
And then I get the valid moves and then I create an expected coordinate of the three.
So we're starting on see one, and I'm wanting to confirm that one of the valid squares that a night
on C one could move to would be up up over, which would be right here.
D3.
And so that's what I've got there.
And then there's my assertion.
All right, so let's see how I did this one.
So I will jump into the get valid moves method now.
Remember, this is going to be the get valid moves method for the night, not for the --.
OK.
So you can already see that this looks a little more streamlined now.
Part of the reason for that is because I didn't bother to capture a variable name for these movements
and then set them on the array separately.
I decided to consolidate all of that into single lines just so it would be more convenient to look at,
I guess.
So here's the very first one and notice.
I also just made these comments here Northeast, so I'm still using the offsets with the coordinates.
And now all I have to say is go one to the right and go to up.
Now notice, though here I did not yet flip these signs.
Remember, I flipped the signs and then I changed the code for this calculate y with direction factor.
So actually, right now, if I go and run the night tests, I'm thinking they're probably going to fail.
Let's let's just see real quick here.
Let's run all of these night tests.
And that several of them, maybe all of them will fail.
Now, actually, that's pretty interesting.
They actually are all still passing.
I have a suspicion that maybe the reason that they are passing is because the pattern of legal spots
is symmetrical.
So from sea one, one of the valid squares would be this square right here, which would mirror a square
that would be two squares back this way if we could keep going with the squares in this direction,
you know.
So in other words, they're a mirror.
Each of these has a mirror.
This, in fact, if we pretend like this, if we pretend like this is see one for a moment, then one
of the valid squares would be this one here, which would be to forward and to the right, but to backward
and to the right would be here, which is a mirror of this one.
So I suspect what may be happening here is that the unit test is still passing because it's picking
up on the equivalent of this square here instead of this one.
That's that's my guess as to what what's probably allowing that to work at any rate.
Let me go ahead and switch the signs of all of these still.
So I'm just going to go ahead and just flip all the signs.
He united America's enemies, and I didn't use my fancy multi-person selection here because I didn't
want to lose track of which ones should be negative and which ones should be positive, it was easier
to just do each one at a time in this case.
So now let me jump back over to the night test again, and let's just run everything and see if they
all still pass.
Hopefully they do.
Yeah, yeah.
So I think that kind of just proves that the reason why these work in either direction is because of
the mirror effect, which actually does suggest that maybe I could have written even better tests that
wouldn't work if you mirrored things.
And one way that I probably could have done that.
I'm not going to do it here.
But one way that I maybe could have done that is to have used a different origin or a different starting
position.
We're like just random, different starting positions for each of these tests.
But instead, what I did was I used a lot of the same positions and I even kind of used mirror positions
for each, for in many cases.
So for example, these two for east, northeast and northwest both starred on C one.
And even this one here is C one.
Then I used C three, which I think was a mirror.
C one was here, then C three OK, well, maybe not so much of a mirror for that one, but I think I
ended up using a lot of the same origins for a lot of the same tests.
All right.
But anyway, so that works.
And so I don't think I really need to go through any of the details of the rest of these because all
of the rest of these moves are really just variations on the same thing, right?
So if the line can move north, west or east, north or east south, for example, all I did was something
like, OK, east south would be two to the right and then one down, which is here or south east, which
would be two to south and then one east southwest to south one west.
West, south to west, one south west, north to west, one north, et etc., OK.
And all I had to do then was just keep using the offset right to specify how many to the left or how
many to the right, or how many to the left and how many up and how many down, basically, OK.
So I think I think that makes sense, right?
So let's just take one more look at the implementation here, and you can see that again.
So north east to north, one east to north, one west, one north to east, et cetera, et cetera.
And then I'm just storing all of those moves in this array and then returning the array.
And that's super simple.
OK, so let's see now.
So I'm going to skip over all the rest of these because they're pretty much all the same thing now that
you've taught your -- and night classes how they're permitted to move.
Let's enable them to be moved by the chessboard class.
Going back to the tests for the chess board in the chess board test Java file, please implement the
ability can move.
See one night to D3.
The test will create a chess board and add a night at sea one.
It will assert that the night is on Square C one, then it will.
It will then request the chess board to move the night to D3.
It will then assert that the night is no longer at C one and that it is now at D3.
So I know this may sound really obvious that I'm being really explicit here, but this is the nature
of halfway, decently written tests.
So let's just take a look at the chess board to see what we're saying here.
So we're going to start tonight on Square C one.
Then we're going to ask the chess board to move the night to D three, and then we are going to assert
at least a couple of things.
We will assert that the night is no longer on c one and that it is now one D3.
So let's see what that would look like.
So we'll have the chess board now place a night at C one, then we will ask the chess board to move
the night to D three, and then we will assert that the night is here and no longer here on C one.
All right, so let's take a look at that.
OK, so here it is.
Can move C one night to D three, so we create an instance of a chessboard, then we create a white
knight.
Then we ask the board to add the knight to Square C one.
Then we ask the board to give us the peace at coordinates C one so that we can just confirm our starting
state.
We want to just confirm that we asked the board to put a white knight on C one and then we want to turn
around and ask the board, Is there still a night at C one at this point, which there should be?
OK, so we use an assert equals to say that the night that we created here should be the night that
we get back from the board at Position C one.
OK, so this is all really just set up OK at this point.
All right.
So now that we've confirmed that our night is where we said it should be.
We then ask the board, please move this night to D3, then we assert a couple of things.
First, we assert that when we ask the board what piece is now at C1, it should be null and we can
do that directly within assert null.
And if for any reason this assertion, this null assertion happens to be false, we will be presented
with this message after move night should no longer be at C1.
OK, so that'll let us know that this particular assertion is the one that failed.
And you may recall that I mentioned before.
I don't frequently use multiple assertions in one test method or in one in one test method, but one
place where I will often use them is if I have multiple assertions in a method like this one here,
because otherwise it can be a little difficult to determine when this test method fails.
Where did it feel like which assertion is the failing assertion?
And so when you get this message here, then it lets you know which assertion failed.
And then finally, I assert that the board sees the P Z, the three as being that night.
So that just lets me know that the board indeed did move that night from C one to D three.
So there's no chance of a copy of the night still being at C1 and at D3 or something crazy like that.
I want to know that it literally moved that night from C one to three.
So let's take a quick look at how I did that.
We'll take a look at the move method here.
All right.
So this gets a little bit more involved.
So the first thing I do is get the starting coordinates of our chess piece, which would be C one.
OK, so that's what we're doing here.
Get the peace, which in this case would be the night, get its coordinates, and I just store those
coordinates right here in a variable called origin, right?
The starting.
Position then I create a new coordinates from the requested destination, which was D3, right?
And so there's the destination or the requested destination.
Now I'm checking some things.
If the destination is occupied by a friendly piece, meaning a chess piece of the same color as the
piece that we're moving, then basically I'm saying do nothing.
This return with nothing here means do nothing.
OK, now this will be an exercise that comes up later.
But since we're looking through the code, I'm choosing to go ahead and explain this at least a little
bit right now.
But maybe I won't dig into how this method is working, but just know that this little bit here, this
condition here is simply saying if the destination that we want to move to is already occupied by a
friendly piece of the same color, then don't do the move because that's an invalid move.
And then I have another condition here.
If the destination is occupied by an enemy, meaning a chess piece of the opposite color, then I do
allow for a lot of things that I'm not going to get into right now because that's also a future use
case.
OK, so we're going to skip over both of these now for what we're doing right now.
Neither of these cases are valid.
OK, we're not moving to a destination that's occupied by a friendly.
Nor are we moving to a destination that's occupied by an enemy.
Instead, we're moving to a destination that is empty.
And so that is going to be covered right down here.
Perform actual move.
OK.
And I pass in the piece the destination coordinates as text.
I believe the as a string and then the origin as a coordinate object and the destination as a coordinate
object.
And probably, I don't actually need this one, I think.
But let's just see.
So let's dig into this perform actual move, because that's where we're doing the good stuff.
So here's the perform actual move method.
So I have a condition here that says if the destination is a permitted move, then get all the valid
moves.
So I have this method call here within the conditional saying destination that is permitted move.
And then we pass into this method.
All of the chess pieces, valid moves.
So really, all I'm trying to do here is to determine whether or not this destination here is one of
the valid moves.
That's really all we're doing here.
And actually, we're essentially doing this exact same kind of check in some of our tests themselves.
Let me just jump over real quick and remind you if we go into the pond tests, for example, this method
right here is Move found an array that's actually pretty much the same move.
So I actually did end up copying this code essentially.
So remember this this method here takes a coordinate and then checks to see if that coordinate is contained
within an array of coordinates.
That's all this is doing.
That's essentially what this guy is doing as well, except I kind of flipped it inside out, and now
the code to do the checking is right here.
So let's jump into that real quick and see.
So there's our familiar for loop right there.
And so again, we're just iterating over all of the moves.
All of the coordinates passed in to this method and checking to see is one of these moves or coordinates
equal to this coordinate that we're in here.
Now this code here is permitted new.
This is a method on the coordinate class.
OK.
In this particular case?
All right.
So let me just make sure this is clear what you're seeing here with the word this that method is on
the destination.
OK.
So I'm going to jump back into here is permitted move.
And so we're saying if any one of these permitted moves, which are these moves here is equal to this
destination move, right?
Because when this code is running, we will be inside of one instance of a destination coordinate.
So we're saying, is this destination one of these permitted moves?
And in fact, maybe I should even rename this variable here to permitted moves just to be even more
clear permitted moves.
OK.
And if it is one of these permitted moves, then return to true.
Otherwise, finish up that loop and then just return a false and I could go ahead and probably rewrite
this method to use the enhanced for loop also.
And in fact, one thing I think I can do if I click on this light bulb here, I think the idea can do
that for it's replaced with enhanced floor.
Let's see what the l- look at that isn't that isn't that awesome?
Now that's intelligent doing that.
That's not Java that was just intelligent, recognizing that, oh yeah, you could just use the enhanced
for loop here.
So that was kind of cool.
I don't think I've ever used that before.
I kind of knew that it was sort of there, but until it does so many.
Things, folks, there, there are capabilities that intelligence has that I sort of kind of see from
time to time, but there's just so much that even I just can't bring myself to always, like consciously
think, Oh, I should use this or I should use that, there's just so much there.
But that was kind of nice.
I'll probably use that again someday.
All right.
So that's what that's doing.
So if the destination that we're trying to get to is one of the permitted destinations, then we do
something kind of cool.
We access the internal array of the chessboard.
Remember that internal two dimensional array, we access the internal rate of the the chessboard.
And the first thing we do is we erase the night on C one by setting the array element that was storing
the night to null.
OK.
So that is to say, we first find the element in the array that corresponds to this square here.
See one in this particular case.
And then we set it to null, which will remove the night from that square.
OK, so that's what we're doing.
They remove from original square.
Then we simply call the add method and add the night to the destination coordinates.
So that's the way that we originally were putting any pieces on the chessboard anyway.
So it's always nice to reuse our own methods here.
So we have this add method right up here was like the very first method I ever wrote that just allows
us to add a piece to the board.
All right.
And so that's how we get the chess piece there.
By the way, I don't remember if I explicitly showed or or talked about this, but you know, in our
Pon and night tests, we didn't even have a chess board, and we were just kind of telling the chess
piece where it was on and an imaginary board by calling P starts at coordinates.
As you can see here, the chess board itself also does this.
It tells the chess piece where it is on the board by calling piece that set coordinates.
So some things will not work correctly if we ever move a chess piece without telling the chess piece
what its own internal coordinates are.
And that's another reason why I'm using the add method to do this.
That way, I can ensure that not only does the chess board have its internal board array updated to
note where that pieces, but also the piece knows where it is.
Now, some of you might be wondering if I'm setting the coordinates on the piece directly.
Why do we even need this internal board?
Also, why do we need that?
Well, the reason we're going to need that is because the chess board itself needs to know where all
the pieces are.
And later on, we'll see a use case where that'll come in.
So I'm not going to go too much more into detail on that right now, but just know that the board needs
to know where everything is, OK.
And so this array just gives us a way to allow the board to track where is everybody?
So the chess pieces need to know where they are so that they can generate their valid moves, right?
They need to know their own position, but the board needs to know where everybody is for various other
use cases.
All right, so let's jump back over to the tests.
And so now I think we have seen how all of this test is working, and I think we'll stop here and we'll
pick back up on the next test in the next lesson.
I'll see you there.