OK, so now let's move on to exercise 20.
So this one says, per the cannot move c one night to invalid square, implement the ability to prevent
the night from being moved to invalid squares, such as from C one to D four.
Now let's just see what that would look like.
So from C one to D four, which would be up here?
Now remember this little dot here is for this depiction of this white knight here.
But we're pretending like we've got a night down here.
So to D four would be invalid because that would not be in the pattern of one, one and two, right?
That would be one one one or one two three and then over, which is not the correct pattern.
So therefore it would not be a valid square to move to from C one.
So what we're going to do then in this exercise is we're going to first write a test to first place
a night at C one, then request the board to move it to D four and then see what happens essentially.
OK, so here's the test.
And so here I am, creating a board, creating a night, asking the board to add the night to see one,
then asserting that the night is starting off at C one, which should be true, then requesting that
the board move the night to D for then asserting that D4 should be null.
OK, so in other words, I'm asserting that even though I asked the board to move the night to D for
the board should essentially ignore me.
And so when I check to say, Hey board, what's that d for?
The answer should be nothing which is null.
And then if I assert that the P Z C one is a night, then that should be true.
So all I'm doing here is just asserting that if I asked the board to move my night to an invalid square,
nothing's going to change that.
It will simply ignore me.
All right.
So let's look a little bit more now at how that should be working.
So here's the move here.
We're grabbing the origin and the destination coordinates, and then we're checking if that's a friendly
square, which it's not.
We're checking if it's an enemy square, which it also is not.
And so finally, we come down here to the perform actual move again just as before.
But now this condition here is actually going to do its job a little bit more because now we're going
to check is the destination square, which is D4 contained essentially within the array of valid moves.
This method here is going to do that check, and it's going to determine that no, this destination
of D4 is not contained within all of the calculated valid moves for our night.
Considering where it currently is located, and therefore none of this here is going to be executed,
our thread is just going to evaluate this.
It's going to evaluate to false and then the thread will jump right over all of that and exit this method
without having done anything at all.
OK.
And so that is why this code is here.
Now let me also make one other point clear again, and I may mention this a few more times sorry, you
are seeing my code written to satisfy all 22 as of the time of this recording.
All 22 exercises under exercise.
Eight.
All 22 sub exercises under exercise.
Let me put it that way, so I don't want you to have the impression that I wrote all of this code and
and then I went and wrote all of those tests.
I wrote this code right here in this way.
Only once I encountered the exercise that required me to implement this kind of a check.
OK.
So I wrote this code 90 percent adherent to TDD principles.
At least 90 percent, in fact.
OK.
All right.
So jumping back over to the test, so that's how that is working.
And now we can jump to the next one, which is per the cannot move c one night to friendly occupied
square.
Implement the ability to prevent the knight from being moved to a square that is already occupied by
another chess piece of the same color.
A friendly.
OK.
So again, we'll start on C one.
But now we will also simulate the idea that there is a pawn at D3 and we are requesting to move the
knight to D3.
OK?
Upon of the same color as the Knight.
So turning back to the test, let's see how I set that one up.
I create a chess board, then I create a pawn who is white, and I add that pawn to the board at D3.
Then I create a knight who is also white and add him to the board at See One.
Then I assert that I have the Knight at sea one.
Then I request the board to move the knight to the three.
Then I assert that at D3, I have a pawn still not a knight, but a pawn.
And I also assert that at C one, I still have the knight.
So in other words, I'm asserting that even though I requested the board to move my knight to D3, in
actuality, nobody moved anywhere at all.
That's what this test is testing.
All right.
And so now let's go see how I implemented that in a little bit more detail.
So again, I grabbed the origin of the Knight, which would be c one and I grabbed the destination,
which is D3.
And then I check if destination is occupied by a friendly and I pass in the the the piece and the destination,
then just don't don't do anything, just return.
Which means to exit this this move method without having done anything, OK?
So really, the magic here is contained all in this one method.
So let's jump into that method and see what it's really doing.
So it's not a big method at all.
So let's see, though.
So I pass in the piece and then the destination.
So what I'm doing is first I ask the chess boards internal two-dimensional array to give me the piece
at our destination coordinates here.
OK, so I just say destination, I get X and get Y.
And so I get the piece here.
So then I'm really just applying a little bit of logic here and I'm using and and here, OK?
So two ampersand together is a logical end.
All right.
So what this is saying is that if the destination piece is not null, meaning it, it's occupied already,
right?
D3 in this case is occupied already, and its color is the same as the color of the piece that we're
trying to move, which in this case is the night.
So that's what I'm saying here.
If the destination piece that we got out of here, which might not be null in this case, has the color
that is the same as the night or the piece that we're trying to move, then return true.
Now you don't see me explicitly saying true.
That's because I don't need to.
This whole entire expression will evaluate to a true if it's true, right?
So if we have a destination piece that isn't null and if the colors match, then that's all going to
be true.
So return a true.
Otherwise, we turn a false if either of these two clauses are not true.
OK, so this is kind of a neat way of being able to say if without actually having to say if at all.
OK, I may not have ever explicitly said this to you, but obviously, right, if you use an ampersand
test like this, is this true and is this true, then you know what you will get out of?
There is a Boolean.
One other nice thing to note about this construct here on Line Fifty Seven is that if the destination
coordinates on the board are empty.
As was the case for our earlier tests, then this destination piece here would be null.
And so when the thread comes down here and evaluates this bit right here, destination piece would be
null.
And in that case, the thread will not even evaluate the rest of this.
It doesn't need to, because with a logical and operation, if the first expression that the thread
evaluates is false, then the thread can stop right there, right?
Because it knows well, if this is zero, then there's no point in evaluating this because the end is
going to be false.
And so that's actually kind of a nice thing to keep in mind.
Sometimes if the thing that you wanted to do on this side of the and operation was expensive, like
a very expensive calculation or call to somewhere, you don't want that evaluation to take place if
this one here is false on the left.
So just make sure that you put your cheaper evaluation, perhaps on the left.
That's kind of, I guess, part of the point.
All right.
So jumping back over here then?
So now we see that if the destination is occupied by friendly, which in this case it is, then don't
do anything, just return, which is what we're going to get there.
And so that's how this test works.
All right.
And then let's go look at this last one then can move.
See one night to enemy occupied square.
So this is saying that you can move to an enemy occupied square.
All right.
So up here we were saying you cannot move to a friendly occupied square, but you can move to an enemy
occupied square.
That's how you capture your enemies pieces, right?
That's so you've got to be allowed to do that.
So let's see how this test works.
So again, we create a chessboard, and upon this time, I'm creating a black pawn, though placing
it at D3.
So just like we did up here, except now the pawn is black, creating a night, a white knight on c
one asserting that we're starting off with that night at sea one then requesting the board move our
knight to the three, and then we can assert a couple of things.
Now here I wanted to assert something a little more indirect.
So what I wanted to do here was to assert that if we move our knight onto an enemy square, that we
are going to capture the enemy that was on that square and that we would collect those enemy captured
pieces somewhere, or at least the board would capture them for us.
OK.
And so if you can imagine that every time you move a piece onto an enemy square and capture that enemy
piece, that those enemy pieces are being collected into a holding tank, a jail cell or something like
that.
So what I wanted was to be able to ask the board, give me all of the captured pieces for white, OK,
because my my knight is white in this case.
So give me all the captured pieces here.
And then I wanted to be able to assert that one of the pieces that got captured for white is the pawn
that started off at D3.
And so that's what I'm doing here now to do that checking.
I wrote this method, which again, is really just the same method that we've been using all along to
kind of iterate over things.
Now, this time, I ended up writing a one off version only because I kind of wanted to see what the
difference in feel would be for how I named this method.
What I really should have done, though, was to keep working on this and consolidate this method with
the other method that does pretty much the exact same thing, which is currently on the chess piece.
Superclass.
And maybe I'll do that with you.
I don't know yet, but but that's what I should have done, because it's the same method, really.
All right.
So this method again, is this iterating over looking for a match?
Also, I did the matching differently.
This time I use the equals operator here, which tests that two objects are the exact same object in
memory, and not that two objects share the same properties.
OK.
And the reason I did that is because at least for this test, I literally knew that the pond that I
created here should be the same pond that I'm getting out of here, though that would have been true
pretty much for the other places where I did this kind of looping as well.
But again, I was just trying some different things here.
So that's basically what it comes down to.
So don't read too deeply into Oh wow, he used equals operator here, but he used the dot equals method
in the other place.
So honestly, I likely will go ahead and consolidate these looping methods somewhere.
OK.
This is me just kind of experimenting a little bit.
All right.
So let's see how this is working then.
So we'll jump into the move.
All right.
So grabbing the origin and destination, if we're moving to an occupied friendly, which we're not.
So we'll skip over that if we're moving to an occupied enemy.
Where, though, which we are then?
Here's what we are going to do.
We retrieve the piece at the destination coordinates and I just wrote a little small utility method
to go do that.
So get the peace at the destination coordinates and we'll look at that method.
So that method is right here where we're passing in chess coordinates.
We build a coordinate object out of that.
Then we look inside the internal two dimensional array and we retrieve that piece and return it.
OK.
So we're getting that piece there, which in this case would be the black pawn at D3.
Then we want to basically take that black pawn off the board.
OK.
And the way that I choose to do that is by setting the Black Pond's coordinates to null.
So that's part of how I take the black pawn off the board.
Now, at this point, I have not removed the black pawn from these coordinates on the internal two dimensional
array, though.
OK, I've just set the Black Pine's internal coordinates to null.
All right.
Then I check what color the piece that we're requesting to move, which in this case is the night I
check that color.
If the piece that we're moving is white, then I have another utility kind of a method here to say add
two captured pieces where I pass in the captured piece, which is the black on, and I also pass in
an array that represents the captured pieces, which is which.
This is the white captured pieces.
OK?
So let me show you this array that's up here.
So I created a couple other arrays, white captured pieces and black captured pieces, and I initialize
this array to zero lengths.
OK.
Just to begin with, and I passed that in.
But somewhat strangely, now when I use this method here, add two captured pieces to add this piece
into either of these arrays.
I actually return a new array.
OK.
And so you're seeing me recapture this.
Now, the reason I chose to do it this way is because of the way that arrays work in Java.
So let's jump in here and we'll see what I'm doing here.
All right.
So here's my add to captured arrays.
So first, I use a utility method of Java on the arrays class to copy an array.
OK.
So I make a copy of the array that I just passed in.
But I make a copy of this array and add one additional element length to the array.
OK.
So in this case, the array started off zero lengths, meaning it's empty and I make a copy of it,
but I add one to it.
So now this temporary captures array here has a length of one.
Now it's still empty, so to speak, right?
I haven't placed any objects in it, but it has one holding tank now.
OK.
Then I take my captured piece and I set my captured piece in the one holding tank on this new temporary
captures array.
Then I return this temporary captures array.
OK.
Because it's a new array now.
And so if I go back to where I'm using this now, I'm setting this new one element array back on the
field of white captured pieces.
OK.
So I just want to make sure that this is somewhat clear for you.
So let me just state that one more time.
Our chess board starts off with an empty array for both white captured pieces and black captured pieces.
And then, when we call, add two captured pieces, we make a copy of that empty array.
But in our copy of that array, we set the length of the new copy to one instead of zero.
OK.
Then we store our captured piece in the one and only holding tank of this newly created array.
And then we return that newly created array from this ad to captured pieces method.
And then we set that newly created array back into the white captured pieces field of our board.
OK.
And so the next time we capture a white piece, we'd go through all of this again.
OK, but the next time we capture a white piece, if we were to jump back into this had two captured
pieces method again, we'd now start off with an array of size one.
But then we'd make a copy of that array, and the copy would now have a length of two.
And then we would store the newly captured piece in the second holding tank or the second element of
this newly created array.
And then we would return the newly created array, which would now have two captured enemy pieces in
it.
And every time we call the add to captured pieces method, we're going to make a copy of the array that
is one element bigger than the original array was.
We will.
Then copy our captured piece in to that last element of this newly copied array.
Then we will return the newly copied array and then that newly copied array will become the new array
for the entire board.
OK, so I hope I made that clear.
Now the reason I have to do that is because arrays cannot dynamically make themselves bigger.
All we can do with an array, if we want more space in an array, is to make a new array that is bigger
than the previous one.
Then copy all of the contents from the original array into the new array and then copy all of the contents
from the original array into the new array.
That's just how you have to do it.
OK.
But the arrays class makes it relatively easy to do that with this copy of method.
I encourage you, by the way, to take a look at all the methods that exist on the arrays class.
It has a lot of interesting methods on it, most of which I probably have never used.
And then we can do the same kind of thing for black captured pieces as well.
And then finally, the night is allowed to move just like it normally would have, even if the destination
square had been empty.
All right.
And so that is how that use case is working.
Now, while we're here and since I did bring up the fact that this element exists, method here is doing
the same thing as the method that I had placed on the chess piece tests class.
Let's just take a quick peek at the chess piece.
Test class here.
Remember this method right here, this guy?
So let's see chess coordinates.
Now, the reason why I have this method here is because it needs to iterate over all of the chess pieces
that may exist within a given array.
OK, now notice it's actually the same pattern as what I'm doing in the chess piece test class, but
working with different pieces.
This method here is technically looking for a chess piece, whereas in the chess piece test method,
we're iterating over coordinates.
But truth of the matter is these two methods are effectively doing pretty much the same thing.
All right.
So I may, in an upcoming lesson, go ahead and consolidate what we're doing here with what we're doing
in the chess piece test here.
But I'm not going to do it in this lesson here.
I'll save that for future lesson.
OK, so I'll see you in the next one.