All right, so in the last lesson, we added the ability to create children for a person and set those
children on the person and then save that person and then confirm that when we save the person, their
children are getting saved with them.
And we wrote this test to confirm that something along those lines was apparently actually happening
here because we could confirm that the IDs of the children were something other than zero as opposed
to null.
So that looks like it worked.
So in this lesson, we're now going to do the other side of this and enable the children to be retrieved
with the person when we find a person by ID.
Now, before we do that, I don't remember if we did this in the last lesson or not.
So I want to just run all the tests just to make sure we're good.
There seems like we did do this, but let's just make sure.
OK.
Very good.
So that's good.
OK, so then let's jump back down here to the can save person with children.
And now let's do a can find person with children.
Right?
So in fact, we've got a few can find person by ID with this address.
So yeah, let's just add another one down here.
Test.
Public void can find person by I.D. with children.
All right.
So I guess we'll just start off with much of what we did for the save right here.
So all of that I will copy and come down here and let me just restate in case any of you are wondering,
because I keep harping on this whole idea that if you're copying data and pasting it, then maybe you
should be extracting a method that tends to be particularly true with our implementation code or the
code that is the system under test.
In my mind, it's a little more nuanced when we're in the test code itself.
Now, I certainly could re-use this block of code, which I just copied from up above.
But in my own opinion, I think that might actually obscure the clarity of what I'm trying to accomplish
with this test.
But it is certainly a possibility for consideration.
If I was possibly going to have a lot of tests that used this same setup or very, very similar setup
such that I could parameter ize a method and reuse it, I might give stronger consideration to doing
that.
But so far, I'm just copying that code one time.
And I think by being able to explicitly see that I'm creating the person and the children and then saving
them, and now I'm getting ready to load that back up or whatever.
I think that actually makes this test a little more clear to see the intent here.
All right.
So anyway, so we will presumably have successfully saved this person with their children.
And so then we can retrieve this person repo, find my I.D. and we will reference the saved person's
ID like so and then we will call get and then we will save a reference to that and call it found person.
As we're doing up here just to stick with the basic format here and now, a few things that we could
consider doing in order to assert that these children actually got loaded properly.
The easiest thing probably that we could do is just assert that the bound person has three children,
right?
So that would be really easy to do.
A little bit better than that might be to verify that there are three children and that their names
are Johnny, Sarah and Jenny.
Because then we'd really know not only that we got those objects, but that we got some of the data
associated with the objects as well.
So let's let's see what our options are here.
So let's do an assert that found person dot get children.
So if we wanted to confirm that there are children with the names of Johnny, Sierra and Jenny.
One way that I can think of doing that would be to actually use the Streams API and map all of the children.
Assuming that we got the children out, we could map those children to just their first names and then
collect those first names into a collection.
And then there should be a certain methods that would allow us to assert that that collection of first
names contains a Johnny, a Sarah and a Jenny, something along those lines.
So that's what I'm that's what I'm kind of thinking and trying out here.
Let's see what that might look like.
So get children stream.
Map.
And let's do a person get first name and we will collect them into a collection I could collect into
a set or a list, and we will collect these into a set like so and we don't need this class here.
I can just do a static import and save a little bit of room like so.
All right.
So now this assertion is dealing with a collection of presumably three names.
So now we can use one of the assertion methods here contains and it takes in this case, bar args of
strings.
And so here let me let's move this down to another line so that we're not so scrunched up here.
So now all I have to do is just say contains Johnny.
Sarah?
Or Jenny?
Like so.
And if I scroll up a bit and hover over this contains method here, let's just see a little bit more
about how this really works so that it verifies that the actual group contains the given values in any
order.
So that's kind of important to know.
So we don't necessarily have to care how the database is going to retrieve this data or what order it's
going to be in.
Right.
So that was one thing that I was just wanting to make sure of.
OK, so now let's run this and see that it will fail.
OK, so we're expecting a harsh set to contain Johnny, Sarah and Jenny, but we could not find any
of those elements of Johnny, Sarah or Jenny.
None of them are there.
So I think this looks like we're pretty good here with the test.
All right.
So now let's just go make this work.
Now this is going to be a lot of fun, I think.
So maybe we'll start in the spreadsheet.
OK, so you already know how this part is working.
We're going to have these children.
And the only difference between a child and a parent is the fact that the children will have a parent
ID.
And by the way, I mean, technically a parent could also be a child.
But maybe we're not going to go quite that far with things.
Okay, because that'll just make stuff even more complicated, OK?
So I think you should already have the skills to know how you could retrieve a person and then make
a separate database call to retrieve their children, right?
You could create a separate school expression.
In fact, here let's let's go to the I.D. and see what I'm talking about.
So let's go into the people repository, and this is the code that gets called today when we are retrieving
a person from the database, right?
So right here.
So if we want to, I'm not going to really do this all the way, all the way through.
But if we wanted to, we could create a private method here that might return a set of people like this.
And maybe it would be like find children by parent.
And it would take.
A parent as an input.
Right?
And then we could actually just do all of the JTBC code right here now, we'd have to write this code
out explicitly because our credit repository doesn't have any scaffolding in place already to let us
go search for children by the parent ID or something like that, right?
That's just a little outside of the templating that we've put in place so far.
But you know, we go get a connection like we've done before and prepare a statement.
And then we could say something like select everything, notice.
I'm using a lowercase here because I don't really care right now.
And by the way, the lowercase uppercase thing I've mentioned this before, it doesn't really matter.
I just tend to write my SQL in uppercase as a convention, select everything from people, then left
outer, join to people as blah blah blah.
Right.
So we we do all of that and so we could execute all of that.
Write all the code here and have the result of that be the children of that parent.
We use a bind parameter to specify that we want all of the records who have a parent ID that matches
the ID of whatever that parent was that we passed into the method.
So here's the parent here this parent will have an ID.
We get that ID and bind it to the parameter for the parent ID.
And that's how the database would just pull back only the children of that parent, right?
Then we'd reconstitute the results sets into people and then return the people.
OK.
So that's a way that we could do that.
However, as you've seen now a number of times previously, we've been trying to avoid situations where
we're making multiple calls back to the database to get this kind of data.
It's almost always better if we can get as much data as we need from the database in one call.
So now I want to show you how we can actually do that because this is a special case.
Up until now, we've been just getting a person and like one address or we got two addresses all in
one row.
But now we want to get potentially multiple additional rows of people all in one go.
And that's a little bit different from what we've done before.
OK.
So let me delete this because that was just, for example, purposes.
And the first thing I want to do is jump back over to the tests and go back up to our say test right
here can save person with children.
And I actually want this test data to be committed to the database just just for once so that we have
some data that we can play with in the real database so that I can show you what this is actually going
to look like for the sequel.
So I'm going to add that signature there.
OK.
And so I'm going to go ahead and run just this one test so that we can actually commit one parent with
three children.
So I'm going to run that, OK?
We're done.
All right.
Now I'm going to head over to the Squirrel sequel client.
And let's connect to the people database.
Connect.
All right.
So first off, let's just find all of those children.
And I think a way that we can do this is to select everything from people where parent underscore ID
is not null, and I haven't shown that one before.
But that's how you can say not null.
You can't do like an exclamation equals like we do in Java.
In SQL, it's is not null.
All right, so let's run that and see what we get.
All right.
Now notice that took a little while to run.
All right, so very good.
There are our three children of John Smith, right?
And if we come over here, we see John Smith's parents ID is right there.
Two seven six nine two two nine zero So they all share the same parent.
So the question is, is there any way that we could write a query that would retrieve John Smith, the
parent and all of the children together, right?
All in one query.
And even if we could do that, what would that even look like?
Would it be some kind of hierarchical thing or whatever?
Right?
That's the question.
So obviously the answer is yes, we can do that.
And you can probably already guess that it's going to involve using joins.
Right?
So without further ado, let me just show you how to do this.
So what we can do is.
We can first set ourselves up to select the parent.
So I'm going to do a select here, and I'm going to pretend like I already have a table alias for the
parent part of this query.
So I'm going to do something like select parent ID.
Now, I don't know if I'm going to retrieve every single field here.
I don't know if I feel like doing that much typing, but let's see here.
So select parents on ID, a parent ID card.
A parent got first name, parent, last name, parent, DOB, parent, salary, parent, female, and
I think that's enough for the parent fields.
Now I'm going to want to use some column aliases here, though, so I'm going to say as an undergrad.
As Karen underscored her first name as parents underscore her last name, as parents, as parents before
salary.
As underscore, any and all right.
Oh, and maybe I'm going to put all of that on its own line like, so all right, so now we'll do a
from people as parent.
So I want to name the alias of this table as parent, right, where parent got ID equals, and then
I will come down here and copy this parent ID.
And paste that right there.
Now, obviously, we're not done.
I'm just getting started.
OK, so now we need to join something, right?
So we'll do our standard, join left outer, join people.
As now here I'm going to call this child on parent dot I.D. equal to child dot parent underscore ID.
Now, I hope that makes sense, right?
We want to join these things wherever the parent dot IED field is equal to the child that parent ID,
right?
This guy right here.
That's how we're that's where we're establishing the relationship.
OK.
All right.
However, we will also now need to specify the additional columns that we want to retrieve.
So I'm going to put a comma here and then drop down a row.
And now I can say child I.D. As as as for I.D., I'm a child, my first name as child or first name
on a child, not last name as child.
Four Last name, color, child.
They learn as a child that salary as a child under four salary on a child that you know, as one or
email.
And I'm really afraid that I may have missed something here, but I guess I'll find out when I try to
run this overseas self-sustainable lesson until listening to the total retail.
Totally.
You know they'll be OK.
Maybe I got it.
All right.
OK, so let's run this and see what we end up with.
OK, now first thing to note is we just got back three rows.
I don't know if that's what you were expecting or not, but we got back three rows, so that's notable,
I think.
Oh, and you know what?
I totally forgot one thing I forgot to give us.
The options that we can see are aliases easily right here.
So you know what?
Hold on just a second here.
Let me just copy all of that that we just did.
I'm just going to copy it.
And then I'm going to actually close our connection for a minute.
And then I'm going to jump over here into the alias, right click on the Alias, go to modify, and
let's turn on that little alias option so that we can see the alias names for the column names when
we execute these queries.
So alias column name equals true.
OK.
And we will connect.
All right.
And then I will just paste that query right back in here, and let's run this again.
There we go.
OK, so now let's see what we've got, so we've got a parent I.D. There's the parent I.D. parent, first
name John Smith, same date.
So these columns here for these three rows are all identical, right?
They're all referring to the parent, John Smith.
OK.
They're just duplicated three times.
All right.
So if we keep going, but now look over here, we've got the child columns here.
So Jenny, Sarah and John.
Right.
So these are all different.
So what we're really looking at here is the children.
We're looking at the relationships between the children and the parent from the children's perspective.
And this is an important concept to make note of, which is when you have a parent child relationship
or a one to many relationship modeled in the database and you join the parents and the children together,
as we've done here, the result that you will get back is really just the children, right?
Whatever the more numerous thing is, which in this case would be the children in a one to many relationship,
you're going to get back the data from the perspective of the children and then the parents or the one
of the one to many relationships will simply be duplicated for all of their children.
OK, so that's an important thing to make note of.
This means that it is possible for us to query the database to say, Give me back John Smith with all
of his children.
What the database will actually do if we use this query is that the database will really just return
back all of his children.
With John Smith duplicated.
However, many times he has kids, so that's about the most efficient way that we can retrieve all the
data in this one to many relationship, at least going down one generation now if we wanted to go multiple
generations down.
I don't know that I would do it this way.
We're probably going to have to go back to just fetching the various generations of children separately.
But this is an extremely common pattern to use.
OK, so we're implementing the ability to fetch a one to many relationship in one query.
All right.
So now that we see how we can do this and you see that the pattern looks pretty much the same as all
of the other left outer join factors that we've done previously, we can make good use of this.
Now we can additionally add in the parents address fields as well, and that'll pretty much look the
same as what we've already been doing.
And in fact, I guess I'll go ahead and just do it.
I'm going to jump over to the eddy just to copy over the a little bit of the sequel so I can do a little
less typing.
All right, so let's see.
We'll jump over to the people repo.
Jump to the top here and we can grab these two lines.
I'm just going to copy that.
Jump back over here, put a comma right there after the child line and then paste and then fix my formatting
a little bit.
So those are the columns for the home address and business address.
And now I can just come down here and add back in the left outer, join left outer join address as home
on parent that home address equal to home that ID and then another one left outer join address as this
on parent dot this address equal to discard ID.
All right, so let's run that again and see what we get.
OK.
Didn't like something here?
What did I miss this table address?
Oh, sorry.
Addresses addresses.
Here we go.
Let's try that again.
Oh, still not happy.
Oh, and my problem here is this dangling comma right at the end that took me a little bit of time to
actually see.
I should have noticed that though, because I was the because I was actually getting a red error there
on the from.
Let me put that coming back in and you see right there the red error.
So that's let that be a lesson to you to always pay attention to red marks and things.
That's usually the tool trying to help you there.
Let me get rid of that dangling comma and come here and try this again.
There we are.
OK, so now I'm going to have an incredibly wide result set here.
So we've got our parent fields and then our child fields and then our home address fields, which are
all null and our business address fields.
So there's everything right there.
All right.
So this hopefully now gives you a really good picture of how we can make much more efficient queries
to pull back all of this data.
So I'm going to go ahead and stop here.
And in the next lesson, we'll put this new knowledge to good use and implement the ability to retrieve
all of the children with the addresses and everything all in one.
He.