All right, so in the last lesson, we learned how to modify our SQL query to do a left outer join back
on to the same people table so that we could retrieve all the data and a one to many relationship all
in one go.
And what we basically learned is that when you do a one to many join, you're going to get back as many
records as there are on the many side of that relationship.
So in other words, in a one two many or a parent child relationship, if you're trying to get a parent
with all their children, what you'll get back are all the children, with the one parent just duplicated
as many times as there are children.
OK.
And then we can still join all of the rest of the stuff.
So we joined the two addresses as well.
All right, so fairly straightforward.
And it really just builds on the basic joining patterns that we've already been playing with for the
last several lessons.
So now we're going to implement this in Java code.
OK, so here we are back in the IDP and what we are going to want to do is to presumably modify this
sequel again to just pull back everything.
And actually, maybe what I will do in this case is just start with the sequel that we have over there
in Squirrel.
So let me just jump back over here and I'm going to start by just grabbing all of that and copying it.
And I will come back over here and I think I'm just going to paste it all in.
In fact, hold on a minute, let me get myself a new line there and paste all of this in like so and
then let me fix my indentation.
I'm going to get rid of this backslash s which the idea kind of inserted in there.
For me, I guess it was just trying to help me or something.
Here's another one here.
Let me get rid of that also.
All right.
And then let me parameter rise this bit again, like so all right.
So I think that's a good start.
Now, couple of things.
In the previous version of this query, I was not spelling out the word parent.
I just had Piedad ID, although that part's not the important part.
The the important part is the alias here parent underscore ID.
So let me just go double check what I was referring to these columns as wherever we are currently retrieving
the person for the find by ID method.
OK, so currently, I'm referring to those fields with no prefix on them, and I can already pretty
much guess that just as we needed to use a dynamic prefix to get the addresses, we're going to need
to do the same type of thing now to get all of the fields of a person as well.
So let's just keep that in mind as we're implementing the changes that we need to make here.
Now, another thing that we need to consider is currently this extract entity from results set method
was really written with the expectation that we would just be getting back one row of a result set and
converting that one row into ultimately one entity, which in this case is the person and then returning
that.
However, as you see here, if we execute this query, we're going to get back a result set with three
rows in it.
And so we're going to have to think now of what do we do with these three rows in this context?
And let me show you something here.
If we jump up into the crud repository, which is actually calling this and passing us a result set,
let's just remind ourselves of what's actually there.
OK.
So this is the actual find by ID method, most of which we don't need to see because it's up in the
credit repository, right?
But here's the main thing I want to do to see what's actually happening here is we're executing the
query, getting back this result set and then this guy is calling Dot next.
Now, up until now, when we call fine by ID, this R-Sport next is only happening one time because
there's only ever one row, right?
Every time we call next, that's that's sending a cursor, if you will, down to the next row of data
in our results set.
And you can think of the results set as what everything that you're seeing down here in this area.
OK.
So all of the find by ID queries that we've been doing thus far have only resulted in one row.
And so when asked next is called, it just goes to the one and only row.
And then we extract all of our values out and put them into objects and then return that object or whatever.
But this time we're actually going to have, in this particular case, three rows of data or however,
many rows right for the number of children.
So we need to figure out how do we want to handle the fact that we need to somehow extract all three
of the children for one parent?
So what I'm actually thinking here.
Let me jump back in to our people repository.
So what I'm actually thinking here is that we can actually loop over all of the children right here.
This result, set here, is the same results set that's up in the credit repository where we were doing
that right.
Next, we could do more, r-st next right down here as well for as many children as there are.
OK.
That might that might not quite make sense to you.
But basically what I'm sort of getting at is from the perspective of the parent KRudd repository.
We're going to let this guy kind of behave as though there's really only one row, but.
But down here, we will iterate over multiple rows of our results that if those rows are all for the
same parent, that's what I kind of have in mind.
OK.
All right.
So how are we going to do this?
Well, the first thing I'm thinking is maybe we want to create a method out of these lines here or maybe
these lines here.
I'm not sure exactly where where I want to stop but extract the method here, and that method will take
a few parameters.
And one of those parameters, just like here, will be the ability to pass in a prefix so that it will
know how to retrieve the columns for the parent versus the columns for the child.
If we jump back over here again, you see that the only difference is the prefix of the word parent
for the parent columns versus the prefix of child for the child columns, right?
So just as we did that here, we can do something similar here.
So let's give that a shot.
So I've already got these rows selected, so I'm going to do an option command em or control alt m unable
to extract method.
There are multiple variables to return.
Oh, OK.
So it's telling me that there are multiple variables to return.
And really, I guess what we'd want here is to have this newly extracted method just return a person
and that would be this person right here.
So let's see what this would look like if we were to move this line up to here, because I think that's
fine.
We're creating the person and then we're and then we're extracting these additional addresses and then
setting them.
So I think that's all fine.
So then if we select all of this and then do an option command m, yeah, there we go.
And it knows to return the person now.
And so we will call this method extract person.
There we go.
OK.
And actually, I'm liking this because now that just made this more generic extract entity from results
set method shorter.
Right?
OK, so that's step one.
Step two is we're going to now need a way to prepend these column alias names, if you will, with whatever
our column alias prefix is going to be.
And so just as we did before with the addresses, I will just do one manually and then I will convert
that into a parameter.
So I'm putting my cursor right here and I'm just going to hard code one of them to say parent underscore
plus just like that, then I will move my cursor back over here and select all of this and then do an
option command p to convert that into a parameter like so.
And then I will call this alias.
Prefix, which is what I called it for the address stuff as well.
All right, so that's looking OK.
All right.
And then I will just copy all of that, including the plus and even the space there into a command C
to copy that.
And then I will use a multi cursor on the rest of these lines, the one there, and I'm holding down
on the option and shift and one there and one here and here and here.
And then I will paste.
Like, sir.
All right.
We got that.
Oh, now one really important thing that I almost forgot.
I'm still just using a regular old RC get string method here, and that's not going to work with these
column aliases the way that we're currently establishing our connection and everything, right?
So just as we did down here, where I shifted everything over to use the get value by alias method,
I'm going to replace all of these with get value by alias as well.
Now this looks like it's a little more mixed than the other ones that we had before.
So maybe I'm going to do each of these manually get value by alias and then put my cursor over here
and pass in the result set and then the data type, which is Loncar class and then same thing again,
get value by alias.
Our strongest.
By Elias.
All right.
And this is also a stirring the class.
Now here, I'm not doing it there, I'm doing it in here, right?
I guess I'm pronouncing it.
Yes, I think that's a.
If you place.
And long.
All right, there we go.
And so now that we've got all of that, which was right up here, I think we can go ahead and and now
just duplicate this line once.
And now here will be one child.
And so I will call this person child.
And then we will change the prefix here, and I think we called that child, didn't we?
Yes, we called that child.
OK, so we will do so here as well, child underscore.
So you see what we're doing here, we're just teaching our code how to extract out the various columns
from our results set.
So let me let me walk us through this a little bit now.
So for one row of our results set, we will have a column called Parenting the parent, first name,
parent, last name, parent Dobby.
And over here we will do parent underscore ID, parent underscore, first name, parent, underscore,
last name, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
And then as we scroll farther down, we will also have child ID, child, first name, child, last
name.
And so this bit here will find those columns child underscore ID, child underscore, first name, child
underscore, last name, etc. and extract all the values from those and fill them in on a person and
then return that person right here.
OK.
So hopefully that will retrieve the children.
Now here's the next issue.
We know that for this particular example, we're going to have three children for the day unit test
that we're using to kind of drive this coding that we're doing.
So this will allow us to get the first child.
But how do we get the other two now?
That's the question.
So here's what I'm thinking.
And again, this is an example of where you have to be kind of creative.
I'm not basing what I'm doing here off of any template or any book where I learned how to do these things.
I'm making this up in front of you pretty much as I go.
Now one thing I will confess, though I did take about 20 minutes before I started recording this lesson
right now to kind of just stare at the code.
I didn't write any code at all.
I just stared at the code for about 20 minutes and in my head I was just kind of working out, OK,
how could we solve these problems that we are now encountering?
So I have taken about 20 minutes to kind of run through it all.
But I didn't write any code at all.
So all the code that you're seeing me right right now is the very first time I'm ever writing it.
If I make a really bad mistake that I'm afraid will confuse you, I'll probably edit that out.
But other than that, you're seeing the first ideas that popped in my head essentially well after 20
minutes of thinking about it.
All right.
So one of the things that I thought about in that 20 minutes, though, to solve the problem of how
to get the other children out of here was I considered maybe wrapping all of this, perhaps inside of
a do while loop, some selecting all of this, and I'll explain why in just a second here.
But so I've selected all of this, and then I'm going to do an optional command T and I'm going to choose
number four, do while loop.
All right.
Now I almost never use do I loops in real life, but this feels like it might be a good place to to
consider using one.
Because what I want to do here is I want to extract out.
In this case, all three children and I know that I need this loop to run at least one time because
that would simulate what we've already been doing with previous use cases like this.
You know, the repository calls this method, and we always end up having one record to pull out.
So we know we're always going to have the one record, at least.
I mean, we presume we're going to have at least one record to go grab.
OK.
But how do we get the subsequent records?
So let's just consider what would happen if, first off, we were to just do an arrest next right here
inside of this while loop, which is really what's happening in the crud repository method that's calling
this one if we jump back up there again.
Right?
We've got the rest next call inside of this wire loop, although it's not a do, while loop is just
a regular while loop, but basically the same thing here.
Right?
All right, so let's jump back over here, so here's the thing, though now with this approach, let's
look at the Squirrel sequel sample result set.
So looking again at our sample results set here in Squirrel sequel, we see that we're getting back
three records, which basically represent the three children of John Smith.
And we're also getting back.
John Smith duplicated three times, right?
So let's just walk through what this code would do as it currently is written more or less.
OK, so let's start off in the calling method real quick here.
OK, so we're in a while loop and R-Sport next is going to be called the first time that is called right
here.
That's going to essentially highlight this first row.
OK.
So just a quick reminder of the way that result sets work is that when you first get a result set for
results from a query, there's kind of like a row cursor that starts above the first row, OK?
And so you have to call R-Sport next at least one time to get that cursor on to the very first row.
OK, so here's that very first call to start next.
That's taking us taking our cursor down to the very first row.
Then our credit repository is calling the extract entity from results set method, which is then taking
us back to here.
OK.
And so now at this point, we start extracting all of the values from the parent columns of row one,
right?
So parent ID, the parent, first name, parent, last name, due date of birth, salary, email, et
cetera, right?
All right.
So that's what we're doing with this extract person.
Then we call extract person again and then we tell it now go find all of the columns that we care about,
at least that are presented with child, right?
So then that's going to get the ID, first name, last name, date of birth, etc., right?
All right.
So now we've extracted the parent, we might want to call this parent.
In fact, let me let me rename this shift of six parent.
OK, so we've extracted a parent and now we've extracted a child as well.
And then we extract the address fields that are presented with home and bills.
Let's see those.
Yeah, so home street address Home City and there's Buis Street address, busy city, etc. right?
So that's us extracting all these columns out of that one row and building objects from them.
And then we're setting the objects on to the parent, right set home address, said Business address.
Right now, I think what we'd also want to do here is set the child, parent and child something along
these lines right now.
Here's the problem, though, with as as this is currently written, then if we do and start next here,
that's going to make the road cursor go down to the second row, right?
However, as soon as that happens, because we're inside of a loop, what happens to this parent, right?
So as this is currently written, the parent from the first row would actually become garbage collected
and then we'd end up creating a new parent again.
Do you see that because we're going to loop back up here?
We're going to extract the second parent, which is a duplicate of the first parent, right?
This is the same parent three times, right?
But our code currently doesn't know that it's going to just say, Oh, here's another.
Here's a second parent.
Let me go create a new parent object with the exact same name as the first one.
Our code won't know that, though, right?
And so as this code is currently written, we end up just creating three parents each with one child.
That's not what we want.
We want one parent with three children inside of the parent.
So what I think we really want to do here is maybe somehow create the parent the very first time.
Then as long as the subsequent parents match the very first parent, don't keep recreating that parent.
I know I'm using the word parent a lot.
I hope you're you're sticking with me, right?
So let's just look at it from here.
The first time we create this parent, that's fine.
We're going to create a parent object.
OK, then we're going to come down to this next row and we're going to create another parent object
again.
But now I think maybe we want to compare this second parent object to the first one.
And if they are equal, then probably just ignore this second one and then create the second child and
then add the second child to the first parent, then come down to the third row and then do the same
thing again, temporarily create a third parent.
But compared this third parent to the first parent.
And if they are equal, then don't.
Use this third parent to let that third parent kick garbage collected and then create the child, the
third child, and add that third child to the first parent.
OK, so I think that's got to be our approach or our algorithm for how to convert the three rows of
duplicated parents but differentiated children into one parent with three children.
OK, so that's that's what we have to solve here.
So I'd like to encourage you to try to figure out how you can accomplish that in Java code.
This is an opportunity for you to really engage a lot of the concepts that you've learned throughout
this course and really try to solve a bit of a puzzle here.
OK.
So why don't you take a moment and see if you can work this out and then unpause and join back up with
me?
All right, so let's see how we can do this.
So what I'm thinking here is that I want one parent object outside of this loop who represents the one
and final, the final parent object who will collect all of the children.
OK, so maybe I'm going to actually call this parent right here, something like final parent, maybe,
and I'm going to go ahead and just initialize that to null as well.
And then this parent down here, maybe I'm going to call this one.
Person Shift six, I'm going to rename this to current parent.
OK.
And so then based on the little algorithm that I was saying a minute ago over here, go to the first
row, extract a current parent here and then maybe like compare the current parent to the final parent.
If they are equal, then discard the current parent.
Extract the current child.
Add the current child to the final parent and then advance to the next row.
Extract the current parent of the next row.
Compare that parent to the final parent.
If they are the same, then discard or ignore this current parent.
Extract this current child.
Add the current child to the final parent and then advance again to the next row.
Does that make sense?
Now, one thing I didn't state is what happens if, when comparing the current parent to the final parent,
the final parent isn't null and they aren't the same anymore.
So I think we'll save that use case for a little bit later.
We are going to have to tackle that also, but let's just see if we can codify what I just said here.
All right.
So we've got a final parent and then we've got a current parent.
So as soon as we've got this current parent, maybe we can test right here and say something like if
final parent is null, then final parent equals current parent.
Right?
So if this is the first time we're coming through here and final parent is null, go ahead and just
set the current parent to the final parent.
OK, so that essentially gives us two variables that are both pointing to the same object.
OK.
And that would be this first row in the database.
All right.
So now we've got our final parent.
Then we go ahead and extract the child and the addresses.
And so then what I'm thinking here is maybe we just go ahead and set all of these things home address,
business address and child on the final parent.
So let's see what that looks like.
Final parent and I'll I'll just copy and paste.
All of these like so.
All right, so then we advanced to the next row, so now we're on this row.
Then we come back up here to the top of the loop again.
We extract the parent.
So now at this point, final parent will not be null.
So I think we want to test, though, if final parent equals current parent.
So what should we do now if final parent equals the current parent?
Which is to say that we're still on John Smith, right, that's what that would mean.
We're seeing a duplicate of John Smith.
So in that case, I think just do nothing.
Which is what we have right here, do nothing.
Don't do anything here.
So in that case, we proceed to extract the child and the addresses, and then we would just add the
child to the final parent.
Now we would be unnecessarily setting this home address in business address again.
It is true that we would be doing that, but maybe we don't worry about that right now.
It's not going to hurt anything.
It's just kind of a waste of processing a small waste of processing time.
But we add this second child to the final parent and then we would proceed to the third row and then
same thing is going to happen again.
We jump back up to the top extract the parent parent and then the final parents, not Knowles, who
would jump down here if final parent equals current parent, which should be true again, then do nothing
and then extract the third child and then eventually add that third child right here and now there are
no more rows.
So this that next will return a false and then we need to just return the final parent.
So I think this should work.
And actually, with the way this is written, I guess we really don't even need this test right here
because currently it's not doing anything.
Now what about the third case where the current parent does not equal the final parent?
First off, let us consider, under what circumstance would we even see that situation happening?
So with this particular use case where we have searched for a parent by IED, I don't think we would
ever see that.
But keep in mind, this extract entity from results set method here is used for more than just finding
by ID.
It's also used for find all, and in that case, you wouldn't get duplicate rows of parents here.
Each row would be a unique parent, and unless we go update the find all school query that we're currently
using, there wouldn't be any children in that at present.
Right?
So for that situation, each time you iterated through here and then compared the current parent to
the final parent, they would be different each time.
So I think in that case, what we might want to do here.
Let's go ahead and just code this up.
So if Final Parent does not equal notice, I put the exclamation here.
If final parent not equals current parent, then what should we do?
So let's just run through that scenario real quick.
Click on a find all.
So again, we start before the first row and the rest start next, which is here gets called one time
right.
And so that takes us to row one.
Now we're pretending like we're walking through a situation where we did a fine doll and each of these
rows is a different parent.
OK.
That's the scenario that we're kind of running through real quick here.
All right.
All right, so we jump into here.
We're on row one.
We extract a parent the very first time we go through here.
Final parent is going to be null.
And so we set the current parent to the final parent.
Then we attempt to extract the child.
Probably there's not going to be one in this particular case.
And depending on what we'd had for the final query, there may or may not be addresses.
That's fine.
So these might be null or empty or whatever.
So in that situation, these may just be set to empty, optional or something like that.
I think that's fine.
Then we proceed to the next row.
So now we're on a next row.
So let's pretend like this isn't John Smith anymore.
Let's pretend like it's Harry Smith now and it's not a child.
So then we come back up here on this loop again and we extract the next parent.
This final parent is no longer null.
Then we get down here.
If final parent is not equal to current parent, that will be true.
All right.
So I think for right now, we're not going to address what happens when these two don't match.
We'll do that a little later or in a follow up lesson, OK?
But I think this looks like it might more or less work.
So let's see if we can find a test to run here.
Yeah.
OK, so here's our method.
I think our test can find person by ID with children.
So let's try running this.
By the way, this is green here because I tried a few things out before I started recording this, but
I honestly don't know how this is going to work currently.
So let's see.
So I'm going to run this.
All right, that failed.
And we're getting a message here.
An error column not found for alias, parent, home address, parent, OK, parent home address.
So we are adding the prefix of parent on to the retrieval of the home address somehow.
Let's see where that's happening, so I will start here at the top of the stack trace line 151.
And then so that's a call being made to the get value by Alias, let's see what's calling that.
Oh, OK, OK.
So we're trying to retrieve the home address IED, and we're referring to it as parent underscore home
underscore address.
But I bet I bet that's not what we called the alias in our sequel here.
So let's see here.
Home street address is what we actually should be looking for, and we're getting a parent home address.
So I think that's just the mistake I must have made in how I coded that.
So let's jump back down here.
So we don't want that to be called parent home address.
This should just be called home street address.
Right?
That should just be called home street address.
OK, home street address and no prefix.
So we can, I think, just get rid of that prefix there, and I'm just going to hard code.
Street address.
And actually, I guess I forgot to add in the retrieval of the business address as well.
And actually, for that matter, I'm not even doing anything with this home street address presently.
So actually, I think this line here probably isn't needed.
Let me let's see what happens if we just delete that.
Yeah, I don't even think we need that line because this is part of extracting the person and we will
get those home addresses and all of that stuff when we call the extract address for home and business.
So I think we didn't even need that here.
I probably just went a little too far with grabbing various values and things, so let's try that again.
Hey, that worked.
Yeah.
I think we're good right there.
All right.
So let me make some room here.
OK, so looks like we've got something that's working now.
If any of this was a little confusing for you.
I think you should really try to re-implement this on your own and then go back into this lesson and
review my explanation of the algorithm, the steps that we're taking to work this out, where I was
showing the rows in the database result set.
OK.
So I don't want to repeat that because this lesson is already quite long, and I don't think I'm going
to do a better job than what I already did earlier in just explaining those steps.
OK, but do make sure you go back and watch that again.
And I think in the next lesson, we will run all of the tests because I'm pretty certain several tests
or at least the find all tests will fail now.
And I think that'll be because we need to implement this conditional situation right here.
OK.
So I'm going to stop this here and then we'll pick right back up at this point and run all those tests
and then probably be forced to do something here.
So I'll see you in the next one.