All right, so now let's take a step back and look a little bit deeper into where these streams actually
can come from, because right now we're only seeing one example of where we can even get a stream from.
And in this case, it's coming from this, this string, this people text variable rates that we're
calling people text that get lines.
So this line's method here is returning a stream, and that's the start of this entire pipeline.
OK.
But there are other ways to create a stream, and I want to show you some of those real quick.
Now, I would say the most common place to get a stream started is actually from any of the collection's
classes.
So generally speaking, the classes that implement the collection interface, which we have previously
learned about right like lists and sets and maps and all those guys, those classes, generally speaking,
have great support for the Streams API, and I would go so far as to say that the Streams API was really
created with the Collections API in mind.
OK.
So let me show you a few examples of what I mean.
Real quick, I'm going to kind of just ignore this bit of code, and we'll just make some new lines
here real quick here.
So let's say that I wanted to create a list of strings.
Now the things that we run, the objects that we run through the streams API do not have to be strings,
by the way, they can be objects and we will see some of that later.
But for example, purposes, it's just easy for me to create a quick collection of strings so that I
don't have to work with creating whole entire objects.
So let's see.
Let's say that I do a list of and then I let import that and I will just do something like one two,
three four.
Then I will capture that inside of a variable nums.
All right.
So there's my variable called NUM's, that it is a list, right?
So now I can refer to the NUM's variable and start doing things with it via the Streams API.
So let's say first off that I just want to print out each of the items in the NUM's collection similarly
to how we're doing up here with the for each right.
So what would that look like?
Well, I will reference Nums and then there's a method on nuns now.
I guess I'll hit enter oops!
And back up a little bit and do a period here.
And the first thing I will need to do is to reference the method stream, right?
Their stream that is how you get a stream or you start a stream from a collection.
Usually the stream method.
OK, so stream.
And then from here I can do something like a for each.
And then I can do what I'm doing up above system outline, print line, just like so and so that would
print out our one two, three four.
And in fact, I guess I'll run this.
Now, mind you, let's see here for right now, I guess I'll comment this out just so we don't have
to see the noise of of both of these.
And I'm running this now.
OK, so there we go one, two, three four.
Just like so and then I can do other neat tricks like I can use the map method here and maybe convert
all of these to uppercase.
Let's see what that would look like, so I can call map.
Let's see String two uppercase.
Look at that.
And so that's the most concise way that I can do this.
And again, notice that I'm not having to explicitly put parentheses in here like this and then pass
in some variable or something.
I could do that, but then I could not use this method reference syntax.
I would need to revert to the two something like a lambda, which is fine.
I can do that right.
I can do like a in four number and then the Arrow operator and then in in that to upper.
And I want this one here, right?
So I can do that.
But many times it's actually less verbose just to use the method reference syntax like so and and some
might argue it's a little clearer.
Also, because essentially, you can if you once you understand the streams API, then you understand
that each of these objects is going to pass through this pipeline and then each thing that we're saying
to do is going to be done on each of those objects, right?
So we're uppercase in each of these things and then we're printing each of these things, right?
So let's run that and see what that looks like.
There you go.
So nice, right?
Let's see.
We could get the length of each of them in just print that out.
There you go.
Let's see what that looks like.
I think we should get a three, three, five, yeah, three, three, five four.
Right, yeah.
Cool.
So that's really, really nice right now.
Believe me, there's so much more that we can do with this API.
We're we're not even scratching the surface of all of what it can do.
I just want to kind of ease you into it a little bit here not to imply that it's difficult, but there's
a lot there's a lot of cool stuff that we can do.
So let's see.
So in this particular case, we're working with a list.
Actually tell you what, let me change this collection.
Let me change this interface here to something even more generic like collection.
All right.
And I can do that, right?
That's valid because list is a subclass, technically a sub interface of collection, and so I can always
store instances of of a sub in the super class, right on a subclass in the super class, right?
The reason I did that is, though, is because I want to change the implementation here also.
So instead of a list, let's say I do a set.
And I will import that.
There we go.
And nothing needs to change here.
OK.
And I don't know.
Let's do one more little thing here.
How about calling?
How about getting the hash code?
So if we want the hash code, we can refer to that.
Let's see what that'll look like.
There they are, there are the hash codes.
Now these are in decimal.
What if we wanted them to be in hexadecimal?
Can you think of a way to convert these to hexadecimal and get them all printed out?
One way that I can think of converting that to hash code to a hexadecimal representation would be maybe
to to do another map.
So you can you can stream together pretty much infinite numbers of steps in your pipeline and you can
do multiple of the multiples of the same steps if you like, if it makes sense to do.
So what I what we're getting here is the hat.
This first map is converting the string into a hash code, which is an integer, right?
But I want that integer to be represented as a hexadecimal value, and one way that I can think of doing
that would be to call another map.
And there's a there's a magical method on the integer class integer Cohen.
To Hex String, there it is like that.
Let's try that out and see what we get.
Yeah, there we go.
Pretty nice right now.
I can think of another way to do this as well.
And just for grins, I'll show you real quick.
This doesn't have much to do with streams anymore, but always good to do a little tiny bit of review.
So the other way that I can think of to get these hacked strings, I'll delete that would be to do it
down here in the for each.
So I will delete this system out line and I will revert to using the lambda notation again.
So I'll do something like an h and then an arrow.
I'm just picking a random variable name here h for Hex, right?
And then system got out print f and then I will use a print format code right and I can do a percent
h and then a percent in for a new line and then refer to that variable.
So what I'm saying here is take this value h, which is going to be passed in from the previous step
in the pipeline.
So this is going to be the Hex, the hash code in in decimal form, though, right?
H, here's four hash code, I guess.
And then we're going to call a system out print f where we're going to pass in that hash code in decimal
form, but we're asking print f to convert the decimal to hex.
That's what this is actually doing.
OK.
Let's see if this works.
All right.
So yeah, so there's an alternative way that we could get that done right?
But I would say that this is a little noisier than than than that.
I don't know.
To my eye, this looks a little a little cleaner, a little more straightforward.
So just to reiterate.
You can call the stream method on any collection to start using the Streams API to do things right.
And so any types of objects that would be valid in a collection can be manipulated or worked with in
with the Streams API, right?
So they don't have to be strings.
You could have a collection of people or or integers or whatever.
It doesn't really matter.
All right.
Now, did you think we were done learning how to create streams because we're not even nearly done?
There are a whole lot of other ways to create your initial stream, and we're going to try to just do
a quick marathon run through most, if not all, of those ways.
So right now, we're creating a stream of strings from a set by calling the dot stream method on this
set right.
And so in general, we can do this with collections.
However, there's so much more that we can do.
Let's see here.
So what I want to show you.
Let's let's let's just let's see.
Let's get rid of all of this, I think.
And I think we can even get rid of that.
And now let me show you what else we can do.
Alternatively, so the stream class itself has the ability to create streams, and it's actually quite
useful.
And so if we just do a stream dot.
There you go.
And we'll get rid of the semicolon, and then of course, we won't need to call a stream method explicitly,
and in fact, it doesn't exist anyway.
So we'll get rid of that.
And voila, we are now creating a stream of strings, just using the stream class.
Boy, that's that's a that's a bit of a tongue twister, isn't it?
So anyway, very straightforward.
Super convenient.
Now this of method here can do quite a bit more.
So in this particular case, we're using it to, you know, create a stream of strings, right?
However, look what else we can do.
If I get rid of these, we could refer to a bunch of numbers one two three four.
Like so and no problem there.
However, we do end up with a problem with the mapping, right?
So the thing is this of method here recognizes the general type of the objects that we're passing in.
In this particular case, it recognizes that we're referring to numbers, integers, and so it automatically
returns a stream of integer now because it's returning a stream of integers.
We can't refer to the string hash code, right?
So I don't know, we could just get rid of that.
There you go.
Let's say that we even wanted to create a stream of some custom class of some sort.
So we could do that.
In fact, I'll do it real quickly in line here.
Now, I won't technically create an actual class.
I will create a record.
If you remember, records are basically just like more streamlined classes with a lot less boilerplate.
So I can create a record right here in line.
I can just use the keyword record just as I would have used the keyword class.
Let's say we want a model cars, for example.
So here's a car and then I can just specify kind of like the constructor, right?
All in line here.
So let's say that we're going to have we're going to model a car and we can have properties of a make
and a model like so.
Here we go now down here.
I can start creating a stream of cars.
Like this?
Ford.
Bronco.
And A.
Tesla.
ABC's.
And one more.
We'll do another Tesla.
Tesla.
Three.
OK, so like that now, of course, in this particular case, mapping to the integer hex string doesn't
make sense, so we'll just get rid of that and we can run this now that's going to end up just calling
the default implementation of the two string method, right?
There we go.
So wonderful.
And you know, we could even do some fancy things here, like the filtering filter.
Let's see for car looks for cars where car does not make.
Equals.
Tesla, and as you know, maybe we'd prefer to put the Tesla in the front.
Tesla, that equals.
See that make.
All right, so that should only give us the Teslas, right?
There we go.
Yes.
Only the Teslas, OK, so we can do that.
Now I want to show you a couple other things before we leave the stream sort of method here.
So I'm going to get rid of these cars.
And let's just go back to using strings for a second here.
So we'll just do one easy string.
We'll get rid of the filter, OK, so we already know that this will work.
So here we're creating a stream that will contain one string in it right now.
What would happen if, for whatever reason, we happened to be populating a null value into the stream?
So for example, let's say that we had a let's say that we had a variable here.
My VAR equals and we were using some kind of a method call that would populate this my VAR string.
But under certain circumstances that we could not foresee, sometimes that value could be null.
Right.
So so sometimes it's hello in here.
We'll even change this to be my VAR.
All right.
So that would be valid.
But what if this was null because of some method call that was being made to populate the my VAR, right?
So let's see what happens then.
OK, so we get a novel getting printed out here.
Maybe that's what you were expecting, maybe that's fine.
However, you might want to consider, is that really what you want?
If you've got a null value getting populated in to your stream, why not just not have it be in the
stream at all, right?
Like if it's null, meaning it's essentially nothing, right?
Do we really want that in the stream at all?
So if you don't want novels to be in the stream, in other words, you kind of want them just filtered
out magically, right?
If there's nothing for a particular value.
Maybe you don't want that in the stream at all.
Well, instead of doing stream, sort of, you can call streamed out of Nullarbor.
And now we're just telling the stream sort of method Hey, look out for null values and if you encounter
them, watch this.
So if we run it now, watch what happens.
Nothing, we get nothing now.
The reason we're getting nothing now is that because we're only attempting to put one object in this
stream, and in this particular case, the object happens to be null.
We end up ultimately with an empty stream.
And when a stream is empty, then the subsequent steps in that pipeline and that streams pipeline don't
even execute right because you're at the end of the stream already.
And so it's like we have it's almost like there's a filter step in there that's looking for needles
and just getting rid of them.
OK.
So keep that in mind if you ever need that need or want that type of functionality where you just get
rid of the the null, OK?
And speaking of empty streams, there's one more here.
There might be some circumstances where you actually explicitly want to create an empty stream, and
if you ever did want to do that, bam, there you go.
One example of where I can think you might have wanted this in the past, maybe you'd have something
like this stream.
My stream equals no.
Then here let's let's get rid of that.
Then you might have some logic that said something like, if my VAR is null, then my stream.
Equals stream that in the.
Else my stream.
Equals streamed out of my VAR.
Then down here, you would just reference my stream, right?
So this would have been like an old school poor man's way of maybe, you know, trying to be efficient
with your use of streams or something like that, right?
Obviously, you don't really need to write this kind of code, but that's one example of maybe why you
might have used the stream that empty.
I'm sure you'll think of some really good reasons for that.
Now, in addition to using the stream method itself, which is very, very useful, right?
Let's see.
We can also do a few other things.
We can create what's called an end to stream it.
So let me show you the entire stream.
So what this is is just an explicit stream of integers, right?
But it's but it's its own thing.
So I'll show you what I mean here so we can reference the streams.
Let's say that we just want to count from one through four.
OK.
So one way we could do that is to reference an end to stream like so and then call the of method of
the stream and then just pass in some values like so and then we can, yeah, maybe do a for each and
do a system that our loops print line like.
So and let's just run that and you know what that's going to do.
It'll be very straightforward.
And there you go.
OK, so that makes good sense, right?
However, I don't know what if you wanted to do the same thing, but you wanted to go like from one
to 100.
You probably don't want to have to do five, six, seven eight now, you know, et cetera, et cetera,
right?
And guess what?
You don't need to.
So there's another method.
In fact, there's a couple that we can use on the stream.
There's one called range where we can pass in an inclusive starting number and an exclusive ending number.
So if we want to list out the numbers one through 100, for example, we could do something like this
one comma 101.
That last number is exclusive, right?
So the last digit that you refer to here won't be printed, right?
So it'll go up to that, but not including that exclusive right.
So if we went one through 100, then we probably want to say one one for our end number here.
So if we do this, let's let's run that.
There we go.
So we're getting a bunch of numbers, right?
One through 100.
Pretty easy.
Straightforward.
OK.
And then there's one other version of this, which is almost the exact same thing, except it's called
closed.
Now this one is inclusive.
That's really about the only difference.
Right?
So starting inclusive and ending inclusive, right?
So if we just want to end right on 100, in fact, maybe I won't go so far this time we'll do 40 right
one through 40.
Let's run that.
That's going to do what you think it should.
OK.
Now, in addition to the enter stream, there's also a double stream and a long stream.
OK, and actually, there's even a there's even more classes that actually inherit from the same parent
that these these numeric stream classes inherit from.
But those are probably the main ones that you might ever be, you know, interested in.
So, you know, integers now.
So integers, longs and doubles, right, is what they're all about.
Now, one thing to be aware of the end stream is spitting out something different from from from this.
So in this case, the streamed out of one two three is actually returning, I'll show you here a stream
of integer like that, whereas the entire stream is actually spitting out an actual thing called an
end loops stream.
OK?
So it's not a stream of integers, it's it's its own thing.
It's an end to stream now.
Now, conceptually, it is still a stream of integers, but one of the key differences, as I think
we did see already, there are context aware methods that exist exclusively on these numerical streams,
such as the stream, such as being able to get a max number and and summing up the total.
You know, the total of all the numbers in the stream and things like that, you cannot do those operations
on a generic stream, right?
This generic stream type doesn't care what what type of data is in the stream, right?
It can be cars.
It can be strings.
It can be integers.
So think about it.
If you're using a generic stream, it doesn't make sense to call a some method on a generic stream.
That stream doesn't doesn't actively know that you've put numbers inside of it, right?
And it doesn't care, right?
It doesn't really know that.
So it wouldn't know.
Like, it wouldn't know to make the some method available.
Only if you have put numbers in here, right?
Because it's the same class, no matter what.
So what the Java creators have done is they've given us specific numerical stream types when we want
to do numeric operations on the data that's in those streams.
And and as such, the data has to be numerical, right?
All right.
Now we may have already seen this again.
Forgive me.
We may have already seen this or I'm getting ready to show it to you in a future lesson.
But either way, I want to show you a little bit more about the end stream here.
Let's say that we let's see here.
Let's let's get rid of that.
And let's.
All right.
So let's say that we wanted to, I don't know, have some output that looks like something like this
where maybe like we're just tacking on a hyphen after each number, right?
So I don't know, maybe we do five of them.
OK.
So let's say that that's the output that we want.
How can we get that output?
Well, one way that I could think of doing this might be to if we could treat each of these numbers
as a string, then we could contact concatenate the hyphens onto the end of them, right and then just
print it all out, right?
That would be pretty straightforward.
So let's see if we can do that.
All right.
So we know how to.
We know how to generally convert within a stream.
We know how to generally convert an object from one type to another, right with with the map method,
right?
So maybe we could do something like map.
So we want to convert these numbers to strings.
Can you think of how to do that?
You're wanting a string from a number.
All right.
Did you think of it?
We learned it a long time ago.
All right.
So that'll since the thing that we're going to is a string and it's coming from a simple, primitive
type, essentially, which is a number.
What we can do is just make use of the string value of method.
Right?
Generally speaking, that's what we can do.
However, if you try this, let's see what error we're getting here.
Bad return type in method reference cannot convert string to end cannot code cannot convert string to
end what's going on?
Well, if you look down here, look at this little hint that is telling us replace map with map to object.
So let's go ahead and click that and see what happens.
OK, now the little error went away, so what is that all about?
Well, the problem here is essentially the fact that we're again, we're not dealing with a stream of
integers, right?
We're dealing with something that is its own type and end stream.
And unfortunately, an entire stream is fundamentally incompatible with the idea of taking the individual
numbers in it and converting them and and mapping them to other things in and of themselves, right?
We first must get our hands on those individual numbers that are in this special enter stream so that
we can convert them into something else, right?
And so the entire stream class gives us a couple of ways to do that.
One way is by calling the map to object method here.
Now this is useful if you know that you want to map or convert the the values that are in your into
stream to something that is probably not numerical, although it could be numerical.
But I'm going to show you another way that you could do that as well.
OK.
So in our case, we want to convert these numbers in the stream to strings themselves, right?
And so we're wanting to map the information or the values that are in the stream to some object type.
And in this case, the objects are strings, right?
And so we can do that just like this.
OK.
And now that we've got strings now we can do a regular map like so and we've got these strings.
So I'll just use a lambda here and we'll say something like a second cat.
And then there's our hyphens, and now if we run this, we should get the desired output.
There we go.
There it is, right?
All right.
So that's one way we can do that now instead of the map to object.
The other way we could do this is to insert one more method call up above, which is called boxed.
And then here we can just do a regular old map.
OK, now the difference is that the box, the method, what it actually returns is a stream of integers,
right?
So again, what fundamentally comes from an end to stream is its own data type.
It's something called end stream, so it's not a stream of anything.
It is an entire stream just if you're having trouble understanding this.
Maybe you should just think of it this way and into stream doesn't have numbers in it.
It has things in it that we can't know about.
OK.
But it can give us numbers if we either call the box method or if we call the map to object.
OK, now what?
So the boxed method is actually returning a traditional stream of integers.
OK.
So in this case, if you knew that you wanted a stream of integers explicitly and you weren't planning
to convert them to something else soon afterwards, then using the boxed method might make sense.
Although, generally speaking, what that's doing, the reason it's called boxed is because it is boxing.
It is boxing our integers using the using the numerical wrapper classes that we've learned about before.
Right.
So.
So this integer here, right, that's the box class.
And I don't know if you'll recall, but I but I stated before that these these wrapper classes are a
little expensive, right?
That's the whole reason that Java has the primitive data types, in fact, was to kind of avoid having
the expense of using full full on objects for something so fundamental as just like numbers and things.
But if you know you need that for whatever reason, there you have it now with these two approaches
that I've just shown better approach would be, I'm going to undo.
This would be to just use the map to object because we're avoiding the unnecessary additional step of
having a stream of integers and then only to turn around and convert the stream of integers into strings
anyway, right?
So with this approach, we skip that middleman step and just go straight from the unknowable numbers
that we're not supposed to know about that are in the stream directly to strings, right?
OK, and then we've touched this once in one of the less previous lessons.
I can't remember exactly what we were doing in there, but so the next thing I want to show you is we
can create an array.
So I don't know.
Let's create a string array.
OK, we'll call it names.
And we will initialize it.
Terry Sam.
Jake?
All right, so there we go.
Three three names in this array.
So if we want to create a stream from this array, we can simply call arrays dot stream and then we
can pass in our array.
All right.
So arrays that stream and then we pass in our array.
And now we can use these streams API methods.
So again, we can do like a for each system that out print line, right?
There we go.
And I don't know, we can get a little fancier with it and do a mapping as well and maybe like uppercase
them, all right.
So we can do string to uppercase like, so there we go.
OK, cool.
All right.
So that's pretty straightforward.
Very nice.
Easy, convenient way to go from an array to a stream of whatever the value types that were in that
array.
And note, it does not have to be an array of strings.
It can be an array of anything, really.
Right?
OK.
And then finally, the last one and this is going to be a sneak preview into a future module where we
will learn how to work with files like actual files, data files, text files, things like that.
So I'm going to give you a quick little sneak preview here.
So one thing that we've been doing for a long time now in many, many lessons is we keep copying and
pasting.
You know, this big thing here, but we could actually put all of this inside of a text file.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to shift.
I'm going to switch over into the column selection mode with a command shift eight.
And what that's going to allow me to do is to select just the columns that I want of text rather than
the entire lines like so.
OK.
And then when I do a command c, I can copy all of that.
Then I'll get out of out of this mode.
Now I'm going to come up here and I'm going to create a new file, new new file, and I'm going to call
it employees that you like.
So.
And here we are in this file, and then I will just paste everybody in there like so right?
And then I will save that.
And now, if I open up the the Project Explorer pane on the left here, you'll see that I now have this
file employees that text.
Now what I will do is I'm going to right click on this file and I'm going to select copy path and I'm
going to choose absolute path.
And now that's what that's telling me is where on my computer's hard drive or in my case, solid state
drive, right?
Where on the on the storage device of my computer, what path is this file actually at?
I'm going to need that for in a moment here, so I'm going to select that.
OK, cool.
Now I will go back over to the streams stuff and I can close the project bit there.
And if I come down here, watch this.
Now, let's not lose sight of what we're actually trying to do.
What I want to do is I want to read in this data as a stream, but from a file, not from a variable
like we've been doing.
And it's actually incredibly easy to do.
So what I can do is simply reference the files class, and this class has a method on it.
Called lines, does that look familiar?
You know, we've been reading these, we've been reading these lines here from the string variable because
the string class also has a short lines method, right?
Well, so does this class called files, right?
So I can refer to this line's method here and notice it takes as input something called a path.
That's a file path.
So if I actually just type in the refer to another class called Path Dot of, they're really fond of
this of pattern because it just makes everything so easy to to do, you know?
So anyway, path sort of.
And now I can pass in a string.
Guess what, string I'm going to paste in here, the one that I just copied a little bit ago, right?
Here's this this full this full path here.
Like so OK.
And now what what will happen is this lines method here, just like the lines method of the string class,
it returns a stream of strings, right?
The lines in this case loads returning a stream of the lines of text in that text file.
Now, before I do that, though, I have to address this little squiggly line here.
Now that's telling me I have an unhindered exception.
We haven't learned explicitly a whole lot about exceptions, but I've mentioned them from time to time,
and I've told you that essentially they represent errors going wrong in the program.
The problem here is that it is possible that the path that I'm passing in here is invalid, and any
time you're dealing, particularly with files and things, you have the potential to screw things up
badly, right?
Like you could refer to a file that doesn't exist in the file system.
And if that were to happen, basically, Java wants me to programmatically tell it, what should I do
or what should the what should Java do if the file that I tell it to go look for doesn't exist right
now?
What I can do here is if I hover over this, I'm getting a little helper here that's saying, Hey,
do you want me to add what's called an exception to this method signature?
Actually, no, I don't want that in this particular case.
But but that that might have been one of the things I could have done.
Instead, one minute is also going to click on this more here, and it's going to offer me a few other
options.
OK?
And one of the options that I like is to surround with a try catch.
We're going to learn about this later.
So don't worry about it right now, OK?
Basically, though, I'm telling it with this code, try to open this file.
And if it doesn't work out for you, then do whatever I say to do down here, right like this is kind
of an alternative, right?
So don't worry about the rest of that for now.
So now I can come back up here now in the rest of this code inside of what's called a try block here.
I can proceed with with doing things as if everything worked out right.
So now I can just call my strings that API things.
And so let's say I want to do a for each and I'll just print out those lines for now.
OK, so if I run this, let's see what happens.
Hey, look at that.
Look at that.
Right.
So there's all those lines now just to prove that that's not coming from from here.
Let me comment all of this out.
There we go.
All right.
So now nothing could be coming from there.
And if I run this one more time?
Cool.
So it still works, right?
So we can see that this is actually loading that data from an actual file.
And this would be a much more realistic way that if you really wanted to be loading data, long lines
of data and things, this would be a more realistic way that we'd be doing it as professional Java developers
rather than copying and pasting text into our program inside of a variable multi-line or a text block
or something like that.
Right.
I've just been doing that for you with you for now because we haven't learned how to do file things
yet.
But like I said, this is a little sneak preview of how to do that.
So the main takeaway here is that this file stat lines method here really has a lot of functionality
packed into very little code.
It knows how to go find that file at that path, open it up if it's readable and in good and all of
that, it will read the individual lines out just like the string that lines method does, and then
and then spit out a stream of strings, right?
And then we can process them just as just as we've been doing for a while here.
All right.
And so I know this again was a pretty long one because I just wanted to show you and one big set most
of the ways that you can create a stream.
OK.
And there you go.
So I will see you in the next one.