All right, so in the last lesson, we learned that enemies inherit a built in method called ordinal,
which conveys the order in which the in-room constants exist or are defined.
And although you need to be very careful when using this, it can be at times a really useful feature
of an enum, as we see here in that we're able to use it to derive a value from the various constants.
And then we also ended up using the newer version of the Java switch in its expression form so that
we could convert the values of Jack, Queen and King to a 10 and all other values using the default
here to the natural ordinal value of the Enum plus one.
So now I want to show you something else that's kind of neat within MS.
So I've mentioned now a number of times that enemies really are just a special form of class.
But the key thing for you to keep in mind here is that they are a type of class.
And so many of the things that we've learned that we can do with a class can be done with an enum as
well.
So to prove that point, I want to show you something kind of neat.
So here's something I kind of want to show you.
Here's a line of thinking.
We've got this get value method here that is currently living on the card class, right?
But what does it actually do?
It accesses the information about the rank of that card, and then it basically just translates that
rank into a value.
Now, one concept with object orientation is that you want your methods or your behavior in object oriented
terminology.
You want your methods or behavior to live as closely as possible to the data that they work with typically.
OK, so what does that actually mean?
In this particular case, the data that this method get value needs is a rank, right?
And with that rank, that's basically the input into this method.
Even though we're not technically passing an input in, but it's getting this rank from outside of the
method itself, right?
It's pulling that in from the surrounding object or class, right?
And then it's translating that rank into a value.
So here are the actual rank constants, if you will, and it's converting that either into a 10 or into
whatever value the the number card has, right the face value of the card.
So there's something about this.
Now we're doing this on the card class itself.
But can you think of anywhere else more fundamental of where this rank data actually comes from?
So this rank data actually is coming from the rank class itself, right?
The rank enum sorry itself.
And because enemies are classes, one of the tricks that they can do which they have in common with
regular classes is that an enum can have methods.
So do you kind of see where I'm going with this?
If one of the object oriented best practices or principles is that you want your behavior, which has
methods to be as close as possible to their data?
Right.
The data that they work with?
Well, then what would happen if we could basically take this method here?
And put it on the rank enum itself.
Let's see what that might look like.
So I'm literally just going over here to the rank class, and I'm going to put a couple of spaces here
and then I'm going to start off by just pasting.
All right.
Now when I do that, I do get a couple of little red marks here because it doesn't quite know what I'm
talking about in a couple of cases.
Online 19, I'm getting a red mark for the word rank because there is no property on this enum called
rank right.
However, when I'm working with a method of an enum, the instance of this enum, which would really
be any of these values here in this case innately would hold the rank.
I'll try to show you what I mean.
So if we want this to work, we can start off by simply removing the word rank.
Because let me put it this way, when this code is executing inside of an enum, the rank is the entire
object itself, right?
I mean, this is the rank class.
So each of these constants here is an actual instance of a rank.
And if we could call a get value method on an instance of an enum, that would mean that that instance
itself is a rank, which means we would not have to say this does not rank.
We could simply say this.
OK, now the keyword.
This means the instance of the object that we are dealing with at this moment.
OK.
And I can I can already hear some of you are listening to what I'm saying, and it's not meaning anything.
So I promise you, I'm going to drill in on this.
OK.
So let me let me finish fixing the errors here, and then we'll write a little bit of code to use this,
and then I'll try to make it more clear.
All right.
So we can switch on this instance.
So in this case, this would mean whichever one of these constants.
We are working with in some other code, in another class, OK?
Or each of these things would be an instance of the Enum.
OK.
Now we need to fix this little bit here as well, and to do that, since this code would be running
inside of an actual instance of an enum.
And we know that instances of the Enum have or inherit a method called ordinal ordinal.
Then we don't need this or rank.
We can just get rid of these
and just use the the ordinal method, which is essentially inherited by the instance of the enum itself.
OK?
So that's why we don't have any error now.
All right.
So let's see what this can look like.
So to do that, we're going to create a test for the rank enum itself, and I'm going to do that by
doing a command shift T.
And then I will choose create new test and I will accept all of the defaults and click, OK.
All right.
And now I'll do a command in four Windows Linux, you'll have to right click, I think, right click,
you know, just somewhere inside of the class on an empty space somewhere.
Mac users can do command in and then choose test method.
All right.
So we've got a test method here.
So let's just play around a little bit.
Let's just see what happens if I don't know.
For right now, I'm going to just name this something kind of slightly throwaway.
Get value of king.
OK, so what I will do here is I will assert equals I'm going to assert that the value of a king is
a 10.
And then the way I will actually get this is I will refer to the rank enum king dot get value just like
that.
OK.
Now that I've copied the get value method onto the rank class, every instance of the rank inherits
this, so let me show you in some measure code, what another way of looking at at this, OK?
To help you to understand what that this keyword was doing, OK?
This instance here ranking you might think of it a lot, like saying something like this rank king equals
new rank.
King, you might think of.
This as being kind of equivalent to this.
OK.
That's one way you could think of it.
And so you could imagine that there are all of these instances of inhumane.
I'll make one more, by the way, let me show you another little neat trick here.
I'm full a little neat tricks with the aid, OK?
I like short shortcuts for the aid.
And sometimes I forget about them myself.
I just was changing this queen here and here.
And then I remembered, Oh, wait a minute, there's a slightly better or more efficient way for me
to do that, so I can double click on this king here and then I can hold down on option shift and double
click on this king here.
And now I've selected both kings at the same time, and I can change them both at the same time.
So watch this J A C K So I'm typing in two places at once so that I can change that.
And now to get rid of these double cursors, I can just hit escape buttons.
All right.
So anyway, these things here, these instances, these would be.
These guys here, OK?
That's what these are.
So when we're defining these constants here, what we're basically doing is creating a shorthand for
something kind of equivalent to this.
OK, if that helps you a little bit to understand a little bit better, what's going on, OK?
It's just like some weird compiler magic, some compiler voodoo that the creators of Java have implemented
in order to allow us to have enemies.
By the way, let me say enemies have not existed in Java from the beginning.
I think they came about in version Java five, if I'm not mistaken.
And they were kind of a big deal because there are other languages that already had this notion of an
enum and prior to having proper enemies.
If Java developers wanted to have something like this with, you know, type safe, tightly constrained
objects that we could use in places like where we're using it here, we had to create classes and then
go through a bunch of nonsense, and it still wasn't quite as good as what you get with an actual proper
enum type.
OK.
So just a little little history on iTunes there.
All right.
So anyway, hopefully by now you understand this approach to creating an instance of an object.
Now, don't be alarmed by the fact that here I've chosen to name the instances in all caps.
That's just in keeping with the convention of Enemies, which are sort of modeled off of constants anyway.
But other than that, the, you know, you could maybe think of them as just regular instances of some
class and also ignore the fact that I chose to pretend like there's some kind of a constant that takes
a string.
This is just me sort of giving you a mental picture, a mental model to work with.
This isn't literally how informs exactly work, though.
It's not too far off, to be honest with you.
It actually isn't too far off because internally enemies have an internal property called name.
And this this constant that we are defining here, these constants here actually end up being treated
as strings that get stored inside of an internal property of an instance which is called name.
So you really can pretty much think of venoms as being something along this, these lines here.
All right.
So you can think of it as these instances of an object, right?
Now let's look at how this get value method works.
And in fact, you know what I'm going to I'm going to copy this.
I'm going to copy this as a little gentle reminder.
And we're going to jump in to this get value method here, and I'm going to just paste paste that there.
So you have a little reference point, OK?
So let me explain the this keyword and how it's being used here.
OK.
So when we call get value, in fact, hold on a second here.
Let me even let's even bring let's even bring this line over as well so we can look at that to.
I'll just bring it in as a comment.
All right.
There we brought everybody to the party now.
OK.
So when we call get value like we're doing here from somewhere other than in this class, especially
the thread comes in here.
So what is it actually in, though?
Well, it's inside of an instance.
It's inside of an instance.
Like it could be this instance right here, right?
So you're inside of an actual object?
Right?
And now you're just calling the get value method of that particular object right?
And so when the thread gets down here, do switch this the word this refers to.
This instance, whatever instance you happen to be in.
So in this particular case, if we were calling ranking get value, then that would mean we are in the
get value method of this instance of the king object.
OK.
Or of the King Enum, if you will.
And this instance of the king object will have certain properties that it has inherited or that have
been set on it.
OK.
So one of the properties that is set on the king is its ordinal value, right, which we get out of
it from the ordinal method.
Now that's set by magic as far as I'm concerned, right?
Like, we don't set that somehow when the compiler is building is compiling and building these instances,
it's keeping track, I suppose, of the order in which these constants are defined and then it's somehow
setting those on these instances.
Well, actually, I should back up.
I don't know if that's happening at compile time or at runtime or whatever.
And right now, I don't really care.
But somehow that that ordinal value is being associated with each of these instances at some point.
OK.
And that will be stored on each of the individual instances, though.
Now, when we call, switch and pass this in a certain level of Java, magic is happening for the Switch
statement to basically summarize what each and the essence of an instance of an enum is OK.
So for all I know, it might just be using the actual string name of the of the enum itself.
OK, that that might be what it's doing, or it might be a little fancier than that.
But this this here refers to this entire instance of an enum.
Let's see.
And then OK.
So then when we get down here to calling ordinal, this is working because again, each instance of
the enum inherits the ordinal method.
OK.
So as far as this code is concerned, this is just a class and an instance of that class.
I've probably over explained it by now.
I hope I have at least OK.
So hopefully that's making sense to you.
And obviously, you know, you've seen the word this before.
Now, I haven't spent a ton of time on it, but it always will refer to the current instance of the
object that the word this is inside of a OK.
So in this case, if we were calling King Typekit value, then this would refer to the king instance.
OK, if we were calling ranked queen get value, then the word this would be referring to that object,
the queen object.
OK.
All right.
Let's see here.
So.
Oh, now let's jump back over to that test because I never actually ran it, did I?
All right, so let's run this guy.
All right.
And so that passes as we should have expected that it would.
So now that we have implemented the get value method directly on the Enum, let's see what the implications
may be for our card class.
So if we jump back over to the card class now, this means that maybe we could do some things so I can
see a couple of options here.
One is that we could consider simplifying the get value method on the card class and do something like
this return this rank.
Does it get value?
So basically here we're just delegating the get value call down to the lower level, get value, call
OK, and to prove that this should still work.
Now, if we jump over to the test for the card itself, we should be able to run all of these tests
and they should all still pass.
So let's see.
Yeah, they all still still work, right?
So just to reiterate the point here, I have two points that I want to reiterate.
One is that enemies are essentially just special classes, and because they are special classes, they
do share a few of the same capabilities as a class.
Chief among them is that you can put methods on them.
OK.
And then the other idea that I want to reiterate is the idea that you'll usually want to keep your methods
as close to the data that they work with as possible.
OK, so here in this case, we started off with a method living on the card class, but you can now
see that the data that the get value method in the card class needed was really not data that's directly
on the card class.
It's actually data that's a little lower one level lower in the rank class.
So that's why we were able to just basically take this whole method and push it down one level, if
you will, to the rank class and with very minimal changes, that method still works, OK?
And now it's arguably a tiny bit more efficient as well.
OK.
So I've seen developers who would put almost every single method that they needed in an entire program,
all in like one class, even though the data that those various methods were working with may have been
in various lower level classes.
And that's a really bad idea.
It violates certain principles of object orientation, such as encapsulation, where you really want
to hide your data within the classes where that data pertains the most and not let that data leak out
until it's actually needed.
And even then, you only want to allow outside access to just the narrowest amount of data necessary.
OK.
Which is why you see so much Java code with classes and properties where the properties are defaulted
to being private.
OK.
So that way we just make sure hey, if you need access to this, use the getters and setters.
So that way we have an opportunity to kind of police who's accessing it and what that data actually
comes out looking like.
All right.
So that's going to be it for this little lesson, and we're going to stick with Interms for a little
bit longer, though there's a few more things that are cool that you should learn about.
So I'll see you in the next one.