Now I'm going to challenge you to pause the video and see if you can think of a way to make this all
happy, right?
Like how can you make this work?
So take a moment to do that.
All right.
So I'm going to do it now.
So there's a little bit of review and we're going to just kind of cram a bunch of cool things together
here.
OK, so we've got records.
So first thing we're going to want to do record is a collection, and we know that the collections classes
all implement a stream method on them so we can go to the stream there.
And from here, I don't know.
Maybe we want to do a filter.
Perhaps there's several ways to skin this cat, but let's just do a filter.
And so the filter method takes a predicate.
We know that a predicate is an interface.
By the way, predicate is actually a generic interface, and we see it right there.
Predicate of something.
That's how I read this question mark, something that has a superclass of T. So we'll learn a little
bit more about what this is really meaning here.
But I just wanted to point out that these functional interfaces are all not only functional, they're
also generic, OK?
They work with virtually any data type.
So anyway, it takes a predicate.
A predicate is simply an interface that exposes a method that is simply an interface for us to write
essentially a lambda or a method reference that takes an input and then returns a Boolean or true or
false to determine whether or not objects that pass that predicate should be allowed to flow through
the stream filter through the stream or be blocked.
OK, so we're going to pass in a lambda expression.
With an arrow there, P. I'll call it P for person, and then we'll just say something like where I
don't know that I'd.
Oh, and look, look at this now we've got a problem here.
Now, do you know what the problem is?
And you probably ran into this while you tried to do this?
All right.
So do you know what the problem is?
Well, what is the type of P?
I'm calling it P because I'm assuming I'm going to use it for a person, right?
But in actuality, in the repository class, there's no mention of a person anywhere.
Right?
There's no place in here that we're mentioning a person within this class, not down here in the public
static void main, which you can almost consider to not be part of the repository class at all.
Yes, we are referring to a person down here, but up here in our definition of a repository which effectively
ends right here.
There's no mention of p right of a person, rather.
So the problem is that we're trying to access a method or a property of a class and in code that doesn't
know that class like it doesn't know that type.
And I did this actually on purpose so that I could set us up for another little piece of learning that
we're going to get into.
So how can we address this?
So this gets into a slightly more advanced scenario here.
What we can do.
We don't want to necessarily hard code our repository to just work with person because that would effectively
put us right back where we started from right instead of string.
Now we're hardcoded to person.
We still might want to be able to use a lot of different data types, right?
So what we can do, though, is we can somewhat constrain.
Right.
So right now, it's kind of wide open with this T here.
So maybe what we could do is we could introduce an interface that implements a Get ID method.
OK.
And then we could tell our generic class here, accept any class that is implementing this particular
interface.
OK.
So that's what we could do.
So to do that, I'm going to come down here to where I've already defined one class, the record.
And you know, you notice I'm using the term record class kind of interchangeably because I just want
to make sure that you are fully aware that a record is effectively a class still.
It's just a very constrained class.
All right.
So let's introduce an interface, and let's call this idea bowl, OK, because it's going to be something
that is capable of having an idea.
And let's define one method on it, and this will be a method called idea.
Now, normally we'd want to call this something like get ID, but I want this to be fully compatible
with our record here.
And records don't create getters with the get word in front of them.
They just create their getters with the same name as whatever the property is.
So here we have a property called ID.
So the getter for this is also going to just be called ID, and I want this all to match up.
All right.
So down here, my getter is simply going to be defined as ID.
OK.
Now that's going to need a return type.
And this is going to be kind of interesting here.
So here's another opportunity to use a generic.
I don't really want a hard code type long on this.
I could, but that also kind of pigeonholed me a little more than I would like to be pigeonholed, right?
So I don't want to do that.
Instead, I want to use a generic data type again.
So again, I'm just going to use T.
And by the way, I could I could call this anything, OK?
I could use any letter here.
And in fact, you know, why don't I?
I'll just use a different letter just so you can see that I can use any any letter I want.
Now that I've put this up here, now I'm getting a red line because the compiler does not know what
this data type is.
So I need to tell it, Oh, that's not going to be a real data type that I'm going to create a class
for.
That's just a generic right.
And so for me to tell the ad in Java that this is a generic and not a future upcoming data type, some
class that I was going to create in the future, which it is not.
I need to come over here and now make this interface generic, which takes us to another kind of a point,
which is that interfaces can also be generic.
As I was saying earlier, with all the functional interfaces we've got right?
And so again, I can just do that.
OK, so now we've got a generic data type for our IDs as well.
All right.
And so now that we've got this idea bowl thing here, I can now come up here and constrain our class
a little bit.
OK?
Just to the point that we're going to say Ti needs to be something that implements the ideal interface.
And so to do that, I can just say extends idea all.
Now, notice that it's stuck this repository thing in front here because this is a nested class, right?
So it's nested inside of the repository, so just put that there.
All right.
So now that T is something that extends repository date idea bill, and by the way, we're not quite
done.
But I'll come back to that in just a moment.
OK, now that this is something that extends Idea Bill, I can now come down here and acknowledge that
whatever items are coming out of this record that stream, this is going to be a stream of.
Right?
A stream of tea.
And I now know that these key records that are in this stream are going to be objects that implement
Idea Bill.
And I know that ideal bill always has a method called ID on it.
All right.
So if I put my cursor here into a control space, we'll look at that now.
It knows about the ID method.
OK, which is all I ever wanted.
And so will delete that.
Now notice I'm still getting a red squiggly line here.
That's just be that's partially because I'm not done right.
This needs to be a lambda expression that takes a p as an input, and then it's going to have to return
a Boolean to evaluate whether or not this particular object should be allowed to flow through the filter
here.
OK?
So sorry, we took a long detour just to come back into this lambda expression here.
All right.
So we need to determine whether or not P will be allowed to flow through the filter, and that should
be based on whether or not these ID matches this ID here that we're looking for.
And so that should be easy enough to do, Peter added.
That equals.
I'd.
OK, now we're getting another red squiggly line, and that's because we're still not done.
So now what's coming out of all of this currently records that stream that filter will be a stream of
T, right?
If I hover over this?
Yeah, we're getting a stream of tea.
And what we're really needing to return, though, is just a T.
Right.
So now we need to take that stream of T and just get one out of it, right?
And so one way that we can do that is with the find first method of the Streams API, so we can do that.
However, the fine first method doesn't just return it to it returns an optional P.
Right?
And we learned a little bit about option.
We're going to learn more about Options Real soon here.
So what we can do here is actually, let's have a little fun and let's actually use this method on the
optional class, which is or else through now that we've learned about exceptions and throwing and all
of that, can you understand what this method will do?
Look at that.
All of our squiggly lines went away, and it all seems to be happy.
So what do you think that method is doing?
Take a second and think about it.
All right.
So what this method is doing or else through is it's saying if we got back a legitimate object of type
T, go ahead and return that right.
And so that's what's going to come out of here.
However, if for some reason, though, you were not able to find an object of type out of all of this
stream, then just throw an exception and the exception.
If we hover over this, let's see here it's going to throw a no such element exception which feels fairly
appropriate for what we are doing.
OK, so that's what's going to happen there.
It's going to blow up, and I'm OK with that in this particular case.
And actually, if I recall correctly, I believe that defined by ID, methods on real repositories typically
can blow up if you refer to an ID, that just doesn't exist.
OK.
So I think that's legit.
All right.
Now I said I was going to come back to some.
Oh, yes, I said it was going to come back up here.
So we're saying T extends a repository that idea bowl.
Now our ideal bowl interface is itself generic, and that means that we could pass in a generic type
here as well.
But the question would be, Well, what should we pass in?
The answer is that up here, we don't have to actually decide a specific data type.
We can leave it generic.
And this brings us to another little lesson that I want to point out, which is when we are creating
generic classes are generic classes or interfaces, whatever.
Our generic types can have more than one parameter.
So right now, our our repository class has just one parameter, one generic parameter, which is T,
but we can actually have multiple generic parameters.
And in fact, some of the functional interfaces do in fact, work with two or even three parameters.
I don't recall if there are any that take more than three, but there are definitely quite a number
of that take two.
Like any of the functional interfaces that are called by or binary or something like that, frequently
they're going to take at least two parameters, right?
So we can add another parameter to the repository class, and that parameter will be used to specify
what the data type is for our IDs.
OK.
So the way we can do that is I'm going to put a comma here and then I'm going to introduce another parameter
and I will call this V.
Now again, I can call it whatever I want.
OK.
In fact, I was sort of debating the call it you because I did call this thing down here.
You and this thing here is actually going to end up being tied to this.
But I didn't want to be.
I don't know if I don't know if it's going to be confusing for you to see it that way or not.
I didn't, and I also didn't want you to think that it had to be called the same thing because it does
not.
So let's let's stick with the V for right now, and you'll see.
All right.
So we've got this v here, right?
And so now I can come over here and I can use this.
I know this might start to get a little confusing looking, but I will try my best to just explain what's
going on.
So now I can say that this idea bowl interface is going to be of type the.
Just like that.
And now this whatever data type we're working with here is actually what we're going to be working with
down here.
Now let me show you what that's really going to look like.
Notice I now have a couple of errors, by the way.
Now the errors that we're getting are telling us, Oh, you're trying to create a repository of person?
But the problem is that person is not a class and string are not classes that extend from ideas.
All right.
So now we're further constrained what types are allowed for association with the repository?
And so we're getting this now.
And so now we need to make this happy.
Now I can tell you now we're never going to make it happy for string, and that's by design.
We're done with string, so I'm going to go ahead and just comment out all of that.
OK.
That's never going to work because we didn't write the string class, nor would I care for it to work
anyway.
But the person class we can do something about.
So what we need to do now with the person class is simply make it implement idea bill.
That's it.
That's all it has to do.
And so we can actually just come over here and say implements ideas.
Now, since this is a generic type, we can actually go a little further and state what the generic
type is.
Now here will be a little less fancy.
We've already decided that for the person class, it's IDs are of type long.
Right?
And so it is appropriate and correct to actually go ahead and state the actual type that we want tied
to this interface here as being type long that way.
This interface, when used in the context of the person class, will have an ID method that is actually
showing up as a returning type long.
OK.
All right.
So now that we've done that, let's come back down here and we still got squiggly lines, so let's hover
over that and see wrong number of type arguments.
We're passing in one and it's but two are required.
And that makes sense because we now are saying that to create a repository, you need to pass in T and
you also have to pass in the right.
So down here, we can now say that the tea is person, right?
That's the data type that we are generally referring to.
But then we can also specify what type the IDs for person should be.
And that is long.
And now that ever goes away.
All right.
And now we also will get rid of this first system now that print because I got rid of the that first
repo, OK?
And now I think we are ready to actually run this and maybe it won't blow up.
So we're passing in 30 and we've got our lamda up here that's looking for the IEDs and comparing them.
So let's try it out and see we should get back.
Jerry Johnson.
OK, so let's run it and see.
All right.
So good news.
It did not blow up and good news again.
We got back Gary Johnson for this first person here, right?
So that is now working as expected.
OK, so now that we've constrained what T can be when working with a repository, this generic T is
said to be bounded now.
OK.
So in other words, it's it's constrained, it's bounded in that it has to be something that implements
essentially, although we're using the word extent here because that's what generic supports.
But it has to be something in this case that implements the idea.
By the way, just as we're using an interface here, I could also have bound this to a class.
OK, so if I had a superclass that person extended from, I could have said something like T extends
whatever the name of that superclass is.
So whether it's a class or an interface doesn't really matter.
Here you use, the word extends either way.
And with that said, I want to show you one other thing related relating to this.
Let's say that I also had another interface.
This one would be just kind of like for show interface.
Let's call this savable.
All right, and I'm not even going to define any methods on it, it's just a an interface.
And occasionally in Java, you will see interfaces that don't actually implement any methods at all.
Those are typically called flag interfaces, and their purpose is simply to flag that this classes of
a certain type.
OK, so here I have a flag interface called savable.
So if I wanted to even further, further bind or constrain my generic T here, I could say only allow
me to create repositories that work with instances of objects that are both ideal and survivable.
And the way I can do that is by coming up extends repository that idea able.
And then after all of the generics there and.
Savable.
So I can do that now.
Having done that notice, this is an error again.
And the reason is because my person class currently does not implement both of those interfaces.
It only implements the ideal interface.
So now I need to come over here and add in another interface that this guy is said to be implementing.
And now the red marks go away.
So the only point of me showing you this was just to say that you can really, really, really constrain
your generic types if you want to or need to.
OK, now let me also step back and say I could have avoided using generics altogether and simply come
down here to the internal collection for this.
And instead of saying T, I could have said something like a list of.
Idea.
All right.
I could have done that.
And that would have given given me very similar functionality here, except I would have been missing
out on a few things.
All of my types would have had to be of type ideal bill, which means they would have been less specific
than what they actually are, right?
Everything would be ideal and then I would have to still cast if I wanted to get back out a person like
here.
Right?
So here I'm doing a fine by ID.
I'm getting an actual person because this method, if I go, look at it right?
Look at this fine by ID.
The I.D. is telling me that it returns an actual person, right?
That's because it's generic.
If I hadn't had not used a generic and I had simply just defined the list here to be of type ideal,
then this method and all other methods like it would have just been returning something of type ideal.
And then if I wanted to work with this variable here, the person, I would have had to cast it to person
so that I could then call whatever special special methods are on that person class.
So again, I using generics, I'm not needing to cast anything OK?
And it's actually keeping my utilization of the repository class relatively simple.
Even though the implementation may look a little complicated to some of you.
Now let me also state that I don't really expect that the majority of you as junior developers, I mean,
you're taking this course so that you can learn Java from from nowhere, right?
I don't really expect that any of you who would take a job as a Java developer after taking this course
are likely to be getting deep into any of this.
And that's why this whole entire module is just doing one offs where I'm just kind of blowing through
a lot of these, a lot of these techniques that most of you are not super likely to go real deep on.
So rather than creating an entire module just on generics, which some courses may do and I'm not,
I'm not saying that's a bad thing to do.
But the whole point of this particular course is for you to be able to learn.
What I know is most commonly going to be used by most Java developers in a company.
And most Java developers are not having to do a whole lot of this.
When you're creating classes that are as generic as this, using all these fancy techniques and everything,
you're typically creating what are called APIs, right?
Those are the programming tools that programmers use, right?
So you're making the tools that a programmer would use.
So most of you are not likely to be doing that real soon.
OK?
But again, in the interest of somewhat completeness, want to just show you how some of this stuff
is working?
All right.
And so I've got one more technique that I want to show you now.
It's still with generics, but not super related to any of this stuff here.
Not only can we use generics on classes and interfaces, as we're doing here, we can also use them
on methods.
And I don't mean like these instants methods that we've got here that are just utilizing the definition
of T as a as it exists on the class itself.
We can use generics on static methods.
So we're going to create a static method that honestly isn't going to really have anything to do with
this class.
I just don't feel like making another class and we don't need one here.
We're going to make a static method that is going to simulate the ability to encode data.
OK.
So you're going to pass in some data of a type.
And then this method will return an encrypted representation of that data.
Now, we're not really going to make any real encryption stuff here.
This will be like, you know, fake.
But this will allow me to show you how you can make generic static methods, which actually can be quite
useful at times, and this might be something that you'll maybe really use.
All right.
So we're going to have a method and let's just call it, I don't know, encrypt and it's going to take
input.
And again, I don't want to have to specify specifically what the data type will be.
So I'm just going to say it's going to take something of time.
Now this is going to be different from the tee up here, by the way, I could use a different letter,
but I'm not going to.
Instead, I'm going to say this, though, when working with static methods, which I haven't actually
declared the static yet, I guess I will now working with static methods that use generic types there,
generics have nothing to do with the generic types that may exist on their enclosing class.
OK, so this tie up here is completely different and unrelated to this tie down here.
Just know that rule.
OK.
All right, so T and I don't know.
Let's just call it.
Message, no, let's call it data.
And then it's going to return something, and let's even make the return type generic as well.
So let's call that the OK.
And then it's going to have a body and we're going to do some stuff for right now, I'm just going to
say no.
All right.
So we got a problem already.
As you see here, we've got red squiggly thunder, the T and the V.
Why is that?
Well, for a static method like this that is meant to be generic, the ADC doesn't know what these data
types are, right?
And so we need to tell the IED these aren't going to be just data types of classes that we're going
to go and create in another, you know, somewhere, right?
Like we can create a class called T, I suppose.
We don't want that, though we need to tell Java that this is a generic method.
And the way we can do that is by putting our cursor in front of the first generic type there, and we're
going to use the, you know, greater than and less than symbols again.
And now we can say T comma v.
And now those went away.
So that lets us tell Java that this is a generic method.
OK.
By putting this here and this is a generic method with two parameters now, I could have made it a generic
method with one parameter if I'd wanted to.
But this one is with two generic parameters.
And while we're at it, actually, let's also go ahead and let it let this method take to actual parameters,
not generic parameters, right?
So it's going to take the data and then we're also going to be able to pass in a method that's actually
going to do the encrypting, OK?
And you'll see why we're doing that in just a moment here.
And so here's an opportunity that I didn't show explicitly in the lambdas module, but I will show it
now.
So here we are, creating a method that will utilize a lambda expression or a method reference.
OK.
So we want this encrypt method to be able to take some, some data of type T, and it's going to take
that data and encrypted using an algorithm that we also can pass in.
OK.
And so the algorithm itself will simply be a function.
It'll be a function that takes an input, which will be our data, and then it will spit out an output.
OK.
And so we can actually utilize the pre-existing functional interfaces that Java comes with to do exactly
this.
And in fact, if I just start typing function, there we go.
That's the guy that I actually want to use.
I want a function that takes an input and returns an output.
The input will be of type T.
The output in here is referred to as R.
OK.
So.
A function, and I will say that it's going to use our T and the V there, and then I will call this,
I don't know if you can see.
All right.
And now down here I can say funk dot apply.
And the apply is how I will actually execute whatever lambda I pass in here.
OK.
So now you're getting to see this from the other side, right?
So if it's not entirely clear, hopefully it will become clear in just a moment here.
All right.
So we're going to pass in the data.
There we go.
So we have now created a generic static method that is also functional.
And by the way, this is what all of those functional methods that we were using.
This is what they look like.
They they do things like this, OK?
This is how they're written.
They are coded using these functional interfaces, and they're all generic.
And so now we're kind of creating some of our own here.
OK.
All right.
So now we can come down here somewhere, I guess I'll do it down here.
And let's just do a system that out.
And so now we can refer to this encrypted method like so and we can pass it in some data.
So let's just pass in the word hello for now.
And then it needs a function.
And now we can just pass in a lambda expression.
OK.
That's going to operate on that word.
Hello, in this case.
So our message, I'll call it in.
And then an arrow indicator.
And let's encrypted now.
We're not really going to encrypt this wolf.
We'll fake it.
We'll start off by doing a very easy encryption.
We'll just uppercase the the word okay, so we can do that by saying in that to upper.
Now notice I'm typing to upper here, but I'm not getting any auto completion.
The reason for that is because at the moment, the I.D. doesn't actually know what this data type is.
OK?
It's just not quite smart enough to be able to infer that from the fact that I'm passing in a string
here and then coming up here and looking at all of this and determining, Oh, OK, so this thing here
is of type T, and he's going to want to return something of type B.
And it also has no way right now of even knowing what that type V should be.
Especially since we're not able to finish this bit here.
So how do we get around this?
Well, one of the easiest things to do in this case would be to simply tell it what those data types
are.
And we can do that right here on this encrypt call here.
So what I can do is first, I will use the fully qualified class name of this encrypt method.
Repository Dot Encrypt.
All right.
That's step one.
Step two is I will put my cursor right after that period there, and then I can use the less than greater
than symbol here, and I can actually specify the generic data types that this encrypt method should
be working with.
So in this case, string and string, because my input will be of type string and the output will also
be of type string.
So notice now some of the error marks went away.
And now if I put my cursor back here on this M period and do a control space.
Now look at that.
I am now seeing the methods of the string class because now the I.D. slash java knows what this type
really should be because I'm basically telling it right there.
OK.
And so now I can do a two uppercase whoops.
There we go.
Here we go.
And now I can run this.
And I get all uppercase, hello.
And let's do one more of that.
So we'll do another repository, Dot now, this time I will pass in a string and I want to get a long
out.
Encrypt.
World.
And here's my message.
Use the arrow indicator, but this time I'm going to call Dot.
Hash code.
Oh, I'm sorry, and hash code method actually returns an integer.
There we go and see see that.
So when I had it as a long, that was an error, but I changed it to an integer and now it all matches
up, right?
So there's the there's the generics at work for you.
All right.
And so let's run that.
There we go.
And so now we're getting that, so we're pretending like these methods are encrypting something, but
really we're not doing real encryption, right?
We're just pretending like it.
OK, so I know this was a lot.
I know this was a whole lot.
Don't worry if you didn't follow every single thing that I gave you here.
If you really, really, really want to understand this better, I would advise you to go actually sit
down with a good book and go into more depth.
But I'm telling you now that the overwhelming majority of Java developers, especially business developers,
which is a lot of weird Java is used the most may never really need to learn most of these techniques
to this, to even this level of detail, to be really honest with you, OK?
You can just consider this lesson to be for those of you who really wanted to go a little deeper, right?
So, OK, we went a little deeper now, but these are some pretty powerful techniques, and it's nice
to just be aware that you can do them right.
So don't worry about memorizing how to do all of this.
I rarely use most of these techniques myself.
So you can always go back and rewatch this video if and when you think you have a good reason to need
some of these techniques.
And you can also obviously go find a book and go into more detail on it.
OK.
So with that being said, I am going to go ahead and wrap this up now.
And you now know a little bit more about generics.
I will see you in the next one.