Now, all data in the computer ultimately gets stored in binary like so OK.
And that means that all data that we work with in the computer needs space in the computer.
And that's where we get into the idea of RAM for your computer.
So when you buy a computer, one of the specifications that you probably will pay attention to is how
much ram or how much memory does the computer have not to be confused with storage?
So the RAM in a computer?
Modern computers as of 2021 probably will tend to come with maybe four gigs of RAM, eight gigs of RAM,
16GB of RAM.
Those three are probably the most common configuration for the average computer these days.
But what does that actually mean?
Four gigs, eight gigs, 16 gigs of RAM.
Well, to understand that we need to kind of look at what some of the Greek prefixes that are used when
referring to memory.
So right here, we're looking at one byte, which is eight bits.
OK.
But if we had a thousand bytes, you could call that one kilobyte because kilo means 1000.
Right?
However, in computing, typically when we are referring to the amount of storage and bytes of a computer
and we use these these Greek prefixes like kilo and mega and giga and terabyte and things like that,
we don't typically mean just a simple number like 1000 memory and computers tends to be based on powers
of two.
And so the number one thousand is not a power of two.
The closest number to 1000 that would be a power of two is 1024.
And so if we were to say that a computer has one kilobyte of RAM, we would likely mean that it has
1024 bytes, not 1000 bytes.
OK.
So sometimes you may see these odd numbers thirty two thousand seven hundred sixty eight or sixty five
thousand five hundred thirty five or something like that.
The reason you see these kind of weird numbers instead of like nice even hole numbers, is because memory
in computers tends to be measured in powers of two.
Now in the computer, every time we allocate memory for something like every time we use the new operator
and we say new string or something like that, what we're actually doing is we're asking the computer
to find some space in the computer, like, think about these these squares here, find some unused
space in the computer in which to create and store this new thing that we're creating.
OK.
So any time we store like an integer or a long or a string or whatever, some new area in memory that
wasn't already in use gets allocated and assigned for the use of that new data.
So let's see a little bit of what that might look like.
In fact, if we go over to the ADP and I'm going, I'm going to create a new file and you're welcome
to follow along, but I don't think you need to for this.
I'm just going to show a couple of brief examples of some things.
No stuff.
All right.
So I'll create my typical PSP in here, and I'm going to create a variable, let's say first, I'm going
to create a a byte and I'll just call it my byte.
Equals 13, and then I will print that byte.
And I'll even go ahead and run this.
OK, now when the Java program gets to line three and runs this line, it's going to ask the computer
to give it one byte, one unused byte of memory in the computer so that it can store the number 13,
which I happen to have right here at 13.
OK.
And this byte in the computer will have an address.
Now that address, if I go back over here again, that address might look like look something like.
At.
Two F.
Three.
I'm just going to put some random.
Numbers here.
OK, that might be the address of.
This bite right here, these eight bits that represent this one bite.
This number 13 in memory of the computer.
OK.
And let's say the computer has eight gigs of RAM, so that would mean roughly eight billion bytes of
RAM.
But again, it won't be an even number of eight billion.
It'll be whatever number is closest to eight billion.
That is a power of two.
Whatever that number is, it would be a big number.
OK.
So that's how many bytes of storage the computer might have.
And so one of those bytes is going to be assigned the number 13.
And and that's how the computer is actually going going to work.
And then when we tell system that out, that print line to print this might what's going to happen is
that the computer is going to retrieve whatever value was stored at this location.
And and then it's going to print that onto the screen.
OK, so some of the other data types that we have access to, while the smallest data type that we can
use is actually called a Boolean.
So I'm going to create a Boolean real quick.
We don't know my flag.
All right.
So I just created a Boolean variable called my flag, and I set it to true.
So what's going to happen here is that again, Java is going to request storage space for this Boolean,
and a Boolean is just an on or or an off essentially or a true or a false, so it only requires one
bit.
OK, now I'll be honest with you, I don't actually know if the operating system and Java working together
are going to actually just use an entire byte because that is the smallest thing that can actually be
addressed.
Or if Java has some tricky way that for every eight bits that we allocate, it stores them all in one
byte that it keeps track of.
I'm not sure what it's going to do there.
And frankly, it doesn't really matter too much unless you're going to write a program where you're
going to be storing trillions of individual bits.
If every time you allocate a bit, it actually just ends up being a byte, that would be pretty wasteful.
I mean, you would be what you would want to be aware of that.
OK.
So anyway, a bit would just be one little thing here.
It could either be a one or a zero.
OK.
And if it's zero by default, then that means it's false.
And if it's one, then it's true.
So that's how the computer would represent these couple of data types Boolean and Byte.
All right.
So now let's also talk about what are the largest numbers that you could store in some of these data
types.
So obviously with a Boolean, you can only store a zero or a one.
Right.
So the largest number you could store in there if you want to talk about it in terms of numbers would
be a one.
OK?
The largest number that you can store in a byte by default would be well.
There's a range from negative 128 to positive 127, and that might not be super intuitive.
So by default, most of the basic numerical types in Java are what are called signed numbers, meaning
they can be negative or positive.
OK.
However, there's something interesting here.
If you didn't need to store negative numbers with something like a byte, which would be called unsigned,
then you could store a number in a byte up to 255.
So zero through 255.
OK.
Because if you added up, if you put a one in all of these bits of a byte and added all of that up 128
plus 64 plus 32 plus 16, eight, four, two and one, you would get 255.
OK.
However, the reason the range by default in Java is negative 128 to 127 is because now I'm going to
I'm going to.
I'm going to simplify this for you a little bit.
This is just a way that you can understand.
This OK is because in order to indicate to the computer system whether or not a number is negative or
not, the computer system will tend to store a zero or a one in the largest bit for whatever the data
type is.
So if we're talking about a byte, then it may store a one here to indicate that this is a negative
number.
OK, so if we wanted negative one, we might do something like this or rather the computer might do
something like.
This OK, so now this number might not be interpreted as 129, but rather negative one.
And because we're now using up the largest bit in this data type of bite, which is also called the
most significant bit, or maybe the biggest one here because we're using that one up, we've decreased
our range, our total range in half.
OK.
So whereas the largest number that you could have represented in a in an unsigned byte would have been
255 in a sound bite.
It's going to end up being 127, which would be 64 plus 32 plus 16, et cetera, et cetera.
OK.
127.
So that's kind of an important concept to be aware of because it is the combination of the amount of
space that we take up in the computer versus the largest range of numbers that we need to represent.
That helps us to decide what data type we should use.
You may have wondered earlier, Well, why don't we just use the largest data type for everything?
And the reason would be, well, because we'd waste a lot of memory if we were to do that.
And so typically we want to use the smallest data type we can get away with for whatever it is that
we're needing to do in the computer.
All right.
So let's look at some more data types now.
So we've looked at billions and bytes.
The next largest data type is a short OK, and a short route is 16 bits.
OK, so one through 16 or two bytes, OK, and a short number can represent the range of 30 negative
thirty two thousand seven hundred sixty eight to positive thirty two thousand seven hundred sixty seven.
All right.
Also, the data type of care which we have looked at before, is represented with two bytes.
Now that might come as a surprise to some, because if you live in a European or American country,
you probably are used to having an alphabet that has somewhere roughly around 26 letters.
Although I don't know how it works in countries where they use the extra little symbols and things,
but it's not.
It's not likely to be thirty two thousand characters to represent all of the variants of Latin letters
probably should not require anywhere near thirty two thousand numbers.
So why did Java decide to represent characters with two bytes?
Well, the reason for this is because Java wanted to be a programming language that is easily compatible
with all languages on Earth.
And although Latin alphabets don't require anywhere near 32000 characters, there are many other writing
systems and characters in the world.
And to represent all of them, you do need a really big range.
Now, I will say that if you are storing data in a variable of type short, it will have a range of
negative thirty two thousand two positive thirty two thousand roughly.
However, if you use a data type of care, which also is two bytes, you will no longer need the negative
numbers because the whole point of what you're trying to store in a care is not directly numbers, it
is actual characters.
So I'll just show what these look like in Java so we could create a short of my big short thing.
Anybody's ever watched the movie, the Big Short Great Movie, and we'll store a number of, I don't
know, 45 and then I'll create a care my care.
Now for this, I'm actually going to put an actual international character in here.
And if you may recall from previous lessons to allocate one character, you can use a single tick or
a single quote like I have here, and then you can put something in there so I could put a letter like
G.
OK, but I'm going to put something a little more interesting so that you can see firsthand that Java
really does support internationalized characters and strings.
So I'm going to switch to a different writing system, and I will use Korean now.
I'm only going to put one character in here and I will put, I don't know, gung.
All right.
So that's one Korean character, which incidentally, is somewhat equivalent to to this, as in Gangnam
Style.
OK.
So you may also be wondering now this isn't a Korean class, but but this is kind of an interesting
side note.
So you'll recall that I have said that the capital letter A is commonly encoded as a 65 in ASCII.
However, Java's default encoding scheme isn't technically ASCII, it's actually called Unicode.
But what the creators of Unicode did for Latin letters was they started off with ASCII.
And so all of the characters that are known to ASCII actually have the same values in Unicode as well.
So let's say like the letter A, for example, my A.
A capital A..
OK, so this would be in memory a 65.
OK.
However, for encoding Korean Korean works quite a bit differently than Latin letters work.
The creators of Unicode decided to encode Korean characters as syllables.
OK.
And so rather than encoding individual letters of the Korean alphabet, they actually encode entire
syllables of the Korean language.
And the reason for that is because of the way that Korean is printed and written.
This whole entire thing here is equivalent in English to all of these letters Ganji.
But whereas in Latin languages, we would write out each letter one at a time, in this way in Korean,
they're kind of clustered together into a into a little square, if you will, and it just made more
sense to them to encode each and every individual syllable of the Korean language as its own separate
character.
So if you can imagine how many characters would you need in order to represent every syllable in a language,
especially a language like Korean, you need a lot of characters, thousands of characters, in fact,
OK?
And so that's where we start to get into this fact that if you're encoding characters, you're going
to need at least two bytes in order to do it, because Korean alone requires thousands of bytes to encode
each and every single syllable that can exist in that language.