OK.
There's one more data type that I want to introduce you to in this lesson.
And it's kind of a special one.
It's kind of a meta or a hybrid data type, unlike the others that we've learned about so far, because
this data type depends on other data types to do its job, essentially, and that is an array.
So let me define what an array is simplistically.
And then we'll look at some examples to make it more clear.
But basically, an array can be thought of as a collection of other data types.
OK, so we've learned about data types like strings and integers and Boolean and things of things like
that.
Well, an array is a collection of those data types.
So for example, if you wanted to have a list of strings, you could store that list of strings in an
array.
OK?
If you're familiar with spreadsheets like Excel and you're used to putting data in lists in a spreadsheet,
you can kind of visualize data that you might put in one column or in one table of a spreadsheet similarly
to how an array would work if that helps.
All right.
So we're going to look at some examples to create arrays and how they are used.
We won't be going actively here, but I want to just give you a little fountain because you will see
arrays in future lessons.
And I don't want that to be the first time that you encounter them.
Plus, we've already been ignoring them for quite some time, as you're about to find.
So let's jump to the ADC and see what we hear.
All right.
So I think what I want to do is I'm going to create another class first.
And by the way, you're welcome to follow along, but I won't be going out of my way to explain every
single thing that I'm doing in the ADC because right now I just want to introduce you to this topic.
All right.
So I'm going to create a new class.
I don't know.
I'll just call it a ray demo.
All right.
And I'll make a new line, and I'm going to generate a public static void main method.
And right here, we've already got our first array.
I've been putting it off for the entire course thus far.
But this bit right here, that is a reference to an array variable.
The variable is, is this guy here?
ARGs, we get it every single time we generate a public static void.
Main method, but we haven't ever used this variable before.
But what we have here is a variable called args.
That's the name of the variable and it is an array.
And I know that because of these two symbols here, that means it's an array and it's an array that
holds a collection of strings.
And that's why I was saying at the beginning that an array is a special data type because it uses or
it depends on the other data types to be useful.
So you cannot really have an array on its own.
You have to have an array of some data type.
OK.
And let me show you visually what this kind of might look like.
So I'm going to open up a spreadsheet here.
OK.
So I've got an Excel spreadsheet open.
And what I want to show is kind of a visual representation of what an array might look like.
So we could have an array of strings.
And in that array of strings, we might have five different strings.
So maybe I could have strings that represent fruits.
OK.
So each each string in that array might be a different fruit name.
OK, so over here in the in the program, what this is telling us is that when the main method is called,
it is capable of accepting an input of an array of strings.
And we will refer to that array of strings with this name, this variable name of ARGs.
OK.
So you can look at this as a list of strings basically just like this here.
OK, so what do we do with this, though?
Well, let's let me show you a few examples of what we could do with this.
So I'm going to print out that variable there.
OK.
Now, to run this in a meaningful way, I need to do it a little differently than we have been running
things before.
Up until now, we've just been, you know, clicking on the play button or I do a control shift or something
like that, and I and I run it.
In fact, you know, I'll go ahead and just do that real quick.
Just so you can see what is showing me here is that I have this little bracket here is kind of indicating
that I have an array of strings.
That's that's basically what what all of this is saying with that little bracket there.
It's an array of strings that lives that this memory location.
OK, so that's that's basically what we're seeing.
They're not very useful in and of itself.
But if I run this program a little bit differently by running it from the command line, I can do something
that you haven't seen before.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm opening up a command line terminal prompt where I can type things
in essentially OK, and we may learn a little more about this in the future.
But right now, the point isn't for me to teach you about terminals and prompts and things.
The point is just for me to show you other ways of executing this main method so that we can pass something
some data into it.
All right.
So what I can do is I can run this program manually myself instead of letting the ADC run it for me.
I can run this from the command line and to run a Java program from the command line.
I use the Java command, which is all lowercase java, and then I need to tell Java where my class lives,
what folder it's in, which I do by doing this Hyphen P, which stands for class path.
So that's the path in which my class resides, the the classes this array demo.
And I happen to know that this array demo class lives over here in this folder called out production
business array demo.
That's where it lives.
So down here I can refer to that out production and I'm hitting tab to let my command prompt auto fill
in the rest of the path for me business.
And then once I'm in the correct folder, which is business, then I have a space and then I refer to
the class name itself.
OK, so now I'm telling Java to run this class, which resides in this folder, but I can tell it one
more thing too.
If I put another space here, I can pass in some arguments, which is what this word args stands for.
I can pass in some inputs to this, to this main method and use that data for whatever I like.
So I'm going to type in Apple Orange and I'm going to hit enter.
OK, so I got basically the same output as we did when we ran it from within the ADC.
It told me that we're printing out this args reference and that it is an array of strings that reside
at this address.
However, I can dig into this args variable and extract some information out of it.
So first thing I'll do is the ARGS variable being that it is an array has a number of methods that I
can call on it.
And so I can use the period and I can access some of these methods.
And the first method I'm going to access is the length, which will simply tell us how many items are
in this array.
So now if I want to run this again, I'm going to have to run it from the command line in order to be
able to pass in some arguments.
So, yeah, the reason why I'm having to run this program from the command line is so that I can pass
in some arguments because it's not quite as straightforward to do from within the IDE, although it
is possible to do.
But I think it's a little more straightforward just to do it from the command line for now.
OK.
So I'm going to run this again.
However, there's one more thing I'm going to have to do if I want to run this again.
Now that I've changed this code.
I'm going to have to tell the ADP to re compile this program.
So that's something I've been glossing over a lot.
Up until now, every time we've made a change to our programs and then we click this button here, the
I.D. checks to see if we've made any code changes and if we have it, it rebuilds our program and then
it runs it.
However, if we make changes here, but we run the program from the command prompt, the idea doesn't
know that it should rebuild this code.
So we have to either hit the play button, which isn't entirely useful to us because we won't be able
to pass in our inputs that we want.
But it would trigger the ADC to rebuild the program and then we could run it down here.
Or we can simply go up here to the build menu item and then tell the ad to rebuild the project with
this build project setting here.
And so that's what I'm going to do.
OK.
So now it's done rebuilding.
And so now back down here at the command prompt, if I use the up arrow key, I can recall that command
now.
This works on Macs and on Windows.
If you're using PowerShell, I think it might work on the non PowerShell.
And even with the non PowerShell in Windows is called the CMD Command ICSI program, but I just wanted
to not have to retype this whole entire thing again.
All right, and then I'm going to hit return to rerun this, and now I get the number two, and that
makes sense because I passed in two parameters or arguments Apple and Orange.
So what happens if I pass in five?
Grapes and pineapple and raspberry.
All right.
Now I get the number five.
So the program is seeing that I'm passing in all of these arguments now.
And each one is going into its own spot within the array and the array grows in length with each additional
string that I put in there.
OK.
But I can do more than just this.
I can also access the individual words.
And I'll do that on another line.
So let's say that I want to retrieve the first string in that array.
Well, arrays are what they call zero based, which means that I need to use the number zero somehow
as an index to access this first string in the array.
And the way that I do that is with a square bracket and then the index of the element that I want.
OK.
So each of these would be an element, but it's zero based.
So the first element is is zero, then one, then two three four ET.
OK.
So args zero would give me the first word that I pass in.
And now I'm going to have to rebuild.
So I'm going to use Command F nine to do that now.
OK?
And then I will rerun the program and now I get the word Apple in addition to the count.
And so obviously, I can change this and get any value that I want.
I can get the fourth string out of here and rerun that.
OK.
Yeah.
So now I got pineapple.
All right.
So there are other things that I could do.
Now let's say that I passed in numbers instead of words.
So let's say five four three two one.
And then I hit return.
All right.
It tells me that I have five arguments that I passed in.
And the fourth one is a two.
Now, even though I entered a bunch of numbers, those numbers are being stored as strings.
OK.
So what that kind of looks like is sort of like sort of like
something kind of like this.
OK.
So even though I entered a bunch of numbers, they're being stored in strings and therefore everything
that I'm reading out of here is actually a string.
OK?
So when we're passing arguments into a main method, the only data type we can work with for public
static void main method is an array of strings.
Everything is going to get translated into strings.
OK.
All right.
However, we can have other types of arrays and let me show you what that would look like.
So I'm going to delete this.
And we can make an array ourselves, so let's say that we want to have an array of actual numbers,
not strings, but actual numbers.
So to do that, we can create a variable for that array.
We're going to tell it that it's going to hold integers.
We're going to say that it's an array, though, and we can give that array variable a name, such as
numbers.
And now we have the option of initializing this array right now, so we can do that by using curly braces
and then we can pass in a comma delimited list of the data.
So if we wanted this array of numbers to contain the numbers 10 through whatever counting by 10s or
something, we could do something like this 10 comma, 20 comma, 30, 40, 50 and we could just keep
going.
And then we'll close the curly brace and then use a semicolon there.
OK.
And so now we have just created an array of integers, which is called nums.
And now we can use that array similar to how we did on lines three and four.
So we could get the length num start length just like that.
And we could access any one of those numbers by using the square bracket and then the index, OK, so
if we wanted the second number in that array, that would be one because it's zero based, so zero would
be the first one.
One would be the second one.
This would be index zero.
This would be index one index to Index three Index four.
OK, now if I don't care about getting anything useful out of here and I just want to focus on the output
from here, I mostly could go ahead and just run this from within the ADP.
Now, however, if I were to run this from the ADP, right, this moment, the program will blow up
and actually let me just show that real quick, and then I will explain why it's going to blow up and
by blow up.
I mean, have an exception or an error.
OK, so we got an exception, which is an error.
And you know that it's an error because of the ugly red text here.
And the exception is index three out of bounds for length zero at Array Main Blah Blah Blah.
Array demo dot java colon for what that's telling us, is that online for this line right here?
We tried to access index three, this three right here.
In an array, and that index three is out of bounds for an array of length zero, so what it's saying
is that this time when we ran the program, this array had zero elements in it.
And the reason it had zero elements in it is because since we did not run this program from the command
line, we didn't pass any arguments in.
And so if you don't pass any arguments into the program, then the array here will have a length of
zero.
There won't be anything in that array.
And so then when you tell it to give me the fourth element in this array, which has zero elements in
it, you are out of bounds, right?
You, you are going to be you are exceeding the number of elements that exists within this array.
That makes sense, right?
We didn't pass anything in there.
So if we want to run this program from within the ADC where we're not passing any arguments in, we
could comment this one line out.
For now, that's probably the quickest, easiest thing to do.
Or we could get fancier with some things that I haven't taught you yet, where we could say if the length
is zero, then don't execute this line, you know, we could do something like that.
For now, we're just going to comment that line out.
This line is OK, because it's just going to tell us that there's a length of zero, which is fine.
So if we run this again now, it won't blow up.
OK, so first thing we got is zero, which is this bit here, then we got a five, which is this bit
here on line seven.
And then we printed out the second number in the NUM's array, which is 20.
So that's working as expected.
OK, I think that's going to wrap it up for this lesson.
We will revisit arrays.
There's a lot that we can do with them.
But like I said, I wanted to just give a little bit of an introduction into arrays because we're going
to see them more in the future before we go deep into them.
And I didn't want you to have to learn about the arrays plus the other concepts, all at the same time.
So this is going to wrap it up for now, and I will see you in the next one.