All right.
Next up, we're going to learn about two methods that are kind of similar to each other and easily confused.
One is called is empty and the other is is blank.
So let's go back to the A.D. and take a look at these two.
And just as we've done before, we're going to first just clear out what we had before.
All right.
And I don't know, I'll create another string here.
My text.
And so here.
We'll start off with what is commonly referred to as an empty string.
So that's two quotes with no space in between.
And then on the next line, I'll do another you.
And we will reference that variable.
And then we will make use of one of our new methods that we're going to learn.
So the first one will try out as the is empty method.
So let's see what we get here.
Now, this method will return what is called a Boolean, which again, a Boolean is a data type that
conveys true or false yes or no on or off.
OK, so let's run this.
And we get true.
OK.
So is empty simply tells us if the length of the string is zero.
And in this case, this string has no characters, so its length is indeed zero.
All right.
So let's try the.
Well, let's try a few things here, so let's see what we get if we put one space in there and we'll
run it again.
OK, so now we get a false.
So string cannot be empty if it has one or more characters and interestingly, a space is actually a
character, OK?
And the reason for that is because I was talking in one of the previous lessons about Unicode and the
way that every character that can be conveyed on the screen has a code associated with it.
Well, even a space character has a code associated with it.
And so even though it shows up as a as a blank space, it is still a character and therefore the string
is not empty.
All right, so now let's try our other method, which is is blank and notice the way that I'm going
to change this method here is I'm just going to double click there and then I'll just start.
Typing is blank.
And then I can just hit enter and it fills in the rest for me.
All right.
So now we'll see.
Does Java think or does the string think that this space here is blank?
So I will run this again.
Yes, it does think it's blank.
So the definition of whether or not a string is blank is that it determines whether or not there is
any what's called white space.
If there's any white space meaning no visible characters that we can see, then it is.
The string is considered to be blank.
A space character is is white space, as they call it.
And therefore, yes, it is blank.
Let's let's see what happens if we have no space.
Yes, so no space in a string is also considered to be a blank string.
And then let's put one letter in there and try that.
All right, so, yeah, so if you've got a letter in there or something that you can kind of see rather
than white space, then it is no longer considered blank.
So let me just talk to you a little bit about why you would ever want to use any methods like these.
So a couple of examples would be again, where you're writing a program that accepts user input like
you might prompt the user to enter their name and you want to make sure that they actually entered something
before you proceed with processing whatever they entered.
So let's say, for example, that you ask them to enter their name and then you want to have some code
that is going to capitalize the first letter of their name.
However, you wouldn't want to do that if they didn't actually enter anything.
And in fact, you would get an error in the code if you'd proceeded to try to capitalize nothingness,
essentially.
And so you might want to have a little bit of code that safeguards to make sure that before you do further
processing on whatever words they entered that they did actually enter something so you might want to
use.
Typically the is blank method.
I would probably prefer to use the is blank method rather than the is empty method, because is blank
will be true if it's empty or just has a lot of whitespace.
Whereas the is empty method is only true if they literally typed nothing.
But if they hit space of a bunch of times and then hit enter, you wouldn't want that input either.
But the is empty method would not tell you that distinction in the way that you want to know it.
So in most cases, you may prefer to simply use the is blank method, and that's going to do it for
this lesson.
See, in the next one.