OK, so there's another way to do this same type of conditional logic that we're looking at here with
the if else clause.
And to explain that.
Let me show you a little bit more of what we could do first with the if else.
And then I'll show you the alternative.
So let's say that we what I want to do, first of all, is to simplify this a bit.
So let's just say we had something like.
This randomness equals three, and I don't know, maybe it will do one more random number equals four.
We'll do another.
The color is purple.
And then finally, we'll have a kind of like a default, right?
So like, if it wasn't any of these, then do whatever the default is, right?
So that's with our final else block here.
Otherwise, the color is whatever.
OK, so this last little else else block here is our catchall.
If it wasn't one to three or four anything else, just do this right.
That's what we're saying.
OK, so this is a pretty common construct where you kind of have like almost like a list of things kind
of in order, not that they have to be in order they do not have to be.
Now let me show you an alternative way to do this same thing.
So I'm going to comment this out and remember again to comment one or more lines.
You can just select those lines and then do a command forward slash or control forward slash on Windows
and Linux.
All right.
So I've come into that out.
So now I want to show you an alternative way.
So there's another approach using what is called a switch statement and to to use this, what you do
is you simply type switch and then the parentheses and then your variable again.
However, whereas with the if statement, you have to give it some logic like here we're saying random
equals one.
So we're saying if the random number equals one, then do blah blah blah.
Here with the Switch statement, there's no logic here to test for something.
Instead, we're saying, I want you to switch based on the value of the random number.
So let me finish this statement, and then you'll maybe it'll become clear what I mean.
So very similar to the f block switch parentheses, random num and then an opening curly brace here
because we're going to set up a block.
But now inside of this block, what we can do is something like this case one colon and then I can optionally
hit enter.
And then I can use system that out.
The color is red.
And then since that's the only thing I want to do in this particular case, you get it.
In this particular case, then when I'm done with this, what I want it to do there, I have to type
break to finish up this case, and then I can go into another case, such as Case two colon.
Now notice when I hit that colon, the ID automatically unintended, I guess the case structure here
to line these up so that you can kind of see hierarchically case one.
Does this case to does something else, right?
Then I'll hit enter do another print line there.
The color is blue.
Go to the next line.
Put a break their case.
Three Colon enter.
The color is what what was the color green break?
Let's go to the next case.
Case for purple, the color is purple.
And then finally, I can have a catchall or or default scenario as well.
And for that?
Well, actually, let me finish putting the brake there.
And then for my default scenario, I can literally just type the word default colon.
And then whatever the default scenario is, in this case, the color is whatever, just like that.
Now, functionally, this is equivalent to my if clause here.
So it does the same thing.
So let's look at this now just to make sure it's clear.
What we're essentially saying is I want you to switch depending on the value in this variable.
And the testing part where we test for it, if it's blah blah blah, or if it's whatever the testing
comes with these cases, right?
So what we're essentially saying is if random numb equals one, then do this.
If random numb equals two, then do this and so on and so forth.
Otherwise, if it doesn't equal any of these things, then do this default thing here.
Oh, and you can optionally include a break for the default as well, but it is optional.
You don't have to have it.
Now let me explain why we need this break.
Unlike the if else block with a switch statement, let's say that random NUM does equal one.
And so the thread comes down here and executes this line.
Well, if we don't have this break here, the thread will keep moving through these case statements
until it is told to break.
So we'll see that in just a moment.
Let's first just go ahead and run this and see it, see it.
Work with its normal behavior here.
OK.
So the generated number was four and we got the color purple.
So that is correct.
Let's run it a few times.
We got a five.
And so it printed whatever which is correct because five is a catchall or a default, right?
We don't have an explicit case for five.
And so that falls to the default.
So that is correct.
Let's do it again.
Four again for purple.
Wow.
Did I hard code this?
No, I don't think I did.
There we go, wow, that was pretty weird, wasn't it?
That was a lot of fours in a row.
Now we got it too.
Yes, that is correct for blue.
Another four.
Wow.
Really likes for three.
Four Green.
OK, so you get the point two for blue.
All right.
Now let's see what happens if we don't have the breaks in here.
I'm just going to comment them all out.
All right, now, let's see.
Mhm.
Look at that, so see, now it's printing multiple things, so it generated one.
And so it just ran through all of the cases red, blue, green, purple, whatever in order, right?
Let's run it again.
This time we got a three sort of printed green, then purple, then whatever.
So it's falling through, right?
It comes to whatever case the number matched on which in this case was three, right?
It does what it was supposed to do here.
But then it falls through to the other cases, including the default.
If you don't have this brake statement here.
Right?
Let's do a couple more.
There's a two blue, green, purple, whatever.
So you I think you get the point, right?
So what this brake statement does is it tells the thread to jump out of this switch block to the next
line, right, which in this case would be outside here.
OK, and there is no next line.
So then the program just ends.
In this particular case, OK?
But otherwise, the thread would just keep executing each of the subsequent cases.
Some things to look out for, though it's really easy to forget to put this brake here.
Very easy to do, but hopefully it'll also be pretty easy to realize you forgot it when you run your
program and you're getting multiple other cases executing at the same time.
So be really careful about putting that brake statement on each case.
OK, let's see.
So a few other things now.
So far, I've only been showing the if then and now the switch statements, which are testing values
of a number.
But both the false and the switch statements can actually test, if you will, on more than just numbers.
So let me clear this out and show you a quick a couple of quick examples.
So let's say that we have a string called command, and let's set it to go for right now.
And then let's have a switch a switch statement that switches on the word command so we could have a
case where if command is stop, then we do something right.
And by the way, obviously we could do more than just do these print lines.
I'm just using these because they're convenient for us to see something, but we could add some numbers
or call some other method or whatever we wanted to do here.
So let's just say we're going to say something like stopping now.
And then we'll break, and we could have another case for GO.
Going now, and we'll break.
And then let's have a default scenario, also command not understood.
OK, so imagine if we were taking some command line input on this program and that input was getting
stored here in this command and then it did something right.
So let's run this, OK?
So we had to go.
So it called going now and then.
If we had the word stop in here stopping now, so you get the point.
And just as we've done this with a switch statement, we could have done this with an if block as well.
I don't know that I'm going to write the whole thing out, but one quick thing now when you're comparing
variables with an if statement, it is often recommended actually to do the comparison in a way that
might seem a little backward to many of us.
And let me show you what I mean.
So what would normally be somewhat intuitive in this case would be to do something like command dot
equals stop what?
So if command equals stop, then.
Stopping now.
Else, if command that equals go.
Going now.
OK, so you get the idea right now, this is fairly intuitive.
All right.
So now let me show you something.
Let's say that for some reason, the user didn't enter anything on this command, so the command somehow
is null, meaning there's nothing set on it.
And we haven't talked a whole lot about null values, but null is what an object can be set to when
it has no value at all.
OK, so it's not pointing at anything yet.
So it's a null OK, and we can we can explicitly set the value of this object to null.
OK, so just think of it as meaning not nothing.
All right.
So let's run this and see what happens.
Mm hmm.
We get an exception, which again, exceptions are errors, essentially, and the exception is cannot
invoke string that equals object because command is null.
So what what's happening here is we're calling a method the equals method on an object.
But you can't call a method on an object that doesn't actually exist.
And in this particular case, command is null.
There's no object here.
If you recall really when we're dealing with objects, not primitives, but actual objects and storing
them in variables, what those variables really pretty much represent is a reference to an object in
memory somewhere.
They basically point to an object in memory, right?
However, in this case, this variable is pointing to nothing like there's there is no address of an
object in memory that this is pointing to.
It's it's nothing.
Right?
And therefore, when we try to call this method, there is no method to call because there is no object
for which that method lives, right?
And so calling equals or any method on an on a null object results in an error or in an in an exception
being thrown.
OK.
And oftentimes in a program like this, you, the programmer, won't necessarily know whether or not
this object is null at the time when the program is running, which is called runtime.
Now, in this case, I know it because I have explicitly said it this way.
But there are many situations where perhaps you're taking input from somewhere else from a database,
or you're asking the user to enter some, some data and maybe somehow they escaped out of it and didn't
enter anything yet or whatever the case may be.
And so you were expecting that there would be a string here in this particular case, but there's really
nothing at all.
And so you end up with a null and then you try to call some method on a no object and then your whole
program blows up.
OK.
So there's an easy fix for this situation, and what it is is just to flip these things around because
all you're really testing for is, does this equal this?
Well, so you could flip it the other way, and that would still be a valid question, right?
So we could, we could say, does stop equal command?
And now what's good about this scenario is that the equals method will never blow up because of this
being null.
It's not null.
It's right there in front of us, right?
It's a constant.
And so we have some safety here.
So let me flip the other one around as well.
Like so and now let's run it, OK, now nothing prints out because the command is null, so it doesn't
match this one, nor does it match this one either, and I didn't give it a default.
We'll give it a default real quick or else.
Command not understood.
OK, so if we run this again?
There we go.
Command not understood, but the the pertinent thing here is that our program did not blow up this time.
Now with the Switch statement, let me go back to that if I can.
Just I'm just undoing everything until we get back to the version of the code with the Switch statement.
There we go.
All right.
So if we set this Switch statement to null and run this, let's see what happens.
OK, so in this case, because the command was null, the Switch statement is blowing up.
So we don't have that same level of protection against null statements on a switch statement that we
can easily have with the if statement.
So now you're wondering, OK, so when do I use a switch statement versus an if statement?
Well, most people usually consider switch statements to be more readable.
So if you are one of those people, then you may simply prefer to use a switch statement more often.
Also, switch statements execute faster generally than if statements for the same thing, like apple
apples to apples comparison.
Because there are optimizations that the compiler can make when evaluating a switch statement that it
cannot do as well with if statements so switch statements can be faster, however, then there are some
downsides, obviously.
One of them is the fact that you have to put these explicit break statements at the end of each case,
which I don't particularly find to be very elegant myself.
And I think a lot of other developers also don't find that to be super elegant.
It's easy to forget to put that in for sure.
So you've got to be really careful about that.
And then we just saw that you don't have as easy a way to protect against null variables that you may
be switching on.
So you'd have to do an explicit check beforehand to make sure that the variable isn't null.
And you could do that.
Actually, it's not hard to do one way you can do it and would be to simply say something like if command
is not equal to null.
So you could do that, or perhaps you might even want to flip it around and say, if command is null,
then whatever.
So maybe you skip over this if block here now you don't want to make your logic overly complicated.
And when you start nesting, if blocks and else blocks and things like that, you're probably heading
down a road that you really should try to avoid.
But in the interest of just showing some completion here, maybe you do something like else and then
you could put this entire switch inside of an else block like so and so now you're only going to run
this switch if the command is not null.
That's a possibility.
However, I would hope that you could find other ways to avoid having to do something like this.
All right.
So I'm going to wrap this one up and we'll have some more fun with some more of these constructs in
the next lesson, and I will see you there.