OK, so now that you have a little bit better understanding of some of the basics of what your browser
is doing when we're typing in new URLs, let's make something slightly more interesting now using some
Java code.
Now, the first thing I want to do, though, actually is we're going to install a couple of plug ins
for our browser, for Chrome users.
Chrome is really like kind of the industry standard anyway in many, in many respects.
All right.
So the first thing, though, is I'm going to stop using.
So I'm going to stop using Safari now, and I'm going to switch over to Chrome because it has better
general support for a lot of the standard plugins of web application development.
OK.
It's not that you can't do these things with safari, but we might as well get used to doing more of
our web development work in the industry standard browser now, which is which is Chrome.
So I'm going to open up Chrome.
OK, so I've got Chrome here and I've already entered a search criteria here.
So you want to search for install, live reload, plug in as I have here.
And once you've got that, then you can come down here to the second link here chrome dot, google.com,
live reload.
So I'm going to click on that and then I'm going to click this button here.
Add to Chrome, add extension.
All right.
And so it has been added, and there it is, right there.
I'm going to click this little icon here of a jigsaw puzzle.
Like this puzzle piece?
And there's my live reload.
So the first thing I'm going to do is pen this so that it will always show up up here.
So I just click on that little picture there.
All right.
And so there's my live reload.
And so now I can close this tab and I'm going to open up another tab now, and I'm going to just go
right back to my local host Colin ADHD and junk DNA html.
All right, so there's my Hello world again.
So this live reload plugin will be quite handy when we start going kind of back and forth with making
code changes and then wanting to see those changes quickly in the browser.
So the plug in basically will just allow the browser to kind of automatically refresh itself so that
we shouldn't need to manually click the refresh button every time we want to see a change.
All right, so now let's go ahead and make something a little bit more interesting.
Slightly more interesting, at least.
OK, so I'm jumping back over here to the idea now, and we're going to go ahead and create some code,
some explicit code now.
And the first thing I think I will do is to create a new package under this calm neutrino system that
people deep web.
OK, so the first package, I'm going to create someone to do a new package, and I think I'm just going
to call this package web.
Now I'm going to tell you now I don't normally create a web package, but I'm going to do so right now
because I want to be kind of more explicit and obvious for you as to some of the standard layers of
where my code is going.
And I will explain those layers a little bit later, but I want to hurry up and get some code written
here because I know I've talked enough already.
All right.
So there's web and then under here I'm going to make another package, so I'm going to do another new
package and this one will be called controller.
All right.
And I'm going to make a new class.
Java class, and this will be called People Controller New.
All right.
OK.
And so now I'm going to put a bunch of stuff in here.
Let's see, where do we want to start?
I guess I'll start at the top so you can just follow along and I will explain these things that we're
doing a little bit later.
But first thing I'm going to do is put an annotation here.
Let's see, request mapping.
And I'm going to put inside of here some quotes and we'll call this.
People.
Just like that.
Then inside of this class, I will create a method that will return a string.
And for now, I will just call this method, get people like so and I will have this method return a
string called people.
All right.
And then I'm going to annotate this method with an annotation called Get mapping.
Like so.
All right.
And then over here, we're going to create a new file under the Templates folder.
So I'm going to create a new file, and this will also be an HTML file.
And I will call it people died HTML.
And here I will name it, people.
And here, let's just put another hello world style message for right now.
Real quick here.
So we'll say something like, I don't know.
Well, maybe not.
Hello, world, but maybe here are some people.
Maybe something like that, OK?
And that's that's all we're going to do.
First.
Now let me.
Rearrange.
My windows just a little bit here, if I can.
It's going to be a little tough because I don't have a whole lot of.
Room to work with, but yeah, I think that might work, OK.
All right.
So we've got all of that done, some going into the people controller here, and I need one of the one
more really, really important annotation.
It doesn't matter if I put it above or below the request mapping, but I prefer to put it above.
I need an act controller mapping here.
All right.
And again, I will explain what these all do in just a moment.
OK.
And so now I will do another command f nine and we might see there we go.
Yeah, we've got some stuff scrolling by there.
OK, now if we come down here to the browser and refresh.
There we go.
OK, so now we see these words.
Here are some people.
So let me explain very briefly what is the difference between putting an HTML file under static versus
under templates?
The basic gist is if you want to have a HTML that is dynamic and controlled from our Java code, then
you need to put that HTML under templates.
OK, because this will allow us to feed some dynamically generated content into this page and make a
more interesting web page.
Essentially, whereas static web pages that is H.M. pages that we put under the static folder here are
not capable of being fed data from our Java code directly.
I'll put it that way because there are some tricks that we could do with JavaScript, where we could
request data even from the static pages, but I don't know that we'll be getting into any of that in
this section.
OK.
All right.
So that's the first part, though.
So now, though, let's actually put sort of put a little bit of something dynamic in here.
OK.
So what I'm going to do now is let's see here.
So we've got the Web Dot controller package.
So let's make another package under the main combat neutrino service package, and I'm going to call
this one.
Oh, I don't know.
Bill's short for business.
In fact, you know, we can go ahead and just make a couple of packages all at once.
There's that model.
OK, so we're going to make a simple domain model class now.
OK?
And then under bizarre model, make a new class Java class.
And let's call it person.
So we've done this many, many times in this course already.
OK and hit enter.
All right.
And let's see.
So let's have a few fields.
Let's have a string for the first name and a string for the last name and a local day trips.
And a local date for a date of birth and a big decimal for a salary.
And what am I forgetting here?
I know I'm forgetting something, but that's OK.
I will remember it later.
OK, that's enough.
Now, normally at this point since we're working with a class and not a record, I'd let the A.D. generate
my getters and setters and all that good stuff, right?
That's what I would normally do.
However, now that we're using the spring framework with spring boot and we got all this cool added
functionality here, we can do something a little more interesting.
We're going to use a special annotation from a library called Lombok, and the annotation we will use
is called at data.
And so what this annotation will do is that it will allow the Lombok Library to scan this class, find
these fields and generate getters and setters and a constructor and an equals and a hash code and a
two string method, all for us whenever we need it.
OK, so we're getting all of that for free now, and all we had to do is just specify the fields that
we want.
OK.
So it's a super, super convenient.
And so I think for right now, we're going to be done with this class.
Oh, I know.
One thing I was forgetting is the idea.
Yeah, let's let's throw.
Let's throw the idea in here.
Type long and we'll make it an idea.
OK, cool.
All right.
So now let's jump over here to the controller class.
And what we want to do is we're going to first just make a few dummy people right here inside of this
get people method.
And we're going to have those dummy people kind of show up in the browser very simplistically for right
now.
But believe me, by the time we get to the end of this section, it's going to be doing all kinds of
stuff.
All right.
So let's see here.
So let's just create a, I don't know, maybe a list of.
Some people said we'll do like a new person.
And I will import that class and do a command P. And I'm not getting any parameters because I forget
this every single time.
So I need to jump back over here to the person class and we need to throw in at least one more annotation
on here.
So we'll throw a note is that all our constructor on here?
Let's see if that's enough.
There we go.
Yes, that's what we needed the all our contract.
Let me just tell you what that did.
Let me explain that really quickly.
So the data annotation did give us a constructor, but it gave us a no arg default constructor.
But if we want an additional constructor that allows us to specify all of the arguments, then we need
to also add in the All ARGs constructor, which is what I just did there.
OK.
So now I can start specifying these parameters.
So I'm just going to, I don't know, do like a 10 10 L comma.
And it's really fun to read and and and this is one of those things.
And you know, if you need to believe in the much of.
And yeah, that's fine, I'll call them people.
Now, if I want to get this data into the browser here, I will need to pass it into something called
a model.
And I'm not going to explain super deeply right this minute.
What that is, but I need to have a model and then I will pass this data into that model.
And in that model will in turn get passed to the two, not to the browser, but to the the code that
I'm not having to write that that renders out the the final template.
OK, the final version of the template.
OK.
So to get my hands on this model, think of the model as a bucket.
It's just a bucket into which I can put pretty much whatever I want.
OK.
So I am going to get myself a model here.
And I will call it model.
Now, the spring in the sea framework is will see that I have done these annotations, by the way,
these annotations are all part of the spring MVC framework.
OK.
In this model class, here is also part of the spring MVC framework.
Spring will see that.
I have said that I want this method to get called with a model, and the spring MVC framework will actually
create this model and then pass it to me, to my code rather.
All right.
So then what I can do is I can call model that add attribute, and then I can name this list something
like people that would make a lot of sense and then I can bind it to this variable.
So what I'm saying is essentially take my list of people and bind it to a holding tank inside of this
model thing called people.
Really, you can think of the model as a as a map.
OK?
We learned about maps or hash maps, things like that, right?
You have key value pairs.
So the key is this word, people.
And then the value is this list of people.
OK.
So it's just it's really essentially kind of a map.
All right.
So now I can jump back over to this people that HTML file here, and I'm going to keep this relatively
simple for right now, but we will make it much more complex and it'll look great eventually, but not
right now.
So what I will do now is I will use a special HTML.
I will use one of the many HTML tags to show a list of things.
And the tag that I will use here is, I don't know, ordered list.
OK, and then I will have a list item, so that would be like one item in the list.
My junk person.
OK.
So this will serve as kind of a template for what I kind of would like to have displayed and I will
go ahead and now restart the application.
OK, now what I would like to have happen in general is that whenever I restart the application and
make changes of this sort, that this content down here would update, and now I should be able to come
over here to this live reload and enable it.
All right.
So.
Hopefully after I reload this, OK, so there's my one person now this is just hardcoded, right?
But now we're going to make it dynamic, so I'm going to update this now.
Oh, now in order to do this, we're going to have to update a few other things here.
So there is a templating language that is kind of an add on, if you will, for this HTML that we're
doing here, OK?
And one of the things that we added when we were on the start that spring, that issue site, we had
to add a bunch of dependencies.
One of the dependencies we chose was something called thyme leaf.
So Thyme Leaf is a templating library that allows us to template Ty's HTML, and it comes with a lot
of special tags and attributes of HTML that we can utilize to generate more dynamic content within a
browser.
And I bet a lot of what I just said might not mean very much to you yet, but you'll start to see it.
So we're going to allow this web page to make use of the time leaf tags and attributes, OK?
So to do that, I'm first going to open up another tab and I will simply type in here thyme leaf and
dot org.
And by the way, that's to YMC Leaf Thyme Leaf.
OK, so we're on the timewith website here.
And let me break this tab out and make it bigger.
For right now.
OK.
All right, and we will go to Knox for documentation and then we will come down here to timely 3.0.
That's what that's the most current version as of the time of this recording.
But the main thing is that we're just looking for the documentation.
So read online.
All right.
And then over here, I'm going to click on the template engine.
And that just gets me helps me to zoom in on what I'm really looking for, which is basically just some
starting configuration stuff that I need.
OK, so right here in the HTML that you see, we've got what's called an attribute here, and I'm going
to copy all of that.
So this XM, L.A., all of that up to and including the closing quotation mark there some copying that
then I will jump back into the browser and I will go to this browser's HTML tag and I will put my cursor.
No doesn't really matter if I put the cursor after the language study language in or before it.
But somewhere inside of this HTML tag, I will paste that XM, L and S.
So basically, what we're doing here is you can think of it as the HTML equivalent of an import statement.
OK.
What we're basically saying is we want to import a bunch of custom tags that come from the Time Leaf
Library, and whenever we use those tags, we will refer to them throughout our document by starting
with this prefix of of t h.
OK.
So we're importing those special custom tags under the t h namespace, if you will.
But you can think of this whole thing here as kind of like the HTML equivalent of doing an import statement.
OK.
Something very similar to that.
And I think that's all we will need from timely for right now, other than periodically checking in
on some of the references and things.
OK, so now what we want to do is we know that we've got this list of people inside of a model variable
called people OK.
And we want to basically just display each of those people as a list item here.
OK.
So let me just open back up the people page now.
So I want that people page in the browser at the same time so that we can see things that are changing
in real time, OK?
So the way we will do this is we will implement the time leave slash HTML equivalent of a for loop.
OK.
So just as we could have an enhanced for loop that would loop over the items in a list, we can do the
HTML equivalent of that right here.
And the way we will do that is by putting our cursor inside of this list item tag here.
Space to colon each equals.
And then very similarly to the enhanced for Loop, we will specify a variable name for each instance
or for each item in the collection.
So here we can refer to something like person.
And then a colon.
So it does look a fair bit like the enhanced for loop from Java.
And then we will specify the name of the collection that we want to iterate over.
Now the way we do this, though, is a little bit special.
We will use a dollar sign and then an opening and closing curly brace.
And then inside of here we will specify the name of the variable that contains our collection or our
list of people that we bound to the model.
OK, so all that is is people.
Now this this people here.
Is coming from.
Right here.
OK.
Or are actually right here.
All right, so this modeled that ad attribute people.
This is referring this is the name that we used to refer to this collection of people.
OK.
That's where that's coming from.
And so that's what we're doing here.
And so now what we can do is we can use another timely attribute to call and text equals dollar sign.
Curly brace person.
So now what this is going to do is first off this T-H each is going to extract one person at a time
from this people collection and stored in a variable called person.
Then we are going to use this to call and text attribute to basically display this whatever that person
was.
So this is in effect going to call the two string method of the person class.
OK, now what this call and text attribute actually does, though, is it takes whatever text we are
referring to here, and it replaces this with whatever is here.
So if this is going to call the two string method of each instance of a person, then the output of
that two string method is what's going to display here.
And I'm so sorry, I know I'm seeing a lot of words.
I hope you're following me, but let's go ahead and just run it.
And maybe it will be even more obvious.
I think you can intuitively kind of see where I'm going with this.
OK, so to get this to run now, all I should need to do is a command f nine to restart my server.
And look at that.
We updated down here instantaneously, so you can see that this is a typical two string method output
of that of the person class, right?
That's what we just got there.
Now this isn't where we're going to leave it.
I just wanted to do something relatively simple just to get started here, OK?
We will eventually make this look really, really nice.
All right.
And so let's go ahead and stop with this lesson.
And in the next lesson, we'll do a little bit more and we'll go a little further.
OK, so I'll see you in the next one.