All right, so before we jump back in to looking at more of the functions that are available to us with
both sequel and H2, I want to show you a couple other little quick tidbits here.
One of them is the fact that we can actually move these columns around in different order.
So if you, for example, would prefer to have the last name be first.
That's easy enough to do by simply just reordering how they show up in the select list here.
So I'm just.
Swapping those out.
OK, and there you go.
So now you've got the last name and then.
And in the cast there, another thing that you can do now jumping back into some of these functions.
Here we're currently just taking the average of the salary, but let's say that we just want to count
the number of people in each group by last name, which would effectively count the number of people
in the family, right?
So we could do instead of a cast we can call count.
And this is one of the most used functions.
And I I don't know technically, I guess this would be a more of a school function.
This is one of the most used functions you'll ever use in in, in in school.
So typically, the way you'll see this done most often is with the asterisks, meaning we don't even
really care which which column.
So go ahead and just count them all.
So if we do this and run it, there we go.
Now we see that the Johnson family has four members and the Smith family has one.
OK.
Now you can put just about anything in there.
So I could just refer to one of the fields, such as the last name field, which we're already querying
for anyway.
That works just as well.
OK, so then let me show you this now I'm going to take the grouping off now.
And let's see here, let's just do.
Last name, first name, date of birth.
OK, so there are those fields.
OK, so here I've got the H2 website up here and we can look at the various functions that are available
to us if I just click on functions here.
So we've got numeric functions, string functions, time and date functions, and those are about all
that I care to kind of look at at this time.
So a lot of these numeric functions are some of the same types of functions that you would see in Java
under the math class.
OK.
And then the string functions.
Many of these would be the functions that you'd find under the string class.
I wouldn't be surprised.
In fact, since H2 has written in Java, if some of these functions really just delegate down to the
underlying Java string function itself or method themselves.
And then again, some various time and date functions as well.
So we'll play with a few of these, but they're pretty easy to understand.
And if you ever have any interest in using one of these and this is specifically for H2, but other
databases have very similar lists of functions and things.
If there's ever one that you're not sure how to use, you can always just click on it and then see a
little more information, like the syntax of how to use it, for example.
All right, so let's take a look at a few of these like we've got an upper and a lower.
So those are just like the Java versions of two upper to lower.
So if we wanted to uppercase the last names, for example, the way we would do that is just to call
the upper method here, and it looks quite similar to what you would do in Java.
All right.
So by doing that and let's run it, here we go.
So now the last names are all uppercase, like so.
Let's say that we wanted to have one field that we think of as just name, so it's not a last name or
first name, it's just name, right?
And it would be comprised, though, of the last name and the first name, maybe even separated by a
comma.
Perhaps so we can do that.
The way to do that would be there is a cat method can cat and then we can refer to the last name field.
Karma.
And then we can throw a comma in here just like this with another comma.
And then first name.
Like so, so I know that's a little confusing to look at, but we've got the last name and then a comma
and then the first name, so let's run that and see.
All right.
So now you've got Johnson, Harry, I probably should actually put a space after that comma.
Let's run that again.
There we go.
A little more readable now.
We might not like the output field name here.
That's not very friendly.
It would be nicer if it were just called something like name.
So if we put as and then the name of a new field, which is called a column alias, then we can change
the name of the field for the output.
Now we're not really changing the underlying table name, fill filled name or anything like that.
This is just for output purposes.
There you go.
So now you've got a name for this, and that makes a lot of sense, right?
And we can even embed other function calls within our function call.
So if I wanted to make the last name all uppercase, I can upper the last name inside of the contact
call and I could come over here to the first name and maybe lower that.
I don't know why I would want to do that, but let's see what that looks like.
There you go.
So now you've got all uppercase for the last name and all lowercase for the first name, right?
So you can do all kinds of things like that.
Let's see.
We've got the date of birth here.
What if we wanted to warp time for these dates of birth?
We can actually do that as well.
There is a date add method, and let's take a look at that date.
Add.
So we first have to specify what field of time we're trying to warp here.
So in other words, like, are we trying to add weeks, days, months, years, etc., right?
So let's do years.
So to do that, we have to specify the keyword year.
Then how many years we want.
So let's just add 10 years and then the field itself.
So date of birth.
All right.
And then I will close this off.
OK, like that.
And so let's run that and see what we get.
All right, so whereas originally, Harry Johnson was born in 1950.
Now it looks like he was born in 1960.
OK, so it just added 10 years to everybody's date of birth.
And again, if we don't like this, header the new column name here, we could change that as New Dobby.
Here we go.
New Dubai.
And there's even support for regular expressions in here, believe it or not.
So to do that, here's what I'll do.
I'll show you on a fresh little bit here.
You can actually execute queries that aren't even executing against any particular table.
So, for example, if I just wanted to print out a date 1970, and this is just really a strong representation
of the date 1970 10 31, like so I can just execute that.
OK, so there I get that date all by itself.
This is kind of like the equivalent of Hello World, right?
Just printing out, doing a system out that print line and then just say here, print something as as
output, though, so you can always do that.
But now, having done that, let me show you that we can do a regular expression.
So let me bring bring this back in.
So looking at the string functions here, we've got regular expression methods like, yeah, this one
here replace.
So if I click on that, we can see the syntax for it.
So the input string and then a regular expression and then what you want to replace it with.
So what that saying is for your given input string, use the regular expression to find text that matches
inside of the input string and for whatever text it finds that matches replace that matching text with
this replacement text here.
All right.
So let's see how that would, how that might look.
So let's say that we want to find four digits, followed by a hyphen.
OK.
So first off, we will invoke the Regg Exp underscore replace function here and in the first argument
that it takes is the input tax, which is going to be that in this particular case and then a regular
expression.
So if I want to replace the four digits there, I can do.
Ash.
And then I can say something like four digits, followed by a hyphen.
And then what I want to replace them with, so I don't know, let's say first off, we'll just replace
them with AAA.
Like, so let's let's try that out and see what we get.
OK, so we got a 10 Python 31 now.
Probably I should have put oops, put a hyphen in there.
Here we go.
All right.
Or let's see what it looks like with just two A's.
So you get the idea, right?
Pretty easy to do to use regular expressions.
And again, because H2 is written in Java, most likely it's using the standard Java regular expression
engine.
And the reason that's noteworthy is because many languages have their own slightly different variation
of the regular expression language.
Some are based on Perl.
Some have some tweaks, though.
And so it's nice to just know that in all likelihood, the H2 implementation of rejects is actually
using the Java implementation of rejects.
All right.
And so that's going to wrap up our small look into some of the functions, like I said before, though.
You can always go into the documentation for whatever database you happen to be using, not just H2.
And in fact, in business and professional programming, you'll almost certainly not be using H2.
By the way, the most popular database engines in business are by far going to be either Oracle or Microsoft
SQL Server.
Those two are by far the most popular ones.
Another one is DB2 from IBM.
Now those are all commercial databases that are used at the enterprise level.
And by the way, you'll hear the term enterprise all the time as a professional business developer in
particular.
And that just means large corporation wasting a lot of money, typically.
But then there are also free or open source databases that are quite popular.
Each two is actually an open source database, for example, though I do not know that H2 is ever used
for mission critical enterprise level development, I seriously doubt it.
I do use it in enterprise for writing tests, though, because it can run in-memory really, really
quickly, but never for production deployment, where there could be potentially hundreds, thousands
or hundreds of thousands of customers actually needing to do things.
I don't even think the makers of this database themselves would recommend using it for that, but some
other open source databases that could actually be used in that way and are actually used in that way
are MySQL.
Or some people might pronounce it as my school.
That's M.y School or PostgreSQL, PostgreSQL.
These are a couple really, really popular open source database engines that are very robust and heavily
used to support massive amounts of data.
They support sophisticated features like clustering and all kinds of things.
All right, so in the next lesson, we'll try to wrap up our little tour of the basics of sequel.