All right, so in the last lesson, we learned that enemies are special forms of classes, and as such,
they can have methods on them.
And armed with that knowledge, we were able to take the original get value method that we had on the
card class and actually just relocated essentially to our rank enum class.
OK.
And we just had to do a very minor refactoring there to make it work.
But it all works right.
If enemies are special forms of classes on which methods can work.
What else do you think we can do with any new?
Well, enemies can also have fields or properties.
So with that information, I want to show you something else that's kind of neat that we can do with
an enum.
So as you see here, I am showing that when we define these constants of an enum, you can kind of think
of it in your head as being somewhat equivalent to these lines here, where you're creating individual
instances of that enum type.
Kind of like this.
OK, now if you think of it in this way, that will help you when I show you the next thing that you
can do.
So as I just said a moment ago, we can also include fields or variables, properties, instance variables
as they're also called on enemies.
So watch what happens if I create a new line here and I define a field, some make it private, and
let's say I create a field that is an integer and oh, I don't know what if I call it value?
Anybody know where I'm going with this?
I can actually use this field in many of the ways that I could use a field on any other class.
So I could, for example, replace this code here and just say something like return value.
OK, so no errors right now.
As you may imagine, if I were to go rerun all of the tests, they should fail like right now.
And in fact, you know what?
I will go ahead and rerun the tests just to prove that.
OK.
So we just re ran all of the tests on the card class, and every single one of them is failing, which
is exactly what should happen.
And the reason they're failing is because we're now returning this integer value called value, which
hasn't been set to anything at all.
Right.
So right now, this code isn't very useful, but we can make it quite useful.
And let me show you how.
So now that we have this field here, we can actually define a new constructor for this enum.
So again, take a look at these vake lines of code that I've got here, where I'm telling you that each
time we define a constant for an enum, it is fairly equivalent to having a line of code like this where
we have can automatically generated constructor that is sort of automatically setting the text of the
constant on a property that we can't see here.
But but it exists called name.
OK.
That's what this is doing.
However, we can actually define our own.
We can kind of like you can almost think of it as override.
We can kind of override this default constructor, if you will.
Let me show you what that looks like.
So we can create a new constructor.
And in fact, I can even do a command in and just tell it to generate a constructor.
OK, now look at that.
As soon as I did that, the ID said, Do you want to use this new value field as an input for the constructor?
So that intelligence was smart enough to know that if I'm trying to make my own constructor on an enum
and that enum already has a field variable defined on it, there's a good chance.
I'm probably wanting to use that variable as an input for my constructor.
So yes, we do want to do that.
So I'm going to click OK here and now look what it just did.
It generated this new constructor, which again, is almost basically just the method that returns a
new instance of an object, right?
It takes as input an integer called value, and then it sets that value on this internal field called
value, OK?
However, as soon as this constructor got created.
Now all of these constants, these enum constants are in error.
Why do you think that would be?
Well, again, if you look down here at what I said is kind of like the default way of thinking about
defining each of these constants.
What you see is that you can think of it as though there was a default constructor that was taking just
one input, which is the constant name itself.
But now I've created a new constructor that takes an integer.
OK.
And so what's happening is if each of these definitions is equivalent to this, well, then this pattern
doesn't match this constructor here.
This constructor is expecting an integer, and there is no integer to be found anywhere in any of these
definitions.
OK.
And so what we need to do to get these out of error is we now need to pass in this new value, as we
would with any constructor.
So let me show you what that's going to look like.
So all we need to do is use parentheses just like you would with a constructor.
And then we can pass in an integer now.
So what if I want an ace to simply be equivalent to a one?
I can just do that.
To.
Three, four, five, six, eight, nine and 10, 10 and 10.
All right.
So now I'm explicitly setting whatever value I want to associate with these constants, so I no longer
need to rely on the ordinal property and method that is inherited by all enemies.
And instead, I can just take control and say, I want this instance to be associated with this value.
One.
OK.
And so on and so forth.
And the nice thing is that down here, I can explicitly set all of these face cards to 10 or whatever
value I might want to.
And by doing so, my get value method now can simply return whatever.
I set that to this this value here.
OK, now my enum can have additional properties.
If I wanted it to, I could have arbitrary, fake, ridiculous properties like, you know, private
string favorite song, right?
I could just have ridiculous things here, and I could add that to the constructor here if I wanted
to.
Now, as soon as I would do that, these would be an error again until I specified a string as a second
parameter in these basically constructors.
Right?
That's pretty much what these are.
So now having done this, we should be able to rerun these tests and they should go back to working
again.
Let's see.
Look at that.
Back to working again.
So now, you know, a couple of ways that you can associate some data with Constance on an enum.
If the data is numeric and and makes sense to be in some kind of order and you put your enemies in order.
You may be able to rely on the ordinal method, but if you want arbitrary values or just values of whatever
you want and they don't even have to be numeric, they could be anything really.
Then you could always just define a field on the enum itself and then define that field as an input
on a custom constructor for the enum and then make the associations that way as well.
OK, now knowing this, let's go take a look at this suit because there's something kind of interesting
that I think we might be able to do with this.
So let's say that when we create an instance of a card, we may want to override the card classes to
string method.
And if you recall, the two string method is a method that all classes and enemies to inherit from the
object superclass, and it enables any instance of a class to be represented as text as a string, right?
So we can do.
We can pass any object to the system that out that print line method and it will print out it'll print
something, right?
So what if we wanted the suit enum to be able to display the actual symbols for these words, right?
Clubs, diamonds, spades.
It is my understanding, and I promise you, as I'm saying this and recording it, I haven't actually
tried this out.
I'm kind of going out on a limb here.
So hopefully I don't have to delete this part of the video that I'm making right now.
But what I'm thinking of doing here is let's let's associate the text symbol for each of these words
so that when we want to print one of them, we actually get that symbol printed out.
OK.
So here's what I'm thinking will do.
Well, first off, do you want to try taking a stab at this?
So what I have in mind is obviously we'll have a field that will be a string or a character.
You might choose to do a character and we will associate that field with each of these constants.
And then the key here is that I'm thinking we'll use Google and search for Unicode characters that represent
these words because I think those characters are in the Unicode Standard.
And if you don't remember what Unicode is, Unicode is the world standard for associating a number,
a really big number with letters and characters of most of the writing symbols of most of the world.
OK.
So remember, a capital A is a 65, for example.
All right.
So if you want to try that on your own, you can pause this video and go try that and meet back up with
me.
Otherwise I'm going to move on and see if I can work it out, too.
All right.
So first thing I'm going to do is to define a new field.
And I don't know.
Let's try making it a character.
I think we should be able to do that.
All right.
Private care.
And I'm going to call it symbol.
All right.
And then let's make a new constructor that will use that.
And there we go.
And then we just need to fix these.
All right.
So here now we need to do a little googling.
So let me open up a browser window.
Let me open up a tab and I'm going to Google Unicode Spades.
Look at that.
Google already knows what I'm looking for.
There we go.
Playing cards in Unicode and looks like we've got the Unicode symbols.
Are the Unicode for those particular symbols right there?
Perfect.
All right.
Now to use these.
So what was my first thing here?
Clubs?
OK, so clubs is right.
Here it is.
Unicode Symbol two six six seven.
Now I want to show you something else.
I don't want you to think that I just memorize every single aspect of Java and everything we do as a
professional programmer.
You can't possibly memorize every single trick in technique because there are lots of techniques that
you just don't use that frequently.
And one technique that I never use, in fact, I don't know that I've ever done this before is to look
up a Unicode symbol and then specify that in a character in Java.
I don't think I've ever done that before.
And so I may have to look that up myself, and I'm not going to edit the video and cut myself doing
that because I don't want you to think like, I just remember every single thing.
I remember a lot.
I absolutely do remember a lot, but I don't remember everything, and I especially don't remember everything.
Four four techniques that I don't even use or may never have use, such as what I'm about to do here.
So what I do know is that I'm going to need parentheses and I'm going to need single ticks.
And by the way, I don't know if I pointed this out, but be careful when you're using these single
ticks if you haven't already discovered this issue.
The single tick character is the same character that's on the same key with the regular quotation marks,
right?
And the reason I call this out is because there's another key on the keyboard, especially on United
States or North American Kurdy keyboards that's on the same key with the tilde symbol.
OK.
That's a back tick.
You don't want that.
All right.
So to specify a Unicode symbol, let me see if I can wingless now.
I think it might be backslash you.
And then the numbers, two, six, six, three, two, six, six three.
Hey, I might be on to something here.
I'm going to go with this for for a minute and see, maybe I didn't need to look this up, OK?
I really do know almost everything.
We'll see.
I'm not going to get too cocky until I actually run this and see what happens.
All right.
And then Diamonds is two six six six.
All right, so single.
Take backslash you two six six six.
All right.
And then Hearts is two six six five backslash you two six six five and then Spades is two six six zero.
Backslash you two six six zero.
All right.
Well, we're going to find out shortly if this actually works.
So what I am thinking of doing next is to override the two string method of the Enum.
We can do that because again, in rooms are really just special classes, right?
So I will put my cursor at the bottom of this constructor here and I will create a new line.
Be careful that you didn't put your cursor inside of the constructor method that would not be the place
to go.
All right.
And so I can generate an override.
I can override an existing method with a control o and bam.
It already knew.
Hey, there's only one method for you to override.
You must want to override the two string method.
Yes, I do.
All right, so I will click OK, all right.
And now my implementation of the two string method will simply return the symbol.
However, I cannot directly say return this symbol.
And the reason I cannot do that is because symbol is a character and two string returns a string.
That's why it's called two string, right?
So I need to convert this character into a string, right?
There are quite a number of ways I could do that, but one way that's coming to mind right now, and
honestly, I don't know that this is the best or the worst way, but it's a way that I'm thinking of
right now.
So the character primitive also has a wrapper class version, which is character.
And if you recall, when we're wanting to convert numbers to strings, we're able to use the wrapper
class versions of the numbers and then we have a pass method on those numeric wrapper classes to convert
them into a string.
Let's see if the character class has something equivalent in BAM.
Look at that as soon as I type it in.
The very first thing that comes up is probably exactly what I want to string.
There we go.
So I will just surround my character with the two string method there, and it looks like we're good
to go there.
All right.
So now to test this out, I'm going to create another test.
I'm going to create a test class for the suit.
So I will do a command shift T and then I will hit Enter four, create new test and I will accept all
the defaults and then I will do a shift.
Enter maybe a couple of times and I will create a new test with a command in and choose test method.
And I will make a method and I will call it I don't know heart.
Print.
Heart, all right now, really, I don't really even need a test here.
What I really want to see this actually print out on the screen, but you know what I'll make.
I'll make a failing test first.
Okay, just to see.
So here's what I will do.
I will say assert equals and I will pass in a string and I will say I'm expecting the word heart.
And then I will create a suit.
And I will reference the heart's constant just like that.
Now this will be an interesting test because I'm making a few assumptions here.
I'm assuming that a certain equals will be kind of forced, if you will, to see that since my expected
is a heart string, a string with the word heart that ultimately it should call the two string method
of suit eckhart's.
Honestly, I'm not 100 percent certain that that's what it's going to do.
Let's try it out and see.
So I'm going to run this.
All right.
So it failed, as I expect, but the real thing here is that because it failed, it should show me the
difference and that's actually what I wanted to see.
So let's all look at that.
Look at that expected was the word heart and actual is a symbol of a heart.
So it looks like that actually works.
That's pretty cool, huh?
All right.
Now to fix this.
What I can do is get rid of that string there and instead reference the actual Unicode.
And the heart was two six six five two six six five.
And notice now that Java is permitting me to define this Unicode character inside of the string, just
as well as it allowed me to define it inside of a character.
OK, so the only difference is here I'm using double ticks or quotes, right?
And then inside of the suit enum, I used single ticks.
OK, but the Unicode part is the same.
All right.
And so now this should pass.
And as a result of passing, though, I will no longer get to actually see the output, which is again
one of the reasons why I started the test off with something that I knew would fail because I wanted
it to show me the difference so that I could get a chance to see the actual heart character there.
So let's run this again, and it should pass.
OK, so it actually did not pass.
And let's see why.
So it's saying it was expecting a string of value with that heart there, but instead it returned a
different object, not a string, but a suit.
So what's happening here is that now that I've switched to an actual object, J Unit is comparing the
entire object representation and not just the string value.
So if I want this comparison to work properly, probably the easiest thing to do here is to explicitly
call the two string method.
Let's try it now.
There we go.
So yeah, and probably for future reference, if what you're really wanting to compare is the string
representation, it never hurts to just explicitly call the two string method.
I knew I was living a little bit on the edge by relying on J Unit to eventually meander its way towards
calling the two string method, and that worked fine for the first version of this.
But as soon as I put this inside of quotes and this became an object, J Unit decided to compare them
differently than just calling to string.
All right.
Not a big deal, but something worth worth keeping in mind.
So let's go ahead and close out on this lesson, and I can think of a couple of other cool things we
will do.
We'll go ahead and integrate a little piece of code to actually print a card on the screen with the
system that out that print line maybe and actually show the symbols.
OK, so whenever we create a card and we print that card, we'll get the cool little symbol and the
value or something like that.
We'll do that in the next video, though, so I'll see you there.