Welcome.
So in this lesson, we're going to download and install an I.D. I.D. stands for integrated development
environment.
And you can basically think of it as a word processor for programming.
The idea we will be using is called intelligence by a company called Jet Brains, and we'll be using
their free version of this idea, which is a very capable ADC.
So without further ado, let's go grab it now.
All right.
So first up, let's go install the latest version of intelligent idea from the company called Jet Brains.
So to do this, I'm going to simply Google in any browser.
I'm using Safari.
But if you're using Chrome, that's fine too.
You just want to go to Google and we're going to search for download intelligence.
And the very first link that I see here says download intelligence idea, so that's what I want.
Now I happen to be on Mac OS at that at the moment.
And so I'm going to make sure that I have macOS selected.
But if you're in Windows or Linux, you can choose accordingly.
And the version of Intel is that I will officially be teaching from is the Community Edition because
it's completely free and super capable.
The Ultimate Edition will only work for you without paying for it for, I think, 30 days and then you'll
have to pay or something like that.
Now, when I started recording this course, Java version 16 was the current version.
But since that time, version 17 has come out and I have now subtly been updating my course in a few
minor places to teach the very, very few updates that are pertinent for us in Java 17.
However, in order to ensure that some of my lessons that I was teaching with Version 16 continue to
work for you.
With version 17, you will need to download a version of the I.D. that has better support for version
17, specifically better support for one of the build tools that a few of my lessons will utilize,
which is called Gradle.
So on this screen here, normally we'd just be clicking on either of these and starting a download.
However, we want to make sure that we're getting a version of the ADC that has completely full support
for version 17.
Specifically around Gradle.
So looking over here, we see that this is version 2021. 2.3, and now that's what I'm getting at the
time of this recording.
What we really want is 2021. three or higher.
OK.
So if at the time that you're watching this recording and you come out here and follow these instructions
and you're still seeing something less than 2021. three such as that too, like I have here, you're
going to want to follow what I'm saying next.
If you do have 2021 three or higher, you can go ahead and just choose your operating system and then
the community version of Vidi.
And if you're on Mac OS and you're on an Intel Mac, then you choose this.
Otherwise, you can click on this and choose Apple Silicon.
If you happen to be looking at this, though, and you're on something lower than 2021. three, then
you're going to want to come up here and click on coming in 2021. three.
Click on that link and you can download their early access version of 2021.
Three.
All right.
So again, just choose your operating system and then you're going to download the community version.
And again, I'm on a Apple Silicon Mac, so I'm going to choose that.
But if you're on Intel, Mac or Windows, you will just choose Windows or Linux.
Some choosing that and then that's going to start to download.
All right, and so that's done.
And so now I can go ahead and start the installer and hopefully you know how to start an install installation
of downloaded applications for your given operating system.
So I'm going to do it this way.
And then I'm just going to drag this on to my applications folder here.
And yes, I do want to replace in my case because I already have a previous version installed.
So I'm going to replace the one that I currently have.
All right.
And then I can launch it, so I will open up my spotlight search here.
Or you can.
However, you normally find applications that you've installed into the applications folder via the
Finder or File Explorer if you're on Windows or the Start menu and start typing whatever you do.
All right.
So I've just opened up the applications folder by actually just double clicking on this icon and I.
And my operating system is just asking me if I'm okay with opening something up that I downloaded from
the internet, which yes, I am.
There we go.
And so now I can see that I'm running twenty twenty one point three and I can double check that up here
with the about intelligibly dialogue.
Yeah.
Idea twenty twenty one point three release candidate.
That's what the RC stands for, which means that it's almost basically done.
They're just putting it through its final paces.
And when they finalize the release, by the way, we should be able to just update this to the final
release.
All right, so that is good.
All right.
And so now we have the latest, greatest version of Intel is installed and it's ready to work well with
version 17 of the JDK.
See in the next one.