All right, so in this lesson, we're going to continue learning a little bit more kind of more of the
miscellaneous type things perhaps that we can do with lists and collections.
So the first thing I want to run through is Here Online's forty three through 46, we are creating our
list of undesirables.
Let me go and just rename this because I'm enjoying calling them that undesirables, even though it's
hard to spell.
Sort of.
OK, so there's our undesirables, by the way.
You know, I just renamed that by doing a shift at six, right?
That's how I did that.
OK, now I want to show you that.
So the way that we created this list of of undesirables was just to, you know, create an array list
and store it in this variable here.
And then we called the add method of the list.
OK.
But there's actually another shorthand way that you can do this when you want to just quickly specify
a list of things to go into a brand new collection that you are creating, in this case, a brand new
list.
We can do it an alternative way.
Also what we can do.
I'm going to comment these three lines like so and then over here, instead of instantiating a new array
list, there's a utility method that we can call on the list class list, sort of.
So we've seen this sort of business before.
We've done local date, sort of, for example.
OK.
And so what we can do here list sort of then we can actually just specify our strings right here.
So Wilma, five, I shouldn't be typing these in.
I should be copying and pasting, but that's all right.
Barney, four, and Fred, two, like so.
And what that results in is giving us a list just like we wanted before.
But it's a little bit more convenient in some cases, right?
We don't have to use up three lines of code to add these three guys separately.
OK, so this is a nice little utility method that we can utilize.
And as we learn about some of the other implementations of collections such as sets and hash maps,
there are similar utilities for for creating instances of those types of objects as well.
OK, so a lot of what I'm showing you.
In fact, let me just take a moment to state this.
Some of what I'm showing you or what I have already shown you applies to some of the other collections
types, in particular the set.
OK.
What you'll learn about shortly in an upcoming lesson.
So, for example, iterating over objects, if this collection here was not a list and it was a set,
this pattern would be exactly the same.
OK, what else?
Jumping into this remove undesirables method here you can get an iterator from a list.
You can also get an iterator from a set.
OK.
So many implementations of the various collections and their interfaces provide a lot of the same functionality.
All right.
So there's a nice shorthand way to create this list.
Let me go ahead and delete these commented lines now.
All right.
Another thing I want to show you is, let's say that we wanted to grab a hold of a few of these, a
few of the objects, a few of the employees that are now in our employees list and remove them in some
other way.
Maybe not while we're iterating, but just more like manually or something.
That's pretty easy to do.
In fact, actually, I guess many would argue that's actually easier to do than what we're doing here,
though this is a somewhat common pattern that you will encounter from time to time.
So let me show you, though, so let's see here.
We've got our we've got our employees collection here.
So let's say that we want to grab the first three.
Employees in that collection and remove them.
OK.
Just the first three.
So one way that we could do that?
Let me put these lines together real quick here.
OK.
So one way that we could do that, I'll do this up here is we could reference the employees collection
and then use the get method.
OK.
And the get method gives us an object that is inside of this collection based on its index.
So starting with zero zero would be the first one.
So this works a lot like the arrays, right?
So if I wanted to get the first person out of this collection, I could just use get zero.
And then if I want to capture that person, I can do an option Command V. And I'll just say first.
So this should be Fred, the first Fred here.
That's who that should be.
OK.
And then if I want to duplicate this a couple more times and and then get the second one, which is
index one, right?
Because we're zero based and get the third one, which is index two.
And same thing goes here second and third.
All right.
So now I've got my hands on these three employees.
And now, if I want to remove them from the collection, I can do that very easily as well.
So I can just say employees died.
Remove.
And now I actually have a few options here, to be honest with you.
What I was going to show you first, though, was this first one here where I can just say first, OK?
And then I could reference the second and the third as well.
You get the picture.
Second and third.
Third, like so OK.
So that's one way that I can remove individuals or individual objects from a collection very straightforwardly.
OK.
However, you may have seen that there was another way as well that kind of combined that kind of skip
the middle man here.
We're using an index to first get the thing, and then I'm referring to the thing that tell it to remove
it, right?
So I can actually skip past all of that.
Let's see.
We'll just we'll we'll get rid of all of these lines.
And what you can do instead is employees remove and then just pass in an index like so.
So this is equivalent and more streamlined, actually.
Right?
Just pass in the index and then tell it, remove the first, the second and the third.