All right.
So continuing on our journey, the next thing up is we're going to take a slightly deeper dive into
options.
Again, this is one of these topics that we've been kind of touching up on in a few of the previous
modules, a little bit here and there, but we haven't taken much of a deep dive into it.
And again, this is one of these topics that I don't think really requires its own complete module.
So we're going to do another just marathon race through most, maybe even all of the methods of optional
so that I can show you a lot of the use cases.
Now one thing about optional is that I really looked at trying to introduce them to you earlier.
But the problem is that a lot of the really cool things that you can do with options is predicated on
your knowledge of lambdas and the streams API.
And so I realized that if I had tried to introduce optional before now, I wouldn't have been able to
go very deep into a lot of the core functionality of them.
So without further ado, let's jump in.
OK, so what we're going to do, first of all, is to create a new class.
And let's see, we'll do that in this same package.
So we created the repository under data store.
So I'm going to click on data store and do a command in and new Java class and create a new class.
And I'm just going to call it optional test because I don't really care what we call it too much.
All right, there we go.
And then I can close down that side there, OK, and make a new line inside of this class, and we'll
create a familiar public static void main method like so so that we can just kind of play around a little
bit with optional.
All right.
And so the first thing we're going to do will be a little bit of review.
You've seen a few of these tricks before.
First thing we're going to do is to create an optional let me and import that of a string.
And we'll just say something like, hello, and then I'm going to capture that string, and I will call
this opt for optional.
And maybe, I don't know, iMessage MSG, OK?
And then let's print that out within our society.
So we'll refer to the optional message there, and let's just run that and see what we get.
So a little bit of review.
All right.
So we're printing this out.
And as you can see, it does print out the word hello, but it's surrounded by this optional thing because
the object that we have here is not a string.
It is an optional of a string, right?
And so optional.
Present themselves with this word optional and then brackets and then whatever thing is inside of it.
And then it's calling the two string method of whatever object is inside of the optional.
So hopefully you may recall that options are really just wrappers for other objects or for nothing at
all.
Right?
They give us the option of representing either some object existing or no object existing in a particular
case.
Let's talk real quick again about what options are really for the the number one use case for them has
to do with null values.
So whenever we're dealing with objects in Java, we store references to objects in variables, right?
And those variables may or may not actually be pointing back to an object.
So, for example, we could create a string called message and put a word in it, right?
Like, like, so OK.
So in this case, the variable mzgee is pointing to the object.
Hello.
OK, which exist somewhere in memory.
But we could also have, I don't know, message to.
Pointing to nothing.
Right?
That's not all right.
And if I try to do something like amnesty to that to upper, and if I run this, that's going to blow
up with a null pointer exception.
There it is.
NULL pointer exception, right?
Because I'm trying to reference a method of a a method of an object that really does not exist.
OK.
And we don't like these null pointer exceptions because they cause our programs to stop, and we usually
don't want our programs to blow up if we can help it.
OK, so optional.
Let us wrap these variables in a little pretty box, and they provide us with some cool methods that
can help us to detect whether or not we actually have any value in the box.
And if we do, then we can proceed to do things with that value.
So, for example, here I've got the message to uppercase, right?
So let's say that I wrap this message in an optional.
So let's see here I could do something like optional sort of Nullarbor.
Now, if you recall, we did look at the optional sort of an optional dot Nullarbor.
In this particular case, I have to create an optional of the message to object using the of Nullarbor
Method, because we can see right here that this guy is no right and we'll talk a little bit more about
when to use of versus of Nullarbor.
But let me just finish up this little example here, so I'm going to embed the message two in there
and then I'm going to capture this.
And I don't know.
Let's just call it Optimus G, too, right?
So the optional message, too.
And now I'm going to come down here and reference that like, so now, as soon as I do that, I get
at an error because there is no two uppercase method existing on the optional class right now.
This is no longer a string.
It's an optional now, right?
And so I cannot call to uppercase.
So then what's the whole point of using the optional right?
Well, now I can use some of the methods on the optional class to determine first whether or not I have
a value here and then only proceed with the rest of this stuff, sort of sort of kind of if there is
something actually there.
So let's take a look real quick here.
I can do something like or else and then I can provide an alternative string if that value was actually
null, right?
So I don't know.
I'll just say alternative like that.
And now I can put a period here and now that's good.
OK.
So let's run this and see what we're going to get.
Oh, I forgot to actually print it out.
Let's see here.
So tell you what we'll do, so we'll just capture the output of that.
Final output, and then we'll print that out.
Final output.
There we go.
Let's run that.
OK, so we get the word alternative in all caps.
And that makes sense because what this is saying is check and see what value is inside of this optional
if there is a value in it.
Then go ahead and return that value.
Right.
So then this whole entire thing would become whatever that value was that was in here if it wasn't null
and then we would proceed with the two uppercase or else, though, if it is null, if the value that
is inside of this optional is null, then return this value that I'm supplying here, which is alternative.
And so then in that case, this whole entire thing becomes the value of alternative.
And now still, this two uppercase will work, right?
So the point of all of this is that it should now be impossible.
I hope to get a null pointer exception as a result of this value here being null because this or else
is essentially doing some fancy, if then else logic for us, but really, really compactly, right?
And I think I showed that in probably the Stream's module, right?
So this or else is saying, if blah blah blah is not null, then return whatever blah blah blah is.
Or else return alternative, right?
That's why this is saying or else.
OK.
And then I said we'd come back and talk a little bit more about the of knowable, which we've spoken
about before, but this is just a quick reminder.
So in this case, I just had to use this of knowable in order to create an optional of this message,
too, because right here we can see clearly that this value is null.
But let's go ahead and see what would have happened if I had not done it that way.
Someone to just clear some things out a little bit here, so we'll not use the unknowable and instead
we'll just use of right and then we will.
Print that guy.
And I'm not even going to bother with the fancy footwork to get the actual value out of it, we'll just
stop right here and let's run that and see what happens.
OK, so we get an old pointer exception with a nice stack trace, and now we know how to read the stack
trace a little better, right?
So starting from the top, this line here is not code that we wrote, so I do not care about it.
This line here is also not code that we wrote, and so I don't care about it either.
And so now down here, this is the first line in the stack trace that is code that we wrote.
And that's the code I care about, which is line nine.
And I can click on that and let's see where it blew up.
So look at this.
It blew up on Line nine.
Some of you might have thought that it might have blown up down here when we actually tried to do something,
although if you thought about it, that wouldn't actually make sense because even if this had just been
interpreted as a null.
We know that system out.
That print line is doesn't have any problems with printing out a null, right?
So that wouldn't have been an issue there, but it blew up here.
The reason for that is that this of method here is expecting that the value you're passing in to it
is not null.
OK.
So you can almost think of it as this.
You would use an optional dot of so that you could intentionally test.
In part, this is one of the reasons why you would use it so that you could intentionally test and make
sure that the values that you were passing in to it were not null, OK?
And its behavior is going to be to blow up with a null pointer exception if those values are in fact
null.
OK.
So you should generally only be using optional sort of in maybe two cases.
First case is you're 100 percent certain that the values that you will be passing into it won't be null.
The second case, though, would be you're not sure if the values might be null and you're OK with your
program blowing up with a null pointer exception.
And in fact, maybe in some cases you want that to happen, because let's say that the variables that
she'll be passing into the optional dot of ninety nine point nine percent of the time should not be
null.
And if they are, then you've got bigger problems and you want to know about those problems, right?
I eluded to this a little bit in.
I think the last lesson also where sometimes we want things to blow up on purpose.
We don't want our program to just carry on happily when unexpected circumstances occur.
In some cases, we want the program to blow up and die with a nice stack trace so that we can learn
what's going on rather than just like sweeping it under the rug, right?
We don't want things to be swept under the rug because that could result in worse problems.
Think of programs that might be trying to store data in a database across millions of records or something,
and you've got some underlying issue that you were not aware of.
And now, like millions of records of data, are corrupted, right?
Because you decided to just hide or ignore some exceptions.
So don't do that.
All right.
So that's what happens with the optional data, right?
It blows up as soon as you try to pass into it, a value that is null.
If you don't want that behavior, you have to use of null a bull, which then doesn't do that check.
And it's kind of like, maybe there's a value there.
Maybe there isn't.
You will figure it out later on in the in the thread, right?
All right.
So next up, let's look at a few more of the basic methods that exist on an optional.
So we'll start with perhaps the most basic one, which is get right.
So and by the way, let me let's fix this.
Otherwise, we won't be getting too far.
All right.
So.
Now we've got our get here, so now let's run this and see what happens.
OK, so now we get a no such element exception and it is occurring on line 10 now.
Right?
Which is this line.
So because we're using the of Nullarbor, we're not blowing up online nine anymore.
When we pass in this null value now, we're blowing up down here with this get.
So if you may recall the Dot get method.
I actually don't consider it to be all that helpful under a lot of circumstances because it's pretty
dumb.
It just tries to get the value out, OK?
And it doesn't do any checks and it doesn't give us any options.
And I mean, optional, but I mean, like any options of how to do it wisely within the get method itself.
OK, so it's just going to like, go for it.
So oftentimes not a real good method to use because it can result in your program blowing up when you
didn't expect it to.
And in that case, to do what we're doing here is really no better than just not using options at all
and just having a value that could possibly be null and then trying to use it right?
It's pretty much the same thing at this point, especially if we tried to dig in and do something else
like, I don't know, like this to uppercase, right?
If we tried to do that right, in this case, there's no real difference between us doing this versus
doing it, MST2 versus doing that right.
They're both going to blow up.
So no advantage to that.
So the get method is probably only helpful if you combine it with a test and you can do some type of
tests, like if optional message to diet is present.
Then do all of this, right, so now we're wrapping, wrapping this inside of an f block here and we're
testing, so the optional class has this method is present that lets us test whether or not there's
actually a value in there, right?
And in fact, here we'll even throw in both and else there.
There was nothing there.
Right, and let's run that.
So look at what we get now, there was nothing there.
Predictably, right?
So just keep in mind now what we're doing with all of this is equivalent functionally to just doing
something like optional message to that or else.
There was nothing there.
Right?
That's the same thing, except way fewer lines of code right here.
I'll run that and I will get it twice.
So there you go.
There was nothing there.
Right?
And then on the other hand, if we point this Nullarbor to the MSG and then run this now we get.
Hello.
Right.
So the first hello is all caps because it's coming from here.
OK.
The second one is coming here, and we're not doing anything with the resulting string and therefore
it is not being capitalized, I could throw that on here at the end though, right?
I can do that and run this again.
There you go.
So now you're getting hello, hello, all caps for both.
So that just goes to show, though, that generally speaking, a method like or else.
And we're going to see a bunch of variations on this in just a moment.
It's probably a way better choice than using get.
OK.
So you really want to shy away from using that get because it's pretty much only useful if you combine
it with tests above and as soon as you start doing these tests above and all of this.
Well, now you kind of defeat a whole lot of the beauty of even using optional to begin with, right?
Because now you're just writing all this, if they'll stuff all over the place and where's the fun in
that?
Similarly, now, in addition to the is present method, there is also and is empty method.
So with the empty method, it's going to do what you think it's going to do, right?
So in this case, if we wanted the logic to still make sense, we could put a.
Not in front of it.
Remember that the little exclamation mark there, right, so.
So basically, we're saying if this optional is not empty, then go ahead and do all of this.
Otherwise do the other thing right?
So we'll run that.
There you go.
And then we'll point it back at the No.
One, which would result in an empty, optional.
There you go.
Right.
So that's how that would work, so you've got two sides of the same coin, you've got the is present
or you can test for the is empty, right?
They both do opposite versions of the same thing essentially, though, right?
All right.
So then let's look at some of these alternative methods of the or else.
OK, so if I put my cursor down here.
All right.
So we just looked at or else there's also or else through.
Now we did look at that in the last lesson.
We were doing a fine first, I believe, which wants to return an optional.
And we didn't want to return an optional, though.
So instead, we opted to simply call the or else throw.
Right.
So we'll just do that again, just as a quick reminder of how that all works.
And I'll clear this out.
OK, so let's run that.
All right, and so that's blowing up because we're pointing at the null value right here, in fact,
let me it's clear all of that out there, so it's a little less confusing, right?
OK, so no value present.
We got a no such element exception with this guy or else throw.
So that's one thing that you could do.
Let's see.
We also could do this other version, this overloaded version of or else throw that takes a supplier.
So this one just allows us to supply our own exceptions.
So if we wanted a different exception other than the no such element exception because the Orioles through
with the version that we just used, is hardcoded essentially to throw a no such element exception.
But let's say that we wanted to throw a different type of exception.
Well, in that case, we could use the Orioles through method here, and it takes a supplier and supplier
is one of our many, many, many functional interfaces.
It's an interface that represents a method that doesn't take any input, but it throws something.
It supplies something, right?
So in that case, we could do this notice.
By the way, I'm using just the empty parentheses there because again, we're not taking any input for
a supplier interface, right?
Or a supplier function, if you will.
The thing that I'm going to return, though, will be something that extends runtime exception.
OK.
So what I can do here, just for grins, is I will just create an instance of a runtime exception and
I can call its constructor so that I can pass in some simple message like nothing found.
OK, now normally you may recall in the exceptions lesson, I did state that typically in real life,
you don't want to be creating new runtime exceptions like this.
You want a first go look through all of the standard exceptions that are already created with Java and
see if there's one that's already existing whose name matches with your circumstance, right?
So like if you were looking for a file and you couldn't find one, maybe there's a runtime exception
that has something to do with file related exceptions, right?
Something like that.
And only after you've looked through all of the standard exceptions and couldn't find one that matches
with your circumstance in terms of its name, then you could consider creating your own class that extends
runtime exception or exception if that's your case for, like a checked exception or something.
OK.
But for illustrative purposes here, I don't feel like going and creating one of those.
So we're going to just do this for right now, so I'm running this again.
And so now we're getting a runtime exception and there's our message.
Nothing found right?
And that's what I passed in there.
So that's the or else throw.
All right.
Let's see what else we've got here.
We've got or else get.
So this is very similar to the or else in fact, it's almost the same thing, except it uses a supplier.
So let me just remind you real quick what the or else we just were able to give it an alternative string.
Now I'm saying string here because that's what our optional is an optional love.
But if I had created an optional the person, then the thing that I could return from this or else wouldn't
be a string.
It would be a person, right?
So this is a generic class.
And now you know more about these generics, right?
So whatever we're supplying here, so to speak, needs to be of this type.
Whatever the type is, the generic type is for the optional itself, right?
But as the quick reminder, I was just going to show you again that the or else lets us give the alternative
in this case, string right or the alternative object right?
My alt right.
However, we could use the other version of or else the or else get which takes a supplier, which is
again one of the functional interfaces.
And again, it's an interface that represents a method are a function that doesn't take an input, but
it supplies things or values, right?
And the dumb way that we could do this might be something like, here's a method that just returns that
same text, right?
So in this case, this is functionally what I'm doing right now is functionally no different from just
doing the or else that I had before.
So you may be wondering, well, why would you even do this then?
So maybe we could have a method reference, like maybe there's some method somewhere else in our code
that generates passwords, let's say.
Yeah.
In fact, that might be a good example right there.
Maybe we've got some code here.
What's the password that takes some input input from user for password, something like that?
And let's say that for some reason, our code that gets that input from the user results in the user
not having entered anything, though, we really should be checking that before we would get this far.
But for whatever reason, let's say that the user didn't enter their password and they managed to get
past us, right?
And so now this password that we were expecting would have a password that they entered is in fact just
null, OK?
And so then we get down here.
Well, in that case, what you could have is something like basically, if they supplied the password,
then go ahead and do whatever you were planning to do with the password.
But if they did not supply the password, then maybe you're doing this or else get and then this or
else get is pointing at a method reference to some fancy method that can generate new passwords for
us each time we call it.
Right?
And so that would be maybe a really good use of this or else get just giving you some context as to
why you might ever want to use something like this.
Right?
And granted, even with that scenario, you could still just do something like or else.
And then call that method, you know, fancy password generator method, which returns a string, you
could still even just do that like a given they're giving us a lot of options.
All right.
And so finally, the last one here is just the plain old order method, and this one is very similar
to our to our other methods.
Except what it returns will be wrapped inside of an optional.
So let me show you what I mean here.
So it's basically expecting a supplier again.
So I'll make a really dumb supplier.
Nothing, nothing here.
All right.
So I showed you this before, but notice it's still red.
And the reason for that is because I have to actually wrap my value here, my return value in another
optional so I can do of.
Like so now notice with this approach, by the way, let me let me get rid of that, OK?
All right.
And so now I'm just going to be returning another option.
So that's really the only thing about using the border is that it is expecting to return an optional
of some alternative thing.
OK.
And if you hover over it, you'll see here.
Yeah.
So it even shows it in the signature returns an optional of a thing.
All right.
And so let's look at the next method here.
I'm going to go ahead and delete all of that.
Did I get enough of it?
Let's see.
I guess one more.
OK, so let's see.
The next one we'll look at is filter.
So this is cool because we get to see now a lot of these methods that were part of the Streams API have
been brought over or there's a version of them on the optional class, which is another reason why it
made a lot of sense to first learn about the Lambdas and Streams API before we jumped into all of this.
So this filter here works pretty much exactly like the filter in the streams API takes a predicate does
the same stuff, except where the filter from the Streams API would return a stream again.
A stream of whatever this filter here returns an optional of whatever.
OK, so it's got a good parallel there, but it's, you know, a little bit different in what it's returning.
But the functionality is about the same and you'd want to use this if you wanted to ensure not only
that there should be an object inside of the optional, but you can also have a chance to test that
object for some type of property or behavior or whatever.
So let's take a look at what that looks like.
All right, so let me finish this up.
So let's say that we wanted to only print out the value, the word in this case or the string in this
optional if it is greater than three characters long.
OK, so the filter takes a predicate.
So we're going to create a lambda expression to represent this scenario, right?
So that lambda expression is going to take as an input, the string that is in that is presumed to be
inside of this optional right.
So then we can represent that in a lambda expression with, let's say, s for string and then we'll
do one of these things here.
And so now we're just going to say if the length is greater than three.
So if we just hover over the filter and take a look at its Java doc real quick, we can see that it
will return and optional of whatever.
So in this case, if the optional contains a value and that value, which is a string in this case,
is greater in length than three, then this is going to return that optional, right?
So it's not even going to unwrap it or anything, it's just going to return that optional.
Otherwise, though, it's going to filter it out now because this returns an optional.
We can then go on and do the rest of whatever else we might normally have done.
All right.
So let's just run this as it is, so you can just get a sense for how it's going to behave.
So I'm just going to run that.
All right.
So we get an optional dot empty, which makes sense because we are still pointing to this message to
which is currently just null.
Right?
And so we're just printing an optional.
The optional is what came out of the filter, but it's an empty optional.
And so we get optional that empty.
Now, if we want to make sure that we get something more legit to print, which would be some type of
a string, we can fall back on our familiar fallback methods like or else right, so we can do an or
else and then say something like invalid, right?
And so we'll run that.
There we go.
And so now we've got the invalid there.
Now let's test what happens, though, if we actually put legitimate strings in here and not null.
So let's start with something that's only three characters long so cat.
Right?
So let's run that.
OK, so we still get the invalid now.
And so that just goes to show that the word cat is not passing our predicate here because our predicate
is expecting a word or string greater than three characters in length.
And this is only three three is not greater than three.
And so we end up still going into the or else.
So you see what this is doing.
If it's null, you get the URLs or if if the value doesn't pass our predicate, you also get the or
else with with the with the filter here.
OK.
And then let's go ahead and make it a little longer catastrophe, let's say.
OK, so let's run that.
And now we get the original word out because it is now passing our predicate test for the filter.
So that's what Filter does.
Pretty nice.
All right.
And so now we get to jump in to another really interesting method that is pretty much taken straight
from the Streams API.
For this, we're going to do a little bit of setup, though.
So the first thing I want to do is I'm going to create a couple of small.