All right.
Next up on our world wind tour, we're going to learn how to replace parts of text in a string.
So going back to the ABC, I've cleared out the last bit of code that we had and we're still in the
same learning strings class.
And let's see, we'll make a new line is as usual and we'll create a variable.
To hold some text.
All right.
And as usual, you feel free to make the text whatever you want it to be.
It really doesn't matter.
All right.
So now we're going to learn how we can replace any parts of the text with anything else.
So where this might come in handy would be there are a lot of ways that this could come in.
Basically, this is kind of equivalent to a search and replace, but you're doing it programmatically,
so you might accept input typed input from a user like your prompt them to enter something.
And well, here, let's say that you're allowing users to enter text at a prompt and you want to make
sure that they didn't enter any bad words.
OK, now we're not going to use any real bad words here, but let's say that you want to filter out
any time that they say the word first.
I'm just making up a word here, right?
So I'll put that in first.
That's my made up.
Bad word.
OK.
So any time the word first is in the text, you want to filter that out.
All right.
Let's see so what we can do first.
We'll just print out the my text as it is using our trustees.
So you t. my text.
OK.
So that would print out the whole regular sentence.
However, we can call a method on the string variable so I can put a period here.
OK, so there's a method for replacing text, and it is surprise, surprise called replace.
There are a couple versions of it, one that just can replace one character and then another one that
can replace basically a string.
If you look at this signature here, you'll see that the inputs for the second one take something called
a character sequence or care sequence.
I'm not going to go into the details of what that is, but you can think of it as a string and it will
accept a string.
So the way this works is you tell it what you're looking for as the first parameter and then you tell
it what you want to replace with as the second parameter.
All right.
So if I select replace here and I can tell it to look for the word first.
And replace it with something else.
Nice.
OK, so any place where we see the word Firth should now be replaced by the word nice.
So let's run this and see what we get.
And there you go.
Here's my awesome, nice text.
And just to prove, by the way, I should have done this before, but just to prove that that really
is doing a replacement, I'll just remove the replace and run it now.
And I mean, I'm sure you'll you can all see that that's going to.
Yeah, there we go.
There's the word for there.
OK, so I'll put the the replacement back.
Now, let's see what would happen if we had that word in a few places first.
So now I've got it in two places here.
Let's run that and see what we get.
OK, so great.
So any place where our target word is found, we get a replacement there.
Now let's also see if it's case sensitive.
So what if we told the replace method to look for capital first?
Let's see what we get now.
OK, so it is case sensitive, meaning it does care whether or not you're specifying upper or lower
case, it pays attention to that.
So this lower case first in this upper case for are considered to be two completely different strings.
So keep that in mind.
All right.
Let's also look at the other version of the replace method that is looks for characters.
So if I if I erase what was inside of the parentheses there.
And by the way, if I want to see what the different parameters are that that a method can take while
the cursor is inside of the parentheses I can do on Mac Command P four parameter looks like on Windows
and Linux, its control p.
And so that is now showing me what the inputs are.
So what I'm seeing here is here's one input something of type care sequence, and it's the parameters
called target comma.
And then the second parameter, which is also a character sequence for the replacement.
OK.
All right.
So that's for that version of the method.
And then up above that, we're seeing the other version of this method.
So in other words, this method has there are a couple of versions of this method.
They both are called replace, but one takes two characters.
The other one takes two character sequences.
OK?
And like I said, you can think of a character sequence as basically just a string, and then a character
is just one letter essentially in the Latin alphabet.
One character you know of of a string.
So let's see how that works.
So if we tell it, we want to replace C all of the E's with a capital z.
So the way to specify a character in Java is with a single quote rather than a double quote.
So we're going to tell it to look for all of the E's.
Comma.
And then replace them single quote with Capital Z.
Let's run that and see what we get.
Wow, look at that, that's pretty weird looking, HCR Z.
So, yeah, it replaced all of the lowercase E's with a capital z.
Okay.
So pretty, pretty straightforward.
And I think that's going to wrap this up.
This was an easy one.
I'll see you in the next one.