All right, so now we've written two tests and we've refactored any duplication out of the tests as
well.
So now the question becomes, OK, what should we test next?
Another great type of scenario is to try to consider are what are called edge cases.
Now, there's no great formula that I can give you for how to think of edge cases, unfortunately.
But maybe I can at least clue you in a little bit into some some ways of thinking about them.
So in this particular domain here, where we've got this calculator object and currently we're just
testing our ability to add, let's jump into this add method and just be reminded of what it's actually
doing.
So this ad method is taking two integers number one and number two, and then it returns an integer.
Simple enough.
So when I ask myself, are there any potential edge cases that might be good to test with this one thought
that does come to my mind is the fact that we are using an integer and there is a limit of how large
an integer number can actually be.
As we learned in the number module right and integer is 32 bit wide.
And the most significant bit of the integer is used to specify the sign of the number, meaning whether
or not it's negative or positive, right?
And if I recall offhand, because I'm too lazy to go, look, right now, the range of an integer is
roughly on the positive side two point one billion, if I'm not mistaken.
OK.
So one question that comes to my mind is what would happen if we were to pass in the largest number
that an integer can represent in Java plus one or plus two?
These would be edge case scenarios, right?
Because it it's not necessarily entirely clear what the result of that would be.
And because of that, those might be some pretty good scenarios to test.
So how might we want to go about testing that?
All right.
So let's jump back over to the calculator test, and let's just copy one of these test methods and create
a new test.
And let's say something like can add.
I don't know.
Max Ent., +1.
OK, let's consider testing that scenario.
Now we're going to have to consider some things here.
First off, what is the maximum value for an integer?
Well, there's a couple of ways that we could find this out.
Obviously, we could just google it and we might actually do that.
But I do want you to be aware of something if we use the integer wrapper class.
Remember this guy that that class right there?
If you will recall the integer wrapper class and all of the numeric wrapper classes for this matter
have a number of methods on them.
They also have a few constants defined on them, and the integer wrapper class actually has a constant
called max value.
So this does indeed refer to the maximum value of an integer.
And if I select that and hover on it, it even tells us here in the Java Dock a constant holding the
maximum value and can have, which is two to the 31st power minus one.
Oh, and look at that, there's the actual number right there.
If I press f one.
I can make that bigger and then I can select that number and copy it.
So I am now setting up a scenario where we can add the maximum value of an integer plus one.
But now I need to assert what that would equal.
And here's where we need to be a little bit careful.
Now, some of you who may be kind of shrewd might think that we could do something like integer dot
max value plus one.
And I think that's a very logical assumption to make.
So let's run just this one test and see what happens.
OK, great, so that passed.
So we're done right.
Well, not so fast.
We need to be a little careful here because as we've already stated and acknowledged, we're we're running
edge cases now.
So I would encourage that.
In a case like this, we're making certain assumptions here.
We're assuming that adding one to this integer value is going to do what we expect it to do, but we
don't actually know that.
So consider if there's anything faulty in the way that this add method is implemented, which we already
know is essentially doing exactly this.
And then our expected field is doing the exact same thing.
We might just be doubling down on logic that's faulty from the beginning here.
OK.
So what we might want to do in this particular case is to at least just print out what this sum actually
is.
So we could temporarily just put a system that out and then just reference that some just like so.
So let's let's run this again and see what that what that prints out.
Oh, and one more thing before we do that, I copied the actual maximum integer value from the Java
Dock, and I'm going to just put that somewhere in a comment.
So there's that number.
OK.
All right.
So we would expect that the sum of the integer max value and one would be this big, huge number, but
instead of a seven and eight.
Is that a reasonable assumption?
I think that should be reasonable.
All right.
So now let's run this and see what we get.
Oh, interesting, we get a negative number.
Does that make any sense to you?
That is not what I think we would have expected.
It looks like the right digits, but the sign is wrong.
It's negative.
So that's telling us something right here now.
We would have expected that the answer should have been this no, except with an eight on the end positive,
though.
But we got a negative out of this since our assertion is passing.
That means that when we take this max integer and add one to it right here in the assertion, we must
be getting this same negative number, which means that our own assumption of what to expect is actually
wrong.
Right?
So this is shining a light on the fact that our unit tests are only as good as our scenarios that we
can think of, and our unit tests are only as good as our assumptions of what to actually expect.
Now I think what's happening here, if you remember back to how the numbers work in Java, since we
only have 32 bits available to use and the most significant bit of an integer is used for the sign,
right?
What happens when you take the largest number that you can use in an integer, which is this, and then
you add one more to it?
Well, you're likely going to bump up against the most significant bit that last 32 bit.
And I think that's probably the reason why we're getting a negative value now.
If that makes any sense for you, go back and watch.
That lesson is if you need a refresher on some of the concepts that I'm talking about here, but my
suspicion is that something along those lines is happening.
So can you think of a way that we could do a proper comparison without having to worry about running
out of bits down here in the assertion?
If you need to pause the video and think about that for a moment?
All right.
So one thing that I can think of that we might do is in our assertion for the expected field.
What if we don't use an integer and we use something with more precision like a long?
So we could convert these numbers to a long and therefore give ourselves more bits to ensure that we're
not running up against the edge of those of the 32 bits that we have.
Does that make sense now?
Can you think of how we could ensure that when we do this integer max value plus one, we're not stuck
inside of 32 bits and we actually increase the number of bits?
Can you think of how we could do that?
All right.
So you may recall that by default, numbers like this one that we have here are of type, integer or
end, and we know that this number here is an event.
And when you do a math operation like an enter plus an end, by default, the result will be another
event.
But we know that integer only has 32 bits, and we suspect that we're running up against the very edge
of those 32 bits and that may be causing this issue here.
So we can force the JVM or Java to do this math with more bits by simply making one of these numbers
not be an integer.
And the easiest thing I can think to do here would be to actually put my cursor right after this one
and then put an L here, meaning long.
So by doing that, I'm telling the JVM that I want this one to not be an integer with 32 bits, but
I want it to be a long with 64 bits.
And now, by doing so, the sum of these two numbers will be of type long, which has much more room
to grow in the event that you're adding one to the maximum value of an integer.
OK.
So we're giving ourselves more space here.
Now, this isn't a super obvious scenario here, and my purpose in showing you this isn't to revisit
the number module per se.
My purpose here is to shine a light on the fact that when you're testing, you want to try to think
of true edge cases because it is in those edge cases that a lot of bugs can exist and you have to be
really careful when you're doing those edge cases.
But one simple thing that you may want to do is simply print out some of the intermediate values of
what you may assume you're going to get right so you can see it with your own eyes.
And that may help shine a light on how best to go about testing these scenarios as well.
So let's rerun this now and see what we end up with.
Hmm.
Now we get a failure.
And now when we look at that failure, look at what we see here.
We expected a positive number ending with an eight, but we got a negative number ending with an eight.
And it looks like the numbers are the same other than the sign to one four seven four eight three six
four eight.
Yeah.
So the numbers are the same, but the sign is different, and that's enough to now show that this isn't
working correctly.
Right?
So we just uncovered a potential bug.
If someone had chosen to use this add method and pass in a number that is right at the edge of what's
allowed with an integer right.
The I.D. and Java wouldn't have complained at all.
And yet our answers would have been just dead wrong.
Now we're not going to actually try to fix this, because that would require us to really think even
more about the number of systems and how we would want to handle this.
And that's a little beyond the scope of what I want to get into.
For this testing, but I wanted to again, just show that it's important to try to think of edge cases.
You may not always be able to think of a good one like this one, but you should at least try.
And then you want to be super careful with what you're doing to test those edge cases, because in this
case, we made an assumption that we could simply refer to the max value plus one and that that would
work.
And it did pass.
But it wasn't correct.
Right?
It wasn't correct at all.
All right.
So we're going to wrap up this lesson and I will see you in the next one.