All right, now, let's talk about what we need to do when we want to work with numbers that are not
whole integer numbers.
In other words, numbers with fractional parts or decimal points.
So Java has a couple of primitive data types for handling what are called floating point numbers.
That is, numbers that have a floating decimal point, right?
So one point three, seven or eight point zero five nine two things like that and the two data types
that we have for handling these kinds of numbers are float and double.
And they're basically the same thing, except double is twice as wide as float.
Float shares the same number of bits as an end or integer, which is 32 bits and double is twice that
at 64 bits.
However, unlike byte and short and and and long, float and double stored their values pretty differently,
and that causes a few issues that we will look at shortly.
So let's take a look at the basic format for how float and double stored their values.
Now again, this isn't something you absolutely have to know.
Most Java developers wouldn't know this, and by the way, what I'm about to show you isn't really even
all that specific to Java.
This is actually a standard from the Tripoli Engineering Group who came up with this standard, and
I would reckon that all modern languages use pretty much this same approach when handling floating point
numbers.
So let's take a look.
We'll use only the float double is virtually the same, except just twice as long for most of the parts.
All right, so down here I have let me see if I can get this framed up a little better.
I've got this number three point one four one five nine two that is PI the the Greek number PI.
OK?
And so here I've got 32 bits.
OK.
So the way that the float data type stores, its value is as follows the first bit, which you may consider
to be the last bit, the the highest bit that at location thirty two on this chart, this bit indicates
the sign of the number so that that part is the same as the other data types that we've looked at,
where the the highest bit or the last bit, whatever indicates the sign, if it's assigned data type.
So you only need one bit for that.
Then the next eight bits, though, indicate essentially where the decimal places.
That's how you can think of it, OK?
And that's called the exponent.
And then the next 23 bits are called the mantis and they hold the actual value.
However, the way they hold the value is not at all like the way the non floating point numbers store
their values.
And that's what we'll take a little bit of a look at, because this can come back to haunt us a little
bit later on some of our calculations.
All right.
So the way that float and double handle their values is a little bit different.
What they do is they store fractional values in binary, and the way that would look is first, let
me give a quick reminders.
OK, so when we store fractional values in decimal, what we do is we have just as we have the ones
and tens and hundreds place four whole numbers.
We have one over 10, one over 100, one over 1000.
You know, places like that for four decimal, right?
So binary works pretty much the same way.
What, what, what we do there is instead of having two and four and eight, 16, et cetera, we have
one over two one over four, one over eight, one over 16 cetera.
OK.
So it's actually kind of it's the same pattern as what we do with decimal numbers, except instead of
base 10, it's now based two.
OK, so powers of two?
All right.
Let's look at how we could encode a fraction or a decimal number in binary.
So let's first do one easy one.
So let's say we wanted to encode point five.
That should be easy, right?
I think everybody knows point five is the same as one half.
So what you would end up with is if we imagine, here's a here's a decimal point right there.
OK, then you'd have one.
OK.
So that would be point one in binary, OK?
Or, you know, I'll write it somewhere else where it can be seen a little more easily.
Point one point one is the binary equivalent of 0.5.
OK.
So let's say we wanted to do 0.7 seven five.
In binary.
OK, well, so you'll want to find the largest fraction that fits into your final number, which is
0.75 five, so we can start with with with one half or 0.5.
Right.
We know that we're going to need that.
And then one over four is is the same as point to five, right?
So five plus point two five, that would be point seventy five.
So another one here.
OK.
So point seven five in binary is point one.
One, just like that.
All right.
So now let's do something a little less trivial.
So let's see here PI.
The number PI.
The Greek number PI three point one four one five nine two.
I think it's correct.
OK.
Yes, that is correct.
Three point one four one five nine two.
All right.
So let's forget about the three for four while here, and let's just concentrate on the decimal part.
Point one four one five nine two.
All right.
So how can that be encoded in binary?
Let's let's clear this out.
All right.
So we need to find the largest fraction that would fit in point one four one five nine two.
And I can tell you now we're going to need a few more.
We're going to need a few more bits.
So I'm going to add a few more here.
All right.
So we're trying to find something that fits in point one four one five nine two.
So let's see.
That would be 0.5.
That would be point to five.
Let's try one over eight.
So we'll just do some math right here.
One divided by eight is point one to five.
OK, that looks like that works.
That fits, but it's not close enough.
So we need to add some more here.
OK, so we'd have a so far it looks like we'd have a zero and a zero and a one here because this fits
right.
In fact, here we'll just put a one right there.
OK.
Let's see.
How about point one to five plus one 16th, so let's see what one divided by 16 is 0.06 to five.
Let's add that up.
And see what we end up with.
Some of all of that.
OK, so that's point one eight that is too big, so we can't have that value there.
All right.
Let's try one over 32.
Point one five still too big, right?
We're comparing this number to this number here and we can't exceed that number.
So one over 32 is too big.
So clear that out.
Let's try.
One over 64.
What that gives us, point one four zero six, two five, that's looking pretty good.
So looks like we we will have zero zero one zero zero one so far.
OK, now can we get closer?
Yes, I know we can get closer.
So let's see what happens when we do one over one to eight.
All right.
Now that's too big because now we just went to point one for eight and we need to be one for one.
All right, so.
Can't do that.
Put a zero there.
Come over here.
Let's try one over 256.
Two big still.
So zero here.
Nothing here.
How about one over five.
12.
Too big.
So zero here.
Nothing here.
How about one?
Over one to four point one four one six.
OK, now this is an interesting one.
If we want it to stop at this number this mini bit, maybe this could be considered an OK approximation.
Point one four one six.
So I'm going to go and put a one here.
Let's just pretend like this is where we're going to stop.
OK.
So point one four one six.
And in fact, that would feel like we just rounded up point one for one five.
The nine, though.
So, you know, you could imagine the nine caused us to round up to one four one six.
And you're, I don't know, kind of good.
Maybe.
All right.
So this illustrates a an important point that I want to make about representing fractions in binary.
And that point is for fractions whose decimal equivalent is never ending like PI, or whose decimal
equivalent is so long that it would exceed all of the bits that you were willing to allocate in your
computer.
The best you can ever do when trying to represent such numbers in binary is to approximate those numbers.
OK.
And that's usually OK for scientific and engineering programming.
But when it comes to handling money where calculations need to be fairly precise, it won't do at all.
So we'll talk more about how we can handle money and overcome some of the issues with handling fractional
values with Java number types.
But for now, let's jump back over to our chart where we're showing the layout of a float or a double
and see how the rest of this gets put together.
So getting back to how floats and bubbles are represented in the computer, we now have a binary bit
pattern that is an approximation of point one four one five nine two.
Obviously, I chose to round this up because if I had chosen to keep going, what we would have discovered
by the nature of the number PI is that we could never get exactly to the full value of PI.
Anything we would do was always going to be an approximation.
So at any rate, when building a float or double number, this bit pattern that is an approximation
of the fraction or decimal number would then be placed in this light blue area of the 32 bits allocated
to a float.
And then for double, it'll be more.
It'll be a lot more.
But this bit pattern that we had over there would be stored here.
So with float, you are limited to these 23 bits.
OK.
And so honestly, there are a lot of fractional numbers that cannot adequately be represented with just
these 23 bits.
And therefore, the computer often ends up having to approximate and round off in order to represent
those numbers within the 23 bits allocated.
Now I am glossing over a few things that I'll mention very briefly, but I'm not going to go into too
much more detail about them.
So a couple of things I want to mention.
So when the computer represents a number like three point one four one five nine two in float or double
the steps that it will generally go through, ah.
First, it will not try to store three point one four directly.
Instead, it will try to get this number to a format that is more compatible with the way that it internally
stores things.
So what it'll do is it'll take this number three point one four.
It'll determine is that bigger than two?
Basically, in this case, it is.
So then it will divide this number by two and it will keep dividing by two until the number is less
than two.
So in this case, it would only have to do it one time.
OK.
And it will also keep track of the number of times it has to do that division by two.
That number of times that it had to divide by two will then be added to.
The number 127 and that result.
So in this case, 128, because it would only have to divide once, will be encoded here in the exponent
area.
OK.
And so this division by two is equivalent to moving the decimal place.
So once the number has been divided enough times to get it less than two, then it can be encoded,
as we did in this exercise over here.
OK.
And by the way, I mean, obviously the computer is not going to go through the convoluted approach
to determining the binary pattern for a fraction, as we did.
I did that very explicitly so that you could really follow the the the logic of it.
There are mathematical means of doing that, though, where you essentially just keep multiplying by
two and then cutting off the whole integer part of the number if and when it exists.
So I skipped over that.
But that's the basic gist of how floating point numbers are stored in memory of the computer.
And like I said earlier, this is actually a standard that goes beyond Java.
So as far as I know, all computers and probably all modern languages operate in the exact same way
or pretty much the same way when it comes to floats and doubles.
So now let's get back into the ADC and see some examples of how these approximations can affect our
calculations.
All right.
So I will create a double.
My double.
Equals three point one four one five nine two.
OK, so I've just created a double.
Now, if I create a float, my float equals three point one four one five nine two.
Now, look at this, I'm getting an error here.
And the error that I'm getting is required tape is float, but I provided a double.
Now what's happening here is that Java and the ADC working with Java assumes that this number here that
I just typed is a double by default.
If I don't want it to assume that, I need to give it an indication that no, I mean float here, and
the way I can do that is to put my cursor at the end of this number and put an F..
And now the squiggly lines go away.
So when you want to create a float number like this, you need to put an f behind it.
Now you can do a capital or lowercase F. It doesn't matter.
So it accepts that as well.
OK.
But you have to indicate an f behind your floating numbers.
Otherwise, Java assumes that you wanted a double by default.
Let's create a couple of numbers, will create one that is two point one five and then another number
that is one point one zero.
And then let's just print out the difference between those two number one minus number two.
All right.
So that should be one point zero five.
Right?
Let's run this and see what we get.
Ooh, look at that.
So we were supposed to get one point zero five, but we actually get one point zero four nine nine nine
nine, et cetera.
So why are we getting that?
It has everything to do with the fact that these decimal values have to be approximated when being stored
in binary with the number of bits that we have available to us.
And in fact, let's see what happens if we change this double, which gives us more opportunity for
more precision, by the way.
Let's see what happens if we change this double to a float, which has less precision now here because
we're switching to float.
We have to specify that these literals two point one five and one point one zero are actually of type
float.
Otherwise, John.