Welcome back in this lesson, we're going to do the typical first program that everybody always does
when learning a new language and that is called Hello World.
And basically all that is is just writing the minimal amount of code to cause our program to print the
words Hello world or whatever message you will you like to the screen in the simplest way possible.
The reason this type of application or program is usually the very first one we write is because it's
usually pretty simple and people want to see, OK, how do I actually write anything in this language
and get it going?
So that's the purpose of this, and that's what we're going to do.
All right.
So the first thing we're going to need to do is click New Project so that we can start a new project
for our Hello World program.
And after a few moments, a dialog box will open up.
Like this one here?
All right, so we want to make sure that we have Java selected here because we're going to make this
the standard plain Java program for the project SDK.
If your computer already had a previous version of Java installed before Java 17, that is, it might
be showing up here.
If so, just click on this dropdown.
You may have noticed there was a little window open just a moment ago, it was searching the computer
to see if there were other or additional versions of Java installed, which in this case we do have
Java 17 installed in addition to 16 on this computer that I'm working on now.
You might not have Java 16 or anything else installed other than 17.
Hopefully you did follow the Java 17 installation process, so hopefully you should be seeing something
referencing JDK 17.
If so, go ahead and select that.
All right.
That took a moment to register, but it is giving me the option now of Java 17.
And then you can click next.
From this point forward, my screen might look a little different because you may be seeing instructions
that I previously had for setting up this Hello World program on a slightly previous version of Intel
with Java version 16.
But everything else will be the same other than just this step here of choosing Java 17 and then click
next and then click next again.
And here we're going to name our program.
Well, we're going to name our project.
Hello, world.
I'm naming mine with what's called Camel Case, where the the first letter of each word is uppercase
and there's no space between the words.
So H and W are capitalized and there's no space there.
This is a common convention in Java for naming things not absolutely necessary for the project name
because that's not technically part of the program, but still pretty typical to do and then click finish.
And so what's happened there is that the I.D. will have created a new folder on your computer somewhere
on my Mac, it's in my home directory under a directory called Idea Projects and then under a new folder
called Hello World on Windows.
I'm not sure where it will put them, but it doesn't really matter.
OK, let's see.
So we are ready to start creating our program.
If for some reason this left a project pane isn't open on your computer and your screen might look something
like this, if it does, you can hit on Mac Command one to open that on on Windows and Linux Alt one
to open and close this project tab so that toggles open and closed with Alt one or command one.
OK.
You're going to go down here to source and you can right click on.
I'm sorry, you're going to go down here to where it says SIRC.
That stands for source.
That's short for source code, which means the code that we are writing.
This is where all of your code files here that you're going to create to make your program will will
go.
So you can right click on that folder and then select new and then Java class.
And here we will have to name a new file, a new Java class that we're going to create Java class and
file are typically pretty much synonymous.
So here we're going to name our Java class file Hello world again.
Same as the project, so capital H.
Capital W. No space between the words hello and world and make sure you've got class selected here.
If it if it wasn't for some reason and then hit return.
OK.
And so we've now created our first Java class file.
Now I'm going to kind of zip through this real quick, but you can follow along, so I'm going to create
a new line and I prefer to use keyboard shortcuts for as much as I possibly can.
So you won't see me spending a lot of time going up into the menus.
I will try to remember to state what those menu items are, but I strongly, strongly, strongly encourage
you to get very familiar and comfortable with the keyboard shortcuts.
This course isn't just to teach you Java, it's it's to teach you to be an excellent Java developer,
and part of that is learning your tools well, and part of it is getting proficient and fast with using
your tools.
So keyboard shortcuts are a big part of that.
OK, so I'm going to create a new line after line one, and I'm going to do that by hitting shift and
return.
And that creates a new line.
And then we need to create what's called a method here.
And there is a standard method.
So I'm not going to go into a lot of detail on on why we do all of these things in this video.
Let's just get this program written in and get it running.
And then in a subsequent video, we'll come back to it and I will explain in detail every single aspect
of this program, OK?
So we're going to type P s v, which stands for public static void main and then hit return, and that
expands out into what is called a method.
Lines two through four.
And then it puts our cursor right in the middle of that message so that we're ready to start typing
our first statement or command.
OK, and here we're going to do another little shortcut, a little macro s o u t and then hit return
again.
And that expands out into system that out that print line, which is generally pronounced print line.
And then we're going to type one quotation mark.
But that expands out into two quotation marks automatically by the ADP and puts our cursor in the middle
of them, and then we can type Hello World just like that.
OK.
And congratulations, you've just written your first program in Java here.
And now we just want to run it now.
I don't mean to overwhelm, but there's a million ways to run this thing.
Of course, I'm going to prefer to use the keyboard shortcuts, but let me quickly just tell you all
the ways that you can do this.
So you can run this by clicking on this little green play button here and selecting Run, which is telling
the idea to run this method, which is called main.
OK.
Or you could click on this higher green play button and choose to run the whole entire class.
Or you could go up here to run menu and and select run here.
But the way that I'm going to do it is just to do the keyboard shortcut control shift.
Ah, and down here the lady is calling Java to build our project.
So it took a few seconds there, but it did build and then it ran it after it was finished building.
And now we have the words Hello world down here in this little console.
Now, just to make sure that that's not some weird trick.
Let's come back into line three and add a little bit more now you can feel free to put whatever words
you want in here.
It doesn't matter.
It's just that's why we have it in quotes, because the computer is simply going to print whatever we
pass in.
To those the quotes there, I'm going to add in a little more and say something like, Hello world.
Nice to meet you.
OK, in this time, I'll run it, I don't know.
I'll use the top play button here just to mix it up a little bit.
So that's building again.
And after a second, there we go.
Hello, world, karma.
Nice to meet you.
OK, so that just ran our first program, and that's the end of this lesson.
So in the next two lessons, I'm going to give you a little bit of background on the nature of Java,
the language and its and what type of language it is.
And then we will do a slightly deeper dive into every nook and cranny of this short program.
I will make sure that you understand what every key word means in this entire program.
So I'll meet you in the next video.