All right, next up, we're going to learn how to use the strip and trim methods, these methods exist
to allow us to remove any white space from the beginning or the end of a string.
There are perhaps a few reasons why you might want to do this, but one of the most common reasons would
be a situation where you're allowing a user to enter some text like you're asking the user in a program,
what's your first name or your password or something like that?
And you want to ensure that regardless of whether or not the user may have intentionally or accidentally
entered some spaces before they started typing, the real thing that they mean to type in, you just
get rid of those spaces.
So if you ask them for their name and their name is Jake, and they accidentally or intentionally hit
the spacebar a couple of times, for example, before they typed the word, the letter J.
You could just get rid of the extraneous space.
This is good because you want your inputs.
You want your data to be normal.
And typically, you wouldn't be expecting spaces in something like a string holding the first name.
That space could inadvertently affect other things that you do in the code later on, where you're checking
for comparisons of text that they entered or things like that.
So let's take a look at how to do this in the idea of cleared out the previous code that we had, and
we, as usual, will go ahead and create a another variable.
Let's call it first name since I used that example.
Let's create a string and let's go ahead and put some some space in here and call it Jake.
And I'll even put some trailing space.
So the the space in the beginning of this string is called leading space, and then the space at the
end of the string is called trailing space.
OK, so we're going to pretend like these are accidents.
All right.
Oops.
Let's do our trusty print line.
Actually, the you know what?
Let's use a different version of this.
Let's do the format, which we have seen before.
And the reason I want to do this is because, well, here will first build our format string.
And we'll pass in the first name, so that will just print out the first name that is entered.
However, I want to surround that by single ticks.
So that way it's easier for us to see the spaces.
And if you don't know what I mean, you'll see in just a moment here.
So if we run this, OK, so now we have these single ticks, and so it makes it easy for us to see the
spaces where they begin and end.
If I didn't have those ticks there, you wouldn't necessarily it wouldn't be as easy to to distinguish
that.
OK, so we've got that.
So now we'll use the first of our split methods here, and that is just the simple lobster strip method.
So we'll use the first of our strip methods here, which is just this basic one here with no inputs.
And so if we run this now.
You can see that it has removed the leading and the trailing spaces just as we would want, and that's
very straightforward.
Now the there are two other variations of the strip method, and we'll take a look at those.
So there's a strip leading.
And oops, got too many parentheses there.
And what this does is it just it only removes the leading space and doesn't touch the trailing space,
so the the plain old just strip method all by itself.
This one here removes both the leading and the trailing.
The strip leading only removes the leading, and we'll just take a look at that real quick.
OK, so we have no leading space, but we do have the trailing.
And then there's the opposite of this one that removes the trailing space and just for good measure.
We'll take a look at that one as well, and we'll run this and see.
There you go.
So now we have the trailing.
We have the leading space, but we don't have the trailing space.
So those are pretty self-explanatory.
And there's one more strip method that is a little bit less obvious.
And honestly, it's going to be a little difficult to to show in the air, but I will explain it.
So there's one more strip method here, which is strip indent.
Now this one is special, and to show you how it works, I need to make the string literal here a little
different.
So let me explain this real quick.
So with newer versions of Java, I honestly don't remember what version they came out with.
This in mind might have been 13 or 15, I can't remember.
But in more recent versions of Java, Java now supports what are called text blocks or a multi line
strings, which is a capability that some other languages have had for a long time.
But Java took a very long time to get it.
And so we can make a multi line string.
So so far, the only strings I've been making programmatically here have been these single line strings
where it's just one line of of text or whatever.
But we can do loops.
If I, I'll just delete that.
And if I want to make a multi line string that is a string with text across multiple lines.
Instead of using a quotation mark, I will use three quotation marks just like this one to three.
And then the idea automatically puts me on a new line with the cursor here and then is waiting for me
to start typing something.
So I can go ahead and put a semicolon here if I like, and I'm going to make a new line right above
that and I'll even kind of indent in here.
And so I can say something like first line here.
Second line here.
I'm just hitting return.
Third, the third line here.
OK.
So this is a multi line string or a text block.
I think the official term is text block.
OK.
And the reason for this is because it's super convenient and looks easy to read when you want to have
a more complex string holding multiple lines of text.
You could do this without multi-line strings or text blocks.
Let me show you real quick what that looks like, but it's kind of messy.
You can do something like, oops, here's a well, actually, I guess I can see.
First.
Line here.
Second line here.
Third line here.
So the idea is is being very nice and understanding that since I'm hitting enter inside of a string
that it should close that string, give me a plus sign and then put me on the new line and give me a
new string to start typing.
And so the idea is making this relatively convenient for me.
But there is a little more noise in this.
You've got all these quotation marks and then you have to join them all together.
OK, so this would be somewhat equivalent.
But then the next problem is that if I want to format this like I wanted this line to be indented and
I want that line to be indented as well.
I don't know, you just start getting a lot of stuff in here.
So when you want to do something like a multi-line string here in more recent versions of Java, it's
probably nicer to just use a text block.
Like so.
That's just nicer to see.
And then if you want to indent some of the lines or whatever, you can do that as well.
So a couple of places where you might sometimes want to do this is that if you wanted to write some
code that spits out code, write like spits out something that looks like code and doesn't have to be
Java code, it could be like HTML.
If you're familiar with HTML standards at all, you know, might look something like that.
Oops.
Here's a div look, div block.
Right.
And so you'd want that to be formatted and nice looking and everything and.
Oops!
And the spit that out.
OK, all right, so I've explained text blocks and multi-line text only so that I could now jump into
explaining the strip indent method.
So the strip indent method, what it does, it allows the entire text block to go as far to the left
as it possibly can while retaining all of the relative white spaces.
And that might not make sense to you, but I can't.
Unfortunately, I can't easily show it to you in the air because Intel is actually basically does this
automatically.
It strips out the leading spaces, especially in a text block.
But if I had indented this HTML line here like that, let's say, and let's say, I also invented this
one even further.
And let's pretend like this one.
This third line was lined up with the first line here, but I had all of this space here.
So the strip indent method would remove all of this leading space here.
And if this third line was lined up here as well, it would remove that leading space too.
But it would keep this space starting from here.
OK, so just get rid of all the extraneous spaces leading, but it would retain the relative indentation
between all of the individual lines.
OK.
So just kind of takes the whole block and shifts it over.
All right.
Unfortunately, that I can't really show you that because the ad is already doing that.
For me, this line here shows that no matter, regardless of the fact that there's all this space here,
the ad is actually going to strip out all of this space.
So I could really just put this all back.
Just like that.
So again, this line here is just showing that the aid is already stripping out all of that space for
us.
And therefore, the strip indent method here isn't really going to do anything anyway, but that's what
that method does.
All right.
So.
So that's that.
Now let me talk about the other versions of methods for stripping tax.
I'll put some space back in here again.
OK, so there's another method that can do pretty much the same thing, and that is the trim method.
OK?
And the trim method is actually older than the strip methods, but it does the same thing.
We'll we'll run this.
It does pretty much the same thing.
So we'll run this real quick and see.
OK, so there you go.
So we're still getting Jake without the spaces with the trim method.
So then what's the difference between trim and split?
Well, just as one of the other text manipulation methods that we learned a little bit ago, the difference
here is that Java has newer, slightly more improved methods.
Split is what you should be using from now on if you're coding in a version of Java that supports it.
However, in older versions of Java, Split didn't exist, and you had no choice but to use the trim
method.
If you wanted that convenience, you could write these yourself.
Of course, as well.
So the difference, though, is that the trim method is less aware of all of the ways that white space
can be encoded in different regions around the world and in different alphabets and character sets and
things like that.
So as I mentioned in the previous lesson, there is a notion of white space that could be different
depending on what language and characters you're using, and the trim method is not very intelligent
about those differences.
Whereas the split methods are much more aware of all of the different ways in which the world's character
in coatings may have white space.
So that's the real difference.
But the bottom line is, if you have the split methods available to you, you should prefer to use those
only use trim if you have no other choice.
OK, so now that you've learned about the split and trim methods, I think you have learned enough of
the basics here with text manipulation and things that you may be able to write your own very basic
split method yourself.
Now, of course, your split method won't exist on the string class because that would require you to
either write your own string class or extend it or something like that, and you don't necessarily have
to get that fancy.
But what we could do as a challenge is simply introduce a static method on the learned strings class
that can split the leading and trailing spaces off of a string.
And then we it will take a string as input and it will output a cleaned up string.
OK.
So in fact, I'll even show you the signature of the method that I have in mind here, so you could
do something like public static.
String.
Split.
Something like this.
OK, now you fill in the blanks.
Can you write a little bit of code that would take an input of a string?
I'm calling the argument here text, but you can call it whatever you like.
It takes this input.
It strips off the leading and trailing spaces and then returns the cleaned up string as the output.
Why don't you pause the video and take a moment and see if you can work that out and then we'll do it
together to see if you've got it?
I'll see you in a few.
OK, so let's see how you did.
I'm going to go ahead and implement this, as I might really do.
And you know, we're just trying to do a simple version here.
We're not trying to be overly fancy with it.
So what you could probably do is something very simple.
First, you'll you'll want to return something.
So I would just take the text.
I would just use the replace method.
And let's see.
I think I would just go with a string here.
So I'm going to just put one string with one space in there just like that comma.
And then I'm going to put an empty string as the thing it should replace that with.
Just like this, so in other words, find all the places where there's a space character and replace
it with nothing with an empty string.
OK, so no space.
No, nothing.
All right.
And then return that.
So we can try this out now, the way to try this out would be to get rid of this trim method, call
on the string itself and instead we now will call this split method here.
We have to kind of invert the way we're calling things now because we're using our split method.
So I wrap that inside of a parentheses and then close this.
OK, so does that make sense where we're taking the first name variable here and we're passing it into
our split method?
OK.
So by the way, yes, you can name methods the same as other method names as long as there's some difference
there.
And the difference here is that our split method lives on the line strings and it's static.
And the split method you learned previously lives on the string class itself, and it's not static.
OK, so those are considered by Java to be two completely different methods, even though they have
the same name.
They have completely different signatures than they live on different classes.
All right, so let's see if this works.
Hey, look at that.
It does work.
OK.
So this shows that, you know, we could implement a very simple split method.
Now, this split method isn't perfect.
It's a poor man's split method.
There are some issues with it, such as if we used any other types of whitespace besides the space bar,
which is what we've encoded here.
This wouldn't work.
OK.
So if we do use tabs or other white space from other languages or locales or something like that, then
this would not work.
We'd have to write a more extensive method that was smarter and look for all the different types of
white spaces that there could possibly be and then replaced them.
And, you know, we don't need to get that fancy.
One other thing you may be wondering is why did we have to make this static, OK?
So if you recall back to the lesson on static methods, I will state that our program is running inside
of a static method main here, and we're not creating an instance of the learn string this method.
So if you recall, I taught that methods can be static or non static.
If a method is non static, then it can only be used inside of an instance of a class.
But in this program, we're not creating an instance of the class.
We're just writing code directly in the static void main method.
So to keep the code relatively simple, because I did not want to have to create an instance of a class,
I chose to create the new split method static as well.
Because static methods can be called and executed without creating an instance of a class.
And when I say creating an instance of a class, I just mean, I didn't want to have to do something
like, oops.
All of this.
Just so I could then call some kind of like split method or blah blah blah.
Right?
I didn't want to have to do all of that.
It could have, but not necessary.
All right, so that's the reason why this is static.
All right.
So anyway, if you were able to get that awesome and if you weren't.
No worries.
Like I've said a million times already, we'll get plenty more opportunities to to try different challenges
and and you can try challenges for yourself as well.
And so with that, we're going to in this lesson and I'll see you in the next one.