This is an addendum lesson on how to use the newest features of the Switch statement in Java version
17 or JDK 17 in JDK 17.
They have added a sneak preview feature, if you will.
And I want to show you how you can use these features and how you can turn them on as well.
So what I have here is another little class you don't necessarily need to follow along with me, but
you're welcome to copy what I have here.
I just want to show you these features very quickly.
So what I have here is a number of variables that I've created labeled VAR one through five.
I've also created basically a class.
This is a preview that I'm showing you here.
You will learn how to make this, although it's pretty straightforward.
Just know that this thing here.
Record person is basically a class.
It's just a very, very lightweight class, and you will learn this in a later lesson.
So I'm defining a class that models a person with a first name, last name and an age.
OK.
And I'm just doing it here in line because I just wanted to keep everything concise for this lesson.
So let me explain the scenario here.
I've got these variables defined of different data types like here's a string, an integer, a string
array and then a couple of people.
And what I'd like to be able to do is to assign to this OBJ variable any one of these variables up here.
So for example, right now in line 10, I'm assigning VAR one to OBJ, but I could assign VAR to or
VAR five or whatever, right?
And then I'd like to be able to basically test certain characteristics of the object being pointed to
by by OBJ and have some outcome occur.
So for example, if OBJ is a string, then I would like to be able to print out that string with its
message if OBJ is an integer.
Then I'd like to be able to say, Hey, this is a number, and here's your number.
If OBJ is something of type person and that person's first name's length is greater than three, then
print out, it looks like we're talking about Jake and so on and so forth.
Right.
So this ability to do this is called pattern matching and a number of modern languages do have some
capability like this.
Java might be a little late to the party in getting it.
And so what the creators of Java have done is they've enabled an implementation and attempt at implementing
pattern matching with switches.
So they've made it available as a preview feature.
And so in order to get rid of these red squiggles, we have to enable this preview feature.
OK, so first thing, I want to show you how to do that.
Now this is assuming you're running Java version 17 or later now by version eighteen, they may have
gone ahead and enabled this by default, and therefore you won't need to do anything because it'll just
be there.
But as of right now, the current version of Java is 17.
So to enable the pattern matching preview in version 17 of Java.
First of all, let me open up the project pane.
Like so and and then I will highlight the people project here, and then I can right click on it and
go down to.
Open module settings, or you can do a command down.
All right.
And then from here, you need to click on Project and assuming you have version 17, install Java Version
17 installed, which you should.
This should be set.
But down here we can get a little more specific with what types of functionality we want to utilize
in Java version 17.
And so if you click on this dropdown box here, you'll see that there are preview features that you
can enable.
And so all you need to do is simply select that OK and then click Apply and then OK.
And now those red squiggles go away because now the ID understands this syntax.
All right, so I'm going to give myself a little room here by closing the project pane on the left.
All right.
And so now we can play around with these features a little bit.
So currently I'm setting up a two bar one.
And so that should cause this case to run.
Let's confirm that.
Yeah, there we go.
So print it out.
Hello, world.
And we'll just run through these.
So then if I set the bar, if I said OBJ to bar two and we'll run that.
Yeah, there we go.
So now we're getting a different output.
Your number is and then it's actually showing the number.
So the way that this is working is that not only is the case statement matching on the data type of
the object or OBJ variable, it's also giving us a local variable that we can use to refer to whatever
this was that was passed in.
OK, so we're basically saying if OBJ is of type string, then let me refer to OBJ by the name message
so that I can use it over here.
Now you might be wondering, that's kind of weird.
How come we're not just calling it OBJ, right?
The reason we're not calling it OBJ is because the variable OBJ is of type object, which is a highly
generic data type, right?
And so if I were to refer to OBJ directly down in here, I might not be able to access fields and methods
that are specific to whatever the real data type is.
And here's a good example on line 14, we're saying that if OBJ is a type person, then let's start
calling it P instead of OBJ.
And if p dot first name dot length is greater than three.
So this first name dot length would not be available to us if we were just referring to this as OBJ.
And let me show you, in fact, what happens if if I were to even try that, OK, so I will rename this
local P variable to Obi J.
Like so.
And first off, the aid doesn't like it because this is considered a different variable, right?
So it says here variable, it is already defined in the scope, which is this telling us that I've already
got an object up here, right?
So that's one reason I can't do that.
Now the other thing is, if I were to maybe like, get rid of this bit here, then it all starts to
break down because now I'm no longer doing the pattern matching right.
So the way that this pattern matching works is that I am specifying a data type in this particular case,
at least with the pattern matching, I'm specifying a data type.
Which is person?
And then I can also declare a local variable name of that specific data type.
And then I can start using it over here.
So I can't call this OBJ because this OBJ, which is of type object, is already taken.
So you almost can think of the local type down here.
It's really a whole new variable.
OK.
All right, so I'm just going to undo that little change there.
OK, so the other thing to notice here is that as part of my pattern matching down here on Line 14,
not only am I able to use the Switch statement to say, basically if OBJ is of type person, then create
a new variable that refers to its data as, and call it P.
I am also able to add another case to this test.
I'm able to say not only do I want to know if it's of type person, but if it is, then I also want
to be able to test whether or not some property or some properties have some value, right?
So in this case, I'm able to drill in deeper and say if the first name of P if the length of the first
name of P is greater than three.
Then finally, do all of this.
OK, so that's some pretty advanced functionality there.
And that's what you really get with this pattern matching.
OK, and then one other scenario I want to show you here, I think I touched on it in the previous lesson
or the one before that where I said that one downfall of switch statements in Java traditionally is
that they don't handle null.
OK, so if you have null here with the traditional switch implementation, you couldn't say something
like case null.
Like what if the what if the thing is null?
Well, with this preview implementation, you can actually do that.
And the way that we can do that is actually we can come down here and have another case.
And by the way, this bit here, this having this word case here is actually optional.
I didn't need that.
But if I want to be able to say something like for all other cases, just do the default, including
null, including null, I can do this case null, comma default.
So now I'm able to say if it's null or just not any of these things here, then do this, then do this
last bit.
And by the way, I can actually put that case null on its own line as well.
I could also just do this.
It's no.
And then I can get rid of that bit.
There.
OK, so you can do either of those, you can combine the null in the default case in one, as I did
earlier, or you can pull it out into its own separate thing.
All right.
So let's just run that just to prove it real quick.
There you go.
So it's null and then over here, I could do a double.
OK, so there's a double there.
And now if I run this, we should get the default.
Yeah.
I have no idea.
Right.
All right.
So that's all I wanted to show in this lesson.
This is really some pretty powerful stuff that they've added.
But again, I just want emphasize this is as a version 17.
This is still a preview feature.
So if you work at a company and you want to utilize this, you would have to enable this functionality
on the JDK as a switch statement.
If you'll notice here when I'm actually running the program or when the app is running the program,
it's actually throwing this enable preview switch on here.
And you or the people who administer the application servers where Java is actually installed and configured
would have to go in and actually enable this functionality in order for you to be able to use these
things OK.
Or if you're using Docker, which we might touch on what Docker is a little later you'd have to remember
to enable your JVM with this capability.
OK.
So you won't be able to do these things out of the box with current version in Java 17, maybe as of
Java 18 possibly.
All right.
That's going to wrap up this lesson.
See in the next one.