All right, so in this lesson, we are going to take a look at how to perform some sorting or ordering
of our objects using the Streams API, because that's some of the functionality that we played with
in the previous Collections module.
So turning back to our code base here and we're still in the streams stuff class.
So first thing we'll do is let's just try sorting these objects, sorting these employees by the the
salary, OK?
So luckily enough, as you might have imagined, the Streams API has built in support for ordering our
objects.
So the first question is where might we want to stick and ordering function?
Call right where in this pipeline?
So if we think about this for a moment, the line's method here is just breaking.
This is just breaking out the individual lines of this string.
I suppose that could be one place where we could do some, some, some sorting, perhaps some ordering,
perhaps.
But since we want to order them by the by the salary, we wouldn't have the salary data available to
us at that point because at that point, it's just text, right?
The salaries are getting calculated after these text lines become actual objects of type employee,
right?
That's when we are actually able to calculate the salary.
So that wouldn't do us a whole lot of good to try to order them after this line, after the lines call
here.
Let's see then next line thirty eight is where we are converting the text lines into employee's, right?
Uh, and then after that we're taking those employees and we are converting them into integers so that
they can be summed up.
So I think we don't have a lot of choices here.
It looks to me like the place to order them would be right after line.
Thirty eight.
Does that make sense?
All right.
So I'm going to put a new line in here and a period, and we've got a method here called sorted.
And if you look down this list, we've actually got a couple of them, one that doesn't take any inputs
and then another one that does.
Let's let's take a quick look at what this one does for sorted with no inputs.
I'm going to select that.
So if I hover over this, we see that it returns a stream of whatever.
So in other words, it's still going to just return back a string of employees just like we're getting
out of line thirty eight.
So that's good.
And it returns a stream consisting of the elements of the stream sorted according to the natural order.
So we should now know what that means.
It means that as long as the objects that are in that stream implement the comparable interface which
ours do, then it's just going to sort them according to whatever that comparable interfaces is being
implemented to do, right?
So that's fairly straightforward.
So let's just see here real quick.
I'm going to just run this now.
And we can already kind of see here it does look like it's in alphabetical order right now, notice.
We've we've got these duplicate Fred Flintstones here currently.
So we've got a lot of we got a lot of bang for the buck just by using the sorted here.
But just recall now that's only working as well as it is because the employee class happens to be implementing
a comparable.
Now what if?
What if it were not implementing comparable or what if we wanted to override the sort order that our
comparable implementation is, is is implementing, then in that case, we'd use the other sorted method
that takes an input.
And if we hover here, the other version takes an instance of our familiar comparator interface, right?
So we've learned how to do this as well.
And we know that we could satisfy this input with a lambda expression or within anonymous class, right?
We could do either of those in just for grins.
Will will flesh a little bit of that out for a moment.
So we'll do this with a lambda.
So if you'll recall, the comparator interface has a method on, in fact, here we don't have to recall,
we'll just go there and take a look.
All right.
So here we are in the comparator interface and we know that it has a method on it called CP. That takes
two objects to generic objects for input and then returns an integer expected to be negative one, zero
or one so that it can know if the two objects are equal or one is less than or greater than the other,
right?
And we get to decide, you know, how all of that works.
But that's just a quick refresher on how comparator and the compare method work.
OK.
So knowing that then we can supply this sorted method with a lambda expression that takes those two
objects, right?
So we'll refer to them as, I don't know, X and Y.
Then we'll use our arrow and then what we would need to do is to compare something.
So in this case, we want to compare the salaries.
The salaries are primitive integers, right?
So you know that we cannot just do something like X that good salary dot compare because there is no
compare method because primitives don't have methods, right?
However, we can use the wrapper integer class, which has a compare method on it, and we can pass
these guys in this way.
X that get salary, comma y don't get salary like so, and then we need to close that.
And so now if we run this, let's see what we get.
Yep, now they appear to be sorted by salary, right?
OK, cool.
So that works now, as you may recall, if we wanted to do something a little more involved, though
like sort.
According to multiple fields, right?
So right now we're only sorting on one field, which is salary.
What if we wanted to sort?
First on last name, then first name and then salary, right?
That would get more involved.
And we couldn't really do that easily with the lambda expression in this way.
Right.
We'd have to have like a block of code where we kind of be nesting down.
We've played with that a little bit previously.
Now I want to show you an easier way to do this, though.
There is actually some help in Java for doing exactly this use case and what we can do, it's actually
the easiest thing that we could possibly do.
In fact, what we can do is will clear this out and there is a static method on the comparator class
called comparing.
So I can actually refer to it by simply starting to type lowercase lower column.
And the idea already knows where I'm where I'm heading and it beats me to the punch, so to speak,
so to speak.
So we've got various static methods on the comparator class that are all based on this basic idea of
comparing.
And so let's say that we wanted to sort by last name and then first name.
OK.
So what we can do is we can first reference this comparing.
Now look at what this comparing method takes.
It actually takes a function function.
Here again is just an interface that has one method on it.
It's a functional interface that has one method on it that takes one input of a class, and then it
returns an output of another class.
It could be the same type of class, by the way, but it doesn't have to be.
It's it can be a different class.
OK, so it takes one input, one output.
Here's some cool stuff, though.
Now that we've learned about method references, we can do something pretty interesting here.
So.
So let me back up and just say again, we're wanting to sort these employees by the first name and last
name, right?
Well, there's a couple of things we're going to need to do if we want to be able to do that.
So, so let's see what happens here if I reference the comparing method here.
What I can do is I can pass into it something called a key extractor now.
I know this may start to look kind of complicated, but it's actually pretty straightforward.
What it's looking for here is for me to essentially give it a method reference to a method that returns
a field that we want to sort by.
OK.
So for example.
If I reference the I employee, Colin Colin, get salary, there's a method reference right there,
so I'm telling it to sort by salary.
That's what I'm doing there now.
In this scenario, though, what I kind of laid out is I want to now be able to sort by two fields,
the last name and then the first name right now.
Unfortunately, right now, I can only use method references that refer to methods that are declared
on the I employee interface.
And as you may recall, the I Am employee interface does only specifies the get salary method.
So if I wanted to be able to sort by last name and first name, I cannot use a method reference to refer
to those fields to those methods.
From the I employee interface, I need to make references to the employee interface.
And we've now learned that I can't just do this because, well, if I hover over it, we get this familiar
method.
Non static method cannot be referenced from a static context.
In other words, the output of Line 38 is a stream of employees.
And now I'm referencing something of type employee and it just isn't going to work that way.
So one way for me to work around this would be first to remap the stream of I am employee to a stream
of employees, right?
And that's easy enough to do.
Do you want to think of how to do that?
Would you want to take a moment and see if you can figure out how to map the stream of AI employees
to a stream of employees?
Why don't you take a moment?
OK, so now I'm going to do this, so what we can do is we know that the output of Line Thirty Eight
is a stream of AI employees.
And so I want to just convert that to a stream of employees.
So what we can do is just another map.
All right.
Now, I don't think off the top of my head.
I don't think there is a fancy method reference way to do this because really what I want to do is just
cast.
So I'm going to use a lambda to do this.
OK, so I will refer to the individual instances of I employee that are coming out of line.
Thirty eight out of the stream of Line thirty eight.
I'll refer to those as EE.
Then I'll use my arrow here and then I'm just going to cast.
So I'm going to cast these AI employees to employees just like that.
And now and so now we're going from a stream of AI employees to a stream of employees.
And now down here, the sorted method is taking as an input a stream of employees.
And now we can easily access the last name and first name in all of those guys, right?
And the way we can do that is right here.
Right?
So instead of calling this now, we can call.
But we got one more problem here.
I never actually implemented getters and setters for the first name and last name, so now we need to
take a quick detour and actually go implement those.
Finally, after all of these lessons where we've just been kind of skirting that issue, right?
So we'll jump into the employee class here.
And let's see here, I'm going to scroll down.
Oh, let's see, maybe two around here.
And generate those real quick with a with a command in getter and setter.
And now I only want to do this for the last name and the first name, so I'm I just held down on the
shift.
So what I did was I selected the last name and then I held down on shift and then selected the first
name field.
So those are the only two that I care to do this for at this time.
And then I will click, OK, and there we go.
Now finally, we've got a we've got getters and setters for the first name and last name.
And then I'm going to do an option command left Arrow to go back or control all left arrow and I'll
go back again.
OK.
And so now if I put my cursor after that, g that I started to type in, forget and do a control space.
There we go.
And now I've got access to the get last name.
And so now we can sort by the last name.
Now one quick thing here, because this comparing method is a static method.
I actually can get rid of the comparator dot bit here by just selecting that and deleting.
And now I can do what's called a static import, which I believe we did learn before.
That'll just import the this method statically so that I don't have to pretend it with its class size
so I can save a little space.
So I'll just put my cursor at the end of the word comparing there, and I can do an option return and
then choose import static method java util comparator comparing.
There we go.
Just like that and what that results in is there it is on line nine import static, blah blah blah comparing.
So just save a little bit of space.
That's the only reason I did that.
All right.
So we've got the last name I want now.
I also want to have a secondary sort order, though, by the first name, and we've learned many lessons
that go in another module that that was a little more involved because you kind of had to do some nested
conditional where you said, basically, if the last name is less than then, that's cool.
If it's greater than and that's cool.
But if they're equal, then come down to another level of nesting and then compare the first names,
right?
So that that code got a little involved.
Watch this though, with this new comparing static method here, we can actually string together additional
levels of sorting order.
So what I can do here now is put a period right after this closing quotation mark, and then I can choose
this fancy additional static method then comparing.
So this is allowing me to kind of do that nested bit here really, really nicely, really concisely
and easily, right?
So I can just choose then comparing and now I use this the same way that I used comparing.
I just use another method reference and refer to some other field so I could refer to employee dot employee
get first name.
And now I'm comparing the first names, right?
Secondarily.
And guess what else?
I can keep going with this.
So in fact, let me clean this up just a little bit, though I don't want to go too far out to the side
there, and I'm kind of backing up the the indentation there.
And let's say I want to add in the salary as well.
I can do that then comparing employee get salary.
Isn't that nice?
So concise and easy to read, right?
I don't have to write any logic and nothing of the logic and all of that business, right?
I can just get right down to it.
And now to prove that this will actually work, let's just run it and see.
All right, what do we have here?
Yeah, they look like they are still in Alpha.
They look like they are back into alphabetical order and we've got a bunch of Fred Flintstones right
here.
And so now if we look at the salaries we can see, yes, the salaries are in ascending order as well.
So I think that's working.
All right, cool.
Now one other thing you may have noticed when we were selecting these additional methods, like the
then comparing if I put my cursor here in hover, you'll see that there are other versions of the then
comparing and I actually of the comparing method as well.
There's then comparing end and double and long.
You may have kind of wondered what are those all about?
That gets into the natural versus lexical graphic ordering of computers.
I've mentioned this once before that by default, the natural ordering that we tend to get from computers
is not actually what we humans would normally consider to be natural at all.
In the sense that the number 10 expressed as a string would actually be would actually come before the
number two in so-called natural ordering because the one in the 10 comes comes before the two, right?
And so that ordering isn't natural.
However, if we use these numeric, these numerical aware versions of the comparing methods, then they
will sort in what humans would consider to be a more natural ordering, if you will.
OK.
So if you want numbers to show up truly in order consistently, you probably will prefer to use the
specific numerical comparing methods here, depending on whatever the data type is.
In our case, the salaries are integers, so we can very well just use the then comparing and just like
so I don't know that we're going to see any difference, though, because in this case, these numbers
are all pretty clear and straightforward anyway.
But we'll go ahead and run this just so you can see.
Yeah, there we go.
All right.
Let's see.
And then let's say that we wanted to reverse the order right of our listings here, we can easily do
that.
So what we can do there is just stick a keyword on the end of our little internal comparing chain here,
Dot reversed.
Just like that, and then we'll run this again.
So currently, we've got Fred Flintstone coming up first, right?
Now, Fred Flintstone at the bottom, though, and at the top we've got Barney rubble, so it's being
printed out in reverse order.
OK, so pretty straightforward.
So you can see now how much easier it can be to sort objects or data within our stream here.
So now let me just make make it clear what is this comparing method actually doing?
How is it actually working right?
So if you'll recall, the sorted method itself takes as an input, simply a comparator.
So what this comparing method is doing this static method here is it builds a comparator for us, right?
Our competitor was doing something like, let's see, we had the the lambda there.
Expedite get whatever last name that compared to, why don't get last name?
Oops, I forgot my parentheses there.
OK, so that's you know, how you might have done just the last name comparisons with a lambda expression
that will in turn implement a comparator right.
So what this comparing is doing is it's basically taking a pattern like this, but temple of teasing
it, if you will.
It's getting down to just the most essence of what we actually care about, which in this case is just
this bit right here, right?
The last names.
And so it's allowing us to kind of skip the whole entire boilerplate and just specify just the method
of the data, the just the method that that refers to the data that we actually care about.
And we're doing it with a method reference right here, right?
So you can kind of imagine that underneath the hood of this comparing static method here, you've got
the code equivalent of this, except that this bit here is kind of templated out, right?
It's able to be replaced by whatever we pass in here.
OK.
So that's kind of what's so that's essentially what's happening here.
And then they've got a more complex pattern that they're kind of taking in if you use the then comparing,
right?
So they've just written out the more complex code in a smart way and they are then temp and then they
are turning that into a template that allows us to plug in just the bits that we care about, which
in this case is just, you know, the field that we're trying to do.
And then when it's all said and done, the comparing method spits back out an instance of a comparator
which can be plugged into this sorted method here.
So that's that's essentially what's going on there.
It's really, really quite intelligent and look at how much more readable our code is now, right?
So in fact, before we wrap this up, let's just kind of read through this just to kind of drive home
the point of how much more readable code can be when we use the Stream's API, right?
So we take a line, we convert that line to an AI employee.
Then we converted again to an employee.
In fact, you can kind of see the hints over here.
Then we sort those employees first by last name, then by first name, then by salary, and then we
flip the order of all of that and then we convert all of those to integers while also printing them
out.
And then we take those integers and sum them all up and then we can print the sums, so it's just really,
really nice to be able to read the code so, so easily now, right?
You're not so much focused on how to write that code to extract these things here and all of this.
And instead, we're more focused on just what is it that we want to do.
It's more declarative.
OK, OK.
We're declaring what we want to do, but we're not so much focused on how we want to do it in terms
of writing all of the explicit code.
And that's kind of emblematic of this type of functional style of coding.
All right.
So we'll wrap this one up and I'll see you in the next one.