All right.
Welcome back.
So now that we have done a little bit of unit testing with something very basic, I'd like to do a couple
of things.
First, I would like to encourage you and challenge you to continue to flesh out the calculator code
that we already started with, so you can add in the ability to subtract, multiply and divide and think
of a few scenarios and add those tests to our test class.
So if you want to take up that challenge, you should probably go ahead and do that now before we move
in to the next thing.
All right.
Now I want to do something a little more interesting.
I want to revisit some of our ability to calculate using the big decimal class.
And I have found on some random websites somewhere some more financial calculations for us to do.
So what I would like to do next is to try doing that with this formula here.
This is a formula for calculating ordinary annuity or a sinking fund.
All right.
So we're going to do this though now in a two way.
So we'll start off writing a test based on the examples and practice answers that are given here.
And that way, we can confirm whether or not we've implemented the code correctly implementing code
in this way, where you're given a bunch of answers or a given set of inputs is fantastic and lends
itself exceedingly well to both TDD and just then testing in general.
So without further ado, let's jump right in.
All right, so let's see.
So we're going to be calculating ordinary annuity.
And by the way, technically you have learned everything that you probably need to know to be able to
work this out on your own.
So if you'd like to.
You certainly are more than welcome to pause the video and try implementing this formula on your own.
Otherwise, I'm going to go ahead and get started here.
All right.
So see, I'm going to create a new test public void and see here now.
I don't feel like thinking too much about the name of this, so I think I'm just going to call it annuity
example, and I'm just taking that name just from this example right here for now.
All right.
So the answer that I expect to get out of whatever this problem is, is something that looks like this.
And I think we now know how to format money and everything.
So I think I want this to be a string that I'm going to get back.
All right.
So I'm going to imagine that I'm going to have some method that I can call and I'm going to pass in
all of the given parts, the inputs and everything, and the output of it will be a string.
So then let's see.
What did they call this?
Well, I'm just going to call it answer answer equals calc dot.
Let's see here now.
Calculate annuity is what I will call the method.
And let's see now the givens are we've got a Joe deposits twenty two thousand dollars at the end of
each year for seven years.
All right.
So we've got twenty two thousand dollars in the in in recurring deposits.
Let's see.
And I think that's probably this are here.
Maybe that means recurring.
I don't know.
But anyway.
All right.
So I'm going to pass that in as a string, I suppose.
Twenty two thousand.
Now I'm going to use an unformed edge string for now.
All right.
So passes in twenty two thousand dollars at the end of each year for seven years.
OK, so we've got a period of seven years.
I guess I'm going to use an integer for that in an account paying six percent compounded annually.
All right, I'm going to pass that in as a string, I suppose.
Point zero six and compounded annually.
Let's see.
So the formula here, the R is probably this amount here.
Twenty two thousand the rate are I'm sorry, the big R is twenty two thousand.
The Little R is probably our interest rate or rate of growth, the end.
I think that would be called the compounding times or times for compounding something like that, which
in this case, it's compounded annually.
So that would be a one in this case.
And then the Ti would be the time, which is seven years.
OK, so let's see.
We've got the compounded annually.
So that would be a one, and I'll use an integer for that and then the time and I'll use an integer
for that as well, I suppose, which is a seven in this case.
All right.
So first.
I want to do is let the idea generate this method.
So I will put my cursor on it and then do an option return and tell it, yes, please create that method.
All right.
And yes, I want to return a string and I want to accept the string.
And this first value will be the I'm just going to use their variable names for now, which are not
good names for programming, but we can always refactor those names later.
So I'm going to use a Capital R and then the next thing we passed in was for seven years.
So that's the time which they're calling T lowercase T, so I will use that as well.
And then a string for the rate they use the lower case R for that.
So I will too.
And then oh, and then the times to compound or compounding times or something like that, which they
used then in lowercase in.
So I will too.
Now, I wouldn't always name my variables like this.
And in fact, I almost never would.
But I just don't feel like having to do a lot of mental gymnastics to translate between the terms that
are used in this formula and the terms that I'm using in the code, at least not right now.
I don't just I just don't feel like doing that at the moment.
Let's see.
Oh, and I'm missing something here and and I are time.
Great time.
Right?
Compound time.
And for some reason, I have an extra variable here.
I don't remember passing that in some just kind of hit return and see what's going on here with that.
Let's see if we go back here.
Oh, OK.
I referred to the time twice.
All right.
So I will get rid of that second one there.
Somehow, I managed to add in one too many parameters.
There we go.
Then I'll go back here and get rid of it.
All right.
And so now we can assert equals.
We will assert that we will receive a string with the value of 184 six six four 43 from the answer.
OK, so there's our first Test set up.
I want to jump back over here to the method real quick and just see.
So currently it's returning a null.
Let's see now we could return an empty string.
I am inclined to do at least that much.
But all right, so there's our empty string and then we can go back over here to our test.
All right, now, let's just run this test.
And in this case, I'm just going to run the test all by itself because this really has nothing to do
with the other calculations that we were doing before.
So let's run this.
All right, so that failed as we would expect.
We were expecting one hundred eighty four thousand and we got an empty string.
That's to be expected.
All right now, let's just go and implement this.
So we'll jump into the annuity calculation here.
And let's see.
So I'm going to make a new line at the top and let's just start breaking it down.
So over here, I'm looking for any patterns that I see first off and I see are over in here and I also
see it here.
So I am inclined to make one variable that represents, ah, over in.
So I'm going to make a big decimal.
Called a for lack of a better name for the term and big decimal equals new big decimal of R.
And that's little R, which is a string so I can simply pass it in like that divided by in which is
an integer.
Now, because that's an integer, I will need to encapsulate it in a big decimal.
So I will create a new big decimal like so and then use the constructor that takes an integer which
is in in this case.
All right.
Now I know that's a little hard to see.
Let me resize the windows a little bit here.
Maybe we don't need quite as much of that, and maybe we can get a little more of this.
There we go.
So there might be a little easier to to see what we're doing now.
OK, so that's our term are over in.
And now we need to make another term one plus are over and so same deal.
I'll call this B equals.
Let's see.
So for this will just do big decimal one, right?
Because that's a constant that exists on the big decimal class one.
And then we'll add a.
So that's our one plus our over in.
And then we need to take all of that and raise it to the end times T power.
So we'll make another big decimal, call it C and we will take B dot power and we will raise it to the
end times T. So now this method power, if you recall, just takes an integer directly.
So we don't need to wrap anything in a big decimal.
And in fact, that wouldn't even work if we tried to.
So we need to just pass in in times T, and I think we can literally do end times T just like that.
Nice and easy.
All right.
So now we've got the OnePlus R over in to the in times T power.
We've got all of that and now we need to take all of that and subtract one from it.
So that should be pretty easy.
We'll do another big decimal, so we'll call this D equals c subtract one.
So big decimal that one.
All right.
So now we have everything in the numerator of this internal bit here.
The whole thing.
And now we just need to divide all of that by R over in and we already have R over in as a so we can
just reuse that part.
So big decimal will make another variable e equals D, which is the whole entire numerator d divided
by a.
Because A is R over in, that's where we started our divided by end.
Yep.
All right.
So now we've got all of this and then all we have left to do is multiply all of that, which is e times
R, and that should be easy enough.
So a big decimal, we'll call this f and by coincidence, it happens to actually be called F here.
So that's nice.
All right.
And so we will simply do e multiply new big decimal of our.
Just like so of course, I could have done this the other way around, I could have done our multipli
e also, I could have done that.
I just didn't.
No reason it doesn't matter.
All right.
And then we want to format the answer as a North American currency.
So do you remember how to do that?
Do you want to pause it and see if you can remember?
All right.
So I'm going to do this now.
So we need a no format so we can do a number format, dot get currency instance because we're doing
money here and then I can do a command option V to capture that instance.
And I'm not even going to rename it.
I'm just going to use the default name currency instance.
And then on my return here, I will just refer to that currency instance dot format.
And then all I need to do is pass in our final big decimal, which was this ETH right here, f bam.
And that should format it into North American money now.
I will warn you that if you are watching this video on a computer in some place other than North America,
but you want that answer to turn out the way it looks here in this example, then you will want to explicitly
set your locale and you can do that by placing a cursor right here in the get currency instance.
Parentheses there and do a L for low cal.
And then you can actually select a locale such as us.
So you can do that if you want to force it to look exactly the way that it does.
In this example that I have found here, if you care, it doesn't matter really.
The the actual digits won't change.
Just the formatting of them will look different, depending on what locale you are in.
All right.
I think we're good there, and I don't even have to go back over to the test because we started off
by running this test.
So if I just click this play button that will rerun the test right now and we will see something.
Oh, and it failed.
All right.
Why did that fail?
So we expected one eighty four thousand six six four are interesting.
Oh, I had a typo in the test.
I put a comma where there should have been a decimal period, a decimal point.
It's a very minor problem there.
So let's go.
But yet there it is.
I put that comma in and I should have put a period period.
Look at that.
All right.
And so let's run it again.
Hey, there we go.
And we've got a winner.
All right.
So now we've got that first example working.
We got the exact same answer.
So now let's just plug in one or two other problems and make sure that this is really working.
So now let's see here, I will just copy all of this and then give myself some space based another one,
and I will call this annuity.
Let's see.
What did they call?
There's practice to practice two.
All right.
So for this one, Napolean deposits twelve hundred bucks.
So I'm going to do 1200 bucks at the end of each quarter for ten years.
So the time is ten in an account, paying eight percent.
So that would be point zero eight compounded quarterly.
So that would be a four four times per year rather than once per year, four times per year.
And the answer is supposed to be.
Seventy two thousand four hundred eighty two period and 38 cents.
Let's see if that's what we get.
And I'm going to run just this one test for free right now.
Hey, we got it all right now.
I might have mentioned earlier that it's actually a good idea to typically just rerun all of the tests
so that we can quote unquote regression test, make sure that we didn't regress or fall fall backward
in any of our previous functionality.
However, in this particular case, we had started to create this one test here using the edge case
scenario of a max, and we already know that that's not going to work.
Let's go ahead and run all the tests, though, and just see.
All right.
So I'm going up to the to the top of the class and I'm going to run this.
Click this test icon here to run all the tests in the class.
All right.
So as you can see, all the tests passed except for that edge case one now I've already indicated that
I'm not interested in trying to resolve this in any meaningful way in this module, but I will take
this time to show you something that you can do about this.
So first off, I just double clicked on this to zoom in on this method here.
Now, if you have a test that you don't want to delete, but you don't really want to deal with it right
now, there are a few things you can do.
You could go to the annotation for it.
You can then hit Enter and then add an additional annotation at disabled.
And so that can disable that particular annotation.
Let me close that.
So that allows you to disable that one test from running.
OK, now let me state something.
This is the latest version of G-Unit, which is G-Unit five.
I don't see a whole lot of point in not teaching the latest stable release of a technology.
However, should you go get a job somewhere?
There's a really good chance they may not be using J Unit five yet, especially if you get a job with
this knowledge in the year 2021.
And so I should also show you, or at least explain to you the alternative approach here.
So in versions of G-Unit prior to G-Unit Unit five, the most common way to do this would be to use
an annotation called at Ignore.
OK, so disabled and ignore will achieve the same thing.
So just know that if you're not, if you're in a version of G-Unit earlier than version five, you will
not be able to do a disabled.
You'll have to use at ignore.
OK.
All right.
So now if we rerun all the tests, we should get a clean bill of health, so to speak.
There we go.
All right.
And so both of our annuity examples worked and passed.
And we're going to go ahead and end this lesson and I will see you in the next one.