All right, and so now wrapping up our little tour of sequel, let's learn a few other techniques that
are quite useful to know.
So so far, we've learned how to create a table.
We've learned how to create records in that table.
We've learned how to read records from that table.
OK, so now we're going to learn how to update records and delete records.
So let's say that we've got Susan here and we want to change Susan's name to Sabrina, for example.
All right.
So what we can do then is use the update command.
Update the people table and set.
The first name.
Equal to Sabrina looks, Sabrina.
Where first name equals?
Susan, so what we're saying here is basically in the people table, go find any records, would that
have a first name of Susan?
And for that record, or those records set the first name filled to Sabrina?
So in effect, we're saying change Susan to Sabrina.
OK, so if we run this?
And then we re query the database.
And run that we now see that we have a Sabrina and there is no more Susan.
So we've just updated that one field and obviously we can use this basic update to update any particular
field of the database.
We can also update multiple records of the database.
Let me show you that real quick as well.
So let's say the Johnson family decides they want to change the spelling of their name so we can do
an update people set last name equal to, I don't know, Joanne.
So in how about that, where last name currently equals Joe H insulin?
OK, so let's run that and then let's query the database.
And so now we we see that we've changed all of the Johnson's in the database like so.
And then you could get fancier with this where clause.
Like, let's say that there were lots of Johnson's, but we didn't want to affect all Johnson's.
Maybe we only wanted to affect all Johnsons who were born between a certain period of time or something
like that.
We could we could do all of that as well.
And then let's also learn how to delete records.
So to delete a record, we actually just use the.
The delete command, so delete from people where and then we just have to tell it what we want to delete.
So if we wanted to delete this oddball over here, Jake, because he's not one of the Johnsons, why
would we want non Johnsen's in this table, right?
So we could get rid of him by any characteristic that distinguishes him apart from the rest of the Johnsons?
So perhaps last name so we can say where last name equals?
Smith.
And let's run that.
And then if we come up here and then query the database again.
There we go.
Smith is gone.
He's toast.
Now, obviously, you want to be super careful using the Delete Command in sequel, especially if you're
operating on corporate data.
Now, typically in any corporation or company that knows what it's doing, they're not even going to
let the developers directly have access to the production database servers so that you could just be
willy nilly executing commands of this sort against the database.
They're not going to allow that.
Typically, what they'll do instead is they'll have you write out a script of a sequel script, which
would be basically everything that we're seeing here, you know, something like that.
It would be in the form of a script where and then they would have you test that script out against
test data on a clone database or a test database, something that isn't in their final production place
where real business is getting done.
They won't let you do it there.
You do it on a lower level database as a test first and confirm that it all worked.
There may be divas who have to look over your script and approve it in the DBS might be the ones who
are actually going to run the script, OK?
And then only after they've confirmed that everything is, you know, safe to do, then maybe your script
gets to run in production.
That's what a lot of big corporations will do.
Now, a lot of more lean and agile companies might not have quite that level of of checks and balances
to go through.
But in one way or another, you'd better be testing out your commands on some test data or some other
environment before you decide to roll that out onto production data.
That's the main idea.
OK, so we can also change the structure of a table itself.
So let's say, for example, that we decided we wanted to add another column to the people table here
so we can do that.
There is an altered command.
Altar table people.
And let's say we just want to add a column so we can add a column.
And I don't know.
Looking over here?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Looking at our our at our original test data, we've got an email field.
That's a good one.
Let's add an email filled.
OK, so we'll add a field called email as a car.
255.
Just like that.
All right.
And so I've just executed that, and so if I go up here back and execute this, select everything from
people.
There we go.
We now have a null email filled now.
It's no obviously right, because we've already been creating data in here and now we've added this
new column.
So where would that data come from for this column?
It won't be there, right?
So if we wanted to perhaps update all of these columns for the existing people, we could do that now,
right?
We could do an update.
People set email equal to nothing and nowhere dot com, for example.
And if I don't specify a where clause, that's going to put that in all of those columns, which is
maybe what I want in this particular case, maybe to initialize it with something.
All right.
So I will run that.
And then come back up here again and re execute the query.
And now we've got nothing at nowhere in all four of these records.
And then I could also get rid of a column just as easily.
So if I don't like that particular column there, I can execute altar table people, drop column email
just like that.
Bam, that column is gone and then requiring the database.
There you go.
It's gone again.
Anytime you're deleting or dropping things, you probably want to be super extra, extra careful.
In fact, a pattern that you'll see quite frequently in business instead of deleting records.
A lot of the times what companies will do is they will add a column that just shows that a record is
supposed to act as though it was deleted, like a delete flag or something like that.
So let me show you what that could look like.
In fact, we could alter this table altered table people and column.
Delete flag, and because this is a flag, we probably should endeavour to make it like a Boolean,
so let's jump into the H2 database here and look at our data types and see if there is a good data type
that represents a flag or a Boolean right.
Oh, and look at that, we've got an actual Boolean field right there and it takes values of true or
false.
That makes sense, right?
So let's make this delete flag a Boolean.
Now, be careful here with these data types like this Boolean here, I can tell you for sure.
Not all databases are going to have a data type called Boolean.
Some may have something called like bit or bit flag or something like that.
Some may not have anything at all.
A lot of the times in older databases and probably even modern ones that are used even now, a lot of
organizations would just use a single character data type like one character.
So it's not a string like of our cards, just one character.
And then they would store a y or an in in that field to use it as a flag.
Because many databases didn't always support a true Boolean or their DBUS or their data or their programmers
who were issuing SQL didn't know what that data type was or that it even existed.
But anyway, so yeah, we've got a Boolean here, so let's use that.
Let's execute this.
All right.
Let's query the database back and see if we added it.
Yet we did.
And so then we can default to all of these fields to being false, meaning they're not to be deleted
for the records, right?
So update people set the elite flag equal to.
False.
All right.
Let's go query.
There we go.
And so now all of those are set to false.
And so let me see, do I still have?
Let's put Jake back in here now so that we can delete him the more humane way.
All right.
So I'm going to add Jake back in, but I won't specify his deletion status.
So I've just re executed the addition of Jake.
Let's query the database.
There we go.
So there's Jake.
And now if I want to delete him in a more humane way without actually removing the record right, then
I can simply update Jake to have a true in the delete flag field there so we can just do a update.
People set to lead flag to True, where?
Last name equals.
Smith.
There we go.
And then let's re query the database.
And so now Jake is virtually deleted.
Now how would we make use of this?
Well, basically any time we wanted to do any kind of processing on records in this table, we would
always be sure to add in a filter, if you will, to say, you know, basically only accept people whose
delete flag is not true or something like that.
So that would, in effect, just leave.
Jake Smith out of everything and then other common columns that you'll see in a business context would
be additional date fields to show.
Like when was the last time we updated one of these records or changed or deleted or things like that
for audit, auditing purposes and things of that sort?
So I think that's going to cover most of what we need to know for now to work with a basic database.
So in the next lessons, we're going to jump back into the Java code now.
And this is going to be a lot of fun, I think.
And we're going to learn how to write Java code that can connect to a database and let us manipulate
and and access data via Java code, which is really powerful.
And that's probably where the vast majority of Java applications really earn their pay is in accessing
large amounts of data that most businesses happened to happen to have.
So see in the next one.