All right, so now we're ready to create a new project to learn about Java and how it can connect and
work with actual databases.
So going in to our idea here, let's create a new project.
So we're going to go up here to file new project.
All right.
Make sure you've got now this is going to be a great project, so make sure you've selected Gradle and
then make sure you've got version 17 of Java selected here.
If at the time that you're watching this, there's a later version of Java that might be OK, too.
But we want to be a little bit careful here because sometimes the version of Gradle that ships with
the intelligent I.D. may not be updated yet to have full support for the current version of Java.
So if you run into a message telling you that it can't do something with version 18 or whatever version
of Java is out at the time that you're going through this course, you may need to temporarily choose
the previous version of Java that has full support for your I.D..
Just a quick little little note there.
All right.
But anyway, as of the time of this recording, Java 17 has only been out for a month and a half couple
of months, something like that.
And I want Java selected here.
And so click next.
And let's see here.
Let's call this project people D.B for People database.
OK.
And then click Finish.
And I will put this in a new window.
All right, so now Gradle will be downloading things that need to be downloaded.
So we'll give it a minute to do all of that good stuff and get our project ready to go.
OK.
And it looks like it's done and it's ready to go.
All right, cool.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to install an additional dependency for this new
application that we are about to write.
So since this is going to be a database driven application, we will need to connect to a database.
In the previous lessons, we were working with the H2 database using the Squirrel sequel client.
So if we want this new application that we are about to write to be able to work and connect to an H2
database, we will need an H2 database driver embedded in our application.
OK?
And that driver will take the form of a library dependency on our project.
So one of the reasons why we're using Gradle besides the fact that Gradle or MAVEN, which are very
equivalent in functionality, are industry standards for professional Java developers.
The other reason, though, is because they give us a nice, standardized way of downloading libraries,
and we've already played with this a little bit in a few previous lessons.
So here we are, just kind of using it some more, just so you can get more accustomed to some of these
industry standard tools and techniques.
OK.
So in our I.D. here, we're currently looking at the build that Gradle file, and this is really just
the configuration file for Gradle based projects.
And one of the things we can specify in this file is additional libraries that we want to get pulled
in and become part of our project.
Now, by the way, if for whatever reason, you didn't start right off with having the build that Gradle
file open like I did, you can easily just navigate to it.
It's right here build.gradle so you can just double click it and then it should open up for you.
OK.
So now my cursor is over here in the editor for this file, and it's really just a text file.
All right.
And so now if I want to add a new dependency via Gradle, I can let the ADP do that for me pretty easily
by hitting command in on Mac, and then I can select add dependency.
By the way, if you're on Windows, I know that the command in think has typically not existed for the
Windows people.
I think you can just right click somewhere in black space here and then choose Generate.
Yeah.
All right.
So same thing for for the Windows players.
Ad dependency.
And that pulls up this window here now.
My window looks a little weird, as you know, because I keep my screen in presentation mode so that
all the text is easy to see.
All right.
But I'm going to come down here to my search area that's kind of flaking out on me a little bit there
and I'm going to type h.
All right.
And so now we're seeing a list of all of the dependencies here.
And I believe the one that we're interested in is this very first one here.
H2 database engine now looks like I need to select a version.
And generally speaking, this is probably the most recent version, though really, truly it doesn't.
It's not going to matter a whole lot for what we're going to be doing.
So I'm selecting the version that's at the top of the list because by the time you're running this,
that version might be something even higher than one point forty two.
Don't worry about it.
Just generally speaking, pick the pick the one that's at the top, and then you can click Add.
And so now what that has done is that has added this line right here under dependencies in my build.gradle
file.
And we're done here.
All right.
So now we've got that dependency here.
Let me open back up my project pane on the left.
And for some of you, that may trigger Gradle via the ADP to go out and download that dependency.
I think I already had that dependency in my computer, so I didn't have to go through that.
All right.
So the next step here is that we're going to do this project TDD style, test driven development.
We haven't done that in a while, but as we're getting towards the end of this course, I'm trying to
do things a little bit more formally to wrap things up and make sure that you're fully engaged in the
standard ways that professional Java developers might be creating applications or at least getting kind
of closer to it.
And you know it actually, while we're at it, let's install one more dependency.
So if I'm going to do another command in here and add dependency again, and this time I'm going to
search for a Cert J.
All right.
This will be used for our TD, for our tests and the very first one here, a search, a fluent assertions,
that's the one we want.
And so again, we'll click on this not set thing here.
Click on that, and I'm going to pick the number at the top there, the version at the top and then
click Add.
And you're going to want to then change the line that says a search from implementation to test implementation
and make sure you have a capital I.
All right.
And so now we are good to go.
All right now, while we're over here in the build that Gradle file, we may need to trigger intelligence
to make sure that it has actually downloaded this library here.
Now, at this moment, I'm actually not 100 percent certain that Intel AJ has in fact downloaded this
Assert J Library.
So if I want to check that I can come over here to the external libraries and open and click on this
little greater than symbol here and then I can search and I can look through here.
And in fact, I do not see it being referenced here, so I need to trigger intelligence to reread and
reload everything that I have listed out as a dependency in this field that Gradle file.
So what I'm going to do is temporarily jump out of presentation mode for just a second here so that
I can see what I'm doing.
So let me let me jump into regular mode.
All right.
So now in regular mode here, sorry that everything's smaller now, but in regular mode, I can come
over here to the Gradle tab, which actually I do need to show this to you anyway.
And I can always click on this little refresh button here or reload button.
And that will trigger Intel AJ to reread things.
And I just noticed that as I did, that looks like it indeed did bring in actually, looks like it might
have had to bring in the H2 database as well, but it certainly brought in the Assert J Library now.
All right.
And so that's what I wanted.
So now I know that I've got the dependencies that I needed in this project and they're loaded up, OK,
and now I can jump back in to my presentation mode here.
Give me a just a second here.
There we go.
OK.
OK, so the next thing that we're going to do is we're going to actually just write a test.
So I'm going to come over here to my test folder and expand that out and click on Java and then do a
command in.
And create a new Java class.
And so what we're going to do is we're going to start with tests, and the first thing we're going to
write tests for is a new repository.
So we did play around with this repository pattern a tiny little bit.
We made a little bit of a poor man's repository a few lessons ago that was backed by an array list,
if I recall correctly.
So we were simulating some of the types of methods that you might find on a typical repository class
in a real company's Java code.
Now we're going to write a more realistic one that actually will connect to an actual database, though.
OK.
So when we create these repositories, typically you'll get one repository per primary domain concept
and buy primary domain concept.
I mean, like a domain model idea.
OK, so this application is going to allow us to do basic what are called crud operations on a person
class crud, by the way, for native English speakers, that's not like crud as in like Creedy or terrible,
right?
Crud is an acronym that stands for Create, Read, Update and Delete.
And we actually were running through examples of how to do basic crud operations with sequel in one
of the previous lessons with the Squirrel sequel client.
Now we're going to implement a lot of those same types of crud operations in Java code.
OK.
So anyway, we're going to create our first test here for a repository that will be called People Repository.
And so the test class, we can name something like people repository tests, OK?
And this will be a class.
And so we will hit enter.
There we go.
Oh, I'm sorry, and I forgot.
We also want this to exist inside of a specific package, though, so let's go and create that as well.
So if you click on Java right above the People Repository Tests class, click on that and I'll do another
command in and we'll make a package.
So choose package.
And so typically when you're working at a company and we've gone through this before, you'll create
a root package structure, which is based on an internet domain name for the company or something like
that.
So I will use my own company's name.
You can use your last name, got first name if you like, or you can make up a fictitious company name
or if you work for a company, you can use their actual domain name.
Now, it's typically done in reverse, though, so in my case, it would become that neutrino system.
OK.
And then maybe the name of the application itself.
So this application is people DB.
And then from here we may choose to group up our classes by function.
Now, grouping our classes by function is probably the most common way to group them by, and I will
stick with that for now.
But I think I may have mentioned this a long time ago and one of the previous lessons, but another
way that you could do it is to group by domain concept.
But since we don't have many of those concepts yet, that would be harder for me to explain and show.
So for now, let's just group them by function.
All right.
And so the function of this class that we're about to create is a repository.
So we'll just call this people do that repository like so.
All right.
So now we've just created that package.
And so now what I'm going to do is I'm going to just drag the people repository tests class that we've
previously created.
I'm going to drag that right on top of the newly created repository.
And so now the idea is ask me, Hey, do you want to move that class into this new repository?
And yes, I do.
So I'm going to tell it to refactor that.
There we go, and so now you see that the ABC has modified the class code a little bit and put a package
here to say that this is inside of the people DVD repository package.
All right.
And so now I'm going to make a new line.
And let's just start writing a first test.
All right.
So there's an app test there, and our tests have to be public and void.
So what's a first scenario to actually test?
Let me make some room there for myself.
So I think the first thing we're going to need is some actual data and to have some data like in the
database, we need to be able to save records.
So let's write a test for us to be able to save one person to the database.
OK.
So I'm just going to call this can save until I think of a better name for it.
All right.
So I'm going to pretend like there is already a class called People Repository People Repository.
And I'm going to create an instance of it, and I will just call it repo for four short, and I will
just knew that guy up or instantiated new people repository for now.
Like so.
All right, so now people repository is red because it doesn't actually exist.
So let's make that happy right now.
I put my cursor, you know, kind of right before the parentheses there, and I'm going to do an option
return and let's just create this class.
And yes, we do want that to be placed inside of the people DB repository repository.
However, we don't want the target destination directory to be the Dot Test folder.
We don't want that.
We want to click on these ellipses here, and we want to move that into the main folder.
OK, because tests belong in the test folder, but real code, which is what this is about to be, what
it's going to create for us that belongs in the main folder.
OK.
So I'm double clicking main and then the idea is giving me a parallel option down down here under main.
So just as we have the people DB repository in Test, we've also got one under Maine, so that's the
one that we actually want.
And now we can click OK and then OK again.
All right, so now it has created this class for us, it doesn't have anything in it yet, but there
it is.
And now to jump back over to the test class, I can either do a command shift and then choose people
repository tests or I could also just go back.
All right.
And so the red marks went away because we've now created this class.
So then the next thing I may want to do is to pretend like I've got a save method on this class repo
dot save.
Now what am I actually going to save, though?
Well, I'm thinking we should model a person and then have an instance of a person that we can pass
into this save method to save that person.
So in order to do that, then I would need to create an instance of this fictional person, right?
So let me make a new line right up here, and I'm going to pretend like I have a class already in this
project called person.
And I'm going to just say, I don't know.
Call it John equals new person, and I'm going to pretend like I've even got a constructor here, something
that maybe takes a first name.
John Comma, a last name, Smith comma, maybe a date of birth, and I will model the date of birth
with a zoned date time.
Of and I guess I may use this version here, so I can specify a year.
So let's say, I don't know, 1980 and a month of November and a day of 15th and an hour of 15 three
p.m..
Fifteen and seconds will be zero.
And I'm running off the screen here.
And what else do we have here in nanoseconds even?
All right.
Zero nanoseconds and what else do we have?
And then a zone I'd OK Zone I.D. of?
And I don't know.
Let's say that he's from Chicago, so I happen to know that.
So I think that should be minus six.
And if it's not, that's OK, I don't care.
All right.
So there's our person who is in error because he does not actually exist.
So now let's let the idea go ahead and create that for us.
So I'm putting my cursor right there before the left parentheses and do an option return.
And let's go ahead and create this class called person.
And so now again, I need to click on these ellipses down here to change where this is going to go because
I don't want this class to be created in the test folder.
So I'm going to click on that and then click on it, and then I'm going to double click on Main and
then I'm going to click here as well.
Now, actually, I don't even want this to go into the repository folder either, but let me click OK,
first and now up here I will change the repository to model because this is going to be a model class.
OK?
And then click OK.
There we go.
All right.
And so now the ad has created this class for us, and it's even trying to create a constructor for us
as well.
So.
A string is fine for the first name, so we'll call that first filled first name and then the last name
will be your last name.
And then this field here will be.
Date of birth.
All right.
And now let's jump back over to our test.
And the red marks went away, so that's good.
And so now I should be able to simply pass in John like that.
And now I want to address this red mark here.
So I put my cursor to the left of the parentheses and then option return and create the save method
and in people repository.
Yes, do that.
OK, so for now, we'll let that return typed be void.
But I think I have stated this before.
Typically, the save method of a repository would return the object that you just saved, and I think
we will update that.
But we'll let the TDI will let the test evolve us into doing that rather than just putting the code
out there before anything actually warranted us doing that.
OK?
All right.
The input type will be of type person, and we don't want to call that John.
Let's just call it person.
All right.
And no more errors here.
Let's jump back over here and no errors here, either.
All right.
So now I think we might be ready to assert something.
So now at this point, I'm just sitting here kind of contemplating what what would be a good thing to
actually assert that isn't like too much, but isn't absolutely nothing, either.
So I'm kind of thinking here, let's assert that upon calling the save method, we would receive an
object back out and that object will now have an I.D. and that I.D. would be generated by the database.
OK, so actually, that's kind of a lot of steps, but that's where we're headed.
So let's just go ahead and do it.
All right.
So let's go ahead and pretend like the safe method will return something to us of type person, and
I'm going to just refer to this thing as a saved person like that.
And so now we're in error again.
So if I do an option, return now the ID is offering to make the save method return something of type
person, which is cool.
That's what I want.
All right, so it's going to return in this case, it's going to return the person that we're passing
in, which is cool.
It went for basically about the simplest thing that we can do, I suppose.
Or that it could do.
All right.
And so now I want to assert something.
So let me show you something now as we're about to jump into these assertions here.
I had you install this test library called a Cert J, because the Assert Test Library works well with
J Unit, which is the, you know, framework that is running our tests for us.
But it gives us what is considered to be a more fluent API for writing our assertions and you'll see
what I mean in just a minute here.
So I just wanted to point that out.
That's why we added this in.
I actually prefer to use the search a lot of the times.
I didn't want to introduce it too early, though, because a lot of companies maybe haven't quite standardized
on a search.
And you can always be safe to just use the default assertions that come with J Unit, but those are
a little lackluster.
Perhaps I'll say, OK, so jumping back now?
All right.
So now we're ready for our first assertion and we're going to use the assertions from the Assert J libraries.
And so let's see now if I can refer to.
My assert, J.
Yes, I can.
OK, so all right, let me let me do that a little slower now.
So I typed assert that and then I went ahead and put my parentheses in here, and then I put my cursor
to the left of the left parentheses.
And then I did an option return, and now I have the option to import static method.
And so what's happening here is that intelligence is pretty familiar with the Assert J Library.
And or or maybe it's being so smart that it's actually scanning through that library that we just got
loaded in and finding all the static methods.
I'm not sure which way it's doing it, but the searching library is an extremely popular one and so
intelligent knows to make the static methods of the Assert J Library available to me conveniently with
this import static method option right there.
And yes, I do want to import that.
All right.
And then it's asking me, well, which version?
Because there's a bunch of them.
All right.
And I think I'll just go for the simplest one here assertions that assert that.
So let's pull that one in.
Assert that saved person.
So what do we actually want to assert here?
I'm thinking, let's assert.
Well, I kind of already stated it earlier.
I said, Let's test that we get back a saved person and that saved person is going to have an actual
I.D. that is set to something.
OK.
So in that case, maybe we can say assert that saved person died.
Get ID.
I know we don't actually have this method yet, but we will get ID.
Like that?
So let's let's make that happy real quick.
So I'm putting my cursor to the left of the parentheses there and then doing in an option return.
And sure.
All right, now, caller ID is actually giving me the option to generate a property called ID, which
I actually prefer to do that, so let's do that because then it will also go ahead and generate the
method as well.
And let's let the type the data type for this be a rapper long, so uppercase long.
Now I could have gone for a lower case long as well.
But what I'm kind of thinking here is that initially when we create a person, they won't have an I.D.
and if I used a primitive long, you can't have a primitive long set to nothing.
It has to be set to something, right?
So you could do negative one or zero or something like that.
So the best that I can kind of think to do right now would be to probably just set it to a long.
Now, if I gave this to a rapper, long now, if I gave this a little more thought, I've never actually
done this before.
I could consider what it would look like to make this an optional, long and optional long.
However, I happen to know because of my experience that I've never in life seen any project do that
before and later down the road.
We're going to learn a little tiny bit about the spring framework and some of the amazing tools that
it makes available to us to ease a lot of what you're going to do in this module.
And I'm a little concerned about over complicating it by bringing in the optional long.
So we're not going to do that right now, but it's certainly worth considering, and it might even be
conceptually the most correct thing to do, possibly.
But for now, we'll use a wrapper long.
All right.
And so now the ID has created a property called ID for us of type long.
So now we can jump back over here.
So now, if I put my cursor at the end of this and then do a period, now here's where we get into what
I was saying a little bit earlier about the Assert J Assertion Library.
It implements what is called a fluent library, and that is to say that you can kind of read your lines
of assertions almost like in English or at least closer to English.
So we can say assert that the saved person's.
And then I can say something like is greater than zero.
See?
So it reads more like English, assert that the saved person's ID is greater than zero.
All right.
So let's go ahead and run that and see it fell.
All right, so that failed, and let's see why it failed, exactly.
Let's see here.
Expecting actual not to be null So yeah, the idea is currently null.
Right?
So in the time honored standards of TDD, what we want to do now is the simplest possible thing to make
this pass, even though the simplest possible thing to make this past may likely be meaningless.
We're going to do it anyway.
All right.
So let's go over here to the Get ID method, and all we need to do is just have this method somehow
return a zero?
Right?
So I could either hardcoded zero here or I could set this field here to zero or something, something
along those lines.
Technically, I should probably be doing it right here because that would probably be the most direct
place to do the minimal change, right?
And then I can just click this green button here and just run that again.
OK, so it's still filled, but I bet it's failing now.
For now, it might be failing for a slightly different reason.
Let's see here expecting actual zero to be greater.
Oh, right.
Oh, so sorry.
Yeah, I forgot my own assertion.
I said that it should be something greater than zero, right?
All right.
Easy enough.
So let's just make this one and run that again.
There we go.
Now it's passing.
All right, so let's go ahead and stop here, and we'll pick right back up at this spot when we get
back into the next lesson and we'll start to get more into the actual database code itself.
So I'll see you in the next one.