All right, so in this lesson, we're going to take a deeper dive into how Java handles dates and times.
Now we've already been playing around with a little tiny bit of this functionality throughout this entire
course, any time we've needed to model a date in particular by using the local date class.
But now we'll dig in a little deeper and see a lot more of the power that exists in this date time API
that Java has, by the way, so quick little history on Java and how it has handled dates and times
in the past.
There's been a bit of controversy there over the years.
I would say there have been three different regimes of how Java handles dates and times.
There was a class called Java Dot You till date and it had some issues and there was Java dot util dot
calendar that attempted to fix some of those issues.
But there was still a lot of controversy.
And so there were a few third party libraries that tried to really fix the issues with handling dates
and time.
And one of these libraries, called Joda Time, ended up becoming so successful that when Java eight
was created, the creators decided to basically just roll a lot of the functionality from the go to
time library, which was a third party library not directly affiliated with the development of the Java
Developer Kit.
They decided to roll that in.
And so now the most modern implementation of handling dates and times in Java as of Java version eight
is heavily influenced by, some might even say, basically copied from the Joda Time library.
So towards the end of this lesson, I will talk a little bit more about what some of those issues were
that caused the maintainers and developers of Java to create the new Java eight date and time API.
All right, so let's jump in here, though, and play with the dates and things.
So I think what we'll do is let's go ahead and just create another class.
So I'm going to open up my project view here, and I think in this data store thing, this is fine.
I will just highlight the data store package there and then do a command in and create a new Java class.
And I guess I'll call this one time.
Test.
Enter.
All right.
And I'll make a new line SVM for public static void main.
Here we go, and then let me close that down.
OK, so let's start with the basics, which we've already done before.
So let's say that we just want to represent the date today.
Right?
So we can do that by creating an instance of a local date.
Just like so.
And keep in mind that that is under the Java that time package there.
But the idea will know what you're talking about.
And then if we just do a dot now, that will give us the date right now and so we can print that.
By the way, I want to show you a little thing that I actually just realized exists in intelligence
myself.
Quite useful.
So let's say that we want to print that that local date now.
Right?
I normally wrap that inside of a system dot out.
We'll watch this.
I can do a period.
So you T. And this is, I guess, a little macro within intelligence, and that's going to take our
expression and wrap it inside of a system that out that print line, that's what it expands out to very,
very useful.
Similarly, there's so you f, which sets us up for print and then we can, you know, put our little
format string there or whatever.
And.
And there's the big thing now you may have seen me use this before, I can't remember if I've used it
on camera, but this one is a little bit more generic, so it just wraps the whole expression in parentheses
and then I could type out whatever or I could make some, you know, my method call if I had some method
that I was trying to call or something like that.
All right.
So anyway, let's wrap that in a system that out, and let's run that.
So there's our date represented there.
Now I could put my cursor here and select all of that and then capture that into a local date variable
with the option command V..
Right.
And sure, I'll call it now and then I can manipulate that in certain ways.
So there are lots and lots of methods for manipulating dates with the API here, and we'll look at a
few of them right now.
So let's say that I wanted to get the date for five days into the future so I could put my period after
this variable for now.
And then I can say plus days and then just put a five in there.
And so that'll be the date.
Five days from now, I can run that.
There we go.
So 11:17.
And I can do that for any standard field, so right now, I'm doing it for days, but I could do that
for.
Let's see.
Years, days, months and weeks, or I could use a more generic method here, I don't mean generic in
the generic sense.
I mean that in the English language sense.
So we've got this, we've got a couple versions of this.
We've got one version of the plus method that takes two arguments a value and then a unit, right?
And so this value and unit thing are really just a long form version of what these methods here are
already doing here.
The unit is baked into the method itself.
And then in this more generic form, we can specify what those units are.
We'll we'll use that and let's do years.
So let's do three years into the future and then to specify the temporal units, we can actually use
the Chrono unit.
And so there are a bunch of constants defined on this chrono unit.
And so if I wanted years, I could do Chrono Unit eight years.
Like so and so let's run that.
There we go.
And so now we're at 2024, 11 12.
OK, so that's a more generic way that you can warp time, if you will.
And just as there's a plus, there's also a minus let's.
We show you that.
So there you go, there's minus there and again, same same analogues to the to the plus message.
All right.
So now in addition to obviously just getting the date today or right now, we can set any arbitrary
date as well.
So that's easy enough to do.
Let's let me see here.
I'm going to just delete both of those and I'll create a new date.
So local date.
Of and we've seen this many times throughout this course, I've used the of method, so I can specify
a year, month and a day of month.
Right.
So let's do New Year's Day, right?
So of 2020.
So month, one now, the month with the Java eight date and time API makes sense.
They start with one OK and the days of the month start with one as well.
That that was not the case where the previous Java date you till date and Java date you till date calendar
classes.
And that was one of many complaints, just the inconsistency.
And in fact, if I'm if I'm not mistaken with Java you till date date.
The months were zero based, but the day of the month was one day.
I don't know why.
So, yeah, little inconsistencies like that kind of drove a lot of developers a little bit nuts.
All right.
So anyway, so what were we doing New Year's Day, right?
So 2020.
January one.
Okay.
And then let's capture that and we'll call it New Year's.
All right.
And then we can print that out.
All right, there we go.
All right, so now let's say that we wanted to know what day of the week was New Year's Day in 2020.
That's really easy to do because there are some really convenient methods on our local date classes
to give us that kind of information so we can do a get.
And there we go right there day of week.
So let's run that.
It was a Wednesday, apparently.
And just to prove that that's really, really working, let's do one for today.
So today is a Friday, so I could do a local date now that get day of the week.
Let's see if it gives me.
Yeah, there we go Friday.
So all right, so there's that.
And just as we have a get day of week, there are actually numerous getter methods, if you will.
Let's just take a quick peek at a few of them so you can get an idea.
So there's good day of the week.
I'm not going to go through each and every one of these, but some key ones get day of month should
be pretty self-explanatory.
Get day of year.
So that'll give us unilateral 365 days a year.
It'll give us the number for the day out of the year.
Get month.
No notice to get month actually gives us something of type month.
So it's not just a number, it's an actual class that represents the month.
There's another one no get month value that does return an actual integer.
So this would give us 11 if it's November get year, that gives us an actual number.
OK, so what a nice, convenient methods there for getting basic date fields that you might be interested
in having.
Now I want to show you something else that builds on so much of what we've been learning in this course,
especially in the last couple of modules where we've really started to get deep into the streams API
and lambdas you.
You can do a little bit of that stuff even with the dates.
I guess once the Java creator has created the lambda and streams stuff, they were seeing all kinds
of places where they could embed that functionality, and they even figured out a way to embedded into
a little bit of the data stuff here.
So let's take a look at that.
So see here.
Let me delete that, and I will use the New Year's variable there.
And so we've got a method dates until.
So what this method will do is it will basically generate all of the dates from whatever date we're
starting on with the object.
So in this case, New Year's right, because that was the date that we set up until some date that we
get it.
OK.
So for example, here dates until.
So this will take a local date.
So I don't know.
I'll just give it today, for example, local date.
Now, all right, now what this returns, if we hover over this method here, it returns a stream of
local dates.
So here's a stream of local dates.
So if I do something like a for each, I can print out each of these dates that it's going to calculate
between new years of 2020 and now, for example.
So let's try that out.
So we'll do a system that out.
And yeah, I can use the method reference format for this.
All right, so let's print this out and see what we get.
There we go.
So it printed out a heck of a lot of dates, right?
So it actually generated each day between 20 20 January 1st and now explicitly.
OK, now if you didn't want that to generate each and every single day, you can actually specify with
an overloaded version of the dates until method a period, right?
Like an amount of time to skip over something like that.
And so there's another version of this method.
It's this second version here that takes a so-called period.
So what a period is is exactly what it means, you know, in in the English time since it's a period
of time.
OK.
So let's see how we can use this.
So if I put my comma here?
I can do.
Period.
And then there are these helper methods, the static helper methods on the period class like of years,
in fact, here let's just see.
So we've got of years of days, of weeks and of months, so I don't know.
Let's do of months.
So basically, we can say skip by month, one month at a time.
OK, so then let's run that.
And so now we're getting January 1st, February 1st, March 1st and so on and so forth, right?
It's skipping by month at a time.
And we could tell it to go every two months.
So there, Jan, Mar May.
And so on and so forth, right?
We could do.
Of days, and I don't know, we could go 150 days at a time.
So I think you get the idea, right?
OK, so going going by 150 days at a time, you end up with all of these oddball dates like this.
But it's pretty cool.
So anything that you could do generally with the Streams API, you can now apply that functionality
to the calculation and iterating of dates, essentially.
Now why might you want to do this?
One scenario that I could kind of think of would be, what if I want to know all of the leap years between
now and the next 10 years from now?
OK, so let's see how we could do that.
So between now and the next 10 years from now, so I'm going to just delete all of that and I will first
create now dates until and I said 10 years from now.
So the way we can do that is I can create another local date now.
Plus years 10 now there are so many ways to skin this cat.
But this is just one way that I'm thinking of at the moment, right?
So dates until.
And let's see.
And then I want to go by years.
So I will do period of years and I'll do every one year, right?
And then what I can do is I can use a filter.
And so watch what I can filter for, so I'm going to use a method that exists on the weight class,
right?
So each object that's going to fall through this stream is going to be a local date so I can call a
method reference local date.
And there's a method, right there is leap year and then I can print those or I could collect them,
in fact, you know, let's let's collect.
We haven't done collecting in a while, so I could collect these into a list like so, so collect and
then collectors start to list.
And now I need to capture that leap years.
And then I can print.
Those leap year.
So there are apparently only two leap years between now and 10 years from now.
Let's see 2024 and 2028.
So like I said before, any time you want to be able to apply these streams, API capabilities and techniques,
now you have a way to do that.
All right.
So now let's move away from local dates for a minute because there's another class that's quite similar
and very helpful.
There's local time.
So basically, all the things that we can do that make sense with local date, we can also do with this
local time.
So let's create an instance of a local time now local time.
So you create it pretty much the same way you can do a local time now.
And let's go ahead and just print that.
There we go.
So there's my local time, 527, so some key things that I want to point out here.
Local date represents literally a date with no time component associated with it.
Local time represents a time with no date associated with it.
This is key to point out because again, the previous date time modeling that Java had prior to Java
version eight had a tendency to confuse and mix these concepts together, which is OK to do in certain
circumstances in many circumstances.
We developers actually do want to know both a date and a time at the same time.
But sometimes we don't want these two things together.
And sometimes by keeping them together, we actually make our jobs more difficult.
And I'll give you a quick example of what I mean.
Let's say that you're working for a company and you're writing an application that needs to store dates
for, I don't know, maybe when people registered for something.
OK?
If you're using an API that doesn't make it easy to just represent dates by themselves, and instead
you're forced to have both a date and a time, you're going to have to do some things if you want to
later on, be able to compare to different people.
So let's say two people registered on the same day, but at different times, and your API really only
does date and time together.
The most naive implementation of some code that might handle this situation might just leave the date
and the time intact and then save it someplace.
And so now, if you want to ask the question, did these two people register at the same time?
Which really means did they register on the same date?
The answer technically is yes.
They did register on the same date.
However, since their time components may be different, a naive implementation might say they do not
match.
And what you need to do in that case is normalize the time component of these date time things or these
timestamps or whatever they're going to be called.
So that's a little extra work on you now.
Whereas if you could have simply modeled the data for what you actually care about, which in this case
you only care about the date and not the time, then you would not have to do that.
In fact, here, if we just create a couple of date objects, real quick local date.
Sorry to go back to the dates, but I'll just show you real quick here d one equals local date.
Of and let's just pick, I don't know, two thousand one one.
And then we'll make another local day called the two local date of Oops, I got the wrong year there,
didn't I?
2000.
And we'll do 2000 one two, and then we can say something like the one dud equals the two, right?
So we're asking, are those equal?
I'm going to comment out that last bit there for a minute.
No, they're not equal.
And then if I set this one to one, so now they should both be equal.
OK, cool.
We get that.
Another way we could do this, by the way, is that there is a compare.
Yeah, compared to D2.
Now this compare to is just like the comparable functionality that we learned back in the collections
module where we were able to compare any two objects, right?
So these date objects implement that same interface.
And so that means that this is going to return not a true false, but numbers, right?
Negative one, zero or positive one, typically.
So these are equal and therefore we get back a zero.
The reason that these classes implement that interface is you can guess it now so that they can be sorted
in order.
Right?
All right.
So that's what that looks like.
But now to get back to our local time examples here, let's create an explicit local time, not just
the now right, but let's do a local time and we'll call this local L.T. one.
And so we'll create a local time dot.
So it works pretty much the same way as the local date and has some really nice, easy to use utility
methods here for creating instances.
So we could do just the hour in the minute or the hour, minute and second, or we could go all the
way down to nanoseconds.
Even for now, let's just go with hour and minute.
So we'll do 10 30.
All right.
And then let's make another one local time L2 equals local time of and for this one, let's do 10.
31.
All right.
And so we already know if we compare those LRT one equals L2, we know that that's going to be false.
There we go.
So yeah, we got false there.
And then if we set that minute to be the same.
Now it's true.
So before we dig in too deeply on the local time methods, let me go ahead and just introduce one more
class here while we're at it.
There is a local date time, and so that would be like, you know, the full culmination of having both
the date and the time together.
And so to kind of wrap up this little example that I was giving you of how when you've got that time
component combined with dates, you have to get the time part precisely to match between any two date
times, right?
So let's create a date time and that'll look the same local date time.
L.D. one equals local date time of.
Now we can create these in a number of ways.
There are quite a number of variations of the of method here.
Right.
So we can specify a year, month, day, minute, year, month, day of month, hour, minute, second
nanoseconds.
Basically, they just took all of the constituent fields for creating a local date and a local time.
And then they put them together in a number of variations, essentially.
And then there are some rolled up versions as well.
And by rolled up, I mean, like this one down here, we can even build a local date time out of a local
date and a local time, which makes sense, right?
And in fact, maybe let's go ahead and use that version for right now.
So we'll make a local daytime comprised of a D one and an L T one.
So what I'm doing here is I'm making a local great time from this date and this time, right?
And then I will make another one local daytime elders to L.D. T-2 and look at a time of and then we'll
do D2 and L.T. to like.
So and then we can compare those LGT one that equals LGT to.
Let's run that.
So that is true.
They are both equal.
And that makes sense because currently we've got dates of 2000 January 1st for both dates and 10 for
both times.
Right.
But now if I even just add a difference of one nanosecond and run this now no longer matching right,
because it's just any difference at all down to that level means that they are just completely not the
same date times anymore.
And so typically you'd be wanting to strip off the time if you were just wanting to compare dates.
And by the way, to strip that time off would be easy to do if you're using the Java eight API, because
let's say that you ended up with a date time given to you from somewhere.
Well, you can easily just extract the local date from a local date time or the local time from a local
date time.
And that's easy enough to do.
We can do an LDL d T1, so that's our local date time dot, and then we can call to local date to get
the local date or the local time so easy enough to just extract the component of either of those out
back out of the local date time.
And I think there's maybe one more fundamental time class that I want to mention briefly and that is
called instant.
So instant is actually quite similar, in my opinion, to local date time, except that local date,
local time and local date time are really all meant for human consumption.
OK, so if you're writing programs that are going to be dealing with dates and times that are meant
for humans to enter or to read, you'd want to be using these classes generally speaking.
Instant.
On the other hand, though functionally somewhat similar to the local date, time has a different purpose,
and that is for machines to share timing with each other.
So let me show you what I mean here.
Let's create an instant.
I'll just make a new line.
Instant is the class and I can do something like now.
And let's just print that.
All right, so here's our instant, so it has very familiar information in it, it's got every year,
month day and then the time component designated by this T.
Right.
So that's why I said it's quite similar to a local date time.
But the instant actually tracks time in terms of seconds.
And this is actually part of a legacy in computing that dates back to a specific date in time 1970 January
1st, which is known as epoch time.
So basically, the creators of the very popular operating system Unix chose to track time in their operating
system from that date.
And that's around the period of time when Unix was released.
So that's kind of the birth time of Unix.
And so they just chose 1970 January 1st, and presumably because so many programs written from that
period of time forward used this notion of time tracking called the epoch time.
It has persisted to this day, which is kind of weird when you really think about it.
And so there may be times as a developer when you need to specify dates and times to other systems that
you may be trying to communicate with and by you.
I mean, your your code, really.
Some of these other systems may require that you pass them date time information using epoch time.
And if you need to do that, you can use the instant class to do so.
Now you may find yourself having to translate from human entered date time data, though, to instance.
And that's easy enough to do.
So let's play around with that a little bit.
So we've got a local date time up here.
I'll get one.
And let's say that we want to convert that into an instant.
How could we do that?