All right.
What I would like to do with you now is to start up another project and do some more unit testing,
but get a little bit more involved now.
So what I'm thinking is let's use a TDD approach to rewriting our guessing game.
In other words, let's see how the guessing game would turn out if we were to do it with a test driven
approach.
So let's go to the ADC and let's just create a new project.
All right.
See, we'll we'll keep all of the defaults here.
Let me let me make it so that you can see this okay, next and don't click anything other than next
again.
And let's just call it a guessing game.
All right.
And then click finish and we will use a new window.
And let me resize this to use up the whole space there.
All right.
And then just as we did before, the first thing we need to do is to add our J Unit library.
So we will right click on the project name here guessing game and then go down to open module settings.
Then go down to libraries.
Click Plus, click from MAVEN.
OK, now it's time for us to enter the maven coordinates for the J Unit library that we want.
Now let's say that you have no idea what those coordinates are, as even I barely can remember myself.
So let me show you what I typically do to learn those coordinates for libraries that I want to use.
What I will typically do is to open up a browser and I will bring one over here.
Like so?
And then I will go to a popular website for exactly this problem called MAVEN Repository.
And you can just Google MAVEN repository, and it's the first link here.
And then up in this search window here, you could maybe just start off by typing J Unit and hit enter
or return.
And looks like the very first thing that comes up is G-Unit Jupyter API, which I happen to know is
a unit version five.
And so that's looking pretty good to me.
Now you will see a lot of things that will come up here, but in this case, I happen to know that Unit
Jupiter is the current version that we want.
So I'm going to click on that.
And now what we see are all of the various versions of J.
Unit Jupiter that have been released well, not just released, but in various states.
And it looks to me like 5.8 is not quite ready for prime time as it is ending with the one we talked
about this before.
So it looks like the most stable release version of J Unit Jupiter is five point seventy two, which
is what we used before.
So if you click on that, then we get this little meta information here, and this information is actually
the maven coordinates for this library.
All right.
Now, I think the easiest way to use this for for our purposes right now to have intelligent download
this library is actually to click on this last tab here, builder.
If you click on that, we have a short, sweet, easy representation of this maven coordinate.
And so if you just grab that, copy it without the single ticks, and if you want, you can grab the
whole entire thing with that.
But leave off the the single text, the little single quotes there and then copy that and then go back
over to the A.D. and then paste it right in here and then click OK.
All right.
And so now we're being told that that library will be added to this module.
The guessing game module, just as we did before with our previous lesson and then click OK and then
click OK again, and that library will have been downloaded.
All right, then we'll have to go back into the project settings one more time.
So again I'm right clicking on the guessing game here and I'm going to go back to the open module settings.
And again, you can't see it on my screen now because it's kind of my menu is longer than what my screen
is displaying.
But take my word for it.
You want to click on open module settings again?
I have the modules option selected here, just as we did before, and then I'm going to come over here
to the source folder and I'm going to right click and then click New Folder and then create a folder
called Man Main, All Lowercase and click OK.
And then I'm going to right click again and new folder and another folder here called Test.
Click OK, then I'm going to single click on Main and then I'm going to.
And if I make this just a little taller, I might be able to get a little more visibility here.
Possibly.
Nope, not quite.
Anyway, all right.
So I will click on Main and then click on this little icon here.
Sources All right, and then I will click on Test and then click on tests.
All right.
And then click OK, and if you need a refresher on why we're doing any of that, go check out the first
lesson in this module.
All right, then click OK.
And now we are ready to rock and roll.
All right.
So what I want to do here is to re-implement our guessing game again more or less.
But this time I want to do it in a test driven way because I obviously we want to practice writing unit
tests, for one thing.
But I also want you to get a little bit familiar with how it feels to write code in this style to write
especially slightly less trivial code than what we did with the calculator.
OK, because we will have to solve a few issues.
So one thing I want to mention is that in our first implementation of the guessing game, we ended up
combining a couple of aspects of that game all into one thing.
First off, we wrote it all in one class, which we will likely do again here.
However, in our previous implementation with just one class, we combined both the user interface and
the game logic all in one class.
And it's it's very tightly integrated.
And what I mean by the user interface is that when we were running that version of the guessing game
to interact with it, we used the command line.
So the guessing game would start up and it would ask us to enter a number that we wanted to guess and
then we could use the keyboard and type in that number, right?
And then whatever we were typing in would go back into the program code and it would do its thing and
figure out if we had a match or not, etc. So in that implementation, the user interface and the game
logic were all mixed in really tightly with each other.
Typically, though, in professional programming, we often want to look for opportunities to separate
the major chunks or sections or functions of our applications.
So it is quite common that if you can, you might separate the user interface code from the business
logic or in this case, since it's a game, the game logic of the code, and you might even separate
them out into two or more separate classes.
Even this is a very common pattern, and one of the reasons you might want to do that, typically,
especially in professional programming, is because it makes your code more flexible and gives you more
options.
So, for example, today we might have a guessing game that we interact with just with the command prompt
or terminal prompt, as we did before.
But tomorrow we might want to reuse the game logic that we already wrote, but use a graphical user
interface, maybe as a native looking Mac application, or maybe in the form of a mobile application.
So in those cases, if we wrote our game logic in a flexible, somewhat independent way, we would then
have the option to slap whatever type of user interface we want on top of it.
And so one of the nice things about writing our code in a more test driven approach is that it tends
to result in code that is more flexible right from the start, because that is how you kind of need
to write code in order to make it more testable anyway.
All right.
So having said all of that, don't worry if this doesn't mean very much to you yet you'll see what I
mean in just a moment here.
All right, so let's get started.
So what I want to do is I want to imagine that we will have a class that will represent the guessing
game engine, if you will, like the heart of the guessing game logic, right?
So we won't worry about printing words on a screen or anything like that.
We'll just focus more on having the rules and the core logic of the guessing game written in code somehow.
And we will write tests which will pretend to be a user interacting with this game engine.
All right, so let's see what this could look like.
So I'm going to open up the source folder, and first thing we want to do is create a class under test
since we're doing test first development.
So I will right click new Java class.
And just as before, I will not only name a class, but I will name that class with a package as well.
So I will use my company domain first neutrinos since that game and then I will call it guessing game.
Now.
This little bit here game, I could have called that anything I could have, call it combat, neutrino,
sister guessing game or or whatever.
It really doesn't matter.
You just want it to be unique like the whole entire thing just needs to be unique.
All right.
So I will click Oh, guessing game test.
All right, and now I can hit return.
All right, so we've got our test class here.
Now I'm going to make a new line here, and the first thing I need to do now is to decide, OK, what's
the very first thing that I even want to test?
So let's think about this for a moment.
So not only I want to figure out what's the first thing to test, but I want to figure out like what
are the easiest, smallest things that we could possibly test that would be somewhat meaningful, right?
So one thought that comes to my mind is, OK, let's imagine that we have this game engine.
Maybe the easiest thing we could do is to guess a correct number, right?
And then you're kind of like, done right there.
All right.
So maybe we could have a method where we just have a new guessing game engine and then we call, I guess,
and then we pass in a number and then maybe that guess method can return a string or something that
tells us if we got it right or something like that.
So let's just see what this might look like, and we may or may not actually go down this road entirely
right now.
I don't know yet, and that's OK.
We don't have to have the whole thing planned out.
We can just try some things and see what they feel like.
All right.
So let's say that we have a public void method, and this time I will start off my method name with
the word test just to mix it up a little bit.
Test simple when situation.
All right.
So in other words, I want to test a simple winning situation like where you just went right off the
bat.
All right.
So I'm going to imagine that I have, I don't know.
Let's say we have a class that represents the game engine itself, and maybe it could be called guessing
game.
Yeah, that's as good a name as anything, right?
Especially since we named our test guessing game test.
So we have a class called guessing game.
And then we're going to make an instance of this game and I'm going to just call it game so that I don't
have to type so much.
Game equals new guessing game.
All right.
So first thing is, we will want to let the ADC create the actual instance of our guessing game.
So I'm going to do an option return and create class guessing game, and I don't want it to go into
the test folder.
I wanted to go into the main folder, source main, click OK and then click OK.
All right, so there's our guessing game class.
All right, and then I will jump back over to the test with a command shift.
All right.
And now the guessing game reference to the class there is no longer read.
So now make a new line, and I'm going to imagine that we would want to make a guess, right?
So let's say like we called Game Dot guess and then we just guess the number three.
And then let's also imagine that this method guess would return a string, which will be like our message,
right?
And I don't know what to call this.
I'm just going to call it message.
All right.
So we have this method called guess as then, you know, like, make a guess and then we're going to
get back a message.
So let's take care of this error here before we proceed, I seldom, if ever like to proceed multiple
lines of code.
If I've got an error, I typically want to take care of that error before I proceed to the next line
of code.
Because the ADC typically isn't happy and I miss out on opportunities for the ADP to help make sure
I'm not doing something stupid because it kind of gets hung up on, Hey, what about that error you
had back on that other line, right?
So I'm going to put my cursor here again and then do an option return and create method.
Guess?
All right.
And so now just this before it's asking me, Hey, I'm going to create this method, guess?
Do you want it to return a string?
And the answer is yes, I do.
And then for some someone, the tab.
And then it's saying like, OK, do you want to pass in an integer into this method?
And yes, I do want to.
And then I will tab again.
And then what do I want to call this?
And I don't know.
Maybe I'll call it guest number and then I will hit enter.
And so now I get a default return statement here, and that just returns null.
And I didn't type this.
Obviously, the ID e generated that for me, and I'm going to leave it for now.
All right.
So then I will jump back over to the test class again.
All right, now, I will go to a new line and now I want to assert equals parentheses.
And again, I need to get rid of this red here.
Now, if I do an option return, then I need to import this method because it is a static method that
I want.
I'm not going to create the method.
I just want to import it.
So I choose import and we'll just go with this first option here.
Assertions that assert equals.
All right, there we go.
And now we want to specify.
And if you don't remember this, you can do a command p to show the parameters for this method.
So the first parameter is what you were expecting and then the second parameter is what you actually
got.
OK.
So let's say that we expect a message that says something like, you got it, and then we will refer
to the message there.
All right.
So there's our first test.
Now you may be thinking there are going to be a number of issues with this test and you would be right.
There's a lot of issues like one issue is the fact that I just put some random number in here expecting
this to be a winning situation.
Right?
Another issue is the fact that our game engine doesn't yet even generate any random numbers or anything
else.
But please recall that one of the rules of good TDD is we try not to write any more real code.
And I'm not talking about the test code, I'm talking about the real code.
So that would be code in the guessing game class itself.
We try not to write any more real code than we absolutely need until the test tells us to write that
code.
OK, and right now, this is about as much as I can think that this test is requiring of us.
So let's go ahead and run this now in order to make this method runnable as a test.
Do you recall what else we need to do?
We will need to place an at test annotation right above this method.
And so I will do an at test with a capital T.
And the first option here is the one that I want and I can click on that or hit enter.
And that caused the ID to automatically import this annotation into our code.
And now we have something that we can actually run.
So let's go ahead and run it.
Now we already know that this is going to fail.
And that's important, though ideally we want to first see our test methods fail, then we want to write
just enough code to make them pass.
And then we want to run them again and make them pass, and we want to just kind of go back and forth
like that.
That way, we make sure that we're actually making real progress and not just starting off with a test
that already for some reason would have passed no matter what you did.
All right.
So I will click the run button here and I will run this test.
And yeah, so it failed as we knew it would, and we got a message that we were expecting the words
You got it and we got a null back instead.
And just a quick reminder, null means kind of like empty object or an object that hasn't been set or
a variable that hasn't been set to an object.
All right.
Now what's the easiest way to get this test to pass?
Well, I think the easiest way to get this to pass would be to jump over here to the guests method and
simply make it return.
You got it.
And I understand this may seem extremely inane, but again, this is the standard approach to doing
TDD, which keeps us honest and helps to protect us from writing extraneous, unnecessary code that
isn't bringing any value.
And so we just take it in baby steps.
All right.
So we've written that message there, and now we can just go ahead and rerun our test and let's see
what we get.
All right.
So now it passes.
Very good.
So now let's jump back over to our test.
All right.
So we're going to go ahead and stop right here, and we'll pick up with this in the next lesson.
So I will see you there.