OK, so one of the last things that I want to cover is an explanation for this word static here.
OK?
I've been putting it off long enough.
Let's let's jump into it.
So I have stated numerous times now that the only place where work can get done is inside of a method
such as these methods here and methods must be contained inside of a class as they are.
OK.
So I think that should be pretty well understood by now.
However, there's one more thing you need to know, though, and that is that by default, these basic
methods here won't actually exist until we have created an instance of the class or of a class.
OK.
So please recall that a class is really just a blueprint for how to build an object.
And by the way, when I say object or instance of a class, an object is an instance of a class.
They are the same thing.
So I can use these terms interchangeably.
You'll hear instance, you'll hear class instance, you'll hear object.
OK.
They're all interchangeable concepts.
So a class is simply a blueprint for an instance or an object.
And because of that, you don't actually have anything that can do work until you create an actual class
under most circumstances.
OK.
That's the default behavior.
And so we must first create an instance of a class before we have methods that we can call, which is
why down here on Line 22 inside of this main method, the very first thing you see me do is to create
an instance of the person class.
That's what I'm doing here.
Create a new instance of person and then store a reference to that person in this variable called P1.
It is only after I have created the instance of the person that I can then call these basic methods
say hello, say something.
So one way of thinking about this is that we're taking the blueprint for a building and then we're constructing
the building.
OK?
And the methods of this class are like rooms of the building.
OK.
So you don't have any rooms of the building until you have constructed the building.
And now we can get work done in those rooms or in these methods.
OK.
Does that does that help make sense now?
Unfortunately, there is one caveat to this there is one way to make these methods or the rooms of the
building without constructing the building first.
OK?
To stick with this analogy a little bit further.
And that is to make what is called a static method.
OK.
If you make a static method or if you make a method static by putting these static keyword in front
of it.
You are essentially instructing Java to create that method to build that method or build that room to
use our metaphor, even without having built an instance of the class.
OK.
And indeed, that is what we're doing here for this main method.
Now, in the case of the main method, by making it static, that allows Java to be able to call this
method before the class has even been created.
So if we consider the order in which things are happening in this program, you know, we are telling
Java to run this class.
And so what Java does is it will first look through the methods of this class to see.
Is there a main method which is both public and static and void, actually?
OK.
Is there a method that matches what's called this this signature?
The signature of the method is simply all of the keywords and the inputs of that method.
So if there is a method that is public static void and called main and takes these inputs, then Java
will call that method automatically if you don't specify any other method for it to call.
And for Java to be able to run that method without first creating an instance of the class, the method
has to be static.
And so in effect, what happens is that this main method becomes the entry point or the starting point
for our program automatically.
OK.
Another way to say this is that in Java, the default starting point of a class has to be a method that
is public and static.
So one of the reasons for making a method static is so that you can use it as the entry point or starting
point of a program.
That's one key reason to make a method static.
Another case where you'll see static methods used in Java is what I like to call a utility class, and
that is a class that just has a lot of useful methods in it that help us to get things done, but don't
necessarily reflect behaviors of some modeled concept.
So although I think Java is a fantastic language, in my opinion, this is one of the places where some
of the decisions made in the creation of Java maybe don't quite fit perfectly.
And what I mean by that is Java is finely tuned for modeling concepts in code.
But sometimes you don't need or want to model a concept in code, but yet you still need to write code
that gets work done.
So sometimes you'll find yourself creating a class that doesn't really represent any real world or business
concept.
And perhaps it's just a place to group useful capabilities or useful methods together.
And that's what I often will refer to as a utility class.
And oftentimes, these kinds of utility classes will have methods on them that are static because you
don't need to create an instance of that class.
It wouldn't necessarily even make sense to do so.
You just want a nice place to put some very convenient methods that you might use throughout your program
or across multiple programs.
And so that's another place where you may see static methods being used.
There are a few other cases that you can encounter from time to time, and we may encounter a few of
those as we proceed with this course, but mainly here.
I just wanted to make sure that we explained why this main method is static while the other methods
are not static.
And I think that's going to wrap up this lesson.
So I would encourage you at this point to maybe try writing a little bit of code yourself.
Now you can try writing a similar class, as we have done here.
Try to do as much as you can from memory before you have to go and look back on this lesson.
For some reminders of how to do things, though, so that you can start to build up a little bit of
your muscle memory, if you will, on how to create a basic class and how to create a basic method,
and also how to create a public static void main method so that you can run that class.
OK.
So some ideas of some things that you could do to practice this would be similar to what I've done here.
Maybe make a method or two that just print something out on the screen.
Maybe make a method that takes input some other ideas or that you could continue forward with what I
did here.
With this add method, you could create a few more methods maybe create a subtract method.
I think you have all of the foundation that you need to be able to do those kinds of things now.
And with that being said, I will see you in the next lesson.