Hey, I wanted to make a quick little side lesson here, this is almost like a side bar to go into a
little bit more detail on the this key word.
For those of you who feel like you may still not be 100 percent certain what that keyword is for or
when you should use it.
For those of you who think you've got it, you can feel free to totally skip over this lesson, though
I will really promise to try to keep it short.
OK.
So I thought what I would do is revisit this diagram that we've looked at early in the course, and
I can use this to kind of give you a little bit more of an understanding of the this keyword.
OK.
So what we're looking at here is a diagram of a package comporte example dot model.
And then in this package, we've got several classes.
We've got this big main class here, which is just kind of like a blown up class so that we can kind
of see more of the details that are in it.
This is the person class here.
So this this this green square here, that's the person class.
And then we've got a few other classes here chair, computer, car, whatever.
So let me just review a few components of this class with you to give you a little bit more or added
context to understand the this keyword.
So in this class, we've got two fields.
Well, actually, we've got three filled.
Technically, we've got this name filled the date of birth field and then we've got this what looks
like a three dimensional thing here, it's actually kind of standing up.
Now this picture that I'm showing here is from a top down view, basically.
And so it's a 2D view, but this one field here called greeting is actually in 3D kind of standing up.
It's not a two dimensional flat thing like the name and Dobby are.
And the reason for this is because it represents a static field.
OK.
Anyway, so we've got this name in this date of birth field here and then these little smaller squares
with doors on them, they're meant to sort of imply rooms, if you will.
These are methods.
OK?
And they're color coding indicates their level of visibility, with red being private and green being
public.
OK.
So as you should know, by now, when our code is executing, what happens is that we have a thread
which you can think of as a little character and the thread visits our code.
And you know, that executable code, for the most part, can only exist inside of methods.
OK.
So anyway, so you can imagine then that a thread would enter a method and then that method would have
lines of code.
I don't think I have any example of what that would look like.
Let me see here, actually.
Yeah, here we go.
I actually do have a diagram of so yeah, this little weird looking guy here, by the way, this little
guy, he is the basically the mascot for Java and his name is Duke.
And you can think of him as the thread.
OK.
And then here we have a method which I have rendered in three dimensions a three dimensional method
called main.
And if you see here, I've even got a line of code here.
OK.
So now you don't have to imagine it.
You can actually see.
Here's thread getting ready to go in to this main method to read and execute this line of code.
OK.
All right.
So I said all of that just to set the stage.
So imagine that thread is inside of this method here, and he's executing lines of code.
And let's also imagine that this method declares a variable called words.
OK.
This variable here is defined inside of this method.
So because it is defined inside of this method, it only has scope within this method.
And you can see that really clearly in this diagram.
This word's variable here only has scope inside of this speak method.
So when the thread moves out of this speak method and into another method like get aids, for example,
the thread can no longer access the data in this variable called words, because this variable called
words only exists within the speak method and does not exist in any other method.
OK.
However, these variables out here, which are fields of the person class because they are outside of
these individual methods.
But inside of this class, the thread can access these variables from anywhere.
OK, so if the thread is inside of the speak variable.
Thread can access name or date of birth if he's inside the Get AIDS method, he can access name or or
date of birth, et cetera, et cetera.
OK, now the this key word, no matter where the thread is, the thread can refer to any items that
are directly inside of the class using the this keyword.
Now he doesn't necessarily have to use this keyword, but he can use it.
So that's one thing there.
The this keyword is generally optional.
OK.
So if the thread was inside of this speak method here and wanted to refer to this name field here,
we could have a line of code that says something like this dot.
Name a line of code in here in this speak method that says this name or this date of birth and the this
keyword really just refers to this whole entire object.
Now I'm kind of switching back and forth between referring to this as a class versus referring to it
as an object.
You will hear developers do this frequently because they truly are two sides of the same coin right.
And it just depends on the context.
When you're talking about a thread executing code, you're almost certainly talking about an object
when we're talking about just looking at a diagram or something.
We're often more often talking about a class, right?
But there are two sides of the same coin.
So the this keyword refers to an object, though it does not refer to a class because it only has meaning
when a thread is actually executing code.
And for there to be something that can be referred to by this, it has to be an object.
OK.
So this whole entire person object instance would be this.
So when we say this dot name, we're talking about the name variable or the name field that is directly
inside of this instance of this class, OK, or this date of birth.
Now you could not say this, that words here, because the variable called words is not a direct member
of the person class.
It is inside of the speak method.
OK.
So you can only use the this keyword to refer to direct members of a class which is in the form of an
object.
OK.
So then these words in bar one, bar two and all these little blue things here and VAR one, VAR two
here.
These are not direct members of the class, and therefore you cannot say this sort VAR one when wanting
to refer to these things.
OK.
Furthermore, and I apologize, I don't have an example of this, but hopefully you get it.
If I had this name field here as a direct member of the class, but let's imagine that I also had a
name variable, a local name variable inside of any one of these methods.
So let's say like in this speak method here, let's imagine that maybe instead of this being called
words, it was called name.
So in that scenario, I would have two variables called name.
I'd have one at the field level and then I'd have a different name variable at the method level or a
local variable.
OK, now in that case, if I had some code that wanted to work with this name field here and not the
one that was local to this method, in that case, I would have to let Java know which name field was
I talking about.
Was I referring to the local one?
Or was I referring to the class instance one or the member one, right?
And in order to be clear, I would need to use this name when referring to this one.
In that case, because otherwise there would be ambiguity.
Does that make sense?
But I would only need the this keyword in that circumstance where I've got the potential for ambiguity
because I have a field member with the same name as a local variable.
OK, now I can also use the this keyword in front of method names because they are direct members of
the class.
So if I'm in the speak method and I want to call the Get AIDS method, I could have a line of code that
says this does get edge.
I could do that.
Do I need to know?
But you will sometimes see code written that way, and I didn't want you to think that there's some
magic reason why sometimes you see developers use the this keyword, and in fact, I may occasionally
use it in places where I don't absolutely have to.
So first off, I just want you to keep in mind that oftentimes the this keyword is optional.
OK.
You often don't need it.
And in fact, probably about the only time that you do need it is to clear up any ambiguity because
you have a field and a local variable with the exact same name, and you want to be clear as to which
variable you're talking about.
So here we have the constructor for our card in the enum stuff that we were learning recently, and
this constructor has two local variables called suit and rank.
But the class has two fields called suit and rank also, so there's potential for real ambiguity there.
And so you can see right here in the body of this method that we're taking this local suit and we want
to set that value on the field called suit.
And so to make sure there's no confusion here, we must use the this keyword to say we want to set this
suit, which is a member of this class.
We want to set this suit to the local suit, which is getting passed into this constructor.
OK, so that's one of the most common ways that you will see the this keyword used.
OK, and then here I chose to use the this keyword in the two string method to refer to the rank, which
is here now.
I absolutely did not need this keyword here.
I just felt like using it, to be perfectly honest with you.
So I will delete that and nothing's going to break at all.
This will still work just as well as it did before in this particular case.
Now you will see a lot of developers just automatically use the this keyword any time they are referring
to member variables or fields of a class, just so that there's no possibility for ambiguity whatsoever.
All right.
So I actually went longer than I was planning to as usual.
Like I said, though, you were free to skip over this if you wanted to.
But hopefully I have completely demolished any questions or ambiguity about what the this keyword is
or what it does.
So I'll see you in the next one.