All right, so in this next lesson, we're going to just continue on with our TV version of the guessing
game.
So in the last lesson, we got the first little test to kind of pass, but it's kind of a fake pass
because we basically just hardcoded the response from our new guess method to return exactly the string
that we were looking for.
So there's no actual logic, no business logic, no game logic actually implemented inside of this guessing
method here.
We're just taking it a number, ignoring it and then just returning something because that's all that
the test is kind of calling for us to do at the moment.
So now let's look at what we're doing here.
So our test is called test simple win situation, meaning, you know, we want to test out the scenario
where we just directly put in a winning number and then we get a winning message like, you got it.
Now one thing that I'm thinking is, well, OK, in this particular case here, we just put a random
number in here.
But in real life, maybe we'd want to be able to know what is the actual random number that the game
generated.
And then at least for our test to be able to query the game to find out what is that winning number
and and then take that winning number and pass it in right kind of equivalent to what we did in the
real guessing game.
If you recall, when we were trying to manually test out various situations and scenarios, we put a
little system that out that print line or print out right after we were generating the number and we
were printing out the randomly generated numbers so that we, the tester could know what that number
was.
I think we need an equivalent here.
And what I'm thinking we could do is to add another method onto our guessing game that would actually
return the randomly generated number and then we can use this.
So maybe something like a game dot get brand number and then this method would return.
I guess integer random equals right?
And then instead of passing in this hardcoded three, maybe we would just pass in the random number
instead.
Right?
So that way, we'd be guaranteed that eventually, when this game engine does start truly generating
a random number, we always win in this scenario.
OK.
So I think we just need to implement this method get random number.
So if I put my cursor right here on right after the get random number method and then do an option return,
I can create method.
Get random number.
There we go.
And for now, I will let it just do the default, which is to return to zero, because that's all our
test is really calling for at this time.
All right, and then I will rerun this test, and it should still pass.
OK, cool.
All right.
So what now?
I'm kind of thinking, well, we've got a test to test the simple win situation.
Maybe we can have a test to test the simple lose situation.
Let's let's see what that might look like.
So I'm going to start off by copying this existing test, and then I will paste here and I will rename
this test simple.
Lose lose situation.
And we're creating our guessing game.
And so for this now.
When we did this with the previous implementation of our guessing game, in order to guarantee that
we always would lose or rather that we would always guess an incorrect number which may be, I might
even change this method name in a moment here, because I think that's the actual situation we want
to test here is test what happens when we get the wrong number.
Yeah.
You know, let's change changes.
Test.
Wrong gas situation.
Maybe test one one wrong guess situation.
We want to make sure that we don't accidentally submit the correct number so I can think of a couple
of ways that we might do this.
We could query for the random number and then add +1 to it or minus one from it and then throw that
number in here.
However, what if the random number plus or minus one ends up being maybe like out of the range that
we are allowing or something like that?
Do we want to do that?
Well, I'll tell you what or what we did in the previous guessing game was that we just always submitted
negative.
No guesses to ensure that we were never going to accidentally hit the right number since our allowed
range was really like one to 10 or something like that.
I think maybe we'll just do it that way still, because that's what we did before someone to delete
that thing.
And then we'll just do like a negative five.
And then we will assume that for this scenario, if one wrong guess that you would test one wrong guess
situation, then we'll just say.
You didn't you didn't get it.
Yeah, I guess that's it.
All right.
So let's run all of the tests and see what we get.
OK, so as expected, the first test passes and the second one fails because we hardcoded.
You got it as the return message there.
So now we need to do the smallest, simplest thing to get this method to pass.
So we want to respond with you didn't get it as a result of passing a negative number in.
So let's go look at the gas method here.
So what we could do, the simplest thing to do and perhaps would be to maybe just use a conditional,
maybe something like, well, you know, we could use a ternary operator and then we could keep it really
short and sweet, something like if the guest number is greater than.
Or equal to zero, then return.
You got it.
Otherwise return.
You didn't get it.
And it's about the simplest way we could do this, I think.
Let's rerun all the tests and see what happens.
Hey, there you go.
So we made that all pass.
Now again, I understand that these little changes we're making are us kind of just dancing around the
real issues.
But again, we just want to evolve the tests to force us to write the correct code rather than to to
just assume what all of the code we would need here should be.
That's kind of the whole point, and by doing so, we will end up with close to 100 percent tested testable
code and hopefully no unnecessary lines of code.
All right.
So let's jump back over to the test, and let's think of another scenario that will force us to flesh
out our game engine more.
So test one wrong guest situation.
Well, I don't know, so we could test what happens when you have to run guesses, or maybe we could
test what happens when you have one wrong gas, followed by a correct gas?
Or actually what would happen if we tested another wrong gas situation where we did not hard code a
negative right?
Because we know in real life there will be nine positive numbers that we could guess that would still
be wrong, right?
So I don't know.
Let's see what this looks like if we do something like test.
So let's change this method now.
Let's flesh this out a little more.
Test one wrong gas situation.
Let's call this test one wrong negative, and I'll just write NEG negative guess situation.
And then for this one, let's test one wrong positive.
Guess situation and maybe to derive our positive for now.
Maybe we will go ahead and do something along these lines.
Well, we'll go grab the.
Random number and then we'll just say random number plus one, and for right now, we're not going to
worry about it being out of range or anything since we're not actually enforcing any ranges anyway.
So we know that the random number will eventually always be a positive number between, I guess, one
in 10.
And therefore, if we just add one to it, that will be guaranteed to be the wrong number and also be
guaranteed to be positive.
All right.
And so now let's run all of the tests.
And so we got to that passed and one that failed in the one that failed is the positive one.
And just as I thought we were expecting, you didn't get it, but we got a you got it because currently
our game logic simply thinks that if we pass a non-negative number in that you win.
So now we need to figure out how to make it smarter than that.
So let's see here.
Maybe the easiest thing we could do now would be something like if.
The guest number equals the random number, then you got it, otherwise you didn't get it.
So that would be pretty easy to do, I think.
So if we do, guest number equals with the equals operator two equal signs.
And then what we can do is we can just call this same method, I suppose, for now, get random number.
Now we're going to have to be a little careful with that.
Perhaps when we flesh this out a little more, I can already kind of foresee something here.
But for now, I think this will make the tests that last test pass.
Let's see.
So we'll rerun everything.
Yeah, there we go.
So now everything's passing.
All right.
Test one wrong positive guest situation.
What's another test that we can do here?
So we've got one winning situation.
One wrong negative situation.
One wrong positive situation.
So one thing I'm wondering about here is the whole point of the guessing game is that it should start
off by generating a random number.
And right now we know that our game is not generating a random number.
So I think we may want to have a test that somehow validates that our game is actually generating random
numbers whenever we start it.
Oh, actually, OK, so now the next thing that I think we want to do and I apologize, I actually forgot
this.
I should have done it on the second test, but that's OK.
We're on the third test.
We've got duplication, right?
We're generating this guessing game.
We're creating a new instance of the guessing game each time within the each test method here.
And so we can do something about that.
Now we've got the choice to make.
Do we want to extract this game variable out into a field and then initialize it in the field, which
would mean that we'd be using the same exact game engine for each test?
Or do we want to create a new game engine or guessing game each time a test is run?
So we know we're going to have to eventually generate a random number.
So I think a big question is when do we generate that random number?
Right?
If we generate the random number each time we create a new guessing game, which is kind of what I'm
leaning towards, then I would think that we probably do want to have a new instance of this guessing
game for each test.
Right?
And if that is the case, then I think we will want to initialize this guessing game in a setup method.
Right.
So we discussed and one of the previous lessons the difference between initializing the system under
test in a field declaration versus initializing it in a setup method.
The difference is really whether or not you want each test method to share the same system under test,
the exact same instance or if you want different ones.
I'm leaning towards having different instances of the guessing game for each test method.
So let's try that out and see what that will look like.
So if we select the game variable here, we can right click on it, go down to refactor and then introduce
a field.
Just like so and then we can initialize it.
We select this, well, that's acting kind of weird in the setup.
Just like that and then hit return.
All right.
And so now the ABC has extracted out a declaration for the game, the variable there and then it is
initializing it inside of the setup and just a reminder here.
So this setup method having the sanitation of before each means that before each test runs J Unit our
testing framework, we'll call this method each time before this test runs, which means that each test
method will get its own new instance of the guessing game.
And the previous instances of the guessing game will be marked for garbage collection by the JVM, the
Java virtual machine, which I generally refer to as this Java.
All right, so that's just a quick little reminder of what this means.
So now having done this, I can delete this line.
And this line on line 32.
And when whenever we do this kind of refactoring, it's always a good idea to just rerun all the tests
and make sure that what was working before is still working.
So I'm going to rerun.
OK, good.
So apparently, we did not break anything.
Very good.
All right.
So now I think we want to write some kind of a test, if possible, to help us determine whether or
not the game engine is actually generating random numbers, right?
Because that's the whole point of the guessing game is to generate random numbers if it only uses zero
every time as it currently is.
That's not a very good guessing game.
So let's see.
What can we do in a test to ensure that we are generating random number?
I'm going to start off by copying one of these existing methods, and I will paste.
And let's see.
We will test that test random number, generation, something like that.
So we need to think of a strategy for how we can actually ensure that random numbers are being generated.
So let's think about this because I think I think this this may not be super obvious, but I think we're
going to have some fun with this, actually.
So our game is supposed to generate a random number between one and 10.
Right?
And so if we were to run this game 10 times in a row under ideal random circumstances, you might think
that you should see numbers one through 10 equally come up within the random generator, right?
If you run it 10 times, you would expect ideally to see the numbers one through 10.
One time in a perfect random generator.
Now, of course, I already know that the random generators that we have access to here are not that
perfect, and we would need to run it more than 10 times if we wanted to have a chance of seeing numbers
one through 10 come up at least once.
So I'm wondering what would happen if we were to run this game engine 100 times, perhaps.
And then if we kept track of whether or not each of the numbers one through 10 was selected, right?
And then at the end of that 100 times, we just kind of tabulate and say, you know, did we ever get
a one?
Did we ever get it to?
Did we ever get a three, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera?
And that might let us know if we have a decent random number generator.
There's I think there's several ways that we could do this, but one way that I'm thinking about might
be, so let's say that we generate numbers one two three four five, six, seven, eight, nine and
10.
And then let's say that we every time we see a number come up from the get random number method, let's
say that we just kind of made a tally mark.
If you will write something like you put a one there and I'll add a one for one, we see a two and a
three.
So, right, so every time these numbers show up, let's say we don't get a five.
The five doesn't show up and then seven doesn't show up in eight does and nine does and 10 does write
something like that.
Now, if we could keep track of that somehow, then at the end of running this program 100 times or
at least generating the random numbers 100 times if we were to add up all of the ones, if we had a
perfect random generator or a good random generator and we ran it 100 times, you would expect that
all of these, including the five and the seven, would have come up at least once.
And so you would expect that if you added up all these ones, you would get at least a 10.
Right?
And then you would know that any number that you added up, that was less than 10.
Especially now let's say that the number two comes up multiple times.
So in that case, maybe we don't tally.
Maybe we simply say, if you ever get any of these to come up, just put a one in it.
Otherwise, let it be a zero or nothing at all.
Right.
So we don't like double and triple count.
We just either it's a one or two zero.
All right.
And then we just add up all the ones.
And so if every single number had come up at least once, you'd have a 10 and anything less than that
would be less than a 10.
And then you would know that the random number generation wasn't maybe completely up to snuff or we
hadn't implemented the random number generation, right?
Furthermore, I think the lower this sum would be, the worse your logic for generating random numbers
would probably be right.
There are definitely some other techniques we could use, but I kind of like this approach because it
tells us a number of things, right?
Like how far off is our random number generation technique?
And it gives us a pretty easy way to quickly determine whether or not we are able to generate.
Random numbers that run the gamut of our range.
So now the question is, OK, how could we code this in a test, right?
Well, here are some patterns that I'm seeing.
I'm seeing that we want to track something that happens across the numbers one through 10 and we want
to associate in this case, some numbers, maybe one in zero with the numbers on top.
And so can you think of a mechanism that we have already learned in programming that would allow us
to associate these bottom numbers with these top numbers?
And this might not be obvious to you, but take a moment to think about this and then I'll tell you
what I'm thinking.
All right.
So I'm thinking this might be a decent scenario for us to use an array.
Now we learned about a raise a while back and you might not remember them, but if you may recall,
an array is basically a collection of things.
You can have an array of integers or an array of strings whenever we create a public static void.
Main method In fact, I'll make one right quick here.
The main method gets passed in to it and array, which is signified by these left and right square brackets.
It gets passed into it an array of strings, which is referred to with this name args, which is short
for arguments.
OK, so that's one example of an array.
So go back and watch the lesson where we cover arrays if you need a quick refresher on how they work.
So one of the characteristics of an array is that arrays have elements in them, and those elements
can be accessed with an index.
And that index is just a number usually zero based, though, but it's just the number.
And so these numbers here could be the index into the array, and we could have an array of integers
and the integers that we would store in the array would be zeros and ones.
So what I'm thinking here is that we would call get random number and it would generate a random number.
And if the implementation of get random number is proper, meaning that it actually truly is generated,
generating a random number between one and 10, then we would take that number and then we would use
it as the index into an array.
So let's say that we call it get random number and it generates a three.
So then we would pass that into an array to say, give us the array element three.
And then we would set that element to a one and then we call get random number again and maybe the next
time it generates a six, and so then we use that six, which would be stored in here to access the
elements six of the same array, and we set that to a one.
But let's also imagine that we never get random number to generate a two.
And so the element two of this array would just be zero, perhaps by default.
Right.
And so when we then finish generating the calling random number, let's say, 100 times or so, we could
simply add up all of the numbers in all of the elements of this array and see if we got 10 and if we
got something less than 10, then we know that our maybe our random number generating method is not
ideal yet.
All right.
Now, if we want to run this 100 times, can you think of a way that we could do this within one test
to run this, plus the logic I just outlined 100 times?
Can you think of how you could do that?
Go ahead and take a moment to think about it?
All right, so I'm thinking we could use a for loop and just tell the far loop to run 100 times, right?
All right.
So without further ado, let's let's try this out and see see how we can do this.
So let's start with the loop.
So we'll have a for loop for integer counters.
So the first thing for our for loop inside of it is we usually will declare and initialize a counter
variable of some sort so we can have an integer called counter or count or whatever.
It doesn't really matter what it's called.
You could call it index, maybe or maybe not index.
And then you'll initialize it.
And so I'll initialize this to zero for now.
And then you'll use a semicolon.
And then the next part of the for loop is where we teach the for loop, when it should stop.
So in this case, I think we want to say something like while the counter is less than 100 because we
want to count 100 times, so this would go from zero to 99, actually.
All right.
But that would be 100.
And then another semicolon and then we just have to increment the counter counter plus plus like so.
All right.
And then we have the body of the loop, which we start off with a curly brace.
Like so and all right.
And now we can start calling this game that get random numbers.
So I'm actually going to grab this line here, line 41 and bring it inside and then indent.
All right.
So we're going to call get random number and then we're going to need an array.
Now we want this array to exist beyond just the scope of this loop, and therefore we need to declare
this array outside of the loop.
So I'm actually going to trade a new line up here and to create and declare an array.
We have to tell it what the data type is.
So we're going to say here's an integer array and then the name of the array.
I don't know.
Maybe I will call it random number count.
Notice how I abbreviate things out of laziness, really?
Now I think in the lesson where we talked about arrays, I may have shown you that we can initialize
with curly braces, but in this case, we don't actually want to initialize this.
Instead, we just want to say that we want an array of 10 elements.
So to do that, we can say new and 10 colon like so.
So what this is saying is give us a new array of integers with 10 elements.
OK.
All right.
And then down here, now we can start actually storing information in the elements in the 10 elements
of this array.
So what we will do is simply we will access the array by name random count.
And then we use the square brackets and then we access whichever element so that say that get random
number generator for.
So that means we would want element four of this array.
So we'll pass and whatever we get back from this call.
So what?
So we can say random, numb.
Equals and then all we have to do is hard code the number one in here.
OK.
That's all we have to do.
This is hard code one.
All right.
So imagine we call it get random number and it generates the number one.
And so then we store into element one, the number one.
Then we call it again in this loop and it generates a two.
And so we store one in here and then engineering to three.
Now, of course, in real life, our random number generator probably wouldn't go an order like that,
but I'm just kind of trying to illustrate the point, right?
So if it generated each of these numbers, then we'd end up storing a one in each of them.
And then when we're done with this loop, we could run another loop, which simply sums up all the numbers
in this array and hopefully we get a 10 back out.
And then if it repeats certain numbers, that's fine.
That means you already had a one there.
You're not hurting anything by setting it to one again.
And if it misses any numbers, then by default, because they are integers, the default value of an
integer is always a zero anyway.
All right.
So that should set all of the ones for all of the random numbers 100 times.
And then what we'll need to do is to simply sum them all up and to do that.
I think maybe the easiest thing to do is just to use another for loop again.
So on another line, we'll set up another for loop, and I think it'll look the same integer.
In fact, I'm going to use the exact same parameters.
My own counter is less than 100 counter + +.
Now, the reason I can reuse this same counter variable here is because this variable counter only has
scope within this for loop.
So this counter here is different from this counter here, right, because they are only available or
valid inside of this loop.
And once the thread leaves this loop, this counter variable ceases to exist.
And once the thread enters this loop, this is a brand new counter variable that's separate and distinct
from that one.
OK, so that's why I can reuse this name.
All right.
So here we just want to sum up the numbers.
Now I am actually thinking we will want an integer that holds the thumb.
And again, because I want to use that integer outside of this loop, I think we need to define it.
We need to declare it outside of the loop.
So let's let's declare an integer called for now.
Just I'll call it some, and that's all we need.
There is default will be zero with default value will be zero.
So I don't have to say some equals zero.
It already is zero.
All right.
And so now all we need to do.
Oh, actually, one more thing now, actually, we don't need to go 100 times here because we only have
10 elements.
All we're going to do is add up all of the values of those 10 elements.
And so we only need to go to 10 here, 029.
However, now we need to be careful here the numbers that we could be generating with our random number
generator.
Once we implement the logic are meant to be one through 10, not zero through nine.
However, this here currently is expecting zero through nine.
So we want to be careful here how we line this up.
So a couple of thoughts I'm having are that we could just be safe and go zero through 11, which I think
I'm fine to do.
And that way we make sure we get everything or else we need to be a little more careful with what we're
doing up here for now, out of laziness, I suppose I'm going to just say zero to 11.
We may have to come back and revisit this, though.
All right, so let's see now.
All we need to do is to access the array element that is pointed to by this counter.
So what that would look like is random num count counter, right?
So then that gives us the number.
And now what we want to do is just add that to the sum.
And the way we can do that is to say some.
Now there's a few ways we can do this.
We can say some equals some plus that number.
OK, we're being told that the sum may not have been initialized.
So just to make that happy, we can come up here and just say equals zero.
All right.
So what this should do is now we're going to loop over the numbers zero through 11 and we're going to
access each value that would be these values here.
So these are the element indexes which would be in the counter.
And then these would be an example of the potential values that would be in there.
So when this is when counter, it's one we're going to access element one of the array and get whatever
is inside of it, which will be either a zero or a one.
And then we will add that to the sum.
Now do you remember there's also a shorthand way to say some equals some plus random count?
Do you remember what that was?
Instead of writing all of this out, we could just do some plus equals.
So that means the same thing, just in a shorthand sum, equal sum, plus whatever.
Just a little shorthand.
All right.
And then when we're done, I wouldn't mind temporarily just printing out that sum just to make sure
that our logic makes some kind of sense, no pun intended.
And then we're going to need an assertion someone to get rid of that line.
And I think our assertion will be pretty easy.
So if we're completely up to snuff, then I think our assertion is that we would have 10 write a value
of 10, which would mean that all of the elements had been selected at least once.
So 10, we're going to expect a 10 from some and actually in in what sense we are using this assertion
here.
We don't actually need to print that out because the ADP is going to tell us in the report what this
number was, if it's especially if it's different from what we got there.
So we don't actually need that.
All right.
I know this is kind of a lot.
Let's run it real quick, though, and see what we end up with and then we'll go from there.
So see here.
I'm going to go all the way up to the top, and I'm just going to rerun all of the tests.
OK.
Very good.
So that last one is failing.
And we've got an index out of bounds exception.
All right.
So let's see what happened there.
Now, if we come down here and we look at this line, it's going to tell us what line of code were the
exception is happening line 49 and we can actually click on that and it'll take take us right there.
So right here.
Oh, OK, I see.
So I'm told our code to access up to Element 10, right?
Because anything less than 11, which means 10 and there is no Element 10 because we only have 10 elements
in the array.
And the first element is is element zero, which means that the last element would be element nine.
And this allows us to access an element 10 of which there is not one, right?
So we're going to have to think think about these index bounds a little more carefully now.
So let's see here.
Maybe the easiest thing to do for now would actually be to just make 11 elements here.
What I'm concerned with is that eventually we will implement our game logic such that it only generates
numbers one through 10, which means that Element Zero might not ever get used right.
Element zero of this array might never get used.
So we could just let it go unused, which is what I'm inclined to do.
Or else we'd have to get a little fancier and generate this random number.
And then when we set and then when we use that random number, we do something random number minus one,
which I don't really want to do because I think that could get a little confusing.
So I think instead, we'll just generate 11 elements here and now everything should be in sync.
All right.
So let's run that again.
So it's still failing, which it should.
But now it's failing are.
And a very expected way, we expected 10 and we only got one.
And that makes sense to me.
Currently, they get random, no method is returning zero, which is outside of the range that we will
be allowing in the future, but we haven't implemented that yet.
So right now it's generating a zero.
And so we're setting element zero to one and then we're summing up all of the elements.
So we're setting element zero to one, whereas all the remaining elements would be zero.
And so when you sum all of that up, you get a one.
And so this is failing, which is telling us that our random number generation algorithm isn't implemented
yet.
All right.
So I know that this has been a long lesson, and some of you may feel like you're struggling a little
bit to follow along.
Don't worry.
Stay with me on this.
We'll get this working.
And then for those of you who still feel like you need a little more help, I will make an additional
lesson to go even into more detail, to go really slowly and make sure that you can really see how this
is working.
So please don't worry, just just stick with us, OK?
And so I will see you in the next video.