OK.
Welcome back.
There are a few more character classes and symbols that we should take a look at that you may encounter
from time to time or a few of them, a couple of them you'll almost certainly encounter very frequently,
in fact.
So for this, I think we're going to leave the the phone number stuff alone.
And I don't know, I'm going to just create a new class here so you can follow along.
So I'm going back over to the source folder here, and I'm going to right click and see new Java class,
and I don't feel like trying to think of a fancy name here.
So what did I call the last one next practice?
I don't know.
So I'll call this one.
Rejects Practice two.
All right.
Not a great name, but for what we're doing, it doesn't really matter.
And I'm going to close the little output window that their loops.
It's not the one I wanted.
I wanted to close this one.
OK?
And as always, will create a public static void main method with SVM all lowercase and then hit return.
OK, so now let's just make a system out like we did at the beginning of learning about regex here,
and we'll make a string literal.
I don't know, let's say like dorgi, and then we'll use the matches method again, and we'll provide
it with a regular expression again.
All right.
So now the next symbol that I want to teach is called the DOT.
So a dot in a regular expression represents any character at all.
OK.
So with this word, doggy, which is what is that five characters, we could match that with five dots
four five.
Just like that.
OK.
So if we run this?
That is a match.
If we only have three dots and we run this.
That is not a match, because we have five characters in the input string and we told it to find a pattern
of only three.
OK.
So the matches any character at all?
Any character?
So it's kind of a catchall on the surface.
It might not seem that useful, but we will see in a later lesson where we'll start to put a lot of
the techniques that we're learning together.
Sometimes you need that dot just kind of to say and then forget about the rest of whatever's in a string.
So if that doesn't make sense right now, it will shortly.
Okay, so you can do a number of things with this dot we could if we wanted to match this whole entire
pattern, we didn't really care what it what it says.
You would just want to match it.
Besides using five dots, you could use a an asterisks, which is a very common pattern.
In Red X, you'll see this a lot.
So this would match, obviously.
So with this, I'm not going to run all of these examples, but OK, so.
So that's one or more, right?
It's one or more.
This one would not match because this means what?
Zero or one?
And we have five.
So zero or one is not five.
So that would not match.
OK.
Some other symbols to be aware of the carrot.
Now we learned about the carrot in the context of a bracket expression, right?
Like an expression like looks like this where you have a carrot.
And then we did something like.
And and in this context, when the carrot symbol is inside of square brackets, this means opposite
of or not.
So we're saying match any character that isn't in a or a B or C or D.
That's what this means inside of square brackets.
However, outside of square brackets, this matches the beginning of a line or the beginning of a string.
OK, so this carrot here would match where my cursor is right now in that string just the beginning
of that string?
OK.
So I could say something like one, two, three, four or five, right?
Let's see if this matches.
Yes.
So this matches because I'm saying start at the beginning of the of the string or of the line and then
five characters of any sort.
OK, so that matches and then along with this carrot, meaning the beginning of the string or the beginning
of the line, there's also another symbol that means the end of the line and that is the dollar sign.
OK.
So there is actually the end of this string right here.
So let's run this and see if that matches.
Yes, so.
So that matches as well.
Now, if I were to put that dollar sign.
Not at the end.
I'll get rid of this, right?
If I were to do this.
That no longer matches, because that makes no sense.
I'm saying start at the beginning of the string, which is here, then go to characters, which is the
DNA.
Oh, then there should be the end of that string, which there isn't.
Now, technically, depending on what operating system you're on and what your settings are for the
regular expression engine, this dollar sign can match what is called a new line character, which in
normal text would cause a line of text to go down to the next line.
But different operating systems and word processors and text editors will encode going to the next line
in slightly different ways.
There's two main ways that I can think of on Unix systems that is an operating system like Linux, not
Windows, and not Mac.
While the Mac is technically a Unix system now.
I digress anyway.
On Unix systems by default, simple Unix text editors will encode going to the new line with just a
new line character.
One character that means go to the new line.
OK.
And that's a non-visible character, by the way.
It's an invisible character.
It is it.
It exists in the data of a file, but it does not visually show up on the screen other than to cause
text to go to the next line.
And then I think on Windows and some other editors by default, to go to the next line, they will use
a combination of two characters, both a new line and a carriage return.
And these are actually let me just show real quick.
There are actually ASCII codes for this, and we talked a little bit about Unicode and character encoding.
So let me just show you an ASCII code table.
I'm going to bring a browser over here real quick and we'll Google for ASCII.
It's AC III.
And let's see what Wikipedia has to say about this.
Here we go.
Yeah, so here's a here's an ASCII table, essentially.
And so there are a number of characters, wolf.
First of all, we'll start with, yeah, let's look at some of the more straightforward characters that
you'd be more familiar with.
Mostly visible ones other than the space, right?
So as I stated in a previous lesson, every character on a computer system has a numeric value associated
with it.
And it is those numeric values that are actually stored in the memory of the computer.
So the computer doesn't literally store ABCD.
Instead, it just stores numbers that represent ABCD and et cetera.
OK.
And every single character that can be represented in the computer has a number.
Now there are a few different character in coatings or schemes, if you will, for assigning a number
to a character or a letter or whatever the original and possibly most famous encoding that was used
generally in America, at least.
And I suppose by extension, probably a lot of the world is called ASCII.
I think it stands for American Standard Code.
Here, hold on.
Let's see what does this stand for?
American standard code for information interchange?
OK.
And I think this came out.
Probably.
Yeah, there you go, 1961.
So it's quite old.
OK?
And just some some computer people got together and decided things like Here what we want to go.
They decided that a capital A. would be the decimal number 41.
Capital B would be, I'm sorry.
The decimal number 65, a capital B would be decimal number 66 and so on and so on.
These other numbers here are other number system representations of the number 65 if we scroll up to
the top here.
So we've got octal and hexadecimal.
These are just other number systems.
So in decimal, which is based 10, I'm not going to get super deep into the numbering systems and things.
But you know, our normal counting, if you're not a computer nerd is called decimal or base 10, right?
You have 10 digits, and that's how we typically count.
But there are other number systems besides base 10 hexadecimal is base 16, so they have the digits
zero through nine, and then they threw in a few letters as well.
So that's why you see here like this to a that's a number, but it's a hexadecimal number.
OK, and then there's also octal, which is base eight.
So they got rid of two two possibilities.
You know, they they got rid of two fingers and they only got to eight.
And the reason that exists is because there have historically been some conveniences on computer systems
to a number of things with a base of only eight.
So when you get to eight, you kind of start over again.
OK, but decimal is probably what you and I are most comfortable with.
And so they give us these three representations actually give us four representations, and then they
give us the binary representation as well right there.
OK.
So, all right, sorry to have gone down that rabbit hole, but it helps to give you a little bit more
insight.
So having seen that, all of these standard letters and characters and things have a number associated
with them in some encoding.
OK, now we'll look at a few of the characters that are not visible because I want you to understand
this as well a little bit.
So I was talking about a new line character, which will tell certain types of computer systems or text
editors to drop down to the next line just to continue showing text or whatever.
And that new line character, as I typically call it here, it's called a line feed.
And so it is represented in some systems as a backslash in.
Let's see what is what this this column represent character escape sequences in C programming.
Okay?
So if you were programming in C or Java, for that matter, backslash in is the common representation
for this character, which humans don't see what their eyes typically.
But it instructs the editor to just or a printer, for example, to go down to the next line.
OK.
And then there's also the carriage return character, which does something kind of similar, and these
two characters have their own codes.
The new line is a 10, and the carriage return is a 13.
OK, so why did I go through all of explaining this?
Well, because if we go back over here, what I'm telling you essentially is that these symbols really
just match on some of these non-visible characters.
That's.
Pretty much all they're doing, and they can be configured in the regular expression because, as I
said, some editors and operating systems will default such that a new line is comprised of both a line
feed character and a carriage return character together.
And in other systems such as default, editors of Unix operating systems is just one character.
So this dollar sign could match either of those scenarios, depending on how you have the regular expression
engine configured.
And I don't know that's something that you want to keep in the back of your mind.
It's not something that you'll probably have to be super aware of all the time, but something that
you should just kind of know.
And I'm making you aware of it now.
All right.
So now in the case of a string like this, there actually is not a new line character.
So this this symbol here is also matching on simply the fact that that is the end of the string.
OK.
So in this case, it's not matching on any of these characters, per se.
It's just literally matching on the fact that that's the very, very, very end of that string.
And this one is the very beginning of this string.
All right.
Let's see.
So there are some other characters and patterns to be aware of.
There's a character class called Boundary.
OK, let's see what happens when we run this.
OK, so that matches so OK.
The boundary character class simply matches the area between a word character and a non word character,
or a non word character and a word character.
So the the the the order of those two things doesn't matter.
But that's what a boundary does.
Sometimes this can be a little difficult to wrap one's head around.
Let me put two words in here Cat space dog.
And let's see, we'll do three characters like this.
OK, so let's see if this matches.
OK, so that does not match.
And the reason it doesn't match is because of this space here and the boundary character, or I can
call it a word boundary character does not match a space itself.
But if I put a space here and then run this.
Now it matches, so what we've got here is the S.A.T. matches these three dots, then we've got a space
here, which is this space here.
But then we've got something in between the space and the word character, and that is actually what
this boundary character class is matching on.
So that's it's another little bit of a weird thing, and sometimes it'll take a little bit of time to
kind of get a sense for where you want to use that.
All right, now, another set of character classes that should be pretty easy to understand are some
character classes that are actually just kind of opposites of the ones we've already learned, some
of the ones we've already learned.
So for example.
We learned about word character class, right, which uses a lowercase W, and so you could, you know,
get rid of these.
And we'll just kind of review this real quick, so I could have three word characters like this and
that would match Cat just fine.
OK?
However, there is an opposite to this as well.
If I wanted anything other than word characters, I could do slash capital W.
OK, so I can do this.
And that means anything other than word characters, so if I run this now, that should not match because.
C a t r word characters, right, so I get a false now.
So what would match this?
Well, I could use hyphens because hyphens are not considered word characters.
So let's run that.
Yep, so that works.
Now you might have thought that I could use numbers.
Like this?
Right?
But if you'll recall, numbers are contained within the range of word characters where characters are
lower and uppercase letters, numbers and underscore.
So this actually would not match and I'll prove that real quick.
Yeah.
So we got a false there, so that actually does not match.
OK.
So there's there's that character class of non word numbers.
And then there are opposites of the others as well, so there's there we learned about digit class,
right with the lowercase D..
Well, there's a Capital D as well, and you can pretty much guess what that's going to represent,
right?
Oops.
And so that will represent non digits.
So obviously, if we have these digits here, this should not match, we'll run it.
Correct.
OK.
Yeah, so that doesn't match.
However, if we do a b c, which are not digits and run this, it should be just fine.
OK.
So, you know, if you were parsing some text, then you wanted to make sure that no one could put explicitly
digits in a certain location or position, you might want to use something like this or the capital
W or whatever.
And then there's also we've we've been using backslash s for space characters.
There is capital s as well for nonce space characters.
So let's see if we first do this with a space character and we'll just put one space in and run this.
This should match one space.
OK, yes, so that matches.
But then if we change this to a non space and run this, obviously that should not match.
Right, so that doesn't match.
Now what happens if we just get rid of that space?
Then what do we get?
OK, now that also doesn't match, and that's because what this expression is saying is it's looking
for one character that isn't a space over here.
We have zero characters, so that doesn't match.
So we need one character that isn't a space.
So anything that isn't the space should make this match.
So I just put a period here.
Let's see.
OK, so that matches.
Right?
So just any any single character in this case that isn't a space will match.
All right.
So those are some of the opposite, as I call them, predefined character classes.
And I think that's going to wrap up this lesson and I will see you in the next one.