Now, I know there's kind of a lot of concepts here, so let's just recap these concepts.
So we've got local, they just represent a calendar day with no time component.
And then we've got local time.
So you can think of that as just, you know, our minutes, seconds, et cetera.
But a time with no day associated with that time, then we can put those two components together to
make a local date time.
It's literally just something that's putting the local date and the local time together.
And then we can measure the passage of time, either with periods, if it's a period of time on the
order of days, weeks, months, years, etc. Or we can use a duration if it's measuring periods of
time on the order of hours, minutes, seconds, et cetera.
Now one thing this is leaving off, though, is what about time zones?
And this can actually be a thorny issue to deal with as a software developer time zones.
Let's say that we are developing a web application that is an application that runs on the web or at
least in a browser, and the application can let you enter messages that you want to be sent to your
friends and loved ones at a particular date and time.
And this application is designed to work worldwide so people in Japan can go into this website and enter
messages to be sent to their loved ones at a particular time, and people in California can do so as
well.
Well, when they're specifying their dates and times, what time zone do they mean?
Do they mean for these messages to be sent to their friends and loved ones in the time zone in which
they themselves are living in or in the time zones of where the servers are, where this application
is storing that data, or some other time zone?
So you kind of need to care about time zones when you're dealing, particularly with people across multiple
zones.
Right?
Even within a country, the continental U.S. itself spans four time zones.
So same situation there.
Somebody goes in and registers something to be sent at some date and time.
What time zone do we use?
So I've actually been involved in a number of conversations with teammates over the years.
It's funny how this problem never seems to be satisfyingly and authoritatively solved, at least by
everyone.
I mean, I feel like I have it solved more or less in my head, but I don't always have everybody on
the team on the same page.
So thankfully, though, this date time API does give us the ability to specify time zone along with
our dates and our times.
They do so by introducing yet another class, but it's really just another build up from what we've
already learned here.
And it is called zoned date time so we can create one very easily second date time.
Of and we can make one in a number of ways we can specify all the constituent parts of a date and a
time plus a time zone, essentially, or we can make one out of a pre-existing local date time and then
just add in time zone information.
And that might be one of the easier ways to go, but point being, there are many ways to do this.
So let's pick this one here.
So I will refer to local daytime one, and then I can also specify essentially a time zone in the form
of a class that they call Zone I.D. So to use this, I can do this.
So let's say first off that I just want to create a zone date time for my own existing time zone.
So to do that, I can really just reference the Zone I.D. dot system default.
And so what this will do is it will read the default time zone information of my computer in the place
where I'm living right now, assuming that your computer's time zone information is correct for where
you geographically are at this moment.
So if you do a fair amount of traveling and coding at the same time, this system default may or may
not be accurate.
If you traveled to someplace where you maybe don't live full time because I don't know if your operating
system on your computer is going to update if it will even realize that you're no longer in the place
where you normally live.
So be careful with that.
But generally speaking, your computer that doesn't move very often will just take whatever the time
zone is now.
Another thing you'd have to keep in mind, though, is that most Java applications that professional
software developer is writing eventually will be deployed onto a server and the servers that your code
is being deployed on could possibly be almost anywhere in the world, but very possibly not in the same
town where you live.
Let's say that you write a bunch of Java code, and it's destined to go live on Amazon Web Services
cloud somewhere.
Now, in that case, you can at least pick the data centers where you may want that code to be deployed,
but you better be careful there.
So this system default thing is very useful for me right now.
What?
I'm showing you this, but you may need to think about it a bit more in real life.
But for right now, let's just start with this.
So zoning the system default.
All right.
And let's just print that out and see what we get now.
All right, so we get two thousand one and a time of 10, 30, and let's see, what did I reference?
I reference the local daytime one, which was here, which referenced the date one so 2001 and the reference
to local time one, which was 10 30.
And so we're seeing all those things here.
But then the extra bit that it added on was this bit right here, the minus six America Chicago.
So that is essentially just the GMT offset GMT for those who are not aware is the time standard that
is based in Greenwich, England, I guess Greenwich London, with Greenwich London being GMT offset
of zero and then cities to the west of that subtract because they are earlier in the day than what's
going on in Greenwich, right?
Anything west of Greenwich is earlier than Greenwich relative to Greenwich, right?
And since I live in the Midwest, I am six hours earlier than Greenwich Mean Time, so I get the minus
six here, which also corresponds to American Central Time generally, which again, for where I live.
I don't live in Chicago, but I'm in the same time zone as Chicago.
And so that's how that's showing up for me.
So that's the part that got added in because I added this zone ID with my system default.
However, I could set that to anything I want.
So if I wanted to set that to.
Some other place I could do and of, and then I can specify this in a number of ways, so we could do
something like a minus five here.
OK.
And let me comment that out.
OK, now let's run that.
So now we get 10, 30 minus five, right?
So it didn't change any of this, which makes sense because all we're doing is combining the date with
the time and now a time zone, right?
That's all a zone.
Date time is as they just took the date, the time and now they just stuck a time zone component on
there as well.
So going back to my example of the web application, where different people can enter dates and times
of when they want a message to be sent, how could we make use of this zone to date time information?
Well, when those users of this system are specifying their dates and times, there's a few different
things we could potentially do when a browser communicates its data back to a centralized server somewhere.
The browser can send back information about its own time zone, so the developers of this web application
could take that time zone information and added on to the specification of the date and the time, and
then save all of that information into a database.
And that's actually not a terrible idea to do.
Alternatively, though, if they don't want to store all these different time zones in the database,
or maybe if their database for some strange reason doesn't support that, then another technique they
could consider doing is to normalize all of the dates and times into one standard time zone, which
will typically be UTC or GMT.
Right.
So Greenwich mean time.
So let's get a little idea of what that might look like.
So let's say that a user requested a local date time, and I'm not saying that they're going to create
that, but let's say they supply the values that I'm about to plug in to this local date, time, local
date, time of 2021.
Twelve, twenty five and.
12 p.m..
So, in other words, noon on Christmas Day of 2021.
All right.
And let's capture that, and we'll call it Christmas.
That's when they want their message to be sent.
And let's also say that this person lives in California.
OK.
And we need to store this information in our server because they want their message to be sent at noon
on December 25th.
California time.
But in our servers, we want to store everything in UTC.
OK.
So.
This is the information that gets transmitted from their Web browser to our servers.
This this period of time.
Plus we also receive the fact that they live in California and that their time zone is GMT minus eight.
I think I'm pretty sure it's GMT minus say, OK, so first thing we might want to do is to create a
zone that daytime.
Of and then we'll use the Christmas there, plus, so an idea of minus eight.
And I will capture that, I'll call it the Xmas.
So I want to save this information somewhere, but I need to normalize it first.
I need to work the time, so to speak.
I want to find out what is this date time in GMT?
OK, so to do that, I can actually just call a method on here with zone.
Same instant with zone.
Same instant.
And so now what I can do is I can pass in another zone I.D..
Of.
Now for this, I can simply say plus zero.
And I do have to pretend that zero with either a plus or minus two, it won't matter which one I use
in this particular case.
But if I don't have a plus or minus, then the parsing logic, which you can read about more in the
Java doc for the above method won't work.
All right.
So if I do that.
And then I can just print that out like so so let's run that.
All right.
And so now we see 2021 December 25th time, 20 hours.
So we specified noon California time.
And so this is telling us that noon California time in GMT would be 8:00 p.m., right?
Which makes sense because we're saying that California time.
I hope I'm right in my assumption here.
I'm not going to go look at them too lazy for that.
But California is eight hours earlier than Greenwich mean time or UTC, right?
And so this makes good sense.
So it's taking our California time and adding eight hours to it to tell us what time that would be in
Greenwich or UTC.
Now, interestingly, let's see what would happen if we specified a time that was late enough in the
day in California that it would wrap around to the next day in Greenwich.
So let's just do something like, well, actually, we can just pick eight p.m., right?
So that would be 20 hours.
Right?
So let's run that and see.
So now this should give us a date of the next day, but very early in the morning.
So the 26th of of of December, right?
So let's see.
Let's run that.
And there we go, yes, so we get December 26th at 4:00 a.m..
And so this might be the information that we'd want to store in our database if for whatever reason,
our database did not support the story, the storage of time zones or if by some company policy, we
just weren't already in the habit of storing time zones, but we were instead normalizing all dates
and times in our database for GMT or UTC.
So this is what you'd have to do this this bit here.
This bit here is us normalizing the date and time.
So I can't stress how important this type of logic would be, though my personal preference in a green
field application where I can control the database as much as I want to, my preference would really
be to go ahead and store the date time ends and time zone information all together in the database.
That would be my preference, but this would be the close second to that.
All right.
So I think you now thoroughly have an understanding of why time zones associated with dates and times
are so important in most applications.
In fact, you'd be surprised, though, to see how many applications written in companies and things
don't take time zone into account.
And countless times that have arrived at a company as a software developer and we start looking at some
application.
Maybe it's an application that already existed there, and we're looking through the database and you
see these date fields there and you ask, So what time zone is this information for?
And nobody knows.
They just like, don't even.
It's like not even a thought.
And there are important events that are supposedly tied to the times that are in those databases, and
people don't know exactly what they mean in terms of like, well, when you say 8:00 p.m. in this database,
what time zone do you mean?
When should this actually be occurring?
8:00 p.m. Where you have to really actually think about this?