All right, so in the last lesson we learned about the while loop in this lesson, we're going to learn
about its very close sibling, which is the do while loop.
So this type of loop is almost completely identical to the wire loop, with one minor exception, whereas
with the wire loop, it is possible that the actual body of the loop might not ever execute if the criteria
within the loop are not met.
Right.
So if the expression within the wire loop does not evaluate to a Boolean true, then the body of the
wire loop will never execute.
However, with a do while loop this while part here where we check the criteria actually moves to the
bottom of the loop.
And then it is replaced by a simple do clause, which has no criteria.
And so what that means is that the body of the loop is guaranteed to execute at least one time, and
it is only at the bottom of the loop that a check will be made to determine whether or not that loop
should be run again.
OK, so let's convert this program to use a do while loop and then see if there are any noticeable changes
to the program.
So the way we can do that is pretty straightforward, and I think we can just cut this portion here
and replace that with the word due and then notice that since the cursor is near this opening curly
brace, which indicates the beginning of the body of the loop, the ID automatically highlights the
corresponding closing curly brace so we can just put our cursor right there.
I'm going to hit space once and then I'm going to paste what we already had the the while clause and
then put a semicolon here because that is the syntax for a do while loop.
And now we've just converted a wire loop into a do wire loop.
So now the body of this loop is guaranteed to execute at least one time, no matter what.
OK, so let's see if this program behaves any differently now.
Let's go ahead and build.
All right, and then let me reopen the terminal and I'm going to rerun the program.
All right.
So it's prompting again to enter a number.
Enter a three.
Five, seven, nine.
One.
Two.
OK, so the random number was two.
You got it.
OK, so so far, I don't see any difference in the functioning of the program.
Let's try one more time, and this time I'm going to try the negative numbers.
Someone to run this again.
Negative one.
And then let's try using cue to quit.
OK, so the program seems to behave exactly in the same way as it did before.
And I would say that's pretty expected because, you know, we didn't make much of a change here.
So let me just reiterate really the only distinction with the do while loop and the while loop is simply
that what they do while loop, we are guaranteed that the body of the loop will execute at least once.
That's basically it.
All right.
Now it might be nice to add a little bit more functionality to this program.
One thing I was thinking of was was that it might be nice if the program would keep track of how many
guesses it takes before we guess the right number.
So I'd like to challenge you.
Can you figure out a way that you could keep track of the number of guesses before the user guesses
the right number?
And then maybe when they do, finally, guess the correct number, you could print that somewhere.
So why don't you take a moment to see if you can figure out how to do that and implement it and then
come back and I'll show you how I do it?
OK, so let's see what we can do here.
So we want to track the number of times the user guesses wrong and then print that when they finally
do, guess the right number.
OK, so we're going to need a variable to keep track of the number of wrong guesses.
And I am intuitively inclined to put that variable right above and before our do while loop, and I'll
try to remember to come back and explain why I'm thinking that.
But for now, let's just do this.
So let's create this variable.
It's going to keep track of the count.
So it's going to be numerical.
And our default numeric number type for things like counting and stuff tends to be an integer, even
though technically we don't really need it to be an integer.
As you learned about the number of types before, we could have used the byte, but I'm going to just
go with into integer four right now, and I think I'm going to call this wrong guess count.
And I guess I will initialize it to zero.
And so now we need to decide, OK, so we've got this place to keep count of how many times we guess
wrong.
Now, every time we do, guess wrong, let's see.
This is the code that gets called.
So anything in this else block here is where we can do things when we guess incorrectly.
So I'm thinking we can slip a line of code right in here.
It doesn't really matter too much if it comes before or after this system out that print desk.
But I'm kind of inclined to put it before, and I think the reason I'm inclined to put it before is
simply that I'm kind of thinking like this outputting of stuff is kind of like the last visible thing
that we do when you get something wrong.
And so keeping track of a counter and stuff that's kind of like the internal housekeeping stuff.
And so just intuitively, I'm thinking like, maybe I want to do the housekeeping things first and then
the outputting last, if that makes any sense.
Like, you kind of prepare things before you present things, right?
So now all we need to do is to increment the wrong guest count variable here.
And so do you remember how to do that?
How can you increment a numerical variable?
Did you get it?
All right?
So there are a few ways, but the probably most program free way to do it would be like this.
Plus plus.
That's it.
Now, you may recall that you could optionally also do a prefixed plus plus like that.
I would say there's probably a little less common in a case like this.
Normally, when we do the prefix plus plus, it might be in the scope of making some kind of a call.
And then you're embedding the incrementing other of the variable or something in that call, and you
want this incrementing to happen before the print line actually executes, but otherwise for most other
cases where you just want to increment a number variable on its own.
Like this, I think it's probably more common that you'll just see the incrementing being put on the
end rather than on the beginning.
In this particular case, it doesn't really matter at all.
It's not going to change the application in any way at all.
I'm simply doing this out of habit and because I think this is the more typical way that most developers
would probably do this.
All right.
So now we're incrementing the wrong guest count, and then we need to simply show it once you do guessed
correctly, right?
So we'll say, like when you get it correct, the random number was blah blah blah and you got it in
x number of times or x number of tries.
Right?
So let's revise this message a little bit.
The random number was whatever you got it in percent d some number of tries.
And then we need to supply this value here.
So let's see.
We'll put a little reference our new what is it wrong guest count variable, just like so.
And then what else do we need now?
Well, so now I'm just thinking, what's the quickest, easiest way to test this out?
I think we want to cheat a little bit and let ourselves know what the actual random number is and that
we will.
We will have complete control over when we are able to enter the correct guess, you know?
So let's see.
So we're generating the random number here.
So maybe on the very next line, we'll just actually maybe I want to do a print death.
Let's just print.
Random number is percent the.
Oops!
Percent in.
Random number.
OK.
And that way, we can see what it is and then we can decide while we're running the program when we
want to, when basically.
All right, and now let's go ahead and build.
And then let's run it.
OK, so the random number is six, oops.
Oh, I put my percent in and slightly the wrong place, there should have put it after that period.
Percent.
And let me fix that real quick.
And kill this and rerun it.
All right.
Random number is three, please.
Guess the number between one and 10, so I think the first thing I want to do is just guess it right
off the bat.
So three enter.
All right.
The random number was three.
You got it in zero.
Try.
So, all right.
So because I decided to initialize this wrong guest count to zero.
We are now seeing you got it in zero in zero of tries.
I don't like that.
That's not how anybody would usually convey that message.
We would normally say, you got it in one try.
And also, I'm not a big fan of the fact that if I had gotten it in one try, this word tries would
be plural.
I'm not crazy about that.
So I want to fix both of those things.
So first thing is, let's make it say you got it in one try.
And I think the easiest thing to do here would be simply to initialize this to a one.
You're always going to get it in at least one try.
Right?
So let's just change it to a one.
Let's rebuild and rerun this and make sure that that works correctly.
All right.
So I'm going to clear.
And let's rerun it.
OK, so random numbers for someone to choose for.
You got it in one of tries.
OK.
And I guess also, I want to fix this of you got it in.
Yeah, I guess we don't need the word of there.
That's kind of weird.
I don't know why put that there.
All right.
We rebuild that again.
Clear and run it again.
All right.
One more time here for the OK, you got it in one tries, OK, and I'm still going to come back and
fix the trace, but we'll do that in a minute.
All right and nice.
The program exited out just fine.
OK, now let's run it again.
And this time let's take a few guesses.
So the number is one, so we'll do two.
Didn't get it three.
For.
And now we'll do the right one one.
You got it in four tries, very good.
One, two, three four.
Very good, so that's counting nicely.
Now, the only other thing I want to fix is if we only had to guess one time, then I want that word
tries to be singular and just say one.
Try not one tries.
Right?
So let's see.
So that is here.
So our logic would be something like if the wrong guest count is one or is equal to one, then present
the word, try else, present the word tries.
Right now, you know how to do this with the standard, if then else blocked.
Now, however, there's another way to do this kind of small little one off.
It does the same thing, but it's we can do it all in one line.
And that is with another conditional structure called a ternary operator.
So the ternary operator allows us to do the same thing that we can do with an if then else block, except
just in one line.
Let me show you what that would look like.
So first off, I need to decide where do I want to put this?
And I'm thinking, I can do this inside of the loop, probably right above line 15.
And the reason I'm thinking that is because I'm going to turn this word tries into a variable now that
I will then just add on with the print f and its value can be different each time we run through this
loop.
And so it is appropriate to set this new variable that we are going to introduce within the loop because
it can change based on what's going on inside of the loop, as opposed to if we were to put it outside
of the loop, which we could do.
You normally want to keep your variables as close as you can to where they're going to be used, and
that has to do with something called scope.
I may have mentioned the idea of scope earlier, but we'll talk about it a little bit more shortly.
So let's see what this might look like if I introduce a new line here and I'm going to create a new
variable that will be a string because I want it to hold a word either try or tries, depending on the
value of the wrong guest count.
OK.
So I'm going to declare a string called, I don't know, try text.
It's not a great name, but try text will equal.
All right.
So here's how we use a ternary operator.
The first part of it is a.
Criteria.
Much the same as we would do within if block, so it would be, you know, whatever you put inside of
the criteria like these criteria here, right?
Something like that.
So in this case, our criteria will be if the wrong guest count equals one.
Right?
So we can say that except we live off the if part, and we also don't need the parentheses.
You can use parentheses, but we don't need it, really.
So if the wrong guest count equals one?
Now here's where the ternary stuff comes into play.
The next thing we do is use a question mark.
OK.
This sets us up to use this compressed form of an if then statement basically, if wrong, guest count
equals one.
And maybe you want to think of this in this question mark in this case as maybe meaning like then I
don't know.
Or you may want to think of it as being like, if wrong guest count equals one, however you want to,
you know, encode that in your head, right?
But now the next thing we put here is what to return if this criteria is true.
OK?
So if wrong guest count equals one, then we want to return and set try text equal to the word try.
Singular.
So that's a string.
So all we're going to say is quote Try.
OK, so if wrong guest count equals one, then return the string try, which would then get set on this
variable here.
And then for the else part.
Otherwise or else return, the word tries now for that.
We use a colon and then the alternative string that we would want to return, which is tries, and then
we can close out that whole entire statement.
So let's read through this if wrong guest count equals one, then return try.
Else return tries.
That's what this construct is saying, and this is how you use the ternary operator, so it's really
the combination of this question mark in this colon.
It's pretty weird.
I will admit, right?
It's highly compressed form of if then else now, why would I prefer to do this over just using anything
else?
Well, I think it should be kind of clear.
It's very, very concise, right?
And I don't need to do much fanciness here with an if then else if I wanted to do a lot of different
lines of things for the two clauses for the, you know, for the kind of like the positive and the negative
clause, like, I wanted to add some numbers and then print some things out and then make a call out
to some other method or whatever.
If I wanted to do a bunch of stuff.
I would not use the ternary operator for that.
The ternary operator is most useful when you just want to have one simple thing that's being returned
in the positive or negative case, and you want that thing that's being returned to be assigned to something
immediately or utilized immediately in some way.
OK.
That's where the ternary operator is most useful in a short, sweet little thing like this.
Anything more than this, and you probably want to be looking at using and then construct of some sort.
All right.
So now that we've got this try text variable here, now we just need to plug it in.
So instead of hard coding, the word tries like we are doing here now, let's plug that in with the
variable.
And so this is a going to be a string.
So this is a string, right?
So here we're going to replace this with a string.
So we need to use the format code percent s, which means string and then we need to bind our new try
text variable to our print death at the end.
Try text, let me be a little clear here.
I think I mentioned this before, but let's just be really clear how this all works.
So I default with print and format.
Each replacement code or format string code that we're using here like the percent de percent de percent
des.
Each of these gets matched with a corresponding variable in the order in which they come by default.
OK, so the first format code that I have here is a percent DX.
And so the first variable that we're passing in as an argument will get matched to that.
Then the next one is another percent DX, and that will get matched to the next argument that we're
passing in.
And then finally, we've got a string of percent.
And there's the last one.
So that's how these are matched up with each other by default.
Now there are ways to specify which one of these you want using an index or something like that, but
we're not needing that here.
So.
And I think I feel like few people usually feel that they need to use that mechanism.
So this is pretty straightforward.
All right.
So let's try this now.
So let's build.
OK, and then let's run it.
I think I'm going to.
Clear first and then let's run it.
All right, our random number is to.
So first, let's try the case where we get it in one, so to.
You got it in one try that looks like very good English to me.
You got it in one try.
Very good.
OK, now let's run it again.
And now let's take a few tries to get it.
Let's take three tries to get it, so let's do a two and a five and a six.
And now let's get it.
So our number was, I think, four.
You got it in four tries.
Oh, well, OK.
I wasn't counting correctly, but that's that's fine.
So yeah, we did four guesses and we got it on the fourth guess.
Very good.
And notice now because we did more than one guess.
It changed the word from try to Tris.
So now we've got grammatically correct English, which I really care about.
Oh, OK.
Now one last thing that I said I wanted to mention here, I told you that I kind of intuitively felt
like this variable belonged outside of the loop.
So let's see what happens when we put it inside of the loop.
Let's see if there's any difference here.
So I'm going to move it in the loop by simply doing a an option shift down arrow.
Yeah, I think this is fine, just anywhere in the loop.
And then I'm going to woops, and then I'm going to indent it because it's inside of the body of this
do loop now.
All right.
So let's see if this is OK, so we need to recompile or rebuild.
And I'm going to clear.
And let's run it again.
All right, so I'm going to intentionally take a few guesses to get this now, so five, six one, and
now I will get it on.
I'll do a couple more.
Seven and now I will get it.
Ah, look, what happened there.
You got it in one try.
So even though I did like five tries here, it says I got it in one try.
So what's going on here?
So this gets into what I briefly mentioned a little bit ago, which is the concept of scope.
And so what's happening here?
Let me make a little bit of room.
I'm going to close that now.
All right.
So what happened is now that this variable is being declared inside of the while loop here, this variable
has what is called a local scope, and that scope refers to how long a variable lives, essentially.
OK.
And the bottom line here is that variables that are declared inside of a loop and there are other structures
too that we'll talk about, but a variable that's declared inside of a loop body like this one only
remembers its values while it's in one iteration of that loop.
So let's look at what that looks like.
So we enter this loop and then we initialize its value to one.
Then we take a guess.
And if we guess incorrectly, we jump down here where we increment this variable by one, so now it's
set to two.
And then the loop repeats.
Now here's the thing, as soon as this loop repeats any variables that are declared within this loop,
reset back to their initialized state.
So in this case, even though down here we incremented this from one to two the first time through when
we loop back up again, this line of code executes again.
And this variable gets reset to one again.
Not at all what we want because it prevents us from being able to keep track of how many times we're
iterating through this loop.
And so that's why I intuitively, if you want to call it that, understood that this variable, if I
wanted to maintain its state and that's a programmer terminology, which means remembering if I wanted
to maintain this, the state of this variable, I needed to declare it outside of this loop so that
whatever number we recorded on this variable would be retained or remembered across multiple iterations
of this loop.
And what I mean by iteration is just each time we go through this loop, right?
So each time you go through the loop, that's one iteration or an iteration.
OK, so we're iterating through this loop so many times each time that we guess wrong, for example,
and we want to keep track of that.
OK.
So this is a really important concept, the concept of scope.
Now we see this concept in other places besides just loops.
In fact, in general, any time you declare a variable within a code block and if you will recall,
a code block generally is just any block of code inside of curly braces.
OK, now there are other smaller scopes of code blocks that are even smaller than what's in a curly
brace.
But the easiest way to recognize a code block is any time you've got one or more lines of code in between
two curly braces, OK, like I have here.
So any variables that are declared within a code block typically only have scope within that code block,
which means that as soon as the thread leaves, that code block the little character that I mentioned
earlier who reads and executes each line of code.
As soon as he leaves a code block, the variables that were declared in that code black ceased to exist.
They disappear, OK?
And then they only come back into existence fresh when the thread comes back into that code block.
OK.
So that's a really important thing to know.
So a couple of really common places where you'll see that behavior are in loops, obviously.
Another one is just in methods themselves.
OK?
Any variables that are declared within a method will lose their value after the thread leaves those
methods, and those are called local variables because they are local to that block of code.
All right.
So with that being said, we now know that this line here has to be outside of the code block in order
to be remembered.
And then I will unindicted again now, oh, so one last thing I want to mention about this scoping of
variables.
Now you might be inclined to just keep all variables as global as you possibly can.
So, for example, just declaring every single variable in your program as high up in the program as
you possibly can.
So in this case, that would mean putting them all around in here.
That would be a mistake, though you don't want to do that because that can potentially be a little
wasteful of memory and resources.
What you want to do instead is you have to actually do a little thinking and analyze, where will I
need access to any given variable and how long will that variable need to retain its data?
You want to keep variables as local to where they're going to be used as possible.
Which is why online 15, I put this particular variable right above the place where I'm going to use
it because I only need this variable right here, and it does not need to retain its value past my use
of it right here.
So each time we iterate through this loop, it needs to be reset anyway.
So why not just declare it and set it as closely to the place where I'm going to use it as possible?
Now, I very well could have declared this variable up here, and that wouldn't have been wrong.
Technically, it would have worked, but now I'd be retaining a value longer than it needed to exist.
And one more thing that I will introduce you to, we won't go into any detail on it right now, but
I will say that Java is a language that has something called garbage collection.
And what that means is when we create objects in Java, you know that they take up space in memory.
But when we declare a variable at various scopes, such as a local scope, when the thread leaves that
scope, those variables are then allowed to be garbage collected within the Java language.
And so that means that the space that those objects are taking up in memory can be reclaimed and reused.
OK.
So in this case of the try text variable here, as soon as the thread leaves the scope of this do while
loop, this variable can be garbage collected by Java.
And when I say by Java specifically, there's something called the JVM, which is the Java virtual machine,
and that's what's actually managing all of the behind the scenes of our program.
OK?
So the JVM is allowed to garbage collect this variable.
Now we don't have a whole lot of control over when that happens.
It may happen immediately.
It may not.
The JVM will decide when is it best for it to collect the garbage?
But if we were to run this program's loop and and guess incorrectly one million times really, really
quickly, and there was no garbage collection, then you would end up with one million string objects
in memory and they would not ever get collected for garbage, right as garbage.
And that would be bad for the utilization of the memory in the computer.
And so that's one of the main reasons why we want to declare variables as close to where they're going
to be used as possible so that they get every opportunity to be garbage collected as soon as they're
no longer needed so that we're not being wasteful with the the computer systems, memory and things
of that sort.
So we'll try to talk more about this in subsequent lessons.
But I wanted to kind of introduce you to these concepts a little bit now.
So with that, I am going to close this lesson and I will see you in the next one.