Welcome back in this lesson, I'm going to introduce you to another streams API technique that's a little
bit more advanced now.
It's nothing you can't handle, though, and it can be a very useful technique to be aware of when you
start to engage in slightly more advanced uses of the Streams API.
So to teach this lesson, we're going to set up a scenario using our existing data set.
So turning to the idea here, let us set up a scenario in which we want to collect all of the first
names in our list of employees.
OK.
And we want to identify all of the unique letters that comprise all of the first names.
Totally a contrived scenario.
OK, maybe maybe you're maybe you're a programmer working for a linguist and the linguist wants to get
like a character frequency, some kind of a character frequency, statistical gathering type of thing,
right?
So they want to know out of all these first names, how many A's are there and how many Zs and something
like that.
So for right now, we won't be counting the frequency of these characters.
We just want to identify each unique instance of the characters and print them out.
So let me show you what I mean.
Let's turn to the virtual sheet of paper here.
Let's pretend like we've got a few first names and I'm not going to write them all out.
But let's say that we've got some first names here, like we've got Fred.
And we've got Barney.
We'll just go with those two.
Barney.
And what we want to do is to identify all of the unique characters that comprise all of the first names
that we encounter.
So when we do that, what we would end up with, like the end goal here would be we'd have an f because
there's only one f we'd have an R just one R, though, even though there are multiple R's here, right?
So we'd have just that one are there are multiple E's.
We just want one.
Let's see, there's a D, there's a B.
Just one and A.
In and a way.
OK, so so this is what we would end up with at the end of this exercise if we only had the two names.
OK, now we're going to iterate over all of the names, though, so we'll we'll have, you know, like
some double you and and I and so on and so forth, right?
But this is just to give you an example.
OK.
Again, I acknowledge this is totally contrived and not very useful in and of itself.
It's just an excuse for us to learn these techniques.
All right.
So then the question becomes, Well, how can we accomplish this, right?
So let's analyze what we know so far.
We know that we can use the Stream's API to iterate over these lines and we can convert them into employees,
and then we can map those employees to their first names, right?
And so right there, when we map the employees to their first names, we're going to end up with a stream
of first name strings.
Right?
So let me show what that might look like graphically.
So a stream of first name strings would look like might look like this.
I'm going to use double quotation marks to indicate a string.
OK, so we'd have Fred.
And we'd have.
Barney.
Again, I'm only going to show a couple of names here.
And then to show that this is a stream of strings, I'm going to use the color blue and I'm just going
to kind of outline.
All of that.
Like, so, OK, so the blue box represents a stream, OK, so we've got a stream of strings.
So we in this case, we've got two strings.
Fred is a string as indicated by the double quotes, and then Barney is a string indicated by the double
quotes.
OK, so that's what we would have.
Let me grab this and make a little room.
So I'm going to bring this down a bit.
OK, so that's what we would have if we were to do something like map.
Employee.
What does it get?
First.
Name.
Right.
We'd end up with a stream of first name strings, as depicted here.
OK, now keep in mind what we're wanting at the end of, of all of our mapping and whatever else we
may find ourselves having to do.
We want to end up with this.
At the end of that, right?
So the the question is, how can we end up with that?
OK, so maybe kind of thinking about this backward a little bit.
What I see down here at the bottom of our end goal here is that we essentially want a stream of.
Character strings.
So I'm depicting each letter as its own string.
Right now, why do I say that?
How do I know that we ultimately want a stream of character strings?
Well, the way that I know that is that we want unique letters, right?
So we're going to have to treat each letter as its own item inside of a stream.
And if we do that, then we can do something kind of cool.
Imagine if we have hold on a second here.
I will even depict this guy as a stream.
OK, imagine prior to this if we have.
The whole entire.
Repeated letters show you what I mean here.
All right, so if we have all of the letters of these first names with no duplicates removed and this
is a dream.
Right.
So if we had that, then what we could do.
Pretty easily is to just call.
Dot distinct, right?
This blue thing is a stream, right, and so we can call the distinct method of the streams API, and
then that would give us.
The stream of unique character strings, right?
So in other words, it would get rid of the duplicates.
Right?
So this distinct tier would find.
Let's see, where are the duplicates it would get rid of that are right there.
It would get rid of that E. Right there, right?
All right.
So kind of going backward.
We know that we would like to have a stream of individual character strings.
So again, the question is how how can we get that?
Well, coming back up here to the mapping of the get first name call, I think we should recognize that
we want to separate out the characters from each of these names, right?
We want the characters as their own separate thing.
So how can we do that now?
I can think of a couple of ways, and I'll be honest with you.
If I were not already familiar with the Streams API and the direction that we're heading down, one
approach that I might have considered doing might have been to try doing something like, let's see
here doing something like a map.
During.
Do you're right?
Two character array.
Now what this would do is it would return something that looks like this.
OK, so that's what we would end up with if we were to do a map, a mapping where we called String two
character array.
Now I want you to notice some details here.
Notice that I'm using.
I'm using single quotes here instead of double quotes like I'm doing up here.
The reason I'm doing that, if you'll recall from past lessons, double quotes depict strings.
Single quotes depict characters.
Okay.
There is a difference.
They're very closely related.
But there is a difference, right?
Those are two different data types, really.
Okay.
Also, I'm using the square brackets here.
As you can see here, right, I'm using these square brackets, square brackets indicate an array.
So what we're looking at here?
So what we're looking at here are two character arrays inside of one stream.
OK.
To characterize inside of one stream.
So that's what we would get if we were to call the two character array method of the string class.
OK, now the problem with this approach is that.
At the end of all of this pipeline that we're about to create.
What we're trying to get to is a stream of character strings.
OK, not a stream of characters.
So I'm just going to put that aside for now and just let you know that the two character array approach
isn't quite going to work now.
We could make it work, by the way, we could write a lambda in the next step.
We could write a lambda in the next step that has multiple lines and an a block of code in it, so it
would be, you know, a full method essentially that would convert the character array to characters
of strings.
Right.
So we convert each character into a a one character string, right?
I we could write that, but it's unnecessary to do so.
That's the thing, right?
We could do this more concisely.
All right.
So we're not so we're not going to go with the two character array approach.
So I'm going to maybe just kind of strike that out, so.
So let's see what else we could do with with these strings to get them closer to being individual character
strings.
OK.
And one thing we can do.
So if we turn to our I.D. and we Google for Java Doc String Class, we can jump into the documentation
for the string class and we can just go look at what methods exist on this class, right?
So scrolling through here, what I'm looking for.
Our methods that might return a breakdown of a string, hopefully as smaller strings, right, because
that's what we're trying to do.
We're trying to break down Fred into a separate string of four separate string of R e d, et cetera,
right?
So let's look through the Java doc here and see if there's any method that jumps out as looking like
it might be capable of doing that.
What I'm looking at specifically here is this is this left column here because those are the return
types.
Here's the method.
Here's the input.
Here's what it does, and here's the return type for that method.
So let's see what we've got here.
All right, so here's here's some byte arrays.
We don't want that because that's a bite.
Now, this is starting to look interesting here.
String arrays, right?
Couple of them, in fact, what what is this?
This is oh, now we're familiar with this method.
We learned this method a long time ago.
I hope you still remember it.
The split method takes a regular expression for a given string, and then it can split that that string
into an array of strings.
Now, just as a quick little reminder, one of the more common ways that you'll see that method used
might be something like if we had a string that said something like.
Johnson.
Comma Mary.
And then we called Split.
And passed in a coma like so this would return.
An array.
With.
Jonathan?
And then, Mary.
So an array with two strings in it.
OK.
That's what it would do if we called Split with the Comma.
There's an interesting little thing, though, that you can do with the split method if you just pass
in an empty quotation.
Like, let me see, how can I pick this?
Let me just.
Erase those and just show quotes with no space in the middle, right?
So just an opening and a closing quote and no space in there, then what you end up getting.
Let's see race this.
What you end up getting now is.
They.
Oh, H.
And S., et cetera, et cetera.
OK.
So instead of splitting on the commas, it now just splits in between each and every character and we
can use that.
We can use that.
OK, so now that we see that, we could potentially just use the split method?
Let us consider how we could do this, though.
So you might initially think that we could just do something like map string.
And then call Split like so.
However, that's not going to work because the split method needs an input.
Right?
It needs to know what are you splitting on?
Like what?
What is the character that you're looking for in order to split?
So we can't quite do it that way.
But what we can do?
If we can just use a regular lambda expression instead, like the old fashioned one instead of a method
reference, we can just use a regular lambda expression.
So now that we know that we can do this, probably by just using the split method.
Let's go ahead and jump into the ad and start putting this together, and we'll kind of go back and
forth between the ABC and the and the virtual paper here.
All right.
So what we're going to do first, I'm scrolling down here to what we had before, and I'm inclined to
just come and do all of that out for right now.
We don't need it.
We'll just kind of do something a little bit fresh, but in this same file, in the same class, OK?
So I'm going to put my cursor here and just put a few new lines.
So we know that we want to iterate over these employees.
We know that we need to convert them into actual employees and then we need to convert those into first
names.
So why don't you try doing that on your own and just get to that point and don't cheat, don't cheat
and look down here.
Just see if you can do it from memory.
OK.
So just get to the point that you are using the Streams API and you're getting a stream of first name
strings.
OK, and then join back up with me.
All right.
So hopefully you were able to do that.
Let me do it now.
So let's see what's her variable called its people text.
OK, so I'm going to reference the people text dot lines.
And I guess again, I would like that to be on its own line.
I'm not going to bother unnamed denting that because I don't feel like fighting with the ADC right now.
All right.
So there are lines, and then I'm going to map that using the employee.
What is it?
Create employee method?
All right.
So now we have AI employees, but I want those to be employees so that I can access the first name,
right?
So then we'll do another mapping.
Let's see.
And this time I have to use an old school lambda expression to just cast these to their actual data
type of employee.
So I will call them E and map that to employee e, just like so and now I have employees.
And we can even see here that we go from a stream of strings to a stream of employees to a stream of
employees, right?
So this is all just review.
All right.
And now that I have employees now we can get a stream of firstname strings, right?
So we can do another mapping.
And so now we can just call employee Oops, first name.
There we go.
All right, so that should get.
So you should be at this point now.
Right.
So we've got a stream of first names, right?
And so now that now we know that our next step is we want to try using the split method of the string
class to split all of the individual letters of each string into into arrays of strings, right?
And again, I'll just remind you, that should look like an array.
Of f r e d, I thought injury of B, a R and E like and then all of that would be inside of a dream.
OK, so that's what we're trying to get to.
And so to do that, all we should need to do is call map and we'll have to do an old school lambda expression
here.
I will call this first name,
first name dot split and then I will pass in empty quotes.
Like so.
And so that should give us what we're seeing down here.
The Fred and Barney arrays.
Right.
So if I come down here to the next line and I'm just going to get this set up.
All right.
So we even see here that the output of Line 41 is a stream of string arrays, right?
Because split returns and returns a string array.
So now the next thing we need to get closer to what we've got down here on the second to last area of
our virtual paper, though, right?
So we want to get rid of the arrays, right?
We don't want to have all of the letters in their own arrays, right?
We want to just strip off the arrays and just have the letters out in the open, right?
So how can we do that?
Well, there's a utility method on the arrays class that can take the contents of an array and strip
them out of that array and put them into a stream.
So there's a method that can do pretty much exactly what we're needing.
Let me show you visually what that what I mean by this, though.
OK, so first off, the method is called arrays dot stream.
So maybe we could do something like.
Map.
Actually.
Arrays that stream.
And what that should output would be something like f r e, d, b, a R and E like, except for one
problem.
The arrays that stream method does take the contents of an array and put and strip them out of the array
and put them into a stream.
However.
What you end up with is now this.
There's one stream.
There's another stream, and then because all of this is happening within the greater context of a of
a API pipeline.
All of that is still inside of.
One big stream, right?
So now what you end up with is a stream of streams of strings.
OK, so let's go ahead and see what this is going to look like and then I'll show you how we can fix
it.
All right.
So let's see.
We've got a map here.
And so we're simply going to call.
Arrays.
Don't.
Arrays stream.
All right.
And now you can see right here, the output of this is a stream of streams of strings, right?
And then just look down here at the depiction again and you can see.
So essentially all that you have to kind of keep in mind to keep your head straight on this is that
each of these arrays that we had previously became a stream.
But you know that the output of every step in our pipeline is also a stream, and therefore you end
up with a stream of streams.
OK, now that won't do because ultimately what we're trying to get to is just one stream of character
strings, right?
That's what we're trying to get to.
So now.
And by the way, what I'm about to show you next is really like the whole crux of why we're even doing
this lesson, OK?
I just wanted you to have the fullest context so that you could appreciate what you're about to learn
now, right?
So this whole entire thing leads up to this.
When you have a stream of streams and you don't want that, you really just want one ultimate stream
of whatever the things were that were inside of the child stream, right?
That's what you really want.
All you need to do is not use the map.
Method and instead use.
Flat map.
So what the flat map method does, if you didn't already get it, is it kind of flattens or it collapses
the redundant child streams, right?
So it gets rid of the internal blue stream here and you just end up with what we have down here, which
is just one super stream with whatever the original contents were embedded.
And so now we see here on Line 42, we end up now with a stream of strings, right?
And now that we've got a stream of strings, guess what we can do at this point we can call distinct.
And now that will get rid of the duplicate letters, right, the duplicate letters.
And now finally, let's just print them out.
To do that, we can do a for each and call
system that our.
Print line, and let's run this.
There we go.
And I don't believe I'm seeing any duplicates now, we could make this a little easier to see, though,
if we don't use a print line.
Yeah, we can just use the print method.
It's a print line actually makes each input to it.
Have its own line, right, because it adds a new line character.
But if we don't use the print line, we can just use print and let's see what this does.
There we go now, they're all printed out sideways, and it's just easier to compare everything, right?
So yeah, I think I don't see any duplicates anywhere here, right?
These are all of the unique letters not duplicated now notice there's a difference in Computerworld
between a capital a and a lowercase a right.
There is a difference there.
Now, if we wanted to not care about those differences, can you think of a way that you could do that?
Why don't you?
Why don't you think about it?
OK, so yeah, if you didn't want to differentiate between capital and lowercase versions of the same
letter, you certainly could just do one more mapping somewhere, presumably maybe right after the dot
flat map.
You could do another mapping where you map all the letters to lowercase or uppercase, right?
You just normalize them all to one case, no matter what they started off with.
In fact, here we'll go ahead and just do that real quick dot map string to lower case.
Right?
Let's run that.
There you go.
So now everything's lower case, and because of that, we have even less duplication if you consider
upper and lower case of the same letter to be duplicates, right?
And you also could have done, you know, to upper case if you wanted to write, right?
But that's even even less duplication now.
All right.
So one more time, I just want to state that the main goal of this lesson was to introduce the flat
map.
I myself had a little bit of a harder time wrapping my head around exactly what this method was doing
for quite some time after I learned the Stream's API.
And it wasn't until I really sat down with it and tried to depict visually what the heck is going on
that I was able to kind of get an understanding Ah, OK, OK, we've got you any time you have a situation
with the Stream's API where you end up with a stream of streams.
That's probably not what you wanted in many, many cases.
And you need to flatten that structure into one stream, right?
And that is what the flat map does.
We're going to encounter this flat map a few more times in the future.
And that's one of the other reasons why I wanted to make darn sure that we covered it now rather than
later.
OK.
So I hope this lesson wasn't too convoluted for you, but it's really an important thing, an important
concept for you to understand a lot of Java developers who dabble with the Streams API but don't really
understand it.
They end up just kind of like guessing, like, Oh, it's not working because the ID will tell them,
well, what you're trying to do with this pipeline of the streams API isn't going to work.
And so then they start just kind of guessing like, Oh, what if I try a flat map?
And then it kind of like magically works, but they don't really understand why, right?
So hopefully now you will understand why, and that will set you way ahead of the pack.
All right.
So with that, I'm going to draw this to a close and I'll see you in the next one.