All right, so now we can jump into this repository and get to work.
OK, so here we are in the save method.
This is the part that we actually cared about.
All the rest of this was just setting things up, right?
So now we're in the good stuff, the save method.
So the main thing we want to do here is we want to be able to save this person and we want to be able
to get there automatically generated I.D. after we've saved them because the database is going to generate
these IDs for us, if you recall.
So we want to get our hands on that I.D. Then we want to take that I.D. and stuff it back into this
person as we are returning the person so that the rest of our tests will now all work well, mostly
so that the second test will work right.
All right.
So here's how we're going to do this.
What I'm inclined to do is to mostly just code this up.
I will try to explain a few things, but I'll save the big explanation for closer to the end of getting
this all going, OK?
So in this save method, we're going to refer to our connection and we need to first create what's called
a prepared statement.
And so we can get a prepared statement by calling the prepare statement method, which takes sequel
as an input.
So we're going to reference this method here.
And so here we can simply pass in some sequel just like we were doing in our Squirrel sequel client.
OK, so we can pass in some sequel that will say something like insert into the people table.
Into the columns of let's see, first name, comma, a last name, comma, date of birth.
Let's just go with those for now and then we need to specify our values.
And now here's the thing.
When we were doing this in the Squirrel sequel client, we were just specifying the values directly
like this.
We were saying something like, you know, whatever John Comma, Smith comma and then whatever date,
right?
Blah blah blah.
So that's what we were doing there.
Obviously, here, though, we don't want a hard code.
These values, we need to get the values out of this person.
Now there are a few ways that we could do this.
Actually, one way that we could do it would be we could capture this string into its own variable.
In fact, here I'll just go ahead and do that right now, right?
So there's there's some sequel.
Okay, we could capture that into its own variable and we could append values that we pull out of the
person class.
So, for example, we could do something like plus part.
Person, get first name.
Comma plus, but then we'd have to get into this nasty formatting thing, where then we'd have a comma
space quote, plus you see what I'm saying here, so that starts to get kind of nasty.
Remember what I said about concatenating strings?
That's what we're doing here.
If you're concatenating just two strings, the plus sign is probably a nice, easy way to do it.
No, no, no worries there.
If you're concatenating multiple strings like we'd have to do here, this starts to get nasty and I
wouldn't want to do that.
Another approach that we could take, which would certainly be better in my opinion, would be to use
something like the string dot format method.
And then we could use the little format symbols, right, so we could say something like percent as
comma.
Percent, yes, karma.
Percent.
Percent death notice, I'm not putting single ticks here, because that would be for the date of birth,
right?
Comma.
And then you can pass in those values.
I'm going to go down to the next line here because I'm running out of space person to get first, name
first and get last name, person dot get date of birth.
Now that's a zoned date time, and we're going to talk about that a little more in a moment here.
But you see where I'm going with this, right?
So that's one way that you could do this, for sure.
OK.
That's not how we're going to do it.
I will state, though really quickly that if we were going to do it this way and there's a lot of Java
code written in kind of this way where they're just kind of concatenating strings together to build
their insert SQL statement.
In that case, you wouldn't need a prepared statement.
You could just use another method called Create Statement where you're just going to pass it all in
already built.
OK.
One of the reasons for using the prepared statement those because it actually gives us a more elegant
way to solve the problem of getting our values passed in here.
OK?
And so let me show you that approach.
So we're not actually going to do the string that format.
So I'm just going to get rid of all of that.
Instead, what we can do.
Is we can simply specify question marks just like that.
And so now what we can do is we'll close this off.
And yes, I know I've got this squiggly line here.
And in fact, let's go ahead and do something about this squiggly line here.
So this squiggly line here throws a Java sequel sequel exception as well.
Now, in this case, we don't want to just add this exception to the method signature of our save method.
And the reason for that is if we were to do that, that would mean that this save method would just
be passing on the sequel exception.
And the problem here is that real Java applications that are well-written should be written in layers.
So depending on what type of application it is, you might have two layers.
You might have three layers.
Maybe, perhaps there's even like a standard for having four layers or something like that.
Most of the typical Java applications that I've worked on over my career will typically have three layers,
though, and the bottom layer of these typical applications will be the data access layer.
And that's the layer in which a class like the people repository here would live.
It would live in the data access layer.
The layer above that will would typically be known as the business or service layer.
And one of the purposes of these layers is to isolate and abstract away a lot of the details that only
pertain to that layer.
So if the people repository class is meant to live in the data access layer, then you don't typically
want to allow concepts that are specific to the data access layer to be able to bubble up into other
layers.
The sequel exception is very much a data access layer type of concept.
OK, it has to do with databases.
In other words, we don't want the layer above our data access layer to know that we have to talk to
a database using sequel.
OK.
And so if we were to allow that SQL exception to bubble up from the safe method, that would mean that
classes that interact with this people repository saved method, they'd have to know about the sequel
exception because they'd have to handle it or pass it on.
OK.
And we don't want them to have to know about that.
So probably the better thing to do in this case would be to actually surround this code with a try catch
block.
So I'm going to do that, and I just did an option command T to get the surround with options here,
and then I'm going to choose six.
All right.
And so now that just surrounded the connection, that prepared statement with a try catch and now probably
most of the rest of my code, I'm going to actually write inside of the try clause here.
So now we're calling this prepared statement.
So this method prepared statement actually returns something called a prepared statement.
So we need to capture that.
All right.
So I'm going to have my cursor here at the end of this statement, and I'm going to do an option Command
V. And I'm going to call this resulting variable piece because I don't want to type out prepared statement.
All right.
So now we're capturing this, this prepared statement like so and so now with this prepared statement,
I can bind values to these question marks here and let me show you how I do that.
It's actually pretty straightforward.
I can call press dot set and there are all these setter methods here, such string.
Now this method takes two parameters and index as an integer and then a string.
And so what it's asking me is what string should I bind to the first parameter or the second parameter
of the third parameter, et cetera, et cetera, right?
And so if I want to bind a first name to the first parameter here in my school statement, I will first
refer to the number one because that's the index of that parameter.
Now it's not zero based here, it's actually one one.
And then the actual string that I want to bind to that parameter and I will get that string from my
person instance, person dot, get first name just like that, and then I can proceed to the next parameter
set string.
Second parameter person dot get last name just like that.
Now, the third one is not a string.
The third one is a date of birth.
And if you recall from the database that we modeled as a timestamp now, the database timestamp is most
similar to a Java dot you till date class.
And if you recall the date class, which we will usually try to avoid because it's not as precise or
useful as the newer style, date and time classes that we learned about.
But anyway, the Java you till date date class represents an instant in time.
So what we can do here is we can call pass that set timestamp.
OK.
Set timestamp.
This will be the third parameter.
And now we need to pass.
Send to this method.
A Java that sequel timestamp.
But we don't have a Java, that sequel timestamp.
We have a zoned date time on our person class.
So we need to translate this zoned date time from the person into a timestamp.
And the way we can do that is to first reference the time the Java that SQL timestamp class timestamp.
Now be careful here to make sure you're referring to the Java Java, that sequel and not some of these
other things.
OK.
All right, so timestamp dot.
Now notice it has a method value of that takes a local date time.
So we're getting close to what we actually need here.
So we're going to we're going to use that value of method and now we're going to invoke our person to
get the date of birth method.
But remember, now this Dobb method returns a zoned date time.
That's how we modeled it.
We could have modeled it differently, but we didn't.
All right.
So we still need to do a little conversion here.
So now we're on the zoned date time in this class, if you'll recall, has a method on it with zone.
Same instant.
So if we call this, we can translate our zoned date time, which was set for GMT minus six.
We can set that to another time zone.
So let's back up real quick and let me remind you of something in our database.
We used a timestamp.
The H2 database is timestamp data type does not hold information about a time zone.
OK.
So if we're using a database field that doesn't know about time zones, I strongly recommend that you
standardize on one standard time zone to hold all of your date times in that particular field.
So if we jump over to the database real quick here and let me click on this object's tab here and click
on the people table here and down here, people table and then content, and we can see the actual contents
of that table listed out here without having to type in, you know, select star from people, from
people.
OK, so here we have our dates of birth.
They do not have time zone in.
Information, so what I would recommend is that in real life, if you have the ability to do so, you
should probably choose to standardize all your date times in such a field like this to be something
like GMT zero.
Right?
Just a standard.
So no matter what times you were getting in Java, you should translate those times those date times
into their GMT zero equivalent and only store GMT zero in your database.
That way, you always know what actual instant in the world that event occurred in.
Otherwise, you'd be wondering, you know, if you were translating zone eight times from all kinds
of different time zones and you just stored them directly into here, you'd lose the time zone bit,
but you'd have confusing date time information without knowing what time zone you were referring to.
And so you should just standardize all of the date times in a field like this to something like GMT
zero.
And really, you should probably just do GMT zero.
That's probably the safest thing to do.
So then we need to actually do that.
And so that's actually not that hard we will simply call with.
Zone, same instant.
And now we need to pass in a zone I.D. of and then we can just say plus zero like that, OK, now.
Still not done because this with the zone same instant method is actually still going to return back
a zoned date time.
Now it'll just return back a zoned date time with the date and time of our date of birth in GMT zero.
OK.
But now that we've done that, we can now just call to local date time.
All right.
To translate that into a local daytime, which is what the value of method of the timestamp class wants.
I recognize this may look a little scary.
So I would recommend that you practice writing this code a little bit yourself.
OK.
It's really not that bad.
So just know that date of birth here returns a zoned date time and whatever the time zone was that we
specified when we created it right?
Then we're translating from that time zone to GMT zero with the with zone same instant method here.
And then we're translating that zoned daytime into a local date time, which we can then pass in to
the time stamp value of method.
OK, so now all we need to do is just execute our insert statement and to do that, we can call that
execute.
Now there's a few variations of this method.
One that we can call is execute update.
Because this execute update method will return an integer which represents the number of records that
were modified essentially from our sequel.
OK, so we can call that and then we can capture its output, and I will call this records.
Affected.
OK.
And for right now, what I will do is just print that out, so I'll use a system format and will say.
Records affected Kolan percent, D percent, and then I will refer to that variable.
All right.
And that way, we'll get a little bit of output so that we can see what's kind of going on there.
OK, now the last thing we'll need to do is we need to get our hands on the auto generated I.D. assuming
that this all went well, right?
So we will have inserted this new person into the database table, but we need to find out what their
ID is and the way that we can do that is actually to come back up here to this connection.
That prepared statement and this method actually has a few overloaded versions, and one of those versions
can take some extra parameters where we can tell it how we want it to behave.
And so if I click on this here, I can actually pass in a constant here, if you'll notice.
Let's see.
Yeah, this third version here takes a sequel as the first parameter and then an integer for the second
parameter of auto generated key.
So we actually want to tell the prepared statement that our statement that we're asking it to execute
is capable of returning a generated key.
And so the way we will do that is by referencing a class called statement dot.
And then this statement class has a bunch of constants defined on it.
And the constant that we're interested in is this one right here?
Return generated keys?
All right.
So now if we want to get our hands on the generated key after we've executed our prepared statement,
I'll put my cursor down here right after we executed that.
So what we can now do is call prepared statement or not get generated keys.
Now notice this method returns a something called a result set.
OK.
And we're going to dig into what all of this means a little bit later.
But let's just get this written real quick here.
Get generated keys, and then let's capture that results, and I'm going to just refer to it as RC.
All right.
Now, I don't know if you remember from the collections module and we learned a little bit about it,
traders.
But when you iterate using an iterator, you must call the next method.
And so this is no different from that.
So the way we'll do that is by calling while RSA Dot next.
And the reason this works this way is because the results set essentially can represent a set of rows.
OK.
And so we're going to essentially be able to iterate over rows.
However, in the case of get generated keys for for our use here, where we're only inserting one record.
There could only be at most one row returned, which would be one road that contains the auto generated
ID for the record that we just inserted.
OK.
So if there is a row in this result set, we'll get to it within this while loop here.
And so then to pull out that generated key, we'll call results set r's dot get.
Now that generated key can be mapped to a long.
And so we'll say get along.
And now notice here we can specify a column index.
So this column index here is similar to the parameter index here.
OK.
In this case, the results said that we would get back would be one row with one column.
And so we'll call this and then we'll just pass in a one.
In other words, we're saying we want the first column back and then I'm going to capture that with
an option Command V. And I will call it simply.
And then all I need to do now is set that ID on the person class.
So I'm going to call person to set I.D. to ID.
Like so and then we already have this returned person here, so the person will get returned automatically.
And I think that's enough.
Now I know that there's a bunch here that you're probably not really understanding, and I'm going to
do a deeper dive and explain more of this in the next lesson, OK?
But let's just see if we can even get this running.
All right.
So now let's jump back over to our test class.
I'm doing a command shift T..
All right.
So here we are back in the in the in the test class.
And first off, I'm just going to run this one test method and I happen to know this isn't going to
work, but let's see why it doesn't work.
So I'm going to click on that and click Run.
All right, so our test failed.
So if I click on this red can save one person reference here.
OK, so first off, I happen to already be connected to the database, so I'm getting a database may
be already in use.
You may or may not get that depending on whether or not you left the school.
Squirrel client open, but I did.
So I'm going to jump over to the SQL Squirrel client, and I'm just going to click on this little x
here to close out of my connection because of the embedded nature of the way that we're using H2 in
this particular case.
In other words, we're not using it as a server.
We're just using it as like an embedded driver.
You can only have one connection to the database at a time with this mode.
Now, H2 does support other modes of use, though, where you could have multiple connections, but
we're not using those modes at this time.
All right, so I'm going to close that and it asks me, Am I sure I want to close it?
Yes, I am.
And I had some unsaved changes.
That's OK.
I don't need to save them.
All right.
So there's that.
Now I jump back over here.
So let's run that again.
And I think it's still going to fail, but it should feel for a different reason.
All right.
And so now I get this error down here, Piers.
That said timestamp, and it looks like it's pointing at the person that get the method error cannot
find symbol.
And let's see here, people repository.
Yeah.
OK, so the get date of birth method, I never generated it, I guess.
And so jumping over to the person class, apparently I never did actually create a field for the date
of birth.
And therefore, I also never generated getters and setters for the date of birth.
OK, so that's fine.
So here we'll just do this real quick.
Private zoned a time be like so and then we'll go ahead and generate the getters and setters for that.
Command and or right click on empty space for Windows users and getter setter and click, OK.
All right, there we go for that.
And then while we're here, I also see that we allowed the HD to generate this constructor for us while
we were referencing various fields here, but it didn't actually flesh that out.
So now we can flesh that out a bit.
So this dart first name equals first name.
This last name equals last name.
This date of birth equals date of birth.
OK, so now this test might get a little further.
So I'm going to jump back over to the people repository tests here.
People repository tests, by the way.
I just did that with a command.
Oh, right.
And then I just typed pretty.
Yes, right to jump in to here and from here, I'm going to just click on that play button again and
let's see what we get this time.
OK, I'm going to click on this because I don't trust that I see the green here yet.
Click on that.
OK, cool records affected one.
OK, so that's looking like it may have worked to that to that extent.
So now let's jump back over to the sequel client and see if we actually got a John Smith added into
the database.
All right, so here we are.
So I'm going to just double click on this alias for people test and then choose Connect.
And then we'll go over here to the sequel tab.
And then I will just type in, select everything from people and then do a control return.
Or you can click on that little thing there.
And so now I see yep, I see my John Smith.
I happen to have them in here a couple of times because I probably forgot to clear him out from when
I was preparing for this lesson.
So don't worry if you only have one John Smith while I have to.
No big deal.
All right.
But it looks like we did get him in here, and that's the most important thing for right now.
OK.
All right.
So let's do one last thing in this lesson.
Let's go ahead and run both of those tests and see if they happen to work.
Now, before we can run those tests, I need to get back out of this database, right, because I can't
be connected in here.
Yes, I do want to get out and no, I don't want to save.
OK, jump back over to the.
Now let's jump back.
Jump up to the top here and now I can run all of the tests in this class by coming up here and clicking
on the Green Play button for public class.
Don't pay any mind to that little red thing there.
I did something off camera that you didn't see.
All right, so I'm going to run that run people tests.
All right, so I got one that works can save one person, did work, can save two people, did not work.
So let me click on that and see what I got here.
So it was expecting one to not be one.
So let's see here.
We products save.
Repo dad saved John and repo dad, save Bobby.
And then we did a get I.D. is not equal to safe person to get it.
So let's click on this, get ID here and make sure.
Are.
OK, so we hardcoded this ID, right, and we don't want that anymore, right?
So now what we want to do is we want this get ID method to actually return the Real ID, which is what
was originally here in the first place.
So now we can just replace that with the ID.
Right?
And that's why our first test method was passing as far as we know, right?
All right.
So now if we jump back over here to the tests, now, let's run all the tests again.
OK, we are now we've got two green check marks here, and I'm just going to click on this one.
And yeah, all we're seeing here is records affected one.
Now you might think that we might have seen two here instead of one because we actually ended up saving
two people.
But each time we call Save, that saved method is only saving one person at a time.
And that's why we only see, at most one record being affected.
It's one record per save.
OK, but that looks like it actually may be working for us, and we can actually jump back over to the
school squirrel client one more time and reconnect.
Connect and select everything from people and control return, and now I've got plenty of John Smiths
here because I ran those tests a number of times in trying to troubleshoot what wasn't working.
But we've got a baby and we've got a John a couple of times here.
So the inserts are actually working for us.
So let's go ahead and end this lesson.
And in the next lesson, we're going to take an even deeper dive into how all of that is working and
why I made some of the choices that I made and all kinds of good stuff.
So I will see you in the next one.