So far we've only dealt with whole numbers in this course.
It's now time to start looking at floating point numbers.
And what I've done here is I've created
a new project called FloatAndDouble,
so let's go through now talking
about floating point numbers.
So unlike whole numbers,
floating point numbers have fractional parts
that we express with a decimal point.
3.14159 is an example.
So floating point numbers are also known as real numbers.
We use a floating point number
when we need more precision in calculations.
So there's two primitive types in Java
for expressing floating point numbers,
and that's the float and the double primitive types.
The float is a single precision number
and the double is a double precision number.
So precision here refers to the format
and amount of space occupied by the relevant type.
So single precision,
and that's the float primitive type,
occupies 32 bits or four bytes,
and as per our discussion previously of width,
that means it's got a width of 32.
And a double precision,
and that's the double primitive type, is double that,
so it occupies 64 bits or eight bytes,
and that has a width of 64.
And you can see on the screen there
the float and the double ranges there,
and that should confirm to you that the double is,
basically has a much larger range
and more precision than the float.
All right, so now that we're back at the code,
let's confirm what we saw on the slide,
what those ranges were,
and do something similar to what we've been doing
for other primitive types
by using their min and max values.
So what I'm gonna do now,
I'm gonna double click up here.
You can do that.
That puts the code on fullscreen.
And I'll try and do that for all future videos
just to make it clear,
'cause we don't usually need the project pane open,
and if we do we can just open it for that purpose.
All right, so I'm gonna start by typing
float myMinFloatValue is equal to Float.MIN_VALUE,
and we'll do the same for max,
myMaxFloatValue is equal to Float.MAX_VALUE.
Let's print both out.
Our Float minimum value is equal to plus myMinFloatValue.
And you've probably noticed
as we're going through the course now,
as I've gone through a concept a number of times,
I'm not going to repeat and say all the codes.
In that case I didn't talk about the double quotes.
Because we've done this a few times,
that should be hopefully coming second nature to you.
Likewise for the abbreviations for sout.
I'm just typing those now,
assuming you are familiar with those now.
So I'll do the same for Float maximum value equals,
and we want myMaxFloatValue.
All right, then the other thing we'll do is
we'll just take a copy of that,
paste the code in,
and we'll just do a quick search and replace
and do the same for the double primitive type.
So I'm gonna replace float with double.
You've seen me do this before now.
Making sure match case is checked,
and the same for the uppercase version.
Okay, replace all.
All right, and we'll close down the replace window.
Search and replace window.
All right, so we've now got the capability
to check those minimum max values
for both the float and double primitive types,
so let's do that.
We'll run the code,
make sure that it works.
Okay, there's our output.
I'll just put that up a little bit more so we can see.
Okay, and that confirms the ranges
that you saw on the slides.
So you really can see there that double
can work with a much bigger range of numbers,
and it's also a lot more precise than the float.
But of course, on the other hand,
it needs twice the amount of memory,
64 bits or eight bytes,
to store that number compared to the float,
which stores, which requires 32 bits
or four bytes to store its number.
All right, so let's move on now.
Let's actually start typing in a bit of code.
What we're going to do now is start having a look
at how to use some of these variables,
and we're gonna actually add an integer,
and you'll see why later on in the video.
myIntValue.
We'll set that equal to five.
We'll do the same for float,
so myFloatValue is equal to five.
Then double, myDoubleValue equal five.
Now notice that I haven't put anything on the end there.
I haven't put an f or a d or anything there,
and that's been accepted.
In general, the double data type
is accepted as the default,
much in the same way that the integer data type
is accepted by default for whole numbers.
So we can also put a d there or an f there to confirm that,
and it's good practise to do that in general
if you're typing in literal numbers
to make it abundantly clear of the meaning.
All right, so that's our way
of declaring the three variables,
the int, the float, and the double.
Now, that works fine for a whole number,
but you'll find that if we add a number .25 for 5.25,
5.25 decimal,
now if I remove the f there,
we'll actually get an error.
Now, the reason is that the double
is assumed to be the default floating point number,
so we've got a similar problem that we saw
with other data types in previous videos.
And if I hover over that,
you can see that it's requiring a float,
in this case, a literal value that we've typed in,
and it found a double.
So you can see there that by default,
a floating point number is assumed to be a double by Java.
All right, so quick challenge there for you.
Thinking back to our discussion on casting,
which, if you recall,
we used to convert an integer both back to a byte
and then again to a short,
how do you think you'd do the same for the float
to remove this error?
So have a think about that.
Pause the video and try it out
and see if you can get it to work and to remove the error.
When you're ready, come back and resume the video
and we'll go through the solution.
So pause the video now.
Okay, so welcome back.
Let's get this working.
And we need to use a cast.
If you remember,
the format of the cast is left and right parentheses,
so I'll start with the left one,
the name of the data type you want to convert to,
float, and right parentheses,
and I want you to put a space there just to make it clear.
So what's happened there is the error has disappeared,
as you can see there now,
and that's because we're telling Java,
yes, this is a literal double that's been typed here,
but we want you to treat it as a float,
and for that reason,
the error then disappeared.
Generally not recommended to do that.
Well, there's two reasons.
Firstly, as I'll talk about in the next video,
floats aren't usually recommended
to be used much these days.
Double is the preferred floating point data type to use.
But secondly, it's a lot clearer,
I think you'd agree,
comparing that to adding an f on the end there,
it's just easier,
it's less to actually look at,
and the f right at the end tells you,
okay, that's a float.
And that's generally the format
that most programmers will use.
They would use an f to indicate the type
rather than try and cast it,
which is just a little bit more code to look at.
All right, so let's finish the video here.
In the next one,
we'll start exploring more about these floating point types
and we'll start doing some division
to see what happens and what those numbers look like.
So I'll see you in the next video.