So let's discuss a new feature of this
course added in 2018, coding exercises.
So coding exercises are a feature added by
udemy to allow instructors to add
exercises that students can complete to
help reinforce concepts they've actually
been taught. So the cool thing is that
you can literally click a button and
have your solution checked immediately.
So in other words I'll give you a coding
exercise to complete and you can type
in your solution to it interactively
onto the screen and click a button and
see if the solution is correct. So this
is different to the challenges that
you've seen so far in the course,
challenges will win, okay your challenge
and type some text on the screen and
then allow you to go ahead and try and
solve it and then I'll show you the
solution in a video. Coding exercises are
different in that I give you the
exercise then you do them without seeing
a solution in a video, but you do have
that button to click to check the answer.
So there's still are plenty of upcoming
challenges in this course as well as
coding exercises that are meant to
complement those challenges, so this is
new material I've added to help
reinforce the concepts being taught in
the course. Now the thing about coding
exercises is it can be a bit tricky to
understand initially, so in this video
let me go through a sample coding
exercise just so that you can get a
taste for it and when you get to the
next video where you start your first
coding exercise in the course, you'll be
well-equipped to go about it. So let's go
over to you udemy's website now and open
up a coding exercise and get started.
Alright so as you can see in the browser,
we've got the exercise text or the
coding so the text here or description
showing, this is the problem that we need
to solve. Now below that down here and
the right part bottom of the screen
we've got an area where we can type our
source code in, so that's one way of
doing it just typing the code in there
or alternatively we can now switch over
to IntelliJ and copy and paste the code
from IntelliJ into this text area,
the bottom left-hand corners got a browser
Q&A section which we can click and then
enables you to leave any questions you
may have about the coding exercise but
also check a student's response to this
particular coding exercise, so this will
be a list our questions and answers
related to this specific coding exercise.
See now guess this is all new there's
none at the moment so we'll close it down
so as I mentioned you can either type
your results here, your solution here
directly or you can go back to IntelliJ
and test your code in, then paste it
back in here. We're going to do a little
bit of both as we go through this video,
so you can see in terms of this solution
that's asking you to write a method
called check number with an int
parameter number it talks about does
some more information there but let's
just start that, I'm going to come down
here, I'll type over and they're going to
create the definition I'm going to type
public static void check number
parentheses and within the parentheses
I'm going to type int number I'm going
to add a left curly brace and press enter.
When I do that, you can see the right
curly brace is added automatically,
I'm just gonna go to the end of line that
press enter now just to give us a bit
more space and note that towards the
bottom up here check number method needs
to be defined as public static so I've
defined it that way as public static to
make sure that this will work there's
also another note here about not adding
a main method to use solution code but
more on that shortly though. Notice the
file name here positive negative zero dot
java that's important because that's
going to be the name that you need to
make sure that you use and that's
what gets through the course you'll find
that you may need more than one file to
solve a particular coding exercise but
in this case we've just got the one file,
so we're going to deal with that and
notice that there is some smart team is
automatically highlighting Java keywords
and that you saw I added a left
parenthesis and the right one and
added the right curly brace so it does
recognize the Java language, so you can
do your entire solution in here if you
like or if you prefer to do it in
IntelliJ and test it and then paste your
final version in here, you can do that as
well. So to do that we're going to go
through and create an intelligent
project, so I'm going to select the Java
select a new project before I come back
and I'm going to click on Java click on
next, click on next and I'm going to call
this one all those boys want sample
coding exercise of course you would name
it whatever the name of this particular
exercise coding exercise you're trying
to solve then what I'm going to do is
I'm going to add a new class
and I'm going to call this class
positive negative zero and that's
created positive negative zero dot java if
you recall that was the file name we
need to have the same file name there.
Now the other thing here is I'm going to
copy this declaration, I'll save a bit of
time I'm going to paste that back in
IntelliJ, I'll go ahead and do that
and we've now got a method called check
number and at the moment in IntelliJ we
haven't got a main method now there was
a note on the coding exercise saying
that we weren't to add a main method to
there but obviously if we want to test
this code that we're creating in
IntelliJ, we'll need a main method so I'm
gonna go back up to the top here and
type psvm press tab to create our main
method that we're going to use for
testing, so I can only be using the main
method here to test our check number
method when we're in IntelliJ. Alright so,
let's go back to the exercise again and
see what we're meant to be doing so it
says here that the method shouldn't
return any values and we've met that
criteria by specifying void here, so
that's correct
it's just specifying void after static
but what we need to do is print out the
word positive if the parameter number is
greater than 0 so let's go back to
IntelliJ and write the code for that,
this is within the check number method
so to do that we do if number is greater
than 0, put a code block and I'm going
to type positive in double quotes and
obviously in curly braces so basically
were outputting the word positive if a
number that has been passed as an
argument to check number is greater than
0 and by the way notice that the results
that they're looking at for there are in
a lower case so we should be printing
out whatever they're asking for here and
the double quotes is just an example
there we don't include the double quotes
when we're actually returning the value.
Alright, so back to IntelliJ so just to
test that this is working correctly,
we're going to call the method check
number from the main method let's go
ahead and do that so I'm gonna come down
here and we're gonna put check number,
pass the value of five, so we're going to
meet the first condition if your number
is greater than zero, so we're passing five.
So let's actually run that and see
whether this works, they're gonna run our
application so you would normally run it
you see you've got the valley positive
and I'm just going to push this down to
the bottom of the screen so we can see
it a bit easier. So we can see we've got
the valley positive showing there now,
so far so good
Alright so the next part of the
training exercise we need to print the
word negative if the parameter number is
less than zero, let's get back to
IntelliJ and do that we can put else if
number is less than zero, we're going to
do this out there and in parentheses
double quotes we're going to print out
negative all right and there's a check
that we're going to put check number
let's pass a value and say if negative, ten
so we're going to check that and run up,
you can see we've got positive and
negative working so so far our testing
and IntelliJ is working well they can
see we're getting positive and negative
showing, so let's take the opportunity
now to finish off this exercise if
you're not working back in the udemy
interface so I'm going to take a copy
and noticing that I'm only copying at
the moment the code in between the check
number method, so I'm not copying any
other code I'm going to take a copy of
that, I'm going to go back to our coding
exercise making sure my cursor is in the
right place so type over here I'm going
to paste it in to the check number
method that's the code again that we've
worked on in IntelliJ. Now we know that
we haven't finished the challenge yet
because we haven't checked or tried to
output zero but anytime that you want to
check your solution, you can come over
here and click on check solution and the
computer will actually check that
and tell you if something's wrong they
can see here that method call check
number with a value of zero past in
parentheses was returned and says
returned this value and in double quotes
so in other words an empty value but
zero was expected, in other words you can
see that the test was automatically
trying to check for a value of zero and
was expecting the word zero to be
returned but it didn't get anything and
I didn't get anything because of course
we haven't added that part of the test
yet so you can see how this solution is
working for you
in testing your code, the other thing to
keep in mind is if we add something like
we forget to put a last closing right
brace we check the solution it is smart
enough to determine that your code isn't
invalid java and we see we get a
compilation error there I'll go back and
edit again.
so basic Java will actually be checked
so we know that the code is working, give
them a moment to check in which should
get the same problem of zero so it's a
matter of really over here of reading
what this says because they're still
keeping an indication of what you
haven't completed if the challenge or
show you if you've actually got some
errors in your code in this case it's
telling us we now need to check for the
value of zero so I'm going to do
something a little bit different than
unimportant else, with these the arrows
they go out there but it also if number
is equal to zero the two equal signs
either left or right curly brace now
when you're in here we can't type this
out and press tab that doesn't work
because that's an intelligent feature so
in here we have to type in our code in
full, so that's one of the reasons why
you might consider using IntelliJ to
save you bit of typing but here let's do
something different we going to put in
the number or zero I'll put a semicolon
in the line to make it valid. So now if
we check that again check solution
you can see we've got a different result
here method call check number zero in
parentheses returned this value then the
number was zero but zero was expected so
you need to get the output to be
returned identically to what's being
asked for in the coding exercise we're
going to change that, so I come up here
with some changes and we'll try putting
the value of zero but with a capital Z
check that solution again notice here
that we've got the output of zero but
it's expecting zero and learning that
it's basically telling you that the
codes correct but for capitalization is
different so you can see that it's smart
enough to know that you've got the
answer correct but you've got in this
case an uppercase zero and you weren't
asked to do an uppercase one so I'm
going to change that back to a lowercase
yet another I've done that our solution
should be correct,
Let's check the solution again
and you can see at this point of time
now we've now solved the coding exercise
correctly we've got well done your
solution is correct
and the code that's been placed in there
is correct a couple of other last things
to note if we go ahead and we try and
add another method I'll try another one
here public static void we'll call that
Tim test and check that solution we get
a problem e we get an arrow return extra
methods are detected please add only the
required methods expected one method but
that was - so we've got two methods back
so make sure that till you only have
methods in there that are needed and
that's one of the reasons why you don't
include the main method, so the other
thing is it's important to get the
definitions correct if we remove the
word static from here so we've just got
public void and we check that solution
we've now got a compilation error here
and the area he is relating to the fact
we're trying to access something from a
non-static method, so the point of the
exercise here is that the description is
said to use static so we need to use
what they're suggesting and make sure we
do exactly that to get this to work
properly. I set this back to static again
click on check solution and we should be
correct again. Alright so that's it we've
got our solution to the coding exercise
correct. Now keep in mind with is that
there's no universal solution for the
coding exercise the most important part
is that it works as per these training
exercises text in other words it's
giving the outputs that as being asked
in the coding description you can write
every coding exercise in many different
ways, so some exercises might require
more testing in IntelliJ first so it
might be a good idea to test the code
inside the main method as I started
doing earlier in this video before
transferring and pasting your code back
here into the coding exercise itself
some other was testing it in IntelliJ.
Alright, so that's coding exercises.
Let's now move on to the next video.