In the previous video, we started
working with objects and classes.
You got up to speed with that.
It's now time to talk about Inheritance,
what that is and
how that applies to objects.
To do that, the best way to
get started is to go back and
talk about physical objects again because,
the thing is,
different kinds of objects have a certain
amount in common with each other.
Using an example of computers,
you could say that an iMac computer,
an Android Nexus 9 tablet, and
a Dell PC all share the characteristics of
computers, in that they've got RAM, random
access memory, ROM, read-only memory, and
they've got a current state as to whether
the device is on or off, and so on.
They share common characteristics,
but yet each of these devices
add additional features that collectively
make them different to each other.
For example,
an iMac runs the OSX operating system,
it's got an intel CPU,
got a hard drive, USB ports.
An Android Next 9 tablet, for example,
runs on the Android operating system, and
it's got a touch screen for input.
A Dell PC runs Windows, it's also
got an Intel but maybe an AMD CPU,
it's got a hard drive, a mouse, and so on.
You can see that, while objects
can share similar characteristics,
they can also be different as well.
What object oriented program really
allows us to do is to create classes
to inherit commonly used standard
behavior from other classes.
One of the best ways to
actually show inheritance,
rather than giving you a heap
of slides discussing it,
is to actually immediately go into some
code and actually start working through
some scenarios in showing you what
inheritance looks like in Java code.
What I'm going to do is, I'm gonna
start with the analogy of an animal.
If you think of any animal,
perhaps certain behaviors that
are shared across all types of animals.
For example, animals all eat,
they all are able to move in some way,
they've all got a body so
that's some of the basic things,
but what about things like,
for example, legs?
Well, no, not all animals
have legs because snakes and
worms are an example of
an animal without legs.
Eyes?
Well, no, not all animals have eyes
because there's varieties of spiders, for
example, that have no eyes.
Do they all have a brain?
Well, yes, actually they do, although it
does depend on the definition of a brain,
but essentially, yes,
they've all got that basic mechanism.
They've also got size, and
also they've got a weight as well.
What we could say was,
we could create a very basic class that
we could actually apply to each and
every animal out there, and that we know
that any animal would have these traits.
We're gonna create a new class now and
call it Animal, and we're gonna add some
state and behavior, in other words,
field and methods to model that.
Let's do that now, and
I've created a new class.
I've created a new project
here called Inheritance, so
I'm gonna create a new Java class,
and I'm gonna call it Animal.
We talked about those states, so
we've got brain, we've got a body, a size,
and a weight, are gonna be our four
fields that we're going to apply.
I'm going to create a private field for
each of those,
and we're just gonna have an integer,
private int brain,
private int body, private int size,
private int weight.
We'll also add another one,
and a name because, of course,
every animal has got a name, so
we're gonna create a string for that.
We're not gonna be too worried at this
stage as to what the contents of these
fields are.
I've designed, as you can see, an integer
data type for the brain, body size, and
weight, and
likewise a string for the name.
Doesn't really matter too much at
the moment as to what type of data we're
going to put in there.
The main thing is what we're trying to
do is just come up with characteristics,
state, in this case,
of things that all animals have got.
We're also gonna create a constructor so
that we can construct
an animal class easily.
I'm going to just use my command
to create a constructor, and
I'm going to specify all
five as parameters, like so,
and the other thing we'll do is,
we'll create a getter for
each of those fields, as well,
in case we need to access that later.
That's the basic definition of an animal.
That would be the base class, if you will,
that all our other classes that
we're going to create, sort of subtypes
of animals, will base themselves off.
Another example of an animal is going to
be a dog, so what we're gonna do is create
a class called Dog, but we're gonna
inherit from this animal class.
We're gonna go create a new class,
call it dog.
In Java terminology,
if you want to inherit from another class,
in other words, you wanna be
able to access, in some fashion,
the state of behavior that's in that
other class, you use the extends keyword.
We type extends, and we type animal.
You can see that IntelliJ has come up and
given us choice of animal.
By doing that,
we're able to use the state of behavior
that's been defined in the animal class
in this new dog class we created.
Now, you notice straight away that I've
got an error, so the error that's on
the screen is saying, there's no default
constructor available in the animal class.
What that's saying is, look, I'm trying
to use the animal class, and to do that,
I need to be able to call
the constructor for that class.
That's what we need to do when we're
creating a new class that extends
from another one.
We need to be able to call that other
constructor class to initialize it, and
if you'll recall,
if we go back to the animal class,
we've got a constructor there, so
we can initialize those five parameters.
What we really need to do is make
sure that we've got a constructor for
the dog class that calls that other class,
in other words,
calls the constructor for
that other class.
To do that, generate, and just in case you
aren't sure how I'm generating that again,
click on Code and Generate.
You can see to the right, in my case,
on a Mac, it's Command+N.
You'll go to your operating system, and
there'll be a shortcut for your platform,
so choose that to generate a constructor.
You can see that I just literally
selected constructor, and
intelliJ actually filled in the rest.
What's happened here is, you can see
that automatically, there's those
five parameters that actually are dealing
with the animal class, name, brain,
body size, and weight, have been
created as parameters to the Dog class,
to the Dog constructor, in other words.
Then this keyword super has come up,
so what super means
is to call the constructor that is for
the class that we're extending from.
In this case the, superclass.
The super class, or sort of the big
class that this class is extending from,
using the extends keyword, or
inheriting from, to be more precise.
What this allows us to do is to initialize
the Animal class, and if you recall,
the dog is actually part of an animal
class, so we've defined an animal class.
We're saying it's based on the animal
class, but what we can also do is,
we can add more features
to this Dog class.
Things that are unique to a dog and
not just a very generic animal,
if that makes sense.
That first line there, what that's done,
it's initialized the base characteristics
of an animal, namely the name, the brain,
the body, the size, and
the weight, in a constructor.
What we can also do at this point, because
we're now working in the Dog class,
is we can assign extra state,
extra fields, in other words, and
extra behavior, that is,
methods that are unique for
a dog and aren't necessarily
applicable for an animal.
For example, we could create some fields,
private int eyes
because remembering that not all animals
have eyes, but all dogs do have eyes.
Private int legs, not all animals
have legs, but dogs do have legs.
All dogs have legs.
Private int tail, all dogs have a tail.
Private int teeth, dogs have teeth.
Maybe another one would be private String
coat, would be the type of coat, where
they've got sort of a long silky coat or a
short coat and fur, those types of things.
There are unique characteristics relating
to a dog that we're adding in addition to
the animals there.
You can see, really, what we're saying is,
the dog has got these fields here,
these characteristics, but in addition,
they've also got these base
characteristics, but we've defined those
in the base animal class because they
aren't specific to a dog, and that's
why we're extending from that class.
This is what Java and other object
oriented programming languages allow you
to do, is to create a base class that's
got the basic information to work on, and
then you can extend from that class,
which indeed is very powerful.
Cuz what that also means is not
only with the fields, we can also
add specific methods, like, for example,
going back to our animal class now,
we could introduce some behaviors, and
we could add some methods for those.
For example, all animals have to eat,
so we could create a method called eat,
and we won't worry about the functionality
for now, but it's there anyway.
Another one might be move.
That's two methods that
are unique to all animals.
All animals have some mechanism, some way,
to move, and all animals eat in some way,
shape, or form.
By doing that and making it public, if we
go back to the Dog class, what that means
straight away is that function, that
method, is now available to the Dog class.
The base class we've defined.
We've said, all animals are able to eat
because we specified that
method in the Animal class.
This method is inherited
from Dog automatically, and
we'll be able to use that, and
I'm gonna show how to do that shortly.
Let's look now at this
constructor cuz there's two
components that we need to do
now if you think about it.
When we're creating a dog, and
we're modeling a dog in computer terms,
we've got those parameters that have
been defined there, namely the name,
whether it's got a brain,
the body, the size, and the weight.
But we also need to initialize those
other characteristics as well,
namely the eyes, legs,
tail, teeth, and coat.
Really what we'd need to do is,
we would need to initialize
that in our constructor, and
not just the fields that we've defined
that initialize just the animal class.
Cuz we're now in the Dog class,
we're creating a constructor for the dog.
We need to work with
these extra parameters.
One of the things we can do is,
we can be a little bit smart with our
first definition here with
the parameters that need to be passed.
For argument's sake, we're gonna say that
all dogs have got brains, so instead of
having to use it as a parameter,
I'm gonna remove that parameter there.
I'm just gonna put past the number one,
which really is just our way of saying,
all dogs have got a brain.
Likewise, for the body,
we're going to do the same thing.
We're not going to put it there as
a parameter cuz we're gonna say,
all dogs have got a body.
You can see, we're not done.
I've still initialized the animal class.
It's still got the five parameters
it needs, but what we've said is,
we know that all dogs have got a brain and
a body, so we're not going to force
the programmer who's creating the Dog
class to have to define those.
Well, what we will do is,,
we will add these as extra parameters,
so we'll actually add a parameter for
the eyes, for
the legs, for the tail, for
the teeth, and the coat.
You can see we've used some of
those parameters already, and
those parameters that are in
the Animal class have been sent on, and
we've executed this constructor, and
those fields have been initialized.
What we now need to do is
initialize the other ones.
To do that, and you've seen this before,
we'll just do a this.eyes = eyes;,
this.legs = legs;, this.tail = tail;,
this.teeth = teeth;,
and this.coat = coat;.
Effectively now we've initialized all
of the fields relating to this dog.
Of course, some of those fields were the
basic fields that were part of the Animal
class, and the rest were part of
the Dog class because they were unique
characteristics related to a dog and
not necessarily an animal, which may,
as we've talked about before,
may not have some of these features.
Okay, so
let's try starting some of this code now,
start using some of this code, creating
a new class to see how this works.
What you're going to do first is,
we're going to create an animal,
basic animal class.
As you've seen us create
new classes before,
we're just going to create that
to confirm that it does work.
We'll be creating a new animal class,
we've just got the one constructor, and
you can see we need to do a name,
so we'll just call it Animal.
Animal.
Then we need a body, so we'll say.
Then we need a brain, so put 1,1,.
We need a size, so we'll just say as
the default five and weight five.
You've seen that before.
There's nothing particularly new there,
but
that's just the definition for
base animal.
It doesn't really make a lot of sense
because we want to be specific.
We want to work, in this case,
with a dog, so to do that,
to create a Dog class,
we're gonna type Dog, dog = new Dog, and
remember the parameters will change,
and it'll be here.
So, we might call this dog a Yorkie.
We might say the size is 8,
the weight might be 20, 2 eyes,
4 legs, 1 tail, 20 teeth for
argument's sake, and
we might say it's a long silky,
would be the type of coat.
That's now initializing a dog.
Nothing particularly new there.
You've seen that before, and
I'll just fix that typo.
One of the things we can do, this is where
inheritance really starts making sense,
is we can start using some of
these functions because, remember,
we defined these two public functions,
eat and move.
What we could do, we could type dog.,
and notice the eats come up, so we're able
to use the method eat, even though if we
look at our Dog class, you can see
there's no method definition for eat.
Where's the eat defined?
Well, remember the eat was defined
in this class, in the animal class,
so this is one of the features of
inheriting from another class.
Because we've defined
the method eat as public,
we've said this method
is publicly accessible,
the dog class can see that,
and it's extending animal.
In other words, it's inheriting from the
animal class, and as a result, we're able
to use the eat method, even though it's
not actually part of the Dog class.
And just to confirm that,
we'll go to the animal class, and
we'll let a System.out.print
animal.eat() called,
just so we know that is where
it has actually come from and
which part of the code is being executed.
If we run that.
You can see animal.eat() called,
so just by that process,
even though we're accessing the Dog class,
it knows that the dog is a type of
an animal because we've
inherited from the class animal.
As a result of doing that, we're able to
access the functionality that's part and
parcel of the animal class, and
we are able to use the eat method.
But it does get better than that
because what we can also do,
going back to the Dog class,
we can override this eat method.
What we can say is, well, like a dog eats
in a particular fashion, for example,
the dog chews its food.
All animals don't necessarily chew food,
but the dog does chew its food, so
what we might want to do here is,
we might want to create a private method
called chew, and
this is something unique to a dog.
We'll put something
like dog.chew() called,
but then also what we can do is,
we can use a generate command again.
I can come over here and
I can put in override methods.
Now, what override does, and I'm gonna
select that, you can see straight away,
it's given us a list of methods,
including the constructor,
that are available in the Animal class.
In other words, it says, okay, I know that
you're extending from the Animal class.
These are the methods
that can be overridden.
In other words, we can create
a version of that same method
that exists in the Animal class,
but make it unique for
the Dog class, and that's something
that is inherently very powerful.
The other thing I want to point out here
is, you notice this java.lang.Object,
I'm going to talk about that in
the next video, but what that is,
is that every single class you create,
even though it doesn't come up and
show you by the use of the extends
keyword, it does actually get extended.
You are extending this object class, which
is a special class created by Java, but
more on that in the next video.
For now, let's override the eat method,
which is part of the Animal class.
We're gonna create a special method for
the dog for eating, so
we're gonna click on that.
Java will come up automatically and
give you this @Override symbol, and
that's to remind you that we're overriding
a method that is in the superclass.
In this case, it's in the animal class.
Now, both the Dog class has
got its own eat method, and
also the Animal class
has got its eat method.
What we can then do here is,
we can just put something to
indicate that we're calling in here.
We'll put Dog.eat() called,
and let's also put chew, and
we'll say the process of a dog
eating food is that it's chewing,
so we're gonna call our method that
is unique to the dog class, and
then we're gonna use super.eat.
What super means is call the super
equivalent of that class, a super., and
the name of the function.
Java will automatically come up here and
go, okay, the superclass for
this current class is animal, so
it's gonna go back to here and
look at the eat method and call that.
Let's run that and see what happens.
What's happened is the Dog.eat
method was called.
If you recall previously, when we called
Dog.eat, it went automatically into
the animal method, and it called this
method here in the Animal class because,
of course, we did not have
an eat method in our Dog class.
Now, we've added an eat
method to the dog class.
Dog.eat method has been called first.
We then use chew, which called the private
method chew in the Dog class, but
then we use super.eat,
which called the animal.eat class.
So, that's using inheritance.
This video is getting quite long.
Let's continue this in the next video.