So in this video we're going to talk about
the concept of auto boxing and unboxing.
So to start with we're just gonna have
a little brief recap of arrays and
array lists and
we'll move on to autoboxing.
So firstly, you're aware that we can do
something like this, no doubt because
we've actually been through this with
a code creating a regular array.
Let's just call that stringArray
equals new String(10).
And likewise we could do that for
an integer if we wanted to new int(10) so
that's creating array.
You've seen that before,
I've ten elements starting from position,
element 0 through 9 and
we can also create an array list.
We can do ArrayList String.
You've seen this before and
we'll call that string arrayList
= new arrayList like so.
And we can use that and then we can do
something like stringArrayList.add "Tim".
And that would add an element to
the arrayList and we would actually add
an object of the type string to
the arrayList for us automatically.
But interestingly enough,
what we can't do is something like this.
We can't do an arrayList int
inarrayList = new ArrayList.
We actually get an error.
And the error we actually get is,
type argument cannot be of primitive type.
And this, as it turns out, is an issue
because a primitive type is not a class.
And we actually need that,
a class reference here,
to be able to use that to be able
to save something to an arrayList.
So, if we had a list of integers, we
can't save them based on what we know so
far of Java, in an arrayList.
What we could do, for example,
we could do something like this,
we could create a class.
I'm just going to create it in here,
we can put create, and
we'll do type in class, and
we'll call it intClass.
We can have a private int myValue.
We can add a constructor.
And we can also add a getter and setter.
Like so, very simple little class,
as you can see there, and
we can do something like this.
So we can just comment this line out for
now.
And we could do something like arrayList
= intClass = intClassArrayList
= new ArrayList like so.
And then we could do
intClassArrayList.add.
So we could do something
like new IntClass(54) and
what that would do would be in the first
array element in the array list.
It would actually add an object of
type IntClass with the value 54 and
obviously this would the class.
This would be the class that the objects
being created from that would be added to
the arrayList, so that would work.
It's a little bit messy because there's
all this extra constructor code and
there's getters and setters and so
forth that we'd need to create to do that.
So wouldn't it be good if there
was an easier way to do this and
for all the primitive types,
the variables,
the data types, if there was a way
to actually use those as objects.
Well that's what autoboxing is all
about because Java does provide us
with that functionality.
Now, you might be looking at the string
and saying to yourself, well hang on,
string's a primitive type,
why isn't that working?
Why is that working you should say.
Well if you recall,
String in fact is not a primitive type.
It's actually a class in its own right.
And usually, you can actually tell that.
On the Mac, I'm gonna hold down Ctrl and
hover over it and click.
And you can see that String is
actually a class in its own right.
It's actually fully a class, and
it's got all these other bits and
pieces in it, and this is some of
the Java source code relating to a class.
So that's the reason why that is working,
and that is because that's
actually a class in its own right.
Now contrasting that to going
back to our main again, and
if we try to do the same thing to integer,
I'm holding command on my Mac.
And I can't click on that.
I can hover over the string.
But can't have the integer.
I can hover over the integer, but
nothing happens when I go to click it.
Hover and that's because it isn't a class.
So the bottom line is for the arrayList
but also for lots of these classes and
lots of other Java classes,
it needs to be passed a class.
In other words, passed an object.
So it's very common for you to want
to use these primitive types, and
to be able to pass those as classes.
So again, you could do something
like this example up here,
where you could create your own class and
parse it, and yes, that will work.
That's not really what we want to do.
There's actually a better
way of doing that and
we can use the concept of autoboxing.
And it turns out that Java supports
some primitive types by using a class,
an object wrapper if you will, for
the class because if you think about it,
what we've done with this
class here that we created.
We actually created a wrapper, so in other
words we wrapped and we sort of said
the integer myValue is the variable that's
gonna contain the value for this class.
And we wrapped up in a class.
We made sure that it wasn't
publicly available with a variable.
We can only update the variable using
a constructor initially and then a setter.
And you can retrieve the value
only by using the getter.
So that's sort of
the concept of a wrapper.
Where you're actually wrapping
this functionality and
the way to access this
is the access modifier.
So that not everyone can access it.
Well it turns out that Java's
got a lot of these in built.
So for example in the case of Integer,
we can do something like this.
We can put Integer, and
we can put integer = new Integer.
And you can see that
the default option for
a new Integer when we're creating a new
object, we can actually pass an int value.
So if we do something like that, and
the difference between Integer and
int is that Integer's actually a class.
So again, if we hover over this we can
see that I can actually click on that.
And we get the fact that
it's actually a class.
And all this other stuff relating
to how it's set up within Java.
So you'll find that there's one of those,
one of these for each primitive type.
So there's one there for an int.
Which will see is called the Integer.
There's a Double.
I wanna do a couple.
I won't do all of them.
But the other one's called Double.
We could call that doubleValue
because I can't use the word Double
cuz it's already keyword = new Double.
And if you hover over you can see
it's hunting for doubleValues so
we can put something like (12.25) and that
will quite happily accept that as a value.
So that helps us in a sense that
we can now use in array list.
So we can do something
like arrayList
We can call it intArrayList
= new arrayList.
And you can see now Java's quite happy
with that because this is actually a valid
class unlike what we were trying to do
up here earlier when we were trying to
actually assign a primitive type into it.
So let's just use it as an example
just to see actually how it works.
Let's now we've created our Integer class,
let's just do a full loop and
actually add some entries.
So a typical way to add them would be
something like for(int i=0; i<=10; i++).
We could put intArrayList oops,
intArrayList .add.
And noticing here that it's
wanting an Integer now.
This is the one we're going to select.
The integer is the type for this variable
intArrayList so I'm gonna add or
we could do something
like (Integer.valueOf i).
And what the .valueOf is actually taking
the value of i as the primitive type and
converting it automatically into
the Integer class I should say so
that we can use it as a class.
Therefore then when we come to execute
this, we can do something like,
so we'll just copy that code.
And need that first line and
we'll do something like (i + let's
just output the contents, and
it will be intArrayList.get,
the element that we want to retrieve and
.intValue.
And notice there's a int value which is a
value which converts it back from Integer
from the Integer class back into
an int type to a primitive type.
Again, that's how we convert it.
So essentially the two parts that we're
dealing with here is this part here,
this is auto boxing.
This is when we're creating or
converting an integer,
a base primitive type int to an Integer,
that's called auto boxing.
So we're taking the primitive type and
we're going to the object wrapper.
We're going to the class,
that's called autoboxing.
Unboxing is where we're taking it from
the class or from the object wrapper and
converting it back to a primitive type.
So that's the difference between
autoboxing and unboxing.
So looking at that code, you can see
that it's pretty straightforward and
if we run that, we should find that we
get the results that we think we'll get.
We should just get the output to show
to those integers are being saved.
And we can see we get 0,
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9,
10 as we would expect based on
the code that we have developed.
So nothing particularly hard there, but
it turns out that Java actually
even makes things easy for you.
I wanted to show you the long
way of doing it first.
And now I want to show you the short way,
cuz it turns out that it's actually easier
than you think to create some code to
convert to using this autoboxing and
unboxing.
So for example what we can do is something
like this Integer myIntValue = 56.
So looking at that, you'll probably
think well hang on, why is that working,
because surely that's incorrect.
Because we haven't got any reference
that we have up here Integer = new.
So that when we're creating a new class
you would normally have to use the new key
word and then the name of the class and
then pass in the parameters for
the constructor.
Well it turns out that Java is helping you
out here by issuing a bit of a shortcut.
So when you actually type that command in
what happens is when the code is compiled
this code will be executed.
So the Integer.value(56) I think I typed.
So that's about what
happened at compiled time.
So you can type it like this but at
compile time, it gets converted to that.
In other words Java's doing
the hard work for you.
Because it recognizes and it says okay
this is an integer, an integer object so
this is a class and
you entered an integer here, so
therefore I know what to do with it.
I'm gonna actually use this reference
here to actually create the proper
class based on the proper object,
in this case, myIntValue.
Now if you typed something like 56.56,
that's different because
you've now typed a Double.
And it's actually saying to
you there it's looking for
an integer and you've typed in a Double.
To get that to work,
you'd actually have to use a Double class,
the object wrapper Double
to get that to work.
And the other thing I
want to show you also is,
if I just go back to
make that valid again.
We can then type int myInt = myIntValue.
And again looking at that you'll say well
hang on, this is a primitive type and
this is an object.
How is that working?
Well what's actually happening is Java's
actually doing something like this.
It's actually putting Integer, or
it's actually putting myInt.intValue.
It's putting that code in for
us automatically.
So in other words, if we put that code,
copy that and we paste it in there, that's
essentially what it's actually doing is
oops, that was meant to be myIntValue.
That's actually what it's doing.
Fix that up.
So basically it's looking at myIntValue
and saying, well that's an Integer,
an object wrapper.
And it's actually putting
the .intValue in.
If we have a look at the method .intValue,
you can see that returns an int.
So that's why that's working for us.
So this is the concept of autoboxing and
unboxing.
And you can see that Java is trying to
make things easier for you by actually
at compile time changing the code that you
are typing to what the correct code is for
it to work.
And preventing compile time
errors that come up, and
really just generating
some of the code for you.
So it's important to understand that
what's happening behind the scenes.
Cuz otherwise you'll look at the code and
think well this makes no sense at all.
So there's nothing stopping you
from doing things the long way.
Doing something like that perhaps to
create a new Double or to use in the case
that I showed you up here,
we can actually type Integer.value(56).
If you type it like that,
that would certainly work as well but
just probably with these days with a
modern compilers it's best to actually use
it this way because it's less code.
Easier to read, and
just makes a lot of sense.
So that's just to show
you that this works.
Instead of using integers, because we've
used those a lot in previous examples,
let's do something with a Double type,
just so it makes sense in a loop.
So we can put something like for.
Actually what we'll do first
is we'll create an arrayList.
So it's arrayList Double.
We'll put myDoubleValues = new
arrayList = new arrayList=DoubleValues.
Now we're gonna put something like
for(double we'll call it dbl,
our variable,
dbl equals we'll start on 0.0.
Then we'll put something
like all dbl>=10.0.
Again, we're putting the decimal
points because it's a double.
We wanna increment double += 0.5.
So we're gonna increment it by0.5 each
time we go through the loop starting at
0.0 until we get to 10.0.
So with all that boxing we can
type the name of the array,
so that's myDouble Values.add,
then we can put Double.value of dbl.
And that would certainly work and then
we could actually use that loop again.
What we'll do is
a different loop this time.
We'll actually iterate
through the entire array so
we'll use an integer this time i=0,
i < and
it's gonna be myDoubleValues.size i ++.
And we're gonna put double
value = myDoubleValues.get(i).,
this time it's gonna be .doubleValue,
because we're converting to a double, and
you can see on the right over here it's
actually going to be returning a double.
So that's correct.
So that's gonna return that as a double,
and then we can actually print that out.
We could put something like i + value.
So that's one way of doing it.
So the first example,
double.valueOf, that's autoboxing.
We're converting the primitive
type double to the object wrapper,
to the object in other words,
that's autoboxing.
And here we're using the .doubleValue so
we're actually unboxing,
we're converting it from the object.
The object wrapper back
into the primitive top of
this case the double which is value.
So let's just run that,
make sure it works,
then we'll just do the shortcuts
to this code again.
And I've got a typo here,
should be an i = like that and
we'll just try running them again Okay,
so that's better and
what I might do just to make things
a little bit easy to read, let's just
get rid of those from the output so
that we don't see that in the output.
Then we run it again and
there's our example.
Starting from 0, we've incremented
by 0.5 each time, 0.5, 1,
1.5, right through to 10,
and there's 20 elements.
So again, that's the autoboxing and
unboxing.
But equally, as I mentioned,
we could also use the shortcut.
So the shortcut would actually be to
remove this altogether, and just add dbl.
And likewise for this,
we could do the same thing.
We could actually get rid of this
.doubleValue if you wanted to,
and the code will still compile and run.
And the reason that's
running is behind the scenes.
Java is actually adding those
commands using the dot value of, and
the dot, in this case doubleValue to
actually retrieve those values back and
convert them for us automatically.
So that's auto boxing, and unboxing, good
concept to understand when you need to
actually store the common primitive types.
The primitive data types that
are part of Java in array lists or
pass them as parameters using objects,
especially to some other Java
code that's out there these days that
will actually require you to use these.
So they are used quite a bit.
The object wrapper equivalence for
the primitive type, so
it's certainly good to know those.
And just in finishing off,
as I mentioned there's one of these for
each primitive type so
you can probably find those easily enough.
So I'm going to end the video here.
In the next video I'm going to show you
the challenge for this part of the course.
And type that out and
then you can have a go at that.
So I'll see you in that next video.