So it's noW time to talk in more detail
about operators.
We've discussed very briefly what operators are
and have a few of them in use or have used them.
Let's go deeper into that now.
So what are operators?
Well, operators in Java are special symbols that perform
specific operations on one, two or three operands
and then return a result.
And as an example, we've previously used the plus
or addition operator to sum the value of two variables.
But there are many other operators in Java.
So what is an operand?
Well, an operand is a term used to describe any object
that is manipulated by an operator.
So if we consider this statement,
int myvar equals 15 plus 12;
then plus here is the operator in 15 and 12
are the operands.
And variables used instead of literals are also operands.
So it's another example double mysalary equals
hoursWorked multiplied by hourlyRate.
So in that above line hoursWorked in hourlyRate
are both operands and the star, the multiplication
is the operator.
What's an expression?
An expression is formed by combining variables, literals,
method return values, which we haven't covered yet,
and operators.
So there a way of actually forming and combining
those values to produce a result.
So in the line below, 15 plus 12 is the expression
which returns the value of 27.
Now in the statement below hoursWorked multiplied
by hourlyRate is the expression.
So if hoursWorked was 10, and hourlyRate was 20,
then the expression would return 200
because 10 times 20 is 200.
All right, so let's explore operators using some code
and we'll swing back to IntelliJ to do this.
And I've created a project here called operators,
so do that if you're following along and you haven't already
created a new project.
All right, I'm gonna start by typing
and delete that comment.
And we'll start by typing int result is equal to one
plus two semicolon, I'm going to add two slashes
there on top, one plus two equals three.
You've actually seen this in use before.
we've done and some arithmetic, some basic arithmetic
using the plus or add operator.
And in fact we've used a number of operators already.
But now I just really wanna clarify and go through the major
operators so that you can become familiar with them,
and then know how to use them.
And you'll find that some operators tend to be used
a lot more frequently than others.
So here what I've done is I've added a comment at the end
of the line with two forward slashes to type out
what the expression should evaluate to before
we print it out more on comments in a moment.
But note here that we've got two operators
on this statement.
We've got the equal operator and the plus operator.
So the equal operator is an assignment operator.
So it's used to assign of value.
So in this case it's assigning what's on the right-hand side
of the equal operator.
To the variable we've called result and the value
will be three in this case,
which is the sum of one plus two.
The plus or addition operator sums the operand to the left
and operand to the right.
So the expression is using two operands here.
Now we can also use a single operand by commenting out
the one plus two and replacing it with a three.
So we could obviously come back here and change
that to three.
Back the expression is in there just a single
literal number which is in this case is a three.
So we've got a single operator, the equals to operator
and a literal value, and that's it.
All right, so comments are ignored by the computer
and are added to a programme to help describe something.
Now comments are there for humans.
We use our two forward slashes in front of any code
or on a blank line.
Anything after the two slashes, the two forward slashes
right through to the end of the line you added to is ignored
by the computer.
So aside from describing something about a programme,
comments can be used to temporarily disable code,
and that's another useful thing when you're testing,
which we'll look at and we'll do a little bit later
on in the course.
All right, so let's go back and code some more.
So we're gonna undo that change back to the original
expression of one plus two.
So let's actually print this out to make sure it does work.
And we'll type in one plus two equals
and then we'll print out the value result,
which contains the expression one plus two,
we'll run this.
No surprise is, one plus two equals three.
Well, let's introduce another variable.
Int previous result, we're gonna say equal
to the value of result.
We'll print it out.
We'll put a previous result
is equal to plus previous result,
let's just run that to make sure it's working.
Previous result equals three.
Let's now go ahead and change the value of results.
On the next line I'm going to top result equals result minus
one semicolon, and I'm gonna to press tab
and I'm gonna put a comment there.
And the expression is going to be,
and we'll look at the left operand, the values three
the moment for result.
So it's gonna be three and the operator is minus.
The right operand is one.
So three minus one,
obviously the answer is two.
Let's confirm that, we'll print it out.
Three minus one equals plus result, we'll run that.
Three minus one is two.
So notice how previous result and result are independent
of each other.
So even though we assigned result to previous result,
previous result doesn't get updated when result gets
a new value.
So to confirm that I'm just going to take a copy of line 10,
I'm going to paste that on line 13.
If we run this again we can see that even though that result
was changed to a value of two on line 11,
and we confirmed that once we print out
that result on line 12.
In the case of previous result it's still set to three,
and that's because the assignment for previous result
was done on the line 9 and we didn't update previous result.
Well, so let's try something else for another operator.
So we'll come down here, and we'll do another one.
We're going to top result equals result multiplied by 10
using the asterisks or multiplication operator.
And what should be happening there is the,
we know the value of result is two
So that's going to be two multiplied,
and the right operand is 10.
So two times 10 equals 20.
And if we put this out there should be two times 10
equals plus result.
Let's run that.
Two times 10 equals 20.
And we won't bother using previous result moving forward
because already determined that.
All right, so next, let's try a division.
So result equals result, division is a forward slash.
So here it's going to be,
we know the result currently is set to 20.
So 20 divided by five should equal four.
And we'll print out the value.
That's gonna be 20 divided by five equals,
and print out the value of result.
20 divided by five, and surprisingly is four.
All right, so moving on, let's now look at the remainder
or modulus operator.
And what that does, it retains the remainder
of two operands.
So to see that working, we're going to type the code.
On line 21 I'm going to type result.
Similar to what we've done before.
So result equals result, but this time I'm going to use
the modulus or remainder operator,
which is the percent sign three.
In terms of what we're doing here,
this should be giving us the remainder of operand
in parentheses.
So it's clear, and we know result has left operand.
Current value of a result is four.
So the modulus operator and the right side,
the right operand rather is three.
So how many times does three go into four.
One with one left over.
So the answer there should therefore be one.
Let's print it out.
So it's basically four modulus or remainder
operator three should be equal one.
Let's run it to confirm that that's the case.
All right, we can see four remainder three gives us one,
because of course three goes into four one
with one times with one remainder.
All right, so let's end the video here.
In the next video we'll continue on with the operators.
And we'll start looking at some shortcuts you can use
when using operators.
See you in the next video.