ok so we started this project in the
last video so let's go ahead and finish off the
code and then we'll talk about it a bit
more so we've actually managed to add
the arrays the string arrays for nature
words and divine words to the respective
sets again using the arrays.aslist
method which conveniently does it for us
because their isn't in the Java language at the
moment a set or map literal like you can see
on line 43 we can't do something
equivalent to that for an array with a set of literal at this stage that's why we've
done it that way to get those items
into our sets
so let's figure out the asymmetric
difference nature take divine and also
then do divine take nature to see what it ends up and will have a look at it on the screen after we have done that
come down here and we start by seeing
what the result is of nature take
divine ok nature take
divine so we can do that by typing....
set.....
.....so we are going to initialize that with the nature set and of course we
originally defined on line 41 and then we added to
on line 44 I'm gonna do...
.....
...so we are obviously by doing the
removal alll that's equivalent to divine take nature and
we are going to do....
and the method we are going to used to
print out is going to be....
.....
.......we defining it as a set but it is a hash set because that is how we defined it.....
......
.....
....just gonna show the words left and right across the screen.....
...so if we run this
...and we are getting an error because of a typo and because I didn't end that I wasn't paying enough
attention ok will try again ok and you can see nature take divine gives us all but art thee nature unknown
but deducting nature from divine so divine take nature gives us a different set of
words and again the reason for that is load the image again
circle on the left confirming that
represents the set nature which we can
seen the source code before...
...the one on the right in
blue is divine and where they overlap is
the intersection of the two sets and
the set of everything is in both
is the Union now the asymmetric
difference nature take divine will
contain all the green words as you saw
you can see that just in the output to
the top their top right and divine take
nature will contain the blue ones which
of course
what following code has printed out for both
cases now Java doesn't have a method
for calculating the symmetric difference
possibly because that's used less often
when dealing with sets now the symmetric
difference as opposed to the asymmetric
difference the symmetric difference is
the elements that appear in one set or
the other but not both so it can therefore
be defined as the union minus the
intersection and that will essentially
gives the green and blue words in our
examples now because we know now how to get the union and intersection we can get
the symmetric difference by removing the
intersection from the union that makes
sense so let's go ahead and do....so let's create
another set for this so....
.....
...and we use the wrong variable name because union defined earlier in the code so.....
....
.....and now we can
print out some symmetric difference because we've
done that and again the symmetric
difference is just removing the intersection
from the union so to do that
will type a message as to what it is....
.....
...so if we
run this now
and again bringing up the image on the
screen now we've run it so you can see
that we should have all the green and
all the blue but not the ones in the
Union so we shouldn't have the words to
their which we haven't and we shouldn't have
the word is which we haven't gotten there
but we should have all the other words
so that's asymmetric difference ok so
the last record bit of code for this video is going
to do with is the contains all that's
the last bulk operation and remember in
the previous video we talked about what
bulk operations are and I gave you a link to the
Oracle documentation but contains all is
used to test it if one set is a super set of
another
this one's actually non-destructive so its only
testing membership and doesn't actually
modify the sets just literally returns
a true or false as appropriate depending on
your answer so....
.....
...and lastly we can do a test with divine we can do...
...so if we run this we can see
that the first test on line 68
the divine set is not a subset of nature
but intersection is a subset of both
unsurprisingly because the elements in
the intersection of two sets have to
appear on both sets by
definition if you're not interested in
sets theory sets can still be useful
the divine set we created contain all
the words when initialized with but
each one appears only once so therefore
using a set can be a really quick way to
get all the unique items in the
collection now the other thing to keep in
mind is the hash set class itself is also
very fast so they can be really good way
to group related items together even if
you don't plan to perform mathematical
set operations on it so that's it that's our discussion about sets concluded and
finished in the next video we're going to
put this all into practice with a
challenge so I'll see you in the next video