let's talk about the next problem that
we're going to do or that can
arise when working with threads
that's called starvation now when
starvation occurs it's not that threads
will never progress because they'll
never get a lock but that they rarely
have the opportunity to run and progress
so starvation often occurs due to thread
priority when we assign a high priority
priority as to a thread we are suggesting to
the operating system that it should try
and run the thread before other waiting
threads
remember that when we use
synchronized blocks it's not
first come first served when there's
more than one thread waiting for a lock
and that lock becomes available
the operating system won't necessarily
choose the thread that has been waiting the
longest to run a thread can block on the
lock first but that doesn't mean it will
be the first thread to run when the lock
becomes available
so it's possible that the thread won't
be able to run for a long time because
other threads keep blocking on the lock
and when the lock becomes available
the operating system chooses one of
those other threads to run especially
when one of the other threads has a
higher priority than the first thread
that blocked
let's look at an example just to make
sense of this we're going to create five
threads and assign them at different
priorities
the threads are going to print out the
numbers one to a hundred to the console
let's start by creating a new console
project file new project and
unsurprisingly given that we're talking
about starvation will refer to it as
starvation or call the project
starvation finish and replace
this window because we don't need to the say
hello project anymore and i'm just
going to pull this over to the left a little
bit
ok just to make a bit more space here
for typing so what we do first is will
add our thread color class to the
project
of course we've used that thread color thread color class before
so you can grab the code in the
resources section for this video I'm
just going to create the actual class
and then paste in the values so it's
new
java class i'm going to call this one
thread color as we've done before and
I'm just going to paste in the values
which are in the resources section
all right so going back to our main class we
want to start off by adding a static
variable
we're going to use to synchronize code
so we're going to just put that in the
main as a field
....
again we are going to use that to
synchronize our code now we need to add
a worker class as an inner class of the
main class this will contain the code
that each thread will ultimately run
let's put that down below the main
method within our class as an inner class so
we are going to do
....
.....
the constructor is going to just accept
the color as a parameter only
so just that one click OK and then
we want our run method obviously so.....
....
....and lets write the code for that
and again I mentioned that it's going to
count from 1 to 100.....
....
.....and we want to also write our run count and we
also want to increment that after
displaying that on the screen or outputting it
to the console I should say and put a comment in here to execute
a critical section of code which would
where that would ultimately be so when we
construct an instance of the class we are going
to pass the thread color that we want to
use when the thread runs this code it should
loop a hundred times and each time it
loops
it's going to print out the value of the
loop counter when we call systems.out.format
its current value is stored
when the string is formatted and then
the values incremented as you saw
on line 22 now as you see in a second
we're going to create a worker object
for each thread because each thread
will use its own instance of the worker
class
the threads won't interfere with each
other as they count to a hundred the
code in the run method isn't a critical
section but will pretend that their is some
code after the format call that requires
synchronization and that's where you saw
me put that comment on line 23
for example we could be calling a method
in a class that perhaps isn't thread safe
so now that we've done that let's add
the code to the main method to kick
these threads off
we're going to come back up here and
we're going to put.....
....
and we'll call this one priority 10 and
it's lets take a copy of this and create
another four threads need to change the
names of them....
....
we'll just change the first one to red....
we'll just change colors if we need to second one will go with blue....
the third one let's go with green and we will do cyan for the fourth one and lets use
purple for fifth ones so
priority 10 it will go
...and then what we need to do is do a t1.setpriority for each one of
these over so for t1 we set priority 10 as the
text that's going to be displayed so we
need to make sure we do that as well and
then we'll do the same for the other
four making sure that we set the
priority to the same level as I've
mentioned in the string variable that
we're passing as a parameter so....
....
obviously the last thing to do is to t1.start and we do that for the remaining
four as well
....
ok so we gave each thread a name when we construct a thread instance
on line 7 to 11
we then a set a priority for each one
using the set priority method which is
so we do on line 13 to 17 and keep in
mind that the priority is only a
suggestion to the operating system
it's not actually binding in any way we
can never force the operating system to
run threads in a specific order
so you may look at this code now be
wondering how all the threads could
block on the same lock object since
we're passing a different worker object
to each thread
indeed if you recall in the previous
video we had an issue for that same
reason we're actually passing objects a
different object and we're getting a
deadlock for that reason
so it's true that we are passing a
different worker object to each thread
but the lock object were using is
static you can see that on line 4
so in other words is only one instance
of the object all the threads will be
competing therefore for that one
instances lock
also note that the lock on the object
will be frequently released giving any
blocked threads plenty of
opportunity to run
so let's actually run this code and see
what happens
and again it will depend on timing but
we'll probably see is that the thread
with priority 10 which is the one that we assign red will print out the
numbers one to a hundred before any
other thread has a chance to run after
that it's purely up to the operating
system as to what will happen
it may run the thread with priority
8 but we'll see what happens anyway
let's just try this and see what happens
and you can see this first time when we run it priority 10 got from numbers 1 to
28 then purple kicked in
even though it's got a priority 2 as
you can see here and scrolling down a
little bit further
purple got to a hundred green or cyan I
should is got to go
then we got to green as you can see for
priority 6 priority 8 has a chance with
blue and then priority 10 got the
rest but let's just try running it again
so you can see that I'm getting
different results each time I run it even
though we've assigned priority 10 you
can see this particular case here
priority 10 got from one to a hundred
and then purple got priority 2 which
you would think that priority 8 6
and 4 might have a go beforehand but
that's not necessarily the case
just run it one more time and you can
see that priority 10 has only got a run
count of 3 that time so that's purely up
to the operating system it may run the
thread the second one with priority
8 but that's not necessarily the
case
so its a little bit bizarre when you
look at it when you continually run this
you get different results and there
we've got another result there we're
priority 10 as you think would happen
goes from one to a hundred before the
others get a chance so more than likely you will
you get different results on your
computer then what I'm showing you on
the screen here now so you can see
that it
the order that we've kick things off with
our threads isn't necessarily the order
that the operating system is going to
run it
even though we've told the operating
system or given a suggestion for the
priority that we want these threads to
run
now thread may only be suspended once in
the middle of counting or not
in other words each thread gets to run
for quite a long time in computer time
generally speaking
while the other threads are stuck
waiting now the key takeaway for all this
here is that although this
the lock is released frequently often
the highest priority thread will
probably hog all the time until it's
finished counting and the next thread
that runs won't
necessarily be the thread with priority
8 and you obviously saw that and also
the last thread to terminate won't
necessarily be the thread
with priority 2 and again you saw that
as well we've got this on the screen now
we're going go down and have a look right at the
end priority 6 was the one that
finished in this run so it isn't a
first-come first-serve system now again
this is a trivial example so it doesn't
matter that one thread hogs all the time
but in a real world application the
tasks that a thread is performing might
you know perhaps be a long-running task
what if the run method was performing
database queries or file reads if the
threads block there for seconds or even
minutes because other threads are always
chosen to run when the lock becomes
available then the applications
performance will definitely be adversely
affected
also as we've just seen setting a
priority really is just a suggestion to
the operating system
you saw when i ran the code multiple
times that we've got different results
and priority 10 even wasn't necessarily
finished in completely each time it's
always some other thread that will
kick in and we usually find often found
that priority 2 got the go after
priority 10 for some reason so we
started again you can see priority 10
always gets the first but then it seems
to be priority 2 always comes in next
and again that might be different
for your computer now you might be
thinking at this point the reason that
the thread with priority 10 ran first
was because we assigned it on line 19 as
that if we change these around a little
bit t1 will make that t3...
and leave this t1 so we are starting the
thread with the highest priority last
effectively on line 23
if you run that to see what happens
this will depend on timing again and if we
just run this we can see that priority 6
has got in first run but run this again
it will actually depend on timing and even
though i'm getting the same result each
time you might well find that you get a
different result of this depending on
the order that you set this to on your
computer
what you should be able to find is if
you run this a few times that you
will get priority 10 to start sometimes
when you change the order of the
execution here
but of course when i'm recording a video
is not doing that for me now we've got
priority 10 got nearly got to the first
go so I'll just try one more time and see
whether we can get it
we got priority 10 to come up second
their and again you can see the results
are different each time effectively
when we are running it
so you can see that priority has got an
effect on the order
once we specified that but it's really
loosely if the task wasn't so
trivial the effect on setting a priority
might be more pronounced that's the
other thing to keep in mind because
obviously doing just a little bit of
code here just sort of executing for the
numbers one to a hundred and looping
through them
so we've seen what starvation can do
because the synchronized blocks aren't
first come first served setting
priorities can result in starvation
threads can languish even with when a
lock is frequently released
even when we don't set priorities will
this still be true
so let's actually try not setting
priorities and see what happens
so I'm going to just comment that out
for now the priorities that we defined
and lets see when we run that what
happens
so we got priority 6 working first
we've got priority 10 kicks in then
but notice they have all gone to a hundred
this time we'll just run this a few more
times the same result there so getting
a bit more consistency there
we're getting priority 4 cyan always
appearing last
so you can still see the
threads aren't necessarily running in the
right the same order that we started on
that because t3 is our priority 6 and
that actually started first that was ok
but t1 at the end is priority 10 that
clearly didn't run last did it you can
see that the last we've got our priority
4 which is t3
sorry our t4 and that was second to
last but that finish last
so setting priorities can make
starvation more likely to happen
so how can we actually prevent this
starvation so when we're dealing with
deadlocks the order in which locks are
required was important but the
starvation which thread gets to run
when a lock becomes available is
important
so ideally would like things to be first
come first served
because we can't dictate when threads
will run we can't guarantee a first-come
first-serve order but we can
certainly do our best
I'm going to finish the video now in the
next video we're going to actually talk
about finding a way to get around this
instead of using synchronized blocks
we're going to use something called a
fair lock so let's talk about that in
the next video