In the previous video, we finished off
our discussions about inheritance.
So now it's time for
the challenge to solidify your
understanding of what inheritance is.
But before I do that,
I just want to talk about that all classes
in Java inherit from automatically.
I briefly alluded to that
in the previous videos.
But what actually happens now, even if
you're not typing the keyword to extend
a class, which we've shown in the previous
video, the use of the extends keyword.
The class is automatically inheriting from
a Java supplied class
called the Object class.
And you can see that by opening
up your Generate command,
if you go to Override Methods.
You can see when I've done that, select
methods to override or to implement.
And you can see here,
these are all methods.
The M stands for method.
And these are all methods that are
inherited from java.lang.object which is
a class that, classes that you
create are automatically extend.
So that's equivalent,
essentially, to typing extends.
Java.lang.object, as you can see there.
And we can go and have a look at that, and
you can see, class object is
the root of the class hierarchy.
Every class has object as a superclass.
All objects, including arrays,
implement the methods of this class.
That's really important to know.
This happens automatically, this is the
actual source code for the object class,
which is inherited automatically
from when you create other classes.
So you can see that we'll go
through some of these methods and
get a hash code and equal.
So it's a comparison determining
one type of object against another.
There's also two string which we'll
be using to later, which is a string,
it's just a way to return a string
representation of a specific object.
So I won't go into anymore now, but
the main point I wanted to really pass
on in the moment is even though your
classes when you're creating new ones you
arent actually topping an extends object.
They are automatically extended by
Java and its an interesting thing to
realize and that's just the way
that Java do implement.
Okay so I'll just undo those changes.
Okay, so let's talk a bit now about
the challenge for inheritance.
[SOUND]
Okay,
so here is your
challenge.
You're wanna start with a base class,
which is a vehicle, and
you wanna create a car class that
inherits from that base vehicle class.
And finally, you wanna create
a third class, which is for
a specific type of car that actually
inherits from the car class.
No you be willing to, in these classes
you should be able to handle stirring,
changing gears and moving,
speed in other words.
And you needed to solve where to put
the appropriate stated behaviors
of course that is the fields and methods
that are appropriate for each class.
And you wanna create some unique
behavior that is specific
to that final class that inherits
from the car class as well.
So have a go at doing that challenge,
this will really help your
understanding of what Inheritance is.
And pause the video now,
go away and do that and
once you've had enough or
once you've got a solution and you wanna
compare the solution to what I've come up
with, come back and we'll go through that.
Okay, head it together,
and did you figure it out?
And bearing in mind,
there isn't only one answer to this.
There's quite a few different
ways to implement this.
But the answer I'm gonna come up with
is to start with the vehicle class.
So I'm going to create a new class and
call it vehicle.
And with that vehicle class,
I'm going to have two fields.
I'm gonna have private and
string name, the name of the vehicle.
Because, of course,
all vehicles I have got a name.
I'm also going to go with the size.
You could have some other
generic characteristics here.
So as long as it's specific towards
a generic vehicle and that would be fine,
there would be no problems there.
You would also want to have a constructor.
Constructor for that, both those fields,
so we can initialize our objects.
The other thing that we're going to
have here is also two other fields,
which deal with the current velocity,
the current speed,
in other words the current direction.
And we want velocity so
that we can determine the speed, figure
out how fast the vehicle is going, and
also the direction where it's
pointed to at the moment.
So I'm gonna do private
int current velocity and
private int, current direction.
Now, unlock the first two
fields we're going to find.
What we're gonna do here is when we're
creating a new instance of the vehicle
class, in other words,
creating a new object,
we're just going to initialize velocity
and current direction to zero.
So let's start current
velocity is equal to zero.
This dot current direction,
current direction equals zero.
So next, we talked about, coming back to
our description, how to handle steering,
changing gears and moving.
Well of course, in our vehicle class
we haven't got a concept of gears.
And the reason for
that is not all vehicles have gears.
So it wouldn't be appropriate
to put these in here.
But the other thing was moving, and
moving is of course something
that all vehicles do.
If they move they can be pointed
in a certain direction so
we need to handle that in this class.
So I'm going to first create
a public method called steer.
It's gonna take a parameter for
the direction, and what I'm going to do is
actually add to whatever's been sent to
that method, to the current direction.
So in other words,
it's a mechanism for steering.
So I'm gonna call that public void steer,
int direction.
And I'm gonna put current,
This.currentDirection += direction.
Then I'm going to do some system
output to put Vehicle.steer and
I'm gonna put Steering at,
put the current direction and
we'll call that degrees, but
it might just be an angle or whatever
it is, but we'll just call it degrees.
That's our steering method,
which again, applies to all vehicles.
We're also going to create another method
and we're going to call that Move.
I'm going to accept two parameters,
the velocity and the direction.
So go to public void move int
velocity and int direction.
I'm gonna put current
velocity equals velocity,
current direction equals direction.
And print output message Vehicle.move
moving at plus currentVelocity,
in direction, currentDirection and
I'll lock the steer method.
What we're doing here is we're
actually setting the velocity and
direction to the specific number.
With the steer, the way we've set
that up is we're allowing it to
change relative to the current position,
so we're storing the current position,
or the current direction,
enabling you to move relative to that.
Whereas the move method we're actually
allowing you to just effectively change
the velocity and the direction.
No right or wrong here,
just my implementation for that.
And we also wanna do a getter and
setter for a few of these fields.
So I'm going to just probably speed
wise just going to select that and
choose a getter for all fields.
So that's our vehicle class,
next we wanna create a car class.
We want to obviously extend or
inherit from that vehicle class.
So we're gonna create
a new class call it car.
And of course we're going to extend or
inherit from the vehicle.
And obviously,
it'll want us to create a constructive.
But before we do that, we want to
create our unique fields for our car.
Firstly, we're going to
define the number of wheels,
because not all vehicles have wheels.
Example, some boats are vehicles and
they don't have wheels.
And you're going to define doors.
They're unique to a car,
the number of doors.
In to gears, as in the number of
gears that a present in a car,
because all cars do have gears,
it's just a different number, of course.
We're also going to use a variable,
is manual,
and that's a true or false as to whether
it's got a manual or automatic gearbox.
And we're going to store another
variable called current gear.
If you recall we talked about
that in the vehicle class.
Because not all vehicles have keys,
we have
decided to create a field called current
gear and put that in the car class.
So that's the current key, current gear
that the car is in at any point in time.
So let's create the constructor,
and with constructor is going
to initialize all of these.
But also put some extra code in for us,
which was the two parameters string for
the name and the string for
the size which are going to
initialize our vehicle class as well.
And that's IntelliJ doing that work for
us which is very nice.
But what I'm going to do though is
change the last parameter for the gear.
The current gear, we don't actually
want that to construct a parameter.
And the reason is we're going to assume
that when we create a new object
we can set that to one,
to be in first gear.
And now we need a few other methods here.
What we need is the ability
to change the gear.
We need the ability to change
velocity of the vehicle.
We're gonna add a method to stop, and
we also need to be able to steer as well.
So let's start by creating a setter.
We're gonna create a setter for
the current gear.
So select current gear and
I'm gonna put car.set.gear.
Changed to this dot
current gear plus gear.
So that's just a standard setter to
change to the current gear whenever
we need to do that.
And what we could do,
because it's a setter,
now normally the convention in
the industry use the word set, but in
this case it might actually be better to
rename that and to call that change gear.
You dont have to use set current gear.
In this case we're just gonna call it
change gear which probably reads a little
bit better and makes more sense as to what
were trying to do with it cause this is
going to be a function were
going to be able to call.
So next we want the ability to change
the velocity of the vehicle so
we could just leave it we could
just have no function here.
And just call the basic
function that we've set for
move here, in which case that would
work fine without any problem.
And when you're extending and implementing
classes you have got a choice as to
whether you want to use that
low-level function or override it.
In this case what I'm going to do,
I'm going to create another
method called a change velocity.
Which takes two parameters
which is the velocity or
we are going to call it speed here and
the direction.
And that is going to call the move method.
Move, speed, direction.
Like so, so that's changeVelocity.
And the reason I'm doing that is at some
future point we might wanna have some
other mechanisms in
here with the velocity.
For example, to test the maximum
speed of the vehicle or
some other conditions that are unique
to a car, as opposed to a vehicle.
At this stage we're just gonna be
calling the vehicle move method.
The next method I'm gonna
have is the stop method.
This is the ability to stop so
you could argue that all vehicles
need to have a mechanism to stop, and
to that end we should probably
create a public method for stop.
So public void stop, and I'm creating
that in the vehicle class stop.
And all it's going to do is put
the current velocity set that to zero.
That's all that stop does,
it basically stops it.
It doesn't try and reposition or
anything of that nature,
it just purely stops the vehicle.
But in terms of stopping for a car,
what we wanna do is we want to implement
the method but we wanna override it so
I'm going to override the stop method for
the vehicle, a slight stop.
So what I'm gonna do I'm not going
to call the super method yet.
So actually what I'll do for
now is I'll delete this method because we
don't really need to override it for now.
For this basic car class it's enough for
us to know that we've got to stop,
which will set the velocity to zero.
When we get to using the next class, which
will be the class that inherits from car
class, that's when we'll add some
more functionality to the stop.
And with steering, the same applies, we
don't need to change anything in the car
class because we're going to just
pass that on to the vehicle class.
Okay, so you can see now we've
implemented the car class, so
let's now move on to the next
class which is gonna be
a specific type of car that
extends from the car class.
So I'm going to create a new
class I wanna call it Outlander,
which is a Mitsubishi four wheel drive.
I'm gonna create that and
I'm gonna extends car.
And what I'm going to do, is assume.
So, obviously we're extending from car,
so it's got all the other unique
characteristics from the car and
the vehicle.
But we're gonna add one private field.
So, I'm going to put Road service.
The number of months of road service that
are available for this top of vehicle.
Next I'm gonna create a public
constructor, I'm going to
initialize the road service.
And you'll find it all the medically
initializes all these other fields
for this road.
What we can do with some of these
parameters cuz we can change them.
For example, for the Outlander, we don't
need to do, have that as a parameter.
Cuz we have an Outlander class,
we know that it's the Outlander.
So, we're going to use
that in our constructor.
We're going to pass Outlander.
And for the size,
we're gonna go with four wheel drive.
So we also don't need that as a parameter.
So I'm going to actually change
those from the Outlander parameters.
And we're left only with the wheels,
the doors, the gears, whether it's manual,
and the road service.
And actually, as it turns out,
all of those parameters there.
The wheels, doors,
the gears, and the manual.
Because we're defining now
the actual type of car we
shouldn't really have those as parameters.
What we wanna do is just hard code those,
for
want of a better term,
in the constructor setting.
And of course you could still make
it optional with a moddable types of
Outlanders which there are real terms.
But to keep things simple we're gonna
assume there's only one type of Outlander,
and we know ahead of time the number of
wheels and doors and gears and so forth.
So what I'm going to do there
is put number of wheels to be 5,
including the spare.
5 doors including the rear door.
Six speed and we're gonna put is Manual,
we're gonna set that to false
because it's actually an automatic.
So consequently,
now that I've done that, I can actually
delete those from the constructor.
As you can see there.
So we're left now to
create a new Outlander,
which of course is extending
from the car class.
We really only need to pass one
parameter which is the road service,
the number of months this vehicle
has got for road service.
And new cars they,
with Mitsubishi cars they give you so
many months of free roadside
service if you ever break down.
So what we're defining is how
many months a vehicle has got.
All right, I'm going to pause the video
here, we'll come back in the next one and
continue on with the solution
to the inheritance challenge.