In the previous video we
started work on interfaces and
we came up with a base
example of a desk phone.
And we obviously implemented
the interface, as you can see in the code.
Pretty basic, so what we're going
to do is continue on with this now.
I'm actually gonna come up with another
example, and we're gonna create a mobile
phone class that also implements
the ITelephone interface.
So I'm going to create, new,
java class, and do mobile phone.
And what I'm going to do is actually
grab some of the desktop phone code.
I'm gonna grab it from that point
onwards and copy that there and
then just paste that in just
to save us a bit of time.
You know paste it in like that.
So I've essentially at this stage
got the exact same functionality.
We need to just make a few little
changes so that it obviously works.
So with the mobile phone what we're going
to do is we're going to add another field,
we're gonna add a boolean
to see whether it's on,
cuz obviously you can
turn a mobile phone on.
Generally, you do turn it on or
off, as opposed to a desktop phone
would normally be on all the time.
So boolean is on.
Set that to false, initially.
So it's not going to be on.
But it In the power on section,
we're gonna set that to isOn = true, and
we're gonna change the actual message.
The other one actually said no
action taken, but this one,
we're gonna set it up, so
it actually says mobile phone powered up.
Of course, I gotta change the public
constructor, so we need to do that,
obviously, cuz that's
still got the old code.
So we're gonna set that up and
just make that the mobile phone,
mame instead, like so.
We'll actually also look at the dial.
And with the dial, we'll set it up so
that it has to actually be on,
the phone, before we can actually dial.
And if it's not on we're
gonna show a message.
So we're gonna put if is on, now ringing.
And we'll change this instead,
of on desk phone to put on mobile phone.
Then we'll change that and put an else.
Phone is switched off.
Like so, so that's for the dial.
And we also will change the answer method,
as well.
And also we'll change the call phone.
So with answer,
the only thing we need to do there,
is we'll actually change the message so
it says mobile phone.
Mobile phone like so, and
the call phone method.
We'll change that.
We'll check to see whether
it's our number, but
then we'll also check to see whether
it's is on so we'll put and is on.
Like so, so it has to both be on and
be our phone number in
order to actually call.
Now, we can do something else.
We can maybe put melody playing, so it's
obviously a different type of ring tone
because it's a mobile phone and
I think that should actually be it.
So at this point, then,
we can go back to our main class and
our main method, and
we can do something similar.
So we can actually do
something we did before.
We can set this up now to put Tim's phone,
the same variable,
equals new mobile phone 24565, like so.
We can initially try it with
timsPhone.call, and for the number,
24565 to make sure it's valid,
and timsPhone.answer.
Now, I purposely have left out a line
here, which would be timsPhone.powerOn.
Leaving that out [INAUDIBLE],
leaving that out for the moment cuz
we should be able to see what happens
if we haven't actually got style.
I'm gonna run this.
And ring, ring no action taken this fine
does not have those initial messages.
And what happened with was there
with the call message, call phone.
[INAUDIBLE] was false but
we didn't actually print a message, so
if we go back to mobile phone.
In the call phone,
we actually had this successfully
testing to see whether the phone was on.
But we didn't actually have a message,
so we'll change it there and
we'll put message also to
indicate that mobile phone.
Not on or number different.
So if now you go back and run that again,
we can actually see that message from
the mobile class, mobile phone class.
Mobile phone not on or number different.
Now the other point I want to make here
is if we go back to the main class again.
Notice how I was able to set
a new instance of mobile phone
as a completely different class,
but it still worked.
Now, normally, if we had come up here and
we actually had assigned that
to be the type of desk phone, then this
reassignment wouldn't have worked.
So if we hadn't done that, desk phone
we'll actually get an error here and
that's because of incompatible types.
As you can see one is
obviously desk phone class,
the other one is a mobile phone class.
But because we didn't do that,
we actually changed it to so
the top was the ITelephone interface
we're able to change it, and
to actually create a new instance of
what is essentially a different object,
different class, and it still
actually works, which is pretty cool.
And that's because they both
implement the same interface.
And again we didn't actually put,
we didn't call the power method and
so correctly come up with synthepone
mobile phone number was not on, while
the number was different, so if I add that
code back like so, if we run it again
melody ring answering the mobile phone so
that's all working nicely as you can see.
And again just to be clear, it's a good
idea to actually put the fact that's in
interface by putting the capital I
before the name of the interface,
and that really does make it be abundantly
clear that this is actually an interface.
But the other thing is to point out,
if you actually have a look over
here in the left hand side, and I'll just
zoom it up a little bit so you can see it,
you notice how the other classes
have got a C with a blue circle, but
the interface is in green with an I.
So that does actually tell you that
it's actually an interface at a glance.
You can see that, so do look out for
those types of things with IntelliJ.
Whenever you see some data, some sort of
presentation, like a variable type or
some pop-up window or
something like that, IntelliJ will often
tell you at a glance what it's for.
In this case you can see that
there's an I there for interface.
Okay, so moving on now from this example,
what we're gonna do is we're gonna
open the code from the playlist which was
in our link challenge from lecture 64.
Now that code is available in this video,
so you can go to the resources section of
this video and
you can download that source code.
That's probably the best place to grab it,
and
you do that and unzip and actually run it.
And what we're gonna do is we're
gonna actually change a few things.
We're going to take a list, instead of
a linked list and just make a few other
changes, and show you how easy it is to
actually use the power of interfaces.
So I'm gonna actually close this down now.
Close Project.
And, you can see here,
I've actually created another one.
I've got Interfaces.LinkedList.
So, this is the Linked List Challenge
that we did recently
in the previous section of this course and
what I'm doing now.
I just copied, basically,
the code out of that into a new
folder called Interfaces.LinkedList.
Now I'm just gonna open that up, so
that the changes that we make won't affect
that other code in case you're still
working on it or you want to have that
you know version of the code there.
So, I now go into my programs.
Go into interfaces.linklist.
I'm just going to choose.
I'll go into the link list
challenge sub folder and
choose now,
that should open that up for us.
And this code again should
be pretty familiar to you,
if you've actually been through
the link list challenge.
And again if you haven't that's fine,
there's no problems there.
Now, the reason I've opened this code up
is just to show you how Java lava is make
extensive use of interfaces, and
the one that we used recently
is the list interface.
So what we're gonna do is go and open the
enter playlist method in the album class,
and I want to actually show you how we
can make something make a change and for
it not to actually break anything.
We're gonna go to our album and what
we're looking for is the add to playlist.
The one that's got the track number and
also the list now at the moment we've
got link list there as we talked about.
Because we're using interfaces,
we can change that to list and
it still works quite nicely.
It is just asking for imports.
I will import that.
But you notice how the code
is still compatible.
And if you change that a little bit we get
it back down to the main method where it
is actually calling this code.
And make a change, we can run this code
virtually without changing anything else.
And that's because the java lava are
making extensive usage of interfaces and
if they weren't doing that we would
find a lot of this [INAUDIBLE].
So if we go back to our main method now.
The main method actually what we want to
change is the print list first because
that's got a hard coded
link list in there.
So we're just gonna make
that just a generic list.
And also the play method.
That's also using a link list we change
that so it's just a list as well.
And also, we need to change the
declaration of the playlist to be a list
instead of a linked list.
Make that just a list, like so.
And lastly, if we go to the playlist,
where we actually set up the playlist,
that's this one here,
we're using a linked list there, but
we could actually literally
just change that as well,
we could change that to a list, list.
So we changed the entire type, actually
that one need to be array list, so
we're changing it from an array
list because it was a link list.
If we do that, there is one thing that
didn't change which was in album,
we go back there and have a look at that.
We need to change its preferences
where which was a link list,
change that to list as well cuz we had an
either loaded method for active playlist.
Go back there again and
the error should have disappeared.
And you can see we've done all of that and
it's still going to work.
And that's because the Java libraries
use interfaces extensively, so
we can do something like play next song,
I'm playing Holy Man.
To replay the count song, to go to
next song, next song, previous song.
The bottom line here,
the thing I wanted to point out is,
the java lava do make extensive
usage of interfaces and
because they've done that we're able to
change out the entire implementation.
From what was a linked list to an array
list very simply, and we've actually just
done that with a minimal amount of
changes, which is pretty awesome.
So, this is one of the reasons why
you'd want to be using an interface.
It just makes it a heck of a lot easier
to make your code work in this case.
The Java libraries have set it up so,
you can use array lists,
linked lists and so forth.
And, make those really interchangeable.
You can even use another type and
the reason that this works,
is that the contract that's
defined by the list interface.
So, just to be clear, if we go into
list interface and have a look.
And notice how list is a public
interface because of that contract
with these methods that are actually
in the list [INAUDIBLE] or
being specified in the interface.
So, as long as you create a class
that implements these methods and
actually creates real methods,
creates the code in other words
that create that functionality,
things are gonna actually work fine and
we're able to actually
see in this example,
we were quite easily able to change
this to make this a generic list.
But then, in the main method
where we actually set it up,
we created an array list.
Or, I think, that was already set for an
array list, but we made this generic here.
But, the playlist,
which was originally a linked list,
we changed that to an array list.
And because the array list which
implements the base list interface.
It's still using and
still supporting all the methods,
it has to have implemented those methods.
Everything still works nicely, so
that's really the power of an interface.
And if Java are using that
a lot internally in their code,
you know that it's a good way to
actually code in those scenarios.
Now just to give you another example,
you could use another type of list here.
We could change this,
instead, to a vector.
Vector is another type of list and
we do that and the code still works and
it's not broken.
So it's very normal when you're
creating lists in your code
to define the basic type of type list.
Then when you actually create, or
you actually initialize the variable
that's when you actually
specify the actual type.
In this case, a vector or
a linked list or an array list.
So, it's probably a good
habit to get into,
just to use just a generic list
as the type as I mentioned there.
And then, you just specify the actual
type that you want in your program and
you initialize it.
In terms of actually deciding
whether to implement an interface or
inherit from a base class.
Sometimes, it can be a little bit
difficult to decide which one to do.
In other words, Should you create
a class and extend from that?
In other words, inherit from that class or
should you use an interface?
So that one example would have been,
that we could have had in
our example the telephone.
You could have had that class in
extended it to create a desk phone or
mobile phone class or both of them.
But in this particular case, it probably
wouldn't have been a good approach.
So the way to decide that generally,
is to really consider the relationship
of the final class to the object
that it's extending or implementing.
So in other words, with our telephone
example both devices have a telephone so
the desk phone doesn't have anything else.
But the mobile phone is not just a phone,
despite it's name because of course,
a modern mobile phone
has more computing power than a desktop
computer of only 15 years ago.
I mean,
really can do far more than make or
receive phone calls, so
it's more accurate to say
that a mobile phone is actually
a computer that has a phone interface.
So you can say that a desk
phone can telephone and
a mobile phone can telephone, which
indicates that they should both implement
a phone interface rather than extending
a phone class if that makes sense.
The other thing that's
important to understand,
is that a class can only inherit from
one's super class, unlike other languages,
like c++ for arguments sake,
where you can do that.
But you can actually implement
from many interfaces.
This is something that's
actually quite powerful.
So, you can actually implement
from many interfaces.
As I mentioned, some languages allow
moddable inheritance by allowing,
I should say, a class to inherit
from several base classes.
But, in Java, multiple inheritance
is only available by
implementing several interfaces.
If you want more details than this,
consider the animal class that we created
on the lectures in
the inheritance section.
Though not all animals can walk, so
we cannot put a walk method
in the animal base class.
But we could define, say,
a walk interface, though.
So if that was the case,
we could then consider birds, they can
walk and most of them can also fly.
So we can create a fly interface, as well.
A dog would extend animal and
implement walk.
A bird would extend animal and implement
both walk and fly if that makes sense.
So in this case, a dog is an animal and
a bird is an animal.
So they both inherit
from the animal class.
But a dog can walk so it implements walk.
And a bird can both walk and fly so
that would implement from both interfaces.
So I hope that's clarified,
there's an important distinction there.
And again the way to decide
is to really look at or
really consider the relationship
of the final class
to the object that you're extending or
implementing.
Okay, so I'm gonna end the video here,
in the next video it's time for
a challenge so
we'll do a challenge on interfaces.
So, I'll see you on that next video.