alright so moving on now let's actually
update the code to do our sorting to use
a lambda expression i'm going to just
come down here and what I'm going to do
is I'm actually just going to comment
that out for simplicity and also just
so we got the other code to
compare it against so to do that we're
going to do.....
.....
this is where it's going to get a bit
different so in brackets now we're going
to put.....
.....
.....that's actually it
so you can see this is a lot more
concise now the lambda is being passed
as the second parameter instead of an
anonymous comparator and we split the
lambda over 2 lines which we can do
and if we run it we should see we
get the same results as we saw in
the previous video you can see we still
got the same output and just to clear
things up a little bit I'm comment that out
at the top and just run it again
and you can see we've got our results
and clearly its sorting and working very
well
alright so let's look at this lambda
expression that we've just added so the
three parts that the lambda consists of
are firstly the argument list so in
this case the argument list is these
here the two parameters employee
employee one employee employee 2 the
second part of lambda is our arrow token again
which is this one here and the third
part of course is the body which is the
code on the next line which is
basically that code that I'm
highlighting
so how does this actually work well when
the sort method needs to compare two
objects in the list instead of calling
the compare method of our comparator and
passing it in the two objects it will
instead evaluate the lambda expression
using the two objects it wants to
compare as the parameters to the lambda
now one nice thing about lambdas is so
that it's easy to see what code will be
run and this is especially true when
dealing with shorter methods when one or
two lines of code are buried within an
anonymous class as we've seen previously
that can actually be hard to see or
spot very quickly but the good news is
we can actually even simplify this
lambda expression even further with the
compiler can infer the parameter types and
we don't actually need to include the
types in a lambda in our case the
compiler can infer from the first
parameter employees that the objects to
be compared were both be of type employee
and because of that we can actually
leave the types out and just rewrite it
like this and come back here actually
delete the type and just wrote it to
confirm that its still working and that's
still working as well now if there's
only one parameter we don't actually
need the parentheses in the argument
list so let's take a look at a common
use of lambdas now for this we're going
to need a java FX application let's go
ahead and create a new project so i'm
going to go to file new project as
we've done countless times i'm going to
call this one select java fx first
will call this one button fx
to keep it simple.....and what
we will do is will keep the lambda
expressions project open and we're going
to come back to it so click on new
window so that both projects are open
just make this a bit larger so we can
see it better
alright so first we want to add a button
to the grid pane so going to open up our
source and and go to sample . fxml so
we're going to go and open to create a
button or add a button....
....
.....
....ok now we could add an action handler
here in the fxml we've done that
before in the javafx section of this
course and I accidentally deleted the
closing grid pane so I will fix that up....
.....
ok so we've seen how we add action
handlers here let's suppose we want to
do the controller instead or in the fxml
file so we are gonna need FX ID which
is why we're added that so we can access
that and actually assign the action
handler in the initialize method back
in controller and let's go back and do that
so what we're going to do first is well add
the version of the code that doesn't use
a lambda and we need firstly a private
button......
.....
.....so let's do it
the first way that doesn't use a lambda
expression to set an action so we'll do
that with click me button.....
....
.....and using an
anonymous class for the event handler like I did there is very common in ui
programming especially actually in javas
old tool kit swing which didn't actually
have anything like fxml
everything actually had to be done using
code so when we run this application let's do
that you should see that we got a button
on the screen and were able to click it and
see the output on the console down the
bottom you can see the run window you can see click
me so clearly that's working so we got our action handler added via code
that's working nicely but now we
actually know about lambda expressions
whenever we see an anonymous class
definition that only overrides one
method we can consider using a lambda so lets
actually change the code to do that now
we're going to do first is delete
the anonymous class parameter i'm going
to just delete all that code and
set on action will actually be.....
....
....and again because i've
created a new classes its defaulting to the
wrong language level i'm just going to
change that
clicking over here and change it back to
8 again the language level project
lambdas click on ok alright so when we
run this now and we got the
same result but this time using a lambda
and the point here is just closing out
the run window when we only have one
parameter we don't have to put that one
parameter inside parentheses and that's
why we just type that there without
parentheses this time we only have to use
parentheses when their are no parameters
or more than one parameter when we ran
the application you saw that it worked
like I did before you've probably seen
enough now to know that we map a method
to a lambda expression and as follows
number one the method parameters become
the argument list number 2 the error
token is always there
number three the body of the method
becomes the body of the lambda
expression but what about interfaces
with a single method that returns a
value
now we've only use one in the comparator
example but the sort method handled the
return value
let's take a closer look with a
different example i'm going to go back
to the lambda expressions project we're
going to add a new interface to the main
files let's go ahead and do that go down the
bottom here going to add interface
....
.....so this
interface contains a method that upper
case two strings and then concatenates
them all joins them or pins the second one
to the first one so now that we've
added the interface lets add a
static method to the main class that
uses an up concat instance to create
new string and come back up here just
below the last class there the end of
the class and put....
....
....so the method accepts an
object that implements upper concat and
the two strings that we want uppercase
and concatenated it calls the upper
concat method in the upper concat
interface to do the work now inside the
main method what we need to do is create
a new method we're going to pass an
anonymous classes as the first parameter
and the first two employees in the list
as the second or three parameters so lets
go and do that just up here just after
the for loop it is going to be....
....
.....
.....so when we run this we can see
we get jack hill John doe so hopefully this
point you might be thinking we're using
an anonymous class that overrides the
only method in interface let's use a
lambda expression instead now we still
have to define the interface we can't
get away from doing that when using
lambdas but we can definitely simplify
the rest of the code by passing a lambda
instead of an anonymous class and
remembering the three parts to a lambda
parameters arrow taken and body so to
start with lets define the lambda on a
separate line and assign it to a variable
of type upper concat so we're going to just
comment out the code we just added so we
still got it there to refer to so let's go ahead
and define so it's going to be....
.....
.....notice here that we haven't included the return
keyword in fact if we try to add it
doing something like
....we get a compile error when the lambda body consists of a
single statement that evaluates to a
value return keyword is assumed and the
return value is in third to be the type
of the evaluated value which in this
case is string so going to undo those
changes but we can go one step further
the compiler can infer the types of the
parameters so don't need to
include those either so you can come
back here and delete those to make more
concise and likewise for the second
string as well so you can see that now is
fairly concise and now that we have a
lambda we can use it as the first
parameter in our call to do string stuff
so we just type in that code again....
....
.....
...so if we run that that also works well as you
can see we got our Jack Hill and John
Doe output again
alright I'm going to finish the video
here now in the next video will continue
on with our journey with lambda
expressions see you in the next video