so just a recap of where we are from the
last video so we are setup now so we
can click on an item and we can see the
information appearing in the right hand
side window so that's ok the information
is coming up and when we click the selected
item but if we want to do something like bold the due label will have to display the
deadline outside the text area because
the text area only understands plain
text in addition if the details for the
to-do item are lengthy we have to scroll
down to see the deadline so instead of adding a text area to the center
position of the border pane instead lets add a v box and then we'll add a text area
and h box to the v box and you
see why we are adding a hbox in a minute so lets go ahead make
those changes so we go to our FXML
so down here we are gonna add a v box....
...so lets just run that to see
what it looks like
you could see we have a separate section
here over to the right hand side with the
h box and v box so now we've done
that we can see a text area and our h box
so we are going to add 2 labels to the
h box one for the due text and one
for the deadline we get from our to do item so let's go ahead and do that
so go into our h box and add a label so.....
....
...so that is the first label and the second label we will go and do....
....so the 2
labels for h box ones for the due text
and one for the deadline that we get
from the to do item and we've set this font of the due label to Times New Roman
and the font weight too bold and and also
set the size to 20 and we do
a similar thing for the label that is
ultimately going to display our deadline
now we don't set the text from the deadline
label within the fxml because we have to get it
of course the selected to do item and we'll set
that up within the event handler itself
but do do that for the second label we need
enter an ID so...
.....and course we need to do
that so we can reference it from Java code
so take a copy of this ID and we go
back to our controller
and initialize or create a variable
first a field so....
....
...so within our event
handler itself we no longer need the
string builder so what we're going to do is
delete that out we're going back to setting
the text area to the details set the text or our deadline label to
the deadline so lets go ahead and do that
so comment this other code out and I'll just bring
this up....so the to do we need obviously still but
what we are going to do is....
....
....and in terms of the label for the deadline
we're going update here as well so....
....
...so lets do that and run it and when we click on an item you can see the date is
appearing down the bottom right hand
corner so in other words so we can see
the details and deadlines are displaying
correctly in different areas of the
right hand side and I just want to make a point that I wasn't saying we are going to create a pretty
UI but what we're not gonna leave
it in the state right now the deadline
area is taking up too much room
because obviously it's only one line of
information the due text label and
the date itself so we want to reduce the
amount of space it's taking up but also
it be nice if the entire right hand side
had a white background as opposed to the
top being and white and the other one
being in a grayish background
so let's tackle the deadline label's
first so what we want to do is to display
them with their preferred heights so to
accomplish this we need to work using
vbox.vgrow property in
the text area we need to change that so close
this down and come back to our FXML we need to change
his text area on line 17 to use the
vbox.vgrow to always
so....so we want them basically display with their
preferred heights so what that does it tells the v box to always keep us
as much room as possible to the text area
the v box will size all its other
children to their preferred heights and give
the remaining space to the text area
which is what we wanted in this case
so if we run that we should see that
we've got a lot more space allocated to
the description now and you can see
it's nearly got the entire right hand side
allocated it only just a minimal on the
bottom which is allocated for due label and the data itself so that's good
so lets close that down so next we are going to deal with the labels
background color and will use some CSS
in the FMLX file and set the background to white
this is for the label so let's go ahead and do that so
firstly come here to the first label which got the due text in it
and we will add a style their so add...
....
..so run that you can see the deadline label
still looks great and that is because we haven't
set any texts and so nothing has been
drawn for the label in that area so what
we're seeing is that the v box
background color
click on that and you could see that
it's still showing so we need to find a
way to convert this part here to white
as well so what we really need to do is
changed the v box
background color to white as well so what is showing here behind will also be white
so we come up to v box and set the style for that so....
...so now we've done that we should see that in all
white and its now white down the bottom
as well and obviously when we select
something we still got white in the backgrounds
so the right hand side of our
user interface is completely white other than the text over the top which is what
we're trying to achieve so just running
this one more time now what we could
do is fiddle around and remove the thin border between
the text area and the labels this line
down here but its better to keep because when the details texts is long we want the
border there to separate the two areas
so it's a good idea to leave that there
so its clear distinction between the two
areas it would be nice if the first to do in
the list was selected when the
application first runs so that due
label wasn't there without any
corresponding selected item so lets add
the code to do that now to select the first
item in the to do list whenever the
applications run and we do that in our control initialization method
so right under the line 48
where we chose the selection mode to be
single we can put....
....
so if you run that interesting enough
when we run you we can see that the first
item is selected the top left hand
corner
however the details don't appear on the
right side so the question is why isn't
this working well if we go back to the
fxml file and closes this down the list view here
on line 11
you can see that we're listening for mouse
clicks but in this case we didn't select
the first item by clicking on it we selected
it pragmatically using code now since we
want to select the first time every time
we run we could just set the details
text area directly in the controllers
initialize method by calling
something along the lines of item
details text.settext and in
passing in the details for the first to do item but thinking about it they'll
be other times we want to change the
selection pragmatically for example when
the user adds a new to do item to the
list we want to select it so the first details
are displayed so therefore a better
solution would be to listen for
selection changes regardless of how they take
place you know pragmatically or through
user input so instead of assigning an event handler to the on mouse click
property what we'll do is we'll run our
event handler whenever the selected item
property of the selection model changes
so we have to set our event handling code
rather than the fxml will do this in
the controllers initialization method
and will do that before we select the
first time so let's close this down and
will go back to the
controller code and in our initialize method
and right after the five items were added on line 45 so just going to add it here
so do.....
....
...
and it has written that code for us automatically so its overwritten a method called changed
and if you recall back from the lecture on
events and event handling you will recall these
event handlers are also known as event listeners because an application will listen
for an event and when that event is
raised the Associated event handler will
run so our event handler will be an instance of
the change listener class so in our code we are using an
anonymous class for the event handler
and we are overriding the change method as you can
see on line 51 so when running the code
that creates and sets even listeners its very
common these days to use lambda
expressions but because we haven't got
to lambda expressions in the course yet
we are going to write the code down here for clarity sake so do something along thse
lines going to put....
....
....and then the other
thing we can do now that we made that
change is come back over to main window FXML and we can move this
on mouse click event handler because we've
now written a generic event handler
that handles any time the value changes
so its now going to pick up either way
etiher clicking on a mouse or pragmatically
so lets run that
so you notice automatically the first item was selected and we automatically got the detail showing
on the right hand side and also
when we click equivalent to what was the
mouse event handler before that's also
working so both scenarios are
now being handled by the event code that we
wrote
in our controller.java and this was the list of
that we created on line 51
so that's it for this video in the next
video will move on to displaying the to-do items
deadline so see you in the next video