Alright so let's discuss parsing
values from a string in many cases you
have to pass the value from a string
meaning that you have to convert the
string into some other data type such as
a number string into an int now one news
case where we might need to convert a
number string is when reading input from
the user
perhaps after it's been entered into a
console or after being retrieved
from a user interface in later videos in
this course you'll see this in action
when you learn how to read values from
the user using the scanner class but
let's first discuss how we can convert a
string value into some other primitive
data type so we're going to begin by
typing some code and you can see I've
created a new project here and I've
called it parsing values from string so
the code we want to type in there now is
string number a string equals 2018 in
double quotes then on the next line
we're going to print out number in
double quotes s string equals the space
ending double quote plus number a string
alright so this is a string that we've
defined on line six meaning that it's
interpreted as text and not as a number
value so the goal here is to convert
this piece of text into a number and
firstly let's just quickly run this you
can see we've got the output down the
bottom of the screen there number as
string because 2018 so again the goal
here is to convert this piece of text in
our string into a number now one way to
convert a string into a number is by
means of a parsing method now with these
methods we can convert a string into
various primitive types depending on the
specific pars we choose to use now in
this case since we want to convert our
our string into an integer let's type
this out I'm gonna do it on the line
after the output line and I'm going to
type int make a space there line space
between lines so int
number is equal to an integer with a
capital i dot and I'm going to select
parse int then in parentheses I'm going
to put our string we defined on line six
number a string
alright so line nine contains some code
that we haven't yet seen in the code in
the course so first off we're using a
class called integer and you can see if
it's a class because I'm using a capital
either now this is a wrapper class for
the primitive type int now don't worry
too much about wrapper classes at the
moment because we will be discussing
them in more detail later in the course
one thing to note though is that the
wrapper class integer contains some
useful static methods like the one that
we're using parse int now this method
parseint will try to convert the string
that we're passing as an argument it's a
number of string here into an integer
now if it's successful the number is
converted from a string to an integer
but if the conversion fails we'll get an
error now you may also notice that we
typed integer dot followed by the method
name parse int in order to convert type
string into some other data type in
other words parse the string we need to
include the type we're converting to so
that we're able to get the parsing
method associated with that type so in
our case the result is integer then dot
and then the method name in this case
parse int but later on we're going to
see similar methods to this so simply
put this parse method is a static method
that we can use to convert or to parse a
string type into a number all right so
let's actually print that out just to
confirm that it does work on the next
line I'm going to do a print out in a
double quotes I'm going to tighten
number equals double quote plus number
but this time I go to output number and
not a number of string so we want to
print out the variable number which is
an int that we have hopefully got the
value for the string value 2018 in it so
let's run that
and you can see down the bottom of the
screen we've got number equals 2018 so
pausing is useful but we need to convert
a string into a number in order to use
that number to calculate something so
let's test this by adding 1 to both
number of string and also two number so
what we can do you're going to come down
here and we're going to type number a
string then we're going to type plus
equals 1 then on the following line I'm
going to type the number plus equals 1
now when we add the integer 1 to number
a string Java will automatically convert
the number 1 into a string and then
concatenate these two strings so that
number string will now have the value 2
0 1 8 1 and that's really not what we
were hoping for but by using number plus
equals 1 on the next line line 13 we're
actually incrementing number by 1
because it's an int value and not a
string so therefore the value of number
should be 2019 so to confirm this let's
print out both to see that it is
actually correct so I'm going to start
by printing out a number a string and
double quotes off what number a string
again equals in plus number of string
and on the next line let's print out the
value of number so number equals plus
number all right so let's run this
alright see you now see the difference
that we've discussed when we use the
plus operator with a string type and a
number the number is concatenated to the
string it's appended in other words to
the end of the string so Java is
converting that number to a string in
joining it to that string and you can
see the result here 2 0 1 8 1
however after converting a string type
to an N type we can then use the number
as in perform operations with it so in
our case number is originally defined up
here as an int on line 9 and by
incrementing it by 1 which we did on
line 13 and outputting it we have now
got the value tooth
19 alright so moving on let's pretend
now that a user entered in some data in
this case they entered 2018 which is a
valid number but what would happen if
the user typed something by accident so
they added a letter to the number
sequence so let's see the result of that
by changing our number of string up here
on line 6 to 2018 we're going to add an
A on the end of it so what will happen
when we actually run this well let's
actually run it to see what happens then
you can see that we've actually got an
error down the bottom left-hand corner
of the screen so it didn't work as
expected so I've got this error which is
also known as an exception and you can
see on the screen there it says Java
ranked number format exception for input
string 201 8a in double quotes so the
problem here is our string since its
value is 2018 a it cannot be converted
to an int because that's not a valid
number and so Java throws this or gives
us this number format exception to
indicate that the format isn't correct
now there are a couple of ways to handle
this problem one way is to handle the
actual exception but we're going to be
covering handling exceptions later in
the course we could also create our own
method as an alternative but that too
will come up later on in the course so
instead let's just revert this change by
removing the letter from the string for
now so coming back to the original value
of 2018 now so a similar process for
conversion can be done with other number
types for example the double type so
let's try adding a decimal value to our
string we're going to change number to
be of type double and we're going to use
the double class and the past double
mithun so it's gonna be very similar to
how the intrusion works but with a
double so to do that I'm gonna come up
here first they in type or change rather
the in type to double so it's no double
number then we're going to change the
word integer here to double so it's
going to be double again and then we're
going to change the word int here to
double since we weren't wanting to convert
to the double primitive time now let's
run our application again and see what
happens so far so good but let's
actually now change this valley 2018
we're going to change that to 2018
dot one to five which of course is a
decimal number just to make sure that
our double calculations are working I
mean we've got an idea that it is
working here given that we had a dot
zero the period zero added to the end of
the number but let's run it now that's
the value is 2018 0.125 and see what
happens so he's here we've got number a
string equals 2018 dot one two five one
and that's what we would expect because
it's of type string remembering that if
we try to add a number to a string Java
automatically converts the type back
tostring and appends it to the end of
the string but in the case of the number
or we've defined it as a double and we
did that on line nine adding one to that
we started off with the value of 2018
point one two five
that's the value we got on line nine
we've added one to it and the final
value there is number equals 2019 0.125
and just to be consistent and check this
if we added an A on the end of that and
run it we'll find that will get the same
type of exception in other words error
trying to convert what is now not a
valid number to a number right so I'll
delete that now there's a similar
parsing process that can be used for
other types like float or long but keep
in mind that when we call methods such
as pars double the associated class they
must be used before calling the method
so in this case obviously I changed what
was originally the integer dot parse int
and I changed that to double dot pass
double and again notice how it begins
with a capital letter
while primitive types such as this one
here on line nine this start of the line
starts with a lowercase letter as in
double something like uppercase here
first letter and a lowercase over here
so keep that distinction in mind
but again we'll be covering these
wrapper classes which is what this
double entry here is this class will be
covering that later in the course so
that's it for converting a string to a
number type I'll see you in the next video.