- [Instructor] Alright,
so in the previous videos
we talked about and
looked at the files class
to read and write text files.
Let's now turn our
attention to binary files.
So we're gonna start by
writing to a binary file
so that we've got something we can read.
So we're gonna start by
writing the string hello world,
to a file in binary format.
So I'm gonna comment out this code.
And at the top, we're going to start
by typing file output stream.
Bin file is equal to
new, file output stream.
We're gonna call the file data dot DAT,
call it anything you literally like there.
Then we need a file
channel, so file channel,
bin channel, is equal to
bin file, dot get channel.
Alright, so far so good.
But the next thing we need is a buffer,
because we're writing to a
file, we've got the data,
so you can create a
byte buffer that matches
the length of the data.
In the read cases, you
don't know the length
of the data, so what you can do is create
a buffer of a given length, and
then parse what it receives.
But note that you don't
have to use the same buffer
to do all your reads and writes,
you can create as many
buffers as you like.
So before I type some
more code, let's get some
terminology out of the way.
Firstly, a buffer's
capacity, is the number
of elements it can contain.
Now a buffer's position
is the index of the next
element that should be read or written.
It can't be greater than
the buffer's capacity.
A buffer's mark is used by
the buffer dot reset method,
when this method is called,
the buffer's position
is reset to it's mark.
Now if you know you
wanna rewind the buffer
to a certain point, you'll mark the point,
and then later you can
call the reset method
to reset the position to the mark.
But you'll more of how
that works as we proceed.
So with that out of the way,
let's actually now write
this hello world string to
a file in binary format.
The first thing we need
to create a byte array
for the string that we want to output,
so it's gonna be byte array
output bytes, we'll call it,
is equal to, and we'll
just type in hello world,
exclamation mark, dot bytes,
so there's out byte array.
And then we need a byte buffer,
so we type byte buffer, you can see that's
a java dot NIO input, buffer is equal to,
and it's byte buffer, dot wrap,
note that we're using
a static method there,
then output bytes.
So we've created our buffer now.
So let me first call this
string dot get bytes,
on line 14, but we do call
it to create the byte array,
then we're calling this byte
buffer dot wrap static method,
to create a byte buffer
from the byte array.
The actual wrap method
itself, does the following,
first it wraps the bite
array into the buffer.
What that means is that the buffer
is backed by the byte array.
Now this is actually important.
Modifications to the
buffer will actually change
the array, and modifications to the array,
will change the buffer.
Now if you use the buffer
to write out our string
or our bytes, and then you
use it to read from a file,
the output byte array will be changed,
in other words it'll no
longer contain hello world.
So essentially, when you
call the wrap method,
you're telling the run
time, that you wanna
use the byte array as the buffer.
And since you've used wrap,
the buffer is already filled.
May not be what you're
expecting to happen there.
Secondly, it sets the position
of the buffer to zero,
and when you use the buffer the read-write
will start at position zero.
Thirdly, the buffers capacity will be set
to the byte array's
length, which you'd expect.
And fourthly, the buffers
mark, will be undefined.
And that can be set later.
So now that we've got our
buffer, it contains the bytes,
which was the string object
that we wanted to write,
we can use the channel
to write it to a file.
So we'll do that, int
channel dot write, buffer.
And if you wanna know how many
bytes are actually written,
you can get that from the
write method's return value,
so we could change that to
be int, num bytes, equals,
byte channel dot write buffer.
And then we can print that out,
num bytes, written, was, plus num bytes.
Finally then you'd have
to close the input stream
and the file channel, because of that,
you can use try with resources instead of
creating the instances with the try block.
So it's probably better to do it that way,
so let's actually change that,
to be a try with resources,
so it's gonna read,
try file, output stream,
bin file, equals new,
file output stream, I guess
we could've just copied the
definitions there, actually let's do that.
It'll be much easier to do that,
so we'll put those both in here.
Like that, and I'm going to
put another parentheses there
and then open a code block,
and that should fix that.
So now that we've done
that, we'll find that both
the channel and the output
stream will be closed
once we've finished execution because
we're using try with resources.
I think that's preferable
to creating them within
the try block, so let's
actually try, no pun intended,
to run this application.
You can see we've got 12 bytes written,
which would be consistent
with hello world,
which is exactly 12 bytes,
that we can see over here
our data dot DAT file,
is actually written,
and we can actually see the text
is actually appearing in that file.
Now by the way, it looks like a text file,
because we've used the
UTF eight character set,
and as I mentioned you
can see the 12 bytes
were actually written in the console
window down at the bottom.
Alright, so let's go back to our code.
And actually change it, or add to it,
to actually write an integer.
Now we could reuse the buffer, but instead
what we're gonna do is
create an int buffer,
that you'll use whenever you
want to write an integer.
So we'll actually do that instead.
We'd go, byte buffer,
int buffer is equal to
byte buffer, dot allocate,
integer dot bytes.
So we're calling the byte
buffer dot allocate method,
and we're passing to it
the size that we want
the buffer to be, which is this case is,
because we mentioned we
want to write an integer,
this is the number of bytes in a integer.
So now that we've got the buffer,
we can write an int to the buffer,
so let's write an integer,
number, pick a number,
say 245, so we go int,
buffer dot put int, 245.
Let's write it to our bin channel,
so num bytes, is equal to
bin channel, dot write,
it's gonna be int buffer this time.
And then we'll print that out again.
And let's just copy that line up there.
Alright, so let's actually
run it and see what happens.
And look at our file.
Well that's a bit weird, as you can see,
the integer's not appearing there,
in the data file and then down
here under the second write,
num bytes written was actually zero.
So what actually happened,
why isn't the integer in
the file, and why are we
getting zero as the output?
When trying to write out the integer.
Well here's the deal in a nutshell.
When you created the buffer,
the position of the buffer
was set to zero, now when
you call the put int method,
on line 21 here, you wrote
the int into the buffer,
which changed the buffer's position.
Now in the bin channel dot write method,
which we're using on
the next line, line 22,
goes to read the buffer's contents,
it'll start the read at
the buffer's position.
So you have to explicitly
reset the position to zero
if you want the bin
channel dot write method
to start reading the
buffer from the beginning.
So to do this, we're gonna call
the byte buffer dot flip method.
And the flip method resets
the position to zero,
and discards any mark that
have been set previously.
Now, it'd be obviously
fantastic if the IO methods
did this for us, so that
developers didn't have
to explicitly reset our
buffer's position to zero,
but alas, that's not the case, that was
a design decision,
because you may wanna do
modable writes or reads to a buffer,
before writing to the
channel, in which case
you wouldn't want to reset the position
to zero after every write.
Now, we didn't have to use,
we don't have to use flip
when we use the wrap
method, and that's because
it resets the position to zero.
The wrap method up here, on line 16,
in case you're wondering.
So by using the wrap
method, it's automatically
resetting the position to zero.
And, I listed three things
the wrap method does,
the second on that list is that it
sets the position to zero.
So that's one method that
does take care of this for us,
it's a convenience method to
use when writing byte arrays.
But when writing numerics,
and that's an int,
a long and a short, using the put int,
put long and put short methods, et cetera,
you do have to take care of
resetting the buffer yourself.
And as mentioned, you may
not wanna do so after every
read or write, and that's
why they've actually got
that in there, so if you
had 20 integers to write,
for arguments sake, you
could create a buffer
large enough to accept 20 integers having
called the put int method 20 times.
Each write would start at the buffer's
position in that case.
For the first put int
method, the buffer's position
would be zero, the second
caller would be four,
the third it would be
eight, given that four
is the number of bytes for an integer.
Now also note that you can
write to an explicit index
in the buffer, to do so,
you pass a second parameter
to the put method, that
specifies the start index
for the read or write.
But let's flip the buffer before using it,
to write to the channel,
so we need to put that code
before the write and after the put,
so right down here, we're
going to put int buffer,
dot flip, to reset the position to zero,
and if we run it now, we should find that
the integers written to the file
and we get to four back us
and the right bytes written.
Open data dot date, we've
now got this message
which is consistent with the fact that
we're now writing binary
data, and we've got
the integers showing there, you can see
there's four bytes been out of there,
that's the representation of our integer,
but importantly down here, number bytes
are written was four,
so that actually worked.
Alright, so let's actually
write another integer this time,
we'll use a negative number.
And let's actually
pretend, I'm gonna actually
just copy these three lines,
actually copy these four lines,
but I'm going to get rid of the flip,
and the number I'm gonna write,
I'll use a negative
number, negative 98765.
So we're pretending that,
that we don't understand
that we have to call the flip method
again to reset the buffer,
both before you write
negative 98765 to the
buffer, and then before
you write the buffer to a file.
So if we do that now, in
this scenario, and run it,
we actually get an
exception, you can see here
we've got java dot NIO dot
buffer overflow exception,
and the actual error is on line 26,
and line 26 is this
put int negative 98765,
and the reason for that
is, after we wrote the last
integer, 245 to the file,
the buffer's position
was set to four, but buffer
is only four bytes long,
and that's because when
we used the buffer,
we set it up using the
buffer dot allocate method
to integer drop bytes,
which is a length of four
on a computer, and that's usual with java
the position is zero-based.
So four is actually outside of our bounds,
so the buffer's capacity, there's no room
at position four to write any more bytes,
and then hence we're getting
an exception for that reason.
So calling flip will
obviously solve the problem,
so we need to do two flips
here, we need to do a flip,
and then I'll just copy the code,
flip before our call, to the put int,
and then also, we need to
do a flip after the put int,
prior to the call to the write method.
We'll just run this to
confirm that it works.
This time you can see that it was written,
we've got calls, two bytes,
lots of bytes written,
integers written I should say,
and you can see, although
we can't understand it,
we can see that the extra bytes actually
were written to the file.
So the point here, always
remember to call the flip method
whenever you wanna reset a
buffer's position to zero.
It's a common error to forget to do it,
and then wonder why the
data hasn't been written
to the data source.
Now if you're going to do
multiple writes to a buffer
before writing the buffer to a channel,
you don't have to call
flip on after each write,
but you do have to call it whenever
you flip from reading to
writing, or writing to reading,
and hence the name flip.
When you've filled a
buffer, and you're ready
to write it to a channel,
or to the channel,
you'll actually be reading
from the buffer at that point,
and then read from the buffer
and write to the channel,
and hence the call to flip is required.
Alright, so that's it, I'm going to finish
the video here now, in the next one,
I'm gonna start taking
a look at reading files
using channels and
buffers, and other things
along those lines, so I'll
see you in the next video.