So in the previous video, we actually
got most of our challenge working.
We got the ability to actually
go forward to the playlist,
to the next song on the playlist that is,
and also to go back to the previous one.
So let's now hopefully finish off
the rest of the challenge in this video.
So what we need to do is, firstly we
didn't actually print a menu option.
The actual correct options that
are available for the menu selection.
So we'll do that first, so
we can see what the relevant options are.
So I'm going to first put in here,
in the play method,
once we have determined there
are some songs in the playList.
We're going to actually print out a menu.
So we're just gonna create
a print menu method.
Call that print menu.
Print that there for
the first time and also going down the
list we've actually commented that out.
So actually uncommented it there as
well and once you create that method and
of course that method is only going
to literally print a menu, so
private standing void print menu.
No parameters, and
we'll just put available actions.
Press and the option are going to be
are we talked about some of these,
zero to quit.
So it's actually to leave.
And one is to play the next song which
we saw working in the previous video.
And two of course of
to play previous song.
Song.
Option three is gonna be
to replay the current song.
We haven't developed that method yet.
Whoops.
And option four,
is going to be to actually list the songs.
4- List songs in the playlist.
And option five is going to print this,
this is essentially going to
be this menu option itself.
So 5 print available actions like so.
And that's gonna tree it.
That's that method now.
So let's fix that up.
So, that's good.
So again we've got it working so
it's actually showing the next
song in the playlist.
And also, well not only to go forward,
but also to go back as well.
So the next thing we actually want
to implement is we wanna implement
the ability to actually
show a list of songs.
We're gonna actually print
the list of available songs.
That's easy.
Print list command.
So we'll do that one first.
That's menu selection four or case four.
So the code for
that is going to be private.
Static void.
And it's print list of course.
And the perimeter pass is going to
be linked list of song objects.
And, we'll call that playList.
So, firstly,
we need to create an iterator.
Iterator = playList.iterator.
And, because we're not going backwards and
forwards,
we don't actually need
to use a list iterator.
So, I'm just gonna show you how to use
a regular iterator, which works for
lots of different types
of objects as well.
That's very much the same,
but it doesn't give you
the capability of going backwards.
You really just need to continually go
through forward and it's perfect for
sort of looping through something once,
which is what we're doing this case.
So, let's then print out some equals signs
here just to make it clear in the output
that this is the start of the output.
And then we'll just put
while iterator.hasNext,
so while there is another
song to be displayed, and
we simply put System.out.println,
and it's going to be Iterator.next.
Now note that I could have
also put .toString, but
that is actually the default option.
In the previous video, I actually
put .string, but that is optional.
Sometimes it can be a good
idea to put that in, so
it's clear in your code
what you're trying to do.
But as you can see, it actually accepts
it and works quite nicely without it.
The only thing we need to
do at the end of that,
is actually just print out
another set of equal signs, so
that we can clearly see that the list
is available and actually there.
So that's good.
So that's actually working nicely.
Really the other main thing we need to
do now is, the last thing is case three.
And that's actually in the situation where
we wanna actually play or replay the song.
So what we can do is by being
able to replay the current song,
we can take advantage of
the fact that the ListIterator is
actually somewhere between
the previous and the next.
So in other words,
it's somewhere in the middle.
So one of those will give us
the track we last started playing and
from there we can work
out which one to use.
All we really need to know is which
direction we were moving in at the time.
So for example if we're moving forward, we
just after the currently playing song, so
we need to go back because
we're in a forward position.
But if we're actually going backwards
we would be going to the previous one.
Then we're just before the current song so
we need to go forward.
So in both cases we've
changed the direction.
So we need to set forward appropriately
so, if we're going forward and
go back to play the same track again,
and then forward, vice versa.
So it sounds a little bit confusing but
let's put the code in and
hopefully we're looking for
code it'll actually make more sense.
So the first thing we need to
do is determine the direction so
we'll put an if forward, and
we'll do the code firstly for
the situation where we
were moving forward.
Then we need to check
if there's a previous.
So listIterator.hasprevious.
We can put a message now,
replaying + listIterator.previous and,
we could put .toString
there if you wanted to.
Remembering that, that is optional because
that's the default method, anyway.
So, we could actually take that
out ourself, if we wanted to, but
I'll put that in there for now.
else.
If it didn't have a previous entry,
we can just put we are.
At the start of the list.
Then so
at that point we need to do an else and
an option to determine if
we're going backwards.
So we put an else, here we put else,
so if we weren't going forward,
we do our list interator.hasnext.
And we're replaying plus
listIterator.next.string.
And what I didn't put there, I should
have actually made a topper there, but
also we do also need to set the status,
cuz we're actually putting,
we've done the check for previous, and
we've gone into a forward direction.
We now need to set forward,
equal to false.
So, we've checked to see if
there was a previous one,
we've gone to the previous one, but
then we've set forward to false,
because of course we're telling the
system, we're keeping track of the fact
that we're now going back,
which we had to do to replay that song.
So, contrasting that and
the other situation,
where we were going backwards,
we need to actually set forward to true.
Forward equals true,
because we've had to go forward in order
to actually replay the song again.
So, hopefully that actually makes sense,
and we just need an else here as well.
The else is just going to say else
We have reached the end of the list.
So that's essentially the code there and
that's again, so if we count when we
are moving forward we then check to see
whether there is a previous record.
If there is, we actually move
to the previous record and
actually show the name of the actual
song as it currently is before moving.
Else, we just put a message to say that
we're actually at the start of the list.
And then the opposite applies in the case
where we actually weren't moving forward.
We actually go to the next record,
replay it and set forward,
the forward direction to forward,
no to true,
it'll say which is,
means that we're actually going forward.
At this point, all options are now working
and we have a fully operational playlist.
So let's actually just
check that it does work.
Gonna run that.
Okay we'll make a bit of space here,
we probably need more space.
So this is just option one, so top it in
the source code, we're going to here.
One playing sort of in a previous video.
That's working fine.
See the list I can't go any further,
that's good, now let's go back, going just
back to the front, to the first entry, so
forwards and backwards is working nicely.
Let's actually replay the song
at the start of the list.
We can't do anything because
we haven't played one so
if we play a song, first one, and now if
we actually replay, we're replaying it.
And if we go to the next record or the
next entry in the playlist I should say,
and replay it.
That's working.
If you go back in the previous direction,
number three.
That's also working as well.
And we can go back again at
the start of the playlist and
of course we'll get the fact that
we're at the start of the list.
So that's all working correctly.
And if we do option four
that should be our printout.
That's a list of the songs
in the playlist.
You could see that's working.
That's all the entries that
were added to the playlist.
And option five should be our menu option.
Which of course just repeats
the available menu options.
So that's now working fine.
But there is actually another option.
Remember that we also have a case we
talked about optionally in the challenge.
And as this closes down,
we'll go back and look at that.
As an optional extra, this is right
down the bottom here, provide an option
to remove the current song from the
playlist, a hint was listIterator.remove.
So we'll allocate for that.
It'll be case six here.
Case six.
We can do something like playlist.size.
That's greater than zero.
The top list operator.remove.
And we're doing the check to see whether
the playlist is greater than zero.
Probably don't need that anyway because
up here, we actually did a test
to see whether the play list was greater
than zero or if it was equal to zero.
So you think at first glance
we would need to test again.
But because we've now introduced
the capability of deleting entries,
we do actually want to keep that.
We do actually want to keep that
facility in there to be able to
test each time to see whether there's
still some records in there because we
could have actually
deleted all the records.
If that's the case, we don't want it to
throw up with an error automatically but
there's actually a potential
issue with this.
Well firstly,
we'll just check that it does work.
So if we actually try and delete one,
well firstly we'll need to go to a song.
So we're now playing Holy Man.
If we try and actually delete it.
The option 6.
And we actually have a look at the songs.
We could see it's actually there.
It seems to have worked.
It's actually removed that song,
correctly the current song we're playing.
But if we do a 6 again,
we actually get an error.
So, the actual issue here is to do
with the way that the ListIterator is
actually set up.
The link list.
So it can only be made once
per call to next or previous.
So it actually throws an exception
if neither the .next or
the .previous has been called.
So in other words, each time you delete
a record you then have to do a .next or
a .previous to avoid getting
an error if you try and do it again.
So we need to actually guard against that.
And that's actually built into
the actual linked list code itself.
And you notice I talked
about an exception.
We haven't actually dealt
with exceptions yet, but
that's actually a way to
actually trap an error.
By default Java will give you an error
like you can see on the screen here legal
state exception.
We can actually trap those
using a try catch block and
we'll be doing that later in the course.
So for now what we want to do,
is we want to just change our code
to avoid this, exception coming up.
And generally speaking it's
a good idea to do that.
If you can code something so
that you're not actually getting
these exceptions, that's good.
But later on if you do get exceptions,
you can guard against that.
And we'll be doing that in
later parts of the course.
Let's go back and actually fix this so
we can delete remove records
without any ramifications.
And firstly what I'll do is I'll
quickly add this to the list.
The menu option for six,
which will be six delete.
Current song from playlist, like so.
Okay so
we can now see what that option is.
So the actual code, so what we'll do is.
There's actually two
ways we could handle it.
The one would probably be to use
the exception which I talked about.
So we could actually try and
catch that error if it come through
in that code and perform some action.
But because we haven't actually
talked about exceptions yet
we're going to leave that.
So what the other alternative is is at
this point is to ensure we call either
next or previous immediately after
removing a song and that ensures that if
you try to delete the next record we
don't actually get an error again.
So it's actually not really
that difficult to do.
What we really need to do here
is just after this remove
we put if ListIterator.hasNext, so
if it's going to the next record.
Now playing.
ListIterator.next, so in other words and
we're just automatically gonna move to
the next record if there is one available.
We'll put else if
listIterator.hasPrevious,
Now playing,
ListIterator.previous, like so.
And obviously,
you still need a break here as well
which I didn't actually have before.
Okay, so at that point,
that should actually work.
So what we're now doing
is we're actually doing,
if there are still some entries
available in the playlist, so
we're checking to see whether
the size is greater than zero.
If there is,
we're going to remove the current one.
But then what we're doing is that really
I'm ensuring that either there's a next
available entry or there's a previous and
one of those will have to be true in order
for this to have succeeded, playList.size,
because if that was equal to zero.
We wouldn't have gotten into
AB executing this code anyway.
So what we're doing is we're making sure
that one of these is actually executed,
and that's going to avoid the error.
In the future, because it means that
we actually move to the next record or
the previous record,
depending whether there's a song that's
actually available going forward or
backwards, and that'll actually stop
that error from actually happening.
And really I guess what we're saying we're
doing here is if we do actually delete
a song from the playList, the next
song automatically starts playing.
And that's really what
we're trying to say here.
So it automatically by default
it'll go to the next song.
But if we happen to be
at the end of the list,
then it would go back
to the previous song.
So it would just continue on in this case
playing and that's why it's automatic.
So let's just run that and
make sure it works.
And we should be done.
So, again, we'll actually just
look at our list of songs, and so
next, we'll actually go forward a song.
Play next song.
Playing Holy Man.
So, we now do a delete.
Now playing Soldier of Fortune.
You'll notice that was deleted as well.
We could delete that.
We could delete that, and so on and
so forth, and we go back and
have a look at the list of
entries that are there.
We could go to the next one.
Next, we're at the start of our list now.
Sorry, that was previous I was selecting.
And to go to the next one.
Next, next, next, next, and
we reach the end of the playlist.
And we do a delete there.
Now playing let's go.
It's actually.
Automatically figured out,
even though we're at the end of the list.
It went back, because it couldn't go
forward, and then deleted an entry.
And we're not getting those
exception errors anymore.
And again,
looking at the list that's remaining,
we've only got two songs
left in our playlist.
So that should be it.
That should actually be the challenge now.
We've actually finished everything.
Okay.
So that's the end of this section.
We've now looked at linked lists data,
we went through the theory,
behind their implementation.
And of course, we worked on
the java implementation of it.
And then we actually created
the first the program.
And obviously there's challenge as well.
Hopefully you can get an idea
of what a linked list does.
There's actually, linked lists is just one
example of many different data structures.
I've got trees, queues,
hash tables and maps and many more.
And we'll be dealing with some of
those as we go through the course.
So just keep in mind that there's lots
of different ways to go about resolving
common computer issues by
using a variety of tools that
are actually built into the Java software
development kit which is pretty cool, and
link lister is obviously just one of them.
So, thanks for watching.
And it's now time to move on to
the next section of the course.