alright so let's implement this employee
service class i'm going to come over to
sample right click click on new select
java class and we'll call this one
employee service it needs to extends....
...
...like so
making sure that i'm using the javafx
version of these service all right and
we need to create a task so we're going
to use to create task method control I
and select that so that's created the
task instead of returning null we're
going to return here new......and then we need
to implement the core method so control I again press enter because we
want to return the observable list of type
string and create or override the
call method and what that's going to do is
use the code that we've defined
controller in the initialize i'm just
going to grab all the code starting with
the string array declaration down to
and including the return employees
copy that go back to employees service
and i'm just going
selected paste over the top of that
return null with our code as you can
see and that's added the relevant
imports automatically for us and we've
now got our code and then I just to make
this valid need to put a semicolon there
to close off the create task method that
we created or to be more precise the new
task that we created here on line 14
alright so the employees service will
now return the employee names now all
we've done here is moved the task
declaration from the
initialize method and dropped it inside the
create task method now when we start the
service the jvm will call the create
task method to create the task the
service will run now instead of
declaring a task variable in the
controller though we have to declare the
service variable let's go back to the
controller and before you do to much more
we're going to comment out this code
that's in the initialize method because
again we move that to the employees
service class instead comment that out
we won't be using that and that last line we
need to comment out as well and what I can
actually do is just undo that change and
everything within the initialize i'm
going to comment out there excluding the
last three references which
are linking or data binding the various
properties so I'm going to leave that code in everything else i'm gonna comment out as you can
see they're all right so we need to
declare this task variable in the
controller so let's go ahead and do that
and we will add that just above the
initialize method actually that's going
to be private.....
....
.....now in the initialization
method this is where we're going to
create service instance rather than the
task instance i've commented that
appetizer as you saw me do so just now below
that to commented out code before the
data binding of the various tasks
properties we type...and
technically what we should do to be
consistent here is we can also remove
task from here because we're not going
to be using that i'm going to delete
that out what that means is we need to
change these references here where it's
task.progress property task.
message property and that will need to
be serviced instead so....
....
the last thing we need to do is down
here for the button press method
instead of starting a thread
we need to start the service so we just
change that to the service....
....so you can see we've now
completely swapped out the task out of
the controller all that codes is now in the
employee service and when the button is
pressed we're going to start the service
that we defined here on line 49 and we
should be good to go so let's just run
it and we should get the same results we
got with the previous example when the
task was in the controller let's try again
you can see that worked perfectly
with the same results when we had the
task in the controller the difference
here is of course we're using a service
to run the task rather than directly
creating a thread and this is the
recommended way to work with tasks in
javafx now we can use tasks directly but
using a service allows the javafx
runtime to manage threads for us now
what happens if we actually
already got this once i click on get
employee names again and when we do that
oops we actually get an error here i'm
going to close it down and looking at
the error invocation target exception
and if you scroll down and have a bit of
a look I'm just taking note of the messages down here on the bottom
can only start service in the ready
state was in state succeeded in other
words already processed and the service
had updated itself to the state of
succeeded
we're trying to run it again and that's
why we got an exception so we can
restart the service multiple times but
it must actually be in the ready state
when we start it when the service is
running and completed its task it's in the
succeeded state so lets make a change
to the button action handler so that it
checks the state of the service and then
resets the service as necessary so
our code sort of obviously very simple at
the moment the button press method
let's change that here to do a test so....
....
....and then
we can follow that up with the service....
....and otherwise...
.....so the code here should be if services
in the succeeded state we just reset it
and then start it otherwise
if its in the ready state we're just going
to start it and if its in any other state
we're not going to do anything so it was
already running it means the users
mashing the button so the service
could also be in a failed scheduled or
cancelled state and if the service
failed or scheduled then we wouldn't want
to start it again and if it was cancelled
we could reset it and start it again but
since there's no way to cancel the
service in our application we are not going
to check for it in the code we could
add a cancel button to the
interface that would let the user cancel
the task when it takes too long
let's just run that confirm that it does
work then we can run multiple times now
click on get employee names that works
the first time so it will now be in the
succeeded states if we run again you can
see we can't get into trouble then
clicking multiple times and I was clicking
it while it was still going
it's ignoring those extra clicks and
still processing that current 1 so the
service is working well now the service
class has got methods that allow us to
run code every time the state of the
service changes so what we could do is
hide the progress bar and label when the
application is initialized then perhaps
when the server state changes to a
running we can show them and when it
changes to succeeded will hide them
again so let's add the following code to
the initialize method to
implement that so after the service
equals new employee when we set up we are going
to start by putting....
.....and I can just press enter there
it should create the code for us so its
created the handler for us so in there
this is when the services running
going to do....
true and we're also going to do
oops too many a parentheses there
and we're going to do progress...
....and just before I
continue I need to actually put this
code above that this should be below
that code because you want this service
to be initialized and the various
progress bars and so forth to be
declared and setup before i'm putting this code in so I'm going to just put their
as I have done their which probably makes
more sense putting it there anyway so
that's if the service is running
let's add another one the next one will
be if the services succeed so....
....
and this one is when it succeeded we want
to hide the progress bar....
.....we also wanted do a progress label.....then
outside of that so when its run for the
first time we want to do....
....
....so in other words we've written
the code here whether
the service changes to running or succeeded
but we also when this form is
initialized by default we setting
visibility off to false for the progress
bar on the label
let's try that and see if it works
alright so we don't see the progress bar
initially and obviously we can't confirm
about the label because it wasn't
showing any way until we actually click
the button but let's just try running
this clicking on the button you can
see that did work the label was there as
was a progress bar then they're both
changed and click it again now same
thing there that it's actually showing
when it's working and its hiding
once we finish processing once the
state's changed now there is also just
to let you know there's a set on method
for each possible service state so you
can actually track all of those you know cancelled if you wanted to schedule etc
now remember that we remember that
I said when we are tying 2 things together
meaning that we want one thing to change
when the other thing changes we should
always check the documentation to see if
we can accomplish what we want to do
by binding properties together
well in this case we're tying the
visibility of the progress bar and label
to the running state of the service so
can we bind the two things together
rather than using a set on method
why yes yes we can so we can delete
the code that we've just added and
replace it with a much simpler way of
doing it so close this down and will
temporarily comment out that code and also
comment out these two lines here so we could
do instead is we could put progress bar.....and we can bind that
too .bind to service.running
how cool is that
and likewise for progress label...
.....so now we're
binding the visibility of the progress
bar and label to the running state of
the service only when the running state
of services set so depending on the
value of the running properly that's
going to be reflected in the visible
property for both our progress bar and
label let's just try running that
should give us the same results
and you can see we got the same results
on the screen there you can see that i
compared to the code that i commented
out the binding the binding of
properties is much cleaner and also uses
a lot less code and of course we still
often need to use the set on methods
because we wouldn't always be able to
accomplish what we wanted to do by just
binding it the code to the services
running property but if you are doing
something that's relatively
straightforward you can see that
it's a more elegant solution using a lot
less code so one last note note here
before we leave services if you want to
pass parameters to the task that the
service runs we have to expose those
parameters as properties of the service
sub class now since
properties are a general java
topic and not a javafx topic we won't
discuss how to do that in this lecture
but i just wanted to make you aware that
it is possible to pass information to
the task by adding properties to the
server sub class
alright so thanks for following
along in this lecture and for java
concurrency in general so now that we've
been through so much of this java
concurrency information it's time to put
into practice of what we've learn and
we're going to start in the next video
with some code challenges to hopefully
solidify your understanding of a java
concurrency to see you in the next video