All right, so let's discuss reading input
from a user.
So the goal of this video, is to make
an interactive application where a user will enter his
or her name and year of birth and then the application
will calculate the current age of the user.
Now in one of the previous videos.
We learned how to parse, in other words how to convert
a string type into a number by using the methods Pass Int
and Pass Double.
In this video we're going to cover another useful method
called Next Line as well as a few others.
And we'll also use a class called Scanner.
Which is a simple text scanner that can pass
both Primitive types and Strings.
So essentially scanner uses methods
like parse Int Internally.
Now one method called Next returns a string allowing us
to save the returned value to a variable.
So the application we're going to write will prompt a user
for their name.
In other words we want the user of the application
to enter their name and then our application will store
that as a variable.
So to start let's actually get our scanner set up.
We're going to type some code in our main method,
noting that I've created a new project
called reading user input.
So I'm going to type Scanner with a capital S
then a lowercase scanner and I'm going to select
that option.
And I'm going to make sure that I'm importing this scanner
Java dot util.
So if you get prompted for multiple options,
make sure the scanner dot util is the one you choose.
So the code scanner, scanner equals new scanner
but in parentheses it's going to be System with
a capital S dot in and semicolon to complete the log.
Now you've seen system dot out before and
that dumps text to the console in other words
it outputs information.
And in fact we've used that in all who actually use
that all the time and pretty much every project
that we've worked on.
So System dot in on the other hand is the opposite
in that it allows you to type input into the console
which then gets returned back to the programme.
So that's what we're doing here, when we're defining
a variable of type scanner.
So let's mentioned previously, case here is very important.
So scanner is one of Java's built-in classes
and it allows us to read user import.
So in other words, we can pass primitive types
and strings using methods from this scanner.
And notice also there's this new keyword
that I'm using here as well you know line eight.
We use that to create what's called an Instance of Scanner,
meaning that we are creating a new object of type scanner.
Now, so far we've been using primitive types.
So we haven't needed to use the new keyword but later
in the course we're going to discuss in depth
what an Instance is and why we use new
when creating an Instance.
So keep in mind that we can create as many Scanner instances
as we need by using a new line with the new keyword again
but for our current example we're just going to use
a single scanner.
All right, so we've defined our scanner or the next line
let's now type system dot out dot println I'm gonna put in
double quotes enter your name colon the space the close off
the double quote parentheses and semicolon.
We've seen that before we're just outputting a message there
and on the next line let's type string name equals scanner
this time using the lower case scanner dot next line.
So I'm selecting next line in parentheses.
Alright and then after we've finished using a scanner,
we should close it using the close method.
So note that after closing the scanner calling methods
like Next Line or Next Intimal cause errors.
So we should really ensure we're done with using the scanner
before closing it.
So it's recommended that we close the scanner
after we don't need it anymore as it then releases
the underlying memory that scanner was using internally.
Now this might seem a bit confusing
but later we're going to scan...
We're going to use scanner more frequently,
so things will become clearer.
So for now though what I'm going to do
is add an extra line there.
I put scanner.close with parentheses on the end.
Alright, so what are we done here well to sum up
we're using the variable scanner defined on line eight
and we're calling the method Next Line,
this one here on line 10 scanner dot nextLine to read a line
of input from the console.
And then what we're going to do now you're going to add
some output to print out what was typed.
So I'm going to put after the next line method,
put another space there we're going to print out another
message and the message in double quote to be your name
is space another double quote plus name.
We're now using the next line method here on line 10
to retrieve some information from the console
then on line 12 we're printing out a message your name is
then whatever was typed in by the user.
So let's now try running the application
and see what happens.
All right so you can see down here in the bottom
of the screen is asking for entering your name,
enter your name, we're asking to enter your name.
So I'm going to type Tim into the console.
(typing)
and I'm gonna press enter.
And notice that come up and said your name is Tim
and then the price is finished at the bottom.
So in other words our programme finished after doing that.
Though it always that IntelliJ displayed
what I typed in green.
Which is that really a handy way of knowing that these were
the letters that were actually typed in from the console.
So you can see now that by using this next line method
in conjunction with scanner we were able to retrieve some
input from the console in other words from the keyboard
and they were able to store that in a variable in this case
called Name and then we were able to print out the value
in other words what was entered by the user.
All right, so, so far so good but obviously the main goal
for this application is to not only ask the user
for their name but also for the year of birth,
so that we can then calculate the current users age based on
what the current year is that the programme is running in.
Now we've already handled reading the name.
So let's move on to the next part.
In a previous video we learned how to parse a number
from a string by using the parse int method.
Now let's try retrieving in int from the scanner
so that we can calculate the users age
from their birth year.
You know, we should begin by displaying a message
to the user so he machine knows what to do.
In other words what data to top.
So let's ask the user for their birth year before asking
for their name.
So I'm gonna put that code above the code where we've asked
for their name and I'm gonna put a line after the nine-eight
that had our definition of a scanner.
And I'm gonna start by outputting message into your year
of birth.
(typing)
Then on the next slide, I'm going to type int space year
of birth is equal to scanner dot
this time I'm going to select Next Int.
And put an extra line there just to make sure that
it's clear.
Now to read the age we could have used a string,
in other words we could have used the dot...
the next line method like we did for the user's name
on line 14 and then converted that to an integer as
we've done previously.
But scanner actually has a method that will pass the string
to an integer for us and we were able to use that
by using this scanner dot next int method call here.
So essentially what's happening there is that the integer
at the what the user has typed is automatically converted
into an integer and saved into our variable called year
of birth which is of type int.
Now I'm going to explain shortly while we put this code
above the name retrieval section.
So don't worry about that too much for now.
But now we've got an int value for year of birth thanks
to the next int method we're using on line 11 allowing us
to read an integer from the console.
So to figure out the user's age, we just need to calculate
now the difference between the current year and the year
of birth entered by the user.
So let's calculate the age of the user
and then we'll print it to the console.
So to do that, I'm going to add the code after the code
that has asked for their name.
I'm going to type int age equals we want to enter
our current year which is 2018 minus year of birth,
you put a semicolon there.
That's how we calculate how old the person is based on
the year of birth that they've entered and deducting that
from the current year which is 2018.
So now that we've got the user's age.
Let's print out a different message to the user.
Now in the existing print in statement,
I'm going to add age as well as some additional text.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So remember we've got your name is.
Let's change that to your name is plus name,
we're going to the end of it here.
You'll put plus comma and you are...
and it's place another double quote plus age
plus and another double quote the space there
for years old and closing up the line like so.
Alright, so let's do run this application and see
if it works.
So enter your year of birth is being asked for first.
So I'm going to enter my birth year which is 1964,
press enter and notice what happened.
Automatically I did get a chance to enter my name
and it automatically came up and says your name
is a space comma and you are 54 years old.
So the application didn't give us a chance to enter a name
even though the message "enter your name" was printed.
So what's going on there just to make sure,
let's just run it again.
I've been very careful, gonna enter my year of birth
and press enter.
And you can see it automatically goes past the enter
your name and prints out the message
and didn't give me a chance to enter my name.
So what's actually going on here?
Well, this is actually one of the mistakes that beginners
usually make, which is why I've ordered
the birth year prompt before the name one.
Whenever we relate a number from the scanner,
being an Int or Float or Double or some other type,
we press the Enter key on the keyboard as we just did
with the age.
So doing that ends the line.
So it's recommended after a next enter or call to next int
to call next line again without assigning it to a variable.
In other words to handle the Enter key issue,
we have to call next line, so that the scanner works
as expected.
Now internally the scanner is checking for a line separator
and when we hit Enter we're typing a line separator
so that's interpreted as input.
When we reach the next line method that retrieves the name
the input for a name becomes Enter,
so is essentially skipped.
So knowing that and knowing that that's an issue.
We can now add another call to next line
right off the next int and include a comment to that effect
as well so we know that we had a reason for doing so.
So after the year of birth up here,
I'm going to types scanner dot next line
to call that.
I'm going to put a comma here to say handle
next line character enter key.
So now that I've actually done that,
let's run this again and see what happens.
Into my year of birth again my case 1964 this time
it's now asking me for my name I'm going to enter Tim,
press Enter your name is Tim in your 54 years old,
so the programme is now working as expected.
So keep this in mind for the future,
after you reading a number with a scanner
there must be a next line method call
to handle the Enter key like we've done on line 12.
All right, so upon looking at the birth year entered
by the user, we can see that our application
easily calculated the age.
However there are a few potential problems
and let's talk over those problems, in the next video.