We created a method called make bed,
which then itself called the method,
bed from the bed object.
So all we have to do there
is put bedroom.makebed.
That's how we make the bed.
And the other way of accessing it,
which was by the getter, bedroom.
.getLamp.turnOn.
Let's try running that.
So you can see the bedroom class was
called first, making the bed which it then
in turn called the method make from
the bed object that was, that's part and
parcel of this class, and then of
course the other way of accessing it
which is by the getter,
use that to access the lamp
object which again is part of our
bedroom object and turned on the light.
So you can see that composition is very
very powerful, and as we progress through
this course you will see examples of
Composition and, as I mentioned earlier,
you'll understand more where to use
inheritance and where to use composition.
As a general rule,
you would aim for composition.
Generally, that's what a lot of object
orientation programming experts suggest
you do, is at least look at that first.
So hopefully you did
well on your challenge,
in the next video we're going
to talk about encapsulation,
which is another component of
object orientated programming.
And something that you've actually
been using for some time now but
probably weren't aware
that you were using it.
So I'm going to explain that in
more detail in the next video.
50, "yellow"), whatever you want it to do.
Using the getter or we could access it
directly, accessing the variable directly.
It really depends the way
you're setting yourself up.
Probably the better way of doing it
would be the way that I'm showing you
now with the monitor on the screen because
we don't really need those getters,
they're not actually
adding anything you us.
They're not adding,
they're really just making the code
a little more complex than what we need.
If we needed to do something else,
in other words if we had needed to
check whether the case had been.
If we needed to check whether the objects
had been initialized, we're looking for
something else,
some other sort of form of validation or
verification, we might wanna
leave those getters in there.
What we could actually do is actually
get rid of those altogether.
To make our code look
a bit more streamlined and
then just access those variables directly.
Of course, that's the case.
So we've now got public
function called powerUp and
a private function called drawLogo,
and of course, the powerUp function of
the PC will draw that logo on the screen,
as I mentioned before.
We go back to our main class.
Obviously these methods won't work anymore
because we've actually deleted them, so
I'm gonna delete those.
But what we could do is put
thePC.powerUp(), if we run that,
You'll see that the power button
was pressed drawing pixels at 1250
in color yellow, so obviously to access
that we access thePC.powerUp method.
So I went to our PC, powerUp method,
which calls theCase.pressPowerButton,
which then references the case objective
that's been created for this class.
And if you have a look at case code,
it's calling the pressPowerButton" method,
to show that message on the screen,
and of course the second thing it did
was it actually drew the logo and
it used the monitor.drawPixelAt method.
And of course the monitor method
does the system output there.
So that, in essence,
is what composition is.
It's actually creating
objects within objects.
So you're having like a master object,
in this case the PC is managing and
looking after, and
this is using composition to achieve that,
as opposed to inheritance that we
looked at in the previous video.
So in our future video,
what I'm going to do is explain
where you should be using inheritance and
where you should be using composition.
As a general rule, when you're
designing your programs in Java,
you probably wanna look
at composition first.
So if you do any sort of research on the
Internet, most of the experts will tell
you that as a rule, to look at using
composition before inheritance.
And it does give you the added
advantages and more flexibility.
But with that said, it does depend on the
solution what you're trying to achieve.
Okay, so it's challenge time.
So the challenge is to create a single
room of a house using composition.
So think about the things that
should be included in this room.
Maybe some physical parts of the house.
Maybe some physical parts of the room.
But also furniture as well if you like.
Anything you think should
be included in the room.
You can create as many objects as you want
to compose this add until whatever
level of detail you wanna get into.
Make sure you add at least one method
to access an object that is composed
which is part of that main class to
be accessing that var getter and
then access via a public method that
object that was returned from the getter.
And you saw me do that
in the previous video.
And also then has at least one method
to hide the object completely.
In other words, not using the getter.
Basically exits that object
from another public class, and
you saw me do that in this video.
So go ahead and do that and
see what you can come back with.
And when you're ready, come back and
check out my solution.
So pause the video now and
I'll see you back shortly.
Okay, hopefully you managed to figure it
out, and you had some fun along the way.
Let's go ahead and
now implement one possible scenario, so
what I'm going to do is
implement a bedroom.
So I'm gonna create first the main class.
We'll call it Bedroom.
And I'm going to have a bedroom and
it's gonna first have a name.
Even though we know it's a bedroom,
it's gonna have a name anyway.
Like team's bedroom or
something like that.
And I'm going to create
an object called wall.
I'm gonna have wall one through four.
Obviously there's four walls.
I'm gonna have a ceiling.
Going to have a bed cuz it's a bedroom.
And I just want accessory,
let's go for the lamp.
Okay, I'm now gonna create the
constructor, which is gonna be everything.
There are quite a few things there.
And just to keep things simple,
I'm gonna create a getter for lamp,
I'll just create it manually.
And let's create a public method for
making the bed.
And I'm going to put a note there
to indicate what we're doing.
We're in the bedroom class making bed.
And then we're going to drop bed.make.
Okay, so I'm going to just breeze
through these other classes,
cuz they're gonna be pretty basic.
Let's create the wall class first.
We'll call it wall, and
we're just gonna have one field.
We'll call it direction, where's facing.
And let's just create a constructor.
And let's create a getter.
Very simple wall.
With a ceiling.
Let's do something similar so we're gonna
do create a ceiling, class ceiling.
This one I'm going to have a height.
With a ceiling start.
So let's just go with, say, painted color.
What the current color of the ceiling is.
Constructor.
And also getter as well.
And you can see now as I'm correcting
that some of these errors are going away
because I'm creating the classes.
Next I'm gonna create the bed class.
The bed starts with Install.
Installer bed, how many pillows?
What the height is of the bed from
the ground, maybe the number of sheets,
and whether it has a quilt,
or how many quilts.
Create a constructor.
And we'll create our getters.
But then we also need to
create our make method,
because if you recall we're
using bed.make over here.
So let's create that as well, and
we'll call that it's a void method and
we'll call it make, and
we'll just have a simple message there.
Puts this timer in the bed class, making.
Okay, so we've now created that as well.
And our bedroom class is looking good.
Now we've just got
the lamp to implement now.
Gonna create that now.
Lamp.
Let's try private String style;
private boolean battery;.
Is it a battery powered lamp, yes or no?
And globRating; perhaps.
Rate the Constructor.
And let's create the getters.
Let's create a method
here to turn on the lamp.
So public void turn on.
Turning on.
So it shouldn't have gotten rid of all
that error so now a valid class there,
which is good.
So let's go back to our main
method now and implement this.
So what I'm going to do is start by
creating our walls, I'm gonna put wall.
Wall1= new wall
type ("West") create four walls.
South and North.
I'll make them more unique.
We need a ceiling.
If you recall,
we said it's a 12-foot ceiling.
Painted color, just an integer, 55.
We need to create a bed.
We can write bed = new Bed.
Modern, four pillows, three foot perhaps,
two sheets, and a quilt.
So there's our bed.
Lastly we need to create a lamp so
lamp equals new lamp.
That's classic, false no battery.
And we'll say 75 is the globe rating.
So, we've now got the base objects
that we can now pass to our
bedroom to create this new bedroom.
So, to do that, we need bedroom equals
new bedroom_bedroom equals new bedroom.
Of course the parameters it
needs is the bedroom name.
We'll call it Tim's room, or
just Tim's will be enough
because we know it's Tim's bedroom,
wall1, wall2, wall3, wall4.
ceiling, bed, and of course, lamp.
So we've now got our valid
object Bedroom created.
So how do we make the bed?
Well i