Alright, it's time now for a challenge this
one's called the day of the week
challeng. Alright so your challenge is
to write a method with the name print
day of the week, it's got one parameter
of type int, so name that a parameter day
now the method shouldn't return any
value and a hint there is the word void
using a switch statement print Sunday
Monday then through Tuesday Wednesday
Thursday Friday Saturday
if the in parameter day is as the value
of 0 1 2 3 4 5 or 6 respectively so
depending on the value that has passed
we'll print a different day and if none
of those are true, in other words you've
got a value outside of that range you'd
print invalid day instead, so using that
you do that using a switch statement but
it's a bonus right a second other
solution that instead of using a switch
uses if then else and call your project
when you created in intellij day of the
week challenge and just to note also
that the challenge text is available in
the resources section if you're the type
of person who likes having the challenge
text to refer to while you're going
through the challenge download that from
the resources section alright so now
it's time to pause the video and attempt
the challenge when you finish to come
back and then you can check your
solution with mine so pause the video
now alright so how did you get on
hopefully you managed to figure out a
solution to that challenge let's hop
back in to IntelliJ and go through it
now step-by-step, so you can see here
that I've already created a project
called day of the week challenge and
have already created the main method as
well so the first thing we're going to
do is break this problem up into smaller
parts now if you recall the first
requirement was to write a method that
has one inter parameter with the name
day and it doesn't return anything it's
actually the first sentence in the
challenge so to do that we're going to
go into our code our public class
outside of the main method and before
the closing write curly brace and we're
going to top private static void and
we're going to type print day of the
week of capitalizing each letter other
than the first word print parentheses in
an int day so into the type in the
name of the parameter
and open I left a mic or add a left
curly brace and the white ones added
automatically by IntelliJ
so that's the method definition and
again I'm using the word private they're
that public and private will be
explained later in the course for now if
you've used a private or public or in
fact haven't used either that's
acceptable and was the challenge will
still work at this point in time
so let's our method definition so far on
line nine now the next step is to write
a switch statement using that parameter
day so let's write an empty switch
statement so to do that I'm just going
to type switch and in parentheses and
the word day which is our parameter in
parentheses and then we're going to add
a left curly brace and the right ones
added automatically by IntelliJ,
so that's what we call an empty switch
statement empty because it hasn't got
any code within the left or right curly
braces within the code block so now that
we've done that the next step is to
write our case statements I'm going to
check each day we're going to check the
value and depending on the value print
out an appropriate day if you recall the
requirement was to print Sunday Monday
through Saturday depending on the value
of the day parameter, so zero was Sunday
one means Monday and so on and the last
one was six and that's for Saturday.
So let's add our first case statement so
within the switch statement in the code
block we're going to type firstly case
space is 0 colon so that's our first
case for what 0 then we're going to top
s out and press tab so that system app
type print lynyrd and in case you're
over sunday and then after that we're
going to talk break semicolon so if Neil
handle case 0 which is Sunday so if the
value 0 we're going to print out Sunday
so then we want to get us go through and
add the other case statements for the
other days of the week so let's go ahead
and do that it doesn't matter where you
are on the line if you type a case when
he did intellij we take type it there
and press the colon and that's how
intelligent over to the left well then
I'm going to print Monday because case 1
importantly making sure we add the break
case 2 : gonna be Tuesday
break again case three for Wednesday and
again printout for Wednesday he gets out
another break case four s out and
it's going to be Thursday so you're
getting there a break two more here case
five print it out Friday and outbreak in
case six Saturday break. Alright so
that's our seven days of the week now
identified cases zero through six and
we've got a different day printing out
and here for each one. Alright so at this
point now we've done that the next step
is to decide how we're going to handle
the fact or having a handle or value
outside of the values of what zero three
six in any other scenario we're meant to
print out the text invalid day so how do
we do that well the easiest way the
switch statement is just to use the
default, so you just type default and
that means basically any other values
we're going to print out in valid day,
so really that's just saying that's going
to move that over I need an s out there
I'm just going to move that over
selecting and then holding down shift
and pressing tab to go back sorts in
line, we don't really need a break there
because it's the last line anyway but it
won't hurt if we do add one so to be
consistent we can actually add one there.
So that's it for the method now, so that
should work but obviously we can't just
assume it is, we have to test it out so
what I'm going to do is call the method
and we're going to try it with some
different parameters to make sure it
does work and we're going to call those
parameters from within the main method
so I'm going to start by typing print
day of the week we'll start with
negative one first the negative one is
outside of the range zero three six so
that should return invalid a so let's
right-click and run that and we've got
invalid day showing and I'll just move
this down to the bottom it's a little
bit easy to read invalid day showing so
that's working good so far.
So let's try each day the best way to
try each day would be to copy and paste
one and I've changed the value to zero
zero is going to be Sunday I'm going to
copy and paste I'm going to change the
argument for each one two three four
five six so I've now tested hopefully
Sunday through Saturday and of course
the first line was the one that tested
and a number that's outside that range.
So let's actually run that and we can
see at the output there we've been
invalidated and Sunday Monday Tuesday
Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday that
appears to be working nicely and that's
great then what other test would be to
have a number those larger than six
because we've tested a number that's
less than zero let's just place it one
more I'm going to put in the valley
seven so seven should also give us
invalid day we'll run that we're going
to validate down the bottom and validate
the top so that's looking good
looks like we've solved the challenge.
Alright so what we're going to do now is
we're going to attempt the bonus part of
the challenge if you call the bonus was
to create a solution that instead of
using the switch statement used if then
else is dead so what I'm going to do is
comment out this switch component of our
day of the week method that's going to
comment that out right down into
including the right curly brace that's
lining up with a switch there we don't
want to comment at this last one down
here because that's part of the method
so I'm going to comment it out or
comment it out now and I'm not gonna do
start writing at the top instead I'll
leave that code committed out so you can
refer to that if you happen to download
the source code so if then else it is
very similar making sure that we're
within our first left curly brace after
the method name we've got to start
typing if parentheses day is equal to
zero so we're testing that in
parentheses if that's the case we'll
open a code block and then we'll just
print out Sunday so that's a test there
obviously for Sunday and for the rest of
the days we can just print using else
statements so I can put it else if then
parentheses day is equal to one remember
to use two equal signs there they're
going to print out
for Monday and what we can literally do
there then is put these two line these
three lines here then we'll put this and
paste it in okay so then what we'll do
is we'll change the values so we've got
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 they want to change the
value so - he's going to be Tuesday
threes Wednesday 4 is the first day 5 is Friday
lastly 6 is Saturday then how do we
handle any other values that's quite
simple we can just use an else so else
is basically a catch-all for everything
else everything else that hasn't been
tested already we printed out he gets
out again in a valid day. Okay so now
that we've entered that, we've know we
know already from calling the print day
of the week method when we had a switch
in there that we had all the values
needed to test everything, so you can run
that again and have a look at our output
we've went validate and some time on
that use there was a twister fraud I
said of that an invalid day, so that's an
alternate or bonus version of our
challenge which uses if-then-else
instead of using the switch statement.
So basically the code is doing the
same we're getting the same exact same
output as we did using the if else that
we did when using the switch statement
unless you can see that's proof if you
will there for every challenge there
aren't many ways to solve them and
you've seen a couple of ways of solving
the exact same solution here now so
that's it, I hope you enjoyed that and
got a layer of this challenge let's move
on now to the next video.