All right.
So in the last video we created our first project and created our first Java class called Hello.
Let's now add a method to this new class to print out our hello world message.
Right so firstly what is a method.
Well it's a collection of statements one or more that perform an operation.
We'll be using here a special method called the main method that Java looks for when running a program.
It's the entry point for any Java code.
So in other words Java looks for that specific method and is able to start and run the program when
we use it.
You see how to do that.
Now you can create your own methods as you see later as well as this one.
But for now let's create this special main method.
So the way to do that was going to come up into our class on line two.
And I'm going to tab over and I'm just going to press Enter there. Notice that
Well you see when I start typing that IntelliJ is going to start giving us some hints there.
So I'm gonna start by typing public static and as I type "st" of the word static and IntelliJ suggesting
the word static it's going to press enter there.
So anytime you see something that you want IntelliJ to fill in for you just press enter right continue
gonna type
Now I typed "v" there because I need the word void and notice that IntelliJ is automatically
suggested that as well. I'm gonna press enter there. Next I'm going to type main.
I'm going to put a left to right parentheses in fact I typed the left parentheses and IntelliJ
being ever helpful.
added the right parentheses for us.
I'm going to type in there string for the capital s case is very important.
when you're programming left to right square braces and the word args then I'm going to come over and add
a left curly brace and a right curly brace as you saw me do there.
All right so what have we done there.
Well firstly looking at this statement public was the access modifier we discussed when defining the
class in the last video.
It's the same principle here.
Static is a Java keyword that needs an understanding of other concepts to really be explained adequately.
So for now just know that we need to have a static for Java to find this special method to run the code
that we're going to be adding. Now void is yet another Java keyword used to indicate that the method
won't return any information.
But we're talking again more about that later.
And just a tip here that you might be perhaps thinking well why can't I learn all these things now.
But there is a specific order to learning Java and it pays to learn things in the right order so that
things don't get too overwhelming.
Rest assured that we'll be coming in to all these things in a lot of detail at the relevant point in
the course.
So moving on we've got the left to right parentheses that I talked about and that is needed for
a method declaration and that's what we're doing here by typing in this code.
We defining a method.
So the left the right parentheses are mandatory but they can optionally include one or more parameters
and parameters are a way to pass information to a method.
Now more on that again later.
Have said that a few times now.
But bear with me.
All right so here you can say there's been one parameter has been defined and we'll talk more about
what that means a little bit later.
For now though to enable Java to define the main method it has to be typed exactly like it's typed here.
So if you typed something different like for example if you used a capital P let's try to write when
we do that we suddenly get it highlighted in red and that's IntelliJ telling us that I cannot understand
the word public with a capital P but I'll change it back to where it was which one was a lowercase
P.
It's then quite happy and the error disappears.
So keep that in mind that often you'll find errors can be purely relating to you typing something in uppercase
or lowercase when it should have been the opposite.
All right.
So at the moment now we've got a method.
So let's try running it and we can run it a few ways in IntelliJ.
At the moment we haven't got an option up here to run it in the top right hand corner to the right of
where it says Add configuration that run button is disabled for now but you'll find once we run it for
the first time that when we run it for the first time that'll be enabled.
But over here we can click on these little buttons here to run it.
We can also right click in there and select run as well you can see there's a keyboard shortcut to do
the same thing.
I'm just gonna click over here to run our program some run Hello mine you can see down the bottom something's
happening.
What's actually happening is that IntelliJ via the Java developing kit is compiling the Java program
and you could say we got a little bit of that portend the bottom of the screen and what I've said is
a bit of output the first line there is the line the command that IntelliJ sent to Java to execute
our program and below that we've got this process finished with exit code zero.
And what that essentially means is everything is completed successfully zero as you often used to indicate
that there wasn't a problem.
And the reason we haven't had any other output our Hello World message for argument's sake we haven't
got that because of course we haven't typed the coding yet.
If you have a look at the main method declaration again there on line 3.
Notice that the left or right curly braces didn't talk about what they were.
They're actually a code block.
Now the code block is defined or was used to define the start and end of a method effectively and we
can put our code in between those in the form statements.
So at the start just to recap on that we've got our class.
A class has got the body block of code which is the left Kelly Price and the right Kelly Price of the
entire class.
And our method is effectively within that class.
And it's got its own code block which is a group of code statements if you will that we'll be defining
and that are unique to that specific method.
All right.
So let's continue on now the next thing we want to do is we want to print out a message and to do that
when you come back to this class and I'm just pressing tap and I'm kind of tab so it's indented like
that and I'm going to type system the capital S the period out period printing and noting that intelligence
hopefully helping us along the way and putting in and typing in the left parentheses double quite character
write to top Hallowell.
And notice that when I've done that we've got the right parentheses and double quotes were added automatically
by intelligence for us and it was going to go over to the right hand side and put a semicolon and a
semicolon closes off the line to make it valid.
Notice if I get rid of that I can immediately get an error to the right hand side of that little indication
to say that's an error put a semicolon again.
And the error disappears.
All right.
So what we've done there is we've added a statement.
So what is the statement.
Well that's a complete command to be executed.
It can include one or more expressions and we'll be talking about expressions and a related topic operators
later in the course for now that what we've typed in is a command to basically call a method that comes
as part of Java code print line and we sent out the information of in this case the text hello world.
And it should print that out on the screen for us.
So let's actually try running that see that it works and notice now that up here the green arrow is
now enabled because we've run our code for the first time so I can click up there I can come over here
either way to run our program or I can right click in the main method when I say in the main method
making sure my cursors within there and select run of those ways or did the same thing and looking at
the airport paint on the bottom you can see now we've got Hollow World showing on the screen.
All right.
So at this point we've actually managed to do something we've actually printed up the words hello world.
Let's send the video here and then the next one.
I've got a challenge for you to get you to try making a little bit of a change in this program to print
something out so let's talk about that in the next video.