ok so continuing on with our debugging
session lets actually stop the
application one last time if you haven't
already and we're going to rerun the
debugger again so I have stopped it so I'm going
to rerun let's get to the bottom of this
bug see if we can actually fix it
alright so you can see that execution
has been suspended on the...
...line we're
going to now press the step-over button
and take a look at the state of our
application going to come down and press
this step over button over here
click at once let's see what actually
happened so noticing over here now to
the right the....and the
variables pane has now got
a value of a and if we expand the
s building and the variable section you can
see that the count has been set to one
but over here if we actually expand
s builder we can see that the value has
been set to zero is still zero and we're
also the value of the actual
stringbuilder itself hasn't changed
unlike the field version of our s builder
variable so case it's not clear this
tells us npw that we're updating the
wrong variable we actually wanted to
update the stringbuilder pass to the
method but you can see here actually
updating the instance variable and
obviously that this dot would give that
away as well let's step out of the
method using the step out button so you
come over and click on step out again so
we've now suspended after executing the
call to add char around the last line
here we can see the variables here for
the add char method and click one more
time now you can see how they disappear
now that we've stepped and we're now
back in the main class in the main
method and we are now seeing the variables
for that method other thing to note here
is now on the left hand side there's
only one frame in the frames area now so
if we expand the SB variable here in the
variables area we can see that it's
still empty now the editor is still also
display the current value of SB so
hopefully now you understand why our
applications running out of memory so
we're appending the character to the
string utilities instance variable
rather than to the string builder that
we're passing to the method therefor the
loop is never going to terminate and a
string utilities stringbuilder instance
will continue to grow until the
application runs out of memory to fix
this bug pretty simple fix go back to
string utilities we're going to actually
change this by removing the this.....
take this opportunity to close these extra
java files so we're going to be
updating the variable pass
to this method instead of local instance
variable and if go back now
and will stop this and we'll run
it again and now we check the values
so we step over again and you can see
now that we actually got the right
values being updated we got this we can
open up we can now see that the field
for the class is no longer being updated
and in fact the local the parameter
the sbuilder variable pass to this
method is now being updated you can see
the count is going up as well as the
actual value so that should be that bug
fixed so what we can then do is you can
remove the breakpoint by clicking on it
here and then coming up and clicking on
a resume and we can see that the program
is now finished because these buttons are
now deemed down and no loonger
available and click on the console to see
the output the program finished without
any errors and there's no more
exceptions
alright so let's go back to our debug
view again i'm going to go to set the
breakpoint again in the same area the
same one on line 11 i'm going to click on
the debug as normal to start again
we want to talk a bit more now about these
variables with the glasses on
them you can see that we've got this one
down here this chars added with the
little picture of sunglasses so at
the moment that's the only one there
that's because we no longer referencing
this . s builder within the method
but if you had keen eyes you probably
notice that in a previous video and even
earlier in this video before we fix this
that there was two variables there
the class instance field s builder was
also showing there as well so these
variables with glasses next to them are
actually called watches and their
feature of the IntelliJ debugger
now watchers always appear in the
variables pane
they're updated as the application runs
so let's actually go and step over each
statement in the add char method until
were actually suspended on the closing
curly brace now the step-over do one
more now we are actually suspended on
the curly braces you can see we can see
we've had some values updated so
chars added has been updated to one
and if we click on resume the
application was suspended again at the
same break point because of the loop in
the main method we step over to the
curly brace again you see the values
updated to 2 so this is a convenient way to
watch what's going on with variables of
interest now it may not seem like much
but it's because we don't have many
variables when we're dealing with a
class with a lot of instance variables
and we interested in one of two of them
in particular we can actually want to
set them as watches and as we've seen
intellij has set these
default ones up for us because we didn't
actually set these watches up for
ourselves individually so we're actually
interested to see what happens to the s
builder parameter now we can see the
value is easily enough by coming
down here and clicking on it and having
to look like that but lets suppose we were
very interested specifically in s builder
dot count now we can expand the s builder
parameters as you just saw and see the
count but if you want to do this with
several fields belonging to say
different instances our variables
window will quickly becoming a pretty
cluttered full as expanding everything
as it everything out down here and then
we may have to scroll up and down to see
all the values that were interested in
so to avoid this what we can do is we
can make s builder . count a watch to
do so i'm going to open this up again
we're going to come over here to count in
the variables pane right click on it and
click on add to watches up
here now its actually showing on its own line
going to click away from that
because i wanted to make a point about
the color which will see shortly so lets
go and step over this again so I'm
going to resume and going to step over
there did you notice what happened there
to the watch the sbuilder .count
watch that we've just added notice how
it went blue there
we're we actually when we stepped over
that line 11 now watch will turn blue
when the last statement executed changed
its value so that's a good thing to know
that you can sort of see
that when something's updated it changes
to blue a quick update quick scan you
can sort of see anything in Blue has
been updated now we can simplify this
even further by opening the watches
panel if the panel isn't already opened going
to open it using the show watches in
variables tab toggle which is down here
so if you see that their click on that to
open it but once you've done it once and
if you could come over here and hide it
you notice that this option doesn't come
back here at some point in the future
its then available here to click to restore
the watches view so either those two
places will actually show it but the
the watches view so either those t
bottom line is there we've got a
separate pane for our watches
now depending on how much screen real
estate you've got you might find that
either of those options wasn't available to
find that little watches
pane be able to click that so you
might actually happen you might see 2
greater than signs and you may be seen
it before in this course we'll have a
lot of windows open here at the top a
little greater than sign 2 greater
than signs and you click on that and it
opens up and gives you some other
options so if you can't find it look for
the option here that you can click which
will open up and enable you to
select that option the
show watches in variables tab toggle
option now one thing to note in
here is that this will only show
you watches that you added yourself
not the ones that as set by IntelliJ and
if you want to hide it again as you saw
i can click on the option here to
hide it and can add it back anytime you
want
so if you're no longer want to actually
watch a variable any longer you can
right-click on it and select the remove
watch lets just run
this again and then open this
so again if i wanted to remove that just
right click remove watch that removes it
from that window we can hide that again
okay
now don't confuse watches with field
watch points which is our next topic so
a field watch point is a type of
breakpoint so let's say we suspect that
somewhere in our code the value of a
variable is changing in an unexpected
way we want to locate the code that's
changing the value so what we can do is
we can set a field watch point on that
variable then whenever the value of the
variable is accessed or updated the
application will spend now we can
actually create field watch points in
two ways in the editor we can actually
place the cursor in the field
declaration and then al click in the
gutter
so in other words we want to
know this whenever this char added was
updated come over here hold alt
and click to create the breakpoint
their so that's actually to be more
precise the field watch point notice
that that's a little bit different the
icon to the one we can see there for a
regular breakpoint that's to tell it
telling you that this is actually a
different type of breakpoint or
it's a watch point in this case so
that's one way of doing it the other way
of doing it is to come up to the run
menu click on View breakpoints we want
to select click on plus here and select
java field watch points click on that
and then we can actually specify the
name of the class this code string
utilities and the name of the variable
that we want saying in this case chars
added and click on OK and that would
actually add it when we click on OK and
obviously have done a similar thing with
the way that I've clicked into the
gutter so i'm going to cancel that I won't
add that for now so lets try this i'm
going to remove the breakpoint that
we've had here on line 11 just click on
it click that in the gutter to turn it
off and I've set a java field watch point
in the chars added variable as you can
see here on line 8 and that's going to
click on that again to show something
here so click on that again because it's
two different ways to showing
this and depending which option you
select one will be selected so click on this
one here on line 8 holding alt that should
work for both the pc and mac right to
take it off I just click it without
holding down alt that turns it off we're
going back to our menu our run menu
click on View breakpoints click on +
select java field watch point
select the class string utilities and
the name of the instance variable field
chars added click on OK click on OK
again
see that's added here and when we're
done we can see that added to this area
here as well now this is the way it's
set up with this little dash and this
basically means any time that chars
added the field is modified the program
will automatically break not sure what
happened there I might have accidentally
click that
so any time that it's actually modified
what we can do is hold down alt again and
right click here we get this little menu
and we've got a couple of different
options here so we can actually set the
watch to be anytime the field is
accessed as opposed to modification
modification usually be the one that you
you checking but in any event you can
select either click on done but also
want to show you by coming over here
clicking on alt and right-click again
there's another option here when we
click on more and that it will automatically
open up the view breakpoints window with
that variable that's been defined we can
also click on here remove once hit if we
click on that remove once hit click on
done what happened there is that the
first time the variable is accessed it
will break and then after that point
that point onwards it actually won't
break so if we just click on right click
that again we can see now that I've done
that we've got this removed once hit and
my IntelliJ seems to be playing up a
little bit because what should have
happened at that point is that what we
should have seen a little one showing
their indicating that it was only going
to be a watch point once and then it
would turn itself off automatically
so lets actually just try running this
in to see what happens i'm going to work
resume and see what happened there I
resumed and it only allowed me to
resume once and then you can see the
other program actually finished in other
words the watch point come into effect
once and that first time we've got a
break when that chars added variables
change that field for the first time and
from that point on it then went through
and allowed to program to exit in some
scenarios you may only
want that to happen you may want to break
just the first time of a variable
values changed but their can also be
other scenarios where you want to change
each time we come back and add that
break point again just doing an alt click
again now where it wasn't
doing that before now it's actually
working
that's the one that I was trying to show
you earlier in the video and it it might
be that we have to debug at least
once from perhaps for that to happen but
in any event this what i wanted to show you so
the one there is going to do that to
remove once hit so if I
hold down alt right-clicking again you can
see how that's not showing in this menu
or if you go back and check the earlier
this video wasn't showing so that's the
case where it's only going to show
or its only going to break once the
variables change for the first time we
can take that off if we want we click on done
and the little icon changes that
little dash and the dash means that each
time the variable the variable is
changed in value its going to break so
let's actually test this by debugging
this again so what i'm going to do as you can see
the first time we've gotta break their
i'm just gonna click on resume and
clicking on resume you notice how
each time clicking on resume once it's
breaking at that point that's because
this has been specified to be anywhere
in the code with that particular field
is changed in value
it's going to break it so that can be
really handy if you're trying to figure
out how this variable how this field
actually got updated you might have
quite a complex class and you can't
figure it out
that's what you do to actually set it up
so again you can come here and alt right
click and notice now that
we've actually remove that checkpoint we
can't add it again here from this screen
we can click on more if we wanted to
remove once hit click on done you have
to set it up that way
probably not a good idea to be doing
that during debugging session but i'll
try working in and we'll just confirm
that it works you can see that i click
once and click again and then the watch
point automatically got deactivated
alright so again we just hold down alt
and click you get the one there which is
should have happened I'm not
sure why it didn't happen earlier in the
video and that would be when the value
changes once
the program will then break and we can
just confirm that by just a debugging
and resume never asks again as you can
see
alternatively I can do it alt click i
can do an alt right click click on the remove
once hit
click on done I can debug again and then
i can just resume each time to track
any time that the field is
actually change in value
alright so what I'm shown
you is probably the features that will
be used that you use for debugging
probably 99% of the time there's a
lot we can do but setting breakpoints
and watch points are really what we do
the most but i want to touch on a few
more things so let's start working on
those things in the next video