Continuing on from our generic
class from the last video, so
we actually started this code.
We didn't actually run it.
So I'll just run it now.
Just to confirm that we've actually
got the right number of players,
we should get the answer three cuz
we've actually added three there.
And you can see we've
got the answer three.
But it does actually bring
up interesting issue.
There's an obvious problem
which I started talking about.
And that's that the first time in this
case, our baseball player, and that's Pat,
the first time he actually runs onto the
field and tries to hit the football with
his bat, he's probably gonna be
red carded and sent off the field.
So in other words,
our team class is actually allowing this
to add any kind of player to the team and
there's no actual check to see whether
they're the correct type of player.
Cuz obviously in the case of the Adelaide
Crows, we've decided that that's
a football team so there should be
some way of ensuring that only people,
only players who are football
players can be added to that team.
And likewise for a baseball player,
only baseball players should be able to
be added to a team for that baseball,
and likewise for soccer.
So we need some sort of mechanism to
actually make sure that happens so
that only the right types of
players can be added to teams.
Now there's a few solutions to this.
One solution would be to create three
different team classes, so in other words,
a football team, a baseball team and
a soccer team are three
different classes and ensure that they
only accept the correct player type.
But in that case,
the code's gonna be largely identical.
So we're gonna be duplicating code and
it's usually never an efficient way to
code to actually duplicate codes so
I don't recommend that.
And of course that's not to say we
couldn't extend the team class to create
three different team types within there,
so
sort of have sort of private classes for
each of those team types.
But then if we did that, we need to
implement functionality that's unique
to each team type in that code as well.
So a common code to do
things like add a player,
play a game, record a score et cetera
would be in the base team class.
But fortunately, Java's got generics,
which we're talking about
obviously in this section.
And it enables to really specify
type when we're creating our class.
And this is exactly what we want here.
So what we wanna do is modify
team to be a generic class.
So let's go ahead and actually do that,
and we'll see that working.
So we're gonna go to our team class.
We're gonna come up here.
We're gonna start making
some changes to it.
So at the moment, obviously,
it's accepting a generic player there.
This is in the array list.
Also in the addPlayer method.
So let's actually make some changes.
First so we're going to modify the class
declaration to include the top parameter.
So to do that, we use a diamond as we did
before but we put a T in the middle and
that's to indicate that
there's gonna be a type there.
We also come down here to ArrayList and
we do a similar thing.
So instead of player we delete that and
make that T as well.
T was all can see it comes up,
and IntelliJ comes up and
says this is a type parameter of
com.timbuchalka.t, which is correct.
And the third area you wanna change is our
addPlayer, so instead of allowing a player
class, we're basically adding the type
parameter again for addPlayer.
So again we're changing the type so
we can make this more generic and
it's going to work for any type of player.
And how this basically works is when we
actually instantiate a class the T will be
replaced automatically by Java
with the actual class we're using,
with the real type in other words when
we're actually instantiating the class.
And that's why we've actually
changed the addPlayer and
the ArrayList as well, so
all three changed so that we can actually,
we're able to actually do
that sort of type checking.
So notice that we're actually
getting an error in our player.
And the reason is that we
specify that its type is T,
which is a parameterized
type as we've said before.
And because this type's not known until
we actually instantiate a class in other
words at run time, there's actually no way
for Java to know that an object of type
T in this case really does
have a get nine method.
So the only sensible thing that
a compiler can do in this situation is to
flag an error which is actually
showing on the screen.
Now we can't get around that for
the moment.
So what we're going to do is we're gonna
cast player the player parameterize type
to make that a player type before
attempting to evoke its getName method.
So we're not gonna change
the parameter here.
We're going to actually change it
when we're actually referencing it.
So we're just gonna do this.
We're going to cast that to player
cuz we know ultimately it is going to
be a player object, like so.
We need to actually put two
brackets there for that to work.
Player and then put another bracket
there and that should fix that up.
And likewise with this one,
you need to the cast as well,
player, player and bracket to fix it.
And that fixes it as well.
Now it is a solution but
it's a pretty ugly cast,
in the sense that we're invoking
a method on a cast object and
we need parenthesis around the cast
before we can use getName.
But do not fear, it's only temporary,
very soon we can see.
I'll actually show you how you
can remove the need to do this.
But this is okay,
that's out of trouble for now.
Or yes working through our code.
So getting back to our main method now,
to our main class and
then to our main method, you can see that
there's actually no errors at the moment.
But if we actually have a look at some of
these warnings, we're getting an uncheck
call to add player T as a member
of raw type com.timbuchalka.team.
So I talked about raw types in
the previous video and what they were and
how to get around them and you also
saw why we shouldn't be using them.
So with that said the program is still
going to run, but poor old pat will still
be given a red card, so in other words
we're not validating the type of player.
It gives the particular type of team.
But we can actually fix that quite easily
by specifying what type of team our
football team variable should be.
So team now has the ability to
accept the type of argument.
That's what we've just
changed in the team class.
So what we have to do
is provide it with one.
So we're gonna go back to our
declaration for the adelaideCrows.
We're gonna change that.
So we're gonna add
the type argument to that.
That's going to be FootballPlayer.
So once we've done that, we still actually
got an error here, unchecked assignment,
because what we haven't done is
we haven't added the diamond.
So we need to add
the diamond after the team.
Now they're actually using it to
the left in the declaration section, so
I'm going to put the diamond in there now,
and that now removes that error.
So we've got a proper assignment
about generic class now.
So we've actually indicated that we're
gonna be using the FootballPlayer, and
there's a sequence that during that
you can see now Joe was added.
And the reason that Joe was valid and it's
not telling us that there's a problem is
that he was assigned as a football player.
But in here, the other two, Pat and
Beckham, cuz our baseball players and
soccer players, that ain't meet
the criteria for this top now,
and it's actually being
flagged as an error.
So it's actually an error
not just a warning.
It's telling us that it physically can't
add those to this class anymore based on
the definition.
So in other words this particular
instance of team is now only going to
accept football players and
attempts to add Pat and Beckham,
and there was showing [INAUDIBLE].
So let's give good old
Pat a chance to shine.
So what we're going to do is we're
gonna accommodate these first, tab,
get rid of those.
And let's actually add another class.
We're gonna call it team BaseballPlayer.
We'll call it baseballTeam.
I'll get rid of player team,
we'll call it baseballTeam = new Team.
Yeah, we need to add the diamonds if we're
actually using that on the left-hand side
which we are for your type assignment and
that's the type of team like Chicago Cubs
which is a baseball team in America,
for those who don't know.
And we can now successfully do
baseballTeam.addPlayer(pat).
Now that will work quite nicely,
because again Pat is,
he's been defined up here
as a baseball player.
He's a type baseball player, and
we've defined that as the team of being of
type baseball player, so consequently he's
able to be added without any problems.
But with that said,
there's still some problems here.
And at the moment, the top parameter T,
in our team class can be applied,
can be supplied rather, any type,
except primitive types such as int, so
in other words, any object.
So we're not doing any validation of that.
So we can actually do something like,
for example,
Team brokenTeam = new Team.
And this might work
which it won't work and
if we do something like
brokenTeam.addPlayer,
no-one, the string's in valid type.
And as you can see,
there's no compilation errors.
We're just getting a warning up here,
because Beckham's actually
not in use at the moment.
But the problem with this is, is gonna be
the cast when we actually go to run this.
So if we actually run this code
we actually get an exception.
An exception has got to do with the fact
that java.lang.String cannot be cast to
com.timbuchalka.Player.
And of course if you remember
going back to our team class,
we actually defined that in here.
We actually added this ugly cast
to get the .getName to work.
So what we really need is some sort of way
to validate the type of class actually
when we're using it for this team.
So in other words, we need the ability to
restrict the type that can be provided for
this T argument from the T
from the team blast.
Now the good thing about that is that
Java also provides a mechanism for
restricting the types that can
be used as type arguments.
They actually call these
bounded type parameters.
By using those you can provide
them with an upper bound.
So I'm gonna explain these terms and more
data once we've seen them in action, but
let's actually change the declaration
of our team class first, and
then we'll go through it.
So at the moment we've got team, and
then we've got the type in diamond,
as you can see there.
But we can actually change
this to put extends Player,
noting that I'm actually
typing it within the diamond.
So T extends player now.
If you go back now to our main class, cuz
we've done that we're now actually getting
an error here and
notice it's not a warning.
It's actually an error to say
java.lang.String is not within its bound.
It should extend com.timbuchalka.Player,
so that's our way of actually
restricting the type of class that
we can actually use for team.
Now just wrapping that up again, so
basically what we've said is that we've
told Java that the type parameter we'll
accept for this class when using generics,
is gonna be any type that extends
from player or subclass of player.
So in other words by typing it like
this with this extends Player,
Player is set to be the upper bound of T.
And of course T as I've mentioned
earlier is a bounded type parameter.
So if we attempt to use any class in other
words that is not derived from Player,
we're gonna get that error which
was seen here in main now.
And as a consequence of that
cuz we've actually done that,
the good news is we can go back to
our code again, go back to team,
and we can actually get rid of this cast.
So we can actually remove that and
go back to what it was before
which is just player.getName.
So I'm gonna do that, like so.
And for the next one.
And again the reason why I want to do
that is because of the bounded top
parameter we've put up here,
we've said that all valid upper bounds
of T have to extend from players.
Or as a consequence Java then knows that,
okay,
so in other words Java now knows that the
top T in that player extends from player.
So it's gonna have all its methods
including getName of player.
So basically there's no longer
an error and there's no need for
you to actually add that cast anymore.
Now going back to our main method again,
so
let's actually change now this team here.
We're at the moment the brokenTeam
to be a soccer team, so
we can type SoccerPlayer,
brokenTeam = new Team, this won't work.
And notice how it's still
going to come up okay.
We've defined a new team even
though we haven't changed the name.
But the important part here is this next
declaration is brokenTeam.addPlayer,
we're passing the string.
Java's also showing an error for
that when we try to pass
a string to the addPlayer method.
And again this is exactly what we want
because we've defined the addPlayer method
and the class to require us to use the
player class or a subclass of player and
obviously string isn't there and
that's why we're actually seeing an error.
So if we actually replace that string
with our soccer player Beckham we
actually see that the error goes away,
and we've got a tick in the top
right-hand corner and no warnings either.
So before going on to
the challenge in the next video
just wanna discuss a few other points.
Firstly an argument passed for
a type parameter can either be a class or
an interface.
So you can actually use
interfaces as well.
So although we use the player
of class in these examples,
this is going back to team.
We use the player class there.
You could've declared team to
accept an interface instead.
And that's certainly
valid to do that in Java.
And the other thing to note is that
interfaces themselves can also
specify type parameters.
So in other words you can create instances
of a class that implement an interface,
and then you can ensure that
the interface methods you implement
act on a specific type of object or
objects.
And we've seen that in previous examples
when we used the list string for
example, this was an interface that
takes a generic type parameter.
And the usage is the same as it is for
class.
Now we also used a single bound when
we specify the team top parameter, so
restricting teams to being created for
objects that we'll inherit from the player
class or some class of player only.
Now Java does allow multiple bounds,
although say you can have class T extends
Player in coach and manager, for example,
to allow multiple instances of player
coach or manager to be added to the team.
But with that in mind, the normal
inheritance implements rules still apply.
So in other words, you can only
extend from the single class but
multiple interfaces.
So basically if you wanna do this with
more than one class you'll need to use
interfaces for those other types as well.
And the other thing to keep in mind is
if you're specifying multiple bounds,
then the class must be listed first cuz
otherwise Java's gonna raise an error
when you try to actually compile it.
In other words class first and
then interfaces.
And the way you do that just briefly
we're not gonna actually add the code.
They'll enable you put something like &
Coach, & Manager for argument's sake.
That would be the syntax
you would actually use.
But obviously you can only have one class,
so
these two here with this scenario
will actually have to be interfaces.
So I just wanna confirm that that is
actually the syntax if you're wanting to
use multiple bounds.
So you put the player,
in this case the class first,
then you actually put the interfaces
after that if you wanted to do that.
Obviously, we're not doing
that in this example so
I'm going to actually remove those.
And obviously in the case of moddable
types, you have to then include code to
check what type of objects you're dealing
with before in breaking these methods,
because it wouldn't be just in this case
just the one class which was player and
we need a little more code
to actually to do that.
And finally SoccerPlayer and
also FootballPlayer are both some
classes of player as we know.
So obviously there is
a relationship between them, so
either can be used when calling a method
that expects a player for example.
But the important thing here to remember
is that there's no relationship between
something like this.
So if you'd look at the list manager,
List,
and List,
now I'll just add those even though we're
not gonna do anything more with them.
So there's basically no relationship
in this case between those two.
And the reason is because neither of
them are a subtype of this player.
I do have a common parent, but
the common parent in this case is List.
So I hope that makes sense.
The bottom line is for a code,
probably a lot of the time with generics,
you'll probably be doing something like
this where you'll only be extending or
using one class and maybe an interface.
But if you do need to use multiple bounds,
you'll need to specify the ampersand and
then obviously also
the interfaces as well.
And just one more thing we need to look at
before we actually get to the challenge,
so the team class has got fields, check
how many games were won, tied or lost, but
we haven't actually made use of them yet.
So we do include a match result method.
So let's make some calls
on it now in main,
just to record the game results
before we discuss the method ball.
So I'm just going to actually copy and
paste some code here.
And we'll go back to main, paste this team
in, paste this code and it should say,
like so.
And you're gonna change
that to adelaideCrows.
Then I'm also gonna go
adelaideCrows.matchResult.
And I'm gonna type fremantle, 2, 1,
and adelaideCrows.matchResult,
.matchResult(baseballTeam, 1, 1).
So, if we actually run that, basically
it does seem to be doing something but
we're not actually getting
a lot of feedback from it.
Now, the matchResult method,
if we go back to that and have a look,
you can see that it does actually take
a team object called opponent and
two ints which is our score and
their score.
If our score is greater than their
score and then we've won, so we've won,
as incremented as you can
see in this code here.
Similarly for tied and lost,
we actually go through that process.
The scores are equal, tied,
otherwise we indicate that it's lost.
And that takes care of the team
that matchResult's called from, but
the opponent also needs
its fields updating.
And that's why we've actually
got this additional call here.
So we do that by invoking the opponent's
matchResult method as well.
And this time obviously we're passing
null for the opponent argument.
And only when invoking the opponent's
matchResult method, if opponent is not
null, otherwise it would end up calling
the matchResult of the first team again,
on and on and on again.
We'll get into an infinite loop.
So let's actually just print and
aug message here so
we'll put something like this, just to so
we've got a bit more feedback.
We'll add a variable
called the message string.
Message, and let's set that up
to be message = beat, if a tied,
we're gonna add message = whoops,
drew with, and
last message = lost to, like so.
And if opponent is not equal to null we're
actually gonna put the result there so
we're gonna put System.out, this.getName,
+ message, + opponent.getName.
Just so we've got that bit
of output on the screen.
And notice here that we're also
only printing the message for
the initial team, so we're doing that
test for its null equal to null.
This makes sense, but because we're
printing the name of the opponent,
we get an error if we take this part
of the message outside of the check for
opponent be null.
So let's actually run this.
And you see we're getting some output now.
And drew, we've got a problem there
with the way that I've typed in drew.
I need to put a space there.
So I'll go back to there and run it again.
And you can see it seems we're
getting better feedback now.
Hawthorn beat Fremantle.
Hawthorn lost to Adelaide Crows.
Adelaide Crows beat Fremantle.
Adelaide Crows drew with Chicago Cubs.
Now, can you spot a problem
with matchResult yet?
So the Adelaide Crows drew
against the Chicago Cubs.
What's going on there?
But the Adelaide Crows played football,
and of course Cubs played baseball.
So that's rather an odd match result.
So what we really wanna do here is make
sure that only the correct team type
can be passed to the matchResult
method as well, yeah, and
sort of any object of type team.
So you can probably figure
out how to do that now.
So if we go back to our code again and
I'll just bring up the project window
again and close down a run window.
Go back to team again.
So we need to do something in here.
We can probably figure out what we
need to do to make sure that happens.
We need to make use of its generic type
essentially which we haven't been doing.
So we're gonna change that to use
the generic type which we've defined for
this class.
So now if we do that and go back to our
main method, it should say we're now
correctly getting this error,
and saying that Adelaide Crows,
well it's best to only be using football
players cuz that's how we've defined
the Adelaide Crows up here as
to be of team football player.
So Java's quite correctly indicating
that it's now a compile time error.
So this video's gone on for long enough.
So what I'm going to do
is stop the video here.
In the next video we'll continue on, and
we'll just finish off a few other things
to do with the way we've set this up.
And then we'll move on to the challenge.
So, I'll see you in that next video.