So all videos in this course have been uploaded in 1080P
which is the highest quality format
that Udemy currently accept for videos.
So that's the good news, the bad news is that sometimes
Udemy's video player seems to blur
the videos a little bit.
But the good news again, back to the good news,
is that usually this is a temporary problem
and can be overcome by coming down here
and clicking on the little cog
and choosing a resolution.
A 720P is the best one to choose normally
if you haven't got the auto option.
But if you have got the auto option,
select that because that will give you 1080P,
and that's if Udemy's video player dictates
that your internet speed is fast enough.
So keep in mind that if you do experience blurriness
to try that, but also keep in mind that sometimes
the blurriness will just happen for the first few seconds
for a video and then disappear and playback
in a higher quality format.
And you've probably seen that happen in YouTube as well
where it will start streaming in a lower resolution
and then get back up to a higher quality.
Bottom line is that for most students,
they seem to have no problems playing it but,
playing in the highest quality.
But if you do see an issue just have
a bit fiddle with those settings
and you find that you'll be able to play those videos
in the highest quality.
Thank you for watching, let's move on now to the next video.