in this video we'll start by taking a
whirlwind tour of a few javafx features
that we haven't touched on yet in that
section of the course we're going to
learn how to do a couple of things that
most client applications will
typically want to do we're gonna start
with styling controls using CSS now
we've already done this in a previous
lecture we added a border to control so
that we can see it better within a
layout but we didn't really discuss it
or explain the power of using CSS to
style controls let's start by creating a
new project so i'm going to click on the
create new project we're going to
select javafx click on next
i'm going to call this one javafx
application and click on finish
give us a bit more room here
alright so going to start by
changing our fxml file and what
we're going to do here is we're going to
add some buttons....
...
no surprises there it's actually working
well alright so let's now change the
background color of button 1 to green and
the text color to white now we could set
the text color by setting the buttons
text field property since button if you
recall descends from the labeled class
let's actually try doing this with
or using CSS and for the background color
already seen that we have to use CSS to
change that we've done that previously
let's go back to our fxml file for button
one and will add....
...
...so if we run this
application we should see the background
green text on white so that's working
nicely so be nice if we can actually
just quickly do that so all the buttons
in the application try to look the
same
let's try changing button 2 so we
could do something similar button 2 we
can literally just copy the same code
just replace that line...
....
obviously we can do that change the
second one run it again
no surprises there we should see the
second button has now got the same color
scheme or the same style so it would be
nice if we could do this to all the
buttons in our application so they look
the same
now obviously we can just set the style
for the remaining three buttons you can
just come back and do the equivalent
thing here in the sample dot fxml file
to make the buttons three four and five
look the same but think about scenario
where your applications perhaps got
hundreds of buttons and whatever have
lots of Windows and dialogues each defined
in their own fxml file imagine
having to go through three literally
every fxml file to find every button
and then adding the style properly to it
and worse imagine that we didn't do it
we actually spent consider
amount of time we change the buttons so
they will have a green background and
white text but then our manager or a client
change their mind and decided that no
we don't want green we want
our buttons in fact to
have a blue background
you then have to go back and change the
fxml for every button all
over again so that would be a bit of a
nightmare but fortunately there's a way
to style all the buttons in our
application without having to add the
style property to every single
button we can actually put our styles
into a separate file just as we can with
the CSS for a webpage so let's actually
add a CSS file now what we need to do is
just to open up our project pane need to
make sure that this is expanded we're in
sample we want to actually put it in the
sample package so click on sample click
on file new the new file i'm going to
call this file that we're creating
styles.css just
close the bottom window so you see up
here just with a little icon that
intellij does recognize that this is a
CSS file based on the file extension so
okay we want all our buttons in our
application to have a green background
and white text now in CSS we can use a
selector to specify what we want to
style when we wanted to find a style for
all the buttons on our application we
use the dot button selector because we
want to style all instances of the
button class so going to assign the
properties within a set of curly braces
and separate the property and value with
a colon just as we did in the fxml
so let's go ahead and do
that bearing in mind that each properly
assignment in CSS ends with a semicolon
so we'll start with...
....
...
alright so now we've created the styles
. CSS file we need to associate that
file with our application
so we do that in the fxml file will come
back here to our sample .fxml
and clear up some of these imports
that we added automatically but aren't
being used at the moment
alright so we do it in the fxml files
as I mentioned using the stylesheet properly
and actually put that up here in our grid
pane so we're going to come down here
...
....
alright so let's now run the app and
...
just make sure that it works now and you
alright so let's now run the app and
can see all five buttons have been
just make sure that it works now and you
styled based on the how we defined
can see all five buttons have been
that in the styles . CSS file so
styled based on the how we defined
hopefully getting an idea and seeing how
that in the styles . CSS file so
CSS makes it much easier to change the
hopefully getting an idea and seeing how
entire appearance of an application
CSS makes it much easier to change the
rather than having to manually sort of
entire appearance of an application
go through and do each element which
rather than having to manually sort of
would be a rather painful exercise and
go through and do each element which
turns out in fact that our applications
would be a rather painful exercise and
been using CSS behind-the-scenes all
turns out in fact that our applications
along and that's because javafx uses a
been using CSS behind-the-scenes all
default style sheet to style javafx
along and that's because javafx uses a
applications now obviously this is not a
default style sheet to style javafx
CSS course I can't go into a lot of
applications now obviously this is not a
detail with CSS but you are familiar
CSS course I can't go into a lot of
with web development or software like
detail with CSS but you are familiar
wordpress you probably know that you
with web development or software like
can change the appearance of a website
wordpress you probably know that you
by changing its theme sometimes called a
can change the appearance of a website
template so a theme is simply a set of CSS
by changing its theme sometimes called a
definitions javafx uses themes and the
template so a theme is simply a set of CSS
default theme is the medina theme in a
definitions javafx uses themes and the
minute we going to see how to change to
default theme is the medina theme in a
another theme provided by javafx
minute we going to see how to change to
but first looking at to our was sample
another theme provided by javafx
.fxml let's consider what we'd
but first looking at to our was sample
do if we want button 3 in our
.fxml let's consider what we'd
application to have a blue background
do if we want button 3 in our
now it's obviously can come down here
application to have a blue background
and actually try to make a change to
now it's obviously can come down here
that style
and actually try to make a change to
and we can put...
that style
....
and we can put...
...if you run
....
that we can see that works the buttons
...if you run
button three now got a blue background
that we can see that works the buttons
and white text and that's because when
button three now got a blue background
the CSS is included in the fxml
and white text and that's because when
within a control element or in line in
the CSS is included in the fxml
other words it takes precedence over the
within a control element or in line in
CSS in the style sheet so in other words
other words it takes precedence over the
it overrides the definition in the style
CSS in the style sheet so in other words
sheet in a similar way to how the
it overrides the definition in the style
overriding a method works in Java as
sheet in a similar way to how the
we talk about in the course but with that said
overriding a method works in Java as
defining CSS in line generally isn't
we talk about in the course but with that said
recommended if we decided to change the
defining CSS in line generally isn't
background color of button 3 to yellow
recommended if we decided to change the
we then have to change in the fxml file
background color of button 3 to yellow
again this would be trivial for small
we then have to change in the fxml file
application like this one but in a
again this would be trivial for small
larger application we might not actually
application like this one but in a
know that the style and the style sheet
larger application we might not actually
has been overridden in the fxml file and
know that the style and the style sheet
we might try to set the color for button 3
has been overridden in the fxml file and
in the style sheet which will see how to
we might try to set the color for button 3
do in a minute and wonder why it's not
in the style sheet which will see how to
working and also it could be that
do in a minute and wonder why it's not
another developer is not familiar with
working and also it could be that
the code that has to make the change and
another developer is not familiar with
that they would actually look at the
the code that has to make the change and
style sheet first
that they would actually look at the
so generally again in lining these
style sheet first
styles isn't recommended so go back
so generally again in lining these
to our sample fxml file instead of
styles isn't recommended so go back
styling button 3 in line we can
to our sample fxml file instead of
actually do it in the stylesheet now
styling button 3 in line we can
this time we won't use a cart class
actually do it in the stylesheet now
selector because we don't want every
this time we won't use a cart class
button instance in our application to
selector because we don't want every
have a blue background instead we can
button instance in our application to
use an ID selector so first thing we
have a blue background instead we can
need to do is assign an ID to the button
use an ID selector so first thing we
this case button three let's go back to
need to do is assign an ID to the button
do that so here we're going to put...
this case button three let's go back to
...
do that so here we're going to put...
...and just a
...
note here not we're not assigning the
...and just a
fx colon ID which we do when we
note here not we're not assigning the
want to reference a control in our
fx colon ID which we do when we
control in our controller this is an
want to reference a control in our
id which is a different which is
control in our controller this is an
different to that completely
id which is a different which is
alright and you notice that I also
different to that completely
remove the in-line style definition
alright and you notice that I also
so next we go back to our styles
remove the in-line style definition
. CSS file I'm going to make a change
so next we go back to our styles
here instead of it being .
. CSS file I'm going to make a change
button I will delete that will make that
here instead of it being .
...
button I will delete that will make that
everything else actually remains the same other
...
than the fact here going to change
everything else actually remains the same other
from green to blue now when referring to
than the fact here going to change
an id we're using a hash character in case your
from green to blue now when referring to
wondering why i have used to hash their
an id we're using a hash character in case your
so that relates to the the id that we
wondering why i have used to hash their
specified here so the style sheet would
so that relates to the the id that we
know which basically which control this
specified here so the style sheet would
case to override alright so let's
know which basically which control this
actually try running that and we can see
case to override alright so let's
now that the button 3 has got a
actually try running that and we can see
blue background and better that is still
now that the button 3 has got a
an all-out styling is in a style sheet
blue background and better that is still
and that's going to make changing the
an all-out styling is in a style sheet
style is much easier in the future
and that's going to make changing the
because we go straight to the styles
style is much easier in the future
. CSS file for making our changes
because we go straight to the styles
alright so that's the basics of styling
. CSS file for making our changes
our application using CSS now we can also
alright so that's the basics of styling
style controls within the java code by
our application using CSS now we can also
calling the appropriate methods using
style controls within the java code by
the instances we want to style but i'll
calling the appropriate methods using
leave that as an exercise for you
the instances we want to style but i'll
because generally speaking you probably
leave that as an exercise for you
don't want to do that very often
because generally speaking you probably
now to find out what selectors to use
don't want to do that very often
when styling java fx controls check
now to find out what selectors to use
the javafx ccs says documentation and
when styling java fx controls check
i'm just going to copy link and i'm
the javafx ccs says documentation and
going to just open it up so you can take
i'm just going to copy link and i'm
a look at that at your leisure
going to just open it up so you can take
so there's the page
a look at that at your leisure
there's a lot of information you can
so there's the page
find out about CSS how it relates to
there's a lot of information you can
javafx controls on this page so i
find out about CSS how it relates to
suggest you check it out and looking
javafx controls on this page so i
through here to spend a bit of time
suggest you check it out and looking
through there you'll actually find out
through here to spend a bit of time
that you can also style layouts and other
through there you'll actually find out
javafx elements but there's actually
that you can also style layouts and other
advanced features which you won't be
javafx elements but there's actually
going into this section now before we
advanced features which you won't be
leave see css though let's go back
going into this section now before we
to our code and change the appearance by
leave see css though let's go back
changing the theme and what I'll do you saw all
to our code and change the appearance by
those programs are running their so
changing the theme and what I'll do you saw all
stop some of those probably should close
those programs are running their so
this down before
stop some of those probably should close
ok so how do we do this how do we change the
this down before
appearance of our application by changing
ok so how do we do this how do we change the
the entire theme now I mentioned theirs
appearance of our application by changing
a medina is the default theme use
the entire theme now I mentioned theirs
by javafx but we can also use the
a medina is the default theme use
Caspian theme that's provided also by
by javafx but we can also use the
javafx and to do that we actually go
Caspian theme that's provided also by
back to our main start up here and what
javafx and to do that we actually go
we need to do is use the set user agent
back to our main start up here and what
stylesheet method to actually
we need to do is use the set user agent
activate this particular style sheet we
stylesheet method to actually
want to do that right under this parent
activate this particular style sheet we
root so we would type...
want to do that right under this parent
...
root so we would type...
alright so let's actually run this but
...
bearing in mind that the changes when
alright so let's actually run this but
we run it is going to be very subtle because the
bearing in mind that the changes when
interface is actually so simple at this stage
we run it is going to be very subtle because the
so you can see there that i'm not sure
interface is actually so simple at this stage
you've noticed but size it up
so you can see there that i'm not sure
a little bit but the button corners
you've noticed but size it up
are more rounded when we use the Caspian
a little bit but the button corners
theme then when we used the medina theme
are more rounded when we use the Caspian
so let's just try adding a radio button
theme then when we used the medina theme
to our layout in the second row so we can
so let's just try adding a radio button
maybe get a better idea what this is
to our layout in the second row so we can
going to look like going back to our
maybe get a better idea what this is
samples and we'll add the radio button
going to look like going back to our
on the next line the next row so text
samples and we'll add the radio button
here
on the next line the next row so text
...
here
...so let's have a look and
...
see what that looks like
...so let's have a look and
alright so that shows you again what
see what that looks like
this caspian theme or style
alright so that shows you again what
sheet looks like what we do
this caspian theme or style
we'll run this again but i'll actually
sheet looks like what we do
leave that running so we can actually
we'll run this again but i'll actually
compare the two themes and come back
leave that running so we can actually
here and actually comment out the setting
compare the two themes and come back
so we can see what they both look like so we
here and actually comment out the setting
run that again
so we can see what they both look like so we
ok now we've got the two side by side so
run that again
you can see that there is a difference
ok now we've got the two side by side so
that in also in the background color
you can see that there is a difference
which may be different if you're running
that in also in the background color
on windows or linux compared to me
which may be different if you're running
running on the mac but definitely you
on windows or linux compared to me
can see the buttons certainly on this
running on the mac but definitely you
side here over here with the Caspian style sheet
can see the buttons certainly on this
they're much more rounded so
side here over here with the Caspian style sheet
close it down we go back to the code
they're much more rounded so
again you might be asking why we setting
close it down we go back to the code
the style sheet through code rather than
again you might be asking why we setting
associating it with our
the style sheet through code rather than
application in the fxml file
associating it with our
well in this particular case we're
application in the fxml file
setting the theme for the entire
well in this particular case we're
application so the theme stylesheet will
setting the theme for the entire
apply to every window and dialogue in
application so the theme stylesheet will
control without having to specifically
apply to every window and dialogue in
add it to every fxml file so we can
control without having to specifically
override the themes style definitions by
add it to every fxml file so we can
adding stylesheets to fxml file or
override the themes style definitions by
using inline CSS so here's the order of
adding stylesheets to fxml file or
precedence so inline CSS takes
using inline CSS so here's the order of
precedence over the fxml style sheet
precedence so inline CSS takes
which in turn takes precedence over the
precedence over the fxml style sheet
applications theme style sheet in fact
which in turn takes precedence over the
when we've been changing our control
applications theme style sheet in fact
looks by using CSS by assigning a
when we've been changing our control
property in the fXML what we've actually
looks by using CSS by assigning a
been doing is overriding the default
property in the fXML what we've actually
setting defined by the theme we're using
been doing is overriding the default
for the application so note that when we
setting defined by the theme we're using
set a CSS property by calling
for the application so note that when we
methods in our java code the value we
set a CSS property by calling
set will override any existing value
methods in our java code the value we
for that properly
set will override any existing value
now if you search the web you find
for that properly
themes that can be used in javafx
now if you search the web you find
applications the set user agent style sheet
themes that can be used in javafx
method that we call on line
applications the set user agent style sheet
fourteen accept a URL parameter so all
method that we call on line
we have to do is provide the URL of the
fourteen accept a URL parameter so all
stylesheet that contains all the style
we have to do is provide the URL of the
definitions for the theme of course you
stylesheet that contains all the style
can also start writing your own themes
definitions for the theme of course you
and using them within your
can also start writing your own themes
applications as well
and using them within your
alright so that's it with our whirldwind
applications as well
tour of CSS in the next video we're going to
alright so that's it with our whirldwind
start taking a look at transforming
tour of CSS in the next video we're going to
nodes and see you in the next video
start taking a look at transforming