alright so let's now start taking a look
at transforming nodes now javafx allows
us to transform nodes in the scene graph
which means we can do things like we're
take them
zoom in on them animate them and also
apply other effects
let's start by adding a label to our ui so
go back to a sample . fXML file so gonna
add that below the radio button we
added so its going to label....
...
...just to confirm
will run it to make sure the label
showing alright there's our label showing java
fx effects bit of a mouthful so close
it down and let's now zoom in on that
label by calling the labels set scale X
and set scale y methods we're going to
add an ID to the labels so we can do
that so label text equals javafx
elements and it's going to be...
....go to our
controller dot java file and we need to
first create an instance or add an instance
variable for the label so...
....
...
let's just run this to confirm this work
that it does work there it is all
be it not fitting where it was before
but it's definitely zoomed-in now so
typically wouldn't do that when the
application first runs well actually
zoom in and out in response to some user
interaction for example we might want to
zoom in when the user roles their mouse
button while the cursor is over the
label or perhaps when the user hovers
over the label let's actually do the
later so when the user hovers over the
label we scale it up so that do that we
need to add an event listener that
listens form mouse enter and
mouse exit events when the cursor enters
the label we're going to zoom in
on it and when the cursor exits the
label zoom out so let's go and have a
look at doing that so close down back to
the controller so will delete the
code of the initialize method and
instead we're going to do is create
these two events or event
handlers to be more precise
...
..
....so we've
...
created event handlers we need to
....so we've
associate those event handlers with the
created event handlers we need to
label in our fxml file so let's go ahead
associate those event handlers with the
and do that and with the way we can do
label in our fxml file so let's go ahead
that is just to come down here and
and do that and with the way we can do
put....
that is just to come down here and
....
put....
...
....
ok alright let's try this and see now
...
if it's going to work so we got our default
ok alright let's try this and see now
interface and if I hover over going
if it's going to work so we got our default
into it zooms to double the
interface and if I hover over going
size as soon as I leave and move outside
into it zooms to double the
the area it actually goes back to the
size as soon as I leave and move outside
regular size again pretty cool
the area it actually goes back to the
now you might imagine doing this when
regular size again pretty cool
the user can't see details when the UI is
now you might imagine doing this when
in its default size and we want them to
the user can't see details when the UI is
have to zoom into other areas of the UI
in its default size and we want them to
that is of interest to them so apart of
have to zoom into other areas of the UI
zooming like this javafx also allows us
that is of interest to them so apart of
to rotate controls so lets actually try
zooming like this javafx also allows us
rotating the label 90 degrees and one
to rotate controls so lets actually try
way of doing that is back in the sample
rotating the label 90 degrees and one
. fXML and we can come down here
way of doing that is back in the sample
just start of the line and put rotate
. fXML and we can come down here
equals...
just start of the line and put rotate
...if you run that run
equals...
it you can see where labels looking now
...if you run that run
and this still works because the zoom
it you can see where labels looking now
in and zoom obviously is smart enough to
and this still works because the zoom
figure out that the text was rotated 90
in and zoom obviously is smart enough to
degrees and rotate it in place
figure out that the text was rotated 90
alright so moving on let's try adding a
degrees and rotate it in place
drop shadow to one of our buttons now
alright so moving on let's try adding a
we're going to do this using code
drop shadow to one of our buttons now
because fxml support for effects is
we're going to do this using code
sketchy as at the time that i'm
because fxml support for effects is
recording these videos now we can define
sketchy as at the time that i'm
a couple of the available effects in the
recording these videos now we can define
FXML using CSS but unfortunately not all
a couple of the available effects in the
of them so going to use the set effect
FXML using CSS but unfortunately not all
method here to set a drop shadow on the
of them so going to use the set effect
button and we're going to do that in the
method here to set a drop shadow on the
controller's initialized method we have
button and we're going to do that in the
to declare an instance variable for the
controller's initialized method we have
button in the controller first let's go
to declare an instance variable for the
back and do that
button in the controller first let's go
so we need a button it's going to be...
back and do that
...
so we need a button it's going to be...
....
...
alright so now when we run this we
should see our button 4 has got a
drop shadow you can see the drop shadow
around button 4 now if you want to
you can change the radius color and
other properties of the drop shadow by
setting its properties so quite a
a deal of
flexibility there doing things a
along those lines alright so that's
obviously only a very quick introduction
to transforming nodes to see all the
effects you can go to this link that i'm
going to take you to the browser now we
have it their it's got lots more details
about the various effects that you
can actually implement in your apps for
example i'm going to select one and have
a look it gives you an example code as
well to we'll see how to do things this
case a high-level effect that makes
broader portions of the input image
appear to glow based on a configurable
threshold
alright let's get back to IntelliJ
continue our look at some other features
of the javafx we're going to start
looking at the file chooser class now
it's a very rare client application that
doesn't offer some type of open and save
functionality
now fortunately the file chooser class
means we don't have to reinvent the
wheel and write these open and save
dialogues that's because the file
chooser class does everything we'll
need and in addition it can be
customized it doesn't descend from the
node class
so can't be added to the scene graph in
other words we can add it to layout but
that's okay because the file chooser ui
does everything we want hopefully
does everything that we want
there's no need to embed it in a window
with other UI elements is the point I'm
getting here getting at here
alright so let's actually try changing
buttons 1 text first go back to the sample
. fXML button1 going to change the text
there instead of saying button...
...
....
what we're going to do is we're going to call
...
this show open dialogue method which
what we're going to do is we're going to call
opens the show shows or shows the file chooser in open
this show open dialogue method which
mode but to do that we have to pass in a
opens the show shows or shows the file chooser in open
parent window for the file chooser so
mode but to do that we have to pass in a
what we have to do is go back to our
parent window for the file chooser so
simple . fXML we need to assign a
what we have to do is go back to our
fx ID to our grid pane so that
simple . fXML we need to assign a
we can achieve so coming back
fx ID to our grid pane so that
up here to our grid pane...
we can achieve so coming back
....
up here to our grid pane...
...go back to our
....
controller what we need to do add a
...go back to our
listener to the grid pane so...
controller what we need to do add a
...
listener to the grid pane so...
..
...
so let's actually do that and we run
..
it will just show you what this null
so let's actually do that and we run
does
it will just show you what this null
so firstly if we click on the Open
does
button here our file chooser does open
so firstly if we click on the Open
but if we click on the main window we
button here our file chooser does open
can still interact with it
but if we click on the main window we
in fact we can click on again and open a
can still interact with it
second dialog boxes as you can see here and
in fact we can click on again and open a
you can even close the main window and
second dialog boxes as you can see here and
the file chooser remains up an overall
you can even close the main window and
or both of them in this case which I'll just
the file chooser remains up an overall
cancel out there and clearly that's not
or both of them in this case which I'll just
something that we want its not a
cancel out there and clearly that's not
good way to create an application that
something that we want its not a
does that what we want the file chooser
good way to create an application that
to do or to be modal so that the user has
does that what we want the file chooser
to navigate to a file or cancel the
to do or to be modal so that the user has
dialogue before they can interact with
to navigate to a file or cancel the
the main window again so that's the
dialogue before they can interact with
reason that we're passing the main
the main window again so that's the
window as the parent and by doing that
reason that we're passing the main
we should actually get the behavior we
window as the parent and by doing that
want here so if we go back to the
we should actually get the behavior we
controller we changed null now we
want here so if we go back to the
change that...
controller we changed null now we
...so run this app
change that...
again click open theirs our dialog box and notice
...so run this app
when I'm clicking on that i'm clicking but I
again click open theirs our dialog box and notice
can't get access to it I can't move this at all
when I'm clicking on that i'm clicking but I
it's actually completely modal so we
can't get access to it I can't move this at all
have to actually make an operation
it's actually completely modal so we
select a file or alternatively click on
have to actually make an operation
cancel to go back to the window again so
select a file or alternatively click on
we can only open one file chooser as
cancel to go back to the window again so
well and noticing also that the close
we can only open one file chooser as
button was deactivated on the main hello
well and noticing also that the close
world window we can't literally do
button was deactivated on the main hello
anything there until we've actually
world window we can't literally do
made a decision or done something with
anything there until we've actually
the file chooser alright so by default
made a decision or done something with
the file chooser initially choose shows
the file chooser alright so by default
the default file system view of the
the file chooser initially choose shows
operating system that's running on
the default file system view of the
instead we want to show the last
operating system that's running on
directory the user save to or a directory
instead we want to show the last
that they specified perhaps in the
directory the user save to or a directory
application settings so to have the file
that they specified perhaps in the
chooser initially open to a specific
application settings so to have the file
directory we can use the set initial
chooser initially open to a specific
directory method
directory we can use the set initial
alright so let's run again and open the
directory method
file chooser but this time lets select a
alright so let's run again and open the
directory instead of a file so i'm going
file chooser but this time lets select a
to run it again
directory instead of a file so i'm going
open
to run it again
we're gonna go to folder where I stored
open
some of the projects for this course
we're gonna go to folder where I stored
let's have selected this source code
some of the projects for this course
folder click on open notice I couldn't
let's have selected this source code
do that
folder click on open notice I couldn't
so when I did that when I selected the
do that
directory and actually and click on open
so when I did that when I selected the
it actually open the folder rather than
directory and actually and click on open
allowing is to actually select the
it actually open the folder rather than
directory of that we actually or
allowing is to actually select the
folder that we wanted to in this
directory of that we actually or
scenario so in other words sometimes we
folder that we wanted to in this
want the user to be able to choose a
scenario so in other words sometimes we
directory and not file so if we do want to
want the user to be able to choose a
choose a directory we need to use the
directory and not file so if we do want to
directory chooser instead because we're
choose a directory we need to use the
using the file chooser at the moment again
directory chooser instead because we're
just to confirm that file chooser is
using the file chooser at the moment again
working i can select a file their
just to confirm that file chooser is
click on open it does return back to the
working i can select a file their
main dialogue so if we want to do a
click on open it does return back to the
directory there instead of a file and
main dialogue so if we want to do a
what we need to do is use directory
directory there instead of a file and
chooser as i mentioned and just to see
what we need to do is use directory
how it works lets actually try adding
chooser as i mentioned and just to see
that....
how it works lets actually try adding
....
that....
alright so this ones a bit different we
....
need to actually use a....
alright so this ones a bit different we
we run that again we should find there
need to actually use a....
we can choose a directory so open go
we run that again we should find there
back up one level to my source code
we can choose a directory so open go
folder now I can click on source
back up one level to my source code
code click on open and notice this time
folder now I can click on source
it's now chosen the actual directory
code click on open and notice this time
instead of opening like it did last time
it's now chosen the actual directory
that's directory chooser and
instead of opening like it did last time
incidentally same deal there it expects
that's directory chooser and
the only window to be passed to it and
incidentally same deal there it expects
that's why we were able to use the
the only window to be passed to it and
exact same command the same parameter
that's why we were able to use the
...and just
exact same command the same parameter
to confirm that's working lets actually
...and just
add a bit more code here....
to confirm that's working lets actually
...
add a bit more code here....
..
...
let's try running that to see whether we
do get a response so we run open firstly if I
cancel chooser was cancelled open
again this time we're going to select
a folder the source code open you can see
we get the folder name here I get the
full path back from the directory that
was chosen pretty cool so
open it again though you may have
noticed if we open the folder we seeing
that only thing we can actually select
here are folders you can see these other
files but they aren't selectable and
depending on your operating system you
may not even see the files at all but on
a Mac we can still see the files but
with only got the ability to select
folders and depending on your
operating system as well you might find
it down here where it's got open it
might have the text select folder in the
case of a mac though it still shows as
open I'm gonna finish the video
here now when we get back here to this
in the next video we're going to start
looking at at the file chooser again and
would talk about something called
extension filters so see you in the next
video