- [Tim] Alright,
so let's just run our application again
to list the albums for given artist
so I'm just going to run it
so we get our artists
coming up at the start
and I can select the particular artist
or select AC/DC in the last video,
but let's use one that
what I've used previously
Fleedwood Mac
and click Show Albums Artist.
So obviously, the contents of the table,
now onscreen are being
replaced by the five Fleetwood Mac albums
that are in the database.
I (chuckles) seem to have quite a few
greatest hits and best of albums there.
Alright, so if you wanted to go back
to the list of artists,
we have to click on this
List Artists button.
But first, we need to
assign an event handler
to that button.
Now, what we can do is use the same method
we call from application.start
and we'll have to go back
to the controller to do that.
So let's do that.
So basically, we're just going to call
the List Artist method again,
but obviously, we are
going to do it as an event
for the button when it's clicked.
So I'm going to go back to controller
and we're going to add a new method.
And what we need to do first
is looking at our List Artist method,
now we're going to use it in the FXML.
We need to annotate it at FXML
like we've done before
and that won't affect it running
from the main method though at the start.
But, what it will do is allow us
to use that as an event
or rather an event handler, if you will
for the button.
So to do that, we go back to our main.fxml
and we find a button.
It's the second one here
that "Show Albums (artist)".
Well actually, that's one we fixed
on the last video.
This is the one we want.
The first one, the ListArtists.
We want that to add a known action
so when that's clicked,
we get our list of artists back again.
So let's try doing that.
So it's going to be
onAction="#List Artists"
Alright, so if you run that again now,
I would select a particular artist
and Show Albums
and now we should be able
to click on List Artists
and we get our artists back now
showing on the screen.
The one thing we haven't
talk much about is
what happens if we haven't selected
an artist in the table
and we click on Show Albums,
you noticed down in the (mumbles)
at the buttom left,
we got a message popping up, saying
NO ARTIST SELECTED
and just to confirm
I can select AC/DC again
and it does work,
obviously, we don't get another message.
And then back to the List Artists
to get a list of all the artists again.
Alright, so it's been a bit of a heck
what we've done here
by using the same table
for different data
but otherwise you could see
we've managed to get it to work.
So this will be probably the sort of thing
you would do as a developer
while prototyping.
Now let's turn to the progress bar
that's currently in the layout
but not visible.
Now, we covered how to use a progress bar
with a background task
in the threaded section,
so we're not going to spend too much time
on the implementation here.
We we're fetching a large number records
from the database,
it would be nice to let the user know
that the application is working.
Now we use an indeterminate progress bar
because we fetched the
records using one query
and we don't know how
many records there are.
Now even if we queried the count,
we still couldn't report progress
and that's because we get the records
back in one lump rather than individually.
Another way of doing it, possibly,
would be to query the records in blocks.
For example, we could
ask for records 1 to 100,
then 101 to 200, etc. and report progress
between each query,
but that's probably outside
of the scope of this
and the previous sequel
videos in this section.
So all we can really
do is let the user know
that the application is working.
Alright so let's go
back and close this down
and set up our progress bar first.
So go back to the FXML
and we got this progress bar down here,
down the bottom.
So first, all we need to do is
have a reference stored in the controller
so we're gonna add an FX ID to it.
fx:id="progressBar"
(Tim typing)
Alright, then we're going to go back
to our controller
and we're going to add an entry for it.
And it's going to be
private ProgressBar progressBar.
So when we're fetching
data from the database,
we need to make the progress bar visible
and when that task completes
we need to make it invisible
by setting its visible property to false.
So let's implement this for
the get all artists task.
Down here, down at the bottom.
Now keep in mind that we
can't set the visibility
from inside the core method
and that's because any code that touches
a UI control has to run on the UI thread.
So we will use task.setOn(succeeded)
and task.set on file methods
to set the progress bar
visibility back to false.
And the other thing we have to do is bond
the progress bar to the task.
So let's go ahead and
write the code to do that
and obviously we're coding
this to get all tasks
from the List Artists.
So as I mentioned we can't
put the code in there,
in the core method
because the UI, any code that touches
a UI control has to run on UI threads.
So we'll actually have
to do it in listArtists.
So we got that line there that's right.
The first line that actually (mumbles)
to get (mumbles) tasks
and then setting the items properly
and binding their tasks
that's correct
but we would also want to add one now
for the progress bar.
So progressBar.
That's going to be
progressProperty().bind
and we're going to bind that to
(task.progressProperty())
then we're going to do
progressBar.setVisible(true)
and then we're going to do a
task.setOnSucceeded (e ->
progressBar.setVisible(false))
and same (mumbles)
task.setOnFailed (e ->
progressBar.setVisible(false))
So whether we succeed or fail,
we do want the progress bar to disappear
so just to confirm, we're
using Lander expressions
on line 29 and 30 here
to set the progress bar visibility.
Now there are other setOn methods
in the task class,
for example, we can set
code to run if the task
is cancelled, perhaps due to user action,
but in this case we
only need to worry about
the success and failure cases
for this (mumbles) application.
Now again,
because our task doesn't
report any progress,
the progress bar will be indeterminant.
Now we could run this now
but the query complete so quickly
that we wouldn't see the progress bar.
So what I'm going to do
is slow things down, a
little bit, by adding a
code to thread.sleep while we're looping
through the result set
in the data source.list artists method.
Let's go ahead and have a look at that.
Okay, so query artist method I mean.
Alright so,
what we're going to do
is put the code in here
just to slow things down a little bit
and will put it in the (mumbles) loops
while results start next
we're gonna simulate...
A bit of a delay there, sorry,
again we can see the
progress bar on operation
and we're going to do a Thread.sleep(20.)
We're going to
catch(InterruptedException e).
(Tim typing)
We don't need to do
this but we'll just put
something there, just in case
and then, let it continue on afterwards.
So basically, now we've added the code
so that for every artist, the threads
going to sleep for 20 milliseconds.
Right, so if we run this now,
you'll see the progress
bar down the bottom
and then it disappears once the artists
actually are loaded up successfully.
And again you saw that it was an
indeterminate progress bar so
rather than showing increasing progress,
the bar is gonna animate backwards
and forwards, as you
saw, from left to right
and then back from right to left.
And obviously, it
disappeared when the table
was finished loading.
And again, if we just do a query here,
Show Albums Artists
and then click on 'List Artists' again,
we get the same thing happening.
And there's our artists again.
Alright so that's it for queries.
The important thing to remember is that
we always want to run the query
on a background thread
using something like a task.
When we're ready to
update the user interface,
we have to do so on the
Java FX application UI thread.
And if we're using data binding,
the UI code will run
on the UI thread automatically.
If not, you'd want to
use platform.run later
or a method like task.setOn(succeed)
to run the UI code on the UI thread.
Alright, so let's finish
this video here now,
in the next video let's start
having a bit of discussion about inserts,
updates and deletes,
specifically, how do we
update the UI when dealing
with those.
So, see you in the next video.