- [Tim] All right, so in
this section of the course,
we've learned quite a
lot about using java.nio
with the file system.
Now, some developer tools use java.io
and many existing Java applications,
especially those written before
java.nio became available,
still use java.io.
In addition, many code
examples around the web
also use java.io so it is very important
that you'll be able to read java.io code
and understand what it's doing.
So we're gonna finish up this
section of the course now
by discussing how to map
common java.io operations to java.nio.
So let's start with paths.
Now, I mentioned that rather
than using java.io.file,
it's better to use java.nio.path.
Now, you can use the file.toPath method
to convert an old style file instance
to the preferred java.nio.path instance.
So let's actually give that a try.
So we can type something
like File file = new File
and I'm just gonna have a path
something along these lines for my Mac
and it'll also work on Linux, file.txt,
but you would do something similar on a PC
like C:\\Examples\file.txt.
So I can then convert that by typing
Path convertedPath = file.toPath
and I can print that out.
ConvertedPath = + convertedPath.
I'll try to run that,
convertedPath = /Examples/file.txt
which of course is what
it was in the file object.
Now, note that it doesn't matter
whether the stream that we
passed to the file constructor
points to an existing file.
Just like with paths,
the file doesn't have to exist
until the code tries to
access it and even then,
sometimes it's okay if
the file doesn't exist
for example without being streamed.
If the file doesn't exist,
it'll be created at that point.
All right, so once
we've got a path object,
we can go ahead and use it
with all the java.nio classes and methods.
Now, in the last video,
you learned about the path.resolve method
that takes part of a path
and resolves it relative
to another path instance.
Now, you can do the same
thing using the file class,
but you have to do it when
the file instance is created
using the version of the
constructor that accepts the file
and the string as parameters
or the extracted version
that accepts two strings
so let's have a look at that.
So I can start off with
File parent = new File
and I'm gonna use /Examples for my Mac,
but for PC let's stick with
the example there C:\\Examples
and we'll do File resolvedFile
= new File(parent,)
and then the path and we're
going to use dir/file.txt
again on a Mac.
On Windows, you do something
like dir\\file.txt.
We can print that out resolvedFile.toPath
and then we can also do
using the other version of the constructor
resolvedFile = new File so
we can pass them separately
so we could do /Examples
as the first argument
and for the second one dir/file.txt.
And again on Windows the
two arguments would be
C:\\Examples and the second
one would be dir\\file.txt.
Then we can print that
out resolvedFile.toPath.
So let's run that
and we can see that we've got
that working nicely as well.
And in terms of what we've done
so I have parent which is on line 78,
well that's the instance we used
to invoke the resolve method
and we passed the child part
of the path as the parameter.
So up here with the first call
to the resolvedFile.toPath,
we're passing a file
instance as the parent
and a string as the child
and you can see that's
getting converted to a path
and it's returning a path for us.
In the second example,
we're passing the parent
and the child as strings
and we get the same result.
And incidentally, both
of these are equivalent
to us doing something along these lines,
Path parentPath = Paths.get
I'm gonna do /Examples again,
but again on a Windows instal,
C:\Examples or two backslashes actually
and Path childRelativePath = Paths.get.
Again on a Mac, dir/file.txt.
On a Windows, dir\\file.txt.
And we could print that out which will be
parentPath.resolve(childRelativePath).
Run that.
You can see that the
output is identical there.
So basically both of these options,
the resolvedPath.toPath,
the example there with
passing the file object
and the child path as a string
or passing the two strings
so the constructor is equivalent
to what we've done there
on the code on line 85 through 87.
All right, so we also learned
previously in this section
how to call the files.move
and files.delete methods
to move or rename files
as well as delete files.
Now, the equivalent
methods in the file class
are file.renameTo and
the file.delete methods.
Now, that's pretty self-explanatory
so I won't code an example for those.
Now, in all the examples,
we've used fileSystems.getDefault
to get the working directory
for the application
and that actually returns a path.
Now, when working with
many java.io methods,
you actually need to use a file instance.
Now, there are several ways to do this,
but some of them have drawbacks
and that's another reason
why working with paths
and the java.nio classes is better,
but here's a hack that is more robust
than a lot of other solutions.
It's getting the working directory
so let's have a look at doing that.
So File workingDirectory = new
File("").getAbsoluteFile().
We can print that out
workingDirectory = +
workingDirectory.getAbsolutePath.
A bit of a hack,
but it's one that is most
robust than other solutions.
Now just run that to
confirm that it does work
and you can see that's
consistent with the directory
you can see at the top of the screen there
for the current working directory
for this particular project.
The reason this works on line
89 is because when you pass
an empty string to the file constructor,
it actually translates it to
the current directory for you
and of course that's the working directory
for the application.
Now, one major difference
between java.io and java.nio
is the way you list the
contents of a directory.
Now previously in this section,
you learned how to use a directory stream
when working with java.nio,
but when working with java.io,
you use the file.list method
and file.listFiles method.
Now, these methods do the same thing,
but the list method
returns an array of string
and the listFiles method actually
returns an array of file.
In addition, you can pass an
optional filtering parameter
to the list method.
So let's just take a quick look
at a couple of examples of this.
So what we'll do is we'll
start just putting a message
so we know they're not separated.
We'll print dir1 with
dir1 contents using list,
using the list method.
So I'm gonna do File dir2File = new File
we're going to use the
workingDirectory file object
that we created on line
89 as the first argument
and then we wanna pass
the actual reference
to the subfolder that we want access to
so we're going to use /FileTree/dir2
and that's for my Mac.
If you're on a Windows machine,
you wanna do something along
the lines of \\FileTree\Dir2.
Now that we've got that,
we can do String, a string array,
dir2Contents = dir2File.list
to call the list method.
Then we'll do for[int i=0]
i< Dir2Contents.length i++
and then we'll print out
dir2Contents for element i.
And let's just also
just to be clear there,
we'll put i= + i + we'll do that like so.
All right, so let's try running that.
All right, so you can see
that we're putting the dir1 folder.
I said dir1 in the comments up here,
but we're actually using the dir2 folder
so technically that should have been dir2
just to be consistent there.
But you'll notice that
we're one level deep
so it showed us the dir3 folder,
but it didn't go into the dir3 folder,
but it did give us the other
three filenames as well.
So again, it's only returning
the first-level entries.
It doesn't walk the tree
down to any subfolders.
And we can do something similar
using the listFiles method.
So I can come down here
and we'll do print Dir2
contents using listFiles.
We'll do a File array
dir2Files = dir2File,
again dir2File is defined
on line 93, .listFiles.
Then we can do the same thing for,
well let's actually
just take a copy of this
and let's make a few little changes
just to save a bit of time
and it's gonna be dir2Files this time
and it's going to dir2Files(i)
but then we wanna do .getName
to call the .getName method
because of course we've got
an array of file objects here.
We'll run that
and you can see we've got
an equivalent result there
using the listFiles method
and you can see it's walked
through the tree there,
but again it's only stuck
to the first-level entries.
It doesn't walk the complete
subfolder tree as well.
And the only real difference
there is the getName method.
When we print the files,
that returns the last
segment of the file path
which in this case is the filename.
Now, I discussed previously
how to get a systems
root drive so file stores
and how it can be problematic.
You can actually use the
file.listRoots method
to get the root but it
has the same problem
as the fileSystem.getRootDirectories
method.
So in other words, it lists drive letters
for drives that actually aren't available.
Now, there are many more java.io
versus java.nio operations,
but the difference is how straightforward
in that the method names
are usually a close match.
You should now know enough
to be able to read code
that accesses and modifies the file system
using java.io and java.nio methods.
So let's actually get to the io section.
If you can take away only
one thing from this section,
it's to use java.nio when
working with a file system.
But when it comes to reading
and writing file contents,
sometimes java.io streams
are the still better choice.
You should really run benchmarks
and decide what's best for
your application though,
but my advice is to do as I mentioned,
use java.nio when working
with a file system
and when reading and
writing file contents.
Often, the java.io streams
are the better choice.
All right, so let's move on now
to the next section in this course.