So in the previous video,
we started work on our challenge solution.
So I went through and we've introduced the
basic concept of the ISaveable interface,
as well as creating a class,
a player class that actually
implemented that interface.
And as you saw that the actual
methods that we created will take
any class that implements
the ISaveable interface.
So, player was one example, but
we can actually create a monster class for
the game and persist that data, the data
relating to that, in the same way.
Monsters are very similar to the players,
but they don't have weapons,
just their natural claws and
fangs as we're gonna do here.
So, the point about this is,
by creating this other class,
you can still use these other methods and
create some pretty cool code that
actually saves the state of the monsters.
So, lets do that now.
So I'm going to create a new class,
Monster, and it's going to implement.
Implements the ISaveable interface.
And we're gonna start off having a name,
private String name,
private int hitPoints,
how strong the creature is in other words.
private int strength, like so,
and I'm going to create a public
constructor that's going to
accept those three parameters.
And so we can set them like so.
And we're going to create some getters,
actually we don't need getters, we
actually need setters, because we're gonna
do the setting setup in the constructor.
So, I'll create the getters for
each of those.
So we can access those.
Okay, so let's create the toString.
So I've selected that and
there's different options here,
the one I normally use is this one here.
The first one string [INAUDIBLE] which was
the one that was selected originally, but
I just wanted to point out that
you can actually experiment and
try some other things
if you wanna do that.
But that will be the working fine for this
example, so we're gonna click on that.
And that's our toString,
which we'll see and use later.
And of course, the last two things
we need to create now in this class,
or override, is the two methods,
the write and read.
So we're gonna go down
to Implement Methods,
in our Generate, select both of them.
And we've now got the list, and you can
see it's using the generic lists now,
which is good.
So let's actually start off by
creating the write method, so
that's going to be
arrayList of strings again.
values = new ArrayList,
like so, values.add(0,
this.name).
I could have used a getter
there if I wanted to,
.add(1, this.hitPoints).
values.add(2, this.strength).
And return values.
Like so, so that's our write method.
Very similar to the other method we wrote
in the player class with the same name,
but of course, we've got one less full.
We haven't got a weapon for the monster.
And likewise,
the read is gonna be pretty much the same.
If savedValues is not equal to null, and
savedValues.size is > 0,
then and only then,
we're going to actually try and
retrieve the [INAUDIBLE].
So this time, .name = savedValues.get(0).
this.hitPoints = Integer.parseInt().
And that's going to be savedValues.get(1),
and
this.strength =
Integer.parseInt(savedValues.get(2)).
So, and that's truly it.
So again, we are still implementing
the write and read methods for
this class because we
implemented the interface.
This code could be completely
different if we wanted it to be.
But in this case, it's pretty identical
to what was in the player class.
I mean, there's one less field to
actually save and then ultimately load.
And then intents of going back and running
this, we can go back to our main method.
And we could do something like Saveable,
ISaveable werewolf = new
Monster("Werewolf"),
and hit points, 20, strength, 40, maybe?
We can print out the werewolf.
And we can also save the object.
saveObject(werewolf), just to
see what actually happens.
And I'll take out this load here now,
so we don't go through that again.
So we can actually check it, cuz we
did that at the end of the last video.
And we'll actually run this.
And you can see now we've got monster now
because werewolf hit points equal 20,
strength equals 40.
Saving werewolf to storage device, saving
20 to storage device cuz werewolf was
obviously the name, 20 was the hit points,
and 40 was the strength.
So that's working as well, so you can say
that there are obvious advantages to this
ISaveable interface, in that we're
guaranteeing what's a contract to confirm
that if a class is implementing this
interface, it has to implement that code.
So it's a way for you to make sure that
those particular methods are overwritten,
so that the actual functionality
that is needed for
that class is actually written, and
it doesn't fall back to the super code,
the code that would be in a base
class if you were using Inheritance.
The other thing I wanna point out,
just close this down.
If you go back up here to where we
were with printing out the object,
what we can't really do here so
I'll actually create a new object but
what we can't do is we can't
do werewolf.getStrength.
Obviously, we get an error and of course
going back here though to monster,
we actually have got a method.
We've got a getter, we set up a getter for
get.strength, but it's not working.
It's not working in there.
Now if you want to actually, if you
know that this is the monster class, and
we know that because we've
implemented that here.
We've actually used that when
we're instantiating a new object.
And you actually want to use the
get.strength, and what you have to do is
do something a little bit different
to what you've done before.
But you're actually printing it out, we'll
do something like this, we'd actually do,
let's just assume that line there
we wanted to print it out, and so
we got to print it out.
That's obviously still not gonna work
like the way it is there now, but
what we can actually do, is actually
do this, we can actually put monster.
Werewolf, but get.strength like so,
we need to put a bracket there as well.
Once we do that, it's now valid, because
what we're doing is we're casting it,
we're actually saying this,
yes we know that this base class
will use the ISaveable interface.
But when it comes time to print it out,
what we're saying is now this is actually
the monster class, and remembering that
we're implementing the interface but
it still actually is the monster class.
So we're doing that when we run this,
it's the code is now valid and
we can actually go ahead and do that.
So I can actually change that now and
just confirm.
We can put something like.
Like so, and if we run it.
You can see it's actually working there,
Strength = 40.
So that's how you get around that,
the fact that you actually
declared to this in an interface.
But if you still wanna get access
to it and get access to specific
methods that are actually in the actual
class, in this case, the monster class.
That's actually how you'll
do it with a class.
Remember again,
the other thing you can do if you wanted
to, you can actually just come back here.
We can literally just put the code in
there in which case we can then do
werewolf.getstrength, and
that would actually work.
So it all depends on how you actually go
ahead with the declaration, whether you
decide to actually do as I'm showing on
the screen there, if I just undo this now.
Okay, back to the ISaveable interface.
So it can be a little bit confusing in
deciding when to declare an instance as
the class.
In this case, play, in this case, monster
or player or when you know using ISaveable
interface when actually declaring
the instance like here is the interface.
Generally speaking, it depends on what
you're going to do with the instance.
So if you wanted to declare a variable
that can hold objects of different types,
then it would have to be
the type of the common interface.
But if you want to access methods that
exist in the class like we wanted to do in
the case of monster, we wanted to
get access to get.strength, but
they're not part of the interface itself.
Cuz obviously you go back to interface,
there's no get.strength in there.
So if we wanted to do something
like you saw me do here,
then the object will have to be
declared as the class type itself,
unless you wanna get around it by
using a class like you saw there.
Generally speaking, where there's no
strong reason for using the class type, so
in this case there isn't really a strong
need for us to use the monster class type.
Because we've got these generic
methods for reading and writing, and
we can access those in a similar way.
So that being the case, generally,
you'll probably wanna declare
it using the interface.
And that really is, I do anyway, because
that keeps your code more generic and
makes sure you're getting the best
out of using the interfaces.
You can always cast the instance to the interface or class type as necessary.
Keep that in mind as well.
Also notice that parameters to methods
that have been declared as the interface
type are automatically cast from the class
type for us, which is pretty cool.
So, Java does some of that work for you,
to make sure that that's actually there so
you can sort of move to and fro with
the declaration being an ISaveable.
Or if you're actually doing an,
in this case,
actually using the Monster class itself.
Okay, so that's interfaces.
I hope you got a lot out of that.
And I'll end the video here now,
and I'll see you in the next video.