There's just a few little things now,
to finish off in our generics code,
and then we're actually going
to move on to the challenge.
So in the last video, I just showed
you how to actually change the team
match result method, right here so,
we could actually use that
type to actually confirm,
that any plays of the appropriate type.
Any teams, I should say, of the
appropriate type could call the method.
And so, consequently in match result,
when we're calling that
from the Adelaide Crows,
we can't actually pass a baseball team to
it, because we've defined Adelaide Crows
to actually be a team of type
Football Player, so therefore,
that baseball team isn't going to work,
so I'm going to comment that out now.
Now, the team class includes
a very simple ranking.
I think, I talked very briefly about that.
And the ranking was just
a very simple formula to
calculate how this team is
ranking in this league.
And it's the number of games
won multiplied by two,
plus the number of games tied.,
So, pretty simple.
So, in a real world.
Obviously, league the ranking would also
consider the number of games played, and
things like the goal difference,
and perhaps other things as well.
And obviously, you're free to play more
complexity to the myth if you're interest
in doing these things yourself.
And having a better of play around.
But, we're going to leave
that fairly simple for
this exercise as we move forward.
So, let's actually go ahead now, and
actually, print these rankings out.
And that's actually, quite simple to do.
So, we can just come in here, and
do some printout, or print out some items.
We can say rankings.
Then we could do
Adelaide Crows.getName plus column,
and plus AdelaideCrows.ranking.
LIkewise, we're gonna do the same for
Melbourne.
Melbourne.get name plus colon
space plus Melbourn.ranking.
Next for Fremantle.
Freemantle, is a strain for
[INAUDIBLE] get names
plus call space plus freemantle.ranking.
And lastly, that's all.
It wants to definitely run the 2015
[INAUDIBLE] for Australia.
Plus a space like so.
And it'll be hawthorn.ranking.
So, we can actually now, run that.
And we can actually, see
the Adelaide Crows have got four points.
Then, if we have a look we can see,
sort of see why.
Melbourne and Freemantle have got zero
points, because we haven't actually,
defined them as having
any results essentially.
It's only Freemantle, and LA Crows that
have actually got some results in there,
and that's where I've got two points,
and you can see that's obviously,
from the various metrics
aren't set with actually into.
So, that's all very well.
But one thing we can't
do is compare things,
to see which would be
the highest in the league table.
So, let's make a change to that.
Let's actually,
make a change to our team class
to implement something that's very
useful in interface called comparable.
So, we close down the run window,
and go back to the team class.
We need to actually,
change the definition at the top.
We've obviously, got extending player.
We need to then, implements,
and implements comparable.
Comparable.
And, we need to actually use the diamond,
again, so T again because obviously,
we want to make sure that we are still
using the same generics like that.
And obviously, we are getting an error
now, because it's saying we must implement
the abstract method compare to in order
to, actually fulfill this interface.
And you can see that, there's literally
only one thing to actually change.
One method we need to do to
actually fulfil the interface, and
that's the compare to function.
Because we only want to compare our teams,
to other teams,
that's why we're actually
using the team and the type.
So, it doesn't make sense to compare
a football team to a baseball team.
So, that's why we're actually adding team,
and
then, the actual type,
in another set of diamonds.
So, the infamous part looks complicated,
but in essentially what we're doing is
we've created the ability to have generic
types, such as team football player.
So, all we're actually doing here is
specifying a generic type as a parameter,
to the generic interface comparable.
So, team is the type in this case,
and team football player, or
team T as you got here, is also a type.
So, comparable T in this case
could actually accept either.
So, the compare to method
that we're about to write,
which is defined by the comparable
interface that we're implementing up here,
takes an objec,t and returns a negative
number if this is less than the object.
Zero, if they're equal, and a positive
if this is greater than the object.
So here,what I'm talking about is
less than these that we should sort
earlier then.
And ask if we want teams with higher
rankings to sort higher up the list.
We need to make our compare to
return less if the ranking,
is greater than the opponents.
I hope that actually makes sense.
We've actually used the comparative
method when we implemented our
own link list in a previous challenge.
And many of the Java classes,
actually implement this [INAUDIBLE]
including the string in integer classes.
That's how these objects can be
sorted as a result of doing that.
But we're doing is we're going
to be writing our own code,
because of course we used the string
compare to in the previous challenge,
by using the compare,
comparable or interface.
And, we're gonna be implementing
the compare two method,
which takes the parameter of T,
Team, the type.
Type parameter to compare.
And again, we're doing that so,
we don't try and compare football, and
baseball teams for argument sing.
So, if we had just changed that so,
that was just literally team, like this.
Compare to it, and
could only take 10 as its parameter.
Then, when we write the method,
compare to,
it will also be able to
take team as its parameter.
And, we wouldn't have that ability to
ensure that only the types of teams,
in this case, that are appropriate,
can be parsed to that method.
So, I'm gonna leave that back in so,
let's go ahead, and
actually write this compare to interface.
So, we come down here, under ranking.
And I'm going to implement.
Implement the compare T method.
And you can see, how it's automatically
looked at the definition, and it has added
a similar definition, now I'm going to
change the default of zero to team,
because that's essentially
what it is in this case.
It's the team.
And what we now, need to do is go through.
and do this test like I've said.
So, the first test would be,
if this dot ranking, so
this is the current
object we're comparing.
If it's greater than
what's been passed to us,
the team dot ranking, team dot ranking.
Remember, the higher the score the better.
Then, you're gonna return negative one.
So, in other words, the current team,
the one that we're actually in,
this class in other words, or this
instantiation of the class, if the team
ranking for that is higher than the team
that's been passed to this method,
then it means that this is actually higher
in essence, and we're going to return -1.
That's the first one, otherwise
we're gonna put else if(this.ranking
If it's less than team.ranking,
so is the other way around,
we can have return 1 if
the opposite is true.
The current object hasn't got more points,
essentially, it's got less points so
we're gonna return 1.
And otherwise, we're gonna return 0 cuz it
obviously means that the rankings
are actually the same.
So, that's what we need
to do to implement that.
And then, we can get back to main Java.
Code, and we can actually int that up.
So, we can do something like
AdelaideCrows.compareto, and let's just
say Melbourne and
Melbourne I believe had 0 points and.
So, AdelaideCrows compare to.
Let's just try, those two on them.
So, you can see in this case,
Adelaide Crows has got four points, and
comparing to Hops and Melbourne,
which has got 0 points, it returns -1,
because we've got a higher ranking,
in this case, than Melbourne.
And likewise, compared to Hawthorn,
we've also got a higher ranking.
But, if we actually wanted to do a test,
let's actually compare Hawthorn
to the Adelaide Crows, so
we'll do it the other way around,
just to confirm it's still working.
We'll put, and
Hawthorn compare to LA Crows.
We should get the opposite, because we're
now comparing Hawthorn to the LA Crows
from the other point of view, but
also that's the one that's the same.
We'll do, Melbourne dot compare to
Fremantle by which both should return 0,
so that we should actually get 0,
because they're both the same score.
So, we run those.
So, you can see in the third example, now
,we've got Hawthorn compared to Adelaide.
Adelaide's got more points, Hawthorn had
less, so we're gonna returned 1 there.
And in the last example,
melbourne.compare to(fremantle)
they both actually have 0 points.
So, obviously.
Compare return 0.
So, that's actually working,
which is good.
Now, the reason we've implemented
the comparable interface,
other than to show you how to use it,
because I think it's actually very useful.
But also is going to be to help you, with
the challenge to come in the next video.
So, if you've got a list of
objects that implement comparable,
there such as team for example.
What you can do is you
can quickly sort the lis,
by using the static sort method
of the collections class.
I'm gonna talk more about that, and
give you a little bit of a hint
in the next video when we're actually
gonna go through the challenge.
But essentially,
if you've got an array list of teams you
can use this code, something like this.
Sudo code would be, if you had something
like an array list of teams like so,
you could do collections.sort(teams) and
that would be sorted.
And the whole point about this
is it will actually be sorted,
using the compare to function that we
actually wrote for the actual team itself.
So i,n other words this method would
be actually automatically utilized
by the actual code when we were
actually doing the ".sort".
And we're just getting an error there,
because we haven't actually initialized
it, it is just purely to give you a bit
of an overview of what it can do.
Now ,that's obviously one way to do the
sort, but you can obviously go back and
refer to the sort method that we actually
wrote for the arrays challenge as well.
But then, you can see this is quite
simple actually using the built-in
Java collections class.
And we've got an entire section
of that about collections
in upcoming videos
showing how to use that.
But this is just a simple way of doing it.
But anyway, I will talk more
about that in the next video.
I'm going to start this one now.
There is probably no point in me
starting the challenge in this video.
What I will do is I like to start
the challenge in the next video, and
we will go through what's required and
actually talk about the solution.
So, I will see you in the next video.