So continuing on with our
discussions about packages.
The other thing you can actually
do what you're creating a class
is you can actually specify a package and
will actually make that package for
you automatically at the same
time as creating the class.
Come up here to file,
new, create Java class.
Normally I would just type player And
that should carry that
to org.example.mypackage,
because I'm actually in that area.
I've got clicked, so I click OK.
You can see it's automatically
created that class in that folder,
in that package.
I'm gonna undo that.
I can actually do that again, though.
File -> New -> Java Class, and
this time, if I type a package name,
com.example .game.Player for
arguments sake.
Click on OK with that.
And notice it's actually created
a package sort of within a package
org.example.mypackage.com.example.game.
That's clearly not what we want
in this particular case because
we wanted to create a package Which
was just com dot example dot game.
So it's important to, if you have got
something clicked here to the left,
to probably click or
to definitely click source.
So I'm going to undo that again, and
then come back to source this time or
I can make sure, that's probably
the easiest way is to do that.
And then click on file, new,
java class, and now if we type com dot
example dot game dot player It
correctly creates the new package
com.example.game and puts the new player
in there, the new player class in there.
So what we're going to do now is we're
going to use a few classes from our
interfaces challenge.
So we're going to specifically use
the player class, and I know I've already
created the player class, but also the
monsters class in the isaliable interface.
We're gonna overwrite
the Player class as well.
So we're gonna go back to the source
code for the InterfacesChallenge and
if you haven't got this already.
If you haven't typed it in yourself,
go back and
you can actually download the source
code from the course itself.
There's actually links there so
you can grab this source code.
So I'm going into InterfacesChallenge.
Go into my source folder, and down to and
the first one I'm gonna select is monster.
Now you might think you can actually just
select it and drag, and it does seem like
it's going to work, and you can see it's
highlighting in red the package it's going
to put it to, going to place it,
but the thing is that's a move.
And by moving something you're actually
deleting it from the source folder.
So, probably don't want to do that.
You don't want to delete the code that's
in the current interfaces challenge.
Because that code will
then no longer work.
Because that file won't be there anymore.
So, a better option is to
come back to the finder.
And again, you'd Windows explorer or
whatever your explorer is for
your operating system.
Select Copy, and Copy will be same for
all operating systems.
There's a version there for you.
So select Copy, come back to
the package you want and paste.
This time you can see the message is Copy,
the name.
It's giving us the full name and
ultimately that'll be
the class name as well.
And you can see that the folder it's
pointing it to matches the package com
example game, com example game.
And we click on OK.
And it's been added successfully.
We getting an error here because,
of course,
we haven't yet got the savable interface,
but we're going to do that next.
So I'm gonna go back and do the same
thing for that, our savable copy.
Back to here, select the package.
Right-click, paste, and
we're gonna click on OK.
That's now added the interface.
And that leaves us with the Player class.
Now currently that's however empty.
And what we're going to do is do the same
thing, we're gonna go back to Player.
Right click, copy.
Back here to com,
go to example.game, paste.
And yes, we're going to use the same name.
This time we get a dialog pop up
to tell us that it already exists.
Do we want to overwrite it?
Or do we want to skip it?
We want to override it because we
want the version that came from
the interface challenge so click on
okay and now we've got our three files.
Just confirming, when it's doing this it
will actually fix the package name so
if the old source code has a different
Package, when you're actually
copying it into here IntelliJ is actually
changing the package in this code for you.
So it's quite handy how
it's doing that for you.
So what I'm about to do is create
a package for these three files,
the Player.javamonster.java and
[INAUDIBLE] .java, So that we can
actually use those in another project,
but before we do that we should actually
update our main class and put in the test
code that comes back from the challenge,
so that we can actually test to make sure
that things are working as they should.
It's always a good idea before you create
a jar file, which is what we're doing,
a library, Is to make sure that the code
is obviously working and tested.
So, we'll go back one
more time to our finder.
I'm going to select main,
I'm going to copy that.
And we basically are gonna go in here
to [INAUDIBLE] example.game, and
I'm gonna paste it in there.
And I'm going to overwrite
the existing main.java.
Actually, there wasn't a main.java.
Cuz, of course,
I was thinking of the main.java down here,
on org.example.mypackage.
So if Dale got four classes
in our common.example.game.
And what I am going to do now is
just remove this other package,
this org.example.mypackage because
we no longer need that anymore.
So I am going to right click that, delete.
And I'm just going to double click
mine which is already selected.
And it will just run that to
make sure that it's actually And
you can see we got the same
output we got from the challenge.
The interface challenge so the codes
obviously okay, there's no problems.
We're not getting any compile errors and
you would
obviously do your normal testing at this
point to make sure that actually worked.
Assuming that's working, what we're
gonna do now is delete the main class.
We're going to delete that and the reason
we're doing that is we're going to be
importing this project, these three files,
effectively into a [INAUDIBLE] file
that will then be imported into
another project all together and
that project will have its own main class.
So, we're specifically trying
to include only the code
relating to the actual game itself.
So now that we've actually removed the
other examples I'll actually remove this
[INAUDIBLE] As well,
that shows up for you to delete that as
well because we don't need that anymore.
We're left now just with the content
example dot game, package, and
the three files.
So, what I wanna do next is go into
file and select project structure.
What I wanna select is artifacts.
We're going to create a new artifact so
we're gonna click on the plus button.
We're gonna click on jar,
cuz jar stands for java archive and
that's sort of like a zip file but
for java code.
We're gonna select that and come over here
and select from modules with dependencies.
When I do that, you should see that
package demo came up automatically
as the module.
Module is basically
the project in this case.
The package [INAUDIBLE] although you can't
have moddable modules in a single project.
In our case, we've only got just the one.
Now if you wanted to make the Java file
executable, you'll specify main class.
But we don't want to do that so
we're going to leave that blank.
We're also going to extract
to the target Java as well.
I'm going to click on okay to that.
This actually gives us a folder.
If you have a look in
this to the end of that.
This actually shows us that this current
project slash out slash artifacts slash
package demo underscore jar
which is the folder name.
That's where it's going to actually
create this jar or PackageDemo.jar.
So make sure you actually know where it's
gonna be creating that while having a look
at the app directory.
Once you've done that, click on OK.
That's now specified the folder and
we can actually just go ahead and
we can actually make the project.
We could also at any time build artifacts.
And build artifacts enables
you to actually build this.
So I've packaged You can see that
we got just a clean, edit, rebuild.
I'm just gonna click on build.
And very quick process, you probably saw
something briefly down at the bottom
left hand corner of the screen,
that jar file has now been created.
And just to confirm if you go back now
to our finder, to our navigator and
actually have a look, and
look now in package demo,
because we finished with interfaces
challenge for now, Package demo out.
It's no in the artifacts
folder that's been created.
Package demo I'm just going to go draft,
folder, and
there's our package demo dot Java there
has been created by that build prices.
At this point, what we're going to do now
is we're going to actually create a new
project and we're import that lobry and
make sure it still runs.
So I'm going to click on file,
new, select project.
Click Java and
next do what we normally do.
Create a command like that.
We'll call this one Game Test.
[NOISE]
Into the base package line.
Click on finish until it's asking us
do we want to close this project down?
We'll have two away because
when we click on this window.
Because we don't need
the package demo anymore.
So I click on that.
I've now got a very base
packages as you can see there.
Base project I should say.
Now at this point what we can now
do is we can actually import that.
We'll take a look at the external
libraries, you can see there's
a heap of libraries that are piled with
the Java ones that we have talked about.
But our library's not in there yet,
obviously,
because we haven't actually imported it.
So what we're gonna do
now in this new project,
where we want to actually use
the Java that we've created.
Click on file, go into project structure.
Then we want to go into libraries.
And click on plus.
And we're gonna specify that's
a new project library, a Java one.
And we need to specify where that is.
I'm gonna go down to our folder.
We created it which wa in PackageDemo
> out > artifacts, and that one there.
You can see it's a PackageDemo.jar, which
is in the PackageDemo_jar folder that was
created when we had
the other project open.
Click on OK And it actually tells us that
the library PackageDemo will be added to
the selected modules, GameTest, which is
the name over here of our current project.
We do want that, so we're gonna click
on OK to that, then we click on OK.
So now that we've actually done that,
we External Libraries,
we've now got another option here, we've
got PackageDemo showing as a library.
And if we expand to that, you can see
we've got our package com.example.game And
i've also got two classes there.
Once in player, and
we need to face our savable.
So, now that we've actually done that
you can presume the code is there
executable code to actually run this so
what we can actually do is add
some code to our actual java.
And we should be able to run this now and
instead of the previous interface has
changed, when we're running the code that
was part of this project, we'll be running
the code that's really embedded or
included in that packaged mo.jar so the
easiest way to do that is just to go back
to our interface challenge and
what I'm going to do is copy the main.
And I'm going to actually paste it.
Actually I'm going to close down the
external libraries, open up our project.
I'm going to paste it in com.timbuchalka,
which will overwrite the existing one.
I'm going to do that, and confirming yes,
we do want to override it.
Now did you see what happened there?
There was a brief delay where
the import statements weren't there and
then they actually
showed up automatically.
And again, they're automatically coming up
because of the way we've configured our
preferences, which I showed in, not
the last video, I think it might have been
the video before, but an earlier
video in this section, in any case.
It's automatically found these three
classes this time in the external library,
packaged demo as you can see there.
And that's why that we're able to run it.
So if we actually then run this,
we're still getting the same results.
The code is being executed, but of course,
looking at our project We've only
got a main class, in [INAUDIBLE].
We haven't got those other classes,
because they're actually
coming from this package.
So that's how to go about
actually adding a library,
or creating a library as you saw,
and then adding it to your code.
And that's a good idea if you want
to have some code that you reuse for
multiple projects.
You create a library
like we've done there.
Then you import it using
the mechanism that I showed you.
And then [INAUDIBLE] will actually do
the rest for you, as you saw there.
So that's it for the package discussion.
In the next video we'll go ahead and
actually do a package challenge.
So I'll see you in the next video.