Now if you're having difficulty understanding me,
there could be two reasons for it.
Firstly, I'm a geek and geeks tend to speak fast
because they're excited with programming
and technical things and I fall into that category.
But secondly, I'm an Australian,
so my accent may seem a little bit unfamiliar to you
compared to the traditional US version of English,
or UK, or whatever.
So if you're having difficulty understanding me
for whatever reason, I suggest you turn subtitles on.
Now this is process you follow to turn on subtitles.
You come down here on the screen.
You've got a choice of languages
and click on the relevant language.
And from then on after you've done that,
all the videos that are playing
will show as a subtitle at the bottom of the screen.
Now the thing to remember is
that there's two types of subtitles.
There's hand created or hand edited subtitles
and there's machine-generated subtitles.
Now this course has got hand-edited, English-only subtitles.
So what that means is I've gone through each video,
and that's 77 hours worth of videos
and I've hand-edited all the subtitles
to make them as accurate as possible.
Because perhaps if you've looked at
some other courses on Udemy,
you've probably or possibly seen
that the subtitles can be pretty bad.
In other words, the computer
because they're machine-generated,
the computer's interpreted these,
basically the subtitles,
just listened to the audio
and figured out what it thought was the best words,
and often it gets it wrong.
So for that reason, for the English subtitles,
I hand-edited them to make them as accurate as possible.
Now that's not say you won't find some problems.
There probably are some areas there still.
But anytime a student reports to me
that there's something wrong with a subtitle,
I usually get it fixed the same day.
So if you find a problem with a subtitle,
an English subtitle file,
let me know the video and the time where it comes up
and I'll get that fixed.
Now unfortunately for the other
languages other than English,
they are machine-generated.
So the quality won't be anywhere near
as high as the English ones.
And in case you're wondering,
it's extremely expensive to get subtitles created by people,
particularly in another programming,
oh, sorry, programming,
I meant in another language,
another real, spoken language.
So French for example, I would need to find someone
who knows English well and French well
and get them to go through each subtitle
and it's very, very expensive.
So I haven't able to do that for the other languages
other than English.
So you'll still have machine-generated languages
in other languages which is better than nothing.
But again, for the English ones,
they're hand-edited.
Turn those on is my best advice
to make sure you get the optimal experience
and you're understanding what I'm saying.