alright so in the last video we saw that
lambda expressions are treated like
nested blocks so there within the
enclosing block scope so what that
should mean is that were able to use the
local variable i so lets print its
value to the console from within the
lambda just to see that this is the
case going to put something just below
the first lines output and do....
....and if we run this so you can see
that the code works fine so currently
i isn't declared as final as you can
see on line 100 let's actually go ahead
and change its value to see what happens
....run it again though the moment we do so
IntelliJ complains about the use of
I within the lambda expression in any
local variable we want to use from the
enclosing block has to be effectively
final for the same reason that local
variables have to be declared final if
we want to use them within an anonymous
classes code by effectively final I mean
that the variable has to be either declared
final or it's value must never change
alright so what about variables that we
defined inside the lambda expression
now the parameters are in an
example of this do you think we can use
s 1 and s 2 outside the lambda in
the enclosing block let's actually try
that
so outside of the lambda clock go down here we
put something like....
and no we can't do this you can see
IntelliJ complaining so when working
with lambda is just imagine the code is
enclosed within curly braces and just to
be clear I'm going to just type a bit of
code to show you what the scoping would
be and I was going to remove these other
things that were causing errors so
just imagine that this is what's
actually going on so I would start with
something like
....
alright so within the code block string....
....so we're working with lambdas just
imagine the code is something similar to
this and make that i and j their that's
essentially the scoping now this isn't
entirely accurate the two parameters aren't local variables and we don't want to
return from the entire method the return
statement is returning a result of the
lambda expression but seeing the lambda
this way helps us with scope i think it's
clear that s one and s two won't be
available to the code outside the lambda
block so when working with lambdas
if we want to use the local
variables declared in enclosing block they
have to be effectively final so that the
runtime will know what values to use
when the lambda expression is evaluated
so to drive this point I'm just going to
just type in a bit more code i'm just
going to delete what I added here just
to avoid any complications and lets just
add another method which should make it clear so....
....
alright so in this code we're using a
lambda for a runnable when the code runs
the thread will sleep for five seconds
and then print the value of the number
variable now when thread is sleeping
the print value method will continue to
execute and will exit and that means
that by the time the thread gets around
to printing the number the local variable
will no longer exist
so what will the thread print
well since any variables in the lambdas
are set when the lambda is processed by
the runtime and those values of those
variables won't change because they're
effectively final the runtime knows it
can use the value of 25
that's because that was the value of
number when it process the lambda so in
larger applications quite a bit of time
may elapsed between creating a runnable
and actually using it so hopefully now
you get the point that because lambdas
may not be immediately evaluated any
variables that we use within them from
outside the lambda must be final
now we can change variables declared
inside the lambda because those
variables are within the lambda scope
and so can't be changed outside the
lambda also they won't go away because
the execution of the enclosing scope has
completed as in our case of our print
value method where the method will
finish executing before the lambda runs
alright so let's actually try one more
thing so we're going to add a lambda
expression to the enhanced for loop in
the main method and for every employee
we're going to start a thread that
prints out their age
let's go up and do that we're going back
up to the main method all the way the
top here
I'm just going to clear up some of this
now because we've got sort of copies of a
lot of this in the previous videos we've
been working the same code let's just
clean it up a little bit
alright so we've got our
employees defined as you can see there
so let's add that tap enhance for so....
....
alright so let's actually run that and
see what it does confirm that it works you
can see that works so IntelliJ
doesn't complain and we can run the code
successfully and we can see the ages
printed in the console but obviously it
sporadic times not necessarily in the
same order so if we just run this again
you can see we're getting different
ordering each time we run it
that's because the threads going to be
running at different times so you might
be thinking at this point hang on
wait a minute
the employee variable is declared
outside the lambda and it's values does
change doesn't it have to be effectively
final to be used within the lambda
wel answer to that is yes it does and in
this case the employee variable is
effectively final when using an enhanced
for loop a new local variable is created
for each iteration of the loop and that
means that the variable is effectively
final for each iteration and if we use
instead an old-style for loop you can see
this more clearly so let's just do
that
alright so it's going to be....
.....
....
....but you can now see using
the old style for loop it's clear that
on each iteration a new employee variable
is created and its results effectively
final so it's assigned once and then never
changes
now if you move the declaration of the
employee variable outside the for loop
then it won't be effectively final at
that point we wouldn't be able to use so
what I mean by that is just changing this
code here putting employee employee and
changing this
to employee and we don't get any
warnings or errors from IntelliJ but
when we got to run it you see that we actually
get an error and we got this problem about
the lambda expression must be final or
effectively final so i'm guessing that
IntelliJ on-the-fly parser doesn't
pick up every error of this type
sometimes we need to run it to actually
get these errors to pop up alright before
we close this lecture let's go back to
using an enhanced for loop to print the
employee name and ages again I'm just going to
comment this other code here
now leave the code that we originally had in
it now using lambda expressions we can
actually do better than this
we are printing the ages in another thread to
demonstrate a point let's just print the
ages in the current thread now so what i'm going
to do is just change the here for now I'm
just going to put leave that first
println there change the next one
and just put employee . get age getting rid of the thread
altogether that's going to execute it now
and that should obviously work nothing
particularly unique about that now when
lambda expressions were introduced in
Java 8 a bunch of other features
were also introduced that made use of
the lambdas we're going to take a closer
look at these features in upcoming
videos now let's have a quick look at a
new method in the iterable interface and
when we iterate or when reiterating over a
collection as we are here we can use a
lambda expression and then a new
iterable . for each method now the for
each method takes a lambda expression
and evaluates it for each item in the
iterable collection
let's update our code that we've got on
line 21 to 24 to use a lambda to print the
names and ages
we're going to replace the for loop with
the following i'm just going to comment it
that out actually be the easiest thing to
show you this so we're going to put....
....
...
.....and just to confirm that works
...obviously we got that working as well
so we can see that we're getting the
names and ages just printed just as we did
before but there's a lot actually going
on under the covers when this statement
is executed and we're going to take a
closer look at what is going on in the
next video on the java.util.function
package which was introduced in
Java 8 and that contains a bunch of
a functional interface is meant to be
used with the lambda expressions so now
that we've actually seen lambda
expressions how have they actually
enhanced java for some developers see
lambdas there's nothing more than a
syntactic sugar you know more convenient
and concise way of writing anonymous
classes I mean after all that don't
add anything to the language that wasn't
already there and we can assign them to
variables and pass them around but I
mean we can do that with anonymous class
objects as well as other people say that
lambdas are javas first step into
functional programming which is a
programming paradigm that focuses on
computing and returning results and just
for more information about functional
programming theirs a good wikipedia
article here wikipedia page to be more
concise to be more accurate and I paste
that in there to check out that to find
out a bit more about functional
programming the end of the day there you
really have to make your own mind up
about how significant you think lambda
expressions really are but before we
move on now it is important to note that
we never have to use a lambda expression
and in place for lambda expression we
can always use an anonymous class and
some developers prefer to do so now some
lambda expressions can be difficult to
read and understand especially when you
didn't write them yourself even if you
don't intend to use them
it is important to know about them and
how they work because you might have to
work on someone else's code at some point
and they may use lambda expressions
and also it is possible that future
enhancements to java might bring
features that require the use of lambda
expressions but right now whether to use
them or not is up to each developer or
an employer's coding standard
that matter alright so that concludes
our introduction to lambda expressions
next we are gonna start taking a look at the
java.util.function package so
going back to our code keep this project
open the lambdas project because
we're going to be copying some code
from it in the next video so we'll see
you in the next video