alright so it's time now to start seeing if
we can build some sort of really basic
user interface using scene builder so
what I'm going to do is with scene builder
opened the scene builder
tab opened going to drag some controls
over so will click on controls and select
the button and drag that in release
the mouse like so they're going to
do the same for two more buttons i'm going to
click on
the button again drag it over to the
right of the first button release and do
the same for third button on the
right-hand side move over move to the
right hand side of the second button and
release and you can see we now got
three buttons and note that the row and
column indicators are appearing now for
the grid pane and also the reference
here is changed to say that it's
consuming one row theirs now three elements
in this case buttons 0 to 2 so let's
change the text now offer each for
to make it easy to know which button
we're dealing with now you can select the
buttons into ways we can click on it
within the content area like here for
example the second button or i can
notice when I do that that actually
just selected here in the scene graph
area
alternatively i can just click
on there as well either way will
actually select the button once we've
done that up here where the text is
showing as button going to change that
to ok and press enter and notice that the
user interface is updated to reflect
that also the scene graph on the left
hand side is updated to reflect that and
just if you're not seeing that make sure
you've got properties if you happen
to have layout open you'd see that so you
click on properties because we want
to actually update those let's update
the other two can will actually add the
text canceled for the second button and
for the third button
let's make that one help
so lets now switch back to the text
tab to see the code that scene
builder has generated and looking at
that you can see that it's different
from the code that we write by hand
it's actually very verbose and also
note that scene builder has generated
some optional elements also since we
only have one row it's actually relying
on just the default values for some of
the grid pane . row index and grid pane .
column index settings are not
specifically specified as we did in the
case of our code when were actually coding
it by head
let's go back to scene builder again
now if it's not already selected in my
cases its not click on the grid pane over
here to the left and when I selected
the grid pane the color of the row
column indicators changes to let us know
that we're now going to be working on the
grid pane itself and so what I can then
do is click on this button over here to
the left the row 0 indicator which is
at the left of the ok button if click on
that you see that the settings area
displays the row constraints
for that row if i click on the zero tab
above the button notice how the column contraints
are now showing in the settings
pane on the right hand side so if we
want to change the row or column
constraints
that's how you actually get to them
alright so let's see what happens now if
we add a label above the buttons so i'm
going to do is open this controls and
grab a label got
a place above the ok button i'm just
going to drag it over and place it above
the ok button somewhere so you can see that
when I've done that the row index for
the buttons is now been updated the
buttons are now in the second row this
one down here at row index 1 alright so
with the label selected I'm going to
click here i'm going to click over here
to the left hand side to change its
properties or select this display its
properties and change the text going to
call that my label instead that's
reflected now as you can see on screen
and we go back to our text and take a
look notice that the fmx generated by
the scene builder as we notice before
it's still relying on default values so
the default value for grid pane . row
index and grid pane . column index is 0
and there's no obviously row index or
column index specified for that
label now scene buidler doesn't generate
these properties for the label because
it's at position 0 comma 0
it also doesn't generate the column
index for the ok button because it's at
column 0 so unfortunately this makes the
FXml more difficult to read because we
have to fill in the blank ourselves
generally speaking it's better to spell
out all the properties and we obviously
had been doing that and I've been
showing you how to do that when we've
been writing fxml ourselves
in the case of scene builder it's using
these default properties
alright so let's go back to scene builder
again notice the scene graph
area list all the controls we added on
the left-hand side here now to see what
the graphic the grid pane ui
when we run we just have to click
on an empty part of the content area to
remove the row column indices in my case
just going back to the screen and reset
it and that's actually showing this is
basically representation at the moment
of what it would look like if we
actually run now since the label is
wider than the ok button is now more
space between the buttons and as we
typically do let's actually put the
buttons into a h box by dragging a
h box over the buttons so i'm going
to actually do that going to get a h box
and drag it over the buttons noting that
I'm just selecting that area they're
releasing but you can see at the moment
the h box hasn't wrapped the buttons
instead it's actually added itself as
you can see over here the scene pane and
we can see on screen at row index one
column index one and just to confirm
that we get back to the text view and see
that it's added itself column index one
row index one that isn't what we want we
want the h box to go to row index one
column index zero we want the buttons
added to the h box rather than added
directly to a grid pane
let's get back to the scene builder and
what we're going to do is right-click
the h box over here in the scene graph and
select delete to remove it
that's now deleted so how do
we actually achieve this how do we
actually get those buttons wrapped
within a h box
well there's two ways to do this so we
can actually select all three buttons in
the scene graph area and we can select
three buttons clicking on the first
button holding down shift and selecting
the third one and that's actually going
to highlight the three of them or i can
also individually click on my command
key to select them and you could use a
ctrl key for windows or linux so
basically want to select the three that
way and the other way of doing it would
be just to selected just too select
them here same principle holding a
command because i'm on a mac and you do
a similar thing with ctrl key on Windows
or Linux to select the three buttons
at this point we've now got the three
buttons selected in the scene graph
and in the content area as you can see
we then actually hover over that right
click over here in the scene graph actually
click select rather wrap in and then we
gotta choose h box so go ahead and do
that h box when we did that you can
see that the layout got screwed up if
we switch back to the text view and have
a look you can see that everything's
been placed in a single row so the point
going to make here to you is that scene
builder isn't perfect so let's go
back to the scene builder and see if we
can fix this but do notice just over here
now that I can click on the + and the
three buttons are certainly in the h
box but again we've got this display
issue so how do we actually go about
fixing that we're going to select the
h box over here in the scene graph
and we need to set it row index and
column index properties to what we need
to do is come over and click on layout
you can see the row index and
column index will just make a little
wider are both set to 0 at the moment so we're
going to set the row index here to 1
press enter and we can see now that the UI
will look the way that we want to look
and there when we look at the scene graph
area you can see that the h box over
here has been expanded to show
the buttons and collapsed hide the
buttons would also like to do that if we
want to expand all or hide them and
again the main thing is that interface
and click something somewhere outside of
our controls we can see that we got our
three buttons showing nicely and
they're actually in the h box now one
caution here if we did decide at
this point I don't want these buttons in
a h box if you thought that you
actually just come over here and click
on the h box right click and select
delete which i'm not going to do now
that would actually delete the container
and the three buttons which you probably
definitely wouldn't want to do now there
is a there is also undo capabilities
here and so I was going to show you that
by actually clicking it and
selecting undo but unfortunately the
mac version undo seems to be broken
because every time i do that
intellij seems to lock up and go a
little bit weird so I'm not gonna try to undo
ut you could actually try
doing it and see whether it works just
right click click on delete and once
you've done that you could do a command
z to undo on a mac or control z
on a windows or linux machine or come
up here and click on undo
but again I'm not going to do that now
because on my mac it seems to hang bottom
line here is that you're deleting
container that's got embedded
controls you are going to delete
everything selected so be
very careful when you're selecting that
so how do you remove them well if you
want to actually remove them out of the hbox
instead what you do is you click on
the h box you right click and click on
unwrapped and that would actually take
them out so I can do that now and you
can see that's actually remove them from
the h box that h box has
disappeared completely from our layout
in this case so i actually want
it back so lets actually fix this
up first we go back and change our
buttons which now actually in the
wrong row so let's put changes back to
one we just add the h box back
and what I should probably been doing
they're changing the column index to 2
i'll do that to column 2 for the third
button for the second button change that
to column index 1 alright so we're got our
interface back here we had it again
and we got this spacing issues
which are we going to be addressing in
the next video but we go back and
add our hbox again come back here we can add
it and and that still not how we
want it and the moment it's not
wrapping so I'm just going to
delete that and use the mechanism i
recommend which is selecting the three
buttons right clicking wrapping h box
then we need to do that last change
which was changed the row index for the h box
to 1 and that leaves it wrap in a h box
ok let's now select the ok button again
i can click on here or i can expand this
window over here in the scene graph
expand the container should say click on
ok so we've got the property showing now
button isn't a layout but it still has
the layout area therefore controls we
can use this area to set properties that
influence how the control behaves within
its parent container now for containers
the properties in the layout area affect
how the container is laid out within its
parent or how controls are laid out
within the container that's actually
change the ok button the margin so what
I'm going to do is over here now the
little graph i'm going to really expand
this on the screen really quite largely
you can see it we got these 4 little
fields here and notice that the little
graphic above each input box is telling
us which margin is going to set so
that's obviously the first one is the
top margin the right margin the bottom
margin and the left margin going to the
enter the value of five in the second box one here
which is the right margin if i do that
press ENTER we notice we now got a
space between the ok button and the
cancel button that's because i added 5
pixel margin to the right of the ok
button so that actually put some space
between the ok and cancel buttons but
another and perhaps better way to do it
would be to set the spacing for the
h box so that all controls in the h
box
have the same amount of space between
them so let's go ahead and try doing
that I'm going to get back here
change it back to zero again enter their
to back to see what it was or to
the value that it was going to come over
here and select the h box in the
scene graph area and expand the layout
window if it's not already expanded in
this case which already is
let's now set the left and right-hand
margins over here to 5 for all controls
also the left so that is the left and the right
margins but also to actually affect all
the individual controls lets actually
change the spacing to 5 as well and you
can see that is now affected the
space between all three buttons now if
we actually click over somewhere
outside of the user interface notice now
there's a lot of space to the right of
the Help button and if we click on the
h box you can see it's not the h
box is causing that because you can
actually see this sort
of margin here to the right and that
seems to be quiet ok if we click on the
grid pane we can see that's the culprit
that's the grid pane is what is
actually selecting or using that extra
space and if we have a look over here we
can see the problem here is in the
properties for the grid pane is that the
horizontal gap settings 10 now we only
have one column so we don't need a gap
that separates columns going to set the
h gap back to zero and that then fix
our problem if i click outside here now
we can see that in
terms of the buttons
we've got a nicely sort of position in
the middle there essentially the extra
space disappeared so a simple level
that's really all there is to building a
UI using scene builder you dragged
components from the left-hand side on
into the content area and we set their
properties on the right-hand side and we
can select the component we want to work
with by clicking on its content area or
in the scene graph area and we usually
select containers in the scene graph
area when you wanna run the application
we run it in the usual way by clicking
on the run
and over here i can just right-click
I could have just run over here as
well run and there's our simple little
interface at the moment
ok the other what I find annoying
little thing that this scene builder
does if you click on controls we go back
to say the text and go back to the scene
builder it seems to lose the focus of
where we're at and you got to
re-expand to get access to the
particular controls you want again but i
will be talking I'll be talking about
using the standalone scene builder in a
future video probably in the next video
depending on how long that takes to go
through some of the other things i want
to show you bottom line is that it's
still a very useful tool so let's end
the video here now in the next video
we're going to have a look at this code
menu we haven't really talked it more we
talked a little bit about it but haven't
done anything with it so let's start
working with that in the next video