alright so let's go have a look at this
code section on the right hand side of
the scene builder now we got nothing
selected so there's nothing to or no
properties to show but being able to
build a UI using scene builder wouldn't be that
useful if you still to connect controls
to event handlers by editing the fxml
file so lets actually add an action
handler to the controller dot java file
and what we're going to do is make a
very simple event here handler here
when the ok buttons
pressed I'm going to change the text of
the label to ok button pressed now
since we'll be setting one of the labels
properties we have to declare a member
variable for it and we'll need to
associate that variable with the label
and as you recall we're going to be doing
that using these fx ID as the
variable name as we've always done now
let's go back to our controller
initially and set that up so we're going
to just type it in here the...
...
....ok so that's the code
that we're going to be working with
going back to out going back to scene builder
now we need to make the
connections so first i'm going to select
the label field clicking on that their and
again I could have selected over here if
I wanted to and expand
a little bit more so we can see
what's going on there now under code
section FX ID now sometimes it works and
sometimes it doesn't
the label will actually appear in the FX
ID well obviously this case it hasn't
appeared but what I found you can do is
you click on OK look and back and click on
text in scene builder and see if
it's going to actually work for me code
now it's not gonna work sometimes you do
actually have to type it but i want to
show you guys is I'll type their
anyway if i go back to the ok will try
again scene builder ok code so i got
label the id working successfully
there what it should be doing is
actually showing the drop downs and it
seems a little bit inconsistent that it
doesn't always show this let's make sure
the control is still correct we still got
code and obviously that hasn't
been used yet but the association's
there is now there you can see that the
code is now bold so that part's
working what we should have to do is
select from the drop-down I'm going to
type it....we go back
and check to see
the association's their associations
there but what I'm hoping to show you
but it's not playing ball with us is
that will actually give you a drop-down
it should be doing is actually giving us
a drop down here where we can actually
select the various options but it's not
actually doing it for now
what you should get and what I find does
work i had it working before is
that when you select a particular
control you actually get the little
its smart enough this drop-down list of
all the action all the event handlers
that its find and you can actually just
select the either the ID or the event
handler you want to use by a drop-down and
obviously for whatever reason that's not
working maybe it's a mac bug or the
as I said I did get it working earlier so
bottom line is if it's not coming up for
you automatically
you may have to type in the label here
but in this case what I've done now
with the ok button I have sets set the
handle action method assign that to the
on action event handler
so what that means is we should be able
to run this click on ok
and obviously got the code working in
that's actually fired up the
event handler was going to stop that
there we go now this is what I wanted to
show you perhaps it need a compilation this is what
really was trying to show you there's a
drop down there and you've got multiple
event handlers it would actually find
them for us
likewise with the label what that should
do that still not gonna play ball with
us is a drop-down that will actually
pop up here as well and we would have
been able to select the ID via drop-down
list just try deleting out of interest
updating that seems that work for us
no that is not the right dropdown just
put it back in again
alright long-winded way of showing you
how that works but the bottom line is
that we can use that code part of the
settings area to associate event
handlers and set to ids etc as we
would normally have done manually in the
code
alright so that's how we wire the
controllers to action handlers and fields
using the scene builder and just to
confirm we saw that before both the
label and the method obviously
are now enabled linked just the other
thing which you probably picked up
anyway but just to confirm when we
select the control and we've got the
code part of the settings area open when
we select a different one
it actually changes to give you only the
options that are appropriate for that
particular control only sort of action
handlers that are appropriate which is
pretty cool let's move on now and
talk about style controls with CSS when
using the scene builder now there's a
couple ways of doing this the first ways
to create a style sheet and associate
that with a container or control
let's start by doing that in intellij
and you see how to do that previously
I'm going to right-click the package
click on new select file and we'll call
this on .....and lets
create a simple style here....
...
...and go back to our layout
to scene builder and obviously
nothing's changed yet and we need to
associate what we've just created the
style sheet to our layout i'm going to select
the grid pane and in the properties
section expand this a little bit so you
can see it we have this option here for
style sheets so this plus button which
I'm going to press but fortunately the
integration with the ide is poor here
at least in the version that I'm
checking so when I click on that we
don't get a list of style sheets with this
project in fact we're going to navigate
to that project to actually be able to
select that style sheets so i'm going to go
into that folder right here in the folder
going to go to the source folder sample
and got to manually select the
styles . css once I do that
you can see straight away that the
style has taken effect and over here on
the right-hand side will be using the
stylesheet styles.css what you can also
do their now you can remove that if you
wanted to the other thing can also do is
you can actually have multiple style sheets
you can add a second if you want to we
can open the stylesheet but that
actually opens it outside IntelliJ in
whatever editor is associated with CCS
files in the system so won't flick to the file
within IntelliJ again poor
integration in this particular area
alright let's go back to the CSS file
IntelliJ and changed the green to blue
...and going back to scene builder
notice how it's still green nothing's
changed
so we still seeing green buttons
in the integration but we actually run
the app we do actually get the blue
buttons abeint ones that are very
hard to read so clearly when we run the
app it's actually looking at the updated
style sheet and making those appropriate
changes
unfortunately in terms of scene builder
it's not actually sort of rereading that
file again again poor integration and if
you're finding that when you
changes if you're following along and
you found that these buttons start
started you know you can't still read all
the texts on you can actually resize
these things literally can just move
over your mouse over there and that's
notice when I do that i can make the buttons
bigger or smaller come over here if I wanted
to expand it will make it smaller as
appropriate to resize that's how you do
your resizing you can resize there or
you can click on grid pane and do it
that way by grabbing the sides of each
button and the resizing as appropriate
alright so anyway the bottom line here
is in terms of CSS the integration isn't
great with
intellij ok it's pretty well non
existent if we want you use css to
style our controls my suggestion is to
use scene builder in standalone mode
which would be more convenient and
i'm going to show you how to do the
little bit later for now though
in addition to associated a style sheet
with a container or controls we can
actually also set styles by typing
into the style area i'll show you what I mean
we click on ok we're going to
just put a style on that individual ok
a button down here we've got these two
style input boxes in there what i
can do is i can type in...
...
...and see how
we put an individual style for the ok
button and you can also press + button
if you had more than one style that you
want to associate to one control the other
thing is if you look at the top of the
screen you'll notice got CSS I know it
is a very small font pretty hard to read
but it's got font text was got CSS which
is telling us that the CSS is taking
control of those properties and that
prevents us from accidentally overriding
a value that's been set using CSS it's
pretty cool that it's telling us that
alright so we now know how to style
properties in scene builder using CSS but
really it's not that convenient
so let's actually try running scene
builder as a standalone
application and take a look at the css
integration there to do so here's how to
actually start scene builder stand-alone on a
Windows machine so windows to start scene builder
we can just click on your Start
menu and I can see that I've got scene builder
showing here so i can just
click on that to start it
alternatively you can click on all apps
and it'll be installed under glue on
which is the name of the company scene builder
click on that and that should
start scene builder there we go we got
the stand alone scene builder working on a
linux machine you start scene builder
up by going to the folder where you
actually installed scene builder and
starting it and on a mac I can actually
just press command space and type
scene builder press ENTER and that's going
too fire up scene builder alright i'm just
going to size this up so you can see in a much
larger size now now notice that scene builder
got this menu bar at the top
of the screen here and then enables us
to get access to quite a few extra
features so we can actually open up our
file that we want to work on let's go ahead
and do that file open going to navigate
to the folder where my project is so
here I am in scene builder folder
this intelliJ project
now we are getting down i'm going to open the
sample .fxml that's pretty well
that mirror image of what's currently in
IntelliJ let's actually go back to
IntelliJ and change the style sheet and
change from blue to purple
okay if I go back to scene builder notice
the change was reflected automatically
got this file styles.css was modified
pop-up and the change was instantly
reflected in the UI much better than
working with CSS inside intellij
so if you'll be working on an
application that uses CSS and want to use
scene builder
this is the way to go using it
standalone you can see any changes
without having to run the application
so let's now pretend that we want
to add a table to our grid pane rather
than scrolling through the long list of
controls over here
left we also got a search capability if you
type table and notice how as i'm
typing the library field the area
was updated to show just those controls
that fulfill that criteria so basically the columns
are dynamically matching are updated to
match what we've been looking for and I
can click on table view and actually
click on control if I want to quickly
find out to look for a particular
property i can also do that for example
type effect and get quickly to the field
that I want to work with or I could do
something like the v gap if that's what i was
looking to do with grid pane selected
perhaps v gap and it would actually
show just those properties that basically
match what I'm typing a very quick way to
actually get to the area you want to get
when you're editing your fxml files
now in the standard scene builder there's
also a controller section over here this
is where we specify the controller
that's associated with the FXML we are
editing that's already set because it
was set in the fxml file that we opened
but it wasn't this is where would set it
as you can see there's also a handy
table here that actually lists all the
FX ids defined in the fxml file now
the hierarchy section above the
controller open that out is the same as
what we were calling the scene graph
area it's not labeled with the scene builder
was integrated into IntelliJ now
we can't run an application from the
standard scene builder it is
strictly a UI builder to run our
application will open whatever ide
we're working with and obviously
intelliJ for this course and run it
from there so the workflow would be to
create the project for the javafx
application within IntelliJ and
to create the xml file within their once
all automatically generated and then to
open the fxml with the ID
knows about in scene builder and if you're
using CSS we can also edit the
css files in the ide as we've seen
and the stand alone scene builder
will notice any changes
alright so that's it for our look at
scene builder we can use scene builder to
build a UI for our applications can also
be used to quickly prototype our user
interface
and if we're writing the FXml by hand
and we're not sure how to change the
property or how to position of control
where we want it i suggest you use scene builder
for that and then look at the
fxml that it generates however i think it's
important not to become too dependent on
the scene builder for creating user
interfaces
that's because these tools can go away
and it's always a good thing to know how
to write code before we used tools that
actually generates for us so we're
basically here with a tool that's
currently working combining the best of
both worlds we still got the capability
of editing the fxml if we want but we
can use the scene builder
just short cut our create user
interface creations so while the
integration with intellij can be
convenient if you plan to you scene builder
a lot actually say use the
stand alone version and because it's got
more features and it's especially true
as you saw for using CSS also keep in mind
that there are other ides for example
netbeans also integrates the scene builder
so you might want to check that
out to see if the integrations any
better and it's actually free and that
is actually a stack overflow
answer here that explains how to do it
so quickly bring up on the screen so
you could perhaps have a look at doing
that in net beans if you wanted to show
you how to go about doing that
keep in mind working with net beans the
scene builder integration is looser so
it doesn't integrate scene builder into
IDE user interface but runs the
standalone version which gives us access
to the search field and the menu bar so
which ide to use is a matter of personal
preference
net beans has got a fantastic swing UI
builder and many java ui developers
are in the habit of using it but I think
it's a good combination still to stick
with IntelliJ and just use the standalone
scene builder if you're looking to build CSS
or use CSS within your user interface
alright so that's it that's the end of
our work through with the scene builder I
hope you got a lot out of it and in the next
video we're going to start a challenge
for this section of the course see you
in the next video