So this is Part 2 of
the encapsulation videos.
This is the challenge exercise.
So let's type up what the challenge is.
[NOISE] So this is the encapsulation
challenge to create a class and
to demonstrate proper
encapsulation techniques such
you've learned in the previous video.
The class to create will
be called printer, and
it's going to simulate a real
computer printer a laser printer.
So some of the fields that should
exist in the class, should be one for
the toner level, the percentage of how
much toner level is left, the number of
pages that have been printed, and
also whether it's a duplex printer.
Now duplex printer is capable of
printing on both sides of the paper.
So you'll want to add
methods to fill up the toner,
which should fill it up to a maximum
of 100% based on the current value.
So if it's only 50% full, you have to
figure out a way to make sure that
it doesn't go up beyond 100%, and you need
to add another method to simulate printing
a page, which should increase the number
of pages printed variable as well.
And you also want to take into
account the duplex functionality,
and print out a message if the printer
is a duplex printer when it's printing.
Finally, decide on the scope,
whether to use constructors or anything
else you think is needed to demonstrate
proper encapsulation techniques.
So pause the video now, go away and
check that out and try that out.
And when you're ready to come back and
see my solution, start the video again and
I'll go through it with you.
Okay.
How did you get on,
did you create a solution for
the printer class, using good sound and
capitulation techniques?
So, let's give it a go.
We're gonna create a new
class called printer.
So I'm going to go and do that now.
Printer.
And we need some fields.
We need a field for the toner level, so
I'm going to create just an integer,
private int tonerLevel.
And what I'm going to do there is,
I'm gonna set that to make
the only allowable values to
be between one and 100, and
each number, from one to 100, is going to
be the percentage full that the toner is.
Pages printer printed is going
to be an integer as well.
Pages printed, and lastly whether
the printer is a duplex printer,
in other words capable of printing
both double sided I should say.
I'm gonna create a Boolean variable,
We're gonna call it Duplex.
That's set to true, that means it
is a two-sided page printer and
if it's false, it's just a single page.
So next we need to create a constructor.
So what I'm going to do is just
that: create a constructor.
And what I'm going to do is,
I'm going to set two fields as
the constructor parameters.
The toner level and
also whether it's duplex.
I'm going to leave printers, pages
printed rather, out of the constructor,
because that would normally be something
that's set in the actual printer itself.
It wouldn't be something
that you would create, or
you need to add into the constructor.
I'm going to initialize that to zero.
We're gonna click on those two.
And set those as you can see there.
And I'm also going to put
this.pagePrinted = 0;.
We're also going to do a test here.
We're going to put, If tonerLevel
greater than negative 1, because we
can't allow the toner to be empty.
So I want to make sure the value that
we're going to accept is between zero and
100, and the toner level is less than or
equal to a 100.
Then we're gonna put else.
What we're going to do is we're going to
put this.tonerLevel equals negative 1.
So, that's often a way
to set a variable and
make it just indicate that it
hasn't been set correctly,
by setting it to negative 1 if it
doesn't fulfill some validation.
So that's our constructor.
So next we need to create a few methods.
The first one, we want to create
a method to replace the toner.
Making sure we can't get it beyond 100%.
So I'm gonna create a public method.
It's not going to be void, it's going
to actually return and the integer is
going to be how much toner we actually
added, making sure we don't exceed 100.
So we're going put addToner.
We're going to accept a parameter
which is the TonerAmount.
So the first thing we need to do
is make sure that the amount of
toner that's been passed
to this method is valid.
So to do that,
by putting if(tonerLevel >0 ).
Now we're doing a > in this case, because
the very effect of adding toner to a cart,
to a printer is,
you need to actually add something.
And like the constructor, which we set up,
which actually created printer object,
that could have a value of
zero to set the initial level.
We're actually now creating
a method called add toner.
We're actually adding some toner
to the printer, so therefore,
we want to make sure that the toner
level is actually greater than zero.
So, it's greater than zero and
toner level.
So, the toner amount that should
be is less than or equal to 100.
This one there should be toner amount.
So, that's the toner amount that
we're actually trying to add to it.
And we'll come back and
add that code shortly.
But we're gonna put an else Return- 1;.
Again that's another way of returning
some sort of way of validation.
Some sort of status.
In this case we're saying,
if it falls outside
of the return amount being greater than
zero and less than or equal to a hundred.
We're going to return -1, which is our way
of saying you attempted to add some toner
to the printer but
it was outside our valid ranges.
So therefore what we need to do now is,
we need to actually test the amount
of toner that's already on hand.
So, we need to add to that the toner
amount that was passed to this method.
And if it actually exceeds
the total amount of 100%,
we need to return an error.
To do that,
we are going to put if(this.tonerLevel
+ tonerAmount) Is greater than 100,
Return negative one.
So there's our test to say that if,
for example,
there was 50% fo the toner was half full.
So the value of level
of toner was set to 50.
If we get past an amount of 60,
if we added the 60% to the 50,
that would be actually 110% full,
which is not possible.
So, we're not going to allow that.
So, we're doing a test to
add those two together.
And if they're greater than 100,
that means we're trying to overfill it,
which is impossible.
So, we're just gonna
return an invalid number.
Otherwise, at this point,
we're now able to add the values,
because we know that we've
validated it correctly.
So, we're gonna this.tonerLevel
+= tonerAmount.
Like so.
And then we can put
return dot toner level.
So, we're gonna actually return
the amount that it's now set to.
So adding the toner and it's returning how
much toner is now in the toner cartridge.
I mean returning a negative
one if there was an error.
And if that's the case we're
not actually setting anything,
we're not changing the value
of our toner level.
So let's have a go by adding
the toner in our method.
So the next thing to do is now to
actually implement the printing.
So I'm going to add the printing method.
So I'm going to click on public
int Print pages, we're gonna call it print
pages even though it's possible
to print just the one page.
We're gonna put int pages,
the number of pages to print.
Print.
What we're going to do is we're going to
assume that the page count is actually
the number of physical pieces of paper
that are going through the printer.
So therefore, if we are in duplex mode,
If we're printing on both sides, what we
need to do is divide the total number of
pages by two because that's the net
number of pages that were printed.
So what we're going to do is, we're going
to put int pages to print equals pages.
And we're going to put if this.duplex,
we are going to put pages to
print divided equals two.
We are going to divide the total
number of pages by two
if we are printing in JPEG mode.
Then we also have to print out a message
to put printing in duplex mode,
just so it's clear that we're
actually printing in the duplex mode.
So that's our print pages method.
And the other thing we need to do
is return the number of pages that
were printed.
So we're gonna type return,
pages to print.
And of course there's also another thing
we need to do, we need to update the pages
printed but for this.pagesPrinted
plus=pagesToPrint like so.
alright so
inside the print pages method there's a
logical error now when printing the odd
number of pages the result is in fact
not correct for example printing five
pages in duplex
prints two pages instead of three so to
fix that the code inside the if
statement should be and i'm showing that
on the screen now pages to print equals
parentheses pages divided by 2 plus
parentheses pages modulus 2 the modulus
operator in other words and the modulus
by the way or remainder operator it
requires two operands and it's a
division operation the remainder is
returned by using that operator so
basically in this scenario in case the
result is an odd number of pages the
remainder will be one
and therefore the page to print number
will in fact be correct and just to
thanks to quite a few students who
pointed this out i've now updated this
video to reflect that all right so
moving on
So that's that, and the last thing
we want to do is to add a getter.
So that we can actually retrieve
the number of pages printed
to check that the value
was correct like so.
So that's our basic class now.
So let's go and try using this class.
When we go to this class here now,
the main class and printer.
Call it new printer.
Of course the parameters are toner level,
we're gonna start with 50%,
and we're gonna say true initially.
So let's try doing the page count,
so we know what the page count is,
it should be equal to zero, so
we'll put Initial page count is,
equals printer.get pages printed.
And again we're using encapsulation here
with our constructor, and also with our
getter here so we're not accessing
the field directly which is correct.
Encapsulation techniques object r and
data programming So lets now print say,
four pages.
So we are going put printer,
what we will do is put int pages
printed equals printer dot print pages,
and we will say four initially.
We are going to put pages printed was,
because remember this is how many
physical sheets of paper were printed,
pages printed and then we will
put plus new total print count.
For printer = and that's gonna be our " +
printer.getPagesPrinted ());.
Like so, so let's try running
that first and see what it does.
I'll just move this over so
we can see it a bit better.
So the initial page count was zero,
which is correct.
Printing in duplex mode has been set
because we just defined that to true.
Pages printed was two, because that's the
total number of pages was actually four,
but because we're printing on both sides,
it's only two.
New total print count for
printer equals two as well.
That's correct.
And just to make sure,
let's do another one.
Let's put, we'll put pages
printed = printer.printPages.
Let's say there's another two pages.
And let's just print it out again.
So, let's now run that.
And you can see that what's
happened here is working correctly.
It's now the second example.
It's printing in duplex mode again.
The pages printed was one,
because we passed only two pages.
We have two pages to print,
and it printed on both sides.
New count print for the printer overall,
is now = 3, which of course is
one more than the previous count.
So that's the total number of pages, 84
pages, that have gone through the printer.
So that's working, and then just to
confirm, let's set duplex to false,
and what we should do is
get some different values
here now because we're not printing
on both sides of the printer.
Of all the paper I should say.
Run that,
this your page count was equal to zero.
Pages printed with a four,
new total count for printer equals four.
That's because we're now
not printing in duplex,
maybe we're not printing double sided.
So four pages to print used
four sheets of paper, and
in the second example we used another two
pieces of paper, and it needed two pages.
Two, because that's we actually
passed too as a parameter.
And the total print count was six.
So that's the printer
class using encapsulation.
So it's very, very good object
orientated sound programming practice
to use encapsulation to hide that
functionality from your other classes.
In this case, you can see that we're
not accessing any fields directly,
and we've got proper methods that
are actually doing the appropriate
calculations or adding and subtraction
numbers hidden away from the user.
So if you are someone who's
using this printer class,
you've got no idea of the internal
workings of that class.
And in fact you don't need to know it,
because all you're doing is you're using
any of these methods that
have been set to public.
Scope of public.
And you're using those in a correct manner
and everything's working perfectly.
So that's it,
that's the encapsulation challenge.
I hope you got a lot out of that.
Let's move on now to the next video, where
we're gonna be talking about polymorphism
and what that is and
how to use that in our Java programs.