Because of the size of this course and the sheer amount
of content covered in it, from time to time
you may have the need to have a question answered.
So you might have a question,
you might be stuck and need some help.
This video is all about showing you
how to get help in that situation.
So firstly, what you need to do to get help is to log in
to the course, and when you log in, you've got
these options, as you can see in the screen there.
Choose Q&amp;A.
When you do that, you can click
on Ask a Question, and enter a title about the question
and a detailed description, and I'll talk more
about the tops of how to go about
describing the problem, and then post the question.
So it's literally that easy.
And myself, or Goren, my teaching assistant,
or even another student, a member of the community,
will pop in there and actually help you out.
Here's an example post, just to give you an idea.
So note the title and the description there.
But also, the other thing I wanna show you is
if you've got some source code that's not working,
and this is a programming course,
that's, probably a large amount of cases,
the reason why you're posting...
So if it's not working, don't do a screen image.
I suggest you actually post the code.
So click here and you can paste the code directly in.
And notice that when you do that,
it gets all nicely colour coded and formatted.
So that's the preference.
That makes it easy for other people
to actually take that code and try and use it.
Because if you post an image, if you take a screenshot
of the problem you're having, it's not possible
for someone to grab your code and paste it
into their IDE, into IntelliJ, and get a result,
and try and figure out what's going on.
So if you posted a source code, it just makes it
a lot easier, and again, doing it that way means
that it's all nicely colour coded and formatted.
And you're just increasing the chances,
is what I'm trying to say, of getting your resolution.
All right, but keep in mind that I mentioned images.
You can upload images.
Sometimes images are preferable.
You've got some other issue where you want
to supplement what you've shown,
or you put in your description with an image,
that's how you can upload an image, as well.
So that's also a clue to this, and do that if you need to.
And the other thing I wanna point out, though,
is before you actually ask a question,
try and take advantage of the search facility,
because the chances are pretty high
there's been another student who's had a similar
or the same exact problem that you're having right now.
I say right now, but you're still
watching this video, not coding.
But as you go through, chances are pretty high
that you'll find someone who's been in a similar situation.
Now the search, very simple, as you can see there.
Just type the question here, as you can see,
and it brings up an answer.
Notice that you can search all questions,
all lectures rather, or a specific lecture.
So you might want to hone
your results to a specific lecture.
That can be a good idea, if you've got a problem
with a specific lecture, to try
and search just within that lecture.
But you can also search across all lectures, as well.
And there's lots and lots of questions.
I think at last count, there's 38,000 questions
that have been answered, or more,
so huge amount of questions here.
So make sure you take advantage of that.
It'll definitely help you out.
All right, now the other thing I wanted to quickly raise
is just some tips on actually asking questions.
And this'll help you in your future career
as a programmer, as well.
Firstly, be as specific as you possibly can.
So if you're getting stuck on a particular lecture,
if you just post a question and say,
"I can't get this code to work.
"I can't get the code from this lecture to work."
That's technically correct.
It's probably not working for you.
But it makes it really hard for anyone else to try
and help you, because you haven't
given us any information to work with.
So basically, let us know the lecture
that you're working on, paste in the code you've used,
using what I showed you earlier in the video,
and maybe a screenshot of the exact area,
if you need to do that, as opposed to the code,
the actual error message and so forth you're getting.
And this is great practise for you
for when you become a programmer in the real world,
because that's what you need to do.
If you're starting out at a new job,
and you go to your team leader
or your senior programmer who's working with you,
or even to a peer programmer, you need
to give them as much information as possible.
People aren't gonna be happy if you just say,
"This is not working, can you help me?"
Because we're all busy in today's society.
So basically what I'm saying is,
be as specific as possible, and that's gonna really help you
get some answers quicker and make you
a better programmer in the longer term.
The other thing that's also useful is,
it's usually better to ask a new question,
rather than appending your question
to another question that's been previously answered,
unless your question is completely related
to that one, if that makes sense.
And the reason for that is, some of this depends
on the notification system of Udemy.
Sometimes some of the older questions,
if you post a follow-up question to a question
that's maybe been answered six months ago,
those notifications don't always come through to the people
who are trying to answer these questions for you.
So it's usually better to post a new question,
and get an answer to it that way.
But again, always make sure
you use the search facility first because
that's gonna help you a lot, and give you the skills
to make you a great, productive programmer.
All right, so that's support.
I'll finish the video here.
Let's move on now, to the next video.