In this video we're going to download
and instal Amazon Corretto,
which is the Java Development Kit for the Windows platform.
So first things first,
we're gonna do a little search for Amazon Corretto.
C-O-R-R-E-T-T-O.
And click on the http://www.Amazon.com/Corretto link.
And we're gonna come over here
and click on Download Amazon Corretto 11,
which is the JDK version 11.
And once we get to here, we'll choose our platform.
We're on Windows, so I'm gonna come over here
and click on the MSI file,
which is the executable installer file.
Alternatively, you can download the ZIP file if you want.
There's probably no reason to do that.
We're going to run the instal.
And that'll finish off in this case downloading first,
and then it's going to start with the installation.
You can see that Windows is doing a security scan,
we'll let that finish.
All right, so it's starting the Setup Wizard now.
We're gonna click on Next.
Now noting that the folder that
it's going to be installed in here,
C:\Program Files\Amazon Corretto\
That may be important in a future video,
so you might want to keep a note of that folder.
Also note that here,
that it's going to set up our environment variables
and registry keys for us which is nice.
So that means that it's just something else
we don't need to set up, which is good.
Click on Next and click on Instal.
And once this finishes, I'm just going to the command line.
We'll just click on Yes to the little prompt
that pops up about whether you want to allow this app
to make changes to your device.
So I click on Yes.
And I let the installation complete.
Click on Finish and the installation is now completed.
And one final step is just to come down
to the Start window for Windows here,
click on Command, C-M-D, or type in Command,
and we're gonna type in: java -version
And noting that we've now got some output,
it says: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM Corretto.
So that confirms that the installation
has been successfully installed,
and then the Java Development Kit
is now installed on the computer.
All right, so now that's the installation
of Amazon Corretto JDK for Windows version 11 completed.