- [Tim] In the last two videos,
we looked at the low-level
networking API, which
involves ports and sockets.
Now while it's important to understand
the low-level concepts,
most modern applications
are mainly interested in
accessing the internet,
and we'll use the high-level API to do so.
So in the next two videos,
we're going to look at the high-level API,
which abstracts networking
concepts even further.
So using the high-level
API, you don't actually
even need to know about ports and sockets.
Instead, you'll use URIs and URLs.
The URI stands for universal
resource identifier,
and URL stands for
universal resource locator.
So what is actually the difference
between a URL and a URI?
You'd think that this would
be an easy question to answer,
but it's not necessarily that easy.
So we just bring a up a webpage.
Paste in this link.
So if we have a look here,
you'll see there's a whole paper,
quite a detailed paper as I
scroll down the screen there,
from the W3C, that's the
World Wide Web Consortium,
by the way, who's responsible
for web standards.
This entire paper is trying to explain
the difference between a URL and a URI.
So a good section to start with would
be this section here under confusion.
The body of documents, RFI's, etc.,
covering URI architecture,
syntax, registration, etc.,
spans both the classical
and contemporary periods.
The people who are well
versed in URI matters
tend to use URL, and URI writers
seem to be interchangeable.
So among these experts,
this isn't a problem,
but among the internet
community at large it is.
So people are not convinced
that URI and URL mean
the same thing in documents
where they apparently do.
So when one sees an RFC, by the way an RFC
is a request for comments, by the way.
It's a formal document from
the Internet Engineering Task Force.
So when one sees an RFC that
talks about URI schemes,
another that talks about URL schemes,
and yet another that talks of URN schemes,
it's probably pretty
natural to wonder what
the difference is and how
they relate to each other.
So it can be a bit
confusing, but with that
set aside let's stick to what we need
to know to write Java networking code.
Now when working with
a java dot net package,
a URI is an identifier that
might not provide enough
information to access the
resource that it identifies.
Now a URL, on the other
hand, is an identifier
that includes information about how
to access the resource that it identifies.
So another way to state this is that a URI
can specify a relative path, but a URL has
to be an absolute path,
because when we use the URL,
it has to contain enough information
to locate and access the
resource that it identifies.
Now it's actually easy to
convert between URLs and URIs.
So all you really have to do is provide
what the method you want to use requires,
a URL or a URI, and
you'll actually be fine.
Now the recommended practise when working
with the java dot net
classes is to use a URI
until you actually want
to access a resource,
and then to convert the URI to a URL.
So having said that, sometimes
there's no need to start
with the URI, because the
method you'll use to open
or access a resource accepts
a URL right off the bat.
Now I know that sounds terribly confusing,
but let's see if we can make
a bit more sense of this.
So a scheme is part of a URI or URL
that appears before the colon.
For example, HTTP, file, and
FTP, well they're all schemes.
So another way to define a
URL is that it's a HTTP URI.
So again this terminology
can be confusing.
So developers often use
the terms URI and URL
interchangeably even though
it's technically wrong to do so.
Or they use URI, but they mean URL.
So according to some
developers and documentation,
the term URL is now outdated
and shouldn't be used,
but many developers and
many APIs still use that.
So the point here I'm trying to make
is don't worry about this terminology.
Understanding the sometimes
razor-thin difference
between a URI and a URL
really isn't necessary
to get your feet wet with
writing networking code.
Now if you recall when we
worked with the low-level API,
we used the following classes.
Socket, ServerSocket, and DatagramSocket.
When working with the high-level API,
we're gonna be using
the following classes.
URI, URL, URLConnection,
as well as HttpURLConnection.
So let's actually start with URIs.
We're not gonna spend
too much time on them,
because you'll use URLs
when accessing the internet.
So a URI can actually
contain nine components.
The scheme, number one.
The scheme-specific part, number two.
The authority, number three.
The user info, number four.
The host, number five
Six is the port.
Path, number seven.
Query, number eight.
And fragment, number nine.
And you can see there that
I've got on the screen there
a generic form of a URI,
outlining each component,
and that's taken from the Wikipedia link.
I'll also attach this in
the resources section of this video.
The good thing is you're
gonna see examples of this
as we progress through
the next few videos.
So URIs that specify scheme here,
well they're called absolute URIs.
And when a URI doesn't specify scheme,
it's actually called a relative URI.
Alright, so let's actually go back
to IntelliJ and start creating some code.
So you can see that I've created
a new project here called
networking, so do that if you
haven't already done that.
And let's make a start by adding
some code to the main method.
So we're gonna start with URI, capitals.
You'll notice that
that's wanting to import,
we wanna specify the java dot net one.
The URI is equal to new URI.
We're gonna have DB colon,
forward slash forward slash.
Username colon password.
At my server dot com, colon
5000, forward slash catalogue,
forward slash phones, question mark,
OS equals Android, hash Samsung.
Actually what we'll do is we'll pull aside
surround this in a try catch loop.
We're gonna catch a URI syntax exception.
Okay, back to our code.
So let's now get access to
these individual components
that we talked about in the slides.
So it'll start with the scheme.
So we can do scheme equals
plus URI dot get scheme.
Next we're going to do
the scheme-specific part.
So scheme-specific part is equal to
plus URI dot get scheme specific part.
Authority.
Next we're going to do user info.
That's URI dot get user info.
Next we'll do host, so host equals
URI dot get host
Port, so port equals
plus URI dot get port.
Path, path equals plus URI dot get path.
Next after path, query
equals URI dot get query.
And the last one, fragment.
So fragment.
Fragment equals plus URI dot get fragment.
Alright so in the code here,
we've created a URI instance
for a URL that will form a database query.
So if we actually run this
just to see what happens.
So you see we've got, first,
what scheme equals DB?
The path that actually occurs
before the colon in the URI on line 10.
Now you can write your own schemes,
although you're encouraged not
to do so to avoid name conflicts.
Though usually when you want
to define your own scheme,
there's alternate ways to accomplish
what you're trying to do.
Using name spaces is one example for that.
Next is the scheme-specific part.
This is everything after the colon,
before the hash as you can see there.
So this is the identifier
for the resource that you wanna use.
So in this case it's a
query for the phones table
on the phones table in
the catalogue database.
Now the authority, as you
can see there on the screen,
that contains the host
and optionally a password,
as well as the username and port number.
Now the host can be a registered
name, as in the example,
or an IPv4 slash IPv6 address.
User info, the next one,
that contains the username and password.
Basically any credentials
required to access the resource.
The host is the host name,
or an IPV4 or IPv6 address.
The port is obviously the port number.
Now the path is catalogue slash
phones as you can see here
or slash catalogue slash phones.
It's the path to the resource on the host.
So in this case the resource is a database
and the path points to a specific
table within the database.
Now the query, the next one.
That's always separated from the part
that comes before it by a question mark.
So in this case the query
is OS equals Android,
as you can see there.
The syntax can actually be in any format,
because the standard
doesn't strictly define it,
but it's often a set of key value pairs.
And finally the last one, fragment,
well that specifies a
secondary resource or location.
So in this case it's saying that
only Samsung phones should be returned.
Now if the URI pointed to a webpage,
the fragment could be an
ID, a section heading,
for example, in the HTML itself.
So as you may have
noticed there is overlap
between the contents of
some of these components.
And also many of the
components are optional.
So instead let's actually
make a change here.
We're gonna change the URI completely.
You're gonna make that instead of along
with the database example,
let's just type in hello there.
Now if you should run this,
notice that there's no exceptions thrown,
but as you can see on the screen there,
there's many parts now
that are showing as no,
and also negative one being
printed for the port number.
So, point is though, it's
still a well-formed URI.
It doesn't have a scheme part
because there's no colon,
but it has a path and
a scheme-specific part.
Now of course this resource doesn't exist,
but that doesn't really matter.
Just as with files, until you actually try
to access a resource, it
doesn't have to exist.
And remember that you will use a URL,
rather than a URI, when you
actually access a resource.
Now the only other thing
that I'm gonna touch on
for URIs is how to convert them to URLs.
So let's change the URL
back to one that's sensible.
So I'm gonna undo that change,
well I'm gonna comment that out.
And bring back the other example again.
Alright, I'm commenting it.
And let's comment out the code
that was printing out the
various components for now.
Instead what we're gonna do,
let's have a go at
converting this URI to a URL.
So to do that, just type URL, that's URL,
is equal to URI dot to URL.
Print it out.
URL equals plus URL.
And the other thing we'd wanna do here
is we need to catch a different exception.
We can see over here, you come up,
it's looking for a
malformed URL exception.
So let's catch that one.
So URL malformed.
E dot get message.
So obviously we're using
the URI dot to URL method
to actually perform the conversion to URL.
So if I actually run this,
we actually get an exception,
and the exception was actually caught,
and you can see here we're
printing or executing
the malformed URL exception code block,
or the call exception,
unknown protocol DB.
So hopefully that now demonstrates to you
that the URI doesn't have
to be valid to work with it.
It only has to be valid
when you wanna convert it
to an absolute location,
as we're trying to do here
on the code on line 14 by
converting it to a URL.
So let's actually change the scheme
to something that we're
much more familiar with.
Come back and change
the DB to HTTP instead.
Run that.
You can see that the URL
is now equal to the URI,
because the URI is an absolute path.
Obviously no exceptions
have actually thrown now.
Alright, so let's actually
take a look at a relative URI.
So comment that one out.
And then we'll go with something like,
well actually what we'll do is we'll just
delete the first part up until
the forward slash catalogue.
Cut this out, or just that part of it now,
so it's a relative URI.
So now you can see the
URI is a relative URI
because it doesn't completely
identify the resource.
So in other words it
doesn't contain the schemer,
so you don't know if the
URI points to a webpage or
a database or a file or you
know, perhaps something else.
It doesn't contain the root location,
so if it's, if this was a webpage,
the URL doesn't contain the server
or any credentials required
to access the location.
It also doesn't specify database table
for a disc driver location.
So in other words, there isn't enough
information here to really
access the resource.
So the question for you now would be,
do you think you can
convert this URI to a URL?
Well let's actually run the
code and see what happens.
You can see we've actually
got an exception here,
illegal argument exception
which we haven't tried to catch.
So a URI is not absolute.
Now earlier in this video, I said that
the URIs can be relative, but URLs have
to be absolute, so the
exception makes sense here.
Because we converted to a
URL, it's not gonna be valid
unless the URL ends up
being an absolute URL.
So you kinda get an absolute
URL from a relative URI,
in other words, because there
isn't enough information in
the URI to determine the absolute
location of the resource.
Now when you wanna access a
resource, you will use a URL.
At that point the location
of the resource has
to be absolute, otherwise
the Java Runtime won't
have enough information
ultimately to access it.
Now there will be times when
you wanna relative URIs though,
but usually you'll use
them along with a base URI.
So this base URI will specify the root
of the relative path,
which can be quite handy.
And if you're accessing
lots of pages on a website,
and instead of working with absolute URIs,
it's probably better to have a base URI
that contains the host
information than a bunch
of relative URIs for the specific pages.
Therefore in that scenario,
if the host location changes,
you only really have
to update the base URI.
So let's as an example say
that the host is located
at HTTP example dot com, but later on
it changes to HTTP example dot org.
And if you've used absolute
URIs throughout your code,
you'll have to go through your code
and change each and every URI instance.
But if you've used relative
URIs with a base URI,
then you really only have to change
the one instance of the base URI.
So let's add the base
URI for our relative URI.
So I'm gonna come back and
add some code above that.
So we're gonna call that URI,
base URI is equal to new URI.
And we're gonna copy that part
from the commented out code
up to but not including
the slash after the port.
Now paste that in there and that's
the base URI, as you can see there.
So now that we've done
that, we can make a change.
What we're gonna do is after that URI,
we're gonna create a third URI.
So URI, we'll call this
one resolved URI, equals.
That's gonna be equal to
base URI dot resolve URI.
Now down here we're gonna have
to change this URI, instead of URI now
we're gonna be working
with the resolved URL.
So basically when you
wanna access a webpage
on the my server dot com host,
you'll combine the base
URI with the relative URI
for the webpage, or API or
servers you wanna access,
using the URL dot resolve method.
You can see that we've done that,
so we've created our base URL on line 13.
We've left our relative URI on line 14,
and on line 15 we've
created a resolve URI,
which is the base URI dot resolve URI,
which is basically pending that
and forming a valid absolute URI.
You can see here that we're therefore
able to convert it into a URL.
Now let's just run this to
make sure that it does work.
And you can see we've
got no more exceptions,
and we've successfully
converted that into a URL.
Alright, so let's end the video here.
In the next video we'll continue on,
and we'll do a little bit
more with relative URIs.
So I'll see you in the next video.