In the previous video we finished
off our encapsulation challenge,
let's make a start at one polymorphism.
So I'm gonna go through and
give you an overview of what it is and
show you how it works.
And then in the video following this one,
we're going to give you a challenge for
it.
Now, incidentally,
this is take two of my polymorphism video.
You can see at the top of the screen
there it says polymorphism two.
And that's because I recorded
the entire lecture and
went to edit the video and
found the sound was corrupted.
Very frustrating having to do it twice.
So anyway.
Let's get started.
So, polymorphism is really the method or
the mechanism in object oriented
programming, that allows actions to
act differently based on the actual
object that the object, or sorry,
that the action is being performed on.
Now that probably doesn't make a lot
of sense, so the easiest way is,
as is the case with a lot of programming
things, is to show you an example.
So what I'm going to do to
actually demonstrate polymorphism.
You need to create a number of classes.
And what I'm going to do is
I'm gonna create the classes.
All within this main public class that, or
this main.java source file I should say.
Which is another way of creating
classes that aren't going to be reused.
The advantage of doing this,
it's really only useful to create classes,
usually, in the same Java source files
if they are quite small and compact.
If you start creating big classes and.
Here, you've got moddable
classes in a single Java file,
you can find it gets quite confusing.
And bear in mind also,
that when you're creating these classes,
they're usually are actual,
depending on the modifiers you're using,
they may or may not be accessible
outside of the package.
So, we'll talk more about scope in
a future video but suffice to say now
that the reason that I'm doing this is, is
just to save a bit of time in the videos.
So what we're going to do is we're gonna
create a basic class called movie, and
then we're gonna create a number of
classes that relate to a specific
movie that's coming out of the pass.
I'm just gonna inherit from that.
I'm gonna show you how polymorphism works.
So, firstly, I've got this main.java
created, which is our standard template.
I'm gonna create a new class, class movie,
and it's going to have one field.
We're gonna have a private
string which is going to be
the name of the movie,
we're going to have a constructor and
it's purpose is just to set the value for
our field.
We're also going to
have another method and
that method is going to be called plot and
that's going to be plot on a film itself,
in other words a synopsis
of what the movie is about.
So public string plot is the method name,
as you can see there.
And the default string I'm going to
return is going to be no plot here.
And that will make sense shortly
when we start creating some
of these other classes.
So, let's have base class.
And we're gonna create five
additional classes now.
And they're all going to inherit
from this base movie class,
first one, Class Jaws,
[NOISE] extends Movie.
I'm not sure if you've seen it,
but Jaws was a classic movie.
For you to create a constructor for that,
we're gonna do constructors in a slightly
different way for these sub classes.
We're going to do a public Jaws.
We're gonna put super Jaws so
I'm going to initialize that.
And you can see that using inheritance,
we're actually initializing
the name field from the base class.
Which is in this case is the movie class.
So that's our constructor,
pretty straightforward.
But we're also gonna create
a method called plot.
It's gonna have exactly the same
parameters and return type,
in other words no parameters and
the same return type,
which is string as the base movie
class we're gonna call plot.
We're actually gonna now return the plot
of Jaws, shark eats lots of people.
I'm sure there's more to it than that,
but that's a little summary.
Okay, so let's have jaws class and notice
how the method is exactly the same as
the method that's in movie,
so we're overriding that.
So, probably what I should have done
more correctly is use the override but
either way the same process applies,
method has been overwritten.
The next one we're gonna
create is Independence Day.
Another one of the movies that I like.
And then also extends Movie.
We're gonna have a public constructor.
Incidentally, if we uses
the automatic constructor creation.
Actually gets it a little bit wrong,
cuz it assumes that we want to initialize
the class using a parameter, but we don't
actually wanna do that in this case, so
we're gonna actually delete that and
just type it in there.
For our polymorphism example,
it makes more sense to do it this way.
Independence Day, and
what I was saying was, we can override it.
We could also use override method,
which is the same as typing it manually.
And you can see there it's got the two,
the construct that we can override but
it's also it's got the method plot we
can override, so I'm gonna select that,
press enter.
But I'm not gonna use the super,
I'm just gonna do a return.
Aliens attempt to take over planet earth.
And I spell that wrong.
Independence Day.
That's right.
Okay.
So we've got a few more to create.
So, let's create another one now for
Maze Runner,
another movie that I liked
[SOUND] extends movie.
And let's make a bit of space, so
we can see this with all these
extra messages popping up.
Same deal with the constructor.
I'll just change that.
Like so, and override the method.
The plot and
we'll put
escape a maze.
Okay, let's create another one that's
stored in my memory as a child, Star Wars.
This, you can tell I'm a bit of a geek.
Star Wars extends movie.
Same deal with that construct and
we call it Star Wars.
Just capitalize that and
over at the method, the plot and
the plot's going to be imperial
forces try to take over the universe.
The last one we're gonna create
is a little bit different.
We're gonna create a class called,
forgettable movie.
So it's not actually a specific movie.
It's still going to extend
from the movie though.
Like so, same constructor
Now, importantly, we're not going to
override the plot method for this one.
This will make sense and actually show you
how polymorphism works by not doing that,
so you'll see that later on in this video.
So okay.
We've now got a base class.
Just looking back at and
reviewing what we've done.
We've got our class movie.
Which has got a field code name.
We've got a constructor
that initializes that name.
We've got a method called plot.
Then we've got a title of
five classes that extend, or
inherit, from that movie class.
They all initialize via the constructor,
their own constructor,
passing the parameter of
the name of the particular movie.
And that gets obviously
saved in the base class, and
most of the four of the five classes
have got their own plot method.
Which gives what the plot is,
a very brief summary of the plot for
each of those movies.
Then we've also created a fifth
class called Forgetable, and
it hasn't got the plot method, which we'll
understand why it hasn't got that shortly.
So moving on, what we want to do
now is we want to create a method,
a static method because it's part of this
main.java and not a separate class and
the purpose of this method will
be to return a random movie.
So it's going to return one of those
five classes, one of those five movies,
and you'll see why we're doing that
shortly, so let's create that method.
Now we're gonna do that
with public static.
Actually, what I'll do is,
we need to actually put it into the class,
so I'm gonna actually delete
that to make a bit of space,
then make a bit of space up here.
So, we need to go and create this method.
The method is going to be
part of the main class.
And it's going to be public static.
We're going to return Movie.
So, our return type is
gonna be the object Movie.
And we're gonna call this randomMovie.
So, its purpose is to
return a random movie.
In other words, one of those five movies.
So, in order to able to
return a random movie.
We need to generate a random number.
So that each time that
this method is called,
obviously a random movie is selected.
So how do we do that?
We use a math function.
That comes with Java, right which
will generate a random number for us.
So, we're gonna type,
int Random number equals.
And we need to cast it to int,
you'll see why shortly.
Int, then we need to meth.
Capital M, math.random.
And you can see there that by default,
this method,
you can see on the right hand side there,
it returns a double.
That's why we're doing a cast of
int because we want to convert this
to an integer.
So, by default, which you'll see,
I'll take you into that method shortly,
this will return a random number,
a double between 0 and 1.
So, what we're then doing is we're
converting that to an integer,
and then we're multiplying it,
in this case, by 5.
So, by doing that, that's going to return
a random number in the range 0 to 4.
And what we're gonna do
then is add 1 to that.
So in other words we're going to
return a number between 1 and 5.
So if we just go into that message and
have a look, we can click into there,
and you can see that this is
a method pseudo number generator,
and it returns the number greater than or
equal to 0 and less than 1.
So what we're doing is,
we're casting that as a integer as I said,
returning whatever the number is and
multiplying the answer by 5.
And that will give us an integer,
in this case, between 0 and
4 and then we're adding 1 to that answer.
And that's so
it will make more sense shortly,
while we're doing that it just makes our
current a little bit easier to read.
And then what we need to do is
well actually what we'll do first
is we'll print out what the number was.
What random number
generated was plus random number.
So we'll know what the number is,
so we can actually check that and
see that on the screen.
So next what we're going to do is we need
to do it using the switch statement.
We're going to actually create
one of these movie classes.
So, I'm gonna do switch (randomNumber).
Then I've got case 1, so
if the random number generator was 1,
we wanna return a new, and
of course, the first one was Jaws.
So we're gonna return Jaws.
Case two.
Return new.
The second one that we
created was Independence Day.
And you notice that I'm
not adding a break there.
The reason that I don't need
to add a break is that we've got
a return in there as the first line.
So it would be redundant to actually
go back here and put a break in there.
Can put it in there if you wanted to but
we actually are returning from this method
anyway, so there's no need to do that.
Case three.
Return new,
the third maybe was MazeRunner ().
Case four.
Return new StarWars().
And lastly case five.
We're going to return new Forgettable ();.
Our forgettable movie.
And then what we need to do
here is we put a return null.
And the reason we need to do that
is technically as far as the switch
statements were concerned,
we tested for the numbers 1 through 5.
But as far as it was concerned
it could have other values.
So we could have actually put another
default in here to processe based on that.
So in other words we're gotta put default.
Return null.
Which then makes this return null down
here void or we can just leave that out.
Either way, we need to actually handle the
fact that it could be outside that range.
But the way we've defined random
number that shouldn't happen anyway.
So what it's doing now as you can see,
depending on the number, whether it's 1,
2, 3, 4,or 5.
We're gonna return one
of those Movie classes.
So each time we call this
random movie method now,
we should actually get
a random movie returned to us.
Just take a look at the fact that
we're actually returning the movies or
we're returning a base class.
The super class in this case,
Movie, because of course all these
classes actually inherit from Movie.
And that's why we can use that once
to apply to all these classes.
Because of course the way inheritance
works we can use that is a relationship.
We can say that Jaws is a movie.
Independence day is a movie.
Maze runner is a movie and so on,
that's the basic concept of inheritance.
But let's now have a look
at the polymorphism aspect.
So what we're going to do now is we're
going to go back to our main method up
here and we're going to create a for loop
that actually goes through a number of
times retrieving a random movie and then
actually start using that polymorphism.
To actually call the relevant
plot method for that class,
so the way we do that is we create a for
loop first.
We're going to put for int = 1,
int < 11, i++ so we're
going to cycle through a total of ten
times and I need to put a variable there.
So to call the method,
we're gonna create a variable.
Movie movie = random movie.
So we've now got our movie
in our movie object.
Now let's print something out.
We're gonna go to print, movie#, so
that's the movie that we're working on.
Next we're going to put a +.
So let's type over here, we'll put.
Let's display what the movie name is.
Notice there's no get name yet, and
of course the reason for that is up here,
when I created the movie class,
I didn't create a getter.
I'm going to create a getter now.
Getter for the name field, and
we'll now be able to use that to actually
retrieve what the name of the movie is.
So looking back down at our code again,
we should now have that getter
available which you can see it's there.
And a
, and what that does it
actually generates a new line.
So in other words it starts
the output on the next line.
So we're adding that class, and
we'll just tab over again, and
this time, we're going to actually
do the interesting thing,
which really shows you
how polymorphism works.
We're gonna put "Plot:
" + movie.plot() + and
we'll just create another.
New line so
it will move onto the next line.
So that's that one little part here,
this movie.plot is really the definition
in how polymorphism works.
This is going to be better explained
if I actually show you it running.
So what I'm going to do is just close
that side view, like so and we'll run it.
And then I'll explain when it's done.
And drag this over a little bit.
You can see what's happened there.
Random number generator pulls one,
we got movie number 2.
So the random number generator pulls one,
if you look at our code again.
Case 1,
which should be returning the Jaws movie.
Next time, random number generator was 3,
movie number three should be maze runner,
which it is there.
Well you've got lots of two's and
three's there as well as you can see, but
we've got Independence Day there as well.
So can you see what's happening here,
this is the beauty about polymorphism.
Because if you're looking at that code,
movie.plot,
that's actually doing quite a bit of work.
What it's actually doing, what Java is
doing is it's looking at the object called
movie, the variable that we created, that
was returned from the random movie method.
And then it's going down and
looking into that object and seeing,
has it got a plot method?
And you can see in this case,
if you look at the first example for Jaws,
going back up to our Jaws class.
Yes, we have got a method called plot.
So therefore, it's smart enough to go,
okay,I'm going to execute this method
plot here in the jaws class, and
automatically it returns that
a shark eats lots of people.
And likewise for maize runner,
you can see that we've got a completely
different output for maize runner.
We actually got,
Kids try and escape a maze.
So you can see what's happening is, with
that one line of code this movie.plot,
this is what polymorphism is.
We're actually assigning
different functionality,
depending on the type of
object that we've created.
Bearing in mind that, all these objects
are inherited from the base movie class,
but we've assigned a unique
bit of functionality in
each of those plot methods,
for each of those classes.
Now, in this case, it's a very,
very simple method.
It only outputs the name.
Are the plot, I should say, for the movie.
But you can imagine that
we could have far more
complex functionality built into that,
if we wanted to.
Now just going to run this again,
because this is a random number generator.
It's purely random, and we've got would
seem to be a pattern there of the same
number, three, a number of times.
Is that a random thing?
So let's just run that again,
and get some different results.
Cuz I wanted to come up with number five.
And we can see that we've got
different results this time.
And we have actually got the results,
we got a four this time,
which we didn't have last time.
Which is good.
But we've also got the number five, and
this is the other point about
polymorphism that I wanna make.
The random number generator was five.
And that equates to return in
the new class called forgettable.
So the movie number three,
in the loop, was called forgettable.
The plot, no plot here.
So if you go back and
have a look at our forgettable class.
If you recall we didn't actually
create a plot method for that class.
So what's happened again,
using polymorphism,
is that Java's looked at that and said,
okay, there's no plot method here,
that has been overwritten,
in this forgettable class.
So as a result, I think it looks and
says, okay, I can see that
we're extending from the movie class, and
if we go back up to the movie class, and
it then finds the method called plot,
which is the movie class.
And that's where this code that's
been executed as coming from.
No plot here, which is pretty cool, so
you can see how polymorphism works now.
It will automatically, if you're
inheriting from another class, and
you've got a method, and you override
that method, that's what polymorphism is.
It's giving unique functionality, for
the class that has inherited
from a base class.
So, there you go.
So, that's the concept of polymorphism.
I hope that makes a lot of sense to you.
You'll find this as incredibly useful
once you start developing more Java
applications, because it really enables
you to write quite generic code.
Again, can you imagine if you didn't
have the ability to do polymorphism?
Looking at something like this one line,
movie.plot,
you would have to figure out a way to
decide what the type of class was, and
then to somehow call
the appropriate class.
So, you'd probably have a large switch
statement with, If class equals this name,
then actually, you know,
call this particular method.
So it'll be a lot more work in other
words, but Java really makes it easy for
you by adding this polymorphism
capability automatically.
So, that's polymorphism.
So, I'm going to end this video here.
In the next video, we'll go ahead and
start our polymorphism challenge, so
I'll see you in that video.