so in the previous video we talked about
using the switch statement and in this
video we're going to move on now and
talk about the for statement and
the for statement is used to loop some
code so in other words it is going to allow us
to execute code a certain number of
times now we haven't really looked at
that before and looping code in other words
executing code more than once in a
number of times is something that is
very commonly needed in programming and
I'm going to show an example of why we want to
do that
gonna start off by creating a new method
and call it...
...so this is going to
calculate the interest based on the
amount of money that's passed as a
parameter now one way to do this is
going to be just to do something on
these lines we are going to do a...
...so we will put a bracket in their just to make sure
from an operator precedence point of view that we're
processing it correctly we are
actually figuring out the amount then
multiplying it by the interest rate
divided by 100 and things are being
calculated in the right order and just
to confirm this is working we are gonna create a
sample code and we just gonna call it so
we're gonna put...so
calculate interest and we are going pass...
..so lets run this and make sure that it does work
we got 200 point zero there and that 200.0 means
it's $200 would be the the two percent
interest now this doesn't take into account
anything like compound interest or the amount
of time to pay off the loan or anything
like that it's a very simple contrived
example of calculating interest on an
amount of money this is one way to do it
but lets just say we want to calculate 3% and
4% and 5% and perhaps your
doing a comparison with different places and
you want to calculate a number of them
so you could say that we could do it one way we
could copy this and paste it like so and change
to print out to say 3% 4% 5% and we could
change the parameter 2 to 3% 4% 5% so if we run this 2%
3% 4% and 5% calculated which is $200
$300 $400 and $500 respectively
but you could probably see straight away
that would get really tedious you know if
you have to do that every time you
wanted to calculated a different
interest rate it would be as I said
tedious and what about if we had
twenty interest rates or a under
interest rates calculations we want
to do you can see that there will be lots of
code and it's very inflexible because
you continually having to go back and
change things and it can be a mountains of
code well the good thing here is that
computer's are made for automation so
there is a good solution
to getting around this problem and
that's using a for statement to automate
this process and ultimately to make it a
lot easier now the for statement is
often referred to as the for loop and
the idea is that it repeatedly loop
something until a condition is satisfied when I
say repeatedly loops its processing a
certain amount of code a code block in
other words a given number of times or
until a particular condition is
satisfied the basic structure is
something along these lines we type...
...and I'm just gonna put these three things in there and will discuss them
that's the basic formula of a for statement
so we've got the for the brackets and we
we;ve got init and it means the code that is going
to be initialized once at the start of
the loop termination is telling us what
we do is we tell the for loop how we want to
exit so what at what point do we exit and
that has to evaluate to false and once
it evaluates to false whatever that
condition is we put in there the loop with then
exit and will come down here and start
processing the next line and an increment
that's an expression that's invoke
after each iteration of the loops each
time the loop goes round so common thing to put
in there would be a number that is
incremented each time some sort of like
a count so what we are going to do is write a
very simple example and then ultimately
later in this video we gonna call this
calculate interest method so this is how you'd
start you type something...
...so we need an initialization so common thing to do
would be to initialize the variable so
let's put.....
..so you've seen that before data type and the variable we probably haven't seen
it in a loop like this but what we doing
is we are initializing a special variable
just for this loop once the loop is exited
and finished with this variable won't
exist anymore so it's really just for
the for loop now the termination so
basically that has to be false before
the loop will finish so what we do there is a
a good way is putting...so you can see by putting i<5 so you can see by putting it the first time we run it i is 0
so i<5 well that's going to be true
at the moment so the loop is gonna continue
working until it's false so in this case its going to be true for first time so it is
going to work and the whatever the code we are putting
here is going to be actually executed an
increment and what we want to do there at
the end of each loop we want to increase
the value of i and we can do i++ to
do that so you can see now that we've got
our we are setting our initial variable i to 0 our test is to confirm that i<5
so in other words it is gonna keep processing until
i is 5 or greater and i++
each time you go to the loop we're
heading 1 the value of i so just to
confirm that let's actually put something
or print something out of it so we will put....
...so now we've created a loop and the
loop consists of a code block that's only
got one statement which is an output
that's going to print the value of i
and print a message and hopefully it should go through each
time through the loop and print out
a message each time it goes so run that so you can see whats happened here loop 0 hello! loop 1,2
3 and 4 so you can see what
happened we started on i = 0 and we've
moved on until we've got to 4 and
then what happened was the next one
has come through and i was value of 5 our
condition to check was i less than
five and that then turn false because i was
five and the loop exited and if we come down here
and of course there wasn't any other code so the
Java application finished so you can see
that the computer has executed
the code five times starting at 0 now 0 is just a
value there we don't have to start at 0 we could change it to anything so
for example to 1 run that you can see
we got 1,2,3,4 this time because we
started from one but this time there is only
4 loops because the first time was
loop values was 1 second time it was 2
3rd time was 3 forth time was 4 and of course the fifth time I was
in fact 5 and i is not
less than that point so the loop exited
and of course if we wanted to run at five times we
could change that to say 6 1,2,3,4,5 again we got it to run
again 5 times but it is fairly
typical in these scenarios with for loops
to start with 0 because a lot of Java things
different parts of Java that you're
finding later in the course for example
arrays start at 0 so its a good habit to get
into with your coding to start things at
zero because you will see that a lot in the
course later on that many computer
languages including Java they start the count at 0 and not 1
ok so I've got a mini challenge for you at this
point
I'm gonna paste it in here
so using the for statement we just
learned above I want you to call the
calculate interest method with the
amount of 10,000 with an interest rate
of two three four five six seven and
eight percent and print the results
results to the console window so you
should be able to figure that out based
on line 6 through 9 and how to call the calculate
interest method but also the loop
that we you've learned about so type the
code below this and pause the video now
come back once you've got a solution and
then actually type the code that I have
come up with and you can compare your
results to mine so pause the video now ok so
hopefully you figured it out and I'm
going to show you how to do it so what
we need to do first is obviously for loop
so looking at to what we want to
calculate 2,3,4,5,6,7 and 8 so obviously
we want to create a for loop...
..we can start i=2 because that's how first we
we want to start with so when you doing
your doing your for loop you start with the first element
number you want to start with in this
case its 2 and put i and we want to go up until 8 so therefore our
tests should be one more than 8 because we want to
process 8 i<9 would be our test so once it hits
9 or its greater than 9 its going to exit the loop and we'll just use
an i++ and incident you notice
how you can reuse the variable again
and that is where I mentioned that earlier that
the variable that you create here in this
for loop only exists for this code block in the for loop so as soon as
you exit that that variable doesn't
exist anymore and you can reuse it and
it is also very common just to let you
know in for loops and while loop which you will learn in the
next video to use variables like i, j, k and so forth because they are just there as
index basically indexes to loop through
a number of times so if you see i,j, and k and wondering
tim why aren't you creating better variable names it is very common to use
those on loops such as this ok so next thing we need
to do is we just need to print out a message so what
we can do is just take a copy of this
line
and I'm gonna paste that in their and changed the two point
zero to i you noticed that if your
looking at this you notice that this is an integer but
this is a double the interest rate so
that's correct but what Java is doing
Java is smart enough to know that ok I can
convert whole number integer to a
double so it's doing that for us
automatically know what you could do if
you wanted to be correct you could cast
it as a double but it isn't necessary to do it works quite nicely without it
and of course the other thing would be
if you want to calculate interest rates
percentages than you probably wouldn't
be using an integer there you be using a
double and actually have a different way
incrementing for example you can increment by .5
of a percent or something along those lines but in this case
we are keeping it pretty simple we are using
integers
and we are going through looping like that so let's
run this code and you can see there we
actually got our solution working we've got
2,3,4,5,6,7,8 so in other words 2 through 8 we
actually calculated correctly and what I
didn't do is update the print out for
that so let me do that will put...run it again and their we go 2,3,4,5,6,7,8 which is what we needed
to do in the challenge we needed to
actually
calculated the interest rate on 10,000 on all of those which we've done
so that's the result of the challenge
and one thing you probably noticed here
is that this is has got a lot of decimal points
well sometimes in terms of the
precision of a double it will calculate
things like this and it's not something
you need to worry about we'll be talking
about precision later in the course
but it can be nice to actually get rid of
that so it actually output in a nice way
so one thing you can do to fix it up
if you do want to do that is if we could
actually come in here and type...
.....
....now it's not
something you need to do but what
basically what's happening here is we're
passing the value that we got returned
from our calculate interest
method to the String.format command and what
that does the %.2F this
case means output the number or
convert the number and output it with
just two decimal points and that would
then guarantee that we don't get all
those zeros and it means instead of seeing
200.0 300.0 we should be
getting 2 zeros so lets try running that and we got it now correctly
formatted 2,3,4,5,6,7,8 you can see that other examples their at the top
there only had the one decimal point that's one
way to look at doing this but it's not
something you need to worry too much
about but I just sort of put it in there now in
case you're wondering how to go about
doing that ok so next mini challenge so
how to modify the for loopo above to do the
same thing as shown but start 8% percent
and to work back to 2% so in other
words the first time it runs through the
loop it should be 8 the second time it should be
7 3rd time should be 6
what I suggest you do is copy and paste the
code above down here and then try your
results so that way you keep the
original code up the top so pause
the video and see if you can figure that
out and come back and I'll show you how
to do it ok so hopefully you manage to
figure it out so what we'll do is copy
as I mentioned now instead of putting for i=2 we wanna start at 8%
so we talked about this before where we
start on it's always going to be the
variable value initially then we can put..now we can't put i<9 because obviously in
the first case i=8 is going to work but it's
been it's gonna be so literally going
the wrong way so what we really want to
is change this around how it's gonna end
so where it should end should be is....in other
words its gonna keep processing while
up until i>=2
and the last one where we want
to go backwards this time so we want to do i--
so you can see i=8 i>= i-- that should go
in the backwards direction so lets just try
running that and what we might do is put a message here
just to separate it just so we don't get confuse with the output from the previous
for loop and we run that and you can see we started at
8% 7,6,5,4,3,2 so it's going
backwards again you can have a loop to
go either forward or backward it just
depends on the conditions that you
typing in there and you just need to make
sure you get your ranges correct if you
do get those numbers wrong and I
probably haven't got too much time to go to that
going into that in this video you find that
often the for loop may lock up and it will
continue looping and it won't exit or you might
find it doesn't execute at all so make sure
in those situation just check your
initialization variables but also this
condition here as when it will exit that is really the key in
many ways to the entire loop is what your
condition is what's needs to
be false to be able to allow the loop to
exit ok so what I'm going to do now is finished off with a
challenge for you one other final challenge
and in order to do that what we need to
do what I need to do is give you a bit
of code so I'm gonna give you a code to
generate a prime number that i'm gonna
go through that quickly because it's not
really important to know about that but
you need to do some coding you need
to come up with some code that calls this on a particular amount of times so paste that code
in and just talk about briefly so this is
a function that's going to determine
whether a pass integer is a prime
number and I'm not sure whether you know or not
but a prime number can be divided evenly
only by 1 or by itself
the other thing is it has to be a whole
number greater than 1 this particular
function what it does firstly it tests to
see whether it's one and if it is not
the number one it is going to return
false because prime number can only be
divided evenly only by one or itself and has
to be a whole number greater than 1 so if it is 1
returning false we don't do any other
processing and in term of the for loop I
also want show you how this for loop is a
little bit different so we got for i
int i=2 we are starting on 2
because I remember I said that we
prime number has to be greater than
one and then we did that test on line 35
ok so you can see there we got our loop
we just using n/2 as a shortcut because what we're attempting to do is find
numbers that divide into in n so this for loop is only gonna go through and really
calculate what it needs to do so no number
that is greater than n divided by two
is going to divide into n that's really
the point here that by dividing it by 2
we are optimizing this to make sure that
we're not actually processing numbers we
don't need to process when we are checking and this
code on line 40 is then checking
whether n the remainder between n and i dividing i into n if that is zero it
means there is no remainder so what that
essentially means at this point is we
found another number that divides evenly
into the number that was passed and
therefore this can't be a prime number so we
need to go through the whole loop once
you've been through the whole loop we
can return true because at that point we
determine it is a prime number so that's
the n divided by 2 is there
Its just an optimization technique just to save a bit of time for the computer
again we are just checking for the remainder and if
we find that there is another number
that evenly divides into the number that's passed it means this can't be a prime number so that's what this method
does so what I'm gonna do is just
give you a final challenge to do
now so I'm gonna come up here now that we've
written that so you need that method
obviously and paste the challenge in and your
challenge is to create a for statement
using any range of numbers to determine
if the number is a prime number using
this prime method that I've given you down
below if it is a prime number print it
out and increment a count of the number
of prime numbers found if you get to the
stage where 3 or more are found in other
words you've actually gone through the
loop and you've found three prime numbers
I want you to exit the for loop and as a hint use
the break statement to exit the loop so you
need to use a if statement to check,
count and use break and that will break out of the for loop automatically so that's
it
see if you can figure it out that challenge
pause the video now and do that
once you're ready to see my version of the
code come back and I'll type it in, pause the video now, ok so hopefully you manage to get
it to work and I know this video
is getting long again see if we can finish
this off so I will start off I mentioned
that we
need to have a count determining we are going to exit if the count is
three so....
...so now we need to create a loop go
through and call this prime method a number
of times so put...
....
...so what we gonna do in our loop the first thing to put is...
.....
...so if we have found a prime number its
return true which would have been talked
about the is prime methods so if we found a prime
number what would you do is do a...
....
....then we're going to do a test in here
remember I said to use the break statements so put...
....and that should
be it so we're going through the range
of 10 through 49 basically because once
it hits 50 it will exit checking to see whether the
value the prime number for the value i
is a prime number if it is we are going to
increment the count and we're going to
print a message saying that number is prime number
and if we got three if and only if we got to 3
then we are going to exit otherwise it's just going to continue so
we shouldn't see any other output unless
we found prime numbers and the best way
to do this now is to actually run it
so run it and see whether it works
number 11 is a prime number 13, 17 is
a prime number you can see we are exiting the for
loop
so it successfully finished after 3 so it seems
to be working so let's just go and make
sure that they are prime numbers so I'm
going to do open a browser and type a list of prime numbers and there it is the first 1000 primes is all we need so lets open it up
you can see the link at the top or actually you'll see when I get to the
page seems to be taking a while to load for some
reason there we go 2,3,5,7,11,13,17,19 and if we go back to the code 11,13,17 is
correct so let's just changes this out of interest
a little bit let's put the count to 10
instead of 3 and hopefully it shows 10 prime numbers
11, 13, 17, 19, 23, 29, 31, 37, 41, 43, look good
the seem to be the right prime numbers here so it
seems to be working which is good so
that's our challenge done so the big
thing there again was once we got to the
count whatever the count was we decided
we wanted to exit we printed out the
message and then we did a break and the
break actually exits out of the for loop
completely and processing within
continuing on line 41 if there was any
coding but in this case it was the end of
the program so that's what the break
statement does and that's it I'm going
to finish the video here now just one
really quick thing there is a way also
to optimize this so we talked about
optimizing i<=n/2 there is
another without going into too much detail we
could change that so we could have
actually used a square root an
advantage of doing that would be that
there is less processing still and it would
slightly faster so without spending too
much time explaining why because the video
is already too long we could have done
something like this
....we are using long because the output that comes
back from Math.square can be large
so we are casting it as a long depending
on the number now you wouldn't need to do
that for the small numbers were using
here but that would be a little bit more
optimized so I run that we should get the same
results firstly
we still got the same results but that would actually
be better because you will find the
number of things we need to check would
be less times through the loop
so to speak
you could test that if you wanted to you
could actually put some code in here to
print out each time you going through
the loop and to test your results as to how many times
actually we will just do it really quickly now so will do a.....lets just do that...so for the last one number 41, 1,2,3,4,5,6 so that is 6 loops remembering that for the number 41
so we change that back to n/2 again and look at number 41 this time too
look how many times it actually had to loop through
significantly more times to calculate
that number so that would be the reason
that you use that square root function
for optimization purposes but again you'll
find out more about using those sorts of
things later in the course I just wanted
to point out there is another way of
doing that if you decided to but that's it
so that's the for loop I hope you got a lot out of it that
and just one last thing there's also another
variation of the for loop called the for each
but we're not discussing that here well
the reason for that is we
really need to be talking about arrays
and objects and the like before that makes
sense so you see the for each which again is a
variation of this for loop in future in
future videos in the course so that's it
I'm going to end this video now and in a
next video we are going to start talking
about another type of loop that's available in
Java and that's the while and also the do while
so we'll see you in that video