In the last video we started work
on defining what methods were and
we started work on creating the methods.
So let's continue on with methods.
Okay so we've defined the type of information
coming back, and we've also defined
the actual value to be returned back.
So next what we need to do is I'm going to
take out the print line there,
and I'm going to put:
'int highScore =', because the other thing you can do
is you can assign a variable to a method result.
So what we're doing is saying, take the value
that is returned from the method 'calculateScore'
and put that into the variable called 'highScore'.
We can then do our system output, but the final score
will actually be the variable 'highScore'.
and likewise for here, what we could do
I'll delete that out.
The same deal there. So we can 'Run' that,
just to confirm that it's working.
We've still got the same scores,
but now what happened is, as you can see
there's no print out in this entire method.
So the result of our calculations is being sent back
automatically from our 'calculateScore' method,
and because we've put 'int highScore ='
and then the name of the method and then the
various arguments that we've sent to it,
that value that we return, in this case 'finalScore'
is being sent back and placed
into the 'highScore' variable.
Pretty cool as you can see, because it really
means that you can create methods to do
calculations and just to send back the result of the
calculations, making your code a lot
easier to read. Rather than having
to put all this calculation code
in perhaps an area you didn't want it to be in.
Okay, so it's time for a challenge.
I'll make a bit more space. So here's the challenge.
So that's it, you need to create
a method called displayHighScorePosition,
so it should receive a player's name
name as parameter and a second
parameter should be defined as a position in the
highScore table,
so what you need to do in this method is
display the player's name,
along with the message,
'player's name managed to get in position...'
and then display the number they
receive, the position number.
Then a further message on the highScore table,
and create a second method called
calculateHighScorePosition,
it should be sent one argument only.
In other words only have one parameter which
is the player's score,
it should return an int.
And the return data should be
'1 if the score is >1000',
'2 if the score is >500 and <1000',
'3 if the score is >100 and <500'
and in all other circumstances return '4'.
So you need to call both methods and display the results.
You can come up with any player name,
but the score of 1500, 900, 400 and 50.
So in other words, you would call the various
methods four times to come up with this,
and to be clear the displayHighScorePosition
is a void method, so it doesn't have to
return any data,
and incidentally as I remember it, a void
method can also be known as a procedure
and a method generally speaking can also
known as a function. So you may hear me
using those terms interchangeably throughout the
course. Procedure would generally mean a method
returning type void.
Okay, so see how you go with this challenge,
go away and try and see how you get on
and once you're ready come back
and I'll show you my solution.
PAUSE NOW – TRY TO SOLVE – PRESS PLAY!
Okay so let's have a go with a solution.
So firstly display highscore position,
players name as a parameter and a second
parameter as the position in the high score table,
So we can create something like:
public static and there's no return type so that's
going to be void.
So the method name is displayHighScorePosition,
the parameters are going to be the
first name being the player's name.
We're going to be using a string data type for that
and we'll just call that playerName.
Second parameter is a position in the highscore table,
let's use an integer for that,
it wouldn't really matter what you use but
probably integer would be the most efficient,
and we'll call that highScorePosition.
And what we need to do is display the message,
so it will be display the player name firstly,
+ "managed to get into position +,
and the highscore position;
and notice also how with the variables
if they're being used they're in dark black,
if they're not being used they're in a light gray.
It's a great way of figuring out
if you're variables are being used properly or not.
So I'm going to type in + the highscore
+ "on the high score table".
So for the second method calculateHighScorePosition
we need to do a public static.
Now this one needs to return some data,
so the return should be returning an integer,
therefore it won't be void, but it will be int,
which is the data type.
calculateHighScorePosition, and needs one parameter
which is an integer, the players score,
so we're going to call that int playerScore,
and we need to have some calculations here
to know what to return, so we're going to put.
if(playerScore > 1000) (code block)
we're going to put return 1;
else if (playerScore >500 &&(AND) playerScore <1000)
we need just to return 2;
else if (playerScore >100 && playerScore <500),
return 3;
Then in all other cases we need to return 4
so that'll just be an else without an if. return 4;
So that should be that method.
So we've now fulfilled I think all of that,
What we need to do is we actually
call these methods with various parameter's.
So what we're going to do is start off with 'int'.
we'll call it
highScorePosition = calculateHighScorePosition,
we're going to pass the first one which was 1500
and then we actually want to execute
the second method which is.
displayHighScorePosition("Tim", highScorePosition);
So next, we're not going to redefine the data type,
so I'm just going to copy that,
and the second one we want to pass
900  with the name bob.
For the third one we need to use 400
and we'll put Percy,
and fourth one 50, Gilbert.
So that should be our four arguments,
1500, 900, 400 and 50.
So you can see what we're doing is on the first line we're
figuring out, we're calling the calculateHighScorePosition
method to return the number
and then we're executing the second
method and notice how we haven't got a
type as we're not setting it
to a variable or anything like that
because it's of type void, we're just
physically calling the method
like you can see there on the screen.
So now if we 'Run' that we should hopefully,
get 1,2,3,4 showing because we've
put these in the right order,
of 1500, 900, 400 and 50
which should be the 1,2,3,4,
so let's try that.
Tim managed to get into position 1 on
the high score table.
Bob managed to get into position 2
and Percy managed to get into position 3
and Gilbert managed to get into position 4
on the high score table. So it seems
that our code worked.
So what I want to do is just correct
what was actually a flaw in the original
code that I've developed for this lecture
and just tab over to a discussion
that student left, and you can see
Julian Brown left a message to say that
there's a logic hole in your challenge code,
and he's actually quite correct
so, ... what he goes on to say is
after the first if statement, the second one
does not need to test for less than a 1000,
by doing so a score of l1000 would slip through
and return a 4.
So in other words, what I've done, and
if we go back to the code and have a look,
Well I actually replied here and said
"The challenge as I wrote it
in the lecture was as follows: To return 1 if the score
was greater than 1000, return 2 if the score was
was greater than 500 and less than 1000
and return 3 if score was greater than 100
and less than 500 and otherwise return 4."
So my code actually works, as per the challenge,
but what is quite correct that Julian
points out and also Michael's pointed out a little bit
further down as well is that there is
actually a logic hole, because if we
to pass a score of exactly 1000
to this routine, or a score of 500 or even a
score of 100, we get the wrong results.
So there's actually a bug in the code.
So let's just go back to the code,
and I'm just going to 'Run' it so you can actually see
what the bug is and then we'll actually fix it
just so you just know how to go about doing that.
So these examples have all worked
without any problems, and that's
because they're working within the constraints
of the 'if' and the 'else if's' that are here.
But what we haven't done is try to actually
pass a score that is exactly 1000,
that's exactly 500 or exactly 100.
So for example, let's do one that's exactly 1000.
highScorePosition = calculateHighScorePosition(1000);
We'll do:
displayHighScorePosition("Louise, highScorePosition);
So what should happen in theory
is that the way we've set it out is
if the score is greater than 1000,
that should really be greater than or equal to 1000,
and likewise for this one it should be greater than
or equal to 500 and less than 1000.
should be grater than or equal to
Because in reality we don't really want
a score of 1000 to be number 4,
we'd want to say that okay the score of a 1000 or more,
that should really be in position 1.
But if we run this code as it is now,
we'll find that a 1000 will actually be returning
to position 4. So Louise, even though she managed
to score a 1000 points has got to position 4,
and just confirming the reason for that
is in the actual
calculateHighScorePosition method,
I've got 'if(playerScore > 1000) [to] return 1;'
and the next condition is:
'if(playerScore is > 500 && playerScore < 1000) return 2; '
So you can see the logic there,
The first test is actually checking to see
whether the score is greater than 1000,
the second test is checking to see
whether it's '> 500 and it's < 1000'.
So consequently, if the score is exactly 1000
it actually bypasses all of these and just
goes down to the final else and returns '4'.
So what we should really have done there, ... is put
equals (=) there, so if the playerScore >= 1000
that's going to be position '1' in the high score table,
So it's just that change,
and likewise in 'Player 2', if the score is
'>= 500 && it's < 1000 to return 2'.
And the last test will be:
'if(playerScore >= 100 && playerScore <500)'.
So if we do that, that should actually fix
all our logic problems. So if we just actually 'Run' that,
again we find that Louise
managed to get into position 1 on the highscore
table now, and that's now because we're now
correctly checking to see whether the score is
greater than or equal to 1000,
and likewise if I do a couple more copies here,
And the next one will be a test for 500.
In the previous version of the test,
we were only testing for greater than 500
and then less than 500 in the next one,
so that would have slipped to position 4.
That should now work.
So if we change that to 500, Carol.
And the last test that also had a similar problem.
We're only checking whether the value is
greater than 100, so we should really put
'>= 100' which we've done there, so that
should now work okay.
So we put Frank. So now if we 'Run' those,
they should all be in their correct positions as well.
So we now have Louise managed to get into
into position 1 on the high score table.
Carol managed to get into position 2
and Frank managed to get into position 3.
And just as a recap,
if I actually remove the equals (=) on all
of these to see, to have the code as it was,
before I made the change,
you'll find that they're actually in a different order.
They all, the last three went into position
'4' automatically. Louise, Carol and Frank,
when really they shouldn't have because of
the bug that I had in the code.
I'll put the equals back in and 'Run' it again,
and we've now got them correctly in the right positions.
So thanks to Julian and Michael for
pointing that out, and that's
the correct code now, that's fixed that logic
problem that they found and hopefully
your code's now a lot better as a result of that.
So keep that in mind, that is actually
a really important thing to make sure when your
testing your ranges, that you
include everything. Now clearly it was a
but here that I actually didn't check
to see whether the score that you know
all scores within that particular
range were actually correctly being identified
and they weren't in this case. There was
3 scores that were slipping through the cracks.
Alright, so far we've got a working
solution but I'm going to end the video here, in the
next one there was actually a bug fix
that I want to fix, I want to talk to you about that
and show you where the bug is
but also, I want to show you an alternative
way to write the calculate
high score position method
and the reason I'm showing you that is just
to confirm that there's always almost
always multiple ways to create
a given solution
in a programming language, so I want to show you
an alternative way to create that method.
So let's start working on that in the next video.