We've been working with the int or integer data type
so far in the course.
Now technically that's known as a primitive type in Java.
So in Java, primitive types are
the most basic data types.
An int is one of eight different primitive types.
The eight primitive data types in Java are boolean,
byte, char, short,
int, long,
float, and double.
So consider these types as the building blocks
of data manipulation.
So let's explore the eight primitive types in Java
over the next few videos.
So what we are going to do is close down our project
that we're working on in the last video.
File, close project, and I'm gonna create a new one.
Let's do that.
Click on create your project as we've done previously.
You need to leave Java selected
and the project STK as it was.
This time I'm going to check create project from template
because I want to show you how we can
automate some of this code and get IntelliJ
to do some of the things for us
that we had to do manually when we created our last project.
Click on next.
Here for the project name I'm going to call it Byte.
Short
Int
Long.
And these are four primitive types
which we'll be going through in this course.
Notice this time when I did that,
under the project location,
we've got our current project location
but it's automatically created the subfolder.
I mentioned that it will do that
and it is actually doing that.
The other thing I want to point out here
is this base package.
At the moment I'm using Academy.learn programming.
What actually is a package?
A package is a way to organise your Java projects.
For now, consider packages as folders
with learnprogramming in our example
being a subfolder of the academy folder.
Companies use their domain names reversed as a package.
So learnprogramming.academy, which is our website,
becomes academy.learnprogramming as a package.
We will go into a lot more detail about packages
when we need to later on in the course.
This time we're going to get IntelliJ
to create the class for us as I mentioned.
That's why we checked the checkbox on the previous screen.
So we'll leave that checked.
And I'm going to click on finish.
Notice that this time by doing that,
two things have happened.
First thing, we've got a class there created, main.java.
We've got the package statement on line one
but also we've got this public static void main method
that we've talked about created for us as well.
There's a helpful little line there on line six
saying write your code here.
So it's telling us where we can start coding.
If we expand over the project here, click on source folder.
Notice the packages.
We've got academy and learnprogramming.
I'm clicking those.
And there's how far.
You can see that our main class is in the learnprogramming
part of the academy.learnprogramming package.
But again, more on packages later on in the course.
For now I'm just going to move this over a little bit
because we don't really need to refer too much
to the project.
All right, so if you remember in the previous video,
we created some code.
It did something like this.
I'm going to come over here and I'm going to
delete that bit of text there, which was actually a comment.
I'll talk about comment a little bit later.
So in the last few videos, we did something like
int my
value
equals
10,000 semicolon.
So what that was doing, if you recall,
was creating a variable called myValue of type integer
and we're initialising it
with a value of 10,000 in this case.
So the computer has allocated enough space
to store an integer, and it's assigned a name
for that variable of myValue.
But what actually is an integer?
Now we know that it's a whole number.
But what can we store in an integer?
Is the range infinite?
Well, it turns out there is a range,
which is usually the case for most data types.
There's a minimum and maximum number
that can be expressed or stored in an int.
So let's type in some code.
I'm going to show you how you can determine the range
of a primitive type.
So we can type in this code:
int
myMin
IntValue
We're using this for the minimum value.
We're going to type equals Integer.
A capital I, period, MIN.
Notice that MIN adds core values, I'm selecting that
by pressing enter.
Semicolon.
We're going to do the same for max.
So int myMaxIntValue this time
is equal to Integer period.
This time we're going to use MAX and its core value.
Let's now print those out.
I'm going to type sout for a shortcut
for a system dot out dot println.
I'm going to use double quotes.
Here's our option now.
I'm going to show you how to display
both text and some data on the same line.
We can put our header or comment that we want to show
Integer Minimum Value
equals
and then we've got the closing double quote there.
Then I'm going to add a plus operator
myMinIntValue.
So I'm using the minimum value there.
What I'm going to do is take a copy of this line.
I'm gonna paste it.
You can type it if you prefer.
And I'm going to change minimum to maximum value.
I'm going to change Min over here to Max.
So you can see what we're doing there
is we're printing out both the minimum and maximum values.
But the point here in terms of the double quotes
and the value is we've entered the text
that we want to display on the screen
and then we've added a plus.
What happens is when you start out using
a literal string like we're using here,
then we use the plus operator,
whatever follows the plus operator
is converted to a string and gets outputted.
So it's a handy way to combine text
and, in this case, numeric output.
It's not the best way to do things,
but at this point in the course it's perfectly acceptable.
We're using Integer instead of int.
That's because int is a primitive type
that really only gives us the option
to set the variable's value.
Integer on the other hand is what's called a Wrapper class.
Java uses the concept of a Wrapper class
for all eight primitive types.
In the case of an int, we can use Integer,
and by doing that it gives us ways to perform
different operations on an int number.
In this case, we're using the min and its core value
and the max and its core value
to get Java to tell us what are the minimum
and maximum numbers that can be stored in an int data type.
If we run this programme now,
you can see a minimum range here is
minus 2,147,483,648.
And the maximum value can be 214,7483,647.
So min and its core value there
is the smallest value that we can set an int to,
and max and its core value is the biggest.
Just to confirm that, let's try adding plus one
to one of these values.
Use it for the max value.
And see what happens.
So to do that I'm going to top some code under here.
We're going to do another sout.
Sys out, s out.
Double quotes, we're going to put Busted MAX value
is equal to, and then we're going to put double quote there,
then we're going to write plus.
And then we're going to add parentheses here
just to make it clear what we're doing here.
We're going to get the myMaxIntValue
and add one to it, which technically shouldn't be possible.
Because we've already established that
the line ten contains the maximum value of an integer
and we're in fact trying to add one to it.
So note that we haven't got an error here.
But if we run this,
look what's happened to the maximum value.
We've assigned the maximum value plus one.
And what's happened is that the number,
Busted MAX value down the bottom there,
has turned into a minus number, to a negative number.
This is called an Overflow.
We tried to put too large a number
into the space allocated by the computer for an integer.
Now it didn't fit, so the computer tried to fit it anyway.
By doing that it overflowed.
The reverse is also true here.
So if I change that or actually add a new line.
So an s out, and we'll put Busted MIN value
is equal to a double quote plus
and in parentheses again we'll put my min value, plus one.
Now if I run that, actually what we'll do is
we need to do a minus one there.
And the reason we need to do a minus one there
is we're trying to get a number that's less than
the current minimum number.
So we'll put a minus there.
Let's run that.
You can see what's happened there.
In the case of our busted number, I made a typo there,
so let me fix that up and run it again.
So I've established that that minimum value
is a minus two billion 147 million.
But by trying to deduct one off that minimum number,
we've sort of cycled around to the maximum value.
This is a concept called Underflow this time
and not Overflow.
If you try and put a value larger than the maximum value
in Java, or a value smaller than the minimmum value in Java,
and we've done both in this video,
then you'll get an Overflow in the case of
the maximum value or an Underflow in the case
of the minimum.
So what's happening is the computer just skips back
to the minimum number or the maximum number,
which is usually not what you want.
So it's an important concept to be aware of.
So clearly here Overflow and Underflow is a bad thing.
We don't want that happening with our code.
As we'll see in the next video,
there's a data type to hold much bigger numbers
if we need them.
But ultimately, as a programmer, it's our responsibility
to use the appropriate data type
and ensure the range of numbers we're trying to store
in that data type is within the range.
In this case the min value and max value.
Note that if you just type a number bigger or smaller
than the max or minimum value,
Java will flag that as an error.
So in other words if we use it as a literal.
So to see what I mean, I'm going to grab
the largest maximum value from our output.
I'm just going to double click that.
And do a control-c, command-c on a Mac.
If I type in now int myMaxIntTest
is equal to,
I'm going to paste that value in.
I could have just typed that in.
Clearly we haven't got an error there.
Just to confirm, we've run the programme.
We won't see any different output
because we haven't printed out a message.
But if I try and increase that manually by one now,
we've suddenly got an error.
You can see there the error is telling us
the integer number is too large.
What's happening here is,
because we've typed a literal value for an integer,
and IntelliJ can then figure out and know that
okay, that number is clearly outside of the range
of the maximum number that can be stored.
And we can flag it immediately.
Look what happened with the code on line 13 and 14
which didn't really tell us anything until we ran it.
And in fact even then didn't give us an error.
So any literal number typed without any other character
at the end is assumed to be of type int.
But more on that in the next video.
Just one last point I want to make is,
you might find that that's a little bit unreadable.
But we'll change that back to a seven
so it's no longer got an error.
You can also use underscore.
So we can put 2_147_483_647.
So you can enter it in that format
if that's easier for you to understand
and to read at a glance.
Either way is acceptable.
Either entering it like a number on line 16
or as we've done on line seven.
Both of those ways are perfectly acceptable.
I will say, with that said, I don't see a lot
of code out there using the underscore approach.
But it's valid from Java 7 and higher,
so any version of the Java development kit
from version 7 or higher it'll work.
Let's end the video now we know a bit more about the int.
In the next video we'll get introduced to
three more primitive types,
namely the byte, the short, and the long.
See you in the next video.