In this video, we're going to download
and instal IntelliJ IDEA, which is the IDE,
integrated development environment, or editor programme,
if you will, that we're gonna be using
to run our programmes in this course, to actually create
and run our programmes, for that matter.
So to download that, we're gonna go
to jetbrains.com, www.jetbrains.com.
Once we get there, we're gonna come up
to the Tools menu at the top, select IntelliJ IDEA,
you can see here, click on that.
Click on download.
And click on this little "I Agree"
just to get rid of that on the screen.
You've got two options here, when you
go to download IntelliJ IDEA.
You can grab the Community Edition,
which we'll be doing, which is free, opensource.
You'll never need to pay for it.
Alternatively, you can choose the Ultimate Edition,
which gives you a few extra options,
and basically is for commercial developers.
You can see if I scroll down, there's some
extra features there, JavaScript, TypeScript,
Java Enterprise Edition, Spring, et cetera.
So basically, it gives you more functionality,
which is how the company makes their money.
Now the fact that they offer a free version,
which is fully-featured and certainly enough
for you to use in this course, is fantastic.
So we're gonna click on download, here,
to download the Community Edition.
All right, so I'm gonna give that a moment now to complete.
All right, you can see that IntelliJ IDEA Community Edition,
that's the C in idea there, has finished downloading.
Click on the little magnifying glass there to open Finder.
We're gonna double-click the .dmg file
to start installing it.
I'm gonna close down Safari,
cause we don't need that anymore.
And I'll close down the Finder window for now,
as well, cause we really don't need that either.
Dragging it to applications, there's no doubt
you've done it before with applications on the Mac.
Give that a moment to instal.
So I mentioned we're gonna do some configuration
of IntelliJ IDEA in another video.
But we'll do the first parts of it in this video.
So I'm gonna go down, now, and double-click
on the IntelliJ icon, IntelliJ IDEA CE.
CE stands for Community Edition, that's the free version
that we've downloaded and now installed.
Double-click that to start off the process.
We're gonna close down Finder now, and close down
the instal window there, the installation.
And I'll actually eject IntelliJ IDEA CE,
because we've now finished with the installation.
All right, we've got an option here
telling us that it's from the app.
The app has been downloaded from the internet.
Are you sure?
That's from jetbrains.com, which is
the official site for IntelliJ, so that's fine.
We're gonna click on open, as you saw.
We're prompted for this option.
If you're installing IntelliJ IDEA for the first time,
we haven't got any settings to import.
But if you had a previous installation,
you could click on the top option,
config installation folder, and basically,
that would give the option to drag those settings
from the previous version into this current version,
this new version we're installing.
I'm gonna select Do not import settings,
because it's a brand-new instal.
Click okay.
Privacy policy, there.
Check the checkbox, click on Continue.
You can read that if you like.
We can send anonymous data about features
or plugins, if you want.
I generally click on Don't send,
but you can choose either option.
We're now presented with an option,
which top of the screen colour you would like.
I'm going to leave mine set to light.
Light comes out better for videos.
But if you prefer to use dark colour, then that's...
My development machine is certainly using that,
it's easier on the eyes, then select that.
But choose whichever one you want,
noting you can change these options later in Preferences.
We're gonna click on Next.
Okay, map scheme I'm gonna leave as defaults.
If you've used IntelliJ IDEA before, you can change that
by choosing the option on the right.
I'm gonna click on Next.
This gives you the option
to invoke IntelliJ IDEA from the command line.
If that's something you're doing,
or have done in the past, or want to do
from the command line, then check the box.
There's no harm in doing it, in any event,
so I'm going to do that.
You've got various tools here.
And keep in mind, if you've chosen
to download and instal the Ultimate Edition,
there'll be additional features here.
Generally, I just leave everything as-is.
I never change anything, because you can always
change plugins and add new plugins
at a later time, as well.
Click on Next.
Same deal there, I'm not gonna change any of those settings.
You can come back to it.
You can see down here, Preferences, Plugins,
if you do wanna change that in the future.
Click on Start using IntelliJ IDEA.
Enter my password.
IntelliJ IDEA should start up for us now.
Okay, so at this point, we're now done.
We're gonna end the video here.
There is another video that we'll go through,
and we'll go through and enter or do
the configuration for IntelliJ IDEA.
That's actually connecting the STKs
and so on that we need for this course.
But we'll do all that in a separate video.
Thanks for watching.
Let's move on, now, to the next video.