Usually when you think of blog content, you think of a standard text blog post, now, it might have
some images and videos and stuff like that embedded.
But when it comes to the core content, what most people think of is text.
But I'd like to challenge that assumption a little bit because we as bloggers are by no means limited
to the written word.
There are so many different content formats you can deploy to get your message across, and it's worth
exploring some of the different options to see which formats best suit your personal skillset as well
as the preferences of your audience.
So video is a great example.
We're actually living in the golden age of online video.
So many companies are turning to video as their primary medium for storytelling.
And for a lot of consumers, it's the ideal way to consume media.
So if you're good on camera or if you find video to be compelling, you could experiment with putting
out video content instead of just text.
There are a couple of ways to do that.
You could just upload videos directly to your site.
But what most people tend to prefer is uploading videos to YouTube and then just embedding the videos
in WordPress.
That way, the video is hosted by YouTube, so you don't have to worry about the extra strain on your
server.
And you also get the added benefit of being discoverable on the actual YouTube platform, which is a
great way to start growing an audience.
Podcasting is another medium that's been exploding lately.
I actually hosted a roundtable podcast for a few years and that was enormous fun to do.
So if you think audio may play well with your audience, give it a try.
It's pretty easy to set up a podcast in WordPress.
Personally, I always use the power press plug in.
You just create a regular blog post, attach your audio file with power press and you're good to go.
Here's a little bonus tip.
If you're on a budget and want to start podcasting while keeping your expenses to a minimum.
Pick up the audio Technica 8R twenty one hundred.
This is a high quality, affordable microphone that works over both USP and Zellar and then use the
free program audacity for your recording and editing.
So, again, there's video, there's audio, if you have design skills, you could do infographics or
something like that.
The point here is that you're not limited to the traditional text blog post.
Feel free to take the content ideas we covered earlier in this section and adapt them to a format that
works for you.