OK, at this point, we've covered all the essentials of building a successful blog mindset, technology,
content promotion list, building monetization, you have all the tools you need at your disposal,
but now it's up to you to put them into action.
You can toss around ideas and make plans all day long.
But ultimately, the most important variable of success is your execution.
So if you haven't already get started today, get yourself a domain and a hosting account set up.
WordPress start putting out great content and promoting it.
Make sure you have systems in place to collect emails for your list.
And once you've got an audience, you can start to implement one or more of the revenue models we talked
about to turn your blog into a business.
As time goes on, I'll be adding more bonus content to this course.
And since you're already enrolled, you will have full access to all future content.
In the meantime, I'd love to hear your feedback as well as any questions you have and what you'd like
me to address in future lectures.
And finally, I just want to say thank you for spending some time with me in this course.
Your attention means the world to me.
I really hope it's been valuable and I hope to see you put it all into action and build an amazing blog.
And by the way, I would love to hear updates on your progress as you move forward.
So once again, thank you so much for joining me.
And I wish you nothing but success.