When you're growing a new blog, building an email list should be your absolute number one priority.
I know that surprises some people, but it's true.
Even today, in the age of social media, an email list is still the single most effective tool for
generating repeat traffic and repeat customers on demand.
Think about it.
It's the only communication channel that you actually own, meaning no news feed update or new search
algorithm will ever impact your ability to reach people with it.
Almost everyone checks their email daily, and most importantly, people have to opt in to your email
list, meaning everyone on your list actually wants to hear from you.
Your list is your greatest asset for building a strong community and a profitable business.
Here are some stats from the marketing world.
According to a study by McKinsey and Company, email is 40 times more effective in terms of customer
acquisition than Facebook and Twitter combined.
On top of that, get response reports that for every one dollar invested, email marketing generates
an average return of thirty eight dollars.
In other words, a 37 percent ROIC.
Now keep in mind, a good email marketing campaign begins with a good list.
You want real information from real people who check their email regularly, and you want those people
to be genuinely interested in your blog and what you have to offer.
Don't be tempted to buy an email list from a service that promises thousands of email subscribers for
a very small amount of money.
Most of the emails you get will be old or fake, and the few who are actual people probably won't be
interested in you or your content.
Plus, there's a good chance you'll get flagged as a spammer, which is just icing on the cake of a
very bad investment.
You'll see much better results by growing your own list organically and will cover exactly how to do
that in this section.