Let's talk about the mindset of a successful blogger.
What does that look like and how can you set yourself up for success by getting into the right mindset?
One of the most important pieces of advice I can offer you if you plan on starting a blog or really
any new endeavor is to know your why.
It sounds a little cliche, but it matters.
Think about the overarching vision you have for your life and your career and determine how this project
fits into that long term vision.
What's your endgame?
Why do you want to embark on this journey?
For example, maybe you're really passionate about a topic and you want to share that passion with an
audience.
Maybe you want to start a business that allows you to live with a little more freedom and flexibility
in your lifestyle, or, hey, maybe you just want to earn more money, which is perfectly legitimate.
If that's something that truly drives you, whatever your motivation, keep it in mind to keep you moving
forward, even when things get difficult.
Whenever you run into an obstacle, you can give yourself a boost by thinking back to the reason you
started in the first place.
Now, motivation is important, but to me what's more important is compounding that internal motivation.
With a healthy dose of discipline, you're not going to be super motivated all the time.
That's just reality.
Motivation often comes in waves.
One day you're super excited and just ready to take on the world.
The next day you feel like you're not making any progress and you just want to stay in bed.
That's normal.
The solution, again, is discipline.
Commit to working on your blog and making tangible progress toward your goals every single day, even
when you don't feel particularly motivated.
This commitment, this habitual progress, is truly what separates world class performers from the rest.
Stephen King famously said amateurs sit and wait for inspiration.
The rest of us just get up and go to work.
If you're just getting started, this mindset stuff might feel a little off the wall, a little tangential,
but the fact is most blogs fizzle out long before they've had a chance to prosper.
There's a lot of competition out there and the odds are fundamentally stacked against you.
But when you're working with the right mindset, it's much easier to make everything else fall into
place.
No blogger has ever failed Midde keystroke.
Let me say that again.
No blogger has ever failed.
Midde keystroke failure comes when you stop executing.
Look, you may not have as much traffic as you want or as much influence as you want, or as much revenue
as you want.
But those things can always be improved.
You only fail if you give up and quit.
So if you can start with a strong sense of internal motivation and follow through with discipline and
habit in your execution, you will be unstoppable.
While we're on the topic of mindset, I should also mention that if money is one of your motivations,
your blog is going to be a business and it deserves to be treated like one with any new business.
They're going to be ups and downs and plenty of setbacks, and it's going to take a good deal of time
and effort to grow.
So make sure you're prepared when you start a blog.
What you're really doing is building a media company and a media company needs a business model.
In most cases, your blog is not the product.
What you're actually selling, what you're charging money for is some other product or service, ad
space consulting services, a book, a course or a physical product of some kind.
When you look at it from that perspective, a blog isn't all that different from any other business.
On a related note, it's helpful to think of your revenue model not as monetizing your blog, but as
providing a valuable product or service that improves the lives of your customers or clients.
It's a subtle distinction, but it makes all the difference in growing your business because it shifts
your focus from lining your own pockets to providing something of value that people are actually willing
to pay for.
We'll discuss specific business models in more detail later in the course.
The last mindset thing I want to cover is for those of you who don't consider yourselves good writers,
this is a mental block that keeps a lot of people from getting started.
Look, maybe you're not the best writer.
Maybe you suck, but so did every other writer when they first started.
The only way to get better at anything is to consistently practice and work on mastering your craft.
Ask any well-known blogger and they'll likely tell you that they're embarrassed by their earliest blog
posts.
In a few years you will be, too.
And that's OK.
Again, the best way to improve your writing is to write.
We'll talk more on that later.
But for now, just understand that you don't have to be a Pulitzer Prize winner to build a successful
blog.