In this lecture, I'm going to share with you a strategy used by some of the world's most prolific content
creators to generate what seems like an infinite stream of fresh content.
So as we saw, when you're creating content for your blog, you have a number of different formats to
choose from.
You can do regular written posts.
You could do audio, you can do video.
You can do other visual formats.
You have plenty of options at your disposal and it can actually be in your interest to do more than
one.
You see, when you create a piece of content in one format, there's a huge opportunity there to repurpose
that content and share it again in a different format.
You can use that as a way to promote the original content or to deliver the same message to a completely
different audience.
You can turn video into text and audio.
You could turn text into video and audio.
You can turn text into an info graphic.
You can turn audio and a video with slides or animation.
You can turn blog posts into social media content by sharing quotes and graphics.
The possibilities here are endless.
Repurposing is one of the most valuable secrets of content creation because it's such a simple and effective
way to extract additional value from your existing content and to grow your audience by reaching people
who may prefer a different format.