Before you can set up a WordPress site, you'll need a couple of things a domain name and a web hosting
account.
Your domain name is the address people will use to visit your site, for example your blog dot com.
Your web host is where your site's files are stored and where will install WordPress in the next lecture.
The simplest approach is to get your domain and web hosting package from the same company.
If you don't, you'll just have to point your domain to your web server, and your host should give
you instructions on how to do that.
But again, if you're just getting started and want to keep everything simple, your best bet is to
grab a domain right along with your hosting package.
My current hosting recommendation, if you're building a brand new blog, is Bluehost, and that's for
a couple of reasons.
Number one, Bluehost is the top hosting recommendation on the official WordPress.org website.
And number two, Bluehost is one of the most affordable hosting providers in the industry, which of
course, is a big plus when you're starting a new project that isn't generating income yet.
Bluehost also makes it incredibly easy to set up a new WordPress site.
You don't need any special knowledge or experience to be able to do it.
It's basically just a couple of clicks.
Now, of course, you don't have to use Bluehost if you have another hosting company that you prefer.
That's totally fine.
But for the purposes of this course, I'm going to show you exactly how to do it with Bluehost, and
you're welcome to follow along.
So let's get started now, hopefully after our lecture on naming and branding.
You've got some ideas in mind for what you might like to name your blog, whether it's just your personal
name or some other brand name that you thought of.
And this is where we're going to kind of set that in stone and register a domain name.
So I've created a special tool for students of this course, where you can easily check to see whether
the name you want is available as a domain name.
And then once you've done that, this tool is going to allow you to get your domain for free with your
Bluehost account, so you'll have to pay for the hosting.
But instead of also having to pay for the domain, that is going to be free for the first year.
So to use this tool, you'll want to go to Brad Names dot com.
That's Brad in Amy's dot com.
This is what it's going to look like.
You can enter any domain name that you're interested in into this box, and it's going to check to see
whether it's available, and it also give you some alternatives with other extensions.
So if the dot com isn't available, you can also see if that same name is available on Dot Net Dawg
and so on.
So if we enter example dot com into this tool, we're going to see that example dot com is unfortunately
unavailable and so is Example Dot Net Dawg, Echo Dot Info, Dot US and dot biz.
So that's not going to work.
But if I enter something a little more original, say my cool test site dot com.
That one actually is available, and so are all these other extensions, so you can spend some time
trying different names in this tool, and when you find a name you like, just click claim this name
to get it for free.
That's going to pop you over to Bluehost, where you can sign up for the basic hosting package that's
going to get your website up and running.
So here you'll need to enter some basic information to create your Bluehost account and process your
payment.
Now, you'll notice you have the option of choosing a billing period from 12 to 36 months.
This part is important because the discounted price will be locked in for whatever period you choose
here, and you'll get a steeper discount if you choose a longer billing period.
So in other words, the longer the billing period, the more money you'll save over time.
Now, of course, that does come with a higher upfront cost.
So really, this comes down to what you personally are comfortable with toward the bottom of the page.
Bluehost is going to offer some package extras.
You can add or remove whatever you want here, but I'll give you some quick thoughts on this stuff.
So first, I would recommend adding domain privacy if it's not included in your plan already.
This just ensures that spammers, telemarketers and random internet crazies can't look up your contact
info and your address in the public domain records.
When you add the Domain Privacy Service, Bluehost will effectively act as your agent using their address
and contact info in the public records for your domain.
The other stuff here you don't really need notice they're offering this Microsoft 365 Mailbox trial.
You can take advantage of that if you want, but keep in mind they are going to charge you for that
after the 30 day trial.
So unless you want that service and you're willing to pay for it, you'll want to either uncheck that
box now or remember to cancel it before it renews.
Once you're satisfied with your options, you can enter your credit card details here or click more
payment options.
If you want to pay with PayPal, then just agree to the terms of service and click Submit.
After you've done this, just follow the instructions on screen to create a username and password for
Bluehost and then log into your account.
Meanwhile, you should have received an email from Bluehost asking you to click a link to activate your
domain name.
Make sure you do this as soon as possible.
That way, your website can get up and running without any delays.