When you're just getting started, one of the best blog promotion strategies is writing a series of
guest posts for other, more influential blogs.
It's a time consuming process, but it can give you a huge payoff by launching your blog into the spotlight
and really putting you on the map.
There's an important caveat, though.
Any guest posts you write have to meet an extremely high standard of quality.
If you write a subpar guest post, it probably won't get published.
But even if it does, remember that this is likely going to be the public's first impression of you.
So make sure you only offer your best work for guest posts as far as actually getting published.
I wrote an article about this a few years ago.
I call it The Art of the Pitch.
As an editor, I've gotten tens of thousands of guest post pitches over the years and most of them go
straight to the trash.
So which ones do I actually pay attention to?
Well, here's what a perfect pitch looks like to me.
Simple but descriptive.
Tell me who you are and why I should care and then give me three specific post ideas to choose from
with a simple outline or description for each one.
Start with the smaller blogs in your industry and work your way up to the big guys as you get some posts
under your belt.
You can also do other types of strategic collaboration, like making an appearance on a relevant YouTube
channel or podcast, being interviewed as an expert, doing traditional PR things of that nature.
The idea is you want to become a familiar face in the media world surrounding your particular industry.
This strategy isn't primarily about links or shout outs or anything like that.
Those are great and they'll definitely help you.
But the main purpose here is putting yourself and your brand on the map so that in the future you can
leverage that existing trust.