One of the best things you can do as a content creator is make it a habit to consume lots of content.
Renowned author Stephen King has a great book called On Writing a Memoir of the Craft.
In it, he discusses how important it is for aspiring writers to dedicate time to reading.
He writes, The real importance of reading is that it creates an ease and intimacy with the process
of writing.
One comes to the country of the writer with one's papers and identification.
Pretty much in order.
Constant reading will pull you into a place, a mindset, if you like, the phrase where you can write
eagerly and without self-consciousness.
It also offers you a constantly growing knowledge of what has been done and what hasn't, what is trite
and what is fresh, what works and what just lies there, dying or dead on the page.
The more you read, the less apt you are to make a fool of yourself with your pen or word processor.
Consuming content is also great for ideas synthesis.
You see, there's really no such thing as an original idea.
This is kind of a weird concept to think about, but it's true.
What we call new ideas are simply new combinations of existing elements.
When you immerse yourself in those existing elements, you can really get your creative juices flowing
and encourage the ideation process.
Now, when I say you should consume lots of content, I don't just mean content that's relevant to your
niche.
You should definitely be reading other blogs in your space, but also take the time to read books,
science, poetry, history, even social media posts.
You'd be surprised how two seemingly unrelated concepts can suddenly click and form an incredible idea.
And often this happens when you least expect it.
There's a concept known as unconscious creativity when you're working on a problem and then you stop
and do something else.
Your unconscious mind keeps working in the background until suddenly you have that light bulb moment
in the shower or in your car or in some other situation where you're not actively trying to come up
with ideas.
So consume lots of content, immerse yourself in all those existing elements, and then step back and
let unconscious creativity work its magic.