Once you decide on an email marketing platform and set up a list, you need to convince people to actually
sign up.
Now, of course, you want a place opt in forms in key locations on your website, but very few people
are going to hand over their contact information just because you asked for it.
You have to incentivize the opt in.
In other words, offer something of value in exchange for an email address.
So what exactly constitutes something of value?
Well, in some cases, it can just be the content of the emails you'll be sending, for example, if
you write an industry newsletter or something like that.
But most of the time, it's better to give people instant gratification with some kind of free resource.
This is often referred to as a lead magnet because it attracts leads and it's probably the most effective
way to get email sign ups.
With that in mind, let's take a look at some examples to help you come up with an effective lead magnet
for your blog.
First, we have a checklist or a cheat sheet.
This is a classic lead magnet that converts really well because it's so easy to digest.
You just package everything people need to know into a simple, actionable list.
And interestingly, the general consensus in the marketing world is that short resources like checklists
actually convert better than something like an ebook because they're short and the time required to
consume them is minimal.
A tool kit is similar.
It's basically a list of tools that you use for a particular purpose.
So if you have an audience of photographers, you could put together a list of your favorite equipment
and software for photography.
A resource list saves people from having to do research themselves, and it compiles the most important
resources on a topic in one place.
A template is some kind of simple outline that people can grab and apply to their lives by filling in
the blanks.
Calendars and planners can be a great opportunity if you want to help people achieve a long term goal.
You tell them what to do each day over a certain period of time, and they do it.
For example, in the health and fitness industry, you could offer meal plans or workout routines as
your lead magnet.
Spreadsheets are a great way to manipulate data and make live calculations, but a lot of people don't
know how to program a spreadsheet themselves.
You can fill that need by offering a spreadsheet template as a free resource.
For example, if you cover personal finance, you could offer a budgeting spreadsheet so people can
just download it and input their own numbers to make it work.
So I mentioned that shorter resources tend to outperform longer ones, but if you can write an extended
guide or e-book that's actionable and rewarding enough, it can be a solid lead magnet.
Just make sure you deliver plenty of value and respect people's time.
Another way to offer deeper value is by delivering an email course.
You can do this with the autoresponder feature in your email marketing service.
Just write up a series of emails and cue them up to send every couple of days or so after someone signs
up.
If you cater to a creative audience, principles can be a great option artistic materials, calendars,
shopping lists, any of these things can be delivered as a print friendly PDF file.
Earlier in the course, we talked about conducting original research and sharing the results in a blog
post, another twist on that concept would be to share the results in a downloadable PDF in exchange
for email addresses.
You can summarize your results on your blog and point people to the free download if they want the full
extended report.
As we've seen in certain scenarios, audio makes more sense as a format than text or video.
It's great for busy entrepreneurs or something like guided meditation, for example, just set up an
Opt-In form and deliver the file as an MP3.
Live webinars are an amazing way to build trust with your audience, and they're also a great way to
collect email addresses, have people sign up if they're interested, and then send them more details
by email.
A super easy but effective way to turn blog readers into subscribers is by offering a PDF version of
your longer blog posts.
For some people, it's just a more convenient way to consume your content.
You can do it manually or use a tool like print friendly dotcom to convert your content into a PDF in
under 60 seconds.
Art and wallpaper, if you do design or photography, you can make some of your work available for free
in exchange for an email address, wallpaper's are great, as are Facebook and Twitter cover photos,
Photoshop templates and things like that can also be really effective if you have an audience of creatives.
We've repeatedly covered the value of niche communities focused on your industry, and I even mentioned
that you may want to create a community of your own.
You can also use that idea as a way to grow your list by offering a private community exclusive to people
who opt in to your email list.
This can be something you create and host yourself, or it can be as simple as a Facebook group or slack
team.
We've also talked about the value of a case study where you tell the story of a particular customer
in the role you played in solving their problem.
Another take on that concept is to put the case study behind an Opt-In form and deliver it by email.
The leads you get from that form are all but guaranteed to be highly qualified and far more likely than
other groups to buy from you.
And along the same lines, offering a free quote in exchange for contact information will also deliver
highly qualified leads that you can follow up with and close.
So those are all solid ideas for potential lead magnets.
Now it's worth mentioning that when you create a lead magnet, it's important that you give it the time
and attention it deserves.
The lead magnet sets the tone for your entire relationship with your email subscribers, so it should
be something you're really proud of.
Now, as far as delivery, most people deliver lead magnets in one of two ways.
The first is to include a download link on the thank you page, which is where you send people as soon
as they sign up.
The other is to put a download link in the welcome email that's delivered as soon as people confirm
their subscriptions.
That's the method I prefer because the download link isn't exposed on a public webpage, so only subscribers
can access it.
Lead magnets are essential for growing an email list, so start thinking about which ones you may be
able to employ for your blog.