In this lecture, I want to offer a quick tip about your words themselves.
It's obviously important that you inspire trust in your audience, and one of the best ways to do that
is with your tone and your vocabulary.
Doing this properly comes down to knowing your audience and understanding what they're looking for.
So with your tone, you generally want to match the attitude of your reader.
You don't want to be perceived as too academic, for example, or on the other side of the spectrum,
too juvenile.
You have to strike a balance between being conversational and being informative.
And what that balance looks like is going to vary from one topic or audience to another.
But the best general advice I can give you here is to be human and authentic.
You're not writing an encyclopedia.
The same principles apply to your vocabulary.
It's always a good idea to use the same words and phrases that your audience uses to describe their
problems and pain points.
That's a great way to form a connection and show that you truly understand them, right?
Because when someone lands on your site and sees their problem explained exactly the way they describe
it, they know right away that you're going to be able to help them.
And that also comes with a more technical benefit when it comes to SEO or search engine optimization.
If you use the words and phrases your target audience is searching for, they're going to be more likely
to find your content when they typed those keywords into Google.
If you're unsure about any of this, as far as what words to use or how to best communicate with your
reader, remember, you can always use the techniques and resources we covered for generating content
ideas to also better understand your target audience.