Once again, unconscious creativity can play a big role in the ideation process, but you're not always
going to have an epiphany in the shower or on your drive home.
Sometimes you need to actively extract those ideas from your mind.
One way to do that is by conducting what's called a brain dump.
Here's how it works.
Set a timer for three to five minutes to create a sense of urgency, then just start jotting down content
ideas as quickly as possible.
You can use sticky notes or a whiteboard or a notebook.
Doesn't matter.
Just come up with as many ideas as you can and get them all written down without filtering your thoughts
at all.
This is about quantity, not quality.
So don't worry about how good or bad your ideas are.
Just get them out of your head and worry about refining them later when the time is up.
Sort through your ideas, decide which ones could work and look for any emerging patterns or combinations
that could work.
You may find that more ideas come to your mind during this process, so be sure to record those as well.
At the end of the process, you should have a solid list of ideas that could potentially fit into your
content strategy.