Here's another quick tip that you may find helpful for creating better content in general, every piece
of content you create should have one core idea or solve one main problem.
You never want to try to do too much with a single piece of content.
If you try to be everything for everyone, you're going to dilute the value and ultimately put off the
people who would otherwise be interested.
So start with the problem you want to solve.
Prepare the solution or the core idea or whatever message you're trying to get across and keep that
in mind throughout the writing process to keep you on course.
Now, just to be clear, it's OK to dive deep into certain aspects of the problem as long as they're
relevant.
For example, I recently wrote a 4600 word blog post with more than 25 different subheadings.
But every section and every word of that post was focused on solving one main problem, step by step.
What you don't want to do is go off on some kind of tangent and start talking about something that doesn't
actually contribute to the value of the post.
So whatever your main goal is, whether that's teaching the reader something, arguing a viewpoint,
selling a product, keep that in mind and make sure that everything you write supports that goal in
some way.