Earlier, we talked about expert roundups as something that may fit into your content strategy, but
it deserves a mention as a promotion strategy to not only our expert roundups, a great content format,
they're also an effective way to get leading influencers to share your content.
So to refresh your memory, you reach out to a bunch of experts, ask them a single question and compile
all their answers into one big post.
Then, and this is where it becomes a promotion strategy.
Send them a link to the post when it goes live because they contributed to it.
Chances are they won't mind sharing it with their audience.
The same principle applies to the people to follow list that we talked about.
In this case, the person didn't necessarily contribute, but it's a pleasant surprise and even an honor
to be recognized as one of the top experts on your topic.
So it's worth reaching out to those people as well and saying, hey, we featured you in our list of
experts in our industry.
More than likely they'll check it out to see what you said about them and hopefully share it with their
audience as well.
Now, a word of warning.
This is a strategy that's been overused a bit in the business and marketing niche.
So it's not as effective in that space as it once was.
But if you cover a different topic, there should be plenty of room for you to do one of these roundups.
And by the way, when you're creating this type of content, please don't just throw a bunch of people
into a list because they have a lot of Twitter followers and might end up sharing your post, choose
your candidates based on merit and make sure the end result is something that actually brings value
to your audience.