There are a ton of Eskow plug ins for WordPress, but Yoast SEO has risen above the rest and it's really
become the industry standard for WordPress.
So it's literally the first plug in I install on every new site.
Yose takes all the headaches out of the more technical aspects of SEO page titles, meta description,
site maps, and it really makes optimization a breeze.
The basic version of Yoast is completely free.
There are premium upgrades available, but honestly, the page features are kind of overkill for most
users.
So head over to the plugin section in your WordPress dashboard click.
Add new search for Yoast SEO and install the plugin.
Once it's installed, you'll see a new SEO option in the main WordPress menu.
This is where you'll manage all the various SEO options that iOS provides.
Feel free to poke around, but we'll cover all the essentials in this section.