Another great type of content is Q&amp;A, questions and answers are always a good starting point, and
it's another straightforward way to provide value.
Your audience has questions and you have answers as far as what questions to answer.
We kind of talked about that in the ideas section.
There are so many places to get to know your audience and see what questions they're asking.
One of my favorites again is Quora.
There's just so much information on that site, not just in the answers themselves, but in the wealth
of public data.
You can find on a topic page the most frequently asked questions, how many people are following each
question and so on.
There are a couple of ways to approach Q&amp;A content.
You can write a long list style post answering a bunch of related questions in one place where you can
write a single post answering a single question in detail.
Neither of these approaches is necessarily superior.
They each have their strengths.
So, for example, if I were to write a post listing, say, the top 15 questions asked by new content
marketers, that could be really valuable for people who fall into that demographic and it's going to
be really shareable.
But if I write a post answering just one question and using the question itself as my headline, that
gives me the opportunity to rank on Google and other search engines.
When people search for that question, when it comes to actually writing your answer, make sure you
do some research and see what's already out there and determine how you can dive deeper or offer more
value than the competition.
For example, if a question is really popular on Quora, Quora is almost certainly going to outrank
you when people search for that question just because it's such a popular, authoritative site.
But you can still stand a fighting chance by creating something that's better and more valuable than
any of the answers on Quora and then promoting it accordingly.