The first thing you'll want to do with the Yoast CEO plugin is optimize your page titles, page titles,
determine what you see in your browser tab when you visit your site, and they also dictate how your
site appears in the search results.
The page title is the first line for each result.
So it's your chance to make a great first impression.
In just a moment, we'll use your to go ahead and configure our page titles.
But first, what does a good page title look like?
Well, first, it goes without saying that every title should be descriptive and enticing to encourage
people to click through next.
The keywords you want to rank for should appear early in your page titles.
This is for two reasons.
First, search engines give more ranking weight to the early words.
And second, when people quickly skim through the search results, they're going to see the early words
first.
So if your keywords appear early in your page titles, you're going to be more likely to rank highly
and people are going to be more likely to click through to your site.
It's also a good idea to include your site name in your titles for the sake of brand recognition, but
you'll want that to appear at the end.
So to summarize, good titles are descriptive and enticing.
Contain your target keyword, preferably at the beginning, and contain your brand name, preferably
at the end.
So to configure your global title settings, click search appearance under the menu in WordPress.
The first setting here is your title separator.
This is simply a separator symbol that appears between different elements of your title, like your
post title in your site name.
This is totally arbitrary.
Just pick the one you like the best.
Below that you can set the title for your home page by default.
It's just the name of your site, followed by a page number, which only appears if you're on page two
or three or whatever of your blog, you can customize this using a number of variables or by simply
typing in a custom title of your own.
Next click over to the content types tab.
On this page, you can set the default title template for your posts and pages.
Yost's default arrangement contains these elements.
The title of your post, a page number, which again only appears if you're on at least page two of
your comment section in this case, then we have our separate symbol and then the site title.
Visually, this would typically translate to something like this.
Given that your post titles will likely contain your target keywords, this is a perfect configuration.
It meets all of our requirements for a good title.
If your title structure doesn't look like this, I'd recommend changing it so it does.
You can then use the tabs at the top of this page to adjust your titles for media attachments, taxonomies
such as your categories and tags and archive pages, making sure to follow the same principles for each
of those.
Yoast also allows you to set a custom title for an individual post or page overwriting the default template.
This is a great way to optimize for a specific keyword and ensure your search snippet looks exactly
the way you want without editing the actual name of your post or page.
After you install the Yoast plug in, a new Yoast SEO panel becomes available on the Post editor.
This panel gives you an idea of how your page will appear in the search results.
You can click edit snippet to customize your page title using variables, plaintext or combination of
the two.
This colored bar under the title field indicates whether your page title is too long to be fully displayed
shorter than recommended or just write.
Ideally, you want this bar to be green.
It's always a good idea to examine your snippet preview before publishing a post.
If your title isn't optimized for the keyword you're targeting, it's easy to customize it.