In this lecture, I want to give you a quick overview of the WordPress dashboard to make sure you understand
where everything is and how it all works.
Once again, you can find your WordPress dashboard at your domain slash WP Dash admin.
This is going to be super basic, so bear with me if you're a little more advanced, but I just want
to make sure you have a good understanding of how WordPress works so we can start to dive deeper as
we move forward.
So let's start over here with the main menu.
You'll be using this menu a lot to navigate between different admin pages in WordPress.
The first thing you should notice is that our current page, the dashboard is highlighted and expanded,
and it has a couple of submenu options underneath it.
The same is true with the rest of the menus here.
Just hover your mouse over each option to expand it.
So after the dashboard, we have posts, which is where you manage your blog posts, media, which is
where you'll find any photos, videos or audio that you've uploaded to the site.
Pages are a little different from posts.
These are your permanent static pages like you're about page or your contact page comments.
That's where you can manage and moderate the comments people leave on your site.
Appearance is where you manage your themes and the overall look and feel of your site, plug ins are
basically extensions that add various functionality to WordPress to make it do exactly what you want
it to do, and you can add and manage plug ins here.
Under users, you can edit your profile and account information, or you can add other users to your
site with the exact editing privileges you want them to have.
In the Tools menu, you'll find things like import and export tools, which allow you to move content
from one state to another.
Settings includes all the global settings for WordPress and your site itself.
And finally, you can actually collapse this entire menu to give yourself a little more work space.
And then just click that little icon to bring it back.
Now, let's take a look at the admin bar at the very top of the page.
We'll just start from the left side and work our way across.
The WordPress logo here is something you'll probably never use, but I guess it doesn't hurt to have
it there.
If you click it, it'll give you information about your current version of WordPress and then you can
also go to WordPress.org, read the documentation, visit the support forums or send feedback.
The next item here is just the name of your site.
If you click that, it'll take you to your homepage.
Next, there's a comment button with a little icon to let you know how many comments are waiting for
your approval.
And then we have the new button, which is probably what you'll use more than anything else on the admin
bar.
You can use these options to add a new post, media page or user.
And finally, if we jump all the way over to the right side, it says howdy and then your username.
That's just a quick shortcut to edit your profile or log out.
Now, let's zoom out and take a look at the main dashboard page itself.
When you first create your site, you'll see this box at the top that says, Welcome to WordPress.
We've assembled some links to get you started.
So basically just gives you some easy shortcuts to the essentials.
Pretty useful as you're getting started, but if you want to get rid of it, just click Dismiss and
it disappears.
If you want to bring it back, you can go up to screen options.
And by the way, you'll find this on just about every page inside WordPress.
And check the box next to welcome.
Now, of course, you can also select or select any of these other options to show or hide whatever
you want.
And if you want to customize your experience a little more, you can drag and drop each of these dashboard
widgets to whatever location you like.
And while we're on the subject, let's talk about these widgets and what they do at a glance tells you
some quick information about your site, the number of posts, pages and comments, along with the version
of WordPress you're running and your theme activity shows you what's happening with your site right
now.
You can see your recently published posts and recent comments.
Quick Draft lets you type in a title and just a little bit of content to save it as a draft.
So if you have a quick idea for a blog post, you can use that to make sure you don't forget.
And then you have the WordPress news widget, which is basically just a feed of updates from the official
WordPress blog.
So I guess that's it.
That is the WordPress dashboard, in a nutshell.
Feel free to click around and do some exploring.