Quora is one of my favorite sites on the Web.
It's a Q&amp;A service where people ask and answer questions on thousands of different topics and the questions
get answered by real people with real experience.
I don't know if you remember Yahoo's Q&amp;A site, Yahoo!
Answers, but, man, it was an absolute disaster, wasn't it?
The questions were bad, the answers were bad, and there wasn't really a system in place to keep the
community positive and helpful.
That's not the case with Quora.
They've managed to create an incredible community where you have everyone from car mechanics to astrophysicists
answering questions about their expertise.
And if you consider yourself a curious person, it is a joy to use.
With that in mind, Quora can also be an asset for your content creation efforts because it allows you
to see what questions people are asking about your industry.
So you go to Quora, dotcom, enter a topic and then browse popular questions and answers about that
topic.
If you click topic A Q, you'll see a curated list of the most common questions people have on that
You can also browse related topics and do the same with each of those.
Just like Buzz.
This is a great way to explore the psyche of your ideal reader.
You can see exactly what questions they're asking, what problems they're experiencing, even what words
they're using.
And aside from just knowing your audience, you can also use Quora questions as a direct starting point
for new content.
If a lot of people are asking a particular question and you have the expertise to provide a helpful
answer, there's your piece of content.