If you want to inspire trust in your audience, your writing should be free of errors and your spelling
and grammar should be impeccable.
Now, look, nobody's perfect.
We all make mistakes.
And one of the beautiful things about the Internet is that you can usually go back and fix your mistakes
even after you've published your content.
But the fact of the matter is, people judge you based on your ability to communicate properly.
And if your post is littered with grammatical errors, you're going to face judgment and it's going
to be harder to establish that trust because you're showing a lack of attention to detail.
For example, if I'm reading a blog post about taxes written by a leading accountant and tax expert,
but throughout the post they're using your instead of your, that's going to cause me to think whether
consciously or unconsciously, how can I trust this person to give me tax advice when they can't even
handle basic grammar?
And I don't say that to be a jerk.
I know some people struggle with that stuff, but it's just the cold, honest truth.
People will judge you for your spelling and grammar errors.
So you need to take steps to ensure that those errors don't happen first and foremost, if you haven't
already.
I would strongly urge you to invest the necessary time to learn and master all the grammatical rules
of whatever language you're writing in.
That's important.
Educating yourself is one of the most effective things you can do and that education is going to continue
to pay off for years to come.
Second, and this is especially important if you know you're prone to errors in your writing, have
an editor proofread your content before you publish it.
If you can catch errors in-house before they ever reach your audience, you can have confidence that
everything you publish is high quality and error free.
Finally, please take advantage of the technology you have at your disposal to improve your writing.
Your standard spell check is great for typos and some basic grammatical errors.
But if you really want a comprehensive safety net, I recommend you check out grammar, which gives
you real time context based feedback on the mechanics usage, grammar and spelling in your writing.
It's basically like having an editor looking over your shoulder at all times, which is really helpful.
So with all of that in mind, hopefully you see why error free writing is so important and what you
can do to ensure your writing against those pesky grammar mistakes.