Membership sites are another popular revenue model that has the potential to bring in recurring and
ever increasing revenue for you, a membership site could offer a catalog of courses, an exclusive
community, some kind of live coaching service or something of that nature, and people pay on a monthly
or annual basis for access.
I think membership sites can be a great opportunity, but I have to be honest, they're a difficult
sell.
There are so many membership sites out there.
And it begs the question, does the world really need another membership site?
If you want to be successful with this model, you have to focus on providing some kind of unique value
prop to differentiate yourself.
Why should people join?
And perhaps more importantly, why should they stick around for the long run?
And it may require more upfront work than something like an information product.
If you're offering a catalog of courses, for example, you have to first produce those multiple courses.
And if you're offering a community, you have to seed the community and get some real engagement started
as soon as possible.
Nobody wants to join a ghost town community, especially if they have to pay for it.
Now, if you have your heart set on a membership service, I'm not trying to discourage you.
Often the best opportunities are those with the highest barriers to entry.
If you're up to the challenge and feel you can bring unique value to the table, I say go for it.
You can use plugins like membership by PMU Dev or member press to get the job done.
And again, the sales process is very much like selling a product.
You publish epic content, funnel people into your list with free resources, provide value, build
relationships and then say, hey, if you want to dive deeper, here's a membership where you can get
X, Y and Z.