If your site has a comment section, you know, the people who take the time to leave comments are some
of your most engaged visitors.
So what if you could turn them into email subscribers?
There are a couple of ways to do this.
One way is to redirect people to a thank you page right after they leave a comment.
And on that page, you could offer some kind of free resource if they opt in.
If you use WordPress, you can use the comment redirect plug in, which automatically redirects first
time commenters to a page of your choice.
And it's nice because it's only first time commenters, so you won't be constantly harassing people
who comment regularly.
Another method is to add a checkbox to the comment form itself, where commenters can choose to join
your list right as they post their comments.
Again, if you use WordPress, there are plenty of plugins that do this, including MailChimp for WordPress
and newsletter sign up.