Let's take a look at the WordPress content editor now, as we saw, the page editor and the Post editor
are almost exactly the same, but we're going to dive into the Post editor here because there are a
few extra settings for posts that you should be aware of.
So first of all, you have your post title, we'll go ahead and enter that and then we'll jump straight
down into the main post content.
We compose content in WordPress using these things called Bloks, a blog is basically just a small section
of content in your post is going to be made up of a series of blogs.
Once you get used to this, it's really intuitive.
So if I were to just start typing here, that creates a paragraph blog for me and you'll notice that
when you move your mouse over a paragraph block, you get these formatting options that you're probably
used to from using any other word processor.
So if I press enter, that creates a new block for me.
And if I just keep typing in this new block, it's just treated as another paragraph.
So again, it's just like any other word processor.
But if I want to add some other content element, an image or a heading or something like that, I can
click this plus sign to see a list of options.
Let's go ahead and add a heading.
As you can see, the sidebar over here changes to give you specific options, depending on which type
of block you're working on.
So we'll go ahead and add a subheading formatted as heading to and then press enter to jump down to
the next block, which again defaults to a standard paragraph.
And you'll notice that you can also use these buttons over here to choose from your most commonly used
blocks without having to browse through that menu.
One of the nice things about blocks is that you can rearrange them really easily if you want to.
So say I wanted to move this heading up.
All I have to do is use these options over on the left side of the block.
You can use the arrows or you can drag and drop.
Editing with blocks is a new experience for some people, but I think you'll find again that it's really
intuitive and easy to learn and once you're used to it, it just makes so much sense and it makes creating
content really easy.
So if we click out of our blocks, you'll see that the sidebar switches over to the document tab.
These are your main settings for this particular post.
They're pretty self-explanatory, but we'll run through them real quick here.
So this ability determines whether your post is public, private or password protected.
Most of the time, obviously, you're going to want to leave that public.
Under publish, you can choose to publish your post immediately or schedule for the future or backdate
it so that it appears to have been published in the past.
If you choose to stick the post to the front page, it will always appear on top, even when new posts
have been published after it.
Pending review is generally used for multi author sites where a particular post needs to be reviewed
by an editor.
Below that, you can specify categories as well as tags, every post has to have a category, but not
every post has to have tags.
If you don't specify a category, it'll just go into the default category, which is uncategorized.
Next, you'll choose your featured image, which is basically just a thumbnail for your post, and it
may also appear at the top of your post, depending on what theme you use.
Under excerpt, you can write a custom post excerpt that will show up with this post on your home page
and archives instead of it just pulling out the first few sentences under discussion, you can choose
whether you want to allow comments on this post appear at the top.
You can preview your posts so you can see exactly what it'll look like on your site.
You can save a draft if you want to come back and finish the post later or if you're ready to go, you
can go ahead and click, publish, confirm your settings and publish the post.
So that is the Post editor, obviously one of the core parts of the WordPress interface.
So hopefully now you'll feel pretty comfortable using it.