Another great type of content that you've probably seen and used yourself many times is a review.
Reviews are pretty self-explanatory.
You take a look at a product or service that's relevant to your audience and provide an honest review
of your thoughts and experiences, breaking down the good and the bad.
The goal of a good review is to inform the readers buying decision.
You want to give them all the information they need to make an informed choice.
The most important thing here is to be completely honest.
Your reviews should serve your audience, not the brand or the product itself.
If a product is amazing, you should say so.
But if it sucks, be honest about that and recommend against buying it.
I found the best way to write a review is to start with a brief summary.
Go ahead and disclose your recommendation right up front.
Is the product worth buying or not?
Then break the product down into the most important categories.
For example, if you were reviewing a pair of wireless headphones, you could divide your review into
sections for sound quality noise, cancelling connectivity, battery life and so on.
And for each of these categories, you'll want to provide a detailed analysis of your experience, both
the good and the bad.
I like to close a review with a list of pros and cons and then the bottom line, where I explained whether
I recommend the product or not.
The natural extension of a review is a comparison where you compare to similar products that are competing
in the same market.
In this case, you'll want to go over the details of each product, but focus specifically on the key
differences between the two.
For example, this pair of headphones has longer battery life, but this other pair offer superior sound
quality, things like that.
When you're comparing to products, you may find that there's a clear cut winner, in which case you
should say so.
But often one product or the other may be better suited for a particular group of people.
So you could say the pair of headphones with really good battery life is great for the traveler who's
always on the go.
But the pair with better sound quality is better suited for the audio file.
Who wants the best possible sound experience?
Again, the goal is to provide helpful information to inform the audiences buying decisions.
Keep that in mind.