We keep coming back to niche communities like forums, Subrata, Facebook groups, these are all important
places for you as a content creator to be.
On one hand, it's a great way to get to know your audience, which can help you to create better content.
But these places can also serve as distribution channels if you approach them carefully and respect
their rules.
Nobody likes the shameless self promoter who shows up and starts promoting their own stuff without establishing
a reputation or adding anything of value to the community.
So make sure you know the rules of any community you join and focus on becoming an active member.
First, you can find forums pretty simply by Googling something like your topic, plus forums.
If you end up joining a forum site, one of the simplest ways to promote what you have to offer without
being obtrusive is by including a link in your signature or your profile, and then just focusing on
providing so much value natively on the community itself that people start proactively seeking out your
content to find a Subrata relevant to your industry.
You can go to Reddit dotcom slash credits, enter the topic you're interested in, and it'll give you
some suggestions.
The same rules apply on Reddit, possibly even more so.
You never want to be seen as a spammer.
Reddit is not kind to people who just constantly self promote.
They have this thing called a shadow band, which is basically a way of banning people from the community
without telling them that they've been banned.
So if moderators notice that all you do is promote your own stuff, they can shadow ban you and on your
end you'll still be posting things and using Reddit as normal.
But nobody else will see your posts.
You don't want that to happen.
So keep yourself promotional posts few and far between and again, always focus on providing value to
the community natively without trying to draw people out.
It's counterintuitive, but when people know you and trust you, your occasional self promotional posts
are going to carry a lot more weight and people are going to see them as valuable rather than spammy.
When it comes to groups on Facebook and LinkedIn, the same principles apply.
There's really not much more to say.
Just make sure you know the rules of the community, participate in conversations, provide value and
keep self promotion to a minimum.
As a bonus tip here, another way to approach niche communities for the purpose of content promotion
is by creating a community of your own.
Start your own forum, start your own Facebook group, get some people on board and work on cultivating
a positive, valuable community where you're interacting with your audience, where your audience is
interacting with each other, and then you'll have a platform that you control where you can share content
freely.