We covered social proof earlier in the course, but it's worth reiterating here, social proof works
wonders when you're trying to get people to do anything, whether it's sharing an article, buying a
product or opting in to your list.
If you already have a sizable list, say, ten thousand subscribers, you can show off that number as
a means of social proof.
But if you're just starting out, you're not going to have a huge subscriber base to flaunt.
So here's an alternative testimonials.
Quote, Someone saying something nice about you or your work bonus points.
If that person is a prominent figure in your industry, even if you're relatively new to the game,
you can get testimonials from influencers by offering them some kind of value first, such as a guest
post for their blog.
But even if you don't have anything from the big guys, something is always better than nothing.
Reach out to your most engaged readers and ask for a quote.
If someone leaves you a nice comment or a review, ask permission to feature it.
Social proof will lend credibility to your brand and increase your conversion rates.