WordPress is an extremely powerful content management system, and one of the reasons for that is how
easy it is to customize your site and build something truly unique that's made possible by themes.
WordPress themes take the data and content from WordPress and display it in a way that looks nice and
hopefully meets your individual needs.
WordPress needs a theme to function properly.
So you'll notice that when you first install WordPress, a default theme is already installed and activated
for you.
The default theme gets an overhaul about once a year, and as you'd expect, it's compatible with most
of the things you'd want to do with a WordPress site.
But if you want to give your site a more unique look, you can also install a third party theme.
There are a few ways to get a WordPress theme.
You can get a free one from the WordPress repository.
You can buy one from a third party seller or marketplace.
Or if you really want to go crazy, you could create your own or hire a designer to create one for you.
But in most cases, you should be able to find a WordPress theme that looks and feels exactly how you
want just by doing a little searching.
So the easiest and cheapest way to get a WordPress theme is by installing a free one from the theme
repository on WordPress dawg.
There are thousands to choose from and just because they're free doesn't necessarily mean they're inferior
to premium themes.
Some are definitely better than others.
But there's a nice rating system that should help you identify which themes are good and which ones
aren't so good.
You can actually access the theme repository directly through your own WordPress dashboard.
Just head over to the theme section under appearance and click add new.
There are themes for just about anything.
So whatever you're looking for, you're bound to find something you like.
At the top of this page, you can choose to view featured themes, the most popular themes or the latest
themes, and then you can filter that list by layout, features and subject.
When you see a theme that piques your interest, you can click on it to see a more detailed description
and a rough preview.
If you like it, you can click install to add it to your site and then you can activate it right away
or go back to the main themes page inside WordPress and click live preview next to that theme that you
just installed to see what your actual site will look like.
With that theme, you can then customize some settings using this panel on the left side.
And when you're satisfied, click, activate and publish.
In addition to the free themes from WordPress, dawg, there's a whole world of premium themes that
you can buy from third party sellers and marketplaces.
Like I said, there's nothing inherently wrong with free themes.
But premium themes as a whole do tend to offer more advanced functionality and higher quality design
than free themes.
And the purchase price usually includes support and documentation.
So if anything goes wrong or if you need help getting set up, you've got a lifeline there to help you
out.
So if you have a little money to invest, a premium WordPress theme can be a great investment.
There are a ton of places to buy WordPress themes.
If you do a Google search for WordPress themes, you'll be looking at theme after theme on site after
site for hours.
Personally, one of my favorite places to buy themes is Theme Forest Dot Net, which is a huge marketplace
of independent developers selling their themes in one central location.
The prices are pretty reasonable, anywhere from 20 to 70 U.S. dollars, which is nothing compared to
what you'd have to pay a designer to create a comparable design for you.
So wherever you end up, whether it's theme forest or some other vendor, the process looks pretty much
the same.
Just find a theme like purchase it and then you'll be able to download it as a zip file.
So I'm going to go over to the downloads page and my theme forest account and download one of the themes
I've purchased in the past.
It gives me the option to download all the files and documentation or just the install WordPress file.
Usually I prefer to just get the installer file because it's super easy to upload to WordPress.
In fact, I'll show you what that looks like right now.
If you log in to WordPress and go to the themes page under appearance and then click add new, you'll
see the same page we saw earlier when we were looking at three themes.
But this time we're going to click the upload theme button right at the top and you can add that zip
file right there and it'll install just like that.
So those are the two main ways to install a WordPress theme.
Now, choosing a theme is the hard part, and that always ends up being a huge time suck for me when
I launch a new project.
So I'll leave that part up to you.