From an audio perspective, it's a good idea to have a strategy in mind and know what keywords you want
a page to rank for before you even start writing content for it.
But how do you decide on a keyword to target?
How do you know what to type into that focus keyword box?
Well, you'll have to do some research.
If you're writing a blog post, you'll usually want to aim for what's called a long tail keyword, which
is basically a specific keyword containing multiple words.
If you have a general idea for what you're going for, a great starting point is to go to Google, start
typing some variation of your potential keyword and look at the suggestions in the drop down menu.
By the way, before you do this, I recommend signing out of your Google account or opening a private
browser window so the options won't include your search history or tailored suggestions.
But anyway, all of these suggestions come from real search data.
So these are actual keywords that people are using to search the web.
A good starting point for this method would be frequently asked questions.
Think of the questions that people in your target audience often ask and spin those into the keywords
they may use to do research.
This is another time when Quora and Reddit and niche communities come in handy.
Once you've found some potential keywords you'd like to rank for, the next thing you'll want to do
is determine the search volume for those keywords.
In other words, how many people are searching for them?
Ideally, you'll want something with a relatively high search volume because that means you can get
a lot of traffic by ranking for that keyword to determine search volume, you can use the Google keyword
planner, which you can find pretty easily just by typing keyword planner into Google.
Now, to use this tool, you'll need an active Google AdWords account.
You don't have to run any campaigns or anything, but you do need an active account.
When you get into the keyword planner, you'll see a few options.
We're going to select the one that says get search volume, data and trends.
When this box pops up, you can enter one or more longtail keywords.
Either one per line or separated by commas, for this example, will just enter one keyword and then
click get search volume.
What you get is a table of the keywords you entered in the average number of monthly searches for each
keyword.
There are also columns here for competition and a suggested bid.
Those are directed more at advertisers who are considering running ads for this keyword.
They don't really apply to our objectives here, so you can ignore those.
So just take a look at the average monthly searches for each of your potential keywords.
Eliminate the ones with low search volumes and then make a list of the ones that look like they're worth
pursuing.
Next, go back to Google, make sure you're either signed out or using a private browser window and
then just run a search for each of the keywords on your list.
Make sure to skip over any ads that appear at the top and then take a look at the first few organic
search results.
Are they the same type of content you intend to create?
Would your page fit well into these results?
You'll also want to assess the quality of the results.
Now, of course, this is kind of subjective, but it really comes down to this question.
Would any of the search results completely satisfy someone searching for that keyword?
Once you've answered that, you have a couple of options for your next move when there's nothing on
page one of the search results that would completely satisfy the readers needs, you have the opportunity
to write the first article of its kind.
So spend some time doing research and putting together a really epic resource that provides exactly
what people are looking for when they search for that term.
The second and more likely scenario is that there's already at least one piece of content that would
satisfy the reader, and that's probably result number one.
The question then becomes, can you create something better?
If the first result isn't absolutely amazing, you can take advantage of that and write the article
that people really need by diving deeper and offering more substance than the other top results.
And finally, if you're in a situation where all of the top results for your keyword already offer extremely
valuable content, you still have another option.
You can create a piece of equally amazing content in a different format.
You see the most competitive search results.
Spots are usually won by writers because they can create detailed, long form content that delivers
a ton of value to their readers.
But what about people who don't have an extra fifteen or twenty minutes to read a super long article,
or people who prefer to learn visually?
Often what those long form pieces are lacking is a short synopsis that makes it easier to digest.
You can offer that by presenting the same information as an info graphic or a checklist or video or
anything else that takes existing information and presents it in a different way.
Of course, you'll want to cite your sources and give credit where it's due, but your content may actually
be more valuable than the original stuff to a certain segment of people who prefer that alternative
format.
So those are some ideas you can use to choose a target keyword and create a piece of content that's
worthy of ranking for that keyword.