In this lecture, we're going to cover one of the most effective ways to significantly grow your audience
pretty much overnight, and I know that's a big promise, but this method really delivers if you execute
it properly.
So what are we talking about here?
We're talking about giveaways.
Giveaways generate a ton of buzz because everybody wants free stuff.
Right.
But like I said, if you want to use a giveaway to actually grow your business, you have to be very
strategic in your execution.
Let me explain.
First and foremost, you have to choose a relevant product.
This is the most important part, and it's where most brands fail.
You see, you can give away just about anything of value and you're going to get a lot of traffic and
a lot of entries.
But at the end of the day, if your product isn't relevant to your business, you're just going to get
a bunch of targeted traffic and an audience of people who have no interest in your content and will
never buy from you all the brands giving away iPads and stuff like that.
That is a terrible strategy because think about who wants a free iPad.
Everybody wants a free iPad.
Unless your business is actually focused on electronics or Apple products, giving away an iPad is not
going to help you.
A good product for a giveaway is one that's highly desired, but appeal specifically to your target
audience.
Often this may be your own product, right?
Because what better way to attract people who are interested in your product than by giving away your
product?
But it could be something else entirely.
The idea is to give away something that's extremely valuable to your target market, but may not be
valuable to a random person you meet on the street in terms of actually conducting the giveaway.
There are two plug ins that I highly recommend.
Gleam and King Sumo.
They're both excellent and they allow you to collect emails for your list while also tackling one of
the big problems with viral giveaways.
Nobody wants to share a giveaway because the more people who enter, the lower their chances of winning
become.
And that makes perfect sense.
People tend to act in their own self-interest.
But these plug ins actually incentivize sharing by giving people additional entries for referring their
friends.
So, for example, you get one entry right away and then if you share on Facebook, you get a second
entry, a third for sharing on Twitter.
And then if you refer X number of people, you get X number of additional entries.
This is a much better system than the traditional one entry per person approach because it incentivizes
sharing and makes your giveaway go viral with very little promotion on your part.
With that said, you do still want to do some promotion to kind of get the ball rolling.
A good place to start is by reaching out to friends and contacts, telling them about the giveaway and
asking them to enter and share.
Promote it to your existing email list.
Again, they're already engaged with your brand.
They'll appreciate the opportunity to win a free product and they're likely to share it with their friends.
If you've put the right incentives in place, then of course you'll want to promote it to the rest of
your website visitors.
Most likely you're going to use a blog post as the main entry page, but make sure you're pushing people
in that direction from other areas of your site.
For example, you could use something like the Halo Bar, which adds a simple header bar to the top
of your site where you can say, hey, we're giving away this product, click here to enter.
And of course, you can also submit your giveaway to some relevant Subrata Facebook groups and so on.
And by the time you've done all of this, your giveaway should be gaining steam through people sharing
it, and you should start to see an influx of highly targeted traffic.
Once again, if you select a relevant product, incentivize sharing and do a little bit of promotion
ahead of time.
A giveaway is one of the most effective strategies you can deploy for fast growth.