In the past, a major focus of SVO was this concept of keyword density, which is the percentage of
times a key word or phrase appears on a Web page compared to the total number of words on that page.
Search engines use keyword density as a ranking signal to determine how relevant a page is to a particular
search term.
If a keyword appears a bunch of times on a page, it would make sense to rank that page higher for that
keyword, right?
Unfortunately, the spammy marketers of the world figured out how that worked and started keyword stuffing
basically over optimizing their pages by including the same keyword or related keywords over and over
and over as many times as they could.
And the result was a bunch of pages ranking that weren't actually useful.
They just happened to have keywords littered all over the page with no regard for the quality of the
content.
Google's response came in 2011 with an algorithm update called Pande, which was intended to reduce
the rank of low quality sites and content farms while increasing the rank of higher quality sites that
are more useful to the end user.
One of the effects of the panda update is that keyword density is no longer a linear ranking signal.
So if your keyword density is too low, that tells Google that your page probably isn't relevant.
But it can also be too high.
And if it's too high, that tells Google you're probably a spammer.
Just stuffing your page with keywords.
Today, the ideal keyword density is somewhere between zero point five percent and 2.5 percent.
But rather than stressing about keyword density, just focus on creating a great resource and work keywords
into your content.
Naturally, if you use WordPress, you can enter your focus keyword into the host section in the Post
editor and it'll let you know if your content is over or under optimized.