Next up, we have thought and opinion content, your mileage may vary with this one depending on your
brand and your personal style, but opinion pieces are a great way to go deeper with your content and
encourage reader engagement.
Consider an issue that's important to your audience and take a side elaborated on your position with
logical arguments and help the reader understand your point of view.
You don't want to come across as preachy, so allow some room for disagreement, but at the same time
assert your position and don't be wishy washy.
Interestingly, controversy is very good for traffic and engagement.
I don't think you should actively seek out controversy, but I will say that any time I've taken a stance
on a controversial issue, it has generated a lot of buzz.
Now, of course, I'm talking about things that pertain to your audience and your niche.
Politics and religion and other heavy, divisive topics are usually not going to fit into your strategy
unless, of course, your blog is about one of those particular things, in which case go for it.
But if you're going to weigh in on an issue, make sure it's something that actually matters to your
audience specifically.
For example, a few years ago I wrote a series of posts about a large guest blogging network that was
using some, let's say, questionable tactics to game search engine rankings for the members of their
network.
I took a hard stance against that.
And while I took a lot of heat from the network itself and some of its members, my coverage was widely
credited for spurring Google to take action against them.
So even though it was controversial, my content was informative and persuasive.
It was relevant to my audience in the tech and business world and as a bonus, it resulted in an actual
solution to the problem.