Whenever you're writing a post, it's a good idea to include relevant internal links to other pages
on your site that'll help your users dig deeper into your content, and it'll also help search engines
understand the relevance of certain pages, the value of those pages and the relationships between different
pages.
As we discussed, search engines crawl websites by following links when you link from one place to another
post.
That's a way of signaling that those pages are related.
When it comes to internal linking, you should prioritize the content that you consider to be most important.
Most likely, you'll have a handful of posts that drive a significant portion of your traffic, the
kind of core resources that your site has to offer.
You'll want to link to those whenever you have the opportunity.
Now, it should always be relevant.
Don't just add random links all over the place, but whenever you feel it would make sense to link to
one of your most important posts, you should do so.
This passes link value onto those pages, and the more you do that, the more clear it'll be to the
search engines that those pages represent your most valuable content, which will help them rank more
highly when you add internal links.
What should the anchor text be if you're not familiar?
Anchor text is the clickable text that's actually displayed to your visitors.
In the old days of the common advice was to optimize your anchor text by using keywords.
Basically, if you linked to a post enough times using the same keyword as the anchor text, that post
would start ranking for that keyword.
But today, search engines are a little bit smarter and pay more attention to the context of the surrounding
content than to the anchor text itself.
On top of that, over optimizing by always linking with the same keyword can actually have a negative
impact because Google considers that to be a little spammy, just like the keyword stuffing tactic we
talked about earlier.
So these days, the main thing to think about is whether the anchor text looks natural in your copy
and provides an actual benefit to the end user.
It's OK to use keywords, but don't go overboard and use the same anchor text every time you link to
a post.