One of the biggest selling points of WordPress is its extensibility, you're not stuck with the default
set of features, your WordPress site is yours to customize, and it's very easy to customize.
WordPress plugins offer a way to extend the functionality of your website without having to write the
code yourself.
Just like Theme's WordPress has a repository of free plug ins, which you can also access from the plugin
section of your dashboard.
Plug ins range in their scope from simple things like adding social media buttons to your blog posts
to more complex things like turning your site into a full fledged social network.
So just to give you some examples, let's take a look at a few popular plug ins on WordPress, dawg.
A kismet actually comes preinstalled with every new WordPress installation in its function is to monitor
your comments and contact form submissions to protect your site from spam.
The jetpack plugin gives you access to a bunch of features that are offered to WordPress dotcom users
that self hosted WordPress sites don't have out of the box, for example, it has a great stat tracking
feature that monitors your traffic and gives you real time audience data at a glance.
BBY Press is a solution for adding forums to your WordPress site, and it's actually the same plug in
that WordPress dot org uses for its support forums.
And finally, Yoast CEO is probably the best WordPress plugin for search engine optimization.
We'll actually talk about Yoast in depth later in the course.
So these are just a few examples.
We could talk all day about different plug ins and what they do.
And we'll talk about several specific ones throughout this course.
But for now, I just wanted to introduce you to what they are and where to find them before you install
a plug in from the WordPress repository, always check out the reviews to see what other people are
saying about it.
Does it do what it claims to do?
Does it cause any problems or conflict with other plugins?
You'll often find that information in the reviews.
You can also purchase premium plugins from third party vendors.
But that's not something you'll need to do very often because most of the functionality you can think
of is already covered by free plug ins on WordPress, dawg.