One aspect of that often gets overlooked is image optimization, search engines have no problem reading
your text, but they usually need a little help to understand the context of your photos.
But if you add the proper metadata to your images, which only takes a few seconds, you can generate
some extra traffic by helping your photos rank in places like Google Images, for example.
And as an added benefit, you can also help visually impaired readers make sense of your content if
they're using a screen reader.
The process here is super simple.
Whenever you upload an image to WordPress and insert it into a post or page, take a second to write
a descriptive alt attribute to tell search engines exactly what the image is as I'm doing here.
This is a simple but effective way to tap into a traffic source that your competitors probably neglect.