One of the responsibilities that comes with hosting your own WordPress site is managing your own security
and backups.
This is a pretty dull subject and a lot of people tend to put it off or just assume it's not that important.
But trust me, if your site ever gets hacked or if you lose a bunch of data and some kind of catastrophe,
you're going to wish you've been prepared from the start.
We won't spend too much time on this, but I want to go over the essentials so you can protect yourself.
Let's start with the most basic thing passwords.
Understand that as the administrator of your WordPress site, your password is the only thing stopping
an intruder from gaining unfettered control of your site and locking you out.
So make sure that your WordPress password is secure, like a complex mix of letters, numbers and symbols
that wouldn't be easy to guess and don't use it for any other site.
On a related note, it's a good idea to use a password manager like Last Pass to generate and store
secure passwords for all of your accounts, not just WordPress.
All you have to remember is a single master password.
Last pass handles the rest and it's totally free.
I highly recommend it.
I also recommend you install a plug in called Log Organizer, one of the simplest methods the hackers
use to gain access to a site is a brute force attack, which is a trial and error tactic where a bot
basically tries random username and password combinations over and over and over until it finally gets
in.
This plug in will automatically lock a user out after a set number of unsuccessful login attempts protecting
you from brute force attacks.
There are a lot of plug ins out there for backups and security, but there's one in particular that
I strongly suggest you use, and that's vault press.
Now it is subscription based, so it'll cost you anywhere from five to thirty dollars a month depending
on the plan you choose.
But I'd say it's well worth it for what you get.
So what is Volp press?
It's a service that automatically backs up your data and monitors your site for malware and security
flaws.
If you ever need to restore backup, you can do it basically with a couple of clicks and volp presses
made by the same people who make WordPress so they really know their stuff.
Getting set up is as easy as signing up at Volp Press dot com and then installing the vault press plugin
on your site.
If you can't justify the cost of Volp press yet, there are free plugins out there such as word fence
for security and backup WordPress for backups.
As long as you've got something in place to prepare yourself, you're good.