A case study is a really effective type of content if you have a business and you're trying to promote
your products or services.
Now, I know I've repeatedly said that your primary goal should always be to provide free value.
Constantly touting your products is not the best way to build trust with your readers.
But there's a time and a place for everything.
And a case study is a rare opportunity where bragging about your business's offerings can actually provide
value to your audience.
So first of all, what is a case study?
A case study tells the story of how you've helped a particular customer solve a problem, often with
quotes or testimonials from the customer themselves.
Social proof is important in a case study is the ultimate form of social proof.
So how do you write an effective case study?
Well, first, you want to be sure to select the right candidate.
Whoever you profile in your case study should have extensive knowledge of your product, enthusiasm
about your business and impressive results to back up that enthusiasm.
So reach out to some of your top customers.
Let them know that they're special and important to you, and ask them to help tell their story, not
your story, their story.
It's important to make them the focus when you get somebody on board, move forward with an interview
process, talk to them about their experiences, ask open ended questions and learn more about their
problems and how your business has contributed to the solution.
A good case study should be structured as a story.
In this case, the customer you're profiling is the main character.
You're telling it from their point of view they faced some sort of conflict or problem.
They tried X, Y and Z, but those methods didn't work.
And eventually they overcame the odds and used your business to finally resolve the problem.
That's a case study in a nutshell.
Now, when you're talking about results, you'll want to be as specific as possible.
For example, if I was doing a case study on how I helped a client with their content marketing efforts,
I could say that they were able to triple their traffic or double their conversions.
But those phrases are kind of ambiguous, right?
I could have taken a company from 10 page views a month to 30, and that would technically count as
tripling their traffic.
Even though the end result was only 20 more page views.
It'd be much more effective if I said that I helped grow a client's traffic from, say, twenty thousand
page views to sixty thousand page views.
So use hard facts and concrete data as much as you can.
But of course, make sure you have the customer's permission to share anything that may be somewhat
private.
So those are some things to keep in mind when you're writing a case study.
Again, this is a rare opportunity to openly tout the benefits of your products, but make sure you
always do so within the context of a story.
This is a great way to provide value to your audience when they're in the stage where they're deciding
whether your business may be able to help them.
That social proof, that story of how you helped someone else can make all the difference.