In this section,
we'll briefly cover what an actuator endpoint is and then go into a bit
more detail about several of the built-in actuators,
as well as see them in action with some short demos.
Since we'll be doing a number of different demos with
actuator endpoints in this section,
now is a good time to introduce you to the demo.
The demo is located on my GitHub page at github.comdustinschultz /todo-
app.git and you've got two different choices here.
You can choose to fork and clone the repo or you can just clone it,
it's up to you.
You've already seen a sneak peak of the demo at the beginning of the course, but let's take a closer look at the app and what it does.