In this demo,
we're going to call and see the results of a number
of different actuator endpoints.
First, we need to add a bit of configuration in order for our demos to work.
We need to add configuration that exposes the endpoints
so that we can actually call them.
We'll talk more about enabling and exposing endpoints in the next section.
Navigate to the src, main,
resources folder and open up the application.properties file.
In the application.properties file,
add the management.endpoints .web .exposure .include
configuration and set this to a comma-separated list of all the
names of the endpoints that you want to expose.
For demo purposes, we'll set the value to an asterisk,
which is to expose all endpoints.
Typically,
it's not recommended to expose all of the endpoints
since it could pose a security risk, but in this case,
we're just demoing so it should be fine for now.
Now go ahead and start the application.
To do so, find the main application class,
right-click on it, and go to Run application.
Once the application is up and started, fire up a new browser window.
By default,
all of the actuator endpoints are located at /actuator
and then the id of the endpoint.
The /actuator part is, of course, configurable.
The first endpoint we'll call is the health endpoint.
In the address bar, type localhost:8080/actuator/health.
If everything went as planned,
you'll get back a very boring status UP response letting
you know that the application is healthy.
There's actually a lot behind this response though,
which we'll cover in the next sections.
Next, let's call the matrix endpoint.
In the browser bar, replace health with metrics.
You'll get back a response with all of the available metrics that
Spring Boot Actuator is collecting for you.
Now your response might look a bit different than mine since I have a
Chrome plugin that formats in pretty prints that output.
You can search the Chrome app store and install a similar
plugin in your browser for more readable output.
Each of these individual metrics in this names array can be queried further.
In the browser bar at the end of the URL add a slash
and then type jvm.memory .used.
You'll get back a more detailed response about that particular metric,
in this case, the amount of used jvm memory in the running application.
We'll cover the metrics endpoint in more detail in the following sections,
as well as the next module.
Next, we'll cover the logger endpoint.
Modify the path so that it shows /actuator/loggers.
This will return a list of all of the available and
configured loggers for your application.
You could also use this endpoint to change the log
level of a live running application.
We won't specifically cover that here,
but there is an excellent example on how to do this in the actuator API docs.
Lastly, we'll cover the config props endpoint.
In the browser bar, visit /actuator/configprops.
You'll get back a response of all the configured
properties and their respective values.
This is a super useful endpoint for inspecting the running configuration of an application.