In the last section of this module,
we'll learn how to create our very own entirely custom actuator endpoints.
In typical fashion,
Spring Boot makes it very easy to create your own custom endpoints.
Simply create and register a new bean annotated with the @Endpoint annotation.
Then utilize one of the @ReadOperation, @WriteOperation,
or @DeleteOperation annotations to annotate operational methods that expose,
record, or delete information.
Let's take a look at some example code.
Suppose you wanted to create your own actuator endpoint
that gave you information about the Docker container that
your application was running in.
As we just learned,
we'll need to create a new class registered as a bean with the
@Component annotation and then add the @Endpoint annotation to
designate that it's an actuator endpoint.
Then we need to create methods for gathering information and performing actions.
To gather information,
we create a new method and annotate it with the @ReadOperation annotation,
and in this method, we could gather things like the name of the Docker container,
its version, or maybe some statistics.
To perform actions,
we create a new method annotated with the @WriteOperation
annotation and then we could use this method for actually
performing some Docker related action, such as restarting the container or running a Docker command.