Let's implement our own custom actuator endpoint in our demo application.
In this last demo, we'll write our very own custom actuator endpoint.
Spring Boot Actuator comes with a built-in endpoint for checking
health as we've seen throughout the course,
but it doesn't provide a check for readiness.
So you're probably wondering what exactly is readiness and readiness
determines whether the application is able to receive traffic.
An application may be healthy, but not ready to receive traffic.
Let's write a custom actuator endpoint that determines readiness.
First, create a new package inside the main package called endpoint.
In the new package, create a new class called ReadinessEndpoint.
Annotate the class with the @Component annotation and the @Endpoint annotation.
Set the ID attribute of the @Endpoint annotation to readiness.
This ID will then be used in the path to access our endpoint.
Create a new string instance variable called ready and
initialize it to the String NOT_READY.
Next, add a new method called getReadiness that returns a string.
Annotate the method with the @ReadOperation annotation and return the instance
variable indicating whether or not the application is ready.
When we call the path /actuator/readiness,
this is the method that will get invoked.
Right now, our endpoint is always returning NOT_READY.
Let's create a new method called setReady that returns void.
This method will set whether or not the application is ready to serve traffic.
You can imagine that there could be some complex logic here to
determine whether or not the app is ready.
We'll just be doing a simple check for our demo.
Annotate the method with the @EventListener annotation and use
the ApplicationReadyEvent class as the value.
In the body of the method,
change the instance variable ready to the value of ready.
This method will execute and set the status to ready when Spring
sends the ApplicationReadyEvent after starting up.
We're almost ready to give our new actuator endpoint a try,
but don't forget that we need to expose the endpoint.
Navigate to the src, main, resources, and open up the application.properties.
On the property that controls which endpoints are exposed,
add a comma to the end of the value and type readiness.
We're now ready to start our application.
Navigate to the main application class, right-click, and go to Run.
Once the application is started,
fire up a browser and visit localhost:8080/actuator/readiness.
If everything went as planned,
you'll get back a ready response indicating that the application is ready to receive traffic.