We've reached the end of this module and the end of this course,
let's quickly recap what we learned.
We learned how to enable, disable, expose, and secure actuator endpoints.
We also learned that enabling an endpoint and exposing
an endpoint are two different things.
Enabling an endpoint controls whether it's created and exposing an
endpoint controls whether or not it can be consumed.
We also saw that we can easily secure our actuator endpoints by including the
Spring security library with some optional configuration.
Then we covered how to modify or customize some of the built-in endpoints.
We learned how to add our own custom health checks,
add custom data to the info endpoint, and lastly,
how to add our own custom metrics.
We finished out the module with a section on writing our
very own custom actuator endpoints using the @endpoint
annotation along with the @Read, @Write,
and @DeleteOperation annotations to control whether we
returned information or performed some action.
It's been a pleasure teaching you about Spring Boot Actuator,
and I hope you learned a lot and were able to take away some
useful information that you can either apply to your work
projects or your personal projects. Thank you, and good luck.