Just like the health endpoint, we briefly took a look at the metrics endpoint,
and also like the health endpoint, we really only scratch the surface.
So let's take a deeper look at the metrics endpoint.
Out of the box,
the metrics endpoint supports a large number of monitoring systems.
So it supports everything from Software as a Service
monitoring systems like New Relic and DataDog to self-managed
solutions like Prometheus and Grafana.
If you're wondering whether or not a particular monitoring
system is supported by the metrics endpoint,
be sure to check out the documentation.
The documentation contains a list of all the default supported
monitoring systems and how to configure them.
One of the nice things about the metrics endpoint is that it
supports both a push and a pull model.
A lot of the Software as a Service offerings like New
Relic and DataDog are push models.
You send your metrics to them, they process them,
they analyze them, and they graph them for you.
There is also the pull model like what Grafana uses where the
metrics are available in a certain format,
so in this case it would be a Prometheus format,
and Grafana continuously reaches out to the endpoint to fetch
the data and record and analyze and graph it.
The metrics endpoint also comes with a number of built-in metrics
that it automatically collects and gathers.
These are referred to as the core metrics and they include
things like JVM metrics and CPU metrics.
To get a list of all the available metrics that are exposed,
be sure to check out the documentation.
Lastly, it should come as no surprise that you can add your own custom metrics.
So maybe, for instance,
you have an in-memory cache and you want to see how many
times you had a cache hit or a cache miss,
you can easily expose these metrics at the metrics endpoint,
and not only does it support completely custom metrics,
you can also augment existing metrics.
A common example of this would be adding the AWS region to all of your metrics.
This would then allow you to individually analyze a particular metric within an individual region.