Hello, I'm Fernando Medina Corey,
and welcome to this module of my course on the serverless framework.
In this module,
we'll look at where a serverless is moving with
multi-platform serverless architectures.
We'll start this module with some context by looking IaaS Outages and Risks.
We'll look at cloud provider failures, including notable failures of Azure,
Google Cloud Platform, and AWS.
We'll review these failures and look at some key takeaways from all of them.
Then we'll move into looking directly at multi-platform architectures.
We'll overview what multi-platform architectures are,
and the components that they're comprised of.
Then we'll move into other forms of resilient architectures and provide
examples of how we can add fault tolerance to our applications.
After that,
we'll review a few of the basic best practices in this area before we
look at what we can do with our newfound skills.
So let's get started.
Using any technology has benefits and risks.
The same is true with infrastructure as a service providers.
While you gain a huge amount of benefit in terms of functionality,
you do give up some control to the internals of your systems.
And when a serious provider happens,
you end up only being able to report the problem and twiddle your thumbs.
So here are a few examples of some of the things that could
go wrong with infrastructure providers.
In November of 2014,
Microsoft Azure made a configuration change to improve
the performance of Azure storage.
Usually these kinds of changes are flighted and incrementally rolled out in
different areas to try to preemptively spot any issues.
Unfortunately in this case,
an engineer inadvertently skipped the flighting process and deployed a bug.
Before this could be fixed,
it caused connections to Azure Storage and VMs to fail and
took several hours to fully resolve.
In a more recent example, in April of 2016,
Google Cloud platform was making a configuration change
to traffic routing on its network.
This change caused an issue,
because it was made in only one configuration file and not another.
Because of this inconsistency,
the system was supposed to notice this error with the canary
test and fall back to the previous state.
But while the canary test noticed an unsaved configuration,
a bug in the management software ignored it and deployed the change anyway.
At this point, connections began to fail across Google compute instances,
which launched a series of internal alerts at Google.
These alerts were investigated and then fixed by the engineering team there.
And here's one final example,
just in case you think I'm showing favoritism to AWS.
On February 28, 2017,
an engineer in the AWS billing department tried to remove a
few servers related to work they were doing.
Unfortunately, the command used by the engineer had a typo,
which dramatically changed the outcome and removed many servers,
including servers used by Core AWS simple storage service subsystems.
This removal caused connections to S3 to fail,
which also cascaded down into errors for services
that relied on the AWS S3 service,
which was a substantial number of AWS services.
So why do I show you all these examples?
It's not to convince you that using infrastructure
providers is a bad idea; in fact,
the vast majority of companies that aren't massive
enterprises are probably better off outsourcing their cloud
needs to an infrastructure provider.
The main reason I show you this is to make sure
that you realize that bugs happen,
and you need to take appropriate precautions for your organization.
That might mean planning for cases like these and it might not.
Another important detail here is that the principle of
least privilege makes for safer systems.
In many of these examples,
reducing the ability of humans or programs to take certain
actions may have avoided this issue entirely.
And this is an important thing to bring to your own organizations.
In general, it's also important to have a plan for failures.
For some,
this might simply mean that you're ready to send a tweet
or email about your infrastructure provider having issues
and apologize to your users.
It also might mean that you need to plan a place to
mitigate issues like this entirely, and finally,
it's important to realize that even IaaS providers can fail.
It doesn't happen very often, but it does happen.
Next,
we'll take a look at how we can try and design systems within the serverless framework that avoid these issues when they do come up.