As I mentioned earlier,
community is a huge part of choosing which framework to use,
so let's take a look at some GitHub metrics that serve as
proxies for the quality and size of the development
communities around these frameworks.
We'll be looking at watchers, stars, and forks.
Each of these metrics should indicate relatively how many fellow
developers are interested in the project as of July 2017.
Now some serverless frameworks are supported by smaller groups of developers,
or specific companies.
Or even if they have larger communities,
they may only support a single language,
and can potentially not be the one you're interested in using.
If GitHub can tell us anything,
it's that the serverless framework easily has the largest
development community out of any serverless framework.
It's not a surprise, either,
as the company behind the framework is dedicated to the growth
and maintenance of the framework itself,
rather than the framework being an offshoot of some
other development practice or project.
But don't take my word for it.
In June 2017,
the technology analyst firm Red Monk evaluated several
serverless projects on GitHub over time,
and found that the growth and stars for the serverless
framework vastly outpaced all of the projects that it was
evaluating within the category.
This interest comes not only from smaller startup companies,
like CrazyLister and Ibotta, but it also comes from highly established companies,
like Coca-Cola, Expedia, and Nordstrom.
Now that we understand how popular the serverless framework has become,
let's take a quick look at some of the key features of the framework.
One of the key tooling features that the serverless framework
provides is a highly structured development process,
which we'll look at more shortly.
This process makes it easier to develop new services,
and for developers to quickly gain familiarity with the project.
As part of the structure development process,
the framework also manages all the infrastructure
required for deploying a project.
Because it manages this process,
it starts to significantly reduce the complexity of infrastructure providers.
Rather than having to learn the nuances of multiple APIs,
you can learn the serverless framework commands and that should automate the
deployment process across multiple infrastructure providers.
Further, the framework is somewhat infrastructure independent.
The code structure and deployment process doesn't change very much at
all when switching between infrastructure providers.
While you may have to switch certain libraries, the structure remains the same.
Speaking of infrastructure providers, in addition to using it with AWS,
the serverless framework also has support from Microsoft Azure,
IBM's Open Whisk, and Google Cloud Platform.
Across these infrastructure platforms,
the framework has support for a variety of languages,
including Node.
js, Java, C#, PHP, and Python.
Now I don't want to convince you that this is a
one-size-fits-all kind of solution.
There are potential drawbacks when it comes to using serverless technologies,
and frameworks in particular.
Some of the most common criticisms of the framework is that it obscures
the backend infrastructure behind each of your services.
Now this could technically be both a benefit or a drawback,
depending on whether or not the obscurity increases productivity,
or leads to the potential misunderstandings of the underlying technologies.
I'd say it's important to still have an understanding of the
infrastructure underneath the framework's automation processes,
and keep that in mind when building applications.
The framework is also somewhat permission hungry.
In development environments that are highly locked down,
it can be difficult to use the framework to manage your development processes,
because of the broad permissions required to create and destroy infrastructure.
There are also potential challenges for maintaining
compliance with things like HIPPA.
Because serverless services are by definition somewhat
distributed between many managed services,
it's important to see which ones qualify for compliance and which ones do not.
The development process is also very opinionated.
There's a specific way to write and structure your code,
and similarly, there's a specific way to deploy it.
This again can be a benefit or a drawback, depending on your use case.
So with this basic context out of the way,
let's take a look at the projects and skills that we'll be developing throughout the course.