Now if you take a look at how we structured our function code,
you'll notice that all of it is within the pets directory,
and this is reflective of our serverless.
yml file.
All of the configuration for the handlers had the
pets/ at the beginning of them.
This is because they're all in the pets directory.
Now this is purely by convention.
You could also have each of these functions one level up
and not use the pets directory at all.
Alternatively,
you could spread them out into smaller and smaller directories and continue
to add slashes to direct the path within the serverless.
yml file.
Really,
it's just up to you to define the best way to actually structure
your code for whatever example you're using.
Now let's open up the pets directory and look at each of our function files.
Now each of our functions has some similarities.
In each of them,
we bring in the required dependencies that we'll be
using throughout the function.
In the create function, we used the uuid dependency,
which we'll be using to create consistently unique IDs for each
of the items that we'll be adding to DynamoDB.
In all of our functions, we also bring in the aws-sdk,
which will allow us to interact with DynamoDB.
We also always bring in the DynamoDB document client,
which when we're working with JavaScript allows us to
more easily interact with DynamoDB.
In this case, whenever a create function is run,
it saves the timestamp information of the first run.
It also parses the JSON event.
body and stores it as data.
Then it checks to make sure that there's a petName and a petBreed,
both of type string, in order to continue going through the function.
When that results in a success,
we can scroll down slightly and see that we'll be creating a params object,
which we'll be using later in the function.
That params objects models what's expected to pass into
DynamoDB in order to create an entry in a table.
First it passes in the DYNAMODB_TABLE name environment variable that
we're getting from the configuration in serverless.
yml, and it creates a new ID from UUID using the v1 method,
and also adds in a petName and a petBreed,
as well as the createdAt timestamp.
Once it creates those params,
it passes them through the DynamoDB put method in order
to save that information in DynamoDB.
Then, if successful, it passes back a successful response using the callback.
The delete function essentially uses a bunch of the same information.
It uses the same dependencies, also uses the process environment variable,
the DynamoDB table name,
and then takes the id value that's passed in through the event.
It uses all of this to create a parameters object,
which it then passes to the DynamoDB delete method,
and then returns the response code depending on success or failure.
The get function also does something fairly similar.
It creates the same parameters object and then passes that into the dynamoDb.
get method.
Afterward, it processes that result and returns it with a response.
The list function does something very similar.
It passes in the DynamoDB TableName and then scans the entire table.
The results of the entire scan are then passed back in the response.
This includes all the items that are within the DynamoDB table,
which means that as this table grows,
this operation will become more expensive and contain a lot of additional data.
And finally, update.
js does something similar to what we were seeing in create.
js.
It creates a timestamp and loads the data in from the event.
It then validates to make sure that we have the petName and
petBreed correctly recorded as strings.
And then it creates a params object and again uses the DynamoDB
table name and some information of the event to specify the key
that we see within the DynamoDB table.
The only unique thing that this function does is that it uses some
DynamoDB specific syntax in order to reference the petName,
petBreed, and other values within the table.
This essentially allows us to specify what values
within the table will be updated,
and makes sure to override all of these new values.
Finally,
it passes in that constructed parameters object to
the DynamoDB update operation,
and then returns the result as we expected with a success or failure using the callback.