All right welcome back.
I'm a student so after some time of being very busy I took some time because I wanted to show you guys
how to create dynamic active links.
Right now we have done other namak navigation right here because we have our categories but they're
not being really selective.
Here when we click on it right they're not taking the active class.
And right now we can actually show you how that looks if we right click on this right and we go inspect
element and we come here and we right click again.
It as HD mail and we put a little classier call active.
And this comes from Bootstrap right here like this and you click away from it and you can see that data
get selected right.
So all we got to do is add that active class to each of this links here.
The problem is that we already have navigation and dynamic navigation here and we have study links here.
So we need to figure out a way to do this.
I'm going to show you how to do this right now in the code.
So go to your navigation that BHB page.
All right that's in the front page.
And this is where we're going to be doing this so I'm going to go.
Actually we are already here.
And I think I drank my coffee this morning.
But anyway let me show you how we can do this.
First of all let's create a category on the score a class variable and this is what we're going to be
keeping.
We're going to put this empty here because right now later on we're going to be putting the active key
in here like this.
Depending on where we are on that page.
All right.
And then we can use this category to put it in psi here like this.
Right.
And then we can put that very well there but let me just show you we're getting ahead of ourselves here.
All right so we got the empty variable there.
Let's create another entry variable for the region for the static links like this.
And there are a couple ways of doing this and some of you are already probably doing them in a different
way.
But this is the way I'm going to show you how to do it.
All right.
Then you can come up with your own way on your own time.
So we got these registration we just going to call the registration class like this.
All right.
Now I'm going to show you a little trick here.
This is how we can find out the name of the column page that we are on.
We're going to use this function basename just to clear things up for us a little bit.
All right.
You can look it up and it should be on their website.
We're going to use the server variables.
It's magic Konst and here we're going to say self.
You see this value right here.
Right.
This value would be our
category that BHB.
All right page so that would be the page that we we are on.
Right.
So if we are on in that it would be indexed that BHB.
All right so that's what that is.
So let's assign this to a variable called Page name like this.
All right so now we get the page name here.
And all we have to do is create an if statement.
And check this out.
All right.
So we can say something like this.
First of all let's check to see because we have some dynamic menu right categories.
So let's first check for the get.
All right so let's check to see if we have a get called category.
All right.
So that way we don't get no errors.
And then we want to do is we want to say and I want you to compare this.
All right well what the category Heidi.
All right.
Now keep in mind that there are ways of doing this with javascript Buswell is a little more complicated
than this but I just want you to keep that in mind right.
All right.
So now that we had this condition here.
All right all we got to do is set this category variable right here too active.
All right.
Remember we started this in empty because we wanted something to be there and so you in a minute.
Why.
Because if this is if the page is not selected.
All right.
We don't want anything to be there.
We do want to get any errors there.
So anyway so that would make that work for then we can also do another statement here for our page name
for the static links so we can say if Bache name is equal and you know what we don't even have a page
name here.
All right so let's.
Actually we don't have the registration and we need to make the registration page here like this registration.
We don't have the name on that page.
So we need to do that so we can compare it so we can say if the page name is equal to the registration
then we can say that the category you see this
we need to right here this one we need to set this to active
active.
There we go.
All right.
And now here what I'm going to do because this is going to be the category one we can put the category
clause in there.
All right.
That would do that for that.
And then the registration class we can put it for this static many right here and we can say BHP call
category class which is not selected.
If it's not active right it will be empty.
All right.
Again there are other ways of doing it and you are welcome to do it your way just the way I'm teaching
you so that way you can grab some more ideas if you like.
So let me just show you now why this is right now.
So enter we are in category so we go to registration.
You can see that is already select and this is the static link BHP is already selected if we go inside
or admin and we create another category for example bootstrap category or.
We go to the we click here you can see that it's already selected this is selected select.
Even the restrainer and static page is selected.
All right.
Now keep in mind that every time you make a static link.
You need to create the variable there and then you need to place it.
You've placed a class on that static link as well.
All right.
So that's how you create a static dynamic active navigation link class whatever you want to call it.
Right.
But anyways a pleasure guys.
And I hope you enjoy it and enjoyed it and see you in the next lectures.
Take care.