Oh right perfect we have done a lot of things in this year so far but we still have a lot more to go.
All right.
So don't get frustrated or don't get.
You know get excited get very excited because you're learning a lot.
All right so we're going to keep going don't give up.
And so we started from the top post.
Got to go comments.
The next thing is users.
Before we do anything in the user space because we don't have any right now if I click on it you'll
see that we have we have a pound sign right.
So let's go ahead and go to localhost.
All right localhost
right.
And then we're going to go to the actually local hoes be H-P we need to go to BHB my admin.
So get there and let's fill up page well not page that table we can build a page yet because we need
a table right.
So let's go see a mass.
And I'm just going to say new table here and I actually should have just click on see a mess and they
I can pull many columns I won here.
Well let's call these table users and let's give it.
Geez that's given nine places because we are going to be adding a lot of things for the users.
So the first thing that we need to add is a user ID.
We know how to do that into your list to set it to three characters in that primary and auto increment
Nanse is username.
OK.
Password.
First name first name right.
Almost forgot to spell that for a minute there.
At this hour we should say just roll I guess.
And later on we're going to I'm just going to do it right now.
Rant solt laid on probably when we add new features we might use uses role here to do the same password
encryption but not right now.
All right.
That's extra.
So we want to actually have this last.
It's not that important.
Right.
And this is not that important.
Well it is.
But last name e-mail and what else.
User image.
Right.
And we should just say user everything right.
Use your last name.
Why not.
Is easier.
Now we know user password that when we know the evidence it just says user and username.
All right.
And we should just leave this one like this.
OK.
I think it is very descriptive.
The only thing that doesn't have anything in front of it is just this one here.
It doesn't have the underscore but everything else it does.
Right.
And user user role.
All right so here is going to be of our car.
It's going to be tets remember that 2:55.
You don't have to put two find one of them.
They're not going to be 255 characters.
But I like to do that and I'm just going to touch on that one.
Our car a roll to 55.
And this one of our cars to 55 right now only one integer only integers this one right here.
Perfect.
So let's go ahead and click safe and we are done.
All right so now let's go ahead and show some data right away since we are here right.
User name is going to call this guy Rico password.
One two three.
First name.
What can we call this guy.
Rico first name right there.
Last name Swaby.
And then e-mail Ricos Soie the G.M. that come.
Hope you like the last name and some image we don't have any image right now roll would be Stryver
or admin make maker admin because you know it's just admin right now and then here we're not to worry
about that right now.
And they just click go.
Let me just make sure everything is perfect.
Well not perfect but good to go.
All right.
So we have added that users stable and we have added inserting some content into it.
So the next video we're going to continue on.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching and see your next lecture