Welcome back my student in this lecture here we are going to be adding a registration page and I want
you to download something to your right.
You're going to find a filed called registration.
Let me see if I can find it right here on my desktop right here.
So go to that to the side of your screen if you're in a desktop and download this file right here.
It's going be called the registration that BHB that zipped right.
Unzip it and you're going to have this restriction that BHB there right.
So what I want you to do I want you to go to your CMS folder.
Mine is right here and I want you to drop it in there and we're going to be dropping it right here in
the root directory like this done right.
So now when we go to our specific site localhost see a.
And then if we type in the page name restriction up we we don't get anything in there.
That's because I misspelled it.
There we go.
And now you get it you have something like this right.
This is I mean all this mark up here for you.
And we're going to be building the functionalities.
All right so if we go back to our open brackets ok and go inside brackets go to your CIMS directory.
And here's some where you can find your registration right here.
And we just double click it so I can have it up here in my working files.
And this is the page right here.
All right.
As you can see the images make these sort of smaller looks better when you have it in the high resolution
right.
So this is all the markup that I made here for you.
And that way you wouldn't have to spend 20 minutes doing this and then on the next video we're going
to start building the functionality of this page.
I want to also encrypt whatever information we want to clean information we might as well escape string.
Right.
With my Eskew ally real scale string.
So we wanted to clean the information before going to the database.
The second thing we want to do is encrypt the password that is going inside the database.
That way you can make this hacker proof.
All right.
So all of this information will be going to the database and then it's going to go to the our administration
area where we can allow this user insight or not allow them in psi where we can register them as a regular
user or maybe as an admin user we can do whatever we want as long as we have that information.
So the next lectures are going to be pretty awesome.
Is going to this is something very useful just in case you have a live web site on that on the on line
and you want to allow users to read you serve for your web site.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I see it.
And that's one