High by now you should have the fundamentals of Ph.D. You should know how to use loops arrays variables
functions and many other things.
Now we need to get into serious business.
BHP was meant to be used for the web.
For that reason we need to be able to collect information from users to do different things with it.
Now HP has a couple ways of doing that.
We have forums that users can come and go to a form with their name or subject line or message submit
the form and then we use BHP to process that right.
So that's one way of getting information we're going to learn about that in the following lectures.
There's another way called the euro or links Well they're not called you are links but we can get information
via you are able or right in your browser.
So for example if they use clicks on the link we send some information via that you are able to the
server.
And then we process that information.
Well I'm going to show you how to use that in a minute.
We are also we also getting information via cookies.
You have cookies in your browsers and those cookies get transfer into the server.
And then we can do all the things with it.
When you get the server right.
So we can we can use that information that you guess you sent from your browser to the server to Apache
and we can do all the things with it right.
So I'm going to show you about about cookies in later lectures also.
Another way of getting information from users or using sex sessions and sessions work very close with
cookies as a matter of fact they work with cookies right then as a separate entity from cookies.
They work with cookies without cookies we can have sessions sessions or allow us to have a larger amount
of data than cookies cookies only limited to certain a couple of thousand characters.
SESSIONS only limited to the hard drive that you have on your server so we can get more data in sessions
and use it relating to users.
But anyway this section is going to be awesome.
You I love it.
We've got to get into very serious business here so pay very close attention.
And again congratulation for making it this far.
You're awesome.
Take care.