Welcome ideas students in this new section.
I'm going to show you how to translate your Web site how to translate your applications.
Okay now I'm going to show you a very simple feature is not gonna be something out of this world which
is complicated is gonna be something very simple like I usually do with you guys.
OK so right now we are in a English translation.
OK.
And right now we've got a little select button here.
And if I go ahead and select my second language here or Spanish you can see that that changes to Spanish.
OK.
You can.
You can look it up if you want.
That's or it's Spanish stuff.
OK.
So this this will be the username your e-mail and your password birth in Spanish would be number of
these Swati to quote ale too clubby.
He's right.
If I look it up now in English you can see that that changes to English.
It's going to be very simple and I'm going to help you a lot in your application so if you're ready
let's do it right now.
Guys.