Welcome back.
My amazing students.
So on this section here I want to show you some really cool stuff with BHP.
Some of the things that you can do.
So I found this package a couple years ago called pusher pusher we allow us to send real notifications
I real time notifications in our app to users.
Now I want to show you how to use it.
They got a way to get a free account so you can use a play around with it.
OK.
That's exactly what we're doing.
So if you go to push it out come.
OK.
This is their website here.
And you can read more about it.
OK.
But what I want you to do is sign up get a free account and then when you sign up.
Plus this video now OK.
And then we'll be back.
When you get this stuff setup.
All right.
So hopefully you finish that and you are set up with pusher you got your free account.
I must show you the dashboard.
This is the dashboard right here.
So the first thing that you need to do is create an app.
Simple as that.
So we're gonna say the new see a mess and I'm just gonna put the Newseum as you can see a mess if you
don't have any apps of course.
And just gonna put any cluster here it's like a server if you put your mouse over it would tell you
what is the physical location of the server that can handle the request from your channel's app.
So you want to put something close to your area.
OK.
And front end is going to be vanilla javascript and we're gonna use BHP of course create my app.
Now here are the credentials for your apps the things that you have to go through that you have to be
aware of is your app keys.
OK well let me show you how to use a real quick.
I'm going to copy this.
This is the javascript OK so here's how it works.
We download a package for BHP as deep as the gate package a software development kit.
We write some code OK.
We trigger some type of event.
And on the other side we the email or whatever you're using or BHP but usually javascript.
OK on the client side we catch it with JavaScript and display some type of message coming from the server.
So they go to this page here and BHP and on the other side we can catch that event anywhere we want
in our application.
OK.
Let me show you how to use it real quick.
So I copy these javascript code right here and as a matter of fact let's copy let's do the BHP first
so let's download this package first.
So I got an empty project right here you can add it so you'll see a mess probably if you like but I
have a completely empty problem all I have is a directory I've got a star composer and then initialize
it because that's what we're going to need in order for us to do this.
So I'm gonna press Enter Enter Enter enter into I see these red lines asking me for a name OK.
And then I'm going to put my email for my in this way with my name OK and then enter and enter into
enter enter and to enter it.
There we go.
Clear.
OK.
Now if you have a terminal I'm guessing you're using gay bash or maybe a trial BHP storm whatever other
idea.
Just keep in mind that what you need to do is use your terminal.
Right.
Of course we create a section about this before and I tell you to download get bash.
OK.
So make sure you have some type of terminal you can use.
So we're gonna to download the package.
It's called composer.
Well this is the name pusher pusher.
That's BHP server for those of you that are a little lost.
We already went through using composer.
OK in the course.
So this shouldn't be something new for you.
It if it is you need to go back and look for some type of BHP mailer or composer or some type of section
that says that in the course you can use if you don't know what I'm saying.
You can use get here download get this here and download this and use the bash shell from that is very
similar to what we are using anyway.
So once I have this let's download it real quick.
All right we have it.
Now I'm going to create a page here to to trigger this event.
I'm going to make sure it is an index page or it doesn't really matter what page it is.
This is the page where we are going to be triggering the event triggering the dysfunctionality so when
they visit then that's the functionality is going to be triggered.
OK.
So I got a copy my PSP and then I'm pasting here.
Let me explain it to you a little bit so that way you guys are we are on the same track.
This is requiring auto load of course the packet that was just that package that we downloaded is right
here.
We are requiring it.
OK.
We are creating some variables that this information is coming from the push of documentation.
We instantiating pusher instance we are passing in the first parameter these the Odki.
The second parameter is the secret.
And the third parameter is the AB I.D..
This here this information that you're seeing right here is my own information pusher is populating
this information from my app keys area here so these are my real credentials.
OK.
That's why he's going to work.
So we instantiating our object with all this and we passing in these options.
Ray right here with the cluster and some other functionality right there.
Now we are creating some data whatever data that is if use maybe it's something coming from the database
or whatever that data it's right here with passing in that data OK.
Right here I set our parameters.
So the first with the method trigger is the channel.
The second is event and you can name this whatever you want doesn't have to be these and you pass the
data you want.
OK.
So we are set up with that let's create the next page.
I'm going to call this next page.
I don't know.
Students Students that BHP or student OK let's go back here and let's copy the JavaScript So let's just
paste that in there.
And as you can see what we're doing up here is using a C the N or something from push that come.
That's the library.
The javascript site and this is just for development.
OK.
So we instantiating pusher again.
But on the javascript side with the I think this is the secret of the app by the OK.
Let me see what that is.
I haven't even looked yet.
This is 7 c this is the key.
OK so instantiating push it with the key.
The cluster.
OK.
That is our push for instance right here.
Then with that instance we can subscribe to our channel we have to be the same name channel that we
got here.
OK.
And then we have binding that channel to that event.
That's right here and of course we're passing that data that date is coming back with this function
right here.
Data is coming back and we just displaying some type of alert industry.
OK.
So that's there.
That should work on your pricing now.
Let's see right.
Let's go to my where I have this project push it right here.
OK now I'm going to go to the about page and let's see if we get something let's cross our fingers and
make sure that this works right.
Well hopeful hope
ok it doesn't work.
Let's refresh here.
Come back here.
Let's go it up.
All right all right.
We got to check it out.
Let's see what's going on here.
I'm gonna inspect source what not source might be in the wrong page.
Who knows sometimes that happens he says.
Request now found on this server.
So these are about that BHP is now being found or was we didn't call it about the I know it was something
going on with me.
It's student OK.
That's not even found either.
OK.
Try publishing an event to channel let me see.
OK let's refresh and I.
OK.
All right.
Now he works a gay I'm sorry about that.
I thought we wrote about beach.
But you see what I'm saying.
You look at the data right here.
Okay so that's cool.
Right now you're not going to get any more notifications because it's not continuously right.
You have to first trigger here but watch what happens here in the browser tab when I do this.
Trigger it and you see the little dot right here.
That means there is something waiting for us there.
And of course you can change this.
You can go back to your index here and you can say look I'm just gonna name this channel one for example
event one and I change this to student's
we go.
OK.
Now of course if I go to that page and I trigger it right here yeah and then I go back to the student.
There is nothing going on here because we have to bind to that.
Right.
So we have to get that to work.
So we have to grit this into our channel 1 might bind to our event one.
OK.
I saw that.
And now if I go here and trigger it let's see what all the
went to fast channel one event one.
OK.
Make sure that you read the right thing.
Sometimes when I'm going so fast I can't see it.
OK.
There we go.
It works OK.
So sometimes you have to come here and refresh it and then you have to go back and refresh or a couple
of times just in case.
OK.
There you go.
Say
that's pretty cool
and we know all right.
So I guess we're done with this.
Maybe I'll make another lecture just to show you how to implement this in see a mass and maybe show
you how to implement it in a cool way in a nicer way.
But if I don't make it don't be mad OK.
I'm just trying to show you some cool things here.
OK.
This extra lecture stuff.
Thank you so much.
And I'll see you on the next one.
Don't forget to rate my cause guys.
OK.
Make sure you give me those ratings because I really get motivated when I see those ratings out there.
So remember.
Thank you so much I'll see you in the next one.