All right so what is a variable.
A variable is like a container.
Variables are a container placeholder whatever you want to call it elements that we can use to store
data and then use that data by the variable name.
So we can refer to that data by using the variables name.
So let's say for example I make a variable called names inside that variable we put the name.
Let's say for example Edwyn and then we can use a name without variable names to refer to that specific
name.
Let me show you exactly what a variable is very was a very powerful and they're very very useful.
We are using all kinds of programming languages and that is something that you need to actually use.
So let me show you an example how we create variables in how we use them.
So let's say for example I'm I used a blank that BHP and now don't get confused by all the files you
see here is you have that in your exercise files.
All right so I'm going to use this blank that ph piano to do a Save As and this document and I'm going
to call these variables.
Sometimes I have more files than Then you depending on where you are on the lesson.
But all these files should be in your course.
That's the size files.
Right.
So I'm going to go ahead and open
a peach.
Peter I am going to close it right away.
So I want to show you exactly how we define variables.
Variables are defined in a very easy format.
We use a dollar sign with HP.
Any changes in programming languages in some programming languages we use a word var.
But in this one we're going to be using a dollar sign following the name of the variable.
And I just want to name it this.
I can name it whatever I want.
I can even name and number if I want to.
All right.
So I'm going to name it name and then that's it.
The variable is done.
Now keep in mind that is very empty.
You're not even using this variable right now.
Most of the time where you are going to see is that you're going to see the variable and you're going
to see the variable declare here and assign a value right away.
That's what this is the way you want to see the variable.
It's not you're never going to find it like this because variables we make it for reason we make them
to use and to store data.
So we use something called an assignment operator right here.
So I assigned the variable name or assign it a value right whatever.
So we want to just assign it right now when we use for strings we know we know we use double quotes
or apostrophes where we can use single quotes to pull strings in there.
All right this is how we write strings or têtes in programming language.
Most of the time we need to put quotes around that this is not in ph B but in many different programming
languages if we want to store numbers in there actually them you just put it in about and make let's
make another variable called number and we can go ahead and numbers don't have courts.
This is how BHB knows is a number.
We don't put quotes around it.
All right so now how can we use these variables how can we use them.
Well let's use a function called Eckel and let's echo this out.
Let's open the browser by clicking on this little like right here and we can see right now that we are
displaying that name.
Edwin de-value Edwin by using the variable name.
So now we can refer to this data right here by using the variable name and we can do the same thing
with this one.
All right so now how why are the typical use and how we usually write variables.
Well this is the normal syntax right since that's I mean the way you write it you can write variables
like this.
Capital if you want.
You can put the first capital you can put on the score then you can use name like this however you want.
You can name it you can name however you think it's good for you.
Now the best for best practice is the best way to write is all lowercase.
And then if you have a second word you uppercase the first letter and then you finished writing all
lowercase.
This is the first the best format to write variables.
Another format that I use is this one on the score list and then sometimes I overcame this one here.
All right you will see it like this.
OK.
We see it very often like this.
There are many different ways.
Don't do this.
These are bad form as a matter of fact I'm going to write them down.
This is OK.
I going to write that all right and this is not OK.
What I'm about to do right now this one here.
Don't write your variables like this.
The reason is because again it can be.
It can get confused by thinking that you are so strapped in something from something.
So this is a format you cannot store a variable with a number like this it will not work.
No you see we get an error right here.
When I wrote that OK we got an error right here also.
And now we're good.
You see this is bad for man just going to comment it out.
We can also keep in mind that when you write a variable keep in mind that is variable.
And then to write it right here
this verbal and this very well are different even though they are named the same.
The reason is because it's case sensitive.
So any word any letter that you change here will make this variable different from this one.
All right so even if you have something like this and you just have this one lower case this is a totally
different variable than this right here.
All right.
I mean you can play around with it and find out for yourself there.
All right there are many different ways we can declare variables but make sure they don't have a number
of them make sure they don't have hyphen in between.
Right.
And always make sure that you write the same variable again if you want to use and make sure that you
write it exactly the same.
If if you are referring to the same variable.
Ok so now we can store many different data data types in here and what our data size.
Well we have many different data types in programming.
This is a string data type.
That's right.
We have numbers.
This is an integer and we could also have a floating point number.
That's what it's called because he has a decimal place right here.
Now this type of numbers in ph B are take more memory right because we have a decimal point so we need
to do.
It will be more processing for this type of numbers.
Keep in mind that was if you enclose these numbers in quotes apostrophe's you change the data type to
a string to what têtes.
All right.
So now ph is going to treat this as a string not a number.
So even though BHB will kind of sometimes represent this as a number it with It would think that it
is a string.
Even though you can still add this number distrain with another string mph we would still do it.
But in most cases it would not do it.
So you can not make calculations like you can make with the data number type.
Right.
Because this is a strange BHB is not going to allow that.
In some cases it will in some cases they were not.
So better get used to it when you write in numbers.
Never put quotes around it.
OK I noted that I wanted to talk to you about concatenation.
I'm going to take this moment here to talk to you about that.
The reason because I don't need to make another video is to tell you that you can put data together
in BHB we'd have a dot which is called concatenation.
And for example this variable here it has this value.
I want to put this value Edwyn right which is this value.
I want to put it together with a number 100 so I'm going to copy this variable right here.
I put a dot right here and you're going to copy there as you can see here.
You already printed out your for me because that is a value right here for this variable.
OK.
Now even if it's all together we can put a little separation there by concatenating a string and an
empty string as you can see moved up it moved a little bit to the right.
So as you can see this concatenation will smash worst together.
It will put worse.
It would not only put words but any data type that you you know you can.
You want to put together use a dot.
Make sure that you have a dot between this element and the other element right here.
Right.
Right now we have a string in between here so we need another concatenation there to concatenate the
string with a variable.
Ok of course you can.
This is how you put things together.
All right.
Just letting you know not nothing that you can do also and I'll probably show you X amount if I always
show you another video here.
I think we are we are good with time here.
So this is it.
This is it.
That said I as a matter of fact let me show you a couple more things actually.
Let me take one minute to do.
All right so we know that we with this function we can we can also use I mean just write another variable
here.
We can pool all kinds of data I told you about and we can put the mail in there so we can write something
like this.
Hello.
The next e-mail H-1 talian there enclosed right here.
All right.
And this is going to do two things.
I'm going to show you what they're going to do right now.
Look at this.
So we were able to use a HDMI LTI inside a string and put it aside into this variable right here and
we were able to display below.
So we can assign a simple tax to variables.
Keep that in mind.
We can assign images to variables we can assign the many different types of data into a variable but
always makes Always keep in mind that we can only find one value at a time.
We cannot go ahead and put our coal mine here and put another coalman assign different values like we
can assign.
You know we can assign different values and I will let you know how that works later on when we talk
about race.
All right.
So just keep in mind that you can only assign one value with the variables later on we're going to be
talking about another different type of variable that we can assign multiple values to it.
All right so keep that in mind.
Anyway I hope you were able to get some valuable knowledge out of this lesson and I'll see you in the
next lecture.
Take.