All right so we got the edit pose page.
This place on data right.
So we go to the polls.
We can see that if we click on the Edit we are able to go to the edit on the scoreboard that BHP insists
on data.
Now we're going to be relating this category later on we're going to be put into the category title
there that this post belongs to later on.
Right right now this is static and we're going to we're going to fix it.
All right.
It's going to be a number on your site and but later on we're going to put a title there right.
But that's and that's a recall that we will be doing.
But anyway so we are here and what we need to do now is now that we have all these data here we need
this button here when we click it we need to send that data from the form to our database to update
these fields to whatever we want.
Right so if we want to say this and click Update we want to be able to.
We want to be able to have the data sent to our table.
All right.
So let's go to our ad men for Slash includes for Slash at it squirt balls that BHB page or edit on this
court BHB page.
We're just going to say edit polls.
Right.
It's a lot easier now the first thing that I want to do in here is is that I want to make sure that
when I click on this button from the view of polls I want to make sure that I go to this specific post.
Right.
37 in my case.
In your case might be a different number.
Don't worry about that.
It happens and it doesn't it doesn't mean there is bad it just means that you have a different post.
All right so where we're going to select from polls where what post ID he calls this board ID that we're
getting in there you are all right in the GET requests right so now that we have that now we are good
to go.
Now the next thing is we want to detect this form when it's submitted.
So we need to check for this button right here for the key of day on the score post.
So we're going to say if it's set right
and this is going to be a post
if it's set then we're going to do something right.
You want to make sure they work Celestials or something right
echo high to see if it works refresh.
Whoops We misspelled his function.
Here we go and let's just click it and we can see that he says hi right there.
So it is working.
All right.
So what we want to do is we want to grab all the fields in this name actually you right here.
We want to grabbing that pull super global and copyright here.
We've done that before and I'm just going to copy something that I got in the site and paste it right
here and you can just do the same.
Well you can just copy whatever I have here but just know that all I'm doing is grabbing all the form
values from down here in the name of you right here and these values and I am grabbing in this post
pro-global because that's how we grab it from the form and we are assigning it to a variable.
That's all I'm doing.
All right.
So you're welcome to post his video and copy each of these down for I am also grabbing the images in
this super global files.
All right.
Perfect.
Next thing is the move all bloater function we already saw how to do that.
I'm just going to paste it right here.
And all I'm doing right here.
Like I explained before is moving the image from the temporary location to a permanent location.
Now using this path right here with the image name right here.
Right.
All right.
So the next thing is to submit this right.
Once this is done we need to go ahead actually.
As a matter of fact once this the post is done all right we need to.
Well actually there's another update post.
This is just right here is this.
This name is confusing me a little bit but are just going to leave it like this just for demonstration
purposes only but in another case I would probably name it's made or something like that.
I just don't want every foreign to be named met on the same page.
Well we only have one forum here so it really doesn't matter if we change it to submit.
I'm just going to leave it like this.
All right.
But anyways.
All right so now that we have all this information well we need to construct is there update query.
And for that I already copy this down and I will show it to you right here as you can see.
And now what I'm doing here basically is concatenating all Diskworld because it's super long.
So as you can see here I'm using the same variable over and over again concatenating it with a dot in
the equal symbol.
So basically this square.
All right.
It's one long string and just dividing it just to make it easier for me just like this.
It would be something like.
Right.
And they would have a long line like this with a lot of values and I don't want that.
So I'm just cutting it off concatenating it making it look a little nicer that way if I have a mistake
I can come to one single line and correct it instead of looking through all this one line here.
Right.
So it's better for the bug too.
So I'm saying update pose and then I'm updating it once I say that but I'm going to set the post-Idol
which is the column in the table equal to the post title in my form.
All right.
Remember this is coming from here.
This feels right this value right here is in the variable pulls tighter right now and it pulls categories
also on that.
On this on this value right here.
Now let's go ahead and check that out real quick.
That post category ID is go down to the categories right here.
All right.
And if for some reason you have this select from category where category equals cat ID or something
like that just delete it right and just leave it like this.
Select from categories just if some reason I think I did on the last video when we fixed it.
Right just make sure that you have what I have right now.
Also make sure that you select right here has post on the score category.
Right.
Very important.
So make sure you have that because this is that this is a value that would be submitted.
Every time I select one of these.
So if I select this right that's going to have a value and is going to have this is going to carry that
value right.
He's got to do it right here.
So we're going to explain the name right here but we are carrying that category ID on that option value.
All right.
And the auction value is going to be carried by this guy right here.
So make sure you have that right now.
When we get this on the form right here is going to be pulls on the score category and we're going to
actually rename it to post on the score category I.D. We're now renaming it we are assigning a variable
that is a little different from this.
All right on the score category ID and then we are using that variable right here with the column name
which is the same name.
All right.
So here we are using a function for the date.
This is just going to give us the date for today.
All right.
We don't need cords or anything like that in here.
Just not as I always have cords around my strings the old strings and I always have a space after the
coma.
Make sure you always have a space after the coma and that last one.
Well the one before the last.
All right.
I don't have a coma there.
So make sure you don't have a coma there either.
Right because if you put a coma there you are.
This is not going to work that where statement.
So the hole where we failed so take the coma out.
Now if you want to make sure that this worked.
All right.
First we're going to send the Querrey So we're going to use a variable.
We're going to use the function might rely on the score Querrey.
Right.
And then we are going to sign that connection to this.
Perfect.
Now we're going to use a function right that we have confirm Querrey.
This is a function that we may and we're going to make sure that this works.
All right so now make sure this function that you have is correct go to functions stop being admin.
All right.
And make sure that we have the same that you have the same name for this function.
I might add spell spelled like this before would I am before and I'm spending it with and now and I
fixed it.
I think I already told you how to fix it but it's not.
Just make sure if for some reason this fails this function fails just do the if statement here like
this and just check if not post.
Then you die and you know like this you should know how to do that.
Querrey failed might ask you a lie.
I'm just doing this really quickly so that way you can have a better idea on how this is done right.
But then we pass it in that connection and that's just going to give you the same thing as is confirmed
function.
If for some reason he fails right mine is working so you should be working too.
All right so this should do it right now.
All right.
There's nothing else we've got to do here.
Everything seems to be in order.
Let's go ahead and check it out.
So I'm going to and click enter there.
My you are how am I going to say guys.
As an update.
And now you saw that picture they were going to fix that in a minute right now.
You saw that disappear.
And I tell you in a minute why so we go to View polls.
We see that we were able to update the older guy but we have a problem with image so let's go and fix
that real quick.
All right.
So the problem with the Minxin going to explain what it is.
Right now let's go here is that if I go ahead and choose an image and I choose an image right now like
this.
And by the way if you want these images I'm going to get a file on the right or this lecture you can
download a file that is going to have all these images that I'm just going to blow them for you.
That way you don't have to make them all right.
They're going to be 900 by 300.
So on the right to this lecture download those images if you want them.
I am going to put in there for you.
So if I had this image there right they are right now.
Actually I didn't choose it.
Sorry about that.
And I got it with my computer.
Now for some reason crazy me at once again.
Oops.
Everything just crash.
This just reopened is.
Sorry about that.
I got a lot of things open.
I got like three more monitors on the right hand side on the left.
And of course it's prone to fail.
All right so this is cool down to it men you post.
All right.
Don't worry about what you saw there.
Sometimes I go back in you know after I make 30 lectures I go back and we do a lecture if I don't like
it.
So don't worry about what you saw there.
I'm probably way ahead of you right now.
You know there are lectures but I go back and fix some of these lectures that I make mistakes on sometimes.
Right.
So I'm always fixing things and things like that but anyway let's go down to it let me explain what
happened with the image so I'm going to choose File.
I want to go to pictures and you see that we have the picture I click update.
Now the pictures is fine but if I click Update again we lose that because right now we don't have any
value there.
All right so if I click up they would have no value.
So what we need to do is we need to make sure that this post variable disposed image is not empty and
if it is we need to go get that image somewhere else and that will be in the database.
So right now before we make anything now right here before we do any update on this let's make sure
that this post image is not empty if it is.
We go get that image in the database.
All right.
So we're going to use another function call empty and we're going to say if the post image and listening
if you are sticking with me all this time Congratulations you're really really really really awesome.
Right now a lot of people can do this.
So anyways I just want to tell you that you are awesome and you got to get very far in life.
So if this post image is empty we've got to go to the database and select all from post where those
ID equals what.
Let's get this idea right here.
Why not right.
Polls ID equals this guy right here
and space there.
We're going to call this query select image as a matter of fact that I think I already have written
down somewhere.
Let me see if I find one of my all the money matters.
Yes I have it right here.
So was going to paste it right there.
So we're going to use the miscue like Querrey underscore Querrey to send Querrey we can assign it to
this variable select on the score image.
We're going to use a while loop to loop through that result set right that we get from the database
and we're going to pull out that image again.
All right so that's all I did there.
Gonna save it.
And if I go back and click enter there I don't have an image there but a Feigel end of the this and
if I click Update again you see that I get the image again and again.
All right so perfect we can let's change the image.
I like to change it and of post this click of the pulse again and I get that image.
All right.
Perfect.
So I think this lecture was pretty good.
It was a little long but if you stuck with me to the end you are awesome.
You're doing very good and you're going to be a really good BHP developer.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much and I'll see you on the next lecture.