Book on Welcome back my students so did you finish what I asked for you to do.
Well I hope you did.
If not it's OK.
Let's see if they match.
They don't match.
Of course she is going to refresh.
Let's just say one two three one two and three.
Answer.
And they match as you can see here.
So we got a little validation there.
You can make it better by copying some of the registration page code that we have and plug in it right
here.
That's OK.
OK we can always include some more validation in the future.
But it's very important that you do.
So this is what I did and I asked for you to do this.
We are making sure that this both fields are equal from the form.
So what are we going to do here.
Well first of all we are going to be pulling out of this guy from the
form.
Right.
So let's create a variable and let's assign it to that.
And like actually let's go ahead and hash it.
We're going to be using the same function we have been using.
Let's pass the first parameter is the Bassel we want to hash and this constant here.
And what else.
Let's pass a array of options and we're going to be passing in the cost.
And because the value would be 12 it's good.
OK.
Just going to take a little more time than for any hacker.
Remember that the higher the number is the more this function takes to hash it.
So when you have an automatic software checking checking checking checking is going to take a lifetime
to try to hack into your code.
OK.
So let's see
let's create an if statement here.
What variable was T and T and skew.
Actually this is a prepared statement about the connection and the query what are we going to do.
Well we are going to be updating the users table and we going to set the column talking to empty.
OK.
Because remember that we don't want anything there.
We are updating the because where we don't.
Once we are done using that talking we don't want it anymore.
OK.
So we're going to be using it here.
OK when we come from when the user comes from the e-mail and that say now is no use to us and we are
just going to you know what I don't know why I'm using now using the
double quotes.
So so we're going to get the user password.
We're going to obey the field.
We're going to make sure
that our password is a hash password and we need to get this value here hash password
OK.
Well there we go
where our e-mail user email was questionmark come back here.
And now we need to finish this let's make sure this is right of the users.
Set that column to empty them pulao the user then get the user password column and in clue this hash
password that we are getting here we are encrypting where user email equals that.
So we're getting that e-mail.
Well great.
Remember that we're getting the e-mail OK right here.
When I get requests.
So right now we don't have that e-mail so we need to create that variable just to test things out.
And courting come
sounds about right.
She has me.
Now what are we going to do here.
You remember the function that we need to use.
What are you doing is it buying resold or buying program.
You got it.
If you said this one and then the second parameter What is it.
Well this is the question mark remember.
Is it going to be on into your a string What is it.
Right here
it's going to be a string.
Remember that.
Now of course we're going to get the e-mail.
We're going to be using that very well that we got upstairs.
The not offices up there she says I'm in a apartment building right now and that's what I say upstairs
because they make it a lot of noise upstairs and they're not letting me record because I've got to focus.
OK.
Let's execute this.
And if we're able to do something let's just use dysfunction my obscure lie as A.P. affect the role
should be somewhere here.
Let's pass this statement
and
Echo.
We need to compare this actually greater or equal than one or equal than one usually when it makes a
change is either 1 or 0.
So
I just tell you the way it is.
That's OK.
Bat Querrey
OK.
So what we should see is this being empty this column in the database being empty.
Right here which is not empty right now.
This is as you can see that there and this should be changed as well.
So be careful where we put in there because we won't be able to log in again if we don't put the right
password right.
So let's try this ongoing.
We had a pass where I think mine was one to three or something like that.
So let's just say that is secret just plain secret reset.
He was affected so pay attention to that to see if it changes Amedee as the first three here.
And we got as you can see this is an MVS anymore so something was changed there for sure.
And we don't have that column here anymore so that is empty.