I don't know about you but I'm having a lot of fun teaching you this stuff.
All right.
So hopefully you are really awake.
If not get a cup of coffee.
Pause this video right now get a cup of coffee or Red Bull or some type of energy drink.
Make sure he's healthy though and get ready for this course.
Get ready for the lectures.
Right this is awesome.
We're learning some stuff that's going to make us money that is going to advance us in your personal
life because once you have money you can actually do a lot better in your personal life too.
You know you can fix problems with money you know get a new car get your girlfriend some give or even
your boyfriend or husband wife whatever it is you need money.
Right.
So anyways I don't want to sound too greedy but I'm what I'm telling you is that this is going to help
you.
So we added some really cool functionalities in that last lecture when we updated everything by using
this.
Right now we need to add the rest of the functionality is right.
We need to add the draft and delete.
So this is going to be very similar if you haven't done so already.
I'm going to show you how to do it right now.
All right so let's go ahead and do this.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy and paste.
That's right.
I've got a copy and paste this case right here and right there.
And I'm just going to rename this to draft and post that is here too.
And this draft
and this draft
that said that should that should take care of it.
Believe it or not that's all we need.
Can you believe that could really be that easy.
Yes it can.
So we're going to just make both of them draft look at that boom and that was fast wasn't it.
Now the next one is a little bit different.
All right because we're going to be using a different Querrey but nevertheless it's going to be simple
enough again.
So I'm going to do a copy and paste again.
Best right there the case is going to be the lead.
Right.
And here we're going to be actually doing a live statement delete
all from polls and we're post ID because the polls value right here.
That's it.
That's all we do we know what we need for that update to elite status.
And we're just going to go for it here of the to the leaps.
Status right there.
And that's that's all we need.
I mean it sounds really simple to me.
Well is actually is right just a different statement as to a statement.
Let's go ahead and do that.
And I think we did this pretty quick.
And let's just click here and click delete and apply.
And we've got a query.
All right we got something wrong right.
I knew it wasn't that easy right.
Well we have a little problem right here because we had to delete all.
Actually we can delete all from polls where polls Id close the check value.
All right.
What else would you say the lead from.
How about that.
Is that going to help us out.
And all right let's go ahead and check it out.
Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo boom the lead apply.
Gone.
Look at that.
Beautiful.
So now we are the only bad thing about these guys and ladies is that we need to add more pools.
That's right.
We only got one pulse here and this is actually a hassle to be adding all this stuff here.
Right.
But anyway we are done with this section here.
If you want you can go ahead if you know so she says you can work on the padding for that and just say
padding I think is padding left or something like that but padding is zero.
And you can see that it helps that out so you can target this as a matter of fact.
I'm just going to add what I did was inspect element by the way we can target this I.D. right here and
I copy it.
And that's what I did with my keyboard Comanche and I'm going to go and do a real quick with you guys.
All right.
So because we already have that if they all we have to do with a little padding there.
So let's go to adamancy assess and we have some styles here for we don't have some styles do we have
to have some styles Bushrod men as be adamancy SS or let's just use this one as be as mean as he says
his goal or the way in the bottom.
And let's add this here.
It's going to be a ball container.
There we go and let's just say paddings zero.
Let's see if that helps save.
Now we are going to have to target.
All right.
I helped that out look at that beautiful.
Now this is aligned properly.
Any look is looking really good.
So you can go ahead and rewind the video if it went too fast for you.
All I did was just find out what was affecting this by right clicking specked element on it.
And this is a tool for Chrome.
And I checked on that class or ID that I had contained and I just targeted using C Ss.
All right.
Perfect.
So hopefully you learn a lot on this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.
It was fun.
Bye bye.