All right so we are able to approve and approve comments.
Now I did maybe make a little change here that I want you to make is that I added a d here to this status
here.
I'm going to show you exactly what I did that and the way I did the deeds because when the status comes
here and we approve it I should be in the past tense right.
So I went to you all comments where we were working on.
And I changed it right here on this two queries when we are getting the key and changing the status
to approved.
And this one to own approved.
We did.
That's all I'm doing.
All right.
So make sure that you update those fields.
Now what we want to do is we want to go to the post page here and we want to take a couple of pieces
of the comments actually called out.
So what I want to do is stay with this one here and everything else just throw it out.
All right.
And this is going to be the comments right here.
He's going to throw out this part right here done.
So we go back and we see this.
Right click on it and let's go to that page.
We can see that come in right here.
Well that's not the original comment but it's specific to this post but it is a placeholder.
That's what we want.
All right so now let's go ahead and make the Querrey.
I'm not going to write the whole code because I already wrote it down.
But we explain every little detail.
So what we're going to be doing is doing a Querrey just to select everything phone from where comments
right.
So let me just copy and paste that cold right here and then to show you it's just a Querrey as you can
see right here.
All right.
And I will break that loop right here because we're going to pull some makes milk comment.
Cold inside the loop.
So that way we can get some of this values out there.
So and I'm going to explain right now exactly what's going on.
So let's get this cold right there in the middle right here.
This one we don't want to get this here because that's the whole column and we'll break the HDL code
if we do that if we get that little deaf and deaf there.
Right.
This is the
column up here.
You see that.
All right
so now that we're here let me explain what we were doing.
So very simple.
We select everything.
That's what actually means and you know that from comments where common post ID.
All right.
This is what the the the column in that table that has the pulse ID.
All right equals to the post ID of here.
See that we are getting it as a get request from you are all on the page right here and we are converting
it to that variable and then we are using it down here.
That's all we are doing right here.
And then we saying we using another statement called and and this is just a condition right and common
standard is that's another column in the table equals approved.
Actually we need to change it to the D because we already changed made that change.
Right.
And then we use another statement right here.
And another excuse statement saying order by comment ID which is a column.
Right.
That's the common ID column descending meanings.
Again I give us the newest comments first on top.
All right well it's going to give us a new idea on top.
All right.
And then here we just sending it would that would send him back where he is and we are checking here
in the next line.
We've already done that.
We we're running the loop right here to get so much information out and we get in the coming days the
content and the altar here.
We are going to be that information right here.
We're going to be this plane the other.
OK.
So let's get that right there.
Oops he's made another copy here at my keyboard.
And let's just go ahead and copy this one to this and put the day right here.
And let's take this out and we'll do the comments right here.
The content.
I'm sorry.
Well a comment symtab right content.
All right let's go ahead and check it out and see what happens.
We have the placeholder here.
I refresh here on top.
We get the comments here but we don't we're not getting the content itself actually come in content.
We are having a issue because we are not echoing anything.
Hey make sure you echo that.
If not you're not going to get anything.
Right.
Let's go ahead and do that.
All right so we're getting some information.
All right.
So as you can see here we're getting some of this.
And just to show you that it is actually telling me it's actually giving us information from the news
coming.
Let's go ahead and make a comment.
I'm going to say the author of this right now has one.
Let's call this make a comment with Peter and it's for the Peter information here.
Peter already got press there.
And whenever she mail come and this is just another piece of comment.
Is just another this this is just another piece of comment Perfect's of Mitt.
And it's not showing here because it's not approved.
Let's go to admin and prove it.
Let's see if we got it right here let's just refresh this.
And we need to also play the order of descending right here.
This one used to show the newest on top right.
Let's approve it approved.
Let's go to the specific polls and then I right click and go there let's go and check it out.
As you can see here this is just another piece of comment.
Let's let's actually approved and see what happens.
Let's go back to admen comments and approve it and approve everything and see what do we get.
Let's go back refresh.
We didn't get any comments at all right.
Beautiful.
All right so we are done with a section here.
Hopefully you got some valuable information and I'll see you the next lecture.
Take care.