All right so I thought about it at home.
We're not going to be doing something too fancy right here.
Basically we're going to do some of the queries and we're going to update the rolls right maybe later
on an extra feature will do something a little faster than this but just for demonstration purposes
and you know we're going to be doing it simple.
All right.
So let's go ahead and pass some parameters to this on a proof and let's change actually and say something
like maybe change me chance to admen.
I don't know.
Something like that's fine and changed to subscriber or something
changed to subscriber stop right.
So
let's go ahead and name this link.
Actually name it.
It's admen and this describer
subscriber.
All right.
So let's go.
And the first one is this one so let's put that key right here.
Let's put it right here and
just say
what we're going to be passing here is that link right there admin ID or link.
Well is actually the user's ID right.
The user ID that's fine let's just pass the user id here too.
Doesn't really matter.
And of the users
groups set users user what we name that user role
to admin right where user id he calls that Id
user ID.
There we go.
I think this should be good admen comment.
Admen
let's just call this change admin Querrey to admin Kohary location users up here should be all right
you should know how to use that.
Do this already.
Since we have done this before.
All right.
I think it is good news or good to me list this first get the idea of a user a here.
All right so lets get to here and possibly get it here too.
All right and we can do the other one too.
Since we already did this too fast.
Let's go ahead and change this to what admin Hoopes is directing us to another page.
I think of course its got to be changed to users to now forget that users.
All right so the first one that is working is the admin one and this go to users again and this changes
when you see the changes to admin.
All right.
So let's go into the next one since we did it so fast.
Right.
So that's.
The key for us change to sub and let's right here right.
Right here and the user id has changed.
Its a matter of fact which you get all this right here
is
actually just a query
and change this to subscriber.
I think that it was a rule that said that right there and changed to the sub query right here.
Perfect.
Let's let's check that out now.
All right.
So let's go and refresh this subscriber.
Whoops I misspelled something lets you make sure that these IDs is being sent right is being sent to
the left and the left side and let's check it out that she was wrong where user id Eco's the user id
right here.
This is what happened.
Comment Id put in there.
We left it there.
Make sure you change that.
I should just copy everything I refresh.
Subscriber.
There we go.
Well we don't want to may recall suave.
This was great.
All right.
So perfect.
All right so we kill two birds in one shot.
Thank you so much for watching.
Hopefully you're enjoying the course and we hope to hear from you soon.
Take care.