Are right my dear students in this lecture here I'm going to show you how to prove this a little more.
All right.
So we're going to tell you on the last lecture that we were going to improve this part right here every
time we all day the changes to the full value of subscriber and that's because we have it set to the
fault.
All right.
So for example if I go to view all users and I click Edit and I select admin and all they use or it
does everything fine.
But what if I do it again it goes back to subscribe.
That's because we have a default value on the form and I'll show you right now that's a simple very
simple fix.
But I want you to be aware of that just in case you see it somewhere else and you can fix it you see
right here we have a value of subscriber.
This is a default value.
So you have to do is just copy this and paste it right here and right now what we are doing is that
we are actually setting the full value of the current user role.
All right.
So make sure that you do that safe and that's a simple fix again if you see this anywhere in the form
in the CMOS.
You can fix it you just want to show you a quick way you already know how to do that by the way.
All right so I'm going to go back to all users at it.
I'm going to change it to admin of the user of the user again of the user again of the user again we
are good to go.
All right.
Just wanted to show you how to do that let's try it again right here.
Make this guy admen.
There we go.
We don't have that problem anymore.
All right.
So we're good to go right.
Perfect.
So we can change subscribers right here to remember.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture guys.
And I see you in the next one.
Take care.