All right so we've got a lot of functionality here we're able to change the roles of users delete.
We are even able to add users.
Now what we want to do is being able to edit the user.
So for that we're going to go to the edit user that BHB page that we made but the difference with this
page is that it looks the same as the Post's page.
Does that show you right now if we go to the viewer polls and we click Edit it's gonna look like this
one that we won that edit user page to look like the AD user because it's going to be going to have
the same fields here that we need to edit.
Right.
So we need to do a save as we need to copy this one into the edit user into Aceves.
Let me just show you real quick how the added user looks at that user.
You see that we don't want that.
All right so let's go and open a new tab here real quick.
All right.
I just want to have two tabs there.
We've got to get is you are out in there.
So all right.
So it does go to the user user and this command or control a select everything and command see Control
see.
And let's go to the end user command a command VI control VI.
If you are in a Windows and now that we change a list save it has come back here and actually not here
here refresh.
And when we got on the French table here.
Right.
And the different form perfect.
So we need to start actually adding the query so that where we can pull some data from the database
have it right here.
Right.
Even the the rules.
And and then we are able to update and change a couple of things on this form right here.
All right.
So this edit user and we don't have to change much.
Actually we are sending the same information.
This just changed this year and we're going to say use as a user right.
And what else do we need to do here and add a user one.
Well for starters we need to receive that data somewhere.
So if any user write it where we see that data from somewhere from here then we are going to be actually
the first one of the first thing that we need because right now we're not going to be using the form
unless we update.
So up here we need to receive from the you are all set.
They get requests right.
This request is going to be added user.
Well let's see if we can name that.
I think that's fine.
As a user that's a good good name for it.
And we're just going to say user ID right now.
All right.
Or we can say that user id the user ID just to be just to know that the data is different from the one
that from the database.
And lets just copy this one here put it right here
and where we need to do is echo this out to see if we are getting something right.
Well we also need to update a link here.
It will go to view all uses We don't have the edit link right here that we need.
So to send that request to that page.
So let's go to that of your users there and get that link view of users and the link should be right
here.
All right so let's do the link right here before delete.
All right.
And let's name it delete edit.
And this one is going to go to.
I'm trying to see what we can square.
Where can we.
We are sending this stuff.
We are sending actually we're sending it to the same users that BHB will we're going to be using a parameter
to parameters.
All right so the first parameter that we're going to be using is source.
Remember that source and add it user.
That's the first parameter and then aspirin's ampersand to the VI that parameter added user is going
to be the next one.
And that is the key that we will be receiving in the editing user that BHB page.
All right so once we have that then we've got the user id right here and we're good we're good.
Let's check it out.
So refresh edit and walk.
And then we are echoing that idea right there.
Now if you don't know what I did I'm just going to recap a little bit real quick.
All right.
So we are in the view all users and all I'm doing right here is sending that source Paramor.
The first source parameter that we got I remember we got the source parameter because we got a switch
statement on users.
We did that with a pulse remember.
So let's go to users and you see we got that first parameter says a user.
But that first parameter has a source.
OK.
So he's checking if the source is equal to the user.
Do it.
It said that's why user if it's equal to any user send it to the user.
And right now the source is equal to every user.
So he sends that person to this page right here and we are catching this with they get requests.
Of course.
All right in the edit user page and echoing.
Just to make sure that we are receiving the information that get requests.
All right.
So anyway thanks so much for watching this lecture.
The next one we're going to be continuing to add more code and get this data display here that where
we can see what we are going to be editing from the database from the table.
All right.
Take care and I'll see you the next lecture