All right I think we have come very far on some of the things here and we will come back later on for
the comments when we make the comments section.
But right now I want to see how things look right.
We want to go ahead and let's first let's go to our polls and let's create one polls here and I'm going
to go online actually and I'm going to go to Loring Ibsen
and then I get some some information out of here some dummy tests.
And the reason why I'm doing this because I want to show you.
But you can easily Gricean dummy tests in your data Ed..
I'll show you in a minute but right now we're going to get in touch for this right here.
So right there.
All right.
So post title would be something like Bess Bess BHP course
ever.
Right.
And the category of course we need to display that information here so that way we can add it.
So that's one of the things that we need to add.
But right now we're just going to say category 40 or something like that.
We might get a narrow sense when we can display that on the PSI.
Let's just say it and D.S. post status draft is when you check something out before we go ahead and
continue to check how things look outside on the blocks section.
Right.
So that's what we're going to be doing PH BE AND BEST something like that plus polish.
Let's go to the site let's look at it and you can see here we do have some polls showing already we
have the title here which doesn't go anywhere.
We're going to make that go somewhere.
But that's going to be after we finish all this administration in the bag.
It's going to be adding some of these features.
All right.
The most important thing is getting the crowd ready.
Create read of they indeed ready on the a mess once we get that ready then we start adding little features
like clicking on the titles going into that specific post showing the comments those nice graphs that
I show you in the beginning.
Like go into a profile when you click on certain things.
I mean those things are extra features and we're going to be adding them.
We need to also truncate this.
Make it smaller because we don't want to show all the content right here right.
I said in my file we can do that right now.
Let's go and do that.
As a matter of fact actually will do that in the next video right now.
I want to worry about something else right here.
So we see down the pole section right here on the ad post.
We have this category here.
Let's make this display the category title here so that we can submit it with it right.
We can't submit it.
We can see it here when we edit it.
That's fine we can see it but we need to add some functionality on the other side when we add it.
So let's go ahead and do that.
First of all what we need to do is copy basically what we got there right.
So I think we have it here on the edit and right here right.
We select the categories.
We have a selection right here.
Copy this whole thing even with a form group that would be nice right.
We can get all these functionality working there on the View or post page.
All right so we have that in categories that is not view.
We need to get it on the index.
Let's go to the index of the Web site and what we've got on the it's displaying all this information
here.
Hold on.
No.
All we were doing is that truncate and we're not doing that.
All right.
We're not doing that.
We are fixing this go to admen.
We're facing this at polls so we need to go to the post page.
Sorry about that.
Let's go to that and we got that in and including admen folder in includes We got the post.
All right.
And we have it right here.
So we are going to be pasting that right there with a whole day.
You saw that and then at dawn do we have this this group already selected and we just pasted there.
All right.
So now right here is post category needs to go in there when we check it right here create post.
We need to find the right here somewhere.
Post category right here.
Take that out.
And that's all I'm going to take.
I'll leave it at the same.
All right.
So that field value is going to go in there let's make sure the value is fine.
We've got a cat ID here.
Do we have the kind of weeb displaying the categories here.
We are not displaying the categories so we've got to be careful with that.
So what value are we going to be sending to for this.
We don't have the category we need to to get that.
I mean she got tired actually we have it right here.
Sorry guys cut Title.
All right.
We're going to send it with that.
And we need to send that in the insert.
So in the end sir we need to change that category title values.
Let's get the polls come in count right here.
So actually that the whole thing is going in there that's perfect.
We were good.
We're good.
Actually we don't need to do anything.
All right.
So let's check it out.
Perfect is making you post.
How about that.
All right so example post number 1000 because no one was imposing it ready.
Let's do it in Java and let's say the name of the alter is James and Paul status is to draft a published
White Way drafted let's just make this published right here.
We have all those keywords right here.
Those image issues make another great image.
What about how black my name right there.
Nice.
And false tags doing the ads and content some content from as windy as in big bold letters.
You don't have to write that.
By the way publish.
Let's look at it on the front refresh and we've got it right here.
See that perfit.
And let's see in the back to see we got the categories too.
Let's go back to the back of the website admin right here.
Let's check it out.
You post and we have the Java category let's going update that and change it to something else.
Two procedural actually to assemble category change the image here and draft.
Remember the simple polls number one doesn't update.
Come back here and Zambo category right there.
We updated that and we update of the category.
Let's make one last pause and that said it zestful post 200.
Let's put opii object oriented programming.
Really cool subject.
We probably were going to be touching on that.
Maybe the next course that I make We're going to be doing something totally object oriented programming
which is cool.
All right.
So the polls there will be maybe a mate and pull status would be publish
right and
see who's strap.
I'm just I just don't have any more pictures guys.
All right so if you might get some more pictures but this is just placeholders right.
This is a P course with with with full strap.
All right.
Update.
Send it in and perfit.
Look at that.
Oh.
We are in.
We are worth a lot.
Right now my friend.
So if you were able if you are able to do this right now and you are working in a job related to web
development that should raise your salary.
If you're now working you should be able to find a job very easily in what about a mallees entry level.
If you've got this far and you know how to do this if you don't know how to do is do it a thousand times
until you get it right.
All right.
Be motivated because this is big time.
You're building I see a mess right now so keep that in mind.
We even got the day we got everything here right.
We're going to be continuing our lecture and the next video and hopefully you are feeling good about
yourself.
All right.
Thank you so much and see you in the next one.