All right so doing this comments section here has been pretty interesting right.
Well we still got more a little bit more things to do with comments.
Let's go to post you will post.
And here you can see we still got some static data here.
We've still got the same hard coded data that we input before.
Every time we create a comment.
But we want to do is make this dynamic.
Now we've got two options.
One option is using HP all right to count the amount of comments that this specific post has.
Or we can actually increase the number inside our database so that way we can have that data anytime
we want.
And if you recall let me open another page here and I'm going to go to
localhost BHP my admin.
All right.
And here let's go to the Simmons and bolts.
This goes to a structure and here you can see that we made an extra roll here called a column called
The pause comment count right.
Well here we're going to be input in the count of each of the comments.
And the reason is because it's better to keep the count inside the database.
That way we can add that information any time we want instead of just counting it with BHB.
Sometimes it can be just a matter of preference but I like to do it like this.
So let's go ahead and do that right now.
So what we want to do is we increase this right now this comment section should be 0 in every post that
we get.
So let's go to any specific polls and you can see well is actually four is going to be always four because
we are how hard coding it.
So let's go to the section on post up BHB.
All right.
So every time we create a post we get that data dynamically right.
Well how could it.
So we need to go to the post insertion.
Right so every time we create a post let's go to the insert let me see includes
and post and post.
All right.
As you can see here we are actually doing this right here right.
We are increasing that pulse coming count we don't want to do that anymore.
Right.
So let's go ahead and do that let's not insert that anymore.
Let's just come in that out there in the future if we need it we do it but we're going to take that
out and we're going to take that out here also.
All right.
So let's not insert that every time we do it.
Now that's not going to be inserted dynamically now is going to be zero.
Right.
So we need a way to increment it.
All right.
So what are we going to do is we've got to go the posts now.
Pause post.
Actually go without the s right thing here.
Every time we make a comment we're going to update that field.
All right.
So you might be wondering how in the world we're going to do that we can do that with a query for the
comments section right.
Well what we have to do is actually make another query and we can make as many queries as we want.
So inside this if statement here or code right I want to do another query and the query is going to
be for you to make a little bigger so you can see what I'm doing right there.
So we're going to make another query in.
Can you think about where we are we're going to be making.
If you can you can post a video any time trying to do it yourself.
We're going to update polls.
All right.
Set for us.
See the name of the field that column Post.com and count.
OK.
That's what we're going to be updating.
So we're going to set post comment count equal to what we're going to show you a little trick right
now to increment the values because that's an integer we can do that.
Post comment count last one.
Every single time we make a comment.
All right so now we need to do a where statement here because if we don't this is just going to increment
it to all the polls and we don't want to do that.
So let's make a where statement let's just concatenate this or that way.
Shorter right here.
It's better to have another line by the way to make sure we have that there.
And let's say where false ID equals to what we have the idea here somewhere right here.
All right there we go.
All right.
So we have this data here available to us.
I'm going to show you right now that it does work and it sure work and we don't have any mistakes.
So let's check this again of the post set post comment count does a column equal to the senting polls
coming count plus 1.
So this is how we are signing our value there where polls underscore ID equal to the polls.
Id perfect.
So that dash worked fine.
And then the last step is to actually set send the query right.
So let's send that must not forget to do that update comment hoops comment count.
All right.
So let's use a function to send it in.
So we're going to use this function right here and we're going to be sending it in right here.
All right.
Perfect.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
Check it out and see if it works.
So we're going to go localhost and it's going to be a mess.
All right.
Let's go to any common ground.
Is there going to be three.
And we're going to leave a comment here.
I was just going to say my name is Juan.
E-mail is one at 1 2 for G-mail.
Com.
And hey just anything there.
That's fine.
Let's go to our local.
Let's check on comments Polsce and it's checking the coming count as you can see this coming kowa increase
from four to five because he was four before remember were all will for now eight increase.
Let's go ahead and make another comment and let's call it is.
My name is Wollin.
I don't know if anybody's name is Wooleen but I just came out with it.
If nobody has a name but I'm pretty sure somebody in the world has that name.
Hey I am waffling.
All right.
Let's do that.
So Matt refresh and if we come here you see that increase to 6 right so perfect.
So now we were able to increase that depending on you know how many comments we got for this specific
force.
So that's perfect.
All right.
So the next step is to play.
I'm going to cut off this video here and the next video we're going to be talking about that we're going
to be No.
We're going to be learning how to do that.
All right.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.