Or I saw in the last video we were able to echo some values from the user space.
Right.
So we came here and we click on edit.
We send up for ometer via they you are able to get requests and we were able to catch it in a way right
here.
Now the next step is to instead of echoing this we already know that that works.
We are receiving the parameter we need to Eckl the field try here.
We need to echo the first name last name user name and all these fields here.
And then after that we need to update it.
So the first thing is to pull this information out.
So how are we going to do that.
All right so lets think for a minute.
If we click the end user then we get all this functionality here.
Well I don't want all these functionality right now and not going to user right now.
I mean I wan it but Im not going to use it and we are not going to be using this either because this
is a copy from the add user page.
This is inserting something into the database we don't want to insert We want an update.
So right now what we need to do right here is instead of echoing this we need to turn this into a ID.
Right.
So were going to say the user ID or something like that.
So we would turn that on and we need to do a query here.
So we need to go back to maybe another file that we have that a query like that for users and that would
be be all users have that file that we need that cold.
So cold right here.
So let's grab some of this.
Let's go back to the end user page and it's going to go and use this one here as a user.
All right.
I am going to copy all of that code right here.
Perfect.
We're going to modify this a little bit.
Make sure you close this while Stay blue right here.
All right.
All right so if we get this if we get to any user We're going to be doing all this we're going to convert
the a user parameter into the user id variable.
And then we're going to say select from what users where user ID that's a column in the database equals
what the user id right here.
Right.
Perfect.
All right we don't need to pull cords or anything around that since this is an integer.
Remember that.
So select users query letters call it where used to name a little different from our user page and let's
put that here also.
All right.
And we're going to be pulling all these data out.
So now let's check all these data right.
Let's echo this and let's just echo the user name.
Let's see how that goes.
All right let's go here let's go to the view users and let's click here and then we see that we got
Rico there.
Perfect.
So it is working.
So now let's go ahead and echo this somewhere else.
Right.
Let's go to the fields where we have the first name and all that the form the form right here.
So what we need to do is actually fill in the value attribute here that this has by default is empty
by the full what we will going to fill it up with some BHB Reisen dynamic data.
So it's use value.
And if I can get this right that would be nice.
So this would be the first name.
So let's say first name that's a variable we have on top right remember that.
So let's go ahead and see if that works.
Let's go to view users again and it and we have all the fine variable first name.
All right.
Let's make sure we have the right.
Oh there we go.
We are misspelling there right.
So let's go to this and replace all that.
There we go.
Let's refresh.
And now we got Rico perfit.
All right.
So this is working.
We just got to remember how we name the variables on top.
All right.
So we're going to do something very similar for all of them for the last name.
I'm going to do this just copy the whole value thing to you and put it right here.
And you just made this a little smaller for me so I'm going to echo the last name here the last name.
Make sure you do the same.
All right.
I'm going to do this later.
Right now I want to worry about other things the value.
Let's go ahead and do that actually.
I is something else right here.
All right.
It's looking good.
Make sure that this is user name I think this one doesn't have a prefix issues user name.
That's it.
And the e-mail sort of user e-mail
and the password that's fine let's just call that password but we're going to be queen
just little dots because we have that type I you right here.
Right.
What else.
Let's let's check it out.
Let's check it out let's see what's going on.
All right so we got everything here.
Recall the e-mail even the password.
Perfect.
Right.
So now we need to work on this.
We need to ekal right.
If this user is a subscriber or admin then then we need to change.
Right we're going to do that in the next one since it requires a little bit of cold and I'm going to
show you how to do that right.
So perfect.
So we've done this and we come very far a few are here with me doing this lecture here.
Congratulations.
You are one of the few that actually finish what they start.
So again I see in the next lecture and thank you so much.
Rabbi