All right so another functionality that I want to add to our.
Super simple.
We want to add a drop down right here on the post status.
I'm tired of actually coming here and you know saying that this is going to be a draft.
All right so let's go ahead and add a functionality like this dropdown simple drop down.
It's going to be a start it's not going to be pulling information from anywhere but it's needed.
So that way we don't have to be typing right.
So we're going to go to our admin for slashing kluges and insight and underscore posts that's where
we're going to be adding that.
So Paul status right here.
We are going to be getting a select here.
All right.
So
I'm just going to be changing this input for a select select is going to be like this.
The first option is going to be
select options
options are right and the value is going to be what do we want the value.
For some reason to post the value is going to be published or draft does make it draft that way if something
happens if is something that we don't want people to see it's not published.
All right.
Let's take this out of here real quick and actually let's look at it because we need to send Let's get
his poll status here on this select name.
All right.
Let's make sure we have that then we can just delete it.
Well we don't need it right now.
So perfect.
So let's make a couple more options here and this option is going to be publish published if I can get
the name right that would be nice.
And next that's is going to be draft.
That's fine.
So published right here and draft second option.
All right let's go ahead and check it out and try it on right.
We need to make sure the works.
So let's make sure it's really tidy and nice.
There we go right there.
So you can copy if you want.
All right.
So let's go ahead and try it out.
All right so we have the status right here.
We could.
As a matter of fact just take the label out here.
Let's take the label out of there.
We don't need it.
And let's just say pull status here.
Let's see how that looks.
All right.
It's a lot better.
So Paul status we want to be publish.
All right so let's make a pose and this call is something like Wow another pose polls My hands
are tired
right there.
Yeah right.
Let's make a smiley face.
And I don't why not.
But it's not sad right.
I like this beautiful right.
Edwin other we're going to publish it.
And the post is actually just going to say published right here.
That's fine.
And we're going to choose an image and image is going to be.
That's fine bootstrap.
Let's make this bootstrap right here.
And we're just going to say some content this is this is some content kind.
There we go publish post.
All right.
And let's check it out.
You will post published right here.
Perfect.
Right.
Wow another.
My hands are tired of this and that.
And if we update it that we can view it right here also.
All right.
Perfect.
So that's one feature now looking at it.
I want to add another feature to this and I'm going to add the same feature that I did on the edit post.
As you remember here on these exit polls we have this feature.
Well I want to add that feature to our ad at polls right here.
Every time I make a post I want to have something here if you want to go ahead and do that.
And a little note is that we got on the Edit pose when we update it right here if you want to add the
same functionality to the ad post page.
Go ahead and do that.
I'm going to do that in the next lecture Right.
So take care and I see you in the next one.
Bye bye.