A guy so I had to take a little break because I was so hungry I don't know if you heard me in a couple
years ago that you know I could I just couldn't do it anymore I had to do something.
So anyway I found my little booboo and snide really a booboo.
It's something that we forgot to update.
So if we go to the post of BHB we can see here that we have this static ID here that we are using.
So we need to get the ID of the post the user id here of the looking user right.
So we already have a function.
So we need ID of the logged in user here to make this work.
Thats why I left this for last because you know we didnt have that.
I mean we did have a really good function to play around with.
So I'm just going to say user
she was what he was for that
low end user ID.
That's why we created a function.
We go and the function is returning.
The idea is make sure that it is returning that well that's what he's supposed to do.
We tested that.
So that should be the idea that should do it that should do the trick guys.
Let's going into our database from all this stuff let's delete it ah I just deleted the user's
teleportation.
There we go.
We just teleported back to the past and fixed it.
All right.
I'm joking I just I just pause the video and creating new new users.
OK.
So one thing I forgot to do here was to simply make sure that this is admin.
We're going to need this later.
OK.
With some really cool functionality that I got coming for you guys.
So we do need to with the likes.
I'm pretty sure we do need to do that.
Let's go browse here before we make a mistake in the tables.
And yes and we need to update appose.
Click and zero enter.
There we go.
So now we go to pose the first one says that we have some type of error here.
OK.
Page source.
Let's go back down.
It says quote If you have an error in your syntax server syntax.
Post the dirty nine.
Yeah that's another one that we are hard coding.
For some reason.
OK maybe you're not but I am and this is in your in my Lets look for a number here.
You probably don't have that s probably Sunday.
I'm testing in the in my functions file
this is the link pool right.
That is because in my logged in
I don't think I am logged in.
That's a good thing to because if I'm not logged in yeah that's right.
That's something that we have to fix now.
It's not showing if we are now logged in.
So that's good that we that we encounter the error here.
But as you can see it it will work.
I'm going to do like OK when I log into I'm going to use Safari this time and I'm going to log in as
Maria because I'm going to dance Edwyn down actually am logging Asmara small.
And you can see that we have one like here.
I like it and you can see now that it says on like OK now of course.
Now if we go to add one we can see that changes to and if I go on like it from the editing site has
one in from memory Esai has one but she's still liking it.
OK so that's working.
Not that I want to face real quick here before I forget.
Is this style.
We also need to do whatever we did here to their own like OK
just to make sure that when we all like it that class also has the same size so refresh and you can
see that that goes back to that.
OK so another thing here that we need to address is.
If it's not load then we need to make sure that they don't see that but in OK.
So I think we have a function for that don't we loading user is loved and OK look at this function can
we use it let's try it out.
And let's go back to pose so we don't and we don't want to use it to log in.
We want to see this but we don't want the user to see that like if they're not logged in.
So let's open some ph VTX right here.
And let's close it right here.
Actually we were
let's come back here and write this stuff down and then we play around with it.
OK we could write up here and but let's just do it right here.
So they say if it's logged in then I want to be able to see something right.
So when I close I hear and I'm going to open it right here
and we want to see this link here.
These H1 is not part H.
R. is not part of that.
Let's put it right here.
And then we just say els
we can show them another button to copy this and whoops
and instead of having this
long
you need to know again to like.
And here we can have a buy in with the Logan writing the log in page for mistaking
go and log in and we can just move this link and replace it with his right in between.
OK so that would be good.
That works right.
Meaning we're a lot of BHB we don't know if it works.
Let's look out with Maria and let's go inside one of these polls and you can see that he says you need
to log in to like click it and it gives us this Marion
right perfect saw.
You know you can make this bigger too and you know it's a matter of fact let's do that let's just make
it a little bigger right.
Let's add some type of class to this here to this whole paragraph.
OK.
Let's make it likes just like the and that is INSIGHT.
A We have all of the classes here.
But it's inside paragraph anyway I don't want to go too deep if I don't have to.
Declaring a class and they just make everything seem as if we can actually you know like who is here
and he likes there.
I think we can kill like three words in one shot.
Let's see if I.
There we go.
Perfect.
OK.
So that's looking awesome.
And we have some really cool functionality if we're not logged in.
OK.
We should create a that as well.
There you need to log in.
Suppose we should
create a class here.
Or log in to post.
I think we can even take this further and you know they are all in the same class to do something else
with it.
And the same element B in the paragraph element that we go guys.
This was I think a really awesome section here if you have not given me those five stars.
Go ahead and do it now.
That motivates me to create more lectures.
Hopefully you know I was able to show you some really good cool stuff in this section.
And that's my goal with this course.
And you're welcome to send me a private message if you need extra help or as into discussions and I'll
try my best.
To have me or somebody else help you out.
See you in the next lectures guys.
Take care and thank you for everything you guys are the best.