All right so on the last video we made this work.
All right.
But we thought that you know our search was not working.
Our search engine was not working but it was working.
We just did not give it any content to this play once they found a search.
Once he found a result same result as you can see here and we did this and the last one I just deleted
it.
It is displaying some of it.
And if I go here.
Well that's what it was before but if I go here.
Hello.
Well no resaw on that one.
And if I go here like Belinda which some results right javascript I know some resorts you see that.
So what we want to do is we can have this search in you know we can have something else come here because
we are in the sidebar.
So what we need to do is we meet we need to move all of this data somewhere else.
All right.
We need to move all this functionality from the sidebar.
So what we need to do is make another page make this form submit to the old page and then we're going
to take all these data with us.
All right.
So we're going to take all this deleted when I delete it I come troll ads or command ads and your key
word and let's just make a new file and just do it from the index page and at the end it's all right
and do a Save As and it's called this search that BHB we should put this inside includes actually.
And let's leave it there for now.
Later on we will take it out of there.
We'll do it later.
That's fine.
Let's do it.
Let's do it like this for now.
All right.
So let's just make make this right here in the same root as our end it's just to show you how it works.
So this is a search here and what we want to do is this is the same page.
Now if I go to search here we're going to have some of the data here same data display to us when it
takes some of this data out there especially this from here to there.
But we're going to be putting our code right here.
I think we have some ph feedbacks that we need to worry about.
But then I copy this there and we need to take that out.
You that BHP right here and is BHP what I want to do is inside these else says resoled.
I want to pool all this information right here.
So I take all this and take it out and going to this play right here on this else I'm going to put it
in there.
All right.
So what I did.
Perfect.
Now we see a lot of information here but later on we're going to be able to at the end we're going to
refactor this and make this into function.
Right now we're not going to worry about it.
I think it looks good right now and it does what we need right now.
So another thing that we need to do actually we need to go back to the sidebar and make this Cyber Force
admit to that specific page.
So let's make a submit search that BHB.
All right.
Let's go ahead and test it out.
Let's go to the phone from page and it's.
That works out.
Hello.
Click on it and we get in there of course expect them to follow what a team.
I had a feeling that was going to do that one.
A team on the site search we have found here mistake.
We have a lot of this is breaking this test right here.
What we need is two and three here.
It should work fine now.
Perfect.
Let's go back to the that's again and let's look for something new.
Click on it.
No result.
Let's click.
And then we get that post that only that specific post says Belinda right.
Let's look for.
I don't know what else.
What can we look for.
Belinda right there.
Let's look for let's see in a database where we can look for structure I should post and doing this
look for.
Well when I that we only have two poses there.
And that's why it finds that it is working.
Now let's look for BHB.
All right which is let's look for BHB and see how that works.
We should make another in and try it out like that.
BHB finds out information
finds Belinda there.
But the only problem is I'll show you right now that is displaying everything.
What we want to do is just display why this search is just one item.
All right one individual item for research.
So that's the only thing that we want to display.
So that's why this is explain everything because every time you find something just displays a holding.
Right now we want to make this display just as specific individual polls.
All right.
So for that we just basically not put this in the loop right.
We're not going to be put in.
We get we've got to select it from what we want.
All right so let's fix.
Actually one one it actually FIND A polls.
Not a bunch of information.
So we select from polls where that and depending on that we select everything from polls here and we
are displaying the same polls over and over again there.
And that is the problem.
All right so we need to take this out of here because right now we have that there.
We don't need it.
We have that there and we don't have a while loop.
So we need we just need a WHILE loop.
Now we just take this out of here.
And I think we're good just with this.
We have to change this Querrey search query and put it into a WHILE loop here because that's our search
query.
We need to do that.
All right so now we will get individual results.
It was working fine.
It was it was now working for 100 percent.
We is finding the polls and everything else with it.
So now let's check it out again.
And now we should have something better.
All right.
So we have everything here let's just type in Belinda and see what happens.
Haha nice right now I just found aspecific post right.
Let's pull the take on it.
Just.
Nothing else right.
Now a custom search engine is perfect.
Anyway I hope you like this tutorial this lecture and I hope you learn a lot.
So anyway I see you in the next one.
All right.
Take care.