All right on the last lecture we were able to displace on data from the database here depending on why
use it we have select the here right one click Edit.
We get this parameter and depending on the parameter we make a query pull this information from the
database for this specific user right.
So now the last thing for this is for displaying data here is being able to display the dynamic options
right here.
So for that we need a little bit of coding there and let's do it right now.
Let's go to the select option and that will be right here.
And what I want to do is I want to put some BHB here what we want to do right.
Because you're supposed to be doing this with me hopefully.
All right the first thing that we want to do is display a default option.
So this default option is going to be cold.
Well we're going to be pulling this information from the database right now.
As a matter of fact BHB Eckel and we're going to call the user role.
All right.
So let's check it out and see how that works.
So we are displaying these guys are admen and we can verify that we can go to your users and we can
see that we're always anatman the right click on it again.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and do that and do the rest.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create an if statement here and we're going to say if user
roll.
Right.
It's equal to what to the strain what ad men we're going to do something if this admin We want to display
the subscriber because that way we can give the user the chance to change it to a subscriber.
All right so let's go ahead and change this double quotes here so that we can echo this properly put
the double cords there.
Make sure you close your statement with a semi-colon there and then if it's not an admin then we're
going to say else we're going to play the admin one.
So if it's a subscriber we're going to display admin so that where we can give the option to change
to admin.
All right this is going to come out great you're going to see.
All right perfect.
I think we're good to go here.
All right.
So let's go ahead and check that out and see how everything is working.
Save it.
Come back here and then we can see that he's adamant and then we get the they subscribe and we can send
those parameters.
You see that perfect.
So let's go ahead and change something here.
Let's just make sure this is all lowercase.
That's fine since this is lowercase here.
I don't want that to look on uniform.
Right.
Actually I put an age there.
Geez.
We go.
OK.
Perfect.
That's working great.
And then that's the lecture we're going to finally update this form and make it work.
Right.
So I see you then take care