All right so we get a lot of things going on here and a lot things are working.
We have all the data that we need.
This plane right here on this forum.
The next thing is to update this form and we need to create the update query for that.
And I think we have the update query somewhere in there and let's go ahead in and see if we can get
it from maybe comment and say your comments right here at it.
I think your comments has all of that data that we need so let's use this.
Check it out real quick or we can check out edit post and check it out there.
It pulls does not have they will go at a post that has a little bit of a better one that we need.
All right so let's go ahead and take these actually.
We're going to need this one here and perfit let's just take the whole thing take it from edit post.
This is the great thing about copying page right.
Can go all of that data here.
All right so let's go to where we were before eddied user right here not far away.
All right.
So instead of having all of this here what we need to do is have that query that we just pulled from
there right here.
And let's just paste it right here.
OK.
We need to change a couple of things here though.
All right so we're going to update users.
All right.
And we need to change a couple of these parameters here.
Well not parameters variables and call them names and all of that to match our C or for the user table.
So let's change the columns first.
We're going to change the user first name.
What else is your last name user role and all that.
Let's just type it in.
I think we're going to roll and was and that's one user name user email.
It's actually right there.
So it shows
user name
user e-mail
the user password
password right there.
I think it means anything right now.
Perfect.
Well now this plane a whole bunch of things just what we need.
All right.
And let's change the variables.
How about that.
So let's go ahead and do that right here.
Since we name it name does the same we just copy this in front of the dollar sign and we're good to
go right.
And we don't have that here so we need to make that call right.
Cote's brackets in that space right there make sure we put that dollar sign there.
All right user name
e-mail
password.
OK.
All right so
user id make sure you change the WHERE statement where user ID equals a user ID and is the user ID that
we are using right now.
All right.
Okay perfect.
If this is not now then I need right now.
So
then this is another terrible when Like I said we're now going to need that now we need to send this
information right.
So let's create that we can send this query down.
So we're going to send this.
And actually we can just say the user Kohary
as you lie Kohary.
And what are we going to send it.
We're going to send it in with a connection with Aquarion
and we just make sure that if this query does not work and we can sure that we can use a function.
So confirm that we have the function there available confirm Querrey.
If it's not available we're going out to make it available.
When me see something that's got two functions in the admin and is actually available so you're good
to go.
All right.
So let's let's check it out and see what what kind of errors we get if we get any.
Perfect.
Let's call it swabbies of the user.
We fill you have a narrow.
All right.
We might not be picking up this ID.
So we need to check on that.
How can we miss on that right here user id say is a mistake.
Let's check take this call my out of this.
Check it out again.
All right.
First of all suave is of the use.
There we go.
That's that's.
That was a problem.
All right let's go and check out other users.
You see that Suarez.
So everything is going good.
Great.
Let's change the recall to Ricos.
Subscribe to admin and let's check it out again.
Perfit Rico Suave is let's check this.
Change this to subscribe to see what we're getting.
Perfect.
So everything is working fine we're able to update our users and we can update it from here so we can
delete them if we wanted to.
So we are golden right now if you were able to do this with me congratulations you're doing great.
Do not give up.
Remember that the more information you get the better you become.
The more mistakes you make as a developer and the more practice you get so you will become better eventually.
Right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one don't give up.
Take care.