How my students welcome back in this lecture here we are going to be adding some functionality to this
button right here right now if I click on it.
It's going to take me to a page that does not receive this information.
All right so let's go ahead and fix this.
Let's go to our co-editor and this is getting kind of crowded here isn't it.
So I'm just going to delete a couple of things here ladies right.
You know we don't delete the files.
This is just the leading.
Well we've got in our walking file section so on just clicking this a lot here I want you to do the
same where you have like a cleaning area that you can work on.
Now what I want you to do is go to admin underscored navigation.
And here mine or my site is lined a 47.
This is a type of part that I want to take from here since we already have this link right here and
that's the link that we are going to be airing right here because we want this to go to this page right
here.
If I add post.
That's what we wanted to do.
OK.
Just to make it easier on us.
All right so let's go back and we are in admen underscore navigation that BHB and that includes filing
at me right in the main folder.
So I just going to copy this link to be honest with you right here just a source.
Here we go.
I'm going to go back to to view all posts inside including admen and then double click it to have it
appear so that I can play around with it.
And I'm going to go to that for me is 85.
And this is where I want to go ahead and paste that piece of coal there right.
You make it bigger for you so you can see where I am.
Sometimes what you can do if you can't find this area right here because we have a lot of cold just
press Command F and that's going to open this window here for you to look for.
So you can look at this document.
So they say I want to find this area I just say you know what this button right here.
Let me go back so I can show you these bone dry years.
It has a value of add Neal right that we added to it.
So I would just press command C F to open the Finder or command or control F for Windows users.
Remember I'm mean a Mac.
OK.
So every time I say command for Windows users it's control.
So press command for control F and then look for that button there for that key word as new as you can
see it highlights a way when we find it.
All right.
So make sure that you pays that you are out right here.
OK.
Save it.
Go back to it and let's check it out to see if it works.
This refresh it and add new.
Perfect.
All right.
Now we have that possibility from that site also besides this functionality right here right.
We also have working out a new polls from there.
Perfect.
All right.
I think we're done with this.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Keep it up.
You're doing fine.
Just take it one step at a time and you should be able to learn a lot more in this course.
Take care