Welcome back my students in this lecture here we are going to be improving our CMOS a little bit.
I want to show you a functionality that I want to improve.
I hope you're doing good and having a great day because I'm having an awesome day I have a chance to
teach you something new today.
So what I want to teach you is let's go to you will post right here I want you to pay very close attention
to these comments.
Number right here.
All right.
Now if I go to the front of the side I'm going to right click and go there and I click on many of these
post pages.
All right.
You can see that we have a title here that we need to remove.
That's one improvement and another improvement is that we are also going to be if I click here you can
see that this is empty right.
We don't we don't see anything we're not letting the user know that they can't do that.
They can i just click here and Swaminathan we have to let them know that this field cannot be empty.
Right.
So we've got to let them know that with some javascript we are going to be using BHB to produce.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let me show you what happened to this number.
If I click enter you can see that number increased.
Right that is a problem.
I'm going to show you the problem how that is happening.
So in your root directory and you see a mass folder go to post up BHB which should be very close to
index that BHB and find this if set create value right here.
All right.
Well the problem the problem is that when we click the form by the submit button or this query gets
executed and he's not checking to see if these fields are empty or not.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's go ahead and checked to see if the schools are empty or not.
And all this stuff here that we're finding or we are improving our site is being left by me intentionally
because I want you to learn new features.
All right we can well of course from the beginning do all these great things and you know and build
this.
But but then you won't learn how to actually improve your CIMS you will learn how to do the first time
just one way and that's it.
You know you know you won't be learning but if you build a system if you see a system like this and
we keep improving it then that means you use your mind to be creative.
All right.
And and then he helps you see problems and fix them.
So anyway does my whole idea hopefully you agree with me.
OK.
Now you can send me a message and let me know.
But I've been teaching for a while I know what works for my students or how they can learn better.
So I think this is very beneficial for you.
So anyways so if it's said here we need to actually provide another statement and that's how I want
to do it.
There are a couple of different ways of doing it but this is actually the best way for you right now
for this system.
So I'm going to create another statement here and I'm going to check for these fields to see if they're
empty or not.
All right.
So first I want to actually cut all this because I don't want this to run on unless we first check actually
hold on.
Let's just cut this one off and put it right here right because we need this before the IF statement.
And let's cut the rest and paste it in between the statement.
All right.
So that's going to be the Querrey or the wiring there all right information from the form is going to
be outside.
So how we're going to be checking to see if this feels empty Do you remember a function that I use very
simple function as a matter of fact has the name of where we want to do.
All right so let's use this knot and then let's use the empty function.
Let me just make this a little bigger so you can see that we go.
I think that should be visible for you.
Put this to the side here.
All right.
So if it's not empty was not empty the comment.
All right then we are going to be using that and Procyon here a couple times right twice.
This means.
And for those of you that forgot already I'm just going to copy this and paste it here a couple of times
and then just change the name of it for the e-mail.
When I checked for the e-mail field and for the content field.
All right.
So this is not empty.
Then we're going to run on this square and this is going to happen if not then let's go ahead and do
on if statement and let's do it before we finish that if set create come and here right here else.
So here I want to show you on a really neat trick with BHB and Javascript.
For those of you that don't know javascript you should know javascript is super useful.
I got a really good course on it right.
So let's go ahead and open source script hacks just like we doing actually e-mail and descript of course
I'm going to be dynamic right.
So I'm also going to be using on a function call alert and some single quotes here because it will put
double cords you know we will close your statement before it happens.
So let's say fields cannot be empty.
All right safe.
Let's go back and check that out.
All right.
So I'm going to refresh this here.
Whoops.
We have an error here and 77.
OK.
Let's check it out real quick.
I might have forgot so then you probably saw.
You didn't tell me.
Right.
So two two.
Let me just make this morning because I can see where I make the mistake.
It says 77.
If it's not empty.
I made the mistake right here for I forgot the ampersand twice.
Here we go.
It was easy.
Boom boom boom boom boom boom.
If I click here we get this super Bhatra he says fields cannot be empty so we got some javascript helping
us right.
Beautiful.
That is just beautiful.
So now if we go back to outman I'm just going to reichlich angle and go there.
And we go to the polls.
This is not going to be incremental because jousters stopping it.
Click again.
Come come back here.
Refresh.
Nothing.
All right so perfect.
So we learn a new feature here for those of you that are happy with what I'm showing you and with all
this improving and for features.
Please take the time take one minute of your time and write me a review help me out.
Create more lectures and more videos for you more courses in the future.
All right.
I'm planning to create a lot of horses right now and I need your support.
So for those of you out there that like it just take one minute of your time.
Thank you so much.
And I see you in the next lecture by