High on this video I want us to learn a little bit more about comparison operators and logical operators.
We have used them without knowing what they really are.
And I want to introduce you to them.
So let's go ahead and let's open our coeditor.
I think it's a lot easier for me to show you visually what they are.
So let's grab the blank that be and then do a Save As and call this comparison
operators.
Even though I'm going to show you two kinds of logical ones and the ones that we use for comparison.
I said matter of fact I just made a page here that was useless.
There's two of those save as I'm going to call this comparison because we need to add the PH P to the
end of the page.
If not this does not work.
Comparison of paraders that Ph.
There we go.
And I'm just going to delete this.
All right.
Let's go back to the file.
All right so let's open our BHB tags here.
And of course I need to include that.
OK.
Well our comparison operators are right so I already did a little bit of a stack of mail here that I
want you to have in your exercise files and you will have this file.
Is going to be called comparison operators of course.
I'm going to comment this.
So you could see it on the browser.
So I'm going.
I'm going to explain it to you right now.
So these are a comparison operators right.
We have the equal we have the identical right.
So we would say if something is equal to or identical to we would compare it.
For example we say this is greater than less than greater than or equal than less than or equal to or
less than or greater than.
Right.
This is not with exclamation not equal to.
And this is not identical.
All right.
We already use this.
Here we have not used any of the other ones.
So I just want to show you a couple here.
So now now that we have that let me show you the logical operators real quick before I show you the
example.
All right.
So let's just take these comments here.
Let's come back here fresh from.
You don't need to refresh with brackets.
All right so the logical operators are very simple.
We use it and this is to compare two conditions and I'll touch on that right now and then or I'm going
to show you that with an if statement and they're not right.
So it's going to jump into the cold and show you how they work.
First let's start with the comparison operators.
You're going to use them in loops you and I use them in many different parts of your code.
Let's go ahead and comment on this because I won my BHB to be on the top line there.
Actually I'm going to go all the way down there so that we don't have that.
There we go.
Remember that space really doesn't matter.
MP It should be all right.
Some programming languages might complain but this BHB does not.
So let's write in this statement.
All right now that we know how to write in this statement and let's compare something let's compare
two numbers.
Very simple if four is less than four.
I want you to call this out.
It is true.
All right.
Very simple.
So let's go to the browser refresh is not going to execute because four is now less than four.
What about if four is less than or equal than four.
Now is executing because it is equal then also right.
So what about if 4 is
the same.
Is equal to four.
This execute it is equal to four.
All right what about if it's bigger.
No.
If this moner No.
What about if it's not equal to of course is not executing because it is equal to.
All right but if I change this to five then now we know that four is not equal to five.
All right.
Now what about the identical
same right now for a.
Here it is identical four and four is identical.
But what about when I put it I make it around the string.
Now it's telling me it's not identical Why.
Because this is a data type of string tetes and this is a number and integer.
So they are not identical right here.
They are the same BHB looks at and say OK you have a string here would have four inside that school.
That's the same.
But if I say identical BHB says no no no no no no.
This is not identical because this is the string and this is a number.
Right.
So always keep that in mind.
Now let's talk about the logical operators.
So right now this is not executing because it's not identical.
Let's have a different opinion right here.
So a different choice or so we can test with with these two lines.
Here is a means or so if four is identical to four or five is less than 10 that's a cue.
All right.
So if this doesn't get SECU this or a key what key we're here was not here.
But you see it with this symbol is saying if this does not work then we can try this one out because
it says if four is not identical to four or five this is less than 10 then it's AQ this.
Now the end is a different animal.
And it's like this.
Now both for this condition have to to be true in order for this to.
Therefore has to be identical to four and it fires to be less than 10 to execute.
So if I make this like this for now I was executing right now because Foy's identical to four and five
less than 10.
So did both of these conditions are true.
We executed caught him right in between there right.
So keep that in mind that's the way you write it down.
I'm going to leave this house here for you in the course exercise files and I will you can have kind
of a reference here I want to come back and check this out.
All right.
I'm going to probably write out a couple more statements below just to show you those examples that
we did.
And when we're done here so hopefully you were able to learn a lot on this lesson here and for some
reason suntanned not using understand that 100 percent don't worry.
We're going to be practicing there's an implication that we made for this course and it's going to be
fun.
Right.
So take care and I'll see you in the next life lesson.
My