Hi welcome back on this lecture here I'm going to show you how to build a functionality that will take
us to a different page.
All right.
Where for example when we click on this number here we want to create a link here that when we click
it is going to take us to a page where we're going to have all the comments related to this specific
post or any other specific polls right.
So let's go ahead and build that right now.
So the first thing is go to your view or post page.
Let's create a link right here right.
We'll put each ref close it down.
Make sure that you close down your anchor tag.
And if you come back here and refresh you can see that you have links now.
Right.
So now the next step is because we want to take a DE.
They use it to another page but on that page we want to pool pooled information from this specific pools
rifle pool the comment.
So we need a GET request to you know say hey listen this is the common idea right here.
I want you to pool the comments related to this post.
All right.
So don't use me.
Some of you already understand what I'm trying to say here right.
So on the next page we're going to pool all the comments for any of these specific folks.
All right.
I think I just said it better like that.
Right.
So what we need to do here is we need to create a loop in.
We need to loop through that table and pull out all the comments related to this post right here.
Right.
So we'll see in my ask you apply fetch a right and we'll fetch the results right here.
And then what we need to do is we'll pulao that Id become an ID for that specific comment right.
All right with a semicolon there make sure that you create another variable here so that way you can
put it somewhere down there.
So we're going to create a page called comment that BHB in a minute we're going to pass in a parameter
like say ID for example and we'll put in this common ID there.
So that way we have our requests so that we come here after we save it.
We click on this and if we click.
You see that it takes us to this page comment that BHB ID 7.
All right.
So so now we got to create this comment page.
All right so we got to do a next lecture make sure that you got this on the control that you got this
down pack too.
Right.
So anyway thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture