All right welcome back my students.
So I want you to go to your admin in the HP file right.
This is what we're going to be actually writing this and we can write this here and wrap it up and put
it in a function right and which I suggest you do that so that you can keep this clean.
All right.
So the first thing is we're going to open up the tags.
All right we're going to create a variable and then we're going to catch a session here like this with
a function called session ID.
Basically this function here is just going to have the ID of any users any user that looks into the
our admin area or index.
Right.
Basically we already have a session started right.
I don't believe using admin or something like that.
So every time we start session right now this function is going to catch the idea of that session right.
So if I open chrome I'm going to have a unique session id if I open fire fighting and have another session
ID.
All right.
And if you don't remember how sessions work you need to go back to the foundations on discourse where
I talk about sessions.
All right.
Super simple.
But anyway.
So we're going to have a variable that holds that information then we're going to have a variable that
holds that time like this and we're going to create another variable here that says time out in seconds.
All right.
And this is just the man of time that you want the user to be marked off line.
So in our case we want to set it to say let's have a simple 300 is going to be equal to five minutes
and I'll show you in a minute how we do that.
So I'm going to make it equal to 60.
All right that's going to be 60 seconds.
So that when we do that is let's create another variable here and we're going to do some math.
We're going to call this time out.
All right.
And all we gotta do is mine is that with this time on insects and that's just going to give us that
timeout variable that we need.
All right calculation.
So now the next step is is that we need to actually count.
All right.
The users we're going to need to make equerry So let's go ahead and make equerry and let's say selects
0 from users on line.
Right.
So our table where session equals session.
All right want to make sure that that's the correct user.
All right so once we have that then we say you know what send the Kohary
might ask you a line where we put a connection right here of course always and then we send in the query.
All right.
And then we say you know what.
Just count it.
And this use a function as your line rules for that there we go.
So now we have the count right.
How many users right.
So now we say if the count is equal to no which means nothing is there now even an industry and just
nothing.
My ask you a lie will go here and we say and we can make the inquiry right here.
We want it to.
So I'm just going to make it right away.
I'm going to say you know what connection just to make a short and then we say insert into users on
line.
The Apprentice is here and the values are and this is again I will say I want to answer this.
In the session field and the time I went in search for those things the time
and the session that we go I actually had to make sure that you got it in the correct field OK.
Session and then time there on the line you're going to put the wrong information in the wrong fields.
Right
else.
All right.
That means that we already have a user logged in.
Right.
Right here let me explain this a little bit.
Actually limitedly this will do this in the next lecture.
Let me explain what we're doing here.
So basically we are counting.
See if anybody's on line right.
If nobody's on line then we're going to insert that time.
That means I mean it all on.
All right.
Sorry about that.
If for some reason we find out that my issue live known Rose is equal to none.
Right.
That means is a new use a slogan.
We are going to be inserting the time and the session to that table so that what we're going to keep
track of the user with the time in the session.
All right.
So in the next lecture We'll continue with the statement.
But make sure that you understand this.
All right.
Very simple.
So anyway thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.