Great.
So are you guys ready.
Let's do this.
So the first thing that we are going to be doing is creating a table in our database.
OK.
So let's go to our CMS database going to create a new table and tackle this likes and we're going to
have a couple of fields.
The first one is going to be an ID of course we want to keep track of each individual like let's create
a autoincrement.
And the second that would be maybe a user ID just to keep track of the user doing this OK.
And the third one would be maybe a post ID to make sure that we know which bosy was light.
So once we do that let's click safe and KLISE done.
OK.
So let's start playing around with this.
So we're going to have to Reisen javascript but I don't I don't want you guys to get scared ok.
This is going to be pretty easy.
OK.
So basically we are going to be sending a request via Ajax to the back.
OK and we are going to be updating the polls and you know basically updating our likes to as well.
So right here below the footer are going to be writing so.
So Jake where we just because we already have Jay Querrey there is just going to make it easier for
us to do OK to do javascript.
So
Bob before we do this let's actually create the buttons that we are going to be meeting in our seamless
shoes me.
And let me just get this here.
I believe its here.
The first polls doesnt have an image so we need to maybe fix that too.
OK.
But I'm just going to log in real quick and I don't believe this database has my info.
Actually it does.
OK so let's go to the first post.
I'm going to edit it a little bit and just to make it look better.
And let's go to this guy here.
And came actuaries publish this put some maybe some data.
So I just want some lowering apes in there.
OK let's do that.
Images are already updated.
Let's look at the Post and the image is not working.
That's fine.
Let's go ahead to the code and find out why that image is not working.
So what I want to do is I want to go to the polls and let's see where we have that image the image is
right here.
So this is going to make the link like this let's go back and refresh and
it's going up or are Konsole real quick it says they failed to load the image.
OK.
Well I don't think I have my path correctly.
See mass and the images is in PSI.
And this oh maybe the image is not there.
OK.
So
says come back here the image is number B W D for so it looks like an image is not there.
It wasn't upload it.
So let's go back here again and let's figure out why this image did not overload
and up the post again.
Come back here now the image is there for some reason.
I didn't do it right the first time.
So.
All right.
So we have a post and we want to link right here.
So let's go and create that
we're going to do this right.
No content here.
And let's go ahead and start playing around with this a little bit and see how that looks OK.
We can fix the guys.
I want you to pay very close attention to this.
We are going to be fixing our polls up that BHB page.
We're going to be refactoring all this code and we're going to make some helper functions are going
to help us not just in this page is going to help us along our whole application OK.
I'm telling you right now we're going to make this speech really nice.
We're going to fix this prepared statement.
I'm going to show you guys how to do really awesome things with this mess.
Guys this is a thing you guys I want you guys to learn as much as possible and I want discourse to keep
giving you value for your time and your money.
If you pay for this course.
OK.
So don't worry.
Just follow me along and you can learn a whole bunch of different things.
OK.
So let's go ahead and create a link right here.
So I'm going to create a role for us and we say here a paragraph and maybe inside this paragraph a link
that says like or something like that.
OK.
Want to give this maybe a class of pool right.
Remember I'm using was scrub three with this course.
OK.
There we go we have this like right here.
So maybe we won a nother def down here where if a class of clear fits for bootstrap let's just organize
this a little bit.
And refresh.
That's fine it's not.
And you see it's not doing much is just a little bit outside of the boundary of where I want it.
Well that's OK Will.
If anything will fit to later OK.
But that's that's a start.
That's why we won we won the like button there and we also won the likes below that like the amount
of likes.
OK.
So let's make another here.
And let's go and continue with this let's see.
So here we just going to say likes and we're going to put 10 for now.
OK.
And this doesn't need to be a link.
So let's take that off the slate.
And this refresh and you can see that it says 10 likes.
OK.
Now there is another thing that we have here before the link which is a little thumbnail right now a
thumbnail.
A little thumbs up button.
OK.
So we need to create this ambusher has a really cool class that allows us to do that.
So before the bar and before this here before this word actually I'm going to create a spam and inside
spam.
Actually let me just give you the class right here I'm going to give it a class of delight let me see
if I remember how to spell it as it's spelled the s.
So glyph I know glyph spell this and then I can.
OK.
And then there is another class called glyph again and then comes
up and we are going to be making this dynamically.
So don't worry too much about it.
OK.
Because we're one of these plays that display they like or their own like if you know depending on what
we have in the database.
So let's go back here and refresh and we don't see anything there yet.
So I may one of these so life icon and the life.
Oh I forgot that I can hear.
There we go.
And look my IDs even helping me how I I make that mistake.
So you can see we got a little hand there and you know will we can make that bigger if we wanted to.
All we have to do is you know attack the foreign mailman with some fun size and make it bigger like
100 pixels.
All right.
So that's how you make it bigger.
You know targeting is a fun size.
So I'm pretty sure you learn a couple of things in this lecture here are you guys ready to take it to
the next level.
I am so in the next lecture we're going I started writing on Javascript just like we started down here
but you know I figure we just write for the memoir cup and then we start playing around with it.
So see you in the next lecture guys.
Take care.