All right so we have created a common stable and in of some data in there what we need to do is actually
display that data in the admin.
So let's go to the admin.
If you click on the comments we're not going to see anything.
So what we want to do is we want to have the same amount of information we got here want to have a similar
table like this and we want to be able to do the similar things like we do with this view ports
table.
All right.
So let's go here and what we want to do is copy the page proofs that BHB because this post table has
some other functionality that we care about we like this we need to remove this nice 200 there but any
place we want to copy this and make it come and start BHB right.
Let's do a save as on this page let's call it comments because we want to do some some of the same functionalities
comments that BHB and the default is of course going to be View or comments.
All right.
Instead of your polls of course we're going to make that page right now as a matter of fact let's just
copy this right here.
But let's save this document right here.
And all right.
That's about it.
That's right now we laid on we we're going to start adding some more cases here.
But let's go ahead and create that in the includes.
Right click on it.
This create a page called view from your comments that BHB you see me creating here in the left say
enter.
All right.
So let's have all the view of polls information there.
So they do control or command a copy.
Let's go to viewer comments and Bastet.
Let's see what we get when we go here to comment.
There we go.
We got some information as we get from all post.
That's a good sign or a very good sign.
That means it working.
All right so I'm going to actually cut this video off here and on the next video we're going to start
building this forum especially for comments right.
This table or the querying everything.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.