All right welcome back my student in this lecture here we're going to be improving our registration
system a lot more right now.
The way we have a is this way if somebody registers right now with the same name as a user we already
have in the database they will be inserted in the database.
So for example right now we have a user name Rekos Swaby Insan or whatever.
So let's actually create another recall use user real quick.
And so that you know that this works.
Oh sure you actually let's just make a record.
There we go.
Register now says the registration has been submitted.
All right.
Does it say that it was good but he says it was submitted as you can see here we are able to put to
have the same user name in the database which that's something that we don't want.
Now we could however create a column here that has only only a ceps a unique ID or only sets a unique
value we could do that but we could actually write is it right this thing or BHB code so let's try it
in write using our BHP code and see how we can build the functionality that we allow was to check for
duplicates.
All right so now we have this function here is admen That's pretty cool.
Really cool but this function is going to be a lot quicker than the admin.
All right.
So let's actually start doing this.
So we're just going to name it user name exists and of course it's going to take a user name.
All right.
And let's just create the full value for actually we don't need the full value for it.
And let's use
this one sure should shouldn't have the full value either.
Let's just put it like this.
I wanted you just to show you that we could do that but that's fine.
All right.
So how can we start this.
First of all we need our database connection right.
Then we need to create a query.
So let's hold our query in this very well.
We usually do.
And let's just say I want to select the user name from users where our user name is very similar to
this.
As a matter of fact we can copy this if we want to use to make it easier on us.
There we go.
And instead of doing all this well we can do is we could instead of doing this that we're doing here
we're going to do something a little bit different.
We're going to say I want to check I want this function my ask your line Gnome rose to let me know how
many rolls of this if we are we are able to find something like this dysfunction.
He would give us the rose in our table.
How many rolls he found.
So we're going to pass in the resoled and if the roll in the database is bigger than zero we know we
found something right.
So we're just going to say return TRUE
else we know that we didn't find anything.
And I mean we've got to return false.
Let's just put the in force here.
There we go.
All right cool.
So now this function is done.
Actually we need to change this for user name so like user name from users.
All right.
This seems about right.
So it's time for us for us to test this before we go ahead and do this.
Right now we have this functionality in registration that BHB Let's take this idea here and we have
basically we just have this little check here.
But we're not really doing anything big here.
All right.
Let's see if we can
let's do it up here.
We're using a message so we're going to use this message very well to display something I just want
to do like this just to show you that it is working or that it should work.
So I'm just going to see if we're going to use the name of that function user exists and we're going
to pass in the user name then we want to display something or we want to set a message and then I send
this message to this user.
It's all right
let's try this real quick.
I say Rico and trying to register here.
It just feels can be empty.
All right.
That's because we have order.
They will have to pass for this to say to say that message.
All right.
That's fine.
So I'm going to say Rico whatever here and whatever register
this contain this should not contain a symbol.
Yes.
User exists as you can see here.
You see that.
So it was able to find the user.
Now if we tried another user for example our own W W W and W W W would G.M. I would try this user.
Well first of all has our own defined message because we took that out.
But I want to show you that I do that it does work refresh.
And as you can see here we were able to register the user because it's not a duplicate.
All right.
So in the next lecture we're going to finish this up and we're going to actually we're going to fix
this up a little bit a lot more.
And we're going to make it work with all the inputs here.
We're going to build a pretty nice registration system.
We want.
We want to also check for email just to see the e-mail exists so we're also going to do that.
And that's lecture's All right guys.
So this should give you a pretty good idea how to do the next one for the e-mail.
All right so if you want to go ahead and do that for the e-mail you're welcome to do that.
We're going to do that in the next lecture anyways.
All right.
We're going to finish some of the modifications see and registration that BHB.
And we're also going to create a new function for e-mail.
All right.
See you in the next lecture.