All right welcome back on this video here I'm going to show you something really exciting.
All right.
Well we are going to give you an introduction to a tool called P-H be my admin is going to allow us
to manage databases create delete them edit them do many things with it right.
Well most importantly is that we are getting into databases databases that really is a really exciting
topic.
Right.
So the first thing that I want you to do is open your browser.
I'm going to show you how to go here by manually loco's for Slash BHB my at me like enter and this is
going to take it to the tool here and that's you can see we have many different options here.
All right.
You going to give you a couple.
I'm going to give you a little tour here of other options but here just know that you will have all
the databases here at these default databases.
All right don't touch any of these.
A little more advanced than the what I'm showing you.
So we don't need to really go into this.
So here when you create a database to here so you put a name on the database and you click Create your
database is going to show here is going to show here on the left side we can type in the command manual
if we wanted to create a database so we can say create database or user and we will create it for us
when we click go.
If you know as well we can actually we can check the status of network traffic and all of that stuff
right here.
We have more is I mean is a tool has a bunch of information here.
This would be another course only on its own.
All right.
If this course has I don't know how many lectures already this will be a course as we as much lecture
or more.
All right.
So databases are totally different animal right but we've got to get we're going to touch on them on
this course here a little bit.
All right.
So here we you can check the uses of databases is going to have Sunday for users with some privileges.
All right we can export databases here.
So just in case you have a database is there a database you can export it right here.
So when you select your database you can go to the store and get to select that data was automatic that's
going to tell you we are exporting this database here you're going to click.
You're going to get the file in that as well format and then you can import it right to another database.
Right.
So for example you create a database here called database 1 right.
You do some stuff to create some tables inside of some information and then all of a sudden you want
to replicate that somewhere else.
Or you want to back it up or something whatever you make another big database called database to you
select database too.
And you go to import.
Well first you select the database one then you export it.
So you've got the file on your computer called you know database one that ask you well then you select
all the database database too and you go to import.
And here you will import or you choose a file and then once you have the files here then you can click
go.
And then you will import all that data from database one to that database to really awesome.
You can check the settings of this tool here.
Features equerries and all of that great stuff replication variables.
I mean this is a little bit more advanced than what we are doing here but just know that this information
is here what we're going to be using is this database tab right here.
And that's about it.
And we're going to be probably using users to create users but we've got to create a database.
We're going to create a couple of tables inside because what we're going to be doing in the next story.
Well I'll let you in on the next on THE NEXT VIDEO.
We're going to be doing but on this video here I just gave an introduction of BHB my admin and now you
know your way around.
And on the next video we're going to build on that all right.
So hopefully you will enjoy this little part of my as well because we're going to be creating my Escurial
database right.
And it's going to be awesome.
Right.
So anyway I see you next.
And that's lecture and take care