All right welcome back my students in this lecture here.
We are going to be logging in our user.
All right.
So in the last lecture we looked at how we implemented what.
Right.
We actually we implemented the new password system that we're going to be using right with the password
on the score hash function right there.
And we provided a cost.
Right.
So let's go to a log and THP which is in the front page and the front end and we got I don't know what
you got here by now.
Some of you are having issues with the crypt functions and some of you are not having issues and you
already got it down some of you have tried something else.
All right but we're going to be implementing our new functionality here which is going to be a lot easier
guys.
All right.
So let's go out here let's go to home site and create a new user I'm going to create a new user call.
I don't know.
Peter you already have a user named Peter sense is an easy name.
Peter G-mail dot com.
And one two and three.
The password register.
All right so now let's go to admen checked the user Peter.
All right is it user name subscriber going to make him an admin.
All right.
So let's go now and implement this.
So the first thing that we're going to be doing here is that we don't need to know this stuff here.
All right we're not we don't want to compare on this stuff but we want to do is actually this is going
to take me to end it.
So if it's not this is going to take me to end and.
That's OK.
All right.
This is OK right now if user name not the user name and password now that is going to take me to it
and it's you know what.
Let's just take all this out of here and just make this if you now take this out of here.
Also what I want to do is use a function called Password
verify.
All right.
And basically this is going to take two parameters.
The first line is going to take the original passwords is coming in here.
Right.
And it's going to take the D-B password right here.
He's going to compare it.
Right.
And I think yes that's where it is.
That's what it is.
So if we are in if we were able to verify this and everything is working then we can log in the user
right.
So
here let's look at what we are actually selecting from the users.
Right now we are selecting the user name.
All right.
So we are selecting all users where username is this user name here.
So he's going to bring back the record with with the name of the user and in that we type in box.
And then there we check for the user's name password to see if if it is true.
So this function is going to return true or false if it's true we're going to run all this script and
if it's not then we run this script.
All right so let's save it.
Let's go and try it out log out.
We created you new user.
His name was Peter and his password was 1 2 and 3 enter.
And there we go.
Beautiful right.
So let's go here and refresh and let's see that new Peter person right has a encrypted password.
All right.
So we can also create new users.
So now every time we create a new user we want to pass will also be encrypted.
So we want to include that in the User page also.
All right so make sure that you put that functionality there.
We're going to do then and that's Letcher and if I don't do it you already know how to do it.
All right.
So don't be lazy and do it anyway.
Thank you so much for watching.
Hopefully this system is a lot better than what you learned before.
And if you were having issues without one now you are not going to have any issues again.
You are awesome.
See you in that net.
The lectures