All right so now we've got the form now we need to get that data out there and submit it to our database
and do or queries with it.
Right.
So now that first before we go on let me just say congratulations you're doing really good if you are
in this section right here you are one of the few that have made it this far and you should pat yourself
in the back right now and say you know what I am really really good.
I'm a dedicated person and I will complete this.
All right.
I'm telling you doing great.
I am really really proud of you.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and continue with this course here.
What we want to do is we want to create that page and we're going to create it.
We're going to do a Save As and let's go to that includes sidebar and we're going to do a Save As we
don't really need to do a save as we can just go ahead and right click on includes and create a new
file there and this includes the includes inside the inside the root directory.
OK this is not the wanting admin.
This is the one inside.
They include the root directory.
Let me just show you real quick CMOS and then this includes right here.
Right.
So we created that lawyer right now.
Perfect.
Now we need to include something here so we need to so we can make it work.
The first thing that we need to include here is the
database.
All right.
And we already have this database right here.
As a matter of fact inside the same folder right here on the left side.
See it.
All right.
Because we're going to be using this database here.
Now the first thing that we need to make sure is that we are receiving some data from the data from
the form right from that site.
Our long form that we have right here.
All right.
We need to make sure that we are receiving it by checking this value right here.
And of course we can check all the rest of the values too.
So let's go back to Logan that PH BE Let's open our BHB tags and super happy that you're here and you're
still you know doing this course.
So we're going to say if is set equal to underscore post re what are we checking here.
Remember that Logan.
Right.
And if we find that we're going to do something with it we find that we're going to just like we've
found it for now and then we're going to do the rest.
But right now let's just make sure that that's working.
So I'm just going to put my cursor they click enter for refreshing click submit and we could see that
it says found perfect.
So we're getting some data out of it.
All right so now what we need to do is get the rest of the.
If you go back to where we got some name you've got this password value here and we got this user and
we need to pull that out of there so that way we can use it.
So let's go to Logan and this copy this post here.
Let's do a couple of times.
Let's close it.
Let's change a value and size for the first one is user.
The second one is password perfect.
Let's change it to variables and it's called this user name.
That way we can use a way other things array than password.
Let's equitable to make sure that we are getting those those values there.
Right.
Once we test this out and we can continue with the rest of the form.
So let's just say Edwins here and I'm just going to say pass here.
All right.
I suggest you never use this password DHing password.
All right enter.
You can see that addling and then passwords.
Perfect.
All right so it is working now that we are getting some data we got to continue cleaning up the data
before we put it in the database.
I'm going to show you in the next lecture how we do that.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching this lecture I we're going to make a short and sweet and I see it
and that's one take here.