Or write welcome back my students.
So in this lecture here we're going to continue to build our pagination system.
So what's next.
We already know the count.
All right let's go ahead and call this out for us and find out that it is working.
All right who you wanna keep writing without knowing we are getting our count.
So let's ekal our count and find out exactly how many posts we have.
All right so let's go here and now you can see I saved it by the way RAYOS keeps saving it.
We see that we have 42 posts available.
All right cool.
So how can we actually find out.
All right.
How can we create like a page type of functionality right.
Well if we want to find now.
All right let's say we want 10 items per page.
Right.
All we have to do is actually divide right by the count by 10 right.
So let's say something like this.
Let's say count.
Right.
And we go ahead and say count could be equal to count.
Same thing here.
Divide it by five.
Let's do five.
And now if we save it and come back here we can see that we have eight point four.
All right.
So eight point four times five equals 42.
Right.
So the thing is that the problem here that this is a float number eight point four we need an integer
because we don't have an integer.
We're going to have a problem later on.
Right.
So let's make this an integer.
How do we do that.
Well we could use a function called ceiling or Seele like this.
And I think I show you this in the math section enter.
And now we got nine so he rounds it up.
All right.
Beautiful.
So what else is next.
Well after this what we can do is let's go ahead and displace all links.
All right.
Let's go all the way to the bottom here.
We got our sidebar here and we got even our footer.
Right below are 40 or less display a pagination.
So let's go here and you will I'm going to put a little class here of pager which is from Bootstrap
and is going to help us make our links a lot nicer than what I want to do here is I'm going to display
a static one for now just to show you how this looks.
So let's say this is going to be one
and this is going to be two.
Let's see if this actually looks good.
Answer.
I've got to go all the way to the bottom to show you this is crazy.
All right so you see this right here one and two.
So we got this.
We're going to have to we're going to put that produces links dynamically.
All right.
And when we click on two is going to go to the next page.
Right.
For that we need to process.
We need a loop actually to repeat stuff for us right.
So let's go ahead and create one right now.
Right.
Let's play some ph BTX right here and between this UL and let's actually use a for loop to do this.
All right.
So we're going to say I it's going to be an initialiser right.
It's going to be equal to 1.
All right we want to start one then I want we want I as long as I.
Is this smaller or equal to what count.
All right then we're going to increment.
And now here we can just call.
Nice link.
Can you say a lie and Cluseret here.
As with age referee you're also going to need NH ref so.
All right.
And let's echo this I right here too because that's going to be the number.
Remember counting is Lupin to count.
So we can see here.
All right let's go ahead and check this out.
Enter in.
I don't I don't like that we're going to have to.
We're going to have to actually limit this so that we can show it to you instead of scrolling all the
way down.
This is annoying right.
This is crawlway here.
There you go see that.
So he's starting to look OK.
Right.
Starting to look better.
Beautiful.
So he's looping through or count.
We've got nine.
Remember that we have nine right here.
We rounded up beautiful.
All right.
So the next step is that we need to send a get requests all right and depending on that get requires
that we're going to send.
It's how many pages how many posts we're going to have through page.
All right so what does it get requests.
We're going to sent what are we going to send a request to it's that BHB and the request is going to
be called Page equals what do you think Page is going to equal to.
If you guess the I you are totally correct to put the i right there.
And now if I go here and of course I'm going to scroll down and I click here you can see that he's actually
sending a request number two because I just clicked on number two right.
And if I do 5 he's going to send a 5.
All right.
So now what we need to do is we need to create a condition to the text that get requests and depending
on Dagget get requests we will change our variable dynamically and limit the amount of posts there are
showing in our home page.
Anyway I'm not going to explain any more.
I'm going to start coding and let you know but I'm going to do that in the next lecture.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching.
Hopefully you are enjoying this and I'll see you in the next one