Welcome back my student in this lecture here I'm going to show you how to turn on the feature that we
need in development to see the mistakes we make in our code.
BHB will let us know if we have some type of syntax error.
OK.
So go to your local host in your Zahm folder and go to your BHB in full.
And here we're going to have the server information I'm going to type in Command F F or control F for
Windows.
I'm going to look for display on underscore score error.
OK.
And if I maximize this you can see that I found it right here.
Make sure that yours is on all right because this is going to let us know some of you have this off.
And when you make a mistake in your syntax you're going to spend hours looking for the mistake and you
can tell what it is.
But this if he's on he's going to tell you if he's off what you need to do is you need to find your
Ph.D. Dayanidhi file and this you will find that I show you right now go to your Csound folder.
Some of you have it on the C drive because you're using Windows and I using I'm using a Mac so I have
it on applications but I use them for the day and find your PC folder.
And they say that you find your HP and I file drop it in your coeditor like this right here hear you're
going to drop it.
Get a load like this.
And then I make this a little smaller.
All right.
And then what you do is you search for it.
I press command for my co-editor and I can look for it.
And then we find this line right here.
Mine is the line 533 and you can see that my is on.
All right.
If you have it off again.
Well you need to do is if you have it like this.
Change it to ON MAKE SURE YOU the Capitol there and save it go to your control manager on zap and restart
your services.
You click here and then for my school and for patchin you store everything all right once you do that
then you can go back to to that page right here refresh.
And this is going to have to go back to BHB Imphal and make sure that when you search for Again it's
on.
All right you double check is on to make sure it's on.
Another feature is they make sure that you have output buffering on to I have with a four thousand ninety
six bytes.
Right.
If you have it all.
All right.
Go back here.
Search for it output.
There we go.
Buffering.
That's not even a look at a second time I got an on line to 64 and I have the values of four thousand
ninety six.
OK.
So make sure you change that when you output buffering.
All right.
This has output buffering here too.
For now the setting for the set of change that.
And the second one change.
OK.
So anyway you should be good to go after that.
Just make sure you save this restore your services and you are good to go later on.
The reason why we turning this on here for output buffering is because the headers sometimes sends information
when he says requests.
And we have some spacing between the header of the file when he leaves his call y space.
We have some whitespace or any that files get sent to the server.
The server gives us an error.
OK.
You can look for more information about the output of buffering but just know that we need it later
on we're going to have to turn it in turn it on manually like this.
Let me just show you right here like this with this function all be on the score star and we put it
out the hetter all the way in the first line of that file that we will be using a function called Hetter
right here this function right here is going to redirect us to another page.
We're going to use this function to do that.
And if we use this function and don't start the output buffering on that specific page later on will
we have a problem.
All right.
Always pay attention to that if you get if you will use this function you get an arrow saying oh headers
already being sent then no that's because you are using you know turning and turning this on manually
on that specific page.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture here and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care