Go right welcome back my students.
So going from the future again teaching you some more stuff about BHP.
Right.
But anyway on this lecture we're going to be learning how to actually write to the file.
We already know how to open the file and we don't have is going to create it.
But now it's time for us to put some of the information in there right.
So let's go and let's do it.
So I'm going to grab the opening files one file and I'm going to actually rename it to Aceves and say
writing files safe.
All right so we're going to have the same file here.
And remember when I told you this was a handle here.
Well let's use it.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is we're going to say give
and I'm going to put all this in there.
And I take that semi calling out there.
All right.
And then you say else
first of all we'll close this right here and then we can say something like.
We're not
could not see something like this.
Fall was not OK or the application of Education was not able to write on the file.
Something like that.
All right.
Which is why I wanted to teach you how to handle this information coming back.
So what we want to do is actually before we want it actually write to the file so we're going to use
another function call f right and it's going to take two parameters.
First the follow that he needs to access and what he needs to write.
In this case we're going to be writing like I don't know.
I love BHP.
And this is really really good stuff.
Something like this.
Make sure you use your semi-colons right.
Don't use me.
So let's save it and now let's run it.
So I'm going to go here and you're going to see there.
Let's just refresh here.
I wasn't able to run it to.
Actually we have to come to the demo right here and there we go.
And as you can see I love BHP and this is really good stuff.
So it was able to write to the file pretty cool right.
Let's go here and let's just put this one to your saved and let's come back and refresh.
Let's open this up a little bit.
I'm going to do and another side or I refresh.
And as you can see it will actually rewrite everything again.
Right.
So this is how you write two files in PHC.
And this is how you handle that information coming back with an if statement.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
Hope you're having a lot of fun and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.