High on this video we are going to be learning about arrays in arrays are something wonderful in programming
because we can store multiple types of data inside one container.
If you remember we talked about variables and we said you know variables we can we can store data in
variables but we were only able to store one single data one single value inside a variable.
Right.
Arrays are variables with super power.
That's what arrays are arrays you can store any type of data and only any type of data.
But many many times over and over again.
Let me show you exactly what an array is and it may show you how to use them.
So let's go ahead and open our coeditor now I'm going to grab that blank that BHB and then I go Aceves
here.
And like I said don't mind Mike the files that I got on the left side there just know that you have
that in your course that's the size files.
You might not have some of these files here but we believe me we will go over everything I'm going over
right now and the lecture is why you should have in your exercise files right.
Whatever you see here.
Sometimes it might not be accurate because I will delete some of these files and we'll do it again depending
if I make a mistake on a lecture or something like that.
So anyways I raised that Ph.D. that's going to be the file name and let me show you first.
Let's just open up a BHB tag and let me show you the syntax of how we write it down.
Just like the variable right.
We say that an array is just like a variable with superpower's right.
So we're going to be using the dollar sign because you know it's a variable.
Basically.
We're going to we're going to give us superpowers so we are going to be saying number list.
I'm going to name it number list right.
And the way we assigned this variable superpower to make it an array is by assigning it an array function
right.
Look at that right here.
So that looks very much like a function right.
Well it is a function you know in a way right because it has parentheses here and that's what a function
is.
By the way in ph B you're going to see a name like this and then you going to see a parentheses in a
semicolon.
Hi sorry for the interruption This is evident from the future I just want to make you aware that there
is another type of frame that is a newer way of defining arrays and is this square brackets right here.
This is the other way of doing things even though it's all there.
It is still used.
OK so you're still going to see this and I shouldn't say old you're still going to see this in some
applications because there are some uses to this.
OK.
Now you're going to see this a lot more.
So this is the same thing as this.
OK.
But with this new syntax we don't have the word array and we don't have this parenthesis.
We just have this square brackets.
OK.
So you can still do something like this.
Here is something.
OK.
Or you can still have values here is this same thing as data array on top there.
So when you see the syntax with square brackets keep in mind is the same thing as having this guy right
here.
This is just a little shorter and it's more than this.
OK.
But you can still use both.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in there in a couple of seconds.
Take care guys write functions in PH BE have it do many different things.
In this case this is going to make this variable is going to give this variable superpowers and now
we're going to call this variable array.
Now and I tell you that we can store many different values inside here and that's what I'm about to
do right now look at this all right we can do this with our raised by the way with variables and look
at this
and angle into this.
I love arrays by the way because we can do so many different things with it.
All right.
So
let me just make this a little bigger.
Here is where we can see what we are doing.
All right.
So let's just make this so that we can go to the second line there.
So let's make sure that we have a separator there and actually right here.
We go
all right I think they were good all right so we have this array here with many different type of values
in there we even have an one saying hello there.
So we have.
Now one thing I got to tell you Monterey's that we do these values here.
Each of these values are called indices in the index in an array starts with zero.
So this first spot right here of this number is in that 0.
I'm going to show you in a minute the structure right behind the array inside this page right here when
we publish it on the browser.
So let me first show you that if we go ahead and see this here we don't have anything.
All right that's a good thing because we don't have all arrows but how do we show an array.
How do we display the information.
Let's use an echo echo function and let's say let's just keep this play array.
This this number list on the screen we get an error rate to string conversion not possible right.
So we have an error here.
So how we display these data here well I already told you that arrays have indices right.
We have a name that's of zero here and it's a one two three four and five values.
So we start at zero and we have five values in here.
But we start with zero.
And the way we do that if we want to display the value on the browser we need to refer to it by the
index number and the index is zero.
And we all we use brackets around to refer to that and I'll show you in a minute why we use that.
And as you can see here on this plane to 67.
So on this plane in that zero we use the name of the array following by brackets aim side brackets with
type in the end it's this is in the series like I said.
Now let me show you what I mean in that zero.
And that's what it is.
So I'm just going to comment that out.
And I did this.
This is the same way we do it in the mail basically wearing the mail we do ladies would come and things
like this.
Right.
Well we would just use forward slash twice and that's a single line.
And I'm just repeating this my.
I might have told you already how to do this but just in case.
And for Slash and little star here with do everything until we close it like this.
All right.
And I think you do it like that on CSSA.
I believe if I not mistaken.
So anyways.
So we got this.
They were referring to let me just come in this hour like I was going to do.
And let me show you the structure of an array.
So I'm going to use a function this is a built in function in ph b cold drink.
Our right there you see the percentages there and when to put the name of this array inside here.
And when I come out here I'm going to show you the structure of it.
All right.
Didn't take this halo out of there because that's getting.
I should i got to leave it there.
That's.
Hello we have a think on the first part the last one.
So we said that we need to refer to the first item to 67 by the end that number right here.
All right you see that in this right here.
Zero.
So and it has brackets that's how the race constructor inside has brackets in there around zero.
So we were referred to it by the name of the array.
And by the brackets in the end it's zero.
If we wanted the second value here we refer to it by brackets the number one as you can see here we
can do that.
Say to print are there as is come and out by pressing command.
And the four slash or control the four slash on Windows and then do the same thing to take it off and
on to refer to it by the number one to see what we get.
We get a second value.
All right 87 65.
We do four we get 345 five which is almost the last value we really wanted to get.
Number five and we get five which is this one.
Hello.
Right.
So this is how we take information out of the array and use it very useful.
All right we can pull whatever we want into an array in arrays are actually the number one containers
we use in programming even though variables are something that we use all the time.
But arrays are going to find yourself using it a lot more.
The variable since we can hold more multiple data inside an array.
Right.
And there are different types of types of array and we're going to be talking about that later.
Correct right so anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture here and hopefully you were able
to learn some valuable information.
And I see your next one.
Take care.