Hey welcome back my students so I am from the future I came back because I had to lead the lecture that
was here before because we were installing a the editor and we said we get it's are was free and then
he became a paid plug in.
And we don't one that we want something to be free so we can install these we see week editor that's
going to make our application look a lot better when we are adding pools.
OK right now we have this empty data type of container here right.
It will be nice to have an editor that we can tell a size or create headings or link create links and
things like that.
So if you go to S.K. editor to open source editor that I use pretty cool are going to click here and
they get different versions.
I'm going to be using version 5 they have version 4 other time I'm recording this and they have pretty
easy stuff here but it's pretty easy to installed.
So all we have to do is actually get the link either download it or get a CDN link to install it.
So this is how it's going to look.
We're going to be able to do things like this OK and even create links if we want it to.
So I'm going to click download and we can use NPM know package manager or zip file folder or see the
end which is the one that I'm going to use.
And let's go back here to admin underscore footer right below.
Actually now footer header right below Jake where we are going to place that code.
OK.
So one thing that I want you want to make you aware of.
Do not worry about the extra code you see in your screen right now.
Any extra code in the sky or in here.
Just worry about what I'm showing you how to do right now we are grabbing the link the Syrian link and
we are attaching it in the heading in admin on the score header.
That's all you have to worry about.
OK.
And now make sure that you save the file.
Now the next thing is to get the code to initialize our editor.
So let's go to the documentation.
Let's go to QuickStart.
And here you can find so quick example.
So I'm going to grab this code right here.
I'm going to copy it to my clipboard and I'm going to go to Scripps.
OK.
And I'm going to just face that in here like this.
And save it.
OK.
Now the next step for us to do is to go to that ad puls page or whatever other page we are using right.
And go to that tetes area where your post content is located and in the ID actually view here right
body so our ID for that search area is called Body save it.
Go back to the scripts and edit edit this field right here to select the body.
So he's going to find any tets area that has a body I.D. that's what he's doing right now.
Right.
So now make sure that everything's safe and let's go back here and less refresh.
And now you have a really cool editor here that you can use gray
hello that's testis.
All right.
And heading here lol whatever.
OK.
And then you use publish a post and that should be it.
Again do not worry about anything else that you see here.
This is extra stuff but now you have a really cool
editor that you can use with the wig editor and now you can go ahead and start adding it to the rest
of your CMS system where you have a text area.
I'm not going to do that because you should be able to not to do that now.
All you have to do is look for any tets area that you want to include the editor and give a id of body
and that we automatically be executing okay that code will be executed scripts.
Now later on what we're going to do is we're going to make sure that our body the our document was loaded
so we're going to create something with Jake what we call document that already does this function.
This is what we're going to be doing later.
Now you can go ahead and do it now and just include this piece of code inside here and everything else
that comes after you can put it right here.
OK.
I'm just going to put a come in here and say it's her a C K or something and below here you put the
rest rest of the code.
Now this function here is a G-code functionality which allows us to make sure that the document was
loaded before we do anything.
OK.
And you can save that and that should give us the same result refresh and you still have the same results
right here.
OK.
Pretty simple.
The rest of the code meaning that next time we come to the scripts page you are going to ride everything
else below this line right here.
OK.
In some other videos you're going to see that I have another cold here like tiny MC MC the whatever
that is the other.
So we were using before and we're not going to be using that now.
So if you see that code owned then that's lectures.
Do not worry you can delete it.
You don't have to actually not only the leader you don't have to write it down.
OK.
So I hope you don't skip any lectures and you're watching this one so you don't have to have that code
right here.
All you have to because that code was for the last editor.
We don't have that editor anymore since I came to the lead that lecture because my editor is charging
us money for it.
The matter of fact I'm going to show it to you right now.
It's called Tiny and M C edits or something like that.
I think I forgot the name already right here.
So this one's the functionality we had before and they started charging money for it.
OK as you can see they started charging for it.
They got really big.
And now they're charging 10 bucks and all this stuff.
But with S.K. editor it is open source right now so it's free and there is a lot of things that you
can do with it if you go to the documentation and you click on events set up you can start integrating
more functionalities you can pass in a second parameter on that create method.
Let me show you.
You see this create this is what we got right now right.
And then you can pass a second parameter an object with a property with an array with a bunch of other
plugins that we can use to make our editor more powerful.
Ok so you can read up on the command station if you want something extra and try to build it yourself.
Anyway I want to thank you for being here.
Thank you for being my students.
I'm going to keep updating adding more lectures to this course.
See you around guys.
Take care.