Or write so it's time for us to start working on our structure.
So let's go to the root of our server right here and here on that zem server of course we have the Demel
directory that we were working on on the course here I want you to make another folder and this folder
will be use to place our CMOS system in.
So I'm going to call the CMOS and on December make sure that you're watching right now on the right
hand side is going to be a download link just like that.
Course that's the size files but this folder is going to be called.
This file is going to be called CMOS template.
I have some files there for you.
So let me just open this up right now and let me show you inside a folder.
We have a couple of files that we are going to be copying to this new CIMS folder.
Or as you can see this to see a mess folder and just going to go ahead and then select all and copy
it copies its items.
All right.
Now don't concern yourself with any other fool as you see here this is on my or my personal stuff here.
This is the full design but this is a miscellaneous folder here so don't worry about any of these other
photos that you might not have.
You don't have to have them or you have to have a mass for right here.
You just make it created you don't have to have it just create it and then place the folders that I
just placed inside.
That.
Just right.
So you're going to have once when you open that folder download it from the lecture open it up and put
the files in there you're going to see admin folders see SS funds in that's going to show you in a minute.
Well those are the reason why I created this file is for this you see now we have a template here that
we've got we can use for our site for our CMOS system.
This template is already responsive.
We don't have to deal with that.
OK.
Is using a framework called Bootstrap which I have a course on if you want to learn some bootstrapping
how to make your applications responsive how to use this framework to do exactly this.
There's a phone on line if you go online and you search for maybe
bootstrap themes or something like that.
Then you can find some themes.
All right.
And you can download administration areas you can make this I mean there are so many different things
that you can of course buy really cheaply.
And some of them you can get for free.
All right.
So that's how I found that.
I just wanted to show you that that way you can later on if you want to make another way you can.
But anyway so we have this already in place.
We have the index of our site this is the home page right here.
This is going to be the home page.
So we have that template in place.
Then we have also the poles
template where you know this is going to be the individual post.
If we go to the admin folder we have our administration right here.
All right.
So we have all these forces in place.
I'm not concerned too much about the science to be honest with you since this is more of a programming
course than anything else.
All right.
So we're going to be putting dynamic data inside these template from the database.
So now another file for you that we might need.
Actually we will need.
Let's go to the CMOS route right here.
This is the as you can see here this is the root CMOS.
We're going to right click it and make another for the cool images.
Let's just have that there let's go to admin make another folder called images.
We're going to have some new images also.
All right.
And that's about it for this for the structure.
Now let's go ahead and rename this and let's open our coeditor right here
and let's draw that this is brackets I'm using brackets you can use whatever you want but this is what
I'm using right now.
Right.
So I'm just going to take some of this and then I drop this in there as I drop and that's the whole
entire mess for They're in there.
Right.
Let's drop it in there right there.
Now we can work with it.
All right.
So now that we have this what we need to convert this into that BHB files are right in that stop B.
So let's go ahead and right click and rename it and let's just rename it to that stuff BHB
enter.
Let's rename this one also.
Right click on it.
Rename it to be perfect right.
Double clicking is going to take it to the working area right here.
So I can work with it.
All right let's go to the Admin site and just open this up and also do the same thing with this and
that's in the admin.
Rename it to and that's that BHB enter.
All right.
So let's bring this up in the actually let's go to file project settings and let's make sure that we
are in the localhost.
So we see here that we have to type in HTP local host and this would be in this mess done.
All right let's see this in action.
I'm going to write.
I'm going to click on this little arrow here on the right hand side just to display this on the browser.
All right.
So it's taking us to the page that I just clicked on to just minimize this to 100.
So you guys can see we are in the Add me on that five right.
So this is score.
Check this out.
This one here.
And let's just check it on the browser to see if that's working
right.
Perfect.
All right so this is working MP HB now.
All right so we're set.
Perfect.
So now that we have our working structure we need to go to the next lecture.
Thank you so much and I'll see you.
See you then.