Bore right welcome back my students in this lecture right here I'm going to show you how to add the
functionality of past encrypting and blogging and all that good stuff to our user page.
All right.
Well maybe now they're logging in but the actual functionality of password hashing where I need a simple
system.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Some of you got lazy and didn't do it.
I'm now very proud of you right now.
All right.
So if you want to make me proud stop this video and go do it yourself.
Don't watch me do it anyway.
I'm just taking some of these comments out of here because I'm not using it.
All right.
And I've been playing around with a lot of you know you guys have a lot of files and they just come
here and paste it and test it out to see if it works with mine and I leave a lot of stuff around some
time.
So you're going to see some different data sometimes.
So that's what I do.
I just deleted some stuff that was there.
But anyway go to your registration page and all you have to do is space here.
Right.
And then we update this here and we have the is here and now I'm going to make my costs a little lower
because I don't need this to be slowing psi.
I don't need this to be checking to you know just to do it.
So slowing side because we are in say Azmin come on if day the hacker gets inside our admin.
That's crazy right.
Our system is a super secure getting site.
We need to you know we need to implement a new system right.
So this doesn't matter much here.
So we just kind of leave it like that safe.
And now let's make a new user.
Let's go and refresh.
Let's call this user Pete William flower's name admen Let's make him an admin right away this guy gets
promoted to our admin system.
Let's call him Pat.
You know what Petey.
Just to make him not a pet and pet a G-mail Hajis.
That's called empathy.
And one two three four and five.
As a user we have added a user.
Let's go look at it.
Pity.
Pity pet.
William is anatman can we look again with this guy.
What was his password by the way.
I don't remember.
But anyway let's go to our users.
Let's refresh.
Now we see this new guy right here with a very simple password one two three four and he's already hashed
and created.
Look at that beautiful.
So let's go ahead and turn to a little game with this guy.
Beatty's is using them and get a copy it because that's a complicated use any logo based 1 2 three and
four somet.
I think we gave him some of the password guys.
Seriously.
One two three four and five.
Here we go.
That's impossible.
We gave it.
And now team is logged in in our set.
Simple system is ready to go.
Hopefully you appreciate that very much.
All right.
So Tom stay up for your instructor and see you in the next lecture.
Have fun guys.
Take care