OK so I can start with you know the back end.
Basically I could start with BHP or our I could I can start with the h the amount.
Basically what I want to do is let's just put it here.
I want to create a little bone right here that when I select it is going to change or translate whatever
I got here so I could start with a P because I already know the code but I want to start with something
physical so that way you guys can see how everything works.
Because if I start with a BHP code you guys are not gonna have a clue what I'm doing.
All right.
So let's start with that button there I want to create that bond so I'm going to go to the registration
page and basically it's not a button is a form and has a select button.
So we're gonna put it right below here okay.
And you're gonna say form
I'm just gonna do a simple form like this and it of input I'm not going to have any input buttons here
and select is an input it should and I actually set by and then I.
Sorry about that guys.
All right.
Let's just have a select here.
Complicating myself here.
So this is going to have a variable here that we're going to take to the BHP side so we can detect it.
Okay.
And let's just put some values here so you guys can see it.
Option
is put your option.
There we go.
And the value is going to be English.
And we're going to have another option is going to be Spanish Yes.
Let's just put English here and Spanish
go.
So now I'm not in that I want to do I could actually add a class here to make this go to the right.
So as a matter of fact there is a classical NAF bar form and nav bar.
Right.
That would help me out a lot.
All righty.
And this would be the form control so let's see how that looks.
What is this.
Something I got there.
Let's think come behind here.
Let's just put this in a different screen so that way you guys can see it better.
Let's refresh and now we have those two selections there.
Perfect.
So now that we have this what I want is what I want to happen here what we're going to be doing basically
is we are going to be creating a javascript code.
We are going to be put in a javascript code here that is going to send information once we do something.
OK.
So we can add it doing something like this on change.
Once this select button is changed to something else once I click it and it's selected to something
else I want some action I want something to happen.
So I'm going to call a function that could be like change sea change language or something like that
language OK.
So I'm going to have a function that's going to be called when I do this.
OK.
Language
and just give it an idea so we can pull out some data language form.
So now every time this changes and going to execute this function.
OK.
So this function could be executed from all the way in the bottom here.
So this is where I'm going to do script and I'm going to do function
and just to make sure that it works I'm going to do a console dialogue and he's going to say it works.
So I'm going to open my console right here it sure is big.
So you guys can see it when I click it.
You see now that he says he works.
Put it back there.
Another one.
OK.
So that's working that's beautiful.
So again all I do here was attach an event handler
to the form
and every time I click on select or change it is going to execute this function right here OK.
Perfect.
So we've got a couple more things that we need to do a couple more checks.
But what I want to do at the end of this and you know you guys and show you how to do this.
But what I want to do is I want to access that form by its I.D. which is the language form I believe.
Let's just check it yeah.
Language form is the I.D. of that form.
And what I want to do is I want to submit the form so I'm going to use this submit function that's built
in OK.
And once you submit it that form is going to send some data.
Where is it.
Passed it.
Right here.
So this form is going to submit the data and that data is going to be method get even though it is by
default get we're just going to make sure that it's here that is stated here OK so once it's a mix that
is going to give us some type of data in the PSB code.
OK.
But we are not going to submit the form right now as a matter of fact let's just let's just try for
the for the fun of it.
If I click here let's just refresh it.
Let's see if that form submits some data ok that my mind is not met is not a function it's given me
some arrows with that code.
Let me see what I did wrong here.
Language form submit
submit
to make sure that that's working before we move on.
Let me get.
Make sure that I got the right I.D. from here.
Oh I'm sorry.
This is not.
This is the I.D. for the select.
We need it to.
We need to give the form that I.D. in now let's just refresh it so you can see we did not get any errors.
OK.
And the reason why this is actually refreshing here is changing basically is because you know once we
refresh the page is going to go back to number one.
Right.
The reason why this is actually changing from Spanish to English right now if you notice if I put in
Spanish it changes back to English is because the pages are refreshing.
OK.
Every time the form has been submitted.
So that's why it's actually not staying there in Spanish but we're not getting any errors here.
So we're good to go.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.
Guys let's do this.