All right so we got the comments displaying the same thing as the viewer polls.
We've got the same table there but we need to do is make this table bring data about comments.
Right.
So we need some information here.
First we need the I.D. They all there that's fine.
It's a matter of fact that is totally fine.
All that information there what else do we need from the comments.
We need the e-mail so we got the author actually.
Let's have the comments right here.
I think is more important.
And we're going to be changing the header.
And by the way we are in the view on this score on the score comments that BHB inside includes in sigh
the admin.
All right.
We have the right here on top is the path.
Just in case you don't remember.
So what else we want to bring from there.
We want to bring the e-mail the status.
Actually we had it right there.
And let's bring another field in response to
that feel that we are going to be putting the title of the specific post where the comment was made
too.
All right.
We're going to see a proof here.
And this is going to be the opposite of a proof.
Don't.
We're going to be able to approve or approve comment and then delete
on other important data that we might need is a date.
Let's bring the date of the comment.
That way we know the date right.
So let's bring it up to springeth right here.
All right so we got 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10.
Well that's a lot of information here and we need to change some of this too right because we are our
columns are named differently in.
That table comment alter what else we bring it in.
Calm and content right.
Let's actually check that the table so that way we know exactly what we're bringing in coming Id impose
ID and put it right here so that I know exactly what I'm bringing in.
There we go.
That way we can see exactly what's going on.
So the comment Id comment posts ID
and what else become an an.
This just copy this one here right into this one here and into this one since we have the first comment.
All right.
Coming up Id comment author and if you want you can go ahead and you know it
says you probably can type faster than me.
I got like five screens in front of me so it's sometimes a little distracting.
Right.
So all right come in and start as an uncommon date.
All right so we are getting all those fields we don't need this here.
And let's just go ahead and make these variables come impuls ID with no hopes post
come and e-mail come in content as the comment itself come.
That is Whoops again and come into it.
All right.
That is a lot of great information there.
So we're going to be the plaintiffs in the to your role like we did for the.
So let's actually comment this is play the common ID right here pulls ID and a display that we don't
actually need to play that one as we're bringing in and that in response.
But I'll show you right now in a minute comment alter.
Let's just play that right here comment e-mail.
Should actually have the comment content before the e-mail.
I think so.
More important data right.
So we got one two three four five six seven.
All right.
And it looks good right now.
The title we don't have a title for this but we have the content
here.
What else do we got from the comment e-mail we got that e-mail.
Even though right here the content is before the image before they can't and that's fine.
We don't need to worry about that here we're making a query here on this one here so what we are going
to be making equerry on this one is going to be that we're going to select we're going to do a query
here to find the polls actually and related to this comment later on but right now let's finish up this
form.
And as a matter of fact I'm going to
comment that for now coming content.
We need the comment e-mail after that.
Whoops.
That's just the history here.
Come into e-mail
and we don't need this image here.
Let's take that out.
Come and e-mail content.
Do we have the author.
Now we don't have the alters on just going to come with it come right here.
Are content e-mail down here and status and date
and date.
All right.
And this just take this out of here we are going to be live in the edit
and delete.
We are also going to be needing proof fields so we might as well make that right now.
All right.
Going to be live in this.
You going to see a proof here
and this is just an essay on to prove
prove it in the least.
Of course when it's in different parameters here.
Right.
So that's about it.
That's all we need for this.
Here we're going to be making a different query and we're going to be selecting everything from comments
here to fix that and select comments fits that too.
OK.
So we are done.
One two three four five six seven eight nine ten.
And here we go.
Four five six seven eight nine ten.
All right.
So I think this video is long enough.
You can go ahead.
I'm going to go slowly scrolling here so that we're you composite and copy everything have done whatever
you need to copy it to.
All right.
And on the last lecture we're going to finish it up.
All right thanks a lot.
And I see your next one.
Take care.