All right so we have done some things here in the admin related meetings and organizing some of the
mail right now it's time for us to make something happen and we have a table called categories in the
database and we are going to be explained at page right here.
When we click on this link we want to go to our page and we want something to come and display here.
So we're going to be building the forms that we need.
If you don't remember go back to the lecture where I introduced you to the see a mess and see how that
looks all right.
So let's go ahead and open our co-editor and say add.
I'm going to close this and say admen fine admin.
I'm going to make a new file inside there.
Do we want to make this includes or do we want to let's just make this right.
In the end it's categories actually categories of speech.
You're right.
So let's call these categories at BHB.
And that's just in the root of the admin folder.
Right.
And here what we want to do is we want some of the data from the in that in here.
All right so I'm going to and just write
select everything here and I'm going to copy it into the categories right now if you notice here we
are missing some of we are missing the database.
All right.
So we have the database in includes in here actually.
Is it includes not includes here is and includes right here is where we need to go there and get it.
But I don't want to keep doing this over and over for every page.
Right.
So what I want to do is include this file into the head or actually of our document and of this file
just go to admin and do that on the head.
So let's go into includes And let's go to the head of the admin and we can call this admin Ketterer.
So you don't get confused we can rename it if you want.
Let's call these out.
Well let's just leave it like that.
But just in case for you so you don't want to get confused.
Make sure that you are in the admin folder and includes added that BHB.
All right.
So here I want to include that and I'm just going to say BHP is going to write something down here and
going to include this.
So we are going to include this once let's do it once I think this function should do fine with us because
one can do this once.
We don't want it to be including this all over the place.
So actually just leave it like this for now and then later on we will actually come and fix our bar
and secure our data.
But right now we don't need it.
So we know that this is outside.
So we need to go outside and find a folder called includes the B.
PH be all right because we need to go outside the admin and we need to go to another folder called includes
right.
So now let's check it to see if this connection is working.
So let's go to our admen that's.
And here I want to check on that connection real quick to see if we got a connection.
So let's just say let's open the tag here and let's just check on that connection real quick and let's
just say if connection
then we want to display something we don't actually we don't need.
If we were writing just one line we just you say echo something.
Geez if I can get it right that would be nice.
All right Con Are we just going to say con real quick just to see if this is working.
Let's go back to this refresh and we can see right here.
You can see what he's saying is in that black spot right here.
So we are connected.
All right.
So now that we are connected we need to go to that category speech and includes header categories right
here on the working perfect.
Let's go to the content of the categories.
Let's build a first form and see we have some time on this.
Build for first forne.
And this one we're going to have a diff
shelterless create a div of First we create a diff of call us with this.
Actually this is a class Bushrod class and you just get to make our diff half or the page size half
of the screen is a 12 column grid so this is a six column meaning that is half of the screen.
OK.
And here what we want to create is a form that we can add some data into our database.
All right so now that we have this here and we want to say we have a day off with a class of form group
and just trying to gather my thoughts ending input têtes this is going to be cut Title.
They just put that in there right away.
Make sure that you put this here title.
This is where we're going to be put in the title of our categories.
All right.
So we need two forms one on the left and one on the right.
So we have this div form class there is going to make or form look nice.
We also need a nother div for input and this type is going to be set.
We are going to have that name change to suit MIT and the value is just going to say category category.
All right.
And that should be enough.
And let's just go ahead and make this a little more so I can put something else in here.
What I want to put is a class just to make this look nice.
And the class is let me take this out of here where you can see I don't want you to miss anything between
the two classes primary.
All right.
And this also has a class of
its own.
Let's gather my thoughts with the class.
All right.
So this class is going to be form control and this is going to just going to make things look nice.
So let's see how that looks for now.
That's the only way we can go in.
Let's go to categories.
You've put a link here to categories.
PH B we can see we are getting there and this is this half of the screen like I said before let's put
a label on that and make it look a little nicer.
So let's just make it bigger.
Here we go put a little label on this right here and this is for cat type.
All right.
And just going to put cat title and just a little different there and category title
categories.
I'm just going to put this category there that's fine.
Let's go back to let's see how that looks refresh.
All right.
So we got the first one here right.
I'm going to leave the rest for the next video we're getting in we need to be actually one table here
on the right hand side.
And we need to be another form that we are going to be displaying with some quotes and Javascript.
All right a problem is it won't be hard.
It just takes a little time.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you on the next lecture.
Take care.