All right welcome back.
Media students so it's time for us to start actually creating our all the functionality that we need
in our registration that BHB and that is for checking the e-mail.
All right.
We already have one that checks the user name.
We need another one that checks the e-mail.
And then we're going to start more refine our form just to our registration page just to make it better
than what it is right now.
We have a lot of cold here that I would like to fix and make better.
So let's actually create that real quick.
Let's go to functions and what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy this because this email Wise's function
is going to be very similar to the user name of Jesus right.
So we're just going to say e-mail I exist this is going to take an e-mail right.
We're going to have database connection
and we're going to check the mail the user e-mail column.
This is going to be an e-mail as well.
And this is going to be the user e-mail.
All right.
Basically the senting is a very similar to let's just put this here make it a line.
So I don't see anything wrong with this one here.
I'm going to leave it the way it is.
We're going to check this anyway you're welcome to check in right now if you want but what I want to
do is I want to fix this for him right here.
All right.
I want to fix it.
I want to remove a lot of things from here and just make it a lot better.
All right.
We want to be able to.
Every time we register a user we want to be able to redirect the users somewhere else right redirect
into admin because they already register right.
Unless you want to put them in a queue where you you know you set the user manually but if you have
a Web site that kind of large you might now want to do that.
You might want to just register the user and then if the use is causing some trouble delete them or
sent them idle banned them from your Web site.
So right now we're going to register the user and we're going to redirect them to admin.
And if you know if this doesn't work we're going to redirect them back to this forum of course.
So we need to build a functionality for that.
What I have in mind is also this the head or function that we have we're doing a lot of head a redirection
like this is it will be very nice to create a little Hendee function that we do that for us instead
of us writing this all the time manually.
So let's actually build a little quick function here.
We're going to call a redirect and it's going to take a location
and we're just going to return
something from this function.
We're going to re turn this concatenate this and that's it.
All right.
So very simple to create a function call right.
What else do we need.
All right.
So let's go back to registration here.
What can we do to make this better.
Why can we do.
I want you to look at really good guys.
Would these be nice to put in a function a register function.
Something that can register the user instead of us having all this code.
Here are restrictions that BHB we should have this code in functions at BHB.
All right so let's create that let's create this register function and this function here the redirect
let's just put it all the way on top here.
So the function to have this is put it there let's go all the way to the bottom there here and let's
just create a function to register the user register a user.
All right.
And this function is of course going to take the user name is going to take the e-mail the user is going
to take the password the user password and we go very simple.
All right.
So first of all we need a global connection.
Beautiful.
And actually we have all this cold right here.
But we needed a connection.
We have all this cold here.
This is see where this ends.
These ants right here so I'm going to take all these out.
It's message thing.
All right.
And let's just take all this and see what we can do with it.
Look at that.
That's looking a lot better now.
All right guys let's put it right here and let's see what we can do with it.
Let's fix it up a little nicer and put this call right here.
Whoops
push code there.
Everything's here a little bit
more that way.
All right there is a couple of things that we're going to be doing here.
But we already have a confirmed Querrey here.
So we don't need to use this.
We have a confirmed query somewhere I just want to make sure so we don't need to see we already don't
need something we don't need this guy here.
We just need to use a function call from Querrey and then we just say register use a query like this.
There we go.
All right.
So that's even looking a lot better now.
Right.
So we just want to take this in here.
Look at that.
Looking a lot cleaner right.
All right.
So go ahead and finish this up.
All right just the way I'm doing it right now.
And on the next lecture we're going to continue cleaning this up a little more and figuring it out figuring
this thing out.
How we are we can make it a lot better than what it is right now.
Right.
So right now we are moving all the coal that was here.
Most of it by because we got a little bit left and we are putting it in a function.
But we also need to be able to register the user logged in the user and redirect the user right.
So this race or function is going to be doing a couple of things.
And I also want to Dady K or create another piece of code which is going to be able to log in the user
a swell we have this code here so we're already repeating ourselves right.
We need to log in the user you know functions that BHB and this register the user function we need to
already log in the user from here.
So we would need to write this whole function.
Again we don't want to do that.
So what I want to do is I want to take all this code out of here put it in a function so that we can
use it wherever we want.
All right I'll see you in the next lecture where we're going to be learning how to do that.
See you then.