Welcome back my student.
So we got all this up when we first started this application we had a lot of stuff that we had to learn
and we got very far.
For some of you and you Ph.D. is very large has a lot of more things to learn but I'm hoping that with
this whatever you are launching out there is secure make sure that you know all your queries you apply
this function I know we're going to keep going and we're going to do some insertions and other things
in this application.
We prepare a statement so that way you know exactly how to make it happen.
But don't put your application out there if it's not a hundred percent secure if you're not using prepared
statements.
It's not 100 percent secure.
OK.
So we're fetching here.
We've got to change this a little bit because our application works a little different now.
OK.
So we've got to come here we're not assigning a very new any more because we are fetching a statement.
Now we have a general statement now as you can see here.
So we're going to use that and we don't need to get all these data out like this here.
OK.
So
let's see if this works
data.
OK let's logon.
Now recoils.
All right.
No never.
I should have put.
Never there.
Anyway let's go to you post and I'm going to make this edit to publish
this one to publish as well.
And let's go to the front of the site.
Let's go to javascript's says no categories there.
OK let's take out this guy here which I don't like very much.
We should do that.
And what I wanted to do here is I want to take this guy out too.
And I want to put a shorthand here.
I want to make sure that this ends here.
And while we're here.
OK.
Save that and let's see
let's change this to instead of that.
Whoops what am I getting.
We go to zero.
Sure is correct.
We're going to call this out.
Let's come back and try this again now.
Refresh 109.
This song spects a semicolon to end this.
Let's go back and refresh on the five mice you fetch huh.
81 is undefined because we need to include this in there.
That's a different function.
But what else we got.
Refresh.
And now is working.
OK.
So that's work and we can see this.
And let's go to admin and make sure that he works for the other side as well.
Let's see.
Let's make one draft.
Let's go out.
Of course we're going to see this because we are admin but we will all go and we go to that.
We are only able to see one guy here.
OK.
Pretty cool stuff.
I think it's working 100 percent.
Of course it can be better.
Yes of course.
OK we can do that and make a couple of functions just to make those queries a lot easier to create again
less create and make this Polish again.
Let's go.
Let's come back here and you can see both that's working on your P.S. guys.
Here's the code again.
I'm going to make sure that I included in the new files.
Ok very easy.
Hopefully you know you guys make sure that you obey your code.
We're going to continue with this and we're going to do another one in the next lectures because we're
just fetching data here.
It would be good to see this in insertion and updating all that.
I'll see you in the next one.
Take care