Welcome back my student.
So it's tough for us to start figuring out how we are going to be sending e-mails.
Right.
So we need a third party library because we know the mail function does not work properly.
OK.
So this is the page for the library that we are going to be using and this there are a couple of them.
This is one of the best ones BHB mailer.
There's a whole bunch of functionality here.
OK.
And this is in the home page and you can get to it by just going to Google or something.
Typing BHB mailer clicking on the link and it will give us some more information.
So here's how this works.
We are going to be using a another software Webware program to download to install BHB mayor.
And the reason why we're doing that is because it's going to be easier if you don't know of a composer.
Do not worry.
I'm going to show you how to use a composer is a package manager for BHB So this very simple here you
download it and they tell you how to download it.
And then this or this or the configuration you can basically paste copy and paste into your project
and he would work great.
Make sure you change the host to your whatever.
As a.p is OK.
Your user name your password.
So let me show you let me first explain to you about composing real quick and I got it.
I believe I have a course on that.
And some of these BHB core tools just in case you want to find out some more about it.
If you go here and when you see I have of course you see
and if I go to Edwin díaz real quick let's go to my profile and should be there somewhere.
Is a free course and it's called
See what it is.
They I created that course specifically for for you guys so you guys can actually learn this.
And I think I passed it.
It's it's the tools has to be in the second page.
And now really looking guys
I don't see it there.
Let me actually go to this other web site my on my Web site actually find it free courses and BHB advanced
tools.
OK.
Here you will find how to use composer how to use vagrants.
Very important tools for development.
So anyway let's go back to the course and let's go and type in composer here
get composer that Gorog is a Web site.
Unless they change it.
If you're using Windows when you click download is going to offer you to use Windows.
OK.
Downlow the there is a lot.
It's a lie easier when you download it with Windows because he's going to give you a whole package a
whole thing to download everything with a Mac like I'm running right now from the terminal I can do
this.
OK I copy the first line and I place it in my terminal OK like this.
Well you've got a copy and paste all of it.
One by one.
And then at the end you just delete that file.
OK.
Then you have composer and store pretty cool.
But anyway so.
And there's a whole bunch of if you don't know like I said go to coding faculty that come install it.
And there's a whole bunch of tutorials about it.
But anyway that's how we're going to be using.
And if you don't have it go ahead and download it now.
And that's it.
OK let's go back here.
And once you start using right away I'm going to open my terminal and this is the same thing right here
in this ID as my term you know in the Mac or get Bash.
Oh and by the way if you don't have a terminal a command window and if you want something very similar
to Linux or Mac the one like the one I'm using downhole get bash go to get right here to this Web site
and download this little guy right here.
OK and just follow the prompts and he's going to install something in your desktop is going to stall
bash a command tool that you can use and then double click it and open it and he's going to open a window
like this.
I think it's going to be black and use that in just to send commands that I'm writing.
OK.
I have composer installed globally so make sure that you do us well.
So if I type in composer here you can see that it's going to show a retro like that.
Decide you know the date is installed.
OK.
So let's go ahead and install require.
So I'm going to use composer require a this does not work for you because composer is nine still global.
So make sure they on their page and start to compose or globally.
So this is the
command right here.
OK very simple I just wanted to show you composer require to paste it.
But before we do that let's actually actually you know what I can create if I wanted to the JSM file
with you and composer in it.
That's going to do that.
A creative composer Jason foud that we can and I'm sure actually let me show you how to do that real
quick.
It's going to when I press enter is going to ask me hey what is the name of the vendor.
I'm just going to click enter for everything under a name on just going to type in India's court of
faculty
that come closer with a greater than symbol.
Enter Antar Antar and would you like to find your dependencies.
If I click yes he's going to ask me questions I don't want to do that now.
It's going to ask me if I want to search for a package I can do this be achieved BHB Mailer and it's
going to look for it and you can see that it finds it right here.
If I press 0 here he's going to download it for me but I don't want to do it.
I want to get out of here to show you the composite that Jason File let me see if it's images come out
of there.
Enter
find out if you created the file real quick
OK you've got to actually go back.
Composer Jason and
D.S.
Let's go back here.
I don't use as much.
I think I used to maybe twice because I create most of my projects already in a different way.
It's required actually.
So yes BHB mailer so BHB made it should be the first one zero.
And actually I think it's number three too.
So zero enter no version control constraint.
Click Enter.
And now it's actually doing that for me.
And now the composite additions that Chaisson should be there for me
yes that's fine.
That's fine.
All has to be here.
There we go right here.
So now we can see the composer that Jason fow created for us.
This is the information that I put in.
As you can see now if I want to download some type of file I can say well you see that he has a dependency
here.
It's going to require ph be made right.
So let's clear this and I'm going to Taiping composer install
excuse me and it's installing now for me.
And now I have a new phone directory here with composer of course and BHP mailer OK.
And that's it.
Now I know this could be a little hard to actually do.
So make sure that you download composer.
The only problem that you would have is a few typing composer in your terminal and you don't get you
get a bass note in that command error or something like that.
That means that your composer is nine still globally go to the documentation make sure that you in Windows
I believe you have to put your own path.
You have to have a Ph besides the cuticle file in Windows.
So make sure that when you are installing and going to ask you where is the BHB that executable.
If you have a zap you can find it.
You go to the Zahm application.
And I believe he's in or something like that but it's there.
OK.
You can find it and with a Mac you shouldn't have a problem.
Very easy.
Thank you so much for watching.
And the next lecture we're going to start setting everything on with BHB mail to send e-mails.
Thank you.