Hi welcome back my dear students.
So in this lecture I'm going to show you what we need in order for us to run GHB in our computer.
Now we can.
I'm using a Mac right here.
But this is going to apply to Windows users or Linux users.
OK.
So this is a Mac computer right now.
And I'm going to go to Google and I'm going to type in zap.
OK.
Zap.
Is this tool OK this software that has a stack a stack is a program that has or some type of package
that has different technologies include it that work together to accomplish something.
In this case Zeb has Apache Maria DP for databases BHP and pro this are that stack for them.
And this is what we need in order for us to run BHP successfully in our computer.
So this is going to mimic OK a server in as you know in the clouds.
For example if you're going to go or go Daddy dot com or any other hosting provider they will have a
hosting servers that allows you to run BHP applications.
So these zap here is going to be that software behind the scenes in our computers that is going to allow
us to have the technologies that are that allows us to use BHP.
OK.
So we download it but I don't want you to just go here to any of these links and download it like a
few using windows here.
This is the right link for you if you're using limits.
This is the right link for you and if using OS This is not the right link for you if you use a Mac OS.
The reason is because you have this VM here virtual machine you don't want to download anything like
that so click on download and then look for you the latest version of Zap.
In my case a seven point three but you might have a point to nine depending on the year and the time
you might have a later version than what I have here.
But download the latest version for Windows they only have 32 bit so download that off limits.
They have the same point three download the 64 bit if you have a 64 bit machine right and you should.
And for Mac OS they have two versions the regular versions without the VM OK right here on top and the
virtual machine versions you need to download the regular ones.
This is the latest right here seven point three.
In my case just click on Download OK and you got to see this is going to start downloading down here.
Now while this is downloading let me show you another tool just in case you run into program problems
with zap because not everybody gets a smooth installation.
If you run into any problems there is another tool called map.
OK.
And it's basically the same thing as a stack as a package as a stack to run PSP on your computer and
he's going to detect if you have a Windows or Mac computer or limits and then going to give you the
link.
OK.
This this one's a little different when downloading because we don't deal too much with virtual machines
but if we click on free download here he's gonna take you to this speech and you have a couple options
download map a man pro 5.2 or download man a month a man pro four point one this is for Windows.
This is for Mac OS.
Now in the future all these pages are going to be different.
OK.
The main concept here is that you're downloading the regular versions of any of these tools just to
run PSP depending on the system that you're using.
Now my installation just finished downloading and that would be nice to know where he went.
I guess it was somewhere down there.
I'm just gonna go to my download downloads place where I download everything goes in there I'm just
gonna click on this
OK and once I have it I just double click it and he's going to ask me or this stuff and he's gonna open
it up and make sure that I put my password.
This is for Mac users for Windows using when I have this.
You might have to allow it through your firewall or anything like that because these systems they do
control your computer just a little bit.
Welcome to the set of wizard.
I'm just gonna click nets and nets and nets OK and learn more about bitten a bit Nami.
I don't think so that I don't want and I'm just gonna click nets and nets and that's going to install
it.
OK.
And it's just like any other program on your computer is going to install and then is going to be available
to you in your programs area or like.
Right now let's say you're using a Mac that program is going to be available to me in the applications
area.
So if I go all the way down to that sample folder that's where that program is all the files are here.
The manager control panel is here.
So if I double click on this is going to open it up for me OK.
As you can see is on here and I don't use campus as much as I used to.
But in this cause I am using it.
And if I click on manage servers this this is where all my servers are right now says that Apache web
server is running I can stop it.
OK.
And all you need is to service to be running to services you need may as well make sure that you click
Start an Apache start.
OK now for map this example gay and this is a very similar.
They're all going to be located in a Mac computer in the Applications folder.
So map would be in the same applications for that bullet we know for the code map and then you have
these HD docs folder.
This is where our projects are going to be located inside there are going to show you that later on.
OK something was EMP HD docs.
OK.
So e in the windows computer your map and your zap folders are going to be in your C drive.
So go to your computer go to your control panel or the file manager wherever you have your you can see
the your computer C drive click on it and you're going to see these folders here.
Zap a map OK.
And inside HD docs is where we are going to be working on make sure.
And these programs usually install a icon in here in your desktop so you can double click it and use
your control panel right here.
This.
Ok.
Where's your control panel.
This is for map.
And this is for zap.
Very similar programs.
OK.
The concept here is that you're going to have an Apache server and you got it.
Just turn it on and you're going to see this light up in here.
Now this might look different depending on the version that you're downloading.
But the concept is all the same is a program map or zap or programs that allows us to run P.H. being
our computers we download them we install them like any program and then we turn on our Apache server
service and it might as well server you see that patch you right here.
You see my askew out you turn him on start and start for some users.
You're going to have some issues with them because they use port 80 which Skype uses.
OK.
So if your your Apache server is not working is because he's using the is using port 80 right here.
So you might want to change that poor to something else maybe like just put any numbers here.
You can do board 8 8 8 or something like that.
Or maybe 80 80.
OK.
And then just click it.
And that would change that port for Apache and then you can restart it started again and then that would
work that could work for zap if it doesn't work if that gives you a lot of problems.
Just go ahead and use map map is going to take care of that problem for you guys because it's super
simple to install it but I'm using zap in this course.
So if you want to follow me to the letter you can use AMP and make it work.
OK.
But again just do a word of advice don't download the VM don't do it because it's just it's a little
different.
And he's going to give you issues is more events OK.
Virtual Machine here.
Don't download it for zap or don't download it for any of these programs if they offer it just download
the regular versions.
Zap is what we're using for this course but you are welcome to download map which sometimes is easier
for some users.
So that's Hey guys thank you so much.
Remember that we are.
We have everything on HD docs folder and in the Zap or map folders and that's where we are going to
be working on.
Now this program's just a word of advice.
Let me show you.
These programs have a U or L that we can use to see our applications.
Okay.
Remember that this is acting like a server.
So that dress here for some people is local host.
If you're downloading map like that local shows and this is where all your projects are going to be
located and you're not going to see them like this because this is going to redirect you to the opening
page of The Star page right here of map.
Don't worry about it.
That means that you installation went through successfully the same thing with zap.
OK.
ZAM has its own pages in say Europe computer locally.
So way you know that it is working.
So they offer a page are you URL that you can you know access other tools that we're gonna be using
later as you can see this is it says local hosts this is inside your computer.
This is not outside on the Internet.
OK Zam has a very similar approach.
If I turn on Apache and I started on and was in screen here I mean she's working right now he's running
so if I want to welcome page and I click visit go to application you can see that that's going to open
for me the Zap installation here local host.
So this idea is a little different than the map because map for me is local shows 8 8 8 8 and this one
is local host.
OK now remember that this is gone.
I got it.
I've got a different setup because I deleted mine.
That's for the applications.
So yours is going to redirect you to the start page OK of your program minds is not doing that.
So don't worry about as long as you see something like this like a welcome map has been stored successfully
or zap has been stored successfully once you go to local holes.
You should be good.
Don't worry about it too much here.
We are going to I'm going to go through this later on.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.
Guys take care.
Bye bye.