Or write so now that we've made that table put some data into it.
Fix the links and make the pages we need to modify a couple of things.
Our users tables don't look like our category tables right.
Of course not.
Well they look like it but they don't have the same columns right.
So we need to fix that.
So let's go to the user's view all users.
That's the first one we are going to be facing view users and here on top which you have the headings
right here.
So let's go ahead and open let's just open our DHP our users table here in the database.
Let's just put it to the side here and let's go ahead and get some of this stuff right.
So on the first one we have the ID then here we have the user name and the password we're not going
to show that of course not first name my last name
would go last name and not name name would it.
I right.
An e-mail would be nice right.
What else can we display by the user.
We can display an image but we can do that in the user name.
Sigh there so that's fine.
What about role.
Is that something that we can do.
Yeah.
We can do roll roll actually roll that's fine roll.
And that said for now we've got something else that will we'll put it in later on but right now that's
it for now.
That day it was created that would be nice to know.
And this is the lead on this.
So we've got one two three four five six seven this year save IList see how it looks.
Let's go here.
Refresh.
All right.
Perfect.
Right.
So what else.
All right.
I think that looks pretty good.
I think we're going to leave the rest to during the next lecture says we're going to do a lot of modification.
It's going to take some time to do so in the next lecture.
We're going to continue modifying the of your users and trying to display some data from our table in
the database.
All right.
Thank you so much.
And I see your next lecture