All right welcome back my students.
So on the last lecture on this having fun with the book section we created this functionality for the
no pulse available right.
Beautiful.
And this is for the home page.
Now we need to create the same functionality for our category pages right.
Cool.
Let's go back here.
Let's go to category here and one of the first thing that I want to do is that if we don't have a category
we shouldn't be showing anything.
So let's take this little curly bracket all the way down here.
Let's make an L statement so we don't have a category.
What else can we do.
We can head or we can to send the person somewhere else so let's redirect the person to something like
that.
BHB right.
Beautiful.
Now what I want to do here is I want to return a resoled from this query and I want to return a resoled
based on the pulse status just like we did in this.
But here we got to put another so a little bit different here we just say where Paul started Zeek was
publish but here we're going to say and because we got two statements.
Now another condition.
So and full status
status equals publish.
All right.
And right here I want to create a if condition and it's going to say if my SU line known rows so we're
going to use this function to count how many rolls we have in this Querrey if our roles are less than
one that means we don't have anything coming from that Querrey that means there is no published Polsce
we can say something like There's no pulse.
Let's go back to end that BHB.
Copy that and paste it right here.
Beautiful else
then we can make them Querrey and let's just put another curly bracket right here.
All right let's go and try it out.
Category.
Colon in line 80.
All right here we go.
There we go.
Javascript not in there no pose no pose.
Let's go and change it to publish apply and now we can see everything beautifully.
All right.
Perfect.
This is looking good.
All right.
So I hope you're having a lot of fun with the bugs and this section of the here and this is what we
learn.
This is where we actually get to be more creative and we find solution for problems and we fix them.
And what can I say.
I hope you're having as much fun as I am.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next having fun with the box lecture.