All right welcome back my student.
So in the last lecture we had a little difficulty because we were able to see the user or the author
right here right.
So why do you think the next step is hopefully you were able to fix it.
If not then we'll debug it together and learn how to be better developers.
All right.
So the first thing I think and actually I know is to check to see what's going on in the database right.
So let's go to our post table and let's check the user pulse user column.
We can see that there is nothing here.
If you have a lot of pools make sure that you have this 500 available as you can see actually is.
We do have the idea of the user.
All right so choose me.
We got one and three.
So we know that user ID 1 and 3 have been our you know being sort of there but we're not actually displaying
them here in the view of.
So we need to figure out what's going on.
So this is working our outpolls is working.
Let's find out what's going on here.
All right.
So that was we can see here we we're saying if he said The Post alter or or if is not empty then will
echo outpolls order.
All right.
If not we acquired palsy user.
So let's just double click here and we can see that we are actually pulling out that information.
So the next step would be to test you know any of them.
Let me actually as a matter of fact I think our team is actually working just because sometimes our
mistakes can be so simple.
Let me go ahead and show you our mistakes can be so simple as just to now really looking at information.
Basically you can.
What I'm trying to say is is that we can make mistakes that really you know are not mistakes.
And let me show you what I think might be the problem so I'm going to go to the polls here and sometimes
I was just making sure that it is not nowhere here.
And I can see that there is no user name Rico anywhere.
So I thought that maybe it was showing somewhere else and just because I didn't see here you know.
But anyway it could be as simple as you are looking at the right information.
All right so sometimes we don't make mistakes and we think we have.
So anyway I mean you should too much.
Let's go ahead and what I'm going to do I'm going to take all this out and let's see if this post user
is displaying I'm going to save it.
Come back here and enter.
So we are actually airing the Post's user.
All right but we're getting the idea of course we need to pull out the name of it right now we need
to find out why our condition is not working and this is what we're going to be doing is structuring
our condition differently.
So what I did was command Z or control Z.
All right.
So what we're going to do is I'm going to check to see if we use this condition year if if it works
better.
All right.
If it's 90 Acqui So enter and now we get it.
So we are actually getting that.
Let's just make sure that we get the name right.
So what we need to do is actually insert the name of it instead of the ID right here.
All right.
We could do this two different ways.
We send the ID of the user and we pull it out through here with make another query right here.
Right.
Or we could send the user name here.
So you right now super simple
safe
right now when we add new polls it's not going to show right here on these two and these new ones here.
But we could do it right here.
So let's.
Actually it's from adding in polls.
So let's say tests one Giaours.
We're going to leave it as Rico publish and choose a file most of and put post here.
Key word and content or whatever publish you added more posts as you can see.
Right now we are displaying the user right here where I explain everything as it should.
And if it was author then we will be displaying the altar.
Right.
So let's go ahead and check to see if polls.
Let's check to see if the author is actually working right.
So I'm going to go ahead and go to.
I don't know.
This falls right here.
That's making new polls from actually our polls although he's not going to work anymore.
We are actually now using that functionality.
All right.
If we make a comment then we can see the author of that comment right here.
So that would be somebody from outside.
We're not going to be using the polls all through here anymore.
It is going to be user now.
All right.
So let's change that alter thing that could confuse us the alter keyword and let's change it for user
because only users can make polls.
User
safe and now user.
Now one last thing that we need to do is we need to go to our home site right here make sure that we
are displaying the right information.
So let's go ahead and check that out real quick.
Let's go to.
Let's just minimize all of this stuff here.
Make sure that we go to far in that.
And here instead of post alter we're fetching the post user and post user.
You need to of they were whatever you are actually explain the user or using it.
All right.
One good thing of doing it.
I mean one good way of doing it would be to do a command F to check for everything that says author
here.
As you can see we have some information.
They are actually going here said that we need to upgrade.
All right.
So I to do that the next lecture because this is going to take me some time.
Basically this information here if I click on it it's going to take me to all the polls me by Miguel
for example.
All right.
So we need to upgrade that too where he says all the posts made by this specific user.
So we'll do that in the next lecture.
Take care.