All right welcome back to the students So what can we do next.
Well first of all what I want to do is I want to change the Logan.
Right now the way our logging is for the front page is that we have to go here what if we create a bond
here a link that would take us to another page just in case we need it and we do actually need it for
Forgot possible feature.
By the way let's create a separate page that we can allow the user to log instead of just logging in
through the front of the web site only.
So let's actually find out where our logging pages are logging functionality.
So let's see right now
OK here we go to sidebar This is where our logon is.
OK he's taking us to include and Logan.
So he's actually taking us right here to the same directory and we just have this functionality here.
So I want to move this to the root where your registration page is so let's use that folder there.
And that's where it is.
Now I'm going to remove a couple of things from here.
It's actually now we move all that as a matter of finding just going to remove everything.
I'm going to copy what registration has this to function includes here.
Just take it back to
back here.
OK.
And I have a piece of code that I want to download from this lecture.
OK is going to be where we are going to be using for for this OK.
Slow down make sure you download it in the resources section.
A feast not here and this page if it's out here on this video is on the video of this section that's
where you're going to find all your files.
But I'm going to try to include them in every lecture.
OK.
So whatever you're needing every lecture so let's go ahead and see how this looks in the outside.
Logan BHB okay.
As you can see it's just a regular logon page.
Let's change the footer
and let's just change copyright.
Or let's just say
I just don't like what the footer befooled is saying a date.
And one of the good things I like a bow.
The HP story is that it saves your files automatically.
So make sure you're saving your files OK if you're using any other type or that you that those unsaved.
So make sure that you use command save or command and control as.
So anyway now that we have a log in page there we need to create a link for it.
Here you know I see him as we need actually some type of NAB or something right.
So let's go here make sure that we our includes of navigation or something right here.
This guy here in registration would just go up right above the container and we go.
Now let's look at that.
See how that works.
There we go.
OK let's go back here let's go to navigation real quick and we have to create some type of link and
right here we says admen ongoing to create a link here
to say Logan
see
let's see if we can make it.
No I don't have that feature yet.
You can do the same thing with two registration taking that up BHB out like I show you in the last sections
last lectures.
I don't know my English is getting worse by the minute.
I don't understand it.
All right.
So let's come back here.
Beautiful.
So now what we need to do is detect if they use is.
Then if is low then we don't actually want to show this by in here I link and want to be able to make
this phone form.
Function right.
So to actually do this in the navigation area we need to use some of our functions here.
Let's see
come back here and let's open some BHB tags I'm going to use shorthand for this.
I don't know if I show you this but I have all the courses how to use shorthand BHB code.
So for example like for the IF statements we can close right here and then we can
open another ph speech tag here.
What's going on with my code.
And then we can.
And if like this OK now where you can do is just comput NEHTA mailing there and you don't have to put
BHB tags.
OK.
So let's use one of our functions if
it's logged then.
OK.
And if it's true then we're going to show whatever we want and what we want to show is this Admin Link
here.
And what about the log in.
Actually we are logged in we don't want to show that.
So let's create some type of statement here.
Let's just copy this real quick.
And the elves needs to have that call in here instead of a semicolon.
If I pull a muscle read my DS telling me they is expecting a statement.
We need to put our code below.
So if the user is not logged in we want to be able.
We want him to see the logon page right.
Or her like this
if he's logged in we see the Admin Link if he's not we see the log in.
OK great.
Later on we're also going to be putting the logo on here somewhere because as a matter of fact the list
is your just do it now.
Put a logo
and believe this is insane clues or something like.
BHB OK.
All right.
That looks about right.
We've got to try this out and see if it works.
But first before we try that out we need to also fits our logo and Page 2 so functionality.
So what I want to do is up here somewhere
I want to start writing my BHB code.
So let's do it.
We can use one of our functions is called check if users logged in and redirect because we don't want
to use it to see the log in page right.
If you're logged in we don't even one him here or her.
So this takes a session.
Actually we are now using the session anymore.
This just takes a redirect.
Bache redirect location.
If you go back to functions you can see that right here just takes every location because we are getting
the session from this guy here for this function and we are using the function right there.
OK.
So simple as that.
That's all we have to do with that.
Now we can just use because right now we are going to be getting some information from this form.
So we want to make sure that it is the method that we are looking for.
So I believe we have one that is if it is method and we can pass in a string here for checking for posts
and we can just check the form variables here.
We can even make it more flexible if we wanted to but I think this should give you a pretty good idea.
On how to do it and this is make sure that all fields are set in the form
before we do anything
let's see why we missing one of these guys.
What am I doing with you.
Now here if everything said we want to use our logging user function and we are going to plug them in
right now.
Copy this guy here and this we just change its password.
Simple as that OK else we just redirect.
We can use our function redirect to redirect them somewhere or whatever we want.
In this case we can redirect the person or the machine write to log in and BHB OK.
Basically to the same form again.
Or we can use BHB self here if we wanted to.
I think that should do the trick.
Let's check to see if it works if we get any errors.
We'll fix it.
So now refresh your.
Make sure you save your form and as a matter of fact I don't even have the user name here.
For this
let's see he's a RICO think he's suave it
right.
Oh there we go.
I.
The password because I've been writing so many passwords that I forgot.
Let's just put whatever Bassal here just to make sure that it is working.
As you can see we get redirected back to the index page.
Actually if for some reason the form is now submitted OK so we need to change that we're getting redirected
there.
So let's change the functionality real quick change.
Let's go to what whatever this these functions returning.
Let's go to functions so let's look at a command f control F..
Let's look for logging user OK.
And OK well the problem is that we are redirecting here what we can do is we can just return false here.
We wanted to
that would take care of the issue.
Of course is in line 399 and
I see of course if we are not able to get any of these values.
These values are not going to work.
So I'm going to have all of that
and I'm going to put it inside this loop here.
Simple as that.
I mean take that back real quick.
This is missing something here.
It's like that.
It's another one missing here.
I took it off when I.
I think I did it cut it when I cut it.
There we go and this is missing return statement.
Take care of that.
With a return statement of true here.
Simple as that.
So
let's go back here and let's make sure everything is working.
There we go.
See
beautiful.
OK.
So let's keep going.
We are almost getting close to build in the future.
Forgot Possehl feature so stay tuned for that.
See you in the next lecture guys.
Take care.