All right perfect.
So now that we know our form is sending information and we are able to catch and make sure that you
take your ECOs out of there you my house until like.
Make sure you take them out because we are not testing anymore.
They just take it all right.
Make sure you do that.
Now the next step for this is after we know that we are receiving information and everything is working
fine is that we need to clean up the data.
And I hope you remember my Eskew injection lecture that I gave you if not just go back to it.
Basically you know you can send information or hackers or whatever you want to call it that people there
can send different values in our fields and they can delete data out of our out of our database.
They can send parameters here and do harm to our site.
We don't want that we need to avoid that.
So we appear to be people or developers made to a really cool function called mice you lie on the score
reel on the score scape on the score string that cleans up these data.
Right.
So we're going to send that.
It takes two parameters takes the connection and it takes whatever is cleaning.
All right.
So right now the screen and the user name and what we are going to be assigning it to the same variable
actually to a very local user name which is going to be equal to this new clean version of it.
You can name it whatever you want.
I'm just going to name it it's same.
So that way we are using the same variable name.
All right.
I think he's Make it makes more sense.
So password and let's just change and that's one password.
So I was able to do the ball for both of them real quick here as you can see.
So now that we know that our information is coming from our forms clean and these and they don't have
rescue or injection on it then we can put it into a database and we're just going to make a very simple
query here.
All right to check our column there in our table in our table users we're going to take a call them
and let's check some values here.
First let's just say select and if I can write a right that would be nice select fall from where from
users write us the table we're going to be checking when people are logging in.
So we're going to say where what let's go and check we know if we find a user name that is the same
then we can pull all pull out all the information regarding that user.
So we're going to compare that to this user name right here.
Make sure you put your two quotes here single quotes brackets and then paste that in there because it's
a stream remember that.
All right so we're going to pull everything out of it if we find that this user in our users table is
the same.
All right.
We're going to be pulling out a lot of information from this guy rave from this person.
It could be a woman too.
OK.
Select user Querrey.
All right.
And it's going to be equal to my secure lie we've done this before.
Right.
Many times we send it to parameters like always connection and then we send the query in perfect.
Then we can also test this out if we wanted to.
So we could say if
Slackware is not good then we can do something else with it right.
Then we can just dye everything out and admin side we're using a function that was very handy on this
side we don't have that function since we don't we don't have the same functionality that we have in
the admin here and the front side in the root directory.
Maybe later on we we would include that when we are cleaning up the site and refactoring some things
and maybe we will put that function in there right now like I said before I'm more concerned about you
learning the fundamentals getting everything down.
And then later on then once you get the knowledge then you can start being created by cleaning it up
making it more reusable and doing things like that.
Right.
Right now let's just concentrate on understanding why are we doing here right.
So we are going to say die.
We're going to say Querrey Querrey failed.
And when I say my rescue a lie we're going to concatenate here and for my ask you a lie.
And then these arrows are going to have a connection.
That's the way it's going to connect to this.
All right.
So we're going to die.
We're going to provide a query string right here where we failed.
All right so we can test this right now.
But I want to really keep going.
Let's see if we get any arrows there so we can isolate them from users and we're going to send it square
in.
Let's just make sure that let's see what he does.
Samit and it looks like we don't have any errors so we are doing good.
Perfect.
All right.
All right so let's go ahead and do that while loop real quick and testing our real quick and then we'll
divide this court this lecture into another one right because we don't want to make it too long.
I don't want to get you to tie your.
And then you know to bore too boring right.
This is exciting guys.
We doing something that will change your life very shortly.
And the more you do it the better it is.
All right.
So we using the while loop again to do the same thing with them many times by using them my obscure
life which array to pull that information out of there.
So we need to put the result of that worrying here.
Right.
And remember this function is going to bring those that result in.
And we're going to assign it to these variable and then we use that resoled to loop through it.
All right.
So right now we're looping through without resort and let's check this.
Check it out.
Let's see if we can pull some data out of it.
I did that without any errors.
So let's just say Roe Let's check out these array and I'm going to check on this one here.
Let's check on the roll right here and this.
Anyway let's check it out.
So we know that in to see a mess if we go to admin users actually we have a big thing here and this
use the word you're not going to have the arrow there.
I was just messing around with some sessions.
So don't worry about that.
So we're going to go here and we are going to check on Ricos right so we have a RICO user name and then
we need to check on his password.
Right.
Again don't worry about his dashboard thing here.
This is something that I was testing before I made of course are you going to have that error there.
Right.
All right.
So let's check on the user user's table and we see Rico here has a user name in the past who one two
three.
So let's check on that.
Let's let's see what can we get out of that.
So Rico.
All right.
And one two three.
Submit.
You see that we get one there.
You don't need to put the past where you can use Perrigo submit.
And it gives you the number one I.D. So we know that we're getting some data out of that.
All right.
Perfect.
So he's working now I'm going to divide this lecture into another one and that's when we're going to
finish some of this some more pulling out some more information and doing some more processing right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
I see you the next one.