All right.
Perfect.
The last one we were able to put this value here that namak right.
So now we're going to do the rest.
And they got to be super easy because most of the time what we've got to do is copy and paste right.
So anyways if you are following along grade you are doing awesome.
I'm telling you right now this information this knowledge would pay off.
There's nothing like knowledge and knowledge is power.
Keep that in mind.
All right.
So we've got the Square right here that we're getting and all we've got to do is make a copy of this
right here and go down to the next one which is right here actually.
Yes I was just going to fix this a little bit so you can see it.
All we got to do right now is paste that information right here.
All right.
And this is comments as you can see there.
So we're going to select everything from comments
and select comments change this a little bit.
All right then copy and paste out here.
And call this for comment counts
comments count.
Perfect right here.
Whoops.
All right so let's let's check it out.
Refresh undefined variable one in 991 ry nine.
All right let's do it again refresh.
And now we see we only have one comment so we go to comments we only see how only have one comment.
So we are able to do that when they are right.
So let's do the next one we can all fits all these data but let's go to the next one real quick.
Let's go to the users and do a piece right here on these huge these days with a class of huge array.
This is going to be users.
So select all from users
select all users.
Perfect.
And you're right here
and here is our account we should take the out of the first one that we did for the post since it's
not count it's just count.
And if we go back here to our dashboard we can see that we have two users right now and they do another
copy here.
Let's go to the categories so let's do a pace right here on this.
They were a class huge again unless the send thing here hopefully you don't have the same issue that
I have with a resolution.
Since you don't have to.
You can have a big screen and I have a problem I have to have a bigger solution so that where you could
see it better.
So select everything from categories and you is going to say select all categories.
Can I copy this and right here based in category count we're going to have a couple of those right.
Let's go back and just refresh and we can see we have five categories check on that categories 1 2 3
4 and 5 perfit where the splits on that Nemec data.
This is beautiful.
Now these links don't work.
They go to the users actually and you see the post.
No they're not working right now we need to fix that.
But right now when we are displaying on the namak data we are going there right now.
Right.
So let's go ahead and fixed view polls actually.
I don't like this says counts.
So post counts.
They just make a post count right here.
Perfect.
So we were able to accomplish a lot on this lecture here and that's what we're going to be doing some
other great stuff.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching this lecture and you're doing awesome.
Keep doing it you're the best.
See you in the next one.
Take care.