Or I saw in the last video we modify some of this here.
Let's go ahead and try to display some data now.
Right.
So first thing that we want to do is we want to get everything from users.
There we go.
And we want to change this and we're going to say Sallet users
as you can see it.
Now most of the time what we're doing now is copying and pasting more refine and doing simple things
like that.
So super easy to do now right.
So now let's look at our table in the database.
You see the names of it.
I think we name everything users almost users and we need to make sure that data is correct here on
this site.
So let's put this here.
There we go.
So we got the user their user ID so they get that here user ID.
What else we got.
User name what else.
User password
user password.
What else.
And after that password we got the first name
and user last name.
User email
and user M.H..
All right what else.
Anything else we want to get out of there
let's just get it out and get everything out.
User role just because we're not going to use it just because we're not going to use it here visually
doesn't mean that we're not going to use the end user internally.
All right.
So user username user password user first name I'm just checking all the fields here.
Make sure that we have everything we need.
All right.
Perfect one it's I saw something here that I needed to do but.
OK.
Right here we need to modify this.
So you're going to copy this and put it right here.
Make sure you do the same thing is better to copy and paste actually because if you try to do it thinking
that you're not going to make a mistake believe me.
Super easy to make a mistake.
I hope you are enjoying the course.
If you pay attention and you do what I'm doing here in the course you would do very good you would succeed
in BHB for sure.
Right.
So.
All right.
So just let's just verify that this is all correct.
We can just double click here.
OK that's fine.
All right.
Actually that that is Edita had the same feature as another editor that I was using you double clicking
and we matched the same keyword.
But I guess if you let me see if you if they are the same.
Now it doesn't have a feature.
Maybe is a plug in somewhere for this but this one doesn't have that.
So let's go ahead and echo some of this stuff out real quick.
As a matter of fact that in his video is already long enough on the next one we're going to be finishing
this off and displaying some information.
I think we're we're done with us doing this one here right.
So in the next lecture we're going to be continuing this and hopefully we'll get it to display some
data.
Thank you.
And I see you in the next lecture.