All right so we are displaying content based on condition here we send it I get requests here and there
you are for example like source
34 we get a different content right.
We are on different content on the page.
We know that already and we did it before.
Now we are using a switch statement to do that.
What I really want to do is create another page and include it based on that condition under your age.
But let's go ahead and do that right now.
Let's go to the admin folder images.
That's fine.
Let's go to let's make this a little smaller here so that we can control a little easier.
This form actually is kind of big right here.
All right.
So let's go to the folder and this site includes going to right click and create a new file called add
pools that BHP the HB enter.
All right.
And I'm just going to say hello here.
So that way I know if this is working.
So let's go to the post-up BHB and the condition here would be post and we were going to include the
file.
Depending on the condition let's go into the exchange.
The path here and the filename Well the filename at postop BHB.
Let's go back here
to the first page.
Right.
And let's go ahead and type and get requests here that you are ill.
So we're going to say a source and they're all going to be source because that's the variable we got
in this site right.
The key source source and value would be ad post and you can see that we get different content right.
Pretty cool right.
So now we get we need a form to add the posts.
That's why we are and we intend to do.
Right.
So let's go to pause and lets out the form and I already have the form made and I'm just going to explain
every little detail about it.
I don't want to take 20 minutes of your time writing doing this right for a simple form that you should
be able to make already.
All right.
So this is just a simple form here with some fields and going to save it and show you what it is.
We got a post-Idol feel plus category that later on we're going to be doing this dynamically from the
database for status.
We're going to bring all this information dynamically when we are added in this form.
But just know that some of this information is going to be dynamic is going to be coming in also.
So we also have input for file bloating in this case is going to be an image right.
Paul Staggs and Khant and we've got all of that now.
Let me show you the difference here.
This form is a little different than the rest of the form.
The rest all the forms that we have made and the difference is that we have a picture that we're going
to be uploading.
So for that we need a review called and type.
Right.
And is that your view is going to be in charge of sending different form data.
And that's what is multipart for Shlash form and data is.
So make sure that you have this actually there and you can look it up if you want more information.
It should be on the BE THAT net and here are very simple what I what I what I got here is a diff inclosing
all the inputs with a label and all the inputs have a name actually you that we're going to be sending
to catch widow post-Super global.
Right.
They all have a different one.
Those are that is going to catch them in the form and send it in as we've done before.
This was going to have a different Super of code files and I'm going to show it to you right now as
a matter of fact.
Let's go ahead and catch that data up here make sure that is sent first.
So we're going to use this statement now.
Post a video if you want to copy this down.
All right take your time and do it is it.
Believe me and you're going to scroll down a little bit more so that way you can pause it whenever you
want and copy it down.
So if it's set well we need a tag first.
So let's do that.
Let's close it right here.
So if it's set to post and I'm using a different name here instead of submit I'm using create post.
Why.
Because I wanted to I really wanted to use
preference I think it's it's more descriptive.
So if it's set we create a pools right.
Well let's find out we get some data first right.
Let's echo something else first and let's just echo that title actually right here.
Let's go this out and see if we can get a going.
So it should be good let's say let's see it is refresh here and let's just put something in the title
hey it's admit it and then we get Polish post.
Actually I'm not submitting the term summit in December.
But you saw that is working.
All right I hear a Polish say that it is working.
All right.
So that's working now I'm going to copy and paste some values here.
Actually it's going to be something that you already know.
So you don't have to worry about it not knowing it.
And I'm going to explain it right now in case you forgot.
But should be able to be very familiar with this.
We are getting all the pull the values from the form right here on the right side and we are assigning
it to variables in the left.
And we've done this before.
All right.
So these values are going to be right here on the name attribute.
We're going to pick it up a signing here.
Now you might not see two things here.
First the files super global and the date.
So I'm going to explain them right now for the polls for this.
For the images.
All right.
We need the super global files.
And this is just going to have the name of image which is going to be in the input right here.
And then we have a name right here.
And for this we also have a temporary location.
I'm going to show you right now what a temporary location is.
Basically if you click here and you put it there this saves it in a temporary location in the server.
So when we submit the form we need to send it from this temporary location somewhere else.
Right so we need to tell it where to send it.
Right now it's not going to send anywhere unless we tell it to.
It's just going to give us the reference of the image.
Basically the name of the image and we don't want that name I want it to be somewhere in the in the
server.
Right so we're going to do that.
Also we're going to send it somewhere else with another function that I'm going to show you right now.
But before I do that I also want to show you that I'm sending the date in I did with a function so I'm
assigning a function to this variable here I'm sending that in in this form is going to have the day
the month in the year.
That's what these formant means to date.
All right the date function has this format and you can look it up on the net but this is the format
that we are signing it.
There are different forms that you can use.
Again you can look it up and find out what form is best for you.
And here in the post common count that we're going to be using it we're going to be used.
We're going to use this dynamically later on.
But right now I'm in court I'm hard coding this and getting it from the forum so I'm just assigning
this field of value in our database table.
As you can see we have a common count here and I'm just I don't want it to be empty so I'm putting it
in there for now.
OK.
Because I don't have it in the form right now.
We're going to be submitting that later.
We're going to be using that field later on.
All right.
So this coming count.
All right so everything here is good.
Let's do the function for the images.
So let's go ahead and do the functions call bloated file move or loader file.
See if I get it right and get it right I if we get a.
Yeah that's it.
And we're going to move it from our temp location
to.
And that's the second parameter and it's going to take two parameters.
So the location that we want and this is going to be outside of admin in the root directory in a folder
called images and that's where these two dots mean it's going to take me out of here and put it in and
in the images in the root directory.
I want it to be there because these are these are going to be false.
All right.
So that's what this is going to do.
So first tell me this like this is just going to take that.
So right now we can test this real quick and let's go ahead and do that.
Let's test it see if it works.
If it doesn't get a problem we're going to put some dummy data here dummy data dummy data dummy data.
Now this is not going to go into our database.
Remember that we have not done that.
When I put this image there and we are going to click publish this check check it out let me go to my
Finder which you in this.
In your case it might be a what you call it desktop.
In your case maybe documents or something like that.
We are in the CMOS and we are in the images as you can see here we've got some images there.
All right.
So this image is this is the image that I use.
We put it in there and we can see adding action again if you want right here going to put that image
I just took it off.
I'm going to put another image there.
And that's where I am going to put it right here so you can see it.
And it may actually make a little smaller so you can see this in action real quick and I click it and
you see the image just transfer right there.
All right.
So that's why he does.
Now if this gives you a narrow no doubt you need to come here.
If you get a narrow here on the left side saying that the move overloaded function did not work.
The reason is because you need permission on this folder right here so right click on it and Windows
and Mac and you get to get in for here and you checked if you clicked double click here and you put
it reading right.
That's fine with Mac users for Windows you right click and you get properties and things have properties
you go to security and then change the permissions.
Right.
So for some reason if I'm wrong with windows look it up online but you should be able to change Owego
go to properties.
And then on properties you should go to security and then they are you should be able to edit that permission
and set it at 2 7 5 5 or 7 7 7.
That way these four there has full permission for the HP to put stuff in there right.
So no that.
All right.
Perfect.
Also know that you need to have at least double quoting here.
All right.
Anyway thank you so much for this.
We're watching this and we're going to continue this lecture on the next one is getting kind of long.
And take care