Who welcome back my students on this lecture we are going to take this a little bit further.
Right.
A little bit more advanced because I want you to learn something new.
So now we have added two functionalities right we have the functionality for the home page for the categories
so we're not shown pools.
If it's a category but what if we are an administrator of the site and you know we of course we want
to be able to see that categories of course we want to be able to see our pools in the home page.
Right.
Because we might be making some changes and we want to see that reflect want to see those changes reflect
on the content right.
So what can we do when that is the choice right.
So basically we want to see the pause if even if they are own draft.
But if we are logged in if we're not logged then that means we or somebody else and we don't want to
see it.
We want to see this no pools available right.
So if we are administrator we see a we're not administrator we don't see it.
So how can we do that.
Well let's actually do it.
Let me show you right now if we go to View polls you can still view the individual post because we having
added that functionality to hide it right when he's on draft.
And this is where I'm going to show you the sample how to do this when you are logged in.
How to see and when you logged in in Tennessee and when you log out.
So let's go to the cold real quick.
Re-imposed that BHP were going to be creating this.
All right.
So right now if we click on here the next tag is right here.
I think we should move this all the way to the bottom.
All right.
So let's move this all the way to the bottom right here and then we're going to make sure that it works.
Let's just organizes a little bit here
and save it.
Let's just make sure that it works.
All right.
I didn't break anything.
He works fine.
All right one thing that I went and fetched this head here is bothering me.
Let's just take care of that real quick and not take too much time with it.
Where is it right here.
I'm just going to call this place and take this out of there.
Come back here and refresh as you can see.
There we go.
All right.
So this is the way I'm going to do it here we we're doing this dating or view views for the post-up
functionality that we added.
That's fine.
We'll probably change that in the future.
But right now we will leave it that way it is.
So this is the way I'm going to do this.
I'm going to check first if we are logged in.
Right so if we set the session
Well that's a lot of
if we have a user session.
All right.
If we set and admin
then we are logged in right as an admin.
Perfect.
So what I'm going to do is well for admin I want to make a query with everything.
Yes I want to be able to see everything.
If not admin I'm going to put it else they mean right here.
I'm going to grab this Querrey from here and cut it and we're going to put another conditional here
so select all from polls were foresight equals false ID and rightful status
equals publish.
So for regular people which is which is show the published ones.
All right.
Beautiful right.
But we still have the problem when we are we don't have a.
No polls available right.
So if we refresh here we still see this because we love then.
All right.
But let's look now and let's see how this looks.
First I'm going to copy this top here so that we can come back to it.
So let's see what this is going to do the way it is right now he's not 100 percent right.
It's going to go to admin.
And I love how I'm going to pay that link that I just copy from there and we can see or see that we
we still have to work on it.
But we did not we're not showing the polls.
Let's look again again.
All right.
So let's go to the individual post.
So you need to work on it.
All right so work.
Well we can do here is we can do the same thing we did here in category or in that BHP we created this
ICU known roles we can do the rules so we can do something like that.
There
you know actually this has the same name so else this horror.
So these else we can put this else all the way to the bottom and we can't even put it with this guy
right here else.
Let's check it out real quick and see other looks at him break anything that looks like it worked right.
Let's look out right here in this page that oops I don't have that individual polls.
That sucks.
I'm going to have to log in again and graph
these polls right here.
Copy this logo based that in there.
And now we don't see the polls.
If we are logged now.
But if we are low again we can see it.
So let's look again again.
Rico and I are going to tell you my password.
Let's just paste that link in there.
And we are able to see everything there.
So this is how you can actually do this functionality.
All right.
Beautiful.
Let me see what else can we do here.
I think this is it.
This is what we get.
This is the best we can do for now.
All right.
If you want you can clean up this cold a little bit and you can take all this out a year like this functionality
from there and you can put it anywhere you want.
All right.
You can put even a function right here instead of all these code refactor this.
Take this back to functions that BHB and make this a create common function and you called it right
here.
All right so it's up to you to clean it up if you are one already showing how to refactoring the early
years earlier lectures.
All right.
So beautiful.
Now you can implement this to your whole CMAC.
You can implement it to your home page.
Implement this to your job to your category pages and I will be implementing it.
So don't ask me later on you know how to do this because I'm already showing you.
So if you see it on my CIMS on the next lectures you know that I did it I changed it myself so I'm going
to change the home page and going to change the category to make it look like the post like the individual
polls one.
All right.
To make it like this only available if we are logged in even if they are on draft.
So now let me show you let me just make this real quick.
Draft's right.
Actually they are draft ballots just to publish real quick just to make sure that they're are still
available for everybody else.
So they are all home page categories intact.
And if we go to their individual polls it is showing for everybody else.
Beautiful.
It is working.
It's perfect.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next two lectures.