All welcome back my students.
So if you're here is because you won one of the reasons could be because you want to learn how to you
know display this up here and other racing is you already know how to do this but you just like to listen
to me.
And that's pretty cool.
And I you know I agree with you.
I like to hear myself sometimes.
All right.
Another reason could be just because you are curious to see how I do it.
Whatever you're missing is.
Let's do it.
All right.
So let's go ahead.
All right so I told you that you can put this in a session here.
This is the way I would do it right.
So I would grab all this cold right here and just I would just cut it out of here.
We don't need a year right.
So we can just go to functions if I can remember where I put it.
Right here.
That would be nice.
And we could say we can just put a function here.
CALL IT users on line.
That's a cool name for a function which you think.
And we just put all that code in there like that perfit right.
And here we don't have to set any sessions or anything we can just return.
All right.
Like this return the küng user.
Beautiful.
So now everywhere you want to use a search function here you can go let's say Adamy navigation and Redhill
Homeside right below right before Homeside right here.
We can call a function so I'm just going to put a lie here whoops like that and I'm just going to say
users on line.
Knishes do it with a lowercase users on line that would go Kallen BHP or call you on line.
All right.
And now if we go back here and we say Enter Well it's all Caraquet I see what it is.
I forgot to get my connection there.
All right don't forget that no connection.
We go Antar
Now you can see that my function is working really cool right now.
Let's go back to that.
And let's just make sure that we take that out of there and save it and come back here
and also take this out of your head we go on.
And that's let's come back here after.
All right.
Perfect.
So now let's go back to the fire fight I'm going to refresh and firefights.
And now you could see that this counting number is counting.
All right let's go to safari in mind and to refresh safari.
I'm going to refresh your.
Now you can see that he's actually counting the users.
This is a pretty cool function don't you think.
And one of the best thing is that you can actually change the color of this link here and just you know
just me know how many users are on line.
At one point of time.
Another great thing about this is is that you can come here to your users online and look at your structure
here and you can do all the modifications or make this a lot better than what it is right now.
All right.
You are keeping track of the users that you have.
And this time you are you know the amount of users that you got the number of users in the time you
are in your system.
So now you can be creative here and do other things with it.
All right with this information.
So anyway hopefully this information will help you create better applications.
And it was a really good pleasure for me to create it for you and show you how to do this.
Thank you so much for all your reviews and all your great messages that you send me over e-mails and
discussion boards.
You are awesome and I'll see you in the next lectures