Welcome my dear student.
So this is as from the future.
I came back to update the course.
I'm gonna show you how to send e-mail with a nice package.
We got called BHP Mailer now BHP Mailer House change just.
They made a slight change in the way they use their code.
So that's going to reflect on our projects.
So that's why I came back to to fix this or show you the right way or the updated way of implementing
this package.
Now Edwin from the past is going to show you how to implement this in your project but I'm going to
show you how to implement it anywhere.
OK.
So one thing that you need to have and I want you to have is male trap.
OK just in case you guys don't have it.
This is really cool for testing male is it's like a fake male server but if your males are being delivered
here.
OK.
In your inbox then your code is good.
Now you know if they don't work with another provider out there it's something is going on with your
credentials but something is going on with your code.
OK.
But but right now if they work with this here if your code to work with this you know that your code
is good and you're providing might be the problem OK.
But anyway.
So we are going to be implementing GHB Mailer just like this and it's very simple.
OK.
Or we have to download the package.
So I'm going to go back here you guys already know how to use composer right.
So I'm going to update this.
And while that's downloading well now update but I'm going to download it and well does downloading
I'm going to create a file here to show you this example.
OK.
All right so OK so that's downloaded there.
We can see that that is six points something OK always go to their gay hub page to check on their changes.
OK.
That's how I get my information so to use this is super simple.
I'm just going to copy this whole thing to be honest with you.
I'm going to copy this whole thing so that I can show you what you need and what you don't need.
OK.
So I'm going to go to my end it's going to open some BHP tags like this and paste that in there.
Let's come back here OK
and of course I have a lot of stuff that that dongle here
OK.
Just like that fitting all this stuff BHP Mailer exceptions.
There we go now.
I'm going to leave this the way it is.
I'm not going to make any other changes other than the settings here for the S.A. server.
OK.
So I'm going to grab twenty five.
Twenty five is the point that has worked for me OK so I'm going to change that right here.
Twenty five twenty five.
I'm going to change.
Let me see.
The host of course is this guy so let's start from the top.
Right here.
Change that
and username and password we need.
OK.
So I'm going to grab that from mousetrap user name and then password.
OK
you see right here I'm not going to do anything else here.
Let me just put my credentials even though it don't really matter.
This is just for show.
So I'm just gonna put Edwin Diaz at Edwin Diaz.
Let me just put Edwin at coding faculty.
That's my Web site.
You guys know that right.
Dot com I'm just gonna put here cooling faculty guys in for some of you they're looking for discounts
and things like that if you can't find it on bonus lectures that I create at the end sometimes the platforms
they change the way they the coupons work or the discounts and they stop working just go to my blog
and Diaz our common and you're gonna be able to find some discounts there OK.
Anyway so that's already done there what if I just hit this and see what happens could not access Well
we have this attachment that really don't go where our servers right.
We don't have anything there.
Let's go and try this again refresh and it looks like he has been sent where you think let's go here
Look we got something already that's cool.
Look at that.
I didn't do anything other than change this and maybe change some of these credentials that really no
matter here OK.
I could have left everything the same and just remove these two lines and everything would work OK so
now every from the past in the next lecture or the next lectures he's going to show you how to implement
this into your project but the issue here that you are going to have if you don't implement that hopefully
I will edit our lecture is that this needs to be on top.
OK.
So yeah they're order law is there and we can overload load classes.
We'll make sure that you're putting all this well.
Especially this guy here on the top of your files all the way to the top.
OK.
Make sure that that date's there.
So now you are able to send emails any type of e-mails to your users by using as A.P..
So if you're using Google you know you can google as A.P. Google server makes sure that you gave your
Google Apps some type of permissions because I think Google requires that and some of the providers
out there.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
This is Edwin from the future.
And right back at Edwin from the past.
See you in the medicine extra guys.
Take care.