All right welcome back and with your students.
So we got this working pretty good right.
We can make a post and we can assign it to a user from a user's table.
Pretty cool.
And then we can see it right here.
All right.
So now that all the functionality is not going to be working right here unless it's coming from the
outside.
All right.
Now one thing here is that when we click on edit we don't have the functionality right here right.
Remember that is going to be users now so we need to do something very similar to what we did to that
post.
If you want to go ahead and do that yourself try it because that way you can learn more if not you want
to do the easy lazy way then look at me.
Let's up to the edit post page.
Actually let's go to our pools and copy the user right.
What we got here and they use a copy this come back to the edit posts and right here an author comment
is out.
Save it phased out the code here.
Save it.
Come back.
Hearing update oh this way says Plus son just going to do with a lazy way actually going into Command
F O control f and make sure that every post on the score alters replace.
So actually is replace right here my editor.
So I'm going to replace all of that with post user replace beautiful and save it.
Right now there is another thing that I need to do.
Actually actually I think we're good.
That should check right now.
I think we're good I don't think we're going to change that.
Let's go ahead and refresh.
And now we can see the user right here.
All right.
See that category right here.
It would be nice if you put a label on it so let's go ahead and put a label real quick.
Right.
Let's put a label on our categories.
Where is it where is it right here.
So we get a category here and the user lets put it.
Copy this.
The lazy way and paste and see category is my cut.
To dories and then come back here and save.
Now we got categories and then we got users.
Beautiful right beautiful.
Now
we click petite and update pulls.
We could see that right now we have a problem that we are not explained the default user and we need
to fix that.
If we go to Edit polls you could see the user he is BT.
Let's change it to something else.
I send it to recall of the polls and more polls and we can see now that added the user is Rico.
So in the next lecture we're going to fix that.
We get to add a default user there.
See you in the next lecture.
Take care