I will come back on this video here we are going to be learning about one of the most important components
of B loops and loops allow us to repeat code until certain conditions are met.
You see I loop we go around and around and around multiple times executing the code in between the curly
brackets until a certain condition is met.
Very similar to the statement but more powerful.
So let's go ahead and learn how to write a syntax and let's learn how to use it.
We start with a very simple very simple loop called the while loop.
All right so let's go ahead and we'll bring it to let's do a Save ask on the blank that BHB.
All right.
Let's call these while on the score.
There we go and we we don't need that right.
So let's go ahead and just change the title here for a while.
Why not right.
Do this on the browser.
Open it up.
Perfect.
All right so how can we write a sentence for you.
Let me just expand this so you can see the loops are very similar to a statement.
All we have to change is the key word if in the if statement for the key word while.
And we already have a WHILE loop.
Very simple look at this.
So let's say we have a statement like this.
Let's first write a PH VTX I don't think is going to work without it right.
All right.
And this closes down here
and we say that space really doesn't matter.
This is just for to make it clear for you that that's what it is.
So let's choose a key word for while as you can see here my code is already highlighted the key word
there.
So while this is true wow it is.
All right we're going to repeat this.
When he falls we'll stop.
So for example very very simple very simple to do.
They say wow I don't know.
Four is less than 10.
I want you to keep repeating yourself and what are you going to be repeating.
I don't know let's do an echo and say hello.
I don't know what was there.
Hello students.
All right.
And that's enough.
Hello hello it's unbelievable how these words very close related right well not close related but how
you can just write a bad word there and you can write a good word right here with another word which
is like preview arrows so we're getting error here.
OK I see what we're doing.
You see that they explain to you what happened here.
Right.
We create an infinite loop.
And just because my code is already executing this call when I save it so we got to watch it with brackets
and saving them right.
So let's just go ahead and take that off.
Right now I'm going to show you right now what happened.
All right so while four is less than 10 we're going to keep executing.
But the problem is that four is always going to be less than 10.
That's why you see you saw the cold there in the browser going crazy.
So a lot of words there.
That's because the loop kept going and going and going never stop.
Because four is always going to be less than 10.
So this condition here will not be met.
What we need to do is change the for every time we go around the loop so the loop would go like this.
I would first start here.
Right.
It would look at this and say OK perfect.
But you would look at it and say All right we have a while loop was a condition and then we gave with
a condition and we say listening Apache as long as four is less than 10.
I want you to keep executing whatever is in these lines right.
He's actually talking
right.
Well we're talking BHB is talking to Apache right.
So now the batch is going to be processing this is going to be giving us this.
Every time it goes around the wall the loop starts here and we'll go to the next line and we're printed
on the screen.
Then it ends right here and then we go around again.
He will look at the condition again.
It will still be false.
And then we come back here and print this over again until this condition from 2 until 4 is bigger than
10 we're four is bigger than 10.
That is going to stop.
But like I said before Fornes never bigger than 10.
So we never stop.
This is called an infinite loop.
Right.
And we can't write it like this.
So what we usually do for a while loop is that we create something called a counter initialiser counter
or initialiser whatever you want to call it for the loop.
All right.
So we were places for for that count.
We started the loop 0.
So this is what counter very well we can name and whatever we want and we can in I for initialiser.
We wanted to really doesn't matter.
I just wanted this to be descriptive for you.
Descriptive.
So counter right now is zero.
So we're saying Wow 0 why this counter here that is equal to zero is less than 10.
I want you to keep writing this because that's still an infinite loop.
What we need to do to stop the infinite loop is that every time we go around before the loop finishes
we need to increase counter to 1.
All right plus 1.
So we're going to add one to it every time it goes around.
So this is how we want to play very well.
This is one way of doing it.
So I hope you see what this is doing.
This is outside the loop we have a counter right of equal to zero.
And we're saying here as long as it's counter which is equal to zero is less than you want you to keep
executing the code.
So it goes here analyzes this and goes to the next page and print this out.
And then he goes to the next one and says OK egressed counter we write country again we add 1 to it.
So now Cantu's is going to equal to 1 going to go here.
Going to go up again.
Now the same wild counter which is one now is less than 10 right.
Q This is going to execute it again and again to add another one to counter and remember counting is
already equal to 1.
Now with this extra one is going to be equal to two and it's going to keep going three four five six
seven eight nine.
And then when he reaches 10 then this is not going to execute since 10 is not less than 10 then the
loop will stop.
So this will stop.
All right so right now if you want to see and when he stops or we have to do is printed on the browser
and you see what I mean.
There we go.
All right.
Long story and it goes to the end of the story.
Nine times now.
Let me show you the shorthand version of this is dividing this one.
This is so common that there is a shorthand version for it called right here the increment operator
right there.
Same thing as all that call that we had either.
And just going to leave it here comment.
So you could see it.
It's going to come at that hour.
And then going to write a real one.
One other real one but the different one the short hand version that where you have this in your exercise
files.
There we go.
OK.
So now what I want to do is I want to show you I want to.
Now I don't want to echo Hello Stuart and I want to Aqua's the counter just to show you what happens.
Look at that.
The counter starts a 0 and goes all the way to 9 and then stops because then when he goes to 10 10 he
said Oh no no no no no.
It's now equal to then stuff's right here.
Those in gold and Prince out of 10 if you wanted to print out 10 then you said as long as the counter
is less than or equal than.
So when he gets to 10 is going to print that out because it's equal.
Look at that.
So the printouts 10 printed out.
Right.
Very simple to write for the while loop on the next video we're going to be discussing about another.
All right.
So anyway hopefully you were able to learn a lot on this code and on this video and you can see the
power in this.
We can for example use a while loop to go through a I don't know a paragraph for some type of database
and say while this user is equal to this I want you to check the user and do this to the user as long
as this paragraph is read.
I want you to go through every folder I have on my server and check for a picture.
This is where we use nubes to do things multiple times repeatedly repeatedly without a NOOP.
We will have to copy and paste a million times to get things done right.
So loops are very powerful and if you learn the loops you are going to be very very comfortable with
HP anyway and that's very We're going to be discussing more about loops.
Take care