All right so it's time for us to ask on really cool for Chanology and we're going to be adding the graphs
that I show you in the demo before they're going to be graphs below here.
And we're going to get it from Google.
So the first thing that we need to do is actually go to Google dot com and make sure you have a Google
account and just go to Google charts.
I don't know if they or they will let you use their API without a Google account.
I suggest you grab grab one anyways so you just have a Google account.
Go to the first link there when you search for Google.
Their results then go to overview chart gallery.
And here we're going to have a whole bunch of charts that we can use.
Right now we're going to be using a simple chart like this one right.
And this is that you are Elle you can welcome to post the video and copy that you are l If you want.
It's got a column chart.
And here we will grab one of these pieces of code that will be used and this is just showing you what
the type of things that you can do.
All right.
Just change a couple of things on it and you should be good to go right.
But now we need to grab this whole thing.
And if you keep going down to where you see this.
This one with the colors.
This is the one we are going to be using.
So what I want to do is copy the first thing here which is the script that we are going to be using
from Google to pool this functionality out of it.
Right.
They have this library that has all those javascript called defined already.
So we're going to use that.
Let's go to our admin Hetter at that link in there that script link this is that remould script link.
All right.
So admin on the score header and under all this files we're going to add this before the end of the
head tag right here.
Right.
And that's why we got there.
Perfect.
Now we need to go to the end it's.
And I think I had a working in the tray here and I see him as one wanting admin if I'm passing already.
All right.
I don't see either.
Let me just go to the whanging admin
right here.
All right.
So what we want to do is all the way down here we want to make Roe all the way below all this widgets.
Right.
We're going to create a def with a class of row and we're going to save the file We're going to go back
to charts and we're going to copy this script from there below the head stop actually above the head
start there.
Copy with your mouse key we're And you're going to come to that.
And that's that BHB and paste that in there.
All right.
Now this is not going to work because we don't have any.
We are getting the document GALIUM and by the Culham chart we don't have that div anywhere here.
As a matter of fact right now we don't have that so we need to go back to here and you see this right
here is this.
This is what we need in order to put all this functionality inside it inside of it.
Right.
And if you don't know javascript this is javascript if you don't know javascript I have a really great
cors and Javascript really great reviews a lot of people like it.
All right.
Larry you know and we're going to play out there right here.
All right so let me just make sure that you see it there.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and check it out.
See how that looks.
I just say to by the way and if I refresh you can see that we have really cool functionality already.
All right.
Perfect.
Now we going to of course clean it up a little bit.
And we're not going to be displaying three columns of anything there since this is just plain the data
is related.
We got on this plane probably just pose acted post-draft draft things like that in here.
So we're not we're not going to be needing all these colors there.
By the way it's up to us if we want to.
But I'm not going to complicate things.
All right.
But anyway so we were able to create this chart here the next election we're going to be able to we're
going to start courting this all we make it dynamic so it can pull information from our database into
these nice charts that Google offers.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.