High on the last video we created some instances and we also created some functionalities.
Now it's time for us to create some properties for functionalities for our.
It's for our class.
All right so the first thing that we are going to be doing is using a keyword called var right this
key is going to allow us to create properties that we can use within our class.
Right.
So this is very unique right here and we just now after the keyword var because we keep all var amines
variable we need to put just a regular variable mph p with a dollar sign.
And then the name of the variable and the value if you decide to write.
So we know we got four wheels in a car and I'm going to create a couple of properties here.
I'm going to show you how to use them later.
So let's create another one.
What do we know that a car has.
Hood has a hood.
So we're going to do a value of one there.
We have an engine of one.
We have doors.
That's another important property right.
And you have a default of four doors.
Right.
So now we added some properties to our class or should I say men object.
Well so let's take the Mercedes-Benz out actually and just take it out completely right here.
All right.
So how do we use these properties here.
Right.
How do we use it.
Well everything here inside this class we need to actually use it with an instance.
That's the way we do it right.
Because this whole thing is meant to be used as an object.
So we created right here right by instantiating it and then we use it.
So now that we have this instance here and we put it in a variable Let's go ahead and Kreig and do something
with it.
B and W and then I want to see how many wheels for us.
I have to echo this.
So there we go.
So now we use a word echo like we usually do with the instance with a variable here that we we you know
we assign this instance to this variable.
Now this whole thing is called an instance right.
So we use the minus and the greater than with wheels.
Now we don't put the dollar sign here.
All right we don't put a dollar sign to call this property.
We already have the dollar sign the fine up here the way we use it out here is we don't do that we don't
put a dollar sign right here anymore.
All right.
Just know that right.
So let's let's do something else.
Let's go ahead so we know we have four wheels.
Not that I want to show you is that we can signed.
All right so if I wanted to I can go ahead and do this.
B and W ryme then I can say you we use it we can change the value of this property right here on the
instance if we wanted to.
Right.
We could also use a method to do that.
We can also use this and now one thing that I wanted to show you is that every time we refer to this
car class inside the class every time we refer to this we refer to it with a word called does.
So let me just take this off and show you this.
This keyword here.
All right this is the way we reference desk this class inside the class so we can use a word does.
And we can say this wheels equal to 10.
All right.
And if I take this off here.
OK.
All I have to do now to use this right now is taking that for fourth right now because I'm not doing
anything with it.
All right.
I'm not actually calling this method.
I'm not calling it I need to call it right here.
So I got to do a B and B and W call the method and boom.
Now when I called and said this meant it's going to take care changing this wheel's value to 10.
And when he changes to 10 degree if I call it again already change.
His mentor was able to do that for me.
Right.
So I know that inside the class we referred to each name we did he were called this.
So we don't have to say carping here we don't have to say BMW because we can do that.
We are actually creating an instance outside we create an instance outside and use it outside inside
the class.
We refer to it by Does just know that all right instead of this or this right because what we do here
is did we have the instance which is this here for instance.
Right.
We create a new instance with new car and we assign it a value we assign it we assign it to a variable
and then we use it.
So we create this whole functionality right here inside the class we created as an instance and then
assign it to a variable and then we use this variable to do different things inside here right.
So but to refer to this because we refer to this whole thing this object outside with is we just use
the word key.
This way I know it's a little confusing but I know that we use this to to do things in the other class
that I referred to this object to this class.
All right so now we change that and we can also come back here and change it again if we wanted to.
But I'm not going to do that.
So for example let's create you know what I feel like creating a new instance and just let's create
a new instance of this card class.
Right.
And let's call a truck.
How about that.
And let's just take this idea here.
All right.
So I have this I'm echoing here wheels right for the B and W and what I want to do is I'm going to concatenate
here a b your tag used to make a lot of space and what I want to do is I want to echo the truck I want
to I wanted the truck to have different wheels because in the truck we have what do we have we have
more wheels right.
So what I'm going to do is as a matter of fact I think I can echo the whole thing out right here like
this eco wheels.
There we go.
We can actually even echo the whole thing without having a it for a ride.
So while we did here was we grabbed that we create a new is called Truck.
All right then we are changing the wheels value to 10 and then we are going at the same time we could
do that.
All right.
So keep that in mind.
All right so now the truck has two wheels.
We have a different instance with 10 wheels and we can also have.
Of course the other properties here we can print that out.
All right.
Just know that we can do that.
Now we can create in another matter the here and we can call these men that create doors or something
like that and I say this doors
are no sets.
All right.
And that would change value every time I called this it would change value to set right.
So I can go ahead and say you know what truck.
Right.
And I can see doors and I could just echo it.
Well if I echo this like this it will give me for this put a B or tag here let's just concatenate this.
Right so we've got four here but I don't want four for my truck you know let's assign it a different
value.
Let's have some let's call that.
That this meant to write his own.
We we created it for something let's call it right.
So let's say you know what truck.
So if it's your truck if I remember how to write truck and then boom.
So we call this matter here we change a value to and now and now.
Now truck has a Valeo sits.
Every time we call this method it would change the value of doors to 6.
Now what I'm trying to teach you here on this video here is that we can do whatever we want to do.
All right.
Once we create a distance we can change the properties we can have methods to change properties we can
go manually and change it we can leave it empty and then go ahead down here and start using it however
we want.
All right.
I mean there are many different things that we can do here.
I just want you to get some practice on this so watch the video here.
Practice on your own create a nother class if you want.
Or you can create another class right below this one and call it color in car or something like that
creation colors creation properties for food or you know for your class create some mentors that would
do things in your class.
Practice practice practice makes perfection right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this video.
Hopefully I was able to give you some knowledge here on how to use properties inside the class along
with methods.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lecture.