All right so we are at the second part of this here added in the functionality of a user page.
All right.
So one thing that I want to do here is I want to make sure that everything is inside this edit user
functionality here right.
So we got this going on here.
We got this.
I know that I want to actually include this here that I have a comment that for some reason.
So instead of user pass we're going to make this hash password
right.
And they're not uncommon.
This show is available.
Put my coma right above.
Make it work.
All right.
And again they're going to wrap everything around these edit user right here and that's about it.
That's all I want to do.
To be honest with you if it's not empty then I want to actually do everything here.
So if he's 90 we're going to do this
right.
And we are going to have details as well.
That's OK.
Let's look into it like this.
All right perfect.
And save it.
All right I think we're good to go here.
All right let's just leave this comment real quick.
All right.
Save it or let's go ahead and try and log in.
Call 1 2 and 3.
All right perfect.
So let's go to the user right now the passwords one two three let's add the user and let's make this
do another password.
And then before we do that let's check to see what password we have right now.
So when I click on here and I grab this here and I copy into a text file.
Right.
And this is the old password right here.
So I don't know the old password.
Let's see if it does the new password right.
So I'm just going to put this here and let's see now let's go back and of the user does the user was
updating let's refresh year and looked like he did change.
What do you think.
Yeah for sure.
Now we have a different password.
Let's check it out.
All right totally.
All right we were able to change to that new password so now our functionality is change here.
All right.
So for those of you out there that haven't changed just do it and change it.
Make sure that it's working good for you.
One good thing about this here too is that after you do this it's actually good to to to redirect back
to users.
What do you think.
All right so if you want to add that that's cool you can add it.
All right.
So we're done with this one.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture