All right welcome back my students.
So hopefully you got your files in your server and you overcompressed them.
Hopefully you also export to your database and put that in the desktop.
Perfect.
All right.
So remember she amass at sport and go here and you got a file and they just drop in here.
Just very fine with you that everything is done correctly.
Now let's go to a panel here.
All right this is our main window seat panel and we're got to go to our database wizard.
This is we're going to where we're going to be creating a database so we click on it.
And now we type in a name for a database.
I'm going to type in.
And I don't know.
See him see him them all on the score.
See a mess on the score D-B.
I'm going to grab the name if it if it works.
And then I click next step.
All right.
So he was able to create that.
I'm going to put this in a text it because we are going to be needing this information soon.
So database name right.
And you're going to put it like that database name.
All right.
Put this to the site.
Now we're going to put a user name right.
I'm going to call it underscores a mess on the school user password.
One two three.
Now don't use this passwords.
All right don't do that.
Don't use them.
One two three or eight till I die use something hard to track or hard to crack.
All right.
I'm going to use them a 2:59 as a matter of fact you know what let's just use a password generator right
here and I click on it and now I'm going to copy this.
All right.
And as a password password and or copy this year paste it.
All right so now we use a password generator and that's cool.
So I'm going to say use password.
I checked his bots and then we're going to use that password right.
Make sure that you also copy the user user.
All right.
Perfect.
So now we got the database name the user and the password that's all we need.
And now with click click click create user.
All right.
Perfect and now we're going to click on all privileges right here.
We're going to allow these user to take over everything.
Next step.
Perfect.
So that's being added there.
Now what we need to do is configure this.
So let's go to our panel to a file manager or see panel.
Right.
And let's go to our See umask Let's get in there and let's go to include something that's where we have
our database right here.
Select this and right click and say Cool Edit edit right now choose me.
Look we're going to leave it the same because that's what go daddy uses.
And some other hosting providers don't use something else so if it's not working with local holes for
you verify where your hosting provider but we go that is localhost.
So for the user we have this one I'm going to paste it right here and paste and copying it from my all
their monitor.
Right.
For the past what we got I encrypt that crazy password.
We just we just copied and pasted in there.
And now for the name of the database we also have that right.
And we are sitting here all right and we clicked safe and now we go to that folder.
And for me it's going to be the name of my domain for you if you are creating a need what you would
call it
if you're creating a brand new domain is going to be in the route of course.
Now let me give you an advice before you do that.
Let's go back here real quick.
I'm going to go back to the root.
All right.
Right now if you know what is.
Let me just go back.
Sorry about that.
All right.
Right now this is my root directory.
How do I know because I have public underscore the e-mail I downloaded the whole folder in here.
All right.
So now if you are doing this if you have a new domain make sure right that the contents if you go back
here the contents of this folders in your root directory.
So admin says fonts and even you end up BHB should be right here in the root directory not there.
Let's go to the director sorry about that it should be right here in the root directory not CMOS.
This is the Forder.
This is your equivalent to your root directory.
Remember we did it in local localhost so we needed a folder.
This is going to be the domain in local's basically right.
So the contents of this folder should be right here.
I see a mess.
You need to delete the folder.
Make sure that you copy all the contents first and paste it in that in the root of your server.
Right.
So this is where you're going to have all the contents.
But anyway I just wanted to make that clear.
Anyway let's go back and let's go here.
Let's go to includes.
Let's go to a database.
I think we already have that open somewhere here.
All right.
So we got all of the information right here in our database right in the database file.
We're going to save it.
Let's go to our to the Web site name so whatever domain name you got typing here I'm going to say cold
I think it was Edwin something Edwin cold school not called college.
I think it was.
Does it mean that I that I've bought I go daddy before and then enter now.
This is just going to show me some other project that I'm actually that I have in my root directory
which is a WordPress site.
All right that's another course.
But I have it in a folder called See a mess.
So this is how we are going to be actually creating multiple sites.
Right.
Remember that this account would go daddy is only available for one site but we can store multiple publications
and we make different folders.
So in this folder we just might and this one here we just have this one.
So now I can see that my database is not connecting because I'm not getting any information.
All right.
So we need to find that out.
We need to find out why.
Let's go back to here and let's uncomment this and we're going to verify that our database is not connected.
How well we have a little a little condition here.
But I'm also going to put else in here.
If you're not seeing that.
I know that they are.
So you can see if not we're just going to copy this and put it right here and we're going to say not
connect save changes.
Let's go back here and enter now as you can see here.
He says very clear that he's not connected or something is wrong.
All right.
On the next lecture we got to actually debug this a little bit and find out why he's wrong and fix it.
Thank you so much.
And I see you in the next lecture