There is one thing that we need to do before we start you know going all general crazy on this feature
here is that we need to add one more field to our post table so let's go to BHB admin here.
I want to add Ada likes field here just because we are we going to be updating our likes.
You know we want to tell how many likes a post has.
OK.
So let's call this likes like that and you know of course you can do 11 or you can do more than that
if you like and you're going to do 11.
You'll be the judge of how many likes that post is going to have.
OK.
So make sure that couple of millions you know.
But anyway let's just click save here and say that's all we need for that.
And let's go back to this here.
OK.
So now that we're sending our agents requests make sure that's working guys OK member to have your browser
console open remember that it doesn't work the first time so make sure that you look in your console
as you can see here that that was the area that we had before when the page was sending the wrong request
to let's fix that real quick.
There we go.
And you see now that that's not there.
Make sure you check your network.
Make sure that it's sending that correctly.
Once you click there you should see your headers or you preview or response.
Cookies and all that stuff.
OK in your browser console.
So let's go back here.
Another was sending the data.
What is it that we want to do.
Well let's go back to the top here since this is what we are detecting this.
The first thing that we want to do is write it down and come in here.
We want to select all polls.
Basically we one to select select the post.
That's the first step.
Let's just write it down here.
The second would be to once we select the polls we need to update the polls polls with likes OK.
And then the third thing that we need is to put data inside our likes right.
So insert data or insert likes or or create likes like this create likes for polls OK.
So those are the three things that we need to do.
Let's go ahead and start working with selecting the polls are you know fairly enough that polls so let's
just do the search let's just create a variable here call Search post and we are going to this is going
to be a Querrey So we're going to say select and guys you don't have to uppercase it is just good practice
to differentiate your my statement from your regular you know words.
So I like to open uppercase and you don't have to say I'm going to say let all the polls from polls.
OK.
You don't have to do that you can just select whatever you want.
Where was I.
The is equal to some ID right.
So how do we get the polls.
Well we have it in our you know get requests.
OK.
But we also have it in our post that we're sending So let's create this here.
And we named it false ID.
Remember that just like that.
And I'm just going to create a variable to hold this just because I don't want to insert this thing
in here.
I like it to be a little bit smaller.
Well you can go ahead you can you know minimize your code and put it here if you want.
I'm just going to play of like this in there.
McKay you can separate the concatenate and make it however you want.
This is just how I want it.
So now that we have that less use you get a false result.
Let's just get a variable here to fetch.
So I'm going to fetch the search post as a matter of fact let's just name a search post Querrey.
So it makes a little bit more sense.
OK once I have the post requests the post resoled I want to get it out of there.
Right.
So I'm just going to call this likes and going to do pose we sold right here and just get the likes
symbols that you can name a post if you like if you if you you know want to make it look a little better.
And just like that and this here is saying my school got a string.
So
OK we can come Kartini this but as a matter of fact it says he has a string select from all that's not
what it is.
I know that was right.
It's just that we forgot to upper case.
If you're going to uppercase something make sure if you're going to open a case.
Dean you're my askew statements make sure that you will practice everything ok.
I will complain.
And as a matter of fact as you see right here I know this is fine.
It's supposed to get a.
Actually it's not fine.
It's supposed to get.
We're supposed to do a query sorry about that guys.
So this is why.
Yeah sorry about that.
You know I don't write a lot about my askew so I don't use them much.
OK.
So
let's go back here.
Sure.
I know I was missing something polls.
I should have wrote this in another application.
Right.
I'm just doing this improvising guys.
OK so give me a break.
OK.
So let's do this Kulai
Kohary I believe it is.
There we go.
And we need the connection which we don't have right here let's use this connection very well should
be available to us.
But if it's now don't worry we're going to make it available to us right now.
OK.
So we're going to pass equerry here.
It's a matter of fact.
Let's go ahead.
If he's not available we'll make it available in a minute.
So if this fails we'll find out soon enough.
So it looks like we do have the connection here so yeah.
It is available to us because we have it available somewhere in there.
BHB functions or the head or something would be nice to have a function that will you know anyway.
So now that we have that let's actually make sure that it is working.
So
let's actually say if my ask you Ally known Rose and we pass in the connection here again that salt
ok is greater or equal than one then we are going to Eckel the same.
I don't know the
let's just echo the post ID What do you guys think
those ideas like that.
Let's check it out real quick.
We wrote a lot of code we don't know if it works like and we've got the polls right there and we've
got a preview and you can see that it is displaying 139.
So we are getting the polls data.
So that's the first step.
OK.
Selecting the polls we finished that on the next step.
We're going to be updating our polls so hopefully you did it correctly.
If not don't worry we'll get it right.
Just make sure that you put your questions in the discussion that will help you out.
Thank you so much and see you in the next lecture.