Welcome back my students I feel a lot better so let's get going.
OK guys if you're tired you're not going to be learning as much.
Make sure you get your at something and drink your energy natural juices of course.
So anyway let's get going here on the forgot page.
We're going to be doing is writing some Ph.D. coding having some really cool fun but we don't want anybody
to come in here.
So that's why we created this little get requests here coming from the front page because we don't want
anybody posting anything there right.
So if nobody if the person goes in there it does not.
It's not a request.
OK.
We don't want it there.
So we just a little bit of the security laid on we're going to work more.
But let's just start now here.
Let's create a PH speech X and this race and code.
Let's use some of our function if
see if it is method post.
I mean get so if he's not
OK or
what we want it to be post and we want it to have some type of value so we can save is not that
he's not
you know while we can't use a function twice here
actually the first one we checking for the Met and this one is just going to check for values so we
get I don't have a function for that yet.
You can you can create one if you like.
So if it's not forgot because that's the key we are getting then we are going to redirect immediately
and we're going to redirect this person somewhere else maybe to and that's let's check it out to see
if it works.
So to take the parameters out
that works.
See what I'm doing wrong here.
If this does not get let's just do this.
If it's not it should work.
Should work if is not good and it's not.
So you have to be oh you know what
he has to be bouffe.
So you know what it's just do a or.
Here we go.
One of those we won one of those and here let's just say it right there we go.
So if he's not I get requests or we don't have a key for a get requests we want the person to be here
at all if they have one of the one of them they can be here.
OK.
So that's fine.
Next we are going to be using something like that.
But
there will be different.
We're going to check for a post requests and
if we get those requests we just got to make sure hopes
that some of the values are set right.
We've got to create a function for that.
Getting a little tired of writing the essay.
Right.
But anyway so let's just create one that checks for the e-mail right.
Because in reality what we want is one to be able to get that e-mail.
OK.
From this form here because this form is going to have this email input.
So if that's said we know that something or someone submitted that form OK.
So once I set
we're going to get the e-mail and of course that is going to be this year.
And you of course you can trim it you can escape it.
We have functions for that right.
I leave it that way it is.
Because what we're going to be doing is we are going to be using prepared statements.
All right.
To avoid some actual injections and all that stuff.
OK.
So we are also going to be creating a Automattic a talking here because we are going to be putting that
in the database.
So I'm going to be using a function called been to hats and I believe this is available in lower versions
of BHB.
But I do recommend for for most of you to be OK.
Always keep your ph be upgraded.
Now on this cause I'm using the I started with BHB 5.4 I believe from the beginning.
But as you can tell it on the lectures we're using BHB 7 is faster he has a couple of more features
that we can use now using some of the PSP 7 features yet just because there are many web sites that
we're only running up BHB 5.
OK.
And so that's one of the reasons we're having now using all of it yet but I will use some of it just
to show you.
So this is going to take let's use this being heads is one function but there is another function I
want to use.
Inside here is open hoping to sell something I forgot the random.
There we go Superbikes and let's create a length for talking here because that's going to take a while
and if you want more information of all those functions just go to the web site gives you a lot more
in depth.
We just going to create some random strings here and with some heads values and all that stuff.
OK.
And we go and misspelling that
is G.
Th I always confuse a few seem like courses but the lenth thing where the lenth word super confusing
for me.
OK.
Once we have that then we need to start building up a statement.
We need to start connecting to the databasing all that making sure that the email does not exist in
our database.
You know on and on and on I'll show you how to do that in the next lecture.
Thank you so much.