Hi welcome back on this video here we are going to be looking at another type of loop called the for
loop.
This is a very popular loop since everything is in one line.
All right.
So I'm going to explain it a little bit more about loops on this video.
And I'm going to give you a bit of a better picture.
So if for some reason you did not understand the last video you got to understand this one.
I can guarantee you that.
All right if you do have any problems you can contact me anytime.
So let's go ahead and open our co-editor
and let's do a Save As like we always do on that blank that BHB
Let's call this for loop
safe then we are going to create some PSP tags here.
Right.
Bring it down.
Now I'm going to be a little more specific about loops on this on here because I want you to understand
that I just gave you a little brief introduction about loops and the truth is that while loops and for
loops do the same thing they don't do anything different.
Right.
They just we just write them differently.
Now there are times when you want to use a while loop instead of a for loop but that is just preference.
Right.
You can do the same thing with both.
Now why haven't both.
Well the for loop is actually a lot easier to write.
And I'll show you right now the syntax so we know with a while we need to we need it to create a initialiser
on top and that is called the end it's right the initialiser.
So with a for loop is very simple we create a with a key word called for parentheses just like all the
loops.
And the statement very very similar.
So but the problem the problem the way we write the for loop is very simple.
We create the very well inside the loop.
All right so we instead of outside like the while we create a variable right here.
So we say for example counter equals to zero semi-colon because what we say is we we finished this command
go to the next command.
All right if you have any.
If we don't keep going.
So we have the initial Lizer here the end of the loop.
All right.
The next thing we had on the wall what was it.
Do you remember because this was up here before in the wild.
Now is here.
And then after that we had that little parentheses right.
So what we do is we test the condition here.
So we say wow Cantor were right the very way in is less than whatever condition they could be less than
or equal that the raise inside of an array or whatever or if it's equal then any any rolls on your database
or tables or whatever.
I mean it doesn't have to be a number.
Right now the next step.
So we have three parts here we have the index where we start the loop always we start to look somewhere.
Then we tested for condition right the middle and then at the end we increment.
Are the three steps that we need to make in every loop.
So we grab the counter with.
We use the shorthand version there and we increment it right.
Very simple.
Now here we do the same thing.
Now I'm just going to actually echo out the counter you see how easy this is all in one line.
A lot better down right in the while loop right.
Let's go ahead and see how this looks on the browser.
Perfect.
See the same thing as a while loop.
Now what I want to create is I'm going to concatenate this here.
We're putting a dot here that means I'm going to smash something together with this variable right.
What I want to do is I want to smash it with a B or tie action and that smash.
I want to create a B or tag to separate Every time I Lugo's around and print this out.
So the first time we went around print 0 0 0 0 then it created a B tag re medially after created 0 right
here.
And we do expect Telemann to be cards should be there.
See that.
So he created a B or B or right tag immediately.
This is a and then the amount Aggrey and then he went around again and print out two and then created
another attack.
That's all he's doing right.
See how this starts from the top and programming you a lot of people use this.
You know Mrs. concept the computers would never do anything unless we tell it to.
We need to tell the computer exactly what we want done in order for that specific function to happen
exactly like that if we miss a semi-colon or we do some kind of mistake.
The program would not work.
It will now allow us to work to do.
We now allow the program.
One mistake will destroy the whole function.
Right.
So if we don't control this the right way our would not work what I'm trying to tell you here is that
everything depends on you when you're writing a program.
It doesn't matter what type of language you are using what programming language you're using.
As long as you know what you're doing.
My goal here with this course is to teach you the fundamentals of BHB and show you a couple of tricks
that I learned along the way.
So that way you can be better prepare.
But anyways that's a different topic.
Hopefully on this video here you're able to learn something valuable.
And so let's go ahead and let me show you.
I think I'm going to have to show you the last the last hoop that I want to show you.
So you can be prepared with loops before we go into the practice application on the next video.
All right.
So take care and I'll see you in the next one.