All right so we have cover a lot of ground.
We were able to validate so many information coming from the form putting inside where we are.
Clean it up.
I mean we did a lot of things right.
If we go back to our CMOS year we are able to log in now type of the password he takes us to the admin.
Now this is not good if when they come here we can tell who the user is.
We need to be able to tell when we send when the user tries to log in we need to validate it using we
find it.
But we need to send some information to admin and let let admin know what type of user is coming in.
So if that means he's a user that is not a user that is active he were redirected back to a day in that
space for example or until they use it to register again or something like that.
So we're going to be dealing with this information with sessions and if you remember session just very
similar to cookies.
But we keep that information on our server.
And if you don't remember what sessions are.
Go back to the sessions lecture and in the course before the CMS section here and learn how it works.
All right.
I'm not going to go into detail since you already supposed to know that.
So what we want to do is tell you right now we're going to recap all this at the end.
Don't worry when I finish this session is that if the users are able to log in and this is the else
statement here we're going to give the user to set the user set some sessions.
So before we we set sessions we need to turn it on first.
All right.
So that's something that needs to be turned on before we use it.
So let's open it right here and we're going to use this BHB tags here.
Clean that up and use a function session start.
All right.
That's going to turn on the sessions.
We're going to tell our server to prepare that session for us get it ready so we can set it.
So let's set some values to that session.
Now everything is going to be created for us with this session start but we need to set some values.
So when the user is able to log in and that's what he's saying right here in the else statement right
we find the user is the same.
What do we want to do.
Right now we are redirecting.
I use it to admin while we want to do is we want to send it to admin but we also wanted to set some
sessions so that when we set sessions like this this is how we set them.
And I explained all that in the intersession lecture Right.
So we're going to say we're going to set a session called user name
for this user name right here.
So basically this user name that we're bringing from the database we can assign it to a session called
the username.
So every time we want to access this username in the database we're going to have this value wherever
we pull it out from.
So if we say Eckl somewhere else and we have our sessions turned on we get to be able to get this value.
All right.
So that's what we doing we are signing these variables value to this Session right here.
Remember that we have signed from the right to left.
So now we're going to do this a couple of times actually and we're going to actually try to get as much
data as possible to add me because we don't know the features that we're going to be having admin but
we want to be able to validate some of these information once we get to admen too.
All right.
So we wanted the user name.
Why not get the first name too.
That way we can personalize admin and it will be right.
We can get the last name of the user
and if we can spell it right that would be nice.
And what else we have the user role there and getting all this from here.
Okay.
And of course if I named and named a little bit different there.
All right.
So I think I got it right.
First Name Last Name.
Perfect.
All right.
And this just changed right here.
For this I'm not going to go crazy and type the same as this.
I'm just going to clean it up a little bit and call the last name first name and this one is going to
say user.
All right.
So we're going to Sandal's this information to these sessions so we can pull it somewhere else.
So what we get to at once we get to add.
We're going to have all of this information there but we first need to turn it on.
All right.
So it has got to admin right now and I want to turn it on any wearing admen.
So I would do that by going to the admin Hetter because admin header is what has everything inside the
admin right.
We are we have admin Hetter all over right here so if you haven't done that already did that before.
Let's go ahead and let's start right here.
You're going to have this like this.
All right.
Make sure that you have the session start like this.
Started up like this.
And then then you can go ahead and use that value.
So now we go to admin right here.
There is nothing here.
If you want to bring some values here now that you have the session start now do you have a turn on.
Let's go to navigation.
I think a navigation we can set some values to actually go to the index of admin which is inside that
admin folder and it's echoes so stuff out here.
Let's say Welcome and let's just say let's open a BHB tag here.
Right.
And what we want to do is we want to echo that session.
All right so we're going to say session sessions here like this and use the user name.
All right.
Very simple as simple as this.
Look at this.
That's all we're doing.
So let's just grab this and just put it inside here instead of all there we're going to put it right
there.
And let's see how that looks.
Now let's go here let's go to the home site let's just say Rico.
One two three and submit as you can see here it already personalized it for me sending the Session right
here.
All right and this is how we're going to personalize this site here and how we are going to be checking
if the user is active or the user always admin or subscriber or anything like that.
This is how we're going to be doing all those things.
Right.
And adding some extra features of course later on.
But right now as you can see this is how we can set sessions and receivers somewhere else and personalize
our admin search area.
All right.
So anyway hopefully this lecture here show you a lot.
And if you are doing this Congratulations you're doing a really good job and you're learning really
good information that's going to help you personally and professionally.
Good job.
I see you in the next lecture.
You're doing really good.