So we know that every time we visit a Web site or an application that application could be setting up
a cookie into our browser it could be putting information into our browser so that every time we visit
a Web site where application back they can pull that information and know who we are.
That way they can personalize the application other Web sites and give us a better experience right.
How do we do the same thing they are doing.
How do we make an application that could actually set a cookie for a user and then read the data back
and do things without data.
Well on this video I'm going to show you how to do that.
This is going to be awesome awesome awesome lecture.
All right.
So let's go ahead and we'll bring our co-editor.
The first thing that we got to do and the second thing is always almost a second thing and that is saving
as this blank that BHB and we are going to call this cookies that BHP and here on the doctype declaration
above that we are going to open a BHB tag.
OK.
Now know that the cookies how we set cookies is would a function called Set cookie.
We also got to know that the information of the cookie of the user is saved in a super global cold cookie.
All right.
So this is going to be all the information is going to be saved in the super global here and it's going
to be in a associative array.
OK just know that this is variable.
All right underscore cookie.
Now don't get confused about associative a rating.
Know that BHB handles that in the back.
It's already set for us meaning that we can call this set this cookie.
So pro-global anywhere in our application any page and we don't need to let BHB know that diet is a
global BHB already has a defined for us and has all the methods attached to this.
In the back end when I say methods I mean functions right.
There's a bunch of things happening in the background that we don't know about that BHB takes care.
OK.
And of course with the Apache server.
So now first of all let's go ahead and set the cookie and then I'll show you how to read it.
Right so right now let's let's go ahead and set the cookie we're going to use a function call said cookie.
All right.
And we know this is how we declare this is what we call function with the name of the function and the
parentheses and know that this function is already set for us in ph B is a pre-build function.
So eaks going to take three parameters.
All right.
Know that it takes three parameters the three parameters the first one right here is going to be the
name.
So I'm just going to say name and she's going to say some name right.
You know how descriptive I am with names.
That was actually being ironic right.
The second is going to be the value of that.
All right.
So the value would be I don't know let's say the 100 that would be the value could be anything you want
really doesn't matter.
And the third parameter that is going to take its exploration.
When do we want this cookie to expire next week two weeks from now let's see.
Let me just write this three years from now when do you want that cookie to speired.
The great thing about this is that it's real if you think about it we can go ahead and take control
of the set of values into a user's browser.
Right.
And then we can set the value there for years and when they come back we would know who they are again
and then we can just say listen last time you were watching this now I want you to watch this.
Watch this.
I mean it's unbelievable if you think about arrives really awesome.
So anyways let's go ahead and for inspiration we're going to use a time function this time function
and most of the functions with time related to time they are done with seconds.
So this time functioned the way it is going to give me all the seconds from 1970 and you can reference
this time function in the PH BE that net if you want to check it out.
But basically it's going to give me all the seconds from 1970 to now.
Well we need to do is because we have all the seconds here.
Right.
Coring seconds but when it's what we want to do is add an expiration date.
So for him to say I want to add something here.
And the way I do that is I'm going to use 60 seconds right.
Then we know in 60 seconds.
So we use 60.
Remember this is going to be seconds here.
So you know in 60 seconds we'll have a minute 60 minutes we have an hour.
All right.
And then and then in 24 we have 20.
We have 24 hours we are what we're doing is we're multiplying seconds science minutes times days.
All right.
Right here 7:00.
OK.
This basically this translates into a week ahead.
Right now we're adding a week to it.
So we're doing seconds times minutes times hours.
OK.
We know that 60 Minutes equals one hour right right here times 24 that's 24 hours 24 hours time seven
that equals a week.
All right.
Just keep that in mind these are seconds that we are multiplying.
So we have a week in advance here so we're setting this cookie to expire in a week.
Let's actually set it to expire in a later time.
What about we wanted to do expire later in three years from now.
So we need to make that calculation right here.
I'm not going to go into details about that just know that this is a week from now.
And let's let this video already running a little late so let's go ahead and set this right now so let's
first start with the name.
Let's do the value here.
Right.
And expiration it's duration.
I'm going to do a copy right here here.
All right.
So now all right this cookie is going to be set into the browser every time they visit or our applications
so we have to they have to visit cookies that BHP this is going to be set automatically.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do that and then we'll find out what how we would see if it was set.
So let's go and click here and he's going to go to the document right now the cook is supposed to be
set because we visit that this page right here.
So let's go to Crome and let's find out.
Let's go to settings.
Let's go to short advance settings content settings and should say something about localhost.
All right.
So let's look for software here.
Site locally.
Let's see if we can find it without spending too much time on it.
So this site should be localized.
You've probably seen it already right here locals and you see right here there's some name price value
right there.
So let's click on it and see what information we get.
So we got the name some name we gather value content that domains loco's.
It gave us some extra information.
The forward slash send from any kind of connection the system will yes create it right now.
And in a week it's going to be expired.
Right seven days from now at 9:00 is the.
Right there.
Again we can remove it right here.
So there's video here I show you how to set up a cookie.
Now every time now we can go ahead and test this out if we wanted to.
All right.
So we can find out.
We can send this information in the user's computer.
And then when they come back we can do things depending on this information.
We can say if name is this a value is this or if the user did this and that we do this and that.
I mean I'm not going to go into details right now but just know that we can do things depending on the
user on this cookie cookies values.
Right.
Well then that's me and I'm going to show you how to read this value.
All right.
And how to do things that pending on that value Anyways thank you so much for watching this lecture.
I see you the next one