Welcome back my student let's actually start by taking out this message variable.
There are right in registration that BHB should be right here.
Let's just take this guy out.
We're not going to need him for now.
Maybe we're not going to ever need him again.
So sorry for them for him.
We moved on already right guys.
All right so right now this is not doing anything.
That's fine.
We'll make it work.
So the next thing that I want to do here is actually loop through this era's array and find out if we
have any problems.
And if we do we want to either register the user or not.
All right.
So let's actually create a For Each loop right here.
And we are going to take apart the associative array.
We're going to take the key out and the value and we're just going to see if the kid is empty.
All right then.
Well another key the value actually.
Then we want to re-use to the user.
And of course we're going to be using our register beautiful function right here that we have not tested
yet and we're going to take in the user name and the email and the password.
So you have not.
And then of course we want to log in the user we have not created this function.
We will.
Right.
So user name and the password.
All right we need to create a function and then we need to test everything out.
We have reading a lot of code here guys.
So I suggest you start putting some comments on each of your functionalities.
And so that way you can start debugging this later on if something is wrong.
Right.
All right.
Let's actually go ahead and create our logging user functionality.
And let's actually include
we need to include here something we need to include our functions that ph be there because if we don't
it's not going to work.
So if I remember correctly and that's what I'm trying to remember where it actually is we need to go
out a little bit to our admin and then we know we need to have functions of BHB.
There we go.
If you have some type of arrowing in your path your whole page will break.
All right so make sure that it is working.
So NDB them see something here in the way we have a session so we don't have a session start on the
B that's fine.
We do have a session start right here.
We could just put this all the way up here.
That's fine.
All right.
So let's start breaking this down.
This is a big function here.
Let's just take all this out and the
auction function you are logging user right.
We need to fix that in a minute.
Of course this would be the user name.
Geez it would go in the mail.
All right.
Let's take that out of here
and
we can see a little user here.
I told you guys I was going to take it from a beginner's level to an intermediate level so try to keep
up with me and we go I'm just going to take all that out and look at that beautiful right.
All right.
And let's go back to functions in here.
We are going to be trimming our variables.
Let's actually trim it right here.
Hopefully those and create a problem
with scaping and then we're trimming it.
I don't like to make it like this since it's not clear what we are doing.
I don't want you to let's just trim it.
That's fine.
Let's just trim here
and we'll trim the passwords.
Well
here we go.
I like to write it up like this on times and not for functions and functions together just because I
want you guys to understand exactly what we're doing.
Plus I wanted to make it clear since I now writing a lot of comments here.
All right so let's make this here.
Clean this up a little bit.
And I already can see
that we could use our redirect function right here.
All right we're going to leave that for later.
When we test this out right now we need to also include our connection
right.
This is very fine setting all of the what he needs so let's let's look at this real quick and let's
see where we are.
All right.
The next thing for us to do would be to actually put some type of user notice here telling the user
that something is wrong with their form.
All right.
Now we still need to work on our functions at BHP this might not be 100 percent yet.
So we would need to replace as we redirect we or redirect function that we have.
We also need to just make this a little better.
Right.
And we might need a little work here as well.
But on the next lecture we are going to be modifying our Fung our form here just to give the user some
notification to wice run with their information.
And then after all are we going to test this out if something is wrong we're going to fix it.
All right.
See you in the next lecture