Oh right.
Welcome back my dear students I hope that most of you were able to instill composure.
Or maybe you already had it.
I don't know but if you have any issues please post it in discussions.
OK so we can help you but at least try to solve it yourself a little boy for a little while OK.
That way you learn a little more so what is the next step.
Well let's go back here.
This the packages page is where you can find a whole bunch of packages for BHP.
OK.
So here you can look for let's say mail enter and you'll find a whole bunch of packages.
This just has autocomplete here.
So you see you just click on the package and even tells you how to install it.
And it tells you what it is.
How many people how many installs.
OK so that's that.
Let's go ahead and find out how to actually get this working right.
So we got the minimum installation.
We see that we need to require a file.
This is the order low file for BHP Mailer OK.
This is the file that we need to require to make sure that we have all these objects available this
week instantiate the object the class.
Right.
It's B mailer.
And then we can use that to set it up and send email.
There's a bunch of things that we can do as you can see here you can set the set from address we gave
and send more addresses we can put the name of that dress out in the receipt here reply.
We can do attachment.
We can even send the email of course the subject the body and even the art just in case you got planes
that don't have the email.
And then of course you can confirm the email was sent.
Super super easy.
Well before we do that what I want to do is create a class.
Classes file to actually save up configurations because it's not a good idea to actually have this configuration
line around there.
So I'm gonna create a let's create a folder here on end by the way guys.
This is a procedural cause I showed you how to deal with objects and that's why I was very hesitant
to show you how to send email but I had to say show you how to do this even though this is object oriented.
Okay just because this is the right way of doing it let's create a directory let's call these classes
and he'd say here let's create another file called config that BHP has opened some BHP tags and let's
create a class name it config as well.
Great.
So what are we going to do.
We are going to create some costings and I show you how to create costings with a defined function before.
Now there is something a little newer this core concept and it's being around you can create a constant
just like this.
Been around for a little bit for a couple versions.
I'm using BHP seven but I always keep O'Grady my map installation and one of my BHP to the latest version.
OK.
Because he's not gonna break our application.
I got to make sure that whatever if anything breaks in the future we change it but we can use any BHP
version as of this video and nothing's gonna break.
So what's the difference between the defined function to define a constant and the the declaration cost.
Well the defined function is a little bit more flexible in certain aspects.
OK.
We don't have a lot of flexibility with this but as new versions come in we get a lot more things like
for example we were now able to do a raise here before.
Okay.
Let's just say so Marie.
But now with his version of BHP seven I believe that's when they were introduced.
If I'm not mistaking or BHP sets or something like that I forgot.
But anyway so with a defined function there's a bunch we can we can include expressions and I believe
we cost you were not able to before and now you're able to sell cos he is getting up there but with
any five function there's a bunch of things that we can't do with cost which I'm not gonna get into.
Now you can look it up do a google search for the differences between cause and define.
But anyway so we're going to use this variable declaration we're gonna set up some constants here.
S.M. T.P. host and female trap that we are going to be using cold as same actually as MTBE dot male
trap
IO
is doing not cost
and this is for it I mean for the port board for that I believe is twenty five twenty five for no mistaking
an S empty MCP for the user
said to be user I don't know which one that is yet I have to look it up in my male trap and the password
OK let's go to male Trevor a quick
and I'm going to guys I'm going to get those settings change.
OK.
So it's up to you if you want to cut waste your time trying to log into my account.
Let's go to Settings real quick and I'm gonna be cupping everything from the other monitor.
So this is a user and we have the password here as well
let's go and require that Mailer OK class that's here somewhere OK so let's go to the file that we are
going to be using that on which is the figure up right here and let's write a little come in here
OK
we're going to configure
BHP Major
let's first include it up here somewhere.
So
let's see.
I'll have to open up whole BHP tag for that can just do it right here.
So what I still require
we noise in this directory.
So that's why we put dot when we are requiring files.
We put dot forward slash that's required stuff in the same level two dots is to get out of that level
go to the next one.
Right.
So vendor and it's called BHP Mailer BHP Mailer and then we got a hook into that class BHP mail order
load.
OK.
That's going to overload all those classes that we need.
And let's do another require and what I want to do so I need to require that classes that configuration
so that for and
why did I put that class is the same level as atom in their
we go is upper uppercase for some reason I got it for their upper case
is actually the lower case on that folder
name
and let's do the config.
OK.
So once we require that we come down here we can start using it.
So first things first male new BHP Mailer.
This is Edwin from the future.
OK.
So I came back to warn you about this.
So we're going to have the BHP Mailer instance down here.
Make sure that all above your code right here OK right above your code.
You include the mailer.
That's the new thing for.
OK for BHP Mailer now OK you have to make sure that this class is included all all the way on the top
not inside any other functions.
OK.
So put it all the wind at topping should work anyways.
Thank you so much for watching guys.
And continue your lecture with Adam from the past.
Take care.
Now we need to figure out if this class exists so how can we do that.
How can we make sure that this appears working.
And that's very simple
function right here to try to get this class we get a narrow depending on the under if we can get it
or not.
So let's go here.
So we use this function to get class and we just passing the object.
Simple as that.
So let's see that works.
And
let's go back to our code real quick and of course we have to do a whole bunch of things here to make
this work.
Let's actually take these out for me here
let's just comment on this
let's just do it here.
OK before we do anything
let's go back here.
And as you can see works.
OK so we are connected.
Great.
Make sure you undo all that
OK so we know that is working and we know that the object is available.
Now we need to start setting it up.
OK so let's go back to that github page real quick and let's copy some of these settings because I just
don't want to write all this stuff
go back and a base sitting here.
You can leave this comment if you like.
We have a host right.
So our host is our class config.
And as you can see with these two little dots we can access the class that we want.
OK.
Because we already requiring that up there.
So we just type in the name of that constant and that's it.
Let's actually do that sending
this for this here.
This is I believe user name or user and SNCC cure password.
OK.
So let's see what we got.
We got there.
And I always like to put this somewhere else and take all these out is in my way like I say if you want
to leave it leave it
anyway.
Great.
So I've got the hosts I got what we're missing is the port right here and I like to have this hose they
use a password and the port somewhere they're
OK.
What else do we need.
So we have the hose.
We have we have the port number the port.
We are missing.
Well let's bring back our Sam
true.
Let's bring that back.
Let's see if Melcher works fine with it user password port.
I think we're good to go and if we want to send so much the email which we will.
Let's do this to true OK now it's time for us to see if this works let's try to send some type of email.
So we're going to set from and whatever address we want according faculty
and we can pass in a name if we want to as a second parameter if we want that to show let's actually
add an address
email.
OK.
Whatever email we type in the form and we're gonna get that email variable from up here remember OK
from the get requests OK let's actually make sure we have some type of subject
uppercase.
It's hard to remember all this.
That's why I always have some type of framework that I work that has all this included.
But when you're starting out it's good to actually learn the core version of BHP OK.
So actually this is
this is a property and we are going to say this is test email.
OK.
Now the next one would be the body so the bodies also that and an e-mail female body.
I'm just gonna put that idea like this.
Let's go ahead and send the e-mail ready right.
Let's put this in an even if statement and we're going to say well if the mail was send or sent I don't
have the t there they should it put the T there but that's fine if mail is true then we're going to
say he was sent or something
OK
else
not
OK
OK let's check this out to see if it works.
Oh of course.
Make sure that we have our configuration file ready here Yeah that looks like it it is let's test this
out
OK so
so you know it says we're going to update the database we are going to configure a setup put our settings
in this object or instantiate this class of course we all the settings and send the e-mail right.
So let's see if that works
let's go here and it should send an e-mail.
Remember that the e-mail that you are put in this input has to be the e-mail you have in the database.
I didn't like the way that actually was.
Huh.
Oh I think I know why that is right here
no coding faculty enter.
And that's taking a little bit giving me a good sign.
And he says he was sent.
So let's go to our mail trap and as you can see we have the e-mail right here.
Email body.
And of course you can send the HMO you can test it out yourself if you make this false or if you take
it off you won't be able to send HDMI like this
embedded in here if you send that already you're gonna see that this will be in big here and would be
bolded.
OK.
So you are able to send HMO with that.
We've got it.
We brought you gonna do that later on.
So there you have it.
Now you know how to send emails OK correctly to any e-mail bots out there to any inbox bots or inbox.
Thank you so much guys.
I'll see you in the Ned's lecture.