All right welcome back my students in this lecture here we're finally going to see if we can add some
categories in here right.
Because right now we're not getting anything.
So I hope you're excited this is a good lecture and you've got to learn a lot.
OK.
So let's go ahead and start doing this.
So I mean categories of Ph.D..
And this is the admin.
Right.
And all my code is around thirty eight.
But on your side might be a little different here so I'm going to be right below this
element with a class of call hiving it's s hyphen sits right now.
Make sure one thing that I want to make sure here is down this attribute here method.
Make sure you have the post here because if you don't have that this is not going to work.
Right.
So let's go ahead and start doing this.
All right so the first thing that we need to do is actually detect to see if we are getting some data
from that form right.
So I'm going to say if we said Actually let's put a peach Picardie.
Here we go.
Whoops.
Bring it down a little bit.
If it's set.
All right.
And what do we want to check for.
Remember Paul Superville we're very good Jorge.
So we're checking for the cat title right.
Or we can check for the submit.
Actually back at the submit.
Right.
All right so if we find this with me we want to do something let's go ahead and echo something out to
see if this works.
I'd like to echo is a very good function and I echo something H-1 here.
Hello.
We go.
Let's go ahead and check that out.
REFRESH AND HELLO.
It's available.
Perfect.
Right so it's working.
All right so another form is working.
Let's go ahead and keep building this up.
All right.
I take that out because I don't need it anymore.
So we're going to get something out a year.
We're going to get the title right.
So let's get that out of the superglue.
I'm going to paste that in here because I don't like writing much.
I actually love writing but that's just me.
So Kat let's just name a cat title.
So we got the variable here holding that super global key right here.
Of course the value of it.
All right.
So now that we have that we can we can do a couple of checks here used to make sure because we want
to make sure that if somebody's clicking here if they don't put anything here if it is blank we want
to make sure that we display some type of feedback to the user Hey listen you need to fill this up you
know.
And if you know if it's black would you want to submit it.
And they if they have something then we want to submit it of course right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's let's just say is do a couple little validations here so you learn how you learn the hangovers.
If the cat title equals the string right.
We could do that or empty as you use this function empty.
And if the cat side is empty then we do something right.
So let's go ahead and echo some type of message say Echo.
This field should not be empty.
Not sure but it should not.
I was going to write but again can you believe it.
MT You know what's going on with me today.
I need my coffee.
All right else.
So another thing is so if if it's not empty then.
What do we want to do.
Make sure curly brackets your good right there right there.
Perfect.
All right.
Every time I click on the eye you see the underline there and then are they're lying here.
So that's how I know that they are correct even though you know you just want to make sure.
So if everything is good right now then we want to do our Querrey.
So let's go ahead and do that right now.
So let's say you just put that there and they say insert into category our table or we go and we could
say this is the column in our right here cat category is the columns inside our table database.
And I did a database table.
All right.
So let's go ahead and concatenate the rest of the query and say the values are going to be what.
You know remember the values
and you guess
that title.
That's what we want to put in there.
There we go.
Title.
All right.
For my little space right here and then.
So now that we have our choir we construct here for the database and the last thing is to what to sent.
Right.
So we're just going to say create category and name this variable here.
Got to go or we could go where we are right and then we're going to sign the function that is going
to send this to our database called Querrey.
Right.
The connection with passing the connection and then passing the query of course.
All right.
So after this is done we are good to go.
Now let's do a little.
Another little safety net here.
I call save net because we want to make sure that if for some reason this does not work with nobody.
All right.
So I'm just going to say if for some reason this is not happening if this is false.
I end up with a not here.
Operator So if not create a query if it's not true then what we want to do is make sure that we kill
this stripped right this function should be killed instead of die or die.
That's what I think.
I don't know.
You are welcome to your own opinion with us or I think.
All right so then we could concatenate here a error just to find out exactly what is going on right.
There we go.
So I'm just going to recap real quick and what I just did or when I say is a little bit.
So it looks better.
So we're getting some information we're getting the post-Super global here from the form right.
We are getting the cat title out of it.
We are assigning it to this variable here and they won't do so little validations here.
We're saying if the cat title is empty as an industry or if it's empty then we want to ekal this field
should be should not be empty should not be and this field should not be empty.
Ok I wrote it correctly else than we want if it's 90 then we want to insert the data into our table.
Right.
We're going to send the query right here with him.
Ask you rely on the score Querrey takes two parameter connection in the query and then we are checking
here to see if that where we were successful.
All right.
If it wasn't successful then we are going to kill the script with a strong message where we failed and
we are concatenating this function here and we're passing this parameter here.
Correction just in case it doesn't work.
All right.
So let's go ahead and check that out real quick and see if it works.
And I'm just going to say test here I category.
Voila.
All right.
So this is working now let's do an empty and this fill should not be empty.
So is it works for both so we are getting something here test too.
And if we don't type anything we don't get it.
It doesn't get submitted and we get this little nice string here telling us that the fuel should not
be empty.
All right.
Perfect.
So I think you have the hang of this and you can do this over and over again.
Thank you so much for watching this lecture.
Hopefully you are enjoying yourself.
Keep it up keep the motivation up you learn something super valuable is going to help you in your career.
See you in the next lecture.
Good luck with everything.
Bye bye.