All right so we are able to see some information from our table users say we're in a database.
Now what I really want to do and I have going to target one of these yet what I really want to do is
go ahead and why not just add the users add user pilpul page.
Right.
Let's go adding that page where we can use this to our interface so that way then we can start doing
the leading and improving and doing other things right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I like to switch things around.
I don't like to be neutral or like to be boring you know.
The more I switch around from one place to the other the more you learn the more you exercise your brain
and the more information gets stuck in your brain.
Right.
So let's go ahead and let's add users and let's go to the user page right here and let's see how that
looks first.
All right so let's see if we got it right here at the user.
All right.
We're not even going to page yet.
That See includes the user.
So let's go and check it out.
Why that's not showing.
All right.
So you all users these pages are supposed to send it.
No actually the user's page is right here.
This is the one they're supposed to send us to the user and to the user that BHB.
So we need to say as user on top for us to go into that page and now we refresh we are there.
All right.
Perfect what it is is that this page here
we had this wrong right here on the uses that BHB right.
So make sure that you also added this on here as a user.
All right.
OK.
So that is good.
That's good.
All right so what we want to do we want to have the first name the last name the role maybe the user
name email and password.
So let's go ahead and get a couple of these fields in here.
I want to have the role actually let's use that.
All right.
So let's go to view all users not your users I'm sorry users.
So here let's have the first name.
How about that.
And let's just right here let's just call this first name user first name user underscore first name.
All right.
Let's just make it a little bigger.
Here we go.
All right.
And here I want to say last name and this call this is your last name.
Remember these fields this values are different from the database and just naming it the same.
So the way it's all the same all over the place and they're missing something your last name.
Sometimes I'm too fast for my own good right.
What else.
This will be.
So we got the first name.
Actually we went ahead ourselves right here.
This is supposed to be those feels right here.
All right so let me just take that off
and let's replace it with his first name and last name.
We want to be above the category side of that array.
And this is a match.
My fact I want false image.
There what I my want is the image of the user.
Why not right.
And let's just go ahead and I'm going to come in that aisle and we're going to leave that for later
for extra features or something like that.
There's worry about getting this thing done here first.
So we got the user last name here we're going to put the role of the user and after the role we want
the user name.
So let's go ahead and say user name and
user name thing.
Email right here and we've got to change his input
right here and this change right here with e-mail.
That type is going to be e-mail.
That way we have that validation there right.
These are e-mail.
And the last one is a name put here and then just going to copy that one here and just change the title
password.
This will change it to password.
Everything will change the password and user password.
We need to do a check on this anyway.
But
this is the way it is.
So create users mad and this would be user.
All right.
So this is looking OK I guess right here.
Select from users.
All right but I'll have another one.
Do we have another one.
So let's select from users where we're actually we don't need to add where here because this is going
to be adding is not going to be editing.
All right.
So this is going to be adding something.
So what is his value here.
Well what we want to do is play here.
We want to display the role right.
User role right here and we need to get it out of the user role but we need to change all that and the
rest of the names right.
So and of course we need to send the user ID.
Actually I'm sorry about that.
I don't put
licious user ID.
Restoring order.
Let's do everything in order.
User role and
user role right here.
All right.
That's looking good and right here user id verify that that is loose.
That it is the same in the database.
All right.
So let's go to a local B-tree my admin user ID and user roll.
So we're going to sell everything from users and we're going to say select users here.
This data this query is great for a function right.
So select users or select user users and we're going to copy this right here.
Yes.
So our functions can check in this custom function that we got here.
It's right here also.
All right.
Perfect.
This select is going to be the name user role right now right.
All right.
Perfect perfect perfect.
So in the next lecture here we're going to finish it up and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care