All right.
So on this video here I'm going to show you one of the most powerful loops there are.
It's called the For Each loop and this for each loop this loop works only with a race.
The job of this loop is actually through goal to go through an array and go through every every value
on the array and process that value right go through it.
We will need to go through the whole array.
We don't need to tell him when to stop.
It will already know when to stop and we'll stop when the array finishes at the end of the array the
loser say you know what I'm done with all the information and I'm going to stop right there.
Lazlo wow we need when we need it to tell it exactly when to stop.
And the for loop we needed to tell it this one we don't need to do that but this one only works with
arrays.
So let's go ahead and let me show you how that works.
There's Oprah coeditor.
All right.
And I got this follow your open but I want to do a open on the blank that BHP.
Right.
And I'm going to call this for each.
This is the For Each loop.
There we go.
All right.
So the way we write a For Each loop is very simple very similar to the other ones.
All right let's up here tax.
We're going to use the key word for each parentheses curly brackets right.
Now this is where everything changes for each numbers as we use the key word.
Another key we're writing between as number.
Right.
So now remember this works with arrays so this will be the array in this as well turn.
Once the loop is inside the array we turn to each value of the array.
It will assign it a variable quarter number.
So let's create a variable right here and remember everything inside this curly brackets would get skewed.
So if you now understand it don't worry we will practice this in application.
So we have numbers here and let's create an array with some values inside this tree.
Actually this is numbers go forty five again I'm just typing crazy and typing three forty five three
times either.
And I just put my fingers on the key where randomly.
All right.
So we have a bunch of values here.
We got 0 1 2 3 4 5 and 6 values inside is raise call cold numbers for each ray.
Now we'll jump into that numbers raise will get in there and assign a variable to each of these values.
Every time he goes around Remember this is a loop so we go around.
So the first time he goes around first time is right here he's on three 45.
So 345 is going to be assigned this number.
Name this name number.
So 345 is going to be equal to number.
So whatever we can we want to do to that value.
Here we do it right here on the first time.
And then when he goes around again this number is going to be assigned to this and then this number
is going to be assigned to this variable and it's going to be assigned to each of these.
So look at this.
So for example if I wanted to echo our number
and then just going to put a strain here of B.
So that way I can break into a new line and if I click here look what happens.
We went through the array and we echo everything out just by assigning it.
You see that it went in a sign that this number right here is sign.
Each of these values their variable number so we were able to ask to go ahead every time echo this every
time we went around we that the value where the loop were was.
So they knew it wasn't number one.
We call that first pile when you weren't around the first time.
And he was 345.
Then we went he went around again he assigned the variable to the second value and we printed out three
97 and he keep printing everything out.
When you got to the end.
So he found out what the end was with wild moves.
We would have to probably know exactly the values the amount of values that he had inside.
Or use another function just to check for the length of the array for each already knows that lento
the array saves a whole bunch of lines of code.
I should not allow a lot of lines of code but it does save us some some extra steps that we would take
to make this happen.
So the For Each is very useful when we want to go through an array and check on the values and print
everything out or do whatever we want with those values.
It would do it automatically for us.
All right.
So that for each is really powerful and you would find uses for it in the future when you get a little
bit more advanced 2 mph.
Right.
But on this one I show you how to find a for each loop and I show you how to use one.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture here.
Hopefully you'll learn some valuable information and I'll see you on the next one.
Take care.