All right welcome back to the students.
So let's finish this function right now let's just finish it.
Right now we are sending a request to the server and we're getting some information back.
But the thing is that we need to keep constantly sending this information.
We got to fetch our database constantly.
Right.
Well in order for us to do that we got it.
Type in you know execute this function every couple of seconds.
So for that we're going to use a javascript function call set interval.
I think it funny spelling it correctly it's like this.
There we go.
And then in here will create a function well like this and we'll call this function up here every couple
of seconds.
So I'm just going to call it every half hour.
One second.
All right so 1000 would be one second 1000 millisecond because this is milliseconds right here.
All right.
So half a second.
I want to call this functionality.
All right.
We are done actually with this.
So there's nothing to be done here in if done.
If something happens we'll debug it but we are done for now.
Now let's take this value here.
Copy it and let's take it to functions.
All right.
So here in this user's own line function what we need to do is we need to the text of value that we
just copy.
All right.
All right so because this is coming in a GET request remember.
So if it's set and let's just say get in the space that value in there and it's actually move or there's
a little bit to the right.
Whoops.
My resolution is super small so
super small.
Sorry about that guys right here.
I'll move it later on when I make my resolution a little smarter.
But anyway.
So let's go all the way to the bottom here and we can just mark this as it gets requests.
All right he said or something like that.
So that way we know that that's where it is.
And then with that a little bit there.
All right so once we get this get requests what do we want to do.
Well we would like to
include our connection but now this connection is not going to work.
And the reason why this is not going to work is because when we are coming to this function straight
to this function the data base is not going to be included.
We're not we don't have this global connection available to us in functions that BHB this global connection
is available to us in the header only.
So we go to a head or admin head or we can see that we got this connection this deep be right here and
then we got functions right after.
So that's the only reason why it is.
It is available in functions.
So this is not going to be available once we come straight to this function here.
So we need to include it.
All right.
So first of all Will we try to get it but if we don't have it we'll just put another statement here
will say if not connection.
And chances are it's not going to be of any one just showing you what you can do to test it but by now
you already know that.
First of all we started this session because we don't even have a session at this point because this
functionality is coming straight to functions at BHB and we don't have that available here.
So we started the session and then we include.
All right.
The D.B the D.V. connection.
So we got to go back and includes the Wii that Ph.
All right.
Beautiful.
So once we do that then we can start writing our code and make some space here and now go and get this
all these data out from there and pasted in here
and then make my resolution a little smaller I'm tired of my cold being like that.
This is that connection right here.
I'm going to move everything over like this.
OK.
All right.
Let's just come back.
So once we include it we got everything available to us.
So the next step will be to return it because we don't have anything else that can catch this.
We don't have any and all that HBL there to catch this result.
We need to echo it out like this.
All right.
Beautiful.
Double check if everything is working well.
Be working.
Now let's check it out.
Let's refresh.
We are not getting any results here right.
So let's go back here and see what's going on.
So we are including this we're checking if connection is available or if it's not.
We are starting the sessions.
We got we include in this includes the Wii.
This all looks really good.
One thing that we are not doing is we're actually calling the function.
Right.
So right after your function finishes let's call it like this.
Save it.
And now let's go back to it.
And now you don't even have to refresh is already pulling the information from the database as you can
see right here.
Right.
So now let's test this with another browser.
I'm going to graph Firefox and I'm go into right now log in.
Right.
So let's go to localhost.
See a mess and it's right here.
Actually that was chrome sorry about that guys.
Let's go right here.
This is Firefox right.
You just have a huge monitor and Reihan sigh.
And I got to be minimizing this.
So we got which you use or do we have connected.
We have Rico so let's logon swab it real quick.
So let's say sloven and then the password enter.
And as you can see that changes.
Well you're not going to see adding action like this what I'm going to do is I'm going to go to the
online function and I'm going to make this change every five seconds so that way you can see it because
we're not going to wait 30 seconds for the four to two to see it working right.
So I change this to five seconds.
And if it's not active in five seconds this is going to change.
All right.
So I'm going to logout from another monitor for another.
See this.
I'm Logan using Chrome and you can see it on top.
And this is Firefox.
All right.
So on our logo you're going to see what happens.
I just logged out right now.
See that and look at these numbers going to change.
There you see it just change.
See that.
And now I'm going to log in again right here.
So I'm logging in.
Watch this.
So I've got to log in RICO Rico.
Enter now.
Look at that number change you see that logo.
Watch this.
There you go.
You see that five seconds.
Beautiful.
So now we've got instant results coming from our database.
Really cool stuff right.
Anyway thank you so much for being my student.
I'm always thinking about you.
You know if you have any issues any problems just let me know.
Have a great day.
Enjoy your day.
Have fun and I'll see you in the next lechers