All right so in the last lecture we saw how we can go ahead and log in.
Right.
And how this admin is already receiving data from that special user by using sessions like we did right
here we are echoing that section session and we are sending it right.
So we are using the logon to set sessions and we use in the admin header to receive it.
Now there is a big problem here is that actually in that here.
But of course we are we see we are turning it on by using the admin header.
By the way just that's what I meant.
Now we have a big problem here.
It's if we go I mean here or this is where we are turning it on right now again again if we are we are
Logan in every user here that is a big problem.
We don't want just every user that has a subscriber role or admin role to log in.
We just one the admin to log in.
So we need to check for that.
So let's go to the admin Hetter go to admin head or inciting admen includes And we're going to be doing
some checking right here.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do that right here.
Let's open up the HP tag and let's check if the user rule is admitting or subscribing if it's admin
We of course will send it to the admin and if it's not we send it back to the inn.
It's that BHB.
But in the future what we might want to do is actually limit some of these user if they uses as described
We're going to limit them into not maybe adding passwords or adding users anything like that we can
limit them so that that would be an advance probably cause or events lectures right now we got to.
I want to show you about the rules how can we prevent some Surt certain users from getting into the
admin.
All right.
So let's do this let's do this let's do something like this if set and we're going to check for a session
and we are sending a session actually is called use.
If you remember from the logon.
So if we set we're going to do something with it right.
So if it's said we want to convert this rule it said we want to say let's do another Estaban right here.
All right.
So if it's said let's do if
Israel equals to
admen actually subscriber because that's the only one that we are concerned with.
Then we can say header and you can put this logic however you want you can say if it's not equal to
two men or right here if it makes more sense to you like this.
It is however makes more sense to you if is not equal to admen then you can redirect them somewhere
else.
Let's redirect them to.
And it's right.
And let's just get this out of here that BHB something like that.
All right.
So if we say Rico here and 2:59 submit you can see that we can't log in anymore Rico and we can't see
it but it is refreshing to see that you can see right here he just does so quickly.
So right now he's not equal right to admin.
Let's go ahead and make Rico out and see if he can if he if he's able to logon so adman.
Actually I'm not able to log in either.
So what we need to do is we need to go to a database and check another user that is adamant we can actually
convert it into admin right.
He if he wanted to.
So let's go ahead and do that is let's just make recal let's use refresher here may require admin because
we are unable to log in anymore.
So let's go ahead and change into admin right here admin go.
All right.
So now we change our user to admin and see what happens because we are locked down out of our own CMF
do you believe it.
So Rico want to three submit.
Ah that feels so good.
Now we are able to log in to see him as right.
So again let's just recap a little bit on what we did here and I'm going to recap on everything.
But right now let's see we're checking the user role that we are sending from the log in form and right
here.
See that these are all we are checking to see right now the user always getting the value out of the
database and depending on what values he has on the database that is where values gets transferred to
this session right here and then that session we are using it in the admin header right here.
So right now the value for Rico is admin.
So that's a valid is going to be right here.
So he's saying if he's not equal to admin the admin value then redirect into that if it is then he's
going to let him go.
All right.
So this is how we can we can check on that.
Now another thing I want to recap real quick is Logan.
Just in case for some reason you guys did not understand what we did.
Exactly.
All right.
So perfect.
Let's do that right now.
So we are starting sessions because we are going to be using a we've got the database connection of
course.
So we're getting all this information from the log in form right.
So we say we are receiving information from the local form.
We receive the username password we're going to assign it to variables we can clean it up and we can
assign it to the same variables again.
Right.
Because you can change the variables values over and over again as many times as you want.
Then we using we are doing a query to go to the users table where the user name in the database is equal
to that user name that we are getting from the form right here.
All right here now.
And then once we have all that information from the user that is equal to the user name we are sending
in the select query Well this is the one we select when we use this function then we get all those resource
backing here and these variable we are assigning it to these variable then we are testing here.
If it's not if the query is not true then we do this if it is that goes in and we do a while loop.
Then we look to that result right here.
You see that variable.
We look through it and we check all the values we look through all the values and we pull them out like
an array.
Right because it is an array and we assign it to each of these valuables values to a variable once we
assign is values.
Each of these in that is right in this array two variables then we are checking it right here.
So we are checking if the user name that we're getting from this forum right here is the same as the
one inside the database.
And if the user name is not the same from the from the forms on the same as the the one from the database
and if the past was not the same as the one from the database then we're going to redirect the user
back to it if it is the same.
Then we get to signing sessions right.
And these sessions are going to have the user names they're going to have the values from the database.
So right now this is Rico is going to have the RICO name right here.
We're going to sign it to this session right here.
This is just like another placeholder basically like a variable if you want to use say like that.
All right.
It shows that it works different like cookies.
So then once we have it right here in the session then every time we turn on the session with this function
here we can access that value anywhere.
All right.
And then we redirect and once we assign those values values to these sessions we redirect them to admin
and the thing admin We are catching those values in the admin header and we are displaying right here.
All right.
So hopefully that recap helped you understand better for some of you that were confused if.
If you do have any problems you know where to find me.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and you're doing really awesome.
All right.
Awesome awesome awesome.
Don't ever give up.
Keep doing it right.
I see it.
And that's lecture.
Good job