All right so we are able to read the data for our database.
We're able to add some pools.
Right.
And we are able to delete them.
We are missing though the part of the crowd which is at it.
So we're going to be doing that doing this and this tutorial will first let's just take this off here
this is on static content that we got in the view all polls are right.
And actually I think there's gold down all the way and we can see right here you probably saw that and
took it off already but I have not.
So sorry about that.
Let's go ahead and refresh year and wish you have it good.
So let's go ahead and what we're going to do for the edit is that we're going to be creating a new page.
We have to we don't want to do everything on the same page as it gets too cluttered.
All right.
So let's go to admin and we are going to create a edit page edit that the HP
post actually edit post APHC edit underscore it pours post-up BHB enter.
All right.
So we already have a forum here that we can include in the ad on the score post that BHB So let's do
that let's use our form and this just use their words.
What do you think.
I think we are good if we use it.
Perfect.
And the next thing to do is go to View polls actually you will post post PH BE IN HERE WE GOING include
a form depending on the condition.
So the case that we are going to be using for this is going to be and it underscore what polls say is
actually you did it right.
You did a great not.
Great.
So now we won't include that let's copy this one here you said this is getting more is getting better
because we just copy and pasting stuff now.
It is going to get to a point that we're just going to copy and paste most of the queries and functions.
So it's going to be great.
And this just change the polls there.
All right.
So we want Pat when we pass that we get to that we go to that page let's just pass it source.
He calls it post.
So you see that.
All right.
Perfect.
So I'm going to leave it at this here.
I want to make this tutorial Swedens.
It's short and sweet and I'll see you in the next one.
And that's when we're going to be doing some more great stuff.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you on the next video.