Hi welcome back on this video here.
We are going to be learning about constructor's and you might be asking what is constructed what is
that word.
And when I heard it before I maybe you probably never heard it before right.
But well constructors are just methods and methods that would do something when we create an instance
of a class.
As long as we as soon as we create an instance it would do something for us.
Now it's actually easier for me to show you.
So let's go ahead and open our coeditor and let's create a save as this will save us from class on the
scorecard 3 that BHB.
All right.
So right here let's make this constructor class on the score constructor for that we go now and you
can delete a couple things out of here.
This method right here actually I leave that one and only the one underneath and then I delete all this
is does is it calls.
All right.
So what I want to do is I'm going to take this off.
I'm going to actually comment this out and I'm going to show you on the screen here on the browser there
is nothing there showing for this.
Now how do I make a constructor.
Well very simple.
Let's just take this out there underscore twice.
And the keyword construct.
All right.
This is going to make a constructor anes going to execute this every time we create a new instance.
Now I just want to echo so you can see it now and going to as you can see there's nothing here even
if I say refresh but once I create a new instance which is going to be this one I save the file.
You can see that that created executed is automatically.
All right equity's automatically on the screen.
So look what's happening now.
If I go ahead and create another instance and it's called this truck we get another one.
Let's create another one.
Just keep doing it.
And it's called it's mine.
Every time we create a new instance this construct gets executed.
Now you might be asking so why in the world do I need this.
Why.
Well sometimes we need to do certain functions before we execute a program.
For example we can go to the database and check if the user did something in the program or if the user
exists then we want to create some default values or for this specific object or maybe we want to go
inside the special program when we let's say for example just to give you a quick example.
We create the new instance right of car and we have some of the full values we wanted the card to do
automatically we wanted the cart wheels to move we want to be to have gas or I don't know if we have
one the cars to have four doors one the specific values already in there.
All right.
And we want these methods working.
We create a car construct and we pool all this functionality all this in here.
This is the full values.
And every time we create a new instance of a car it could be a BMW it could be a Mercedes or a Ferrari
or porch.
Then we have all these functionalities already or our cars are running automatically wouldn't have to
be calling methods and doing anything else with it right.
We have all this working automatically we can do so housekeeping stuff to making sure that we check
there are programs are actually working right.
By using a constructor and doing some validations on something I mean a construct is very useful if
you learn how to use it.
You're going to thank me for it.
All right.
So anyways I hope you got the concept here of this.
This is a very easy concept.
Very powerful functionality if you learn how to use it.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this video here and I hope you like the information and I'll see
you in the next one.
Take care.