OK I hope you guys having a lot of fun.
Right.
So for those of you that have raised these course less than five stars do me a favor go over their poses
video and go and change that to five stars.
I think this feature is really awesome and I organize it organize it.
Very good for you guys so I receive this service for you to change your story a little bit.
Right.
So let's go back here and let's create a like for this spokes.
So let's do my issue because that's the API that we're using BHB API.
And let's put the connection here.
And what I want to do is I want to create some type of helper function.
I think I did before I thought I did where we just you know have a function that already has a connection
and you just write the query.
That would be nice to have.
Let's look into our you know let's do the after when we refactor code.
OK.
We're going to see how we can make this code our application look a little better.
Every case.
So we going to insert into likes their user ID and the post Id want to know who y user.
You know like that and which polls and then we're going to put the values here to be the user id we're
getting from.
We haven't gotten that far yet.
Let's use get the user id as well.
Remember that we get getting this from the age request down below.
So they use are we getting that and it's Shinsho to user ID.
And here in the valley is all we have to do is dispatch a user ID and post ID simple as a Okkar.
All right.
Perfect.
Maybe that can look a little better.
We'll fix that code later on OK.
But I just want to get this over with and if we want to make sure that we exit this code let's just
put it and adds it right below here.
OK.
So let's go back and let's just empty this out I'm going to double click it and enter and let's go to
like we don't have any likes.
As you can see it's all empty.
And let's go back to here let's refresh Let's make this a little smaller so you guys can see it.
We don't need this anymore.
It's just less click like go back here.
Let's refresh and you can see now that we have a new like is it like table and we have ID number 26
which is the ID that I you know include it as a static value before in our code.
And that pulls ID and is like number one.
OK.
So we successfully creator for us like we have everything we need right now.
Now the next step is to create their own like OWN like functionality because we want to be able to you
know detect if this post was liked by whom.
And if it was like we need to change his bun to say or like and then we need to change every quest tune
like that pose.
And at the same time update everything else in our database.
OK.
So are you guys ready.
I hope you guys are having a lot of fun and I hope this is very useful for you.
See you in the next lecture.