All right so how are these nice really cool functionalities here.
All right we are echoing back the name of the user we are auto completing and I mean we're doing really
cool stuff here.
So what's next.
Well what's next is that we need to actually display the errors right.
We don't know anything yet.
We don't know what's going on.
If we did something wrong here that this form keeps refreshing going back we do not know so let's actually
start with that.
So what we need to do is take this all the way to the top here and just close it out there.
This one and right here in say this form group def which is this guy here we need to create a paragraph
where you can do whatever you want really doesn't matter.
And we're going to do something very similar to what we did here with this one so you're going to copy
this whole thing and put it right here.
But this one is going to be a little different because what we want to check here is the errors array
or error array.
I've got a problem saying to our guys if you haven't noticed you're going to notice any it more now
that I tell you so anyway.
So this error array.
There we go see that.
So if it's set we're going to show if it's now we're going to show this empty string here so let's hope
hopefully it works.
Let's see.
All right.
So we go and register.
There we go user name cannot be empty.
There we go.
User name needs to be needs to be longer.
Geez I just noticed my typo guys you guys on let me know anything user needs to be longer
user.
All right.
So that's the only one I guess.
Come on guy it really doesn't matter much here.
What matters is the functionality.
All right.
So that's working.
Let's go back down to just copy this whole thing here.
Let's go down to this one here.
Now you can of course fix this forum however you want to you make it tidy and nice.
There we go.
All right.
Of course mine looks like that because I have to make it bigger here.
All right so the e-mail we need it password as well.
Now if we go back here see that e-mail cannot be empty.
All right.
I'm being a little picky here.
I forgot my cup at all uppercase E..
All right.
So now let's do the password as well.
Inside the form group def or the deaf with a Class A form group
and password
password.
All right
let's see how this looks beautiful guys look at that.
That's right Don.
And let's just put something here.
As you can see beautiful
see that it's working nicely.
All right.
So what else do we need.
Well we need to make the registry user function work.
All right.
So we're going to do that on the net lecture.
We're going to try to do that.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lecture