All right let's go back to
this right here.
All right approved and subscriber.
OK.
We don't need subscriber right because we don't have that anymore but we do have an approved and approved
comments we should actually have a line for that.
Yeah we don't have it.
That would be nice to have.
But we also missing comments right.
We do have comments already.
It's so up there coming count.
So a proof and want a proof.
Nice.
What are we doing for.
We don't have a proof.
I was going to Mansouri myself.
Guys I'm asking myself.
So after comments we should say a proof so let's make a variable here.
Proved comment count because we want to prove.
So that's going to be very similar to what we got here.
I'm just going to leave that for reference.
Go back here and let's see how we're going to do this.
So get all user approved
comments off post comments
and let's make another copy here.
And this one will be on the pool.
All right.
We're going to have to do some adjoining tables again to make this better.
I'm going to copy all this from here.
Just because I don't want to type Control key my key word to delete all this stuff oh
any Anyway let's just paste it.
Let's just paste it right here.
So to do approve comments Garrow user comments.
We are going to join these two tables and we're going to say and comment
status
should be approved.
And that's it for that I'm not even going to copy it would go.
And this should be a proof that can not be so simple guys right.
That cannot be so simple to do something like that.
That's why you guys.
Some of you love me because I know some of you hate me for some reason.
I don't know why.
Let's go and say get this to account for us some records and let's to get user
approve comments or let's make sure that this is approved here.
And not in that I forgot to make sure that here after spending comments we have approved comments hoops
and I forgot.
Approved comments.
I'm going to give you an idea here real quick guys every time you have done something with is make sure
that you also all day you loop here that should be serving I believe.
Let's go back and take this all the way to the top.
And for some reason this one is not working says undefined function get 0 user draft polls.
Oh really.
I deleted the posts.
Whoops.
Yeah looks like I did.
OK
I don't even notice.
Make sure you don't.
All right.
So let's go back.
It's why I love my ID.
Right.
There is refresh here.
And yeah it looks like we have categories count here but there's two categories.
Let's go back to categories real quick and let's see what we got.
We had two categories for their use.
Let's make it one and let's go to approve comments and comments it looks like we have no comments for
the user OK.
Well they're not approved.
They won't improve comments so they should be pending we should have a pending come here.
We don't have it.
So to do that or to approve come and count get us right here
refresh.
And while we have wow we have work in the world.
I didn't know we had winds over each
images make it five year.
I'm curious to know
yeah we all have one.
Want one of each.
Yeah.
Was that one up or even the guy super nervous.
I was like why did I do so.
That looks about right.
Let's change some here to make.
So that is Elise
go.
That should be taught in a pool of comments just to make things a little better.
Fresh two pending two comments.
OK.
That's awesome.
All right that's looking a lot better.
I think we're done with this one.
A Come impending come it looks great guys.
I don't know why you guys think we're done with this dashboard.
Maybe in another section we'll jump into creating more personalized pages in other parts of the mess
like the view will pose categories and so on.
They should be really easy already because I am showing you how to do it with a dashboard which is basically
almost the same thing.
All right thank you so much and I'll see you on then that's lecture's enjoy you guys.
Take care.