Walk them back with your students.
So.
So now we have this working or composer working or emails being sent we're using character sets here.
I mean we use an prepared statement you got a lot of things going on we have learned a lot in this couple
of lectures where guys.
Right.
I thought so.
So now what we need is we need to send our code ok into our e-mail with a link.
So when people click here they can go and be varify in our application but we still don't have that
page where we can send that.
But let's actually before we build a page.
Let's actually build the functionality and then once we build the functionality we can build that page
okay to accept those values.
So and to get this functionality this to put the links is super easy is actually right something your
analysts say
Please click
to
the set your password something like that.
And of course what I want to do is of course I don't want to put that in the H-1
or be BHB and that's going to bring out all the way to the bottom.
Let's actually create a link here.
And this is close I say click here.
The fact we're going to include the whole
link with the code in the anchor desk just because some people don't have the ability to get links on
their email.
Believe it or not.
So we have to go to.
Let's say you put the name of a Web site here.
In our case it's just a development server right.
Mine has a port of a C mass.
Yours could be just local host probably and reset.
The HP is a page.
Remember that we need a parameter for this to work.
So we got to send the parameter later on but right now
just know that actually let's just do the parameter now.
This is going to take an e-mail.
OK this parameter I'm going to cut this off right here.
And when I go like this I'm going to concatenate the e-mail variable here OK.
And then when ampersand going to put another parameter there come back here real quick.
And it's going to be I'm going to concatenate the.
Let's do this here real quick and this we'll be talking here like this OK.
That's it.
I mean
so let's.
Actually get the same thing
here like that that looks good.
OK.
We can test this
going to go to every.
We have not created yet.
So let's actually test this is see if it works.
Email there.
OK OK.
Let's come back here.
Corteen
OK we're going to take that off.
But you can see here we have the link.
When we click on it we go to a page that does not exist.
The e-mail is now working as you can see.
Well the e-mail here is like is broken
e-mail programmers are not being passed after that email so let's go back and see where the fail so
let's inspect this
actually.
Here
that should be the problem there.
OK.
You got this email
back here.
A quick
This was good and my editor is not giving me any errors.
Let's come back here let's just put this up here.
Go trying to escape it automatically we can if we want it to escape some of this code and just make
it more readable.
So e-mail we can Kartini that then we can cottony this with a code
OK.
We break here.
Finish that.
We start with the one which is a string
OK that looks pretty good to me let's try it again now.
Come back here.
Whoops.
What happened.
Here we go that's working like this.
I got to we got to fix that a minute.
At
according to
I'm not going to work like that but I was able to get in that page.
So we were able to get in this page.
You were going to face that on the way.
Keep
Oh I see both of them right now.
If it is not good or if it's and if it's not he has to be built for this for this to fail.
That's why I have the word right.
Jesus guys I really really really really.
So if I make a mistake or one of these this is not set
and you know let's go back here and that's and I said we've got it we've got to come up with a better
solution for this so if it's if the method is not set to get met it's not set or this is not forgot.
Then we redirect.
The problem is that when we click here this refreshes and it doesn't have this field like this.
OK.
So we got to cancel that.
This is going to take one of these guys out for now.
Later on we come up with a better solution.
I don't like this solution year because of these conditions they don't they don't meet.
We can't find a better one to do it.
All right now.
Just do it like this.
It really dysfunctionality.
It's something that we can work on later on.
Work out with the logic.
I really don't want to mess around with this right now.
We'll we'll get something a lot better later on.
OK.
Well right now let's do it like that.
That way we don't we can play around with our stuff.
OK.
So
and follow faculty and this just resend this Gray was sent.
Let's play around with this.
And of course was always on the site can be reached where you can see the talking's here and the e-mail
is there.
OK.
So that's working.
My server was down for some reason before.
Nice working.
OK.
So that's working.
Our link is working.
Now let's on the next lecture let's create the reset page and all of the code that we need for that
page.
Thank you so much for watching guys and I'll see you in the next lectures.