Welcome back my students I hope you're having a great day in this lecture here.
We are going to be validating.
All right.
They use every little bit that way.
You know we don't submit data that is not empty well not data wouldn't submit forms like these that
are empty.
For example if I click here now and I go back to here you can see an empty field right here so we don't
want to do that we don't want to have this here.
So let's go ahead and fix that right now.
So the way we're going to be doing this is super simple.
All right we are going to be checking on these fields right here to see if they're empty and we've done
this before many times.
If you want to go ahead and pause the video and do it you know you can go ahead and do that.
Well now what I'm going to do is I want to check first in my file we can do it from up here if we wanted
to from the top.
So we're going to say if whoops if it's not him.
There we go.
And I'm going to put this a couple of times.
All right like this.
And so we're going to check if it's not empty.
They use their name right.
The e-mail.
So we've got this and the what password.
That's right you are right.
All right.
Let's open our curly brackets and close them right away.
And let's just copy and paste all this stuff in there right.
Right.
From here.
Going to copy this thing and I commend ed to actually you and paste it there.
So now we save and we go back to it.
Remonstration right here.
And I try to submit something actually that school its users.
Is open there.
You can see that nothing has been submitted.
All right you can try it many times and refresh this in nothing there.
All right.
So keep that in mind.
We're good to go with that.
All right.
So now what I want to do besides this is that I wanted to also give the user we want to give the user
some type of notification here saying they cannot leave this feel empty right.
And also when they submit the form we also want to give them you know some type of message right.
So let's go ahead and do that right now.
So the way we do that is super simple once we finish writing all these Square-D down we know that it
works right here we're going to set a variable and we're going to put some strings in this very well
we're going to say something like your registration restriction has been submitted.
All right.
There we go.
Perfect.
Now when they submit the form are they going to get this.
But what about if they don't.
So we also need to make sure that they have a valid date we have a validation for that by a message.
So if it's not if is empty then you know if it's 90 it is empty so we need to put something for that.
So now of course we need to equity's this variable somewhere else here in the form and I'll show you
in a minute where but right now let's just finish this fields.
Words can be empty.
There we go.
I'm laughing because I'm making so many typos they're so fast.
All right.
So we got to make sure that we put this somewhere here too.
So right here below this for am I going to minimize this a little bit so I can see my form better.
All right.
It's all right here.
On to the form element.
I'm just going to put in a h sits and I'm going to make this a little bigger so you can see it sits
and some DHB in there.
I need to get down to completion feature.
Hopefully they maybe they have a plug for this editor about that.
But I've got to look it up.
Anyway so we've got to equity's message right here.
All right.
Right now let's make sure that we also make this test straight.
You know when that line is tead So we're going to put a class here of touch center têtes hyphen Center.
All right that's going to center this message we don't want this message to be all the way to the left
like he's defaulted to do.
Now another thing here is that if for some reason we clicked we don't click submit this BHB is going
to be looking for this message here and he's going to be empty so that's going to cause an error.
So let me just show you real quick.
You see that we've got this arrow here because the variable is undefined right now which is actually
trying to equil but is not in there right.
So what we need to do is right below here and this is the main if statement.
The first one right here you can see that it lie onto the curly bracket.
There we do a now statement and we are going to be making that variable empty.
We don't want to display anything there.
We don't need a variable so we're just going to make it empty.
So now if we go back and we click enter nothing is there.
So let's just go ahead and submit something right to see if it works for us.
Let's check this one.
Register fields cannot be empty.
That works.
Let's check something else.
And you can be as great as you want.
You can make this maybe put a class here or EQ or something inside here.
I mean think about it try to be creative you know.
There are many different ways of doing this.
You can put on javascript thing here I mean and I show you how to do that in one of the videos from
before.
How you can click here and have a pop up box open and say you know something to the user but I prefer
they use it to see something.
Têtes But anyway let's go ahead and submit on this I'm just going to call this gambit from the X-Men.
Remember those cartoons that were pretty cool.
Well some kids still watch it.
I don't watch it anymore.
Of course not guys.
Come on.
And some passwords.
There we go and register.
And as you can see here says your registration has been submitted.
All right let's go back to Weidmann.
Actually we can have it right here.
Refresh and you can see that the user was submitted.
Now we're assuming the user with the first name the last name will let them come over here and edit
and put their name right Robert.
And then Sandro.
I don't know if anybody's name like that of the user.
And we go back here and we could see that there.
All right.
So that's a way of doing that.
All right so anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I see you in the next one.