Or write.
So welcome back.
Well the last video we did a really cool thing and we started playing some dynamic categories from my
database for my table right here on the categories right this information with splaying and dynamically.
Pretty cool.
So now the next step is we could actually do different things.
But I want to be able to take it to the meat of the project.
Of course I want to be able to start displaying some of this content here dynamically.
So for us we could do the search engine later and we can do.
We can do this later.
All right.
We don't need to worry about that now.
Let's do the meat right now.
Call me because he's actually like really important.
So we need to make a table for this first.
All right so let's go to our peach be my admin Let's create another table.
All right.
And then just click on CMOS and click create another table called Polsce be all s d s not actually be
all s ts posts so you can see right there last year is created with seven rows.
I think we need columns and on this we are going to be saying we need a post ID.
It's going to be an integer and it just makes this a little less where we don't need to see that right
now it's a matter of writing we can click there and you take the whole stream that we go with and it's
too big here.
All right.
So plus ID is going to be an integer.
That's why I N T means it's going to be three characters it could go to 9 9 9.
That's what he means let's make it in that primary and order increment.
Let's create another one.
Let's call this post Id actually pulls category ID.
It's fine.
This is going gonna be using this to relate related data.
This table with another one right.
So we're going to create relational data relational tables.
All right.
You can look it up on Google but that's when we relay data to other tables with one table.
All right so category ID what else we need we need a post title.
I think we should put that tile title.
There we go.
And I wrote it again.
Here we go.
Let's we're forgetting that we need to put this out of our cars for tets to files to do the math on
this for car.
Actually that's an idea and I'm sorry.
There are cars and that's one of them make it three.
There's a make of our car 55.
And what can we put in that's after the title.
So we got that.
Actually the author is the first thing on our site right here.
We don't need to going order by the way we can organize it laid on with BHB.
But I'd like to do it like this.
I think it's nice to do that.
So we have the post title and then we have the author and the date post title plus alter
2:55.
I think Postie was and that's we don't need to do it like that like I said but we're going to use a
date field in that one.
We don't need to provide that.
And what else can we do here.
Post I think let's go back with this post picture and content is the next so Paul's image pulls content.
All right.
Let's make sure that the images are têtes.
Just in case.
And post content is têtes.
All right.
And I think we're good here and this just clicked safe.
As a matter of fact I forgot something.
Let's go back and let's create this post.
Let's go back to this.
Check this out.
Another idea actually let's add two more.
You're going to hear three more actually.
All right.
Because we want to add post tags here so that way we can use the word search engine for keyword look
up and we want to add common council that where we can count to comment for this specific post and status.
All right so we're going to be doing this in order post and we say that the posting the first thing
that we need is Polls come and count it no poll tax I'm sorry and I'm asking you and you all the way
over there.
Can you answer me right.
That was not nice right.
Post comment count and spell status.
All right.
Status.
All right so far card 255 on all of this post tax could be pretty long.
I don't think we all read 255.
That's fine.
You can make it touch if you want.
Both status.
We are going to be using tax.
We could use zeros and ones just to say that I oppose is zero we can deny it.
Well why not.
But I got to say if our car to 55 and I'm going to set up the fall for this fall for the polls are going
to be denied.
Right.
Or actually draft draft.
All right.
Actually you know what.
I'm not going to even do that right now.
We can do that later.
We can said this later like this.
Actually let's do it right now I'm sorry let's do it right now.
Lol you can see how this works.
All right.
So folks that is come and count both stocks were good to go and let's just click safe.
Perfect.
Let's go back to our structure and we have everything here is to make sure that everything is spelled
correctly.
Content posts.
Come and count.
All right.
I think I do.
Good.
No grammar problems right.
So I think this video is long enough for this lecture here so I'm going to see in the next lecture what
we're going to be doing some more work.
But we on this one here we created the pool table and we added some some of these fields in here some
of these roles.
Right so I think in the next lecture.
Take care.
Thank you