All right welcome back I'm a student so my name's Edwin Of course I'm used truck to but I'm Edwin from
the future and I'm here just to make things a little bit easier for you.
All right.
On this blog and up BHB we have created this blogging functionality but this is now working for everybody
right.
Some of you are having issues.
Maybe not maybe yes.
But I come here just to make this functionality a lot easier for everybody.
All right.
Even though in the future we're going to be changing this into a more advance and easier system.
Believe it or not so in later lectures many probably many lectures after this we are going to change
this because we're going to be adding a lot more lectures you're going to see a lot more lectures in
the course.
But anyway let me make this a lot easier.
All right.
I wanted to show you how to use the L F and ignore that in the course because my goal was in the past
was to show you and still is was to show you how to use all the functionalities all the things that
you learned in the course in the course in the beginning to apply to see a mess.
So that's why I created some of these functionality using else if any else.
But we can make this a little easier and let me show you instead of having this not checking if this
is not equal to this we can say OK let's just make sure that this is equal to that.
And this is equal to this.
And we can make it very strict by doing three equal symbols.
All right two equal symbol makes it equal.
This would make it identical.
So it needs to be this just to make sure that the pass were in use in this pass when this pass is exactly
identical.
But anyway.
So if it's the same.
What we want to do.
Well we want to set some sessions so that way we can use them later.
Whoops right there.
All right so we got the sessions and then we ran.
We want to redirect to admin and we don't need this one and we don't even need these.
What else if here.
There we go.
All right.
That means check the curly brackets.
See if they match this one matches.
And this all matches the function idea up here.
All right so I hope you see what we did.
Super simple.
If they use any from the form and they a name from the databases are the same and if possible from the
form and the puzzle from the database is the same.
We set these values here and redirect to outman else.
Something went wrong here and then we redirect it back to when it's super simple right.
But anyway thank you so much for watching.
Hopefully this will help some of you out there and I'll see you in the next lecture