All right so we are getting the comments and we are able to see it we're missing from the formation
of course.
The only thing we're doing is displaying the comment from here and the other thing is we are able to
create it from the front of the Web site of the same as we are unable to do any Krout right now here
like delete edit or and approve approve any or anything anything like that.
But what we will be doing on this lecture here is relating this comment to the post where I put the
title of the post here and when we click on it it's going to take us to that specific post.
It's going to be great.
All right.
So let's go ahead and start doing it right fast right there.
Let's go to at Main includes viewer comments and here where you see that you see the heading right here.
All right of this table we're going to go after i status.
We're going to go to in response to this song title right there.
All right.
So that would be right here.
Static songs start again.
The male there and we were going to remove that and make sure that we have a Querrey So let's send the
Querrey in.
The first is whether we're going to be writing is to select everything from posts we're going to bring
on data from posts where what they call them post ID Igor's we do you remember what we did with the
post ID when we submitted that comment.
We save it we saved it somewhere right here.
This is where we say that when we submitted the form.
All right so if you want to if you are lost make sure that you go back to the home site right here to
this lecture where we created this little forum here.
Every time we send the form we are also sending this parameter right here.
Right.
And then we are saving it in this common post ID that we are bringing out of the database right now.
All right so now that we have that what we need to do is send it in.
So we select false ID Kohary and are going to send it in my ass.
Q And may I ask you a lie.
Corey
Perry right.
Im going to send it in with a connection.
And we can use a while loop to loop through the resource set well to get that resource set back
my ask you lie.
Fred you're going to use this function to bring back
on back to bring in and always have an issue with his fetch f t c h that s t c h is really hard for
me to get in in my mind anything related to DCH it's on today for some reason I guess.
Language barrier you know because I speak like three languages is a problem.
So when you see me struggling with it I know that that's what it is.
So I got some learning to write hopefully you can forgive me for that.
So we're going to get a post I.D. out of the database and assign it to a variable.
We're going to get a post-Idol out too and this time my hands are going faster than my mouth right there.
Perfect.
All right.
So hopefully we didn't make any mistakes if we did we will probably be blogging in a minute.
All right now let's get this going.
Let's echo this out here
and we need a link right here.
So first let's go ahead and see if
this is actually this plane so how right.
Let's go ahead and check it out.
Admen comment and is already this plane.
Beautiful.
As you can see here we go back.
We see this example three right here.
When you click on it.
So that means that this coming is related to that.
You see it.
All right.
Perfect So it's coming in.
Let's get a link here at Tref let's close it
and get the closing tag for that link.
Let's put that right in the middle here.
All.
Let's make sure that we don't make a mistake here and we're going to send this outside twice because
when we got to come out of the admin and they included go to the root and that's going to be the post
of BHP
and going to BP I will be underscore ID.
He calls the post ID.
Hopefully we get it right.
All right.
So feeling understand what I did.
I'm going to recap a little bit right now if not just forward it and you should be good.
All right so what we do here is that we are making a Querrey from post where post ID which is the column
in the database in the table.
All right Igor's the post ID this post ID we are getting it from this field right here.
And this field contains the post ID from here.
As you can see this coming right here has we have this you are able parameter right here.
Right.
And when we submit the form we're picking it up and saving it in the post composts ID field.
And when we save it in there so we have that value right in this case.
Let's say for example we have that 34 here saved there.
So when we are making this request right here
right here we are saying I want you right to select all the poles where the post the column is equal
to that pulse ID whatever pulse ID we pass it we are on right when the loop is going around.
So right now if we have 20 of them every time we click on the link right now it's going to send that
to that specific false ID.
So anyway let's go to the back here and let's refresh and you as you can see we have the link.
If we click it we go to that specific post.
All right.
So let's test this again and let's just actually make post make a comment on one of these polls right.
Should we have some polls.
We just have to make comments on them.
This one.
Let's make a comment on this one here.
And then supposed to and let's send in a comment and let's call ourself Sandra Yeah we are actually
using girls names now because we have some girls or some women taking these courses and we have to use
them also.
Why not.
All right.
Ed and I are going to say anything about it right.
Ed I think I think your course is good.
All right.
So Mitt perfect submitted.
Let's go and check it out it.
And we could see that Sandra Sumida that post beautiful.
And let's go to outman and let's go to comments.
Let's see right here is on the proof of course it would click on they would take us to that post perfit
we click back.
Let's go to Polsce right.
Perfect.
So we can see that here and these IDs sets and then propose to.
In response to this polls.
Perfect.
This is looking better and better every time.
So we are done with this.
We laid in this table with the post table and on the next one we're going to start doing this crowd
right here.
All right.
Perfit thank you so much for watching.
And I see you on the next lecture