Hi welcome back.
I'm really glad that you are watching this lecture here and you're going to be learning a lot more on
this one.
I promise you that.
Now let's go ahead and get on with this.
Now we had some functionalities here actually some features but we haven't added functionality yet always
the functionalities and we haven't even done that yet.
But anyways we started right.
That's what's important.
So on the last lecture here we added a an array right here on this input as a value for this name match
review.
And of course you know that his name actually will send information via posts.
We have a form by here and we need to catch a song where the are is going to be every time we click
on one of these.
Something we need to send the ID of this specific post so we can do things with them when we select
the right here and click on these buttons right.
So this array saving each of these values we need is something there that we save many different values.
An array is a perfect container for it.
An array can hold as many values as our machine has memory has.
And you know and it's great.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's go ahead and catch those values and do something with them.
So right now we have we know we have this array right here and we need to catch it.
All right so we are going to be going all the way to the top of this form and before eating this phone
starts we're going to be writing some Ph.D. I'm doing this because it's getting kind of crowded down
there with a lot of Kohary.
So let's go into this right here.
So first we need to check if it's available because we don't want to start doing things if it's not
available.
We all get errors.
So the way we do this is by doing of course using the post-Super global because we use in post data
right here and we're going to be checking for the name of this array which is check Bhatt's array.
Let's just double check that's the name right here.
That's the name I'm just going to copy.
We don't need to put his brackets there.
We're just checking for the name right there.
All right.
So we're good to go there right.
So let's make sure that we put a that we are receiving data on she's going to say something like receiving
data.
Let's check it out.
So if we come here and we select all this and we click Apply we see that it says receiving data.
All right.
Now we can do a little something a lot better than that.
We could actually print out the IDs are coming out right.
We could do that if we wanted to.
But anyway let me show you now how we can do that.
So what I want to do right now I'm just explaining one single type of data or just one string.
Because right now there is not there is no loop going around this is an array but I need a little to
go around to through these array.
So what's better then to use a For Each loop that takes care of us takes care of that looping around
to the end of the array.
Right.
You mean.
So let's do a four each.
And what we need to loop around is this Ray right here right.
Perfect.
And then we're going to use the keyword as because we are going to be assigning.
And if you don't remember how to write a For Each loop go to the to the course on top of this CMOS section
and go to for each loops.
Right.
And make sure that you understand how it works.
We're going to add the key we're ass and we're going to be looping through each of these values and
we're going to be naming it check.
And this is a custom variable that I'm making up.
I can put any variable i want.
Basically what we're doing is we are going through each of these fields right here I am assigning a
value to each of this as we loop around.
All right.
And the reason why I want to do that is because look at this if I want to echo the value every time
it goes around you say call.
And if I go here and they say plie actually right here I got an error on line sets out to do for each.
OK of course I have a narrow there because looping through here and I have to there should only have
one.
Right.
I have to.
All right.
So if I click here and I click Apply you can see the IDs 37 and 30 now this plane so it's looping around
already.
Perfect.
All right.
Before we cut this section off I want to take this out of here.
So what I really want to do right is we need to name this select right here.
We need to actually give it a name on the value and because we're going to be picking up this value
soon.
So let's call this Baalke options.
All right.
We're going to be checking his value see your book options and we are going to be taking this as a post
like this and going to copy and paste this one right here actually.
I mean the confusion what I'm doing is Hoopes
is basically picking that value from the select in assigning it to a book options variable there that
I just me there and I'm doing that because we're going to be using this book in a switch statement.
But we're going to do next lecture I'm going to keep this one short.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture on the next one we're going to be doing so more
and more advance really cool functions.
All right.
Take care and I see you then.
Take care.
Bye.