All right so we are missing a couple of things here.
And we're going to finish it up on this lecture.
So we want to display the categories dynamically from our database.
We also want to have this image here and we want to fix this so let's go ahead and start doing that
quickly.
So let's go ahead and fix this.
And this is just very simple fixes put it in the beginning of that and maybe you already did that so
the image is another quickly very quick fix.
We just put an image there.
This source is going to be in the images in the root directory.
And of course there's no ises just two dots there.
We're going to do a Ph.D. here.
Let's make sure that we do it correctly though.
We don't want to make mistakes their false image.
As you can see here I was the something that I did with all other
elements.
All right.
I just put the path here and the name of the image and let's do a with because if Now this image is
huge so we don't want it to be that big.
All right so let's check on that refresh.
We've got the image and we fix this.
Perfect.
Looking great.
All right.
So the categories Let's go ahead and work on that.
We don't need this input here.
Actually take it out.
And this work on a select element there the amount and this like this.
And on this select just going to put a couple options but I'm going to do this options dynamically.
So I'm going to do a query for the categories we want to do is one of these play all the categories
from our database right here and they select
right right now select doesn't have anything.
So if I refresh you sees empty right here we won.
We want to display some stuff from the database.
Right.
I already have a category selected somewhere in the Update section actually right here.
So I'm just going to copy this update categories.
Remember that includes files in the admin.
So I'm just going to select that go to Edit again face studding here.
All right.
So we're going to change a couple of things here.
Select categories who took the idea out there that keyword based right here.
And we have this entire query for us.
There's one thing that I want to change and I probably did not tell you about age that we have a function
here with a misspelled name.
And let's go to functions and here this function if you brawly you didn't name it correctly but I didn't
put a name here and he's supposed to be and then to confirm this is how you spell confirmed C O N and
I misspelled it there.
I might do that once in a while but it really doesn't matter as long as the functionality is good.
But I want my code to be a little cleaner.
So I corrected that and I also went and corrected it in the ADD post right here right.
Well we used that function because right now I'm telling you this because we are going to be using it
right now.
So make sure that you correct it too if you want it.
You don't have to correct it but I want to because I'm going to use it again.
All right so I'm going to use it right here this function
just to confirm that this query will be good.
You see that but it's going to be Kohary right there.
And when you get to use these result that's what it's called resultset.
And we're going to use that query to confirm it that function.
All right.
So here what I want to echo is an option element mail option and I'm just going to go here and make
one because I got him to help me out with that.
And that's the plugin I use with this to remember that let's make this sim go cold's here.
This cords to enclose that in the echo.
Perfect.
All right.
So we have that what do we want to echo here and between these we want to Eccl. cut Title right here.
That's what we're going to call.
You can even lie down.
You can just put the brackets if you want around it.
This is from the future and coming back here just to fix a little Boothville you know that my little
brother Adam from the past just may right now.
9:16 OK.
Nice upset with me.
Please please don't tell him I came back to the course and corrected his lecture for him OK.
He's going to get really upset.
But anyway on 60 if you notice on the video this element right here don't worry about what I got outside
because it's not the same code.
Remember that I'm from the future so I'm just giving you an example and telling you what to fix.
But anyway this is going to be a long 60 on the video make sure that you put the category ID right here.
OK.
Because if you don't put in this value field is not going to be carry in the select element name attribute.
OK remember that this guy right here is the same as the same value as this guy right here.
OK so make sure you have that value which is probably empty right now.
That's why I came back to you guys.
OK so nothing is always good to have your post category ID OK.
This idea here is always good to have it here or have a name for it so that way maybe later on you want
to style this element.
The select element you always have some type of hook into that but you can always leave it empty it's
up to you.
All right so see you.
Maybe I don't see you in the future but you know if I see you that would be good and bad but good to
see what your lecture guys and take care of Hopefully you are enjoying the course.
But by and I think it should work fine right now.
If I enough of getting anything let's check it out.
I write function is not working and that's a function of relief as we go to functions.
Confirm it is make sure that function is
calling frm
make sure that the same name has to be the function
let's compare it real quick.
It is the same name.
It might not be the function
to edit post.
Let's take the function out just to check it out.
A quick and check it out.
Refresh it is a function right.
And the reason why he's giving me that is because we haven't saved here safe refresh still giving me
a problem misspelling something and not doing something right here.
That function should work.
Actually we are doing this the wrong way.
There we go.
We're not supposed to be having that where you statement there.
Refresh.
Perfect.
See that.
So now we have all of the categories here Karaite right.
So we display all of the categories we've got right here.
And if we add another one for example example category category right there we go back to few posts
and then edit we could see that simple category popping in here.
All right.
Perfect.
Great.
So I see your next lecture where we will update the form when we submit it.
We're going to create a query to update the form and he's going to be great.
Thank you so much and I'll see you then.