Welcome back my students.
So it's not for us to start pulling information out of our database so that way we can make sure and
verify that what we getting the information we're getting from the link in the email is the right information.
But most of the right user.
So let's start by creating a prepared statement.
Real quick we know that we need an if statement OK just like we did in the last lectures and we are
going to create a variable here right away.
Make sure that we put this there first connection parameter is a connection.
Second would be a query.
So let's make the query here you've got to learn about making a select query with prepared statements.
So let's pull out the user name.
Let's do the user email and let's do this.
From users where remember that we are going to get this value from day you are on top gain we using
question mark remember that.
So let's create a couple more functions.
My rescue you lie as a.p and when I'm buying the parameters
we are going to get a string on that you are.
And of course you know what let's create a variable because we're not going to be dealing with getting
this and the you are out now.
So let's create a variable without value so that way we can test it out.
Let's go to the database and get that code that we have there.
For that specific user
space here
okay.
So that's where we got combined bind.
Remember that we are going to be buying
to this here to this question mark Okay.
So the next thing to do would be to execute this code
than we want to fetch it.
Maybe we want to close this close statement when we are done with it.
Okay.
So fetch.
Let's just close that a quick
So here this fetch function this function is going to actually you know what
we need another function here.
I almost forgot we need a we need to bind the results by bind results like this so that way we can pull
out the information from there and we're going to do it in order.
We got this column here so we want to put it down dollar value in a very cool user name.
We want to do the same thing with email and incenting with the code.
There we go.
This is make sure that we're well we're not sure if it works yet.
So we're going to call something from the database.
We know we're getting the username from the database right.
So let's check this out to see if it works.
It's so fingers OK preset BHP and it looks like it works.
So we're pulling that value of that column that it has a talking to that you're pulling out the is any
good.
It's working great.
OK.
So that's the first part.
Dan what I want to do is if let's compare some of this if let's say the get request from you or I'll.
It's not equal to the one we get from the database or
get email
is not equal to the one we get from the database.
Then we want to redirect to something we can actually fix this and make it better later.
I mean I'm pretty sure you can come up with some really good logic for it.
OK.
You can make a small bowl for them.
You have to have to pass bowlful it's going to have to pass for this to work OK.
Right now making it so.
Any color here does not match well.
The one we got from the database or the e-mails that match we redirect right away.
OK.
And I'm going to actually comment that out for now.
And we have to work on
the form fields.
We're going to have some form values here down when we click on it.
OK.
We need to make sure that in this form here has passwords.
So we need to make sure this passwords match just two values here match.
Before we do anything else and we also have to hash out the password because what we do what we are
going to be doing here is we are going to be hashing the password from this form so we can insert it
or update the field in a database.
OK.
Because we are going to be updating this field here.
That's what we're doing.
Well we got a hashed out first.
OK.
So we're going to start doing that the next lecture.
Guys thank you so much.