All right so we got a lot of functionality here already we can add categories.
We are reading it and we can delete them.
Now let's go ahead and of functionality to edit the categories right.
So what we want to do is add another form.
Let's copy this form right here.
All right.
Once we copy it then we go here and see it in action right there.
Well actually it's not in action yet but he will be so high.
So this is a couple of things here.
First let's change it edit this name the value name let's change this name also here.
And it actually let's call this update.
Why not.
Because that's what we're going to be doing updating right.
All right.
So I think we're good here and the next thing is just to create a BHB.
So just to let you know what we will be doing right now is adding a link right here on the right hand
side.
So if you want to post a video try that on your own you can.
We're going to add a Edit link and when we click it we're going to be able to echo the values from this
site here.
And then when we click here it's going to update it.
All right.
All right so let's do that.
So let's open a BHB tag and of course it's going to take me all the way to the right.
Love that right.
Love that.
Let's make a.
As a matter of fact we do have this square down here when I use that instead.
There's this whole thing here.
Why are we writing stuff down again.
When we have it here.
Perfect.
Great thing about copy and pasting right.
So we're going to edit a couple of things here so we're going to select categories where why ID.
It's a matter of fact before we do that before we get we getting ahead of ourselves we need to add the
little link right.
So let's copy this and paste it like to do a lot of copy and paste.
It says a lot of time don't you think.
I know you think so let's change the parameter that we're sending the key of D get super global which
is going to be added now and that change the link right here at it.
Right.
So we're going to have to catch it here right.
So we're going to say if it's set and what it is is set get what.
What was the name of it again.
The key at it.
That's right.
You got it right.
All right.
So I said we want to do all these squaring all this great stuff that we're doing right here right.
All right perfect.
So we want to catch up make sure you catch it right here cat and name it something else right.
Put the variable to get a value.
So that way we can see the value in a more flexible way I think a variable would do fine for us.
So we're going to say where can idea which is a column in the database in the Categories table equals
what can you post a video and guess and think a little bit.
Got ID right here.
All right.
Just to get requests variable there.
Perfect.
So let's change this a little bit and let's call this what you want to call it select categories or
no ID that's fine.
We want to make a little different right because we already had these very well down there and we don't
want it to conflict with anything.
All right so this resoled is going to come here.
And once we have this what do we want to do we need to echo something out but we need to break out of
this loop here so we can put some mail.
We need to make sure that we catch that right here before we have some arrows here.
Right.
Make sure you catch that BHP opening right here just to get this BHB curly bracket.
The reason we did that is because we wanted this whole piece inside the loop of the amount right.
And here we're going to have to make a.
This is where this value here is where we're going to put the we're going to be echoing the value from
the table right right here on this value at you.
So what we want to do is if set actually.
Let's do some PSP here.
We're not in ph period.
I forgot.
So BHB let's close it down and we are ready to raise one pitch.
So if it's set
we want to get actually the cat title.
That's what we want to check for.
If it's then we want it if it's set we want to echo title.
All right.
Hopefully we get some arrows and this time I don't want to get it perfect all the time is fun right.
So if you think having errors in your code is fun make a discussion and let me know right.
I think it's fun but that's just my opinion.
You have your own opinion.
All right so let's see.
Let's check this one more time here.
Make sure that I think we're good.
I think we're good.
What do you think.
Right we might have a mistake or two out of I not even want.
I don't even want to check right now because I want to have some type of mistake in our code.
Guess we're missing something all right so why can we possibly be missing.
And it isn't.
All right so we have we are missing.
Unexpected.
You and line a 7.
What could that be.
All right.
Real mistake really well right.
So the reason how come my can't be that easy can be that easy.
Now we go and the file on my 98.
Yes.
So we are now close in something great.
So bump bump.
If this set AGCO this and it can be that easy either I might make a little harder make a little right.
So anyways if we click on edit then we get the added value right here.
We click on edit again we get the bootstrap but we king of data right now we can do that because we
haven't actually made the query for that yet.
I know I know I know we have to make the query lead for another Viti What do you think.
I think this is we are already getting too long for this.
So anyways I'll see your next lecture.
And it was a pleasure like always.
And we're going to be doing some other techniques because I don't want this bunch there to be on this
forum like this.
I don't want to be there.
So we're going to be exploring.
We're going to be importing this form or another place in our CMF system.
So that way every time we click it it appears here we will not see anything in the beginning just like
we did in the Demel demonstration.
Right so I'll see your next lecture and take care