Practical Tools-Business Rules.
Continuously document your Business Rules as you attain them.
As we mentioned, Prototype, Wireframe,
and Mockup workshops greatly enhance your knowledge
and understanding of Business Rules.
Create a document template for a screen's Business Rules.
This'll be comprised of screen name, screen purpose,
references to User Stories or Use Cases,
screenshot of your Mockup,
description of each and every element on the screen Mockup.
So, let's look at a graphic on the next slide.
Practical Tools-Business Rules, Part 2.
As an example,
you can use a word processor and get a screenshot of the
screen and paste it into your document.
Practical Tools-Business Rules, Part 3.
This is a very simple model that you can certainly improve on.
Build a table as follows: Column for the control name,
a column for the control type, a third column for behavior and Business Rules.
Each control type has its own mini template to fill out,
one for text boxes, drop-down lists, grids,
et cetera.
This greatly enhances requirements understanding and data mapping.
Practical Tools-Data Modeling.
Continuously document your Data Model throughout your
requirements gathering life cycle.
Prototype, Wireframe, Mockup workshops,
and writing the Business Rules greatly enhance your
knowledge and understanding of the Data Model.
Create a visual representation of your data model like the one below.
This greatly enhances your understanding of the Data Model.
Delivering Requirements.
So, how do you deliver your requirements that you gathered to the customer?
Remember your stakeholders?
Each stakeholder will have different needs and should see
different views of the results of your requirements.
The product owner stakeholder receives the product definition document,
Prototypes, Wireframes, Mockups, Business Rules,
Data Model, probably not, but maybe, priority list of features and estimates.
A financial or senior management may receive product definition document,
plans and schedules, budgets, and resources.
And, remember,
you may have several other stakeholder types that may receive different parts of your requirements gathering documents.