Welcome to this course unwrapped back in India.
My name is Gaurav and I'm going to be the instructor for this course.
I've been doing software development for over ten years and I'm going to be sharing my knowledge what
I've got regarding the tools, especially the back that is used widely, and we ought to be building
a frontend application.
And this is especially true in the current world where we have this single page application all around.
Generally when we use the single page applications, we are using some sort of skills for building those
applications.
But behind the scenes, most of the skills are using Webpack for bootstrapping your application.
So we are going to be seeing exactly how those calls work and what they do behind the scenes.
So this is have overview of what this entire course contains.
So we are going to be starting off with the basics of Webpack.
And in this we are going to be seeing some of the core concepts such as the loaders, the plugins and
also modules.
Modules is really important because this is the fundamental of the entire application that we're going
to be building.
We are also going to be seeing different kind of modules that as the commandeers types module as well
as the S6 kind of modules.
Okay.
Once our basics are sort of cleared and we know what we are doing with that pack, we are going to be
seeing some more in-depth concepts such as Hot Reloading, Dependency Management, Thesis Module and
Dynamic Import, and all this concept is going to be actually implemented on a project.
So I've created a simple thesis project and we are going to be implementing all this concept on a live
website.
So we are going to be having a very good understanding after this project.
Okay.
Once we are done with this project, we are going to be moving forward and check out those optimizations
that are provided by Webpack.
These optimizations are such as the mundane analysis because the duplicate prevention and the reloading.
So these are some of the advanced concept which are going to help you make the application even faster
and also debug things, which is not going very well in your application.
Okay.
Once you are done with the optimization in the same section, we will also see how to be making the
production graded in the production grade.
While there are a few tweaks that need to be done to develop that configuration file and these are the
changes that are required when you are going to be deploying your website on a life server which your
end customers are going to be using.
So in this, we are also going to be seeing concepts such as dead code elimination, the concept of
shaming, if you're using some sort of old library like the equity and so on, and also CSR splitting.
So these are some of the concepts that are required when you're doing the deployment and also fixing
those errors, which can be sort of tricky to solve.
Okay.
So moving forward, what we see next is building a React application with Webpack, as I told you.
Webpack is sort of the fundamental piece when you're building a single page application.
And in this course, I'm going to be taking the example of a React application.
However, please note this concept can be applied irrespective of React.
You can also be using the same thing on an angular as well as on a view application, although some
tweaks will be required as per the framework that issues.
Okay, with that done, we are going to be going to the final section and this is the most important
and the detail section and that is the micro friends.
So micro frontend is a very new concept and it's a very popular concept, especially in a bigger company.
And we are going to be seeing how do we developing a application from the micro frontend perspective.
We are going to be having five different applications that are going to be coordinating among each other
and that is going to give you a final understanding of what is micro frontend.
So in this we are going to be building a movie booking application so in which you can be thought of
selecting movies, seeing the details of the movies, and finally selecting your seats to do the booking.
So that is about it.
On what we are going to be covering on a very high level in this course, and let's dive in and explore
that back in detail.