Welcome to a brand new section on Lord of Lords as one of the fundamental things that you are going
to be using when you're going to be creating of a back file.
So what exactly is Lords is going to be covered up in the upcoming sections.
But just to give you a heads up on why I've kept a dedicated section for this is because whenever you
are going to be trying to load different kind of file types, let's say JavaScript images, forms or
styles, you're going to be using this concept of lords.
You might also need in your future project to be loading maybe a HD HTML file or JSON file and loaders
is what is going to be helping you with that.
So that's the reason I've kept a dedicated section just for loaders.
Now, once we have implemented loaders in our web back configuration, we are going to be having an
output, which is a combination of all this different file types into this single bundle.
So that is the importance of loaders.
So let's just dive in and see how are going to be configuring this loaders.