Hey, guys, welcome to a brand new section.
And this section is all going to be about optimization.
We have covered the basics in the previous section, and now it's time to take our baby to the next
level.
So far we have just seen how we are creating the bundles, but we're not really seen what's going inside
the bundles and how do we really optimizing and using the true potential of that fact.
So what are we going to be covering in this section?
Well, first of all, we are going to be analyzing the build that we created in the last project.
So all this, what are you going to be doing?
Optimization is going to be on top of the last project.
So once we analyzed the build, we are going to be figuring out that there are a couple of issues that
need to be fixed and we are optimizing it further.
So the main issue is going to be how do we removing the duplicates from the bills?
So we'll see that a lot of libraries are getting loaded again and again, which is not the right way.
Finally, once we have all those optimization in place, you're going to be seeing that the build size
has dramatically decreased and this is going to be improving our load times as well.
So we'll also see things such as pre shaking, how do we moving our styles to a separate library and
so on.
And these are the things that are going to be really optimizing our web backbone.
So if I just talk about the pack being used in production, if you have used something like React of
View or maybe Angular, you generally might be using this here and all this configuration is being done
directly for you using those gels.
But we are going to be seeing exactly in the section how things happen behind the scene.
So I'm really excited to present all of this to you.
So let's move on and see what are the optimizations we can apply to our configurations.