We are in a brand new section and in this section we are going to be covering up things related to react.
Now we have seen all the basics of our pack and in this section we are going to be seeing things specifically
for the React application.
Now, if you have worked already on React application, you must have used a React scale.
And through this, we are bootstrapping the entire application in the back end.
The React scale actually uses Webpack and that's how everything works.
You have things such as preloading, you have the dependencies, resolving and a lot of other things
and that's taken care automatically by the react like.
Now in this we are going to be seeing exactly what happens when this react really works.
So I've just created a sample React application and we will be just seeing all the concepts on this
application.
Now, let me just give you a small demo.
Well, there's just two pages, so not a lot of demo to give here.
Anyways, we have this login page and we are not going to be really entering any of the values here.
So if you just click on sign in, we are taken to the speech, which is the movies I wrote, as you
can see on the top, and many of you see a couple of movies poster.
And this is somewhat related to what you see on Netflix and so on.
Okay.
So that is all about the application.
You can also click on Designer Button and you'll be taken back to the sign in page.
So a couple of things happening here.
First of all, we have these two pages which are getting loaded.
Then we have also set up the routing through which we are routing from one page to the another.
And this is a fundamental difference between what we have been implementing so far in the other applications.
So I've just created a small diagram here.
So as you can see, we are in the browser and we go to some localhost, 3000 and this is where our application
is hosted.
Now in general, we are having multiple entry points.
So for example, if I built this entire application using a traditional approach, there would be two
A.T.M. files.
And we would just go to those appropriate email files and do the navigation.
And in our back configuration, we would be needing the two entry files as well.
Well, things are quite different when you are in the React application or any other single page applications,
you are just going to be having a single entry point.
So for example, this is our single entry container.
And in this container we are loading the pages that is required according to the route that has been
accessed in the browser.
So in this case, in other config, we are just going to be having one entry file.
Okay.
So that is one of the fundamental difference.
And we are also going to be implementing the previous concepts of loaders and plug ins.
And we will also see two additional new concepts.
So the first concept is how do we using the Babel loader now in case of React is we have the Gsx format.
Now Gsx is not really understood by the back end, doesn't know how to compile it.
So for that reason we are going to be using Babel.
And we are also will be using another plugin that is the post CSS plugin, which is going to help us
enhance the thesis that we write in our application.
Okay.
So once we have that, then we are also going to be adding one additional plugin to check how well our
code is written.
And this is the first linked plugin.
So using the years later to list out all the common errors and we are also going to be adding some configuration
to.
Yes.
And we are going to be specifically going to be using the Airbnb excellent configurations.
And that is pretty standard in the market.
Okay.
So that's about it for now.
Let's continue on and see how we can be building React application using Webpack.