We're going to be starting a brand new section.
I'm really excited to present this project to you.
We're going to be using all the knowledge that we have used so far on how to be loading external files,
how to be using the plug ins, and going to be applying to a real project.
We are going to be taking the case of a legacy application that was running without any backpack or
without any tools, and we're going to be optimizing it to use Webpack and get the all the modern things
running in that website.
We are going to be encountering plugins which are directly imported in the mail files and see how are
we moving those into the JavaScript and how do we setting up our back configuration to make the development
very easy?
So what are the things going to be covered in this section?
Well, we are going to be seeing how are we doing the import of the JavaScript and the thesis.
So this is something that we had gone through briefly in our previous sections.
We are also going to be seeing how to be refactoring our entire website so that is more that back friendly
and easier to deploy in a real production environment.
Similarly, we'll also see how are we moving the assets?
So right now we don't have Albert fold already for doing the deployment on a real so.
So after moving the assets into the build folder, we are going to be actually able to just pick up
the very folder and put it on any static web server and the website should function as expected.
So that is going to be a very big win for us.
Similarly, we are just going to be seeing how we are managing multiple dependencies.
So dependency management was also seen briefly here, but there are a lot of dependencies that we're
going to be having already added to human file.
We'll see how removing those dependencies into our JavaScript and also between different pages.
So that's what's in this project.
So it's going to be combining all our knowledge so far and putting it all together in a single website.
Okay, so I'm really excited.
Let's move on and see what this project is all about.