Welcome back.
You continue on from the last video.
In the last year, we had created couple of functions and we exported them using the module dot exports.
Now we're going to be moving on to the newer format, which is the S6 format of using the import and
export keyword.
So let's see how that works.
Now we're going to be just transforming all the things that we had done earlier.
So we more to the actor just fighting.
Now, when we want to be exporting, using the ES6 format instead of putting module or export, you
will say export default, and then you put up the name of the function.
So that's pretty much it.
So this is how you're going to be exporting using the ESX format.
So let me just go ahead and do the same thing for this attract file as well.
So remove all of this and see.
Export default and then subtract.
All right.
So that is done.
Let me close both of this hard and subtract.
And let's head over to our main roads.
Now, whenever you want to be importing these functions, using the import keyword.
So what you're going to be doing is you say import ad from and then the name of the file.
So in this case, the file name is Slash and.
Okay.
So that is pretty much it.
Let me just quickly remove this from here.
Well, actually, we can keep this.
We can just remove and make it as and remove this additional function that we created earlier and remove
the function call.
So that is all the change that you have to do.
But if you try to execute this right now, let's see what happens.
So I'm going to be again running the same thing.
Node means mean.
Just make sure you are in the right folder.
So once you have that go, nothing works.
Well, why is that?
Well, because the import keyword is not understood natively by Node.js.
Node.js only understands the common JS format by default, and we need to sort of teach Node.js.
How do we dealing with all this import and export keywords?
Now this observer back comes in.
Now, if you have used React or Angular, you might be very familiar with the import and export keywords.
And generally you'll be having some sort of compiler behind the scene, which is going to be helping
to compile all of the import and export keywords to the native format with JavaScript.
Understand.
Alright, to be fixing this, we are going to be creating of a pack file.
Now I would highly advise you to go ahead and create the pack file with me because this is going to
be helping you understand and revise SteveA pack concepts again and again.
So what we need to be creating the web back file acted all of our folder.
So in this case the two dot module is our root folder.
So just right click here, give it a file name as Webpack, not config digests.
All right.
Now we're going to be using the format we had seen in the last video, which is the common format for
exporting the modules.
So it's a module not exports equals to an object.
Now in this, we need to be giving the two key perimeters most of the entry.
And in this case, the entry is dot slash.
Mean Darth Jesus.
Okay.
And we also need to be specifying the output.
So output file name.
And the second thing we need to be specifying is the path.
So we'll say path and we need to be importing that port module.
So again, milliseconds apart equals to require.
But.
All right.
Now.
If you do not really understand the concept of part, I would hardly advise you to go to the section
of JavaScript introduction in which you are going to be discussing this part module.
Okay.
Now we have the part module exported so we can see but not resolve.
And in this filter directory name, this is underscore two times.
And then we put up a comma and see this.
All right.
And we are going to be giving the filing.
So let's call this as bundle, Lord, Lord Code.
So that's done.
Now, since we have the part, we also need to be initializing this as a NPM repository.
So what I would do is again, going back to our two modules, we need to be initializing this, so I'll
see NPM in it.
BASH Why?
Okay.
So our NPM repository is now initialized.
Now we can install the mandatory dependencies against NPM, install that and PMI in chart and dash dash
save dev.
So it's going to be saving it as a dev dependency.
And the two dependency that we need is Webpack and Webpack Theola.
Let's give it a quick minute to install.
All right.
Both the dependencies are now installed.
Now, what we can be doing is we can be start running this back file.
Now, last time we ran the web back file, we went to the package or Jason and created some script to
run the Web back file.
Let me show you another way of running the Web packed file.
So instead of using the script in the package or Jason, we are going to be using this here for running
the Web back.
Now, how do you run this relay?
Well, you can just see and be exe that back.
And in this we can pass in the configuration file.
So I'll just put in a dash dash config and the file is that back door config dot.
Yes.
All right.
So this is the first parameter that we need to be passing.
The second parameter we need to be passing is the mode.
So we'll say mode as development.
So this is exactly the thing that we had written in our package, not Jason earlier, but now instead
of writing it or whatever, just running it as a command.
Now let's click on and don't make sure you are in the right folder once again.
Okay.
So as you can see, I made up a mistake in my package and my configuration of a pack solicitors booklet.
Go and fix that.
Now I'm just doing all of this life and I will make mistakes.
And I hope you learn from my mistakes.
I like what a mistake I did over here is we created an object and added a semicolon.
So you cannot have semicolons in an object.
So let's remove that.
Save the file.
Clear the console and run that once again.
All right.
That is done.
We can see that it compiles successfully.
If we have the disk folder in that, we have the bundle dogs now to be running this, we can just see
Node and we can go to the folder called List.
And in that we have the bundle.
So we'll say slash bundle radius.
Awesome.
Now we can see the output is three.
And if I go to my main file, you can see that we are now running using the import and the export keyword.
Now the pack knows exactly how to be handling all this import and export and it's not really dependent
on what Node knows.
Cool.
So we learn something really exciting and new and this is all happening behind the scene and I hope
now you understand how things happen behind the scene, which is very important.
Okay, one more thing I would like to show you.
Let's head over to our files so we have the functions add and subtract.
Now, similar to how we are exported named export in the required order, we can also do it in the newer
format, which is ESX format.
So let's see how that works.
Now if I want to be doing that, what I will do is let's probably do it from the index dojo system.
So we are going to be replacing all this required with import.
So I can say import add from add and import subtract from the local file.
Subtract.
One more point to note here.
We do not really add.
The dog's extension goes by default.
It takes it as Dodger's file.
Okay, now as we learn to live, we are not going to be using module that export and we're going to
be writing here as export.
And this time we are not going to be putting up the default keywords.
Instead we are just going to be putting up object and say add, comma, subtract.
So that's pretty much it.
Now, if I go back to I mean, Dodgers file, I'm not going to be importing it from the file as percent.
Instead we'll say import.
And then we have the named imports from Dada slash functions.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
And they can have the ad right here.
Now, if I just compile my file using the pack once again so we can see using the CLIA.
So is our client executed?
Now, if I type in our run commands so I can say node and just slash bundle dogs.
Alright, things still work as expected.
Now let's suppose you going to be importing all of the functions that are exported by this, you know,
functions our indexed ideas.
How do you do that?
So what you can do for that is you can be removing all of this and say import star as.
Let's suppose I want to be giving this alias name as maybe a dollar sign.
Why not?
So once I have that done.
So what I can do now is instead of saying just add, I can say dollar dot.
And so basically we are aliasing the all the functions that are there in that library to a dollar sign
and then we are saying dollar on that object and then calling the function called ADD.
So things should still work as expected, running the CLIA once again, clearing the console and saying
Node well and as you can see, things still work as expected.
So that is pretty much about it.
All the basics about the new format, the six format, and this is going to be very useful irrespective
of what they are using, whether you're using for Webpack or maybe for some other project that is dependent
on modules of JavaScript.
Alright, let's take a short break and continue on in the next video.