Welcome to the implementation video on routing.
So we have already created this application called as the movie application, which is going to be obvious
application and it's going to be containing all the other applications.
I also mentioned earlier that we are going to be utilizing library called as the reactor outer dome.
And this is going to be helping us to do the navigation.
Now, on a high level, what happens on the movie application is we are going to be having this reactor
outer dome setting or here, which controls the navigation.
And using this, we are going to be loading the appropriate application into the container.
So for example, on the default out, we are going to be loading the home page application.
So the home page application looks something like this.
All right.
So what happens when we click on any of the items on the homepage application?
So for example, we have this movie card here.
So when you click on any of the items, we are going to be getting an event, right?
So whenever you click on a on element, you get the event fired.
Now this event is not going to be handled directly by this homepage application.
Rather, we are going to be passing that event to our movie application because all the routing logic
is contained in this movie application and not directly in this homepage application.
So for that reason, we need to be sort of passing this callback to our movie application, and then
the movie application is going to be calling one of the APIs of this recruiter DOM History API, and
then it's going to be pushing the new application in this container.
So for example, when you click on this, we need to be going to the details bit.
So it's going to be basically removing this home page application from the rendering container and plug
in this details page application right here.
So that's on a high level what's going to happen and how this communication channel is going to set
up.
Now, this is what we are trying to implement.
So let's go to a code and see how this looks on the code.
Okay.
So I'm back in my code base and you can see I already have all my applications already running.
Make sure that you have all your applications on so that, you know, we do not face any issues.
And let's start of making some changes.
So first of all, we need to be sort of exporting our entire page so that it can be used by this movie
application.
So for that, I need to be going to the pages.
So, for example, we can go to the home page application.
And if you open this source folder and if you open up the components, we can see that we have like
two components.
We got like the home page component and we have this quick booking component.
Now, just to give you a visual perspective, let me just open up my browser.
And in this we have this quick booking a component, and then we have this home page component that
is the entire page.
So if I just go back to the code and if I go to the App Store, this you can see that, you know, this
homepage is the main component that's being used.
And within home page, we have the other conference, the quick booking conference that we saw on top.
So in short, we need to sort of expose this enter home content.
And this is going to be the entire page that needs to be loaded as the default route.
All right.
So what we are going to do next is, as usual, so whenever we want to be exposing something to an extended
application, what do we do?
Well, that's right.
We go to our Web back config and start exposing things.
Now, this is going to be interesting case.
You can see that already there's a remote set up and we are also going to be setting up an exposes.
So a program can have both the properties can also have some remote entry files as well.
It can expose some components.
So that's the power of this module federation plug in.
So let me just put up the new property here.
Let's call this as exposes and let's set up the object.
Now, as usual, we need to passing our string as the key.
So that's going to be, let's say, home page.
And then we need to set up the road that is going to be slash SIRC slash component.
Slash home content.
Slash home content, tart sex.
Okay, so just make sure that your part is correct.
If this is not right, it's not going to really work.
Now, since we have made some changes in the back file, we need to be restarting also.
So let me just go to my homepage application server.
So that's right here.
Let's switch start off by saying Control Z and try to start that off again.
So NPM run.
So.
Okay.
So we have our applications starting off and we see the same output as before.
I'm just going to be closing of all the other tabs so that we don't get confused.
So close other tabs.
And that's looking good.
Okay.
Let's go back to our code.
So the component is now exposed.
Now, to use this component, we need to be going to our main application.
So that is the movie app.
And in the movie app, we also need to be importing it.
So if I do go to the web back config, so we do not have any configuration yet set up for the module
preparation.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So as a concept, curly braces equals to require the PAC dot container.
And in here I say module federation, plug in.
Okay.
And if you just go to our plugins section.
So that's right here.
So I'd say new.
Module Federation plug in and pass in an empty object.
Now, in this empty object, I need to be first giving the name of this application so that can be as
let's suppose movie app.
And then we can put up the file name as a remote entry dot gs and then we need to be setting up the
main thing that is the remote.
So I set up the remote and what are the remotes that we need to be promoting the homepage?
So let's call this as.
Home page.
And in here we need to be putting up the application name of the homepage.
So that is as well.
So that's right here and we need to be seeing where it is hosted.
So that's one step, that's SDP double call and slash slash local host.
And then we need to be putting up the port number.
So the port number is 3000 of the home page application.
So that can be added here.
Then we see remote entry dot.
Geez.
Now just make sure that the remote entry file convention is followed.
Exactly.
So for example, we have the entries capital and we here also is capital city.
So just make sure that it is the same.
Okay.
So that's done.
We can just save this file and get our movie application reloaded as well.
So that's my movie application right here.
Stopping this hour and starting that off once again.
All right.
So we have our movie application set up and this is the route out.
So you can see the homepage and this is where we need to be rendering this entire page.
So let's go back to our code and we are going to be going to our movie application.
So let me minimize the things that are not being used and let's open up our easy in movie app.
In this, we open up the app dogs and we need to be replacing this right here.
So in here we need to be putting our dynamic component.
So as usual, how do we load a dynamic component values to react or lazy for it?
So I would say concept.
Homepage.
Equals to.
React.
Not lazy.
And in here we are going to be saying import.
And then we need to be specifying the application name.
Now, if you remember what is going to be our application name, it's the name that we set up in the
movie application and through which we are importing it for that homepage.
So we need to be thing homepage or here.
And then we put up a slash and then we need to specify the module name so module name can be found out
from video importing it.
So that's in the home page Webpack config and or here it says that the exposed property is this so we
need to just copy of this home page.
Exactly.
And have that pasted here.
Okay.
So once you have that done, you should have the homepage component ready for usage so we can actually
be removing all of this and instead of this and what are we putting up?
A suspense block?
So this is suspense.
And in this I'll render the homepage just like that.
Okay.
As usual, we also need a fallback position that's required parameter.
So I'll just put up nail file back here as usual.
And we are actually pretty much done.
So let's check out if our application is working as expected.
So let me go back to my Chrome year refresh and if I just try to see what's wrong, we do not really
see the output.
Right.
And if you go to the console, there are a lot of errors.
So what are these errors?
Well, we are going to be finding that out in the next video.