Similar to a homepage wrote, We are going to be setting up the trout for also the seed booking page
and the details page.
So for that, I also need to be making some changes in both of those applications.
So you can just do it along with me.
Or if you want to be pausing this video in practice along, you can do that as well.
Okay.
So I'm just going to be making the changes in the details page app first.
So I just go to the back configuration in here and let's go to the plugins.
And in this, you see that there's no plugin for by the Model Federation.
So let's just go ahead and add that quickly.
I would say content calibrations because to require.
And in here you'll see the Webpack dart container.
Now, this is sort of repetitive tasks, but we have to be doing it.
So as say module progression, plug in and go ahead and do the implementation.
So in the plug in section as a new module filtration plug in and set up the configurations.
So as usual, this is going to be having the object name.
And in here we'll see.
Details.
So that's going to be the name of our details application.
So in, say, file name as remote and tree dot.
Yes.
And then we also have the exposes object in which you are going to be exposing the details.
So I'll just say it as details page.
And then location of this page is going to be slash.
That's our key component.
And in this let me just verify the name quickly.
That's detailed.
Content.
Details.
Content slash.
Content dot gsx.
Okay.
So we have done this configuration.
Now our application is not going to work because of that bootstrapping as you are in the last video.
So we can quickly go and create those bootstrap files as well.
So I'll just go ahead and create a new file in as I see folder calling it as bootstrap, not Jess and
move all the logic from indexed ideas into bootstrap dodgers and import this bootstrap file right here.
So just like that.
Okay, so that's done.
I can just quickly restart my soul of details page application.
So let me just find that.
Stop the solo and see and run.
So once again.
Okay.
Our application has started of the things are not displaying completely but us.
That's okay for now.
So the same thing also needs to be done for the seed selection application.
So I can just close this off or not open up my seed selection application, go to my CRC.
So first we can probably create those files.
So in ACL, call this as bootstrap dot.
Just move all this index dodgers configurations into bootstrap and import this bootstrap right here.
Alright, so that's done.
Final thing is making changes in our config.
So I'm just going to be doing this quickly and you can just follow along with me.
Okay.
So we got our module filtration plugin initialized and imported in the plugin section.
So as a module filtration plug in.
And then the name as let's call this as seed selection.
So just know that I'm keeping everything in lowercase.
So I just like to keep it like that when I'm doing the naming convention for the Moral Foundation.
If you want, you can change it as well.
Then second is the file name as as usual remote entry.
Dodgers.
And finally, the exposes object.
So I'm going to be exposing this as seat selection.
And then this is going to be in the SRT folder component.
Flash.
Seat selection content.
So I'm just going to copy this name from here so that I don't make any mistake as switch.
So I'll just copy that name and paste it here.
Let's do the same thing for the G6 file as well.
I'll copy the name from G6 and paste it right here.
Okay.
So both our exposes property has been set up.
I can just save this file.
Now, before I forget, I also need to be adding that shared property.
Otherwise application is not going to work.
And when we are trying to import it and don't mean application, we are going to be getting the same
error that react as being initialized multiple times.
So let me just add this shared property and in this field I'm sharing both react as well as react.
Dom I actually forgot to do do this in the details page application as well.
So let me just go to my details page and GoDaddy Webpack config.
And in here also we need to be adding this shared property.
Okay.
So let's restart both of this application, the seed selection as well as the application.
Those top two so started once again and parents of.
Okay.
So our video speed application is working fine.
Let's do the same thing for the seat selection as well.
So stop this huge selection server and start it once again.
Okay so I seed selection application is also running now for the final changes we need to do is we just
need to be importing this into a main application.
So let me just get rid of all this open tab so that we don't get confused closing all of this unused
directories and open up our movie application.
So in the movie application, we need to be first importing all the external applications.
So we enter the module federation plugin.
So we just have one remote for now the homepage, so we can add the additional remote here.
So let's call the other remote as let's see.
Details page.
And this is going to be coming from one location.
And then we have the seed selections, I would say seed selection.
And this is going to be coming from one of the place now just to verify the names, I'm going to be
opening up the of a pack files for details application.
So in this the name is given as details and this is running on port 3001.
So let me just base this or here acted it as GDP local host and this is running on port.
3001 remote.
And three dot G's.
The same thing can be done for seed selection as well.
So let me just probably copy all of this and be strictly and make the changes.
So in the case of seed selection, our application name can be got from the back.
So let's select this from here and paste it right here.
And the port number also need to be verified.
So that's running on port 3003.
So let me put that here.
And the remote entry file limits them.
All right.
So that was a lot of configuration update in many applications, but does I hope you really understand
the concept of importing and exporting the modules?
And then how do we setting up the remote and how do we exposing the components?
And once we get a hang of it, it's quite straightforward and sort of repetitive task.
Okay, so we have all this stuff set up.
The final thing that we need to be doing is we need to be going to the movie application and within
that we need to go to the app charges and set up the routing.
So similar to this homepage application, we just need to be importing the other two also in the same
format.
So let me just make multiple copy of this and call this as detail speech.
And let's call the last one as.
Seat.
Selection pitch.
Okay.
We need to be importing both of them, so I'll just probably have this side by side so I don't have
to switch every time.
So in the case of the page, we are going to be using this key or here and put it over here.
That's how it works.
And then the component name is going to be received from the of a back file of this and it is a remote.
So we can just open the backfill.
So that's right here.
So there's this desperate application about backfill.
So in the backfill, if you just go down to the plugins and we see this is been exposed with the name
called Detail Space.
So I'll just copy that.
Make sure that you copy all of this instead of just typing down because even one later over here, maybe
the capitalization is going to spoil your entire application is going to be really difficult to debug.
As you know, what really happened wrong.
So my advice is to really go ahead and copy all of this names instead of typing it down.
Okay.
So we have got the details.
Space now is the seed selection.
So we copy this parameter from here.
The key value from the movie applications, Webpack based it or here and then the component name can
be received from the the backfill.
So in this case we go to the seed selection.
Open the back config.
And in this we have exposed it with the name as seed selection.
So let's close that and paste it right here.
Okay.
So let me just bring everything here so that, you know, we have enough space and we can see what's
happening.
So we just imported all the three component pieces over here, as you can see, from different locations.
Now we just need to be using them.
So what I can do here is I can sort of remove this booking page with three had earlier the dummy out.
And in this case, I'm just going to be copying and pasting the suspense part or here and instead of
the homepage, we need to be loading the, as you guessed it, the booking page.
So now kids booking page is part of this heap selections and this is the selection page.
The same thing can also be done in the case of detail space.
So remove all of that, put the suspense block here and instead of the home page, we are going to be
loading the details page so that details page.
Okay.
So that was a lot of configuration update.
Right.
And I hope you are able to follow along because this is a lot of repetitive task.
We are not adding anything new as such is just the normal exporting and the importing of components.
Okay, so once that all is done, so I'm just going to restarting starting my movie application.
So because we had added this, remote standards aren't going to be found immediately.
So let's find our movie applications on that right here.
Stop the server and started off once again.
So NPM runs off.
Okay.
So just give me a read that the identified media space has already been declared.
So let us go back and see what else the mistake we did.
Okay.
So I can see that I already have this three dummy applications that we're importing earlier so I can
actually get rid of all this imports that we're using earlier.
And we need to be pulling up all the pages dynamically this time.
So we just need to be keeping these components alive.
So let's just save that and let's see if things are working as expected now.
And congratulations, you got your first micro frontend application working including the routing.
So for example, we are on the router out now.
If I just hit slash details, we get the details page.
So that's excellent.
And similarly, if I just go to the booking page, so I see slash book and we get the booking page and
the booking component of the seed selection component loaded here.
So our entire application is looking, using routing and that that's a really good achievement.
Now we're going to be taking things further and see how we can click on components and do the routing
and what are the kind of challenges that we're going to be facing over the.
And one more thing.
If you get stuck in any of the part and I know it's quite easy to get stuck because you might be having
some name convention issues or maybe some copying pasting was not done properly.
So in that case, what I'm going to do here is I'm going to be copying the entire project up till now
where all the navigation is working into a new folder.
And I'm going to be starting off in a fresh folder in the next video, so you can just copy along all
this 11.1 folder, all the things that are there in this 11.1 folder and get your application started
and follow along in the next video.
So that's it for now.
See you in the next one.