In this video, we're going to be figuring out how to be clicking on this book button and then navigating
to the booking page.
That's the seat selection page.
Now, it might look at first that things are quite simple.
We are clicking on this component and we are navigating to this detail page.
So same logic can be implemented on the book button as well.
Well, in fact, you're not wrong.
It's absolutely correct.
You can do that.
But let me show you what is the challenge that you're going to be facing.
So let me just switch over to my V as Gordon.
I made up a small diagram here.
Now, in the case of the homepage, the homepage had all the components at the main level.
So this was where we had all those movie cards, and we'll just click on that.
And we had a callback function which used to be passed back to our main application, and that's how
we are doing the routing.
So things were quite straightforward.
We just had like one callback function and that's how everything worked, right?
Now in the case of quick booking, quick booking is a separate component altogether, and this component
lives within the homepage, and the homepage is embedded in the main application.
So we're getting deeper down into the component hierarchy.
Now, in the case of two levels, we can sort of do an implementation using callback where the quick
booking is going to be passing a callback to our homepage and the homepage is going to be passing a
callback to our main application.
But just imagine if you have four or five levels, this is not a very practical approach.
So I'm going to be showing you a different approach to do this, and that is using the React context.
So this implementation more from a React perspective.
So if you guys are not really interested in reacting, can just follow along and do the implementation
and you might learn something new.
So those who have already used this context API, it's going to be quite straightforward.
So let's see how this can be implemented.
So let me just switch back to my code base.
And in this we are making a couple of changes now when we're doing the navigation, you can see that
I need this history object so this history object should be present in my homepage.
So that's right here, right now we're not passing anything.
So what I'm going to do over here is I'm going to be passing in a new object here or new parameter here,
and I'm going to be calling this as a routing.
So don't make any changes here because this is what the perimeter of this home page application is expecting.
Now that's already been coordinated there.
So in this, we are going to be having to calibrate it because I'm going to be passing in two objects.
So first one is going to be the history and then the location.
So what I can do over here is within curly braces.
I can say history, comma, location.
So that's pretty much it.
I'm going to be passing both of this because in future, let's suppose you want to be using the location
to read something from the you are.
You can do that as well.
Now one general question might be coming in your mind is here, why can't I just implement this a.k.a
outer dom in that application since that is also react application, right?
Well, you're sort of right, you can do that.
But this is not going to really work because the application that is maintaining the instance of your
routing is the main application.
So this same instance or the same object has to be passed down further to the other application so that
they can use the same object for reference.
So whenever you initialize it like this, a new instance is created and if you try to do the navigation
using a new ID instance, it's not going to work as expected.
So that's the reason we are passing in the same instance as a property.
Okay.
So with that said, let's just come back here.
So we have posted outing attribute along with the history and location.
Let's just save that and move over to our homepage.
So let me close this off and open up my homepage application.
So let me close those details up.
We don't need that for now.
And iMovie app lets us open up the home page app.
Okay.
Now how the context API works is we need to be creating a context for us.
So for that, I'm just going to be creating a new folder and in that I'm maintaining the context.
So let's call that folder as utils and index the returns folder.
I'm going to be calling this as a routing provider dot gas.
Okay.
So in this, we are going to be importing react from React.
And in this, we are going to be creating a context as a concept.
History.
Context equals to react, not create context.
And in this we want to be passing a default value as null.
And I'm also going to be exporting it as our default.
So as the export default history context.
So this is how you generally create a context which is going to be used by the consumer as well as provider
of the context API.
Now if this all seems new to you and you've not really worked with React, do not really worry about
that and just follow along.
This has nothing to do with Webpack specifically is just reacting.
Okay, so with that done, so let's go ahead and provide this context.
So I'm going to be opening up my components within this.
We have the home component and in this home content, our gsx, we are going to be providing this.
So what I'm trying to do here is I'm going to be creating a context.
So in here I need to be first importing the context.
So I'll say context, history, context equals to import.
And then we had just created the context that's in the utils folder.
So utils slash routing provider, actually, let me just go ahead and rename this.
So instead of history, it's going to be the routing context.
That sounds more appropriate.
And then I have to use this context.
So basically what we're doing over here and why are we doing specifically in the home content or desks,
is because this is the main page that was exported from this application and used in our main movie
application.
So that's where we need to be providing it.
And you'll see the property or here the props.
This is the place where we're going to be getting this routing object that we had provided from our
movie application.
So if you see prop start routing, we are going to be getting both the location as well as the history
object.
Okay.
So with that said, let me just go down.
So this is where our gsx is being rendered in the return part.
And I'm going to be providing the context here.
So instead of added to it, probably I'll provide it inside this.
So I'll say routing context dot provider.
And just closed us and we're going to be closing this year as well.
We also need to be passing the value that we received in the prop.
So I'll put up over here as value equals two as prop start routing.
So that's going to be the routing provider.
Okay.
So let's just see.
Save this quickly.
Anything seems to be feeling.
So let me just validate quickly what's happening here in here.
If I just check out my imports, this is the problem.
So instead of saying, Konst, I should have just done import routing context from this location.
So my bad in case you noticed it.
Great.
Let's see if that and see if things are working properly now.
So if I just give this a refresh, then go to the details page.
So thing seems to be working now.
Okay, so we got the provider setup.
The next thing is the consumer.
So just switching back to our diagram.
So from the context we were able to provide now at the quick booking level, we are going to be consuming
the context that we had just provided.
So I'm just going to be doing that.
So if I go to the quick booking application and in this we need to be first importing the context.
So I'll say import, then let's call this the routing context.
From dada slash, dada slash, then utils slash routing provider.
So we got the context in here.
Now we're going to be ordering the consumer.
So we'll say routing context, dot consumer and just encapsulate your entire code block with this consumer.
So that's right.
Yeah.
Okay, so that looks good.
We got our consumer set up now.
As soon as we encapsulate all of this into a consumer, we are going to be having access to that routing
object.
So we need that routing object where so we need to be part passing in the context here.
So how do we pass a context is basically using function block.
So in here we need to be putting the calibrator and define a function just like that and we need to
be returning this entire gsx order.
So what we'll see is we'll have those rounded brackets and move all this div within that section.
So right here.
Okay, so if this is looking confusing, if you're using React for the first time, I'm sorry about
that, but this is how it works and this is the way that I wanted to implement it in in order to avoid
those multiple callbacks.
So we got the consumer, then we have this open braces, then we have this open and close rounded braces.
Define a function and returning a gsx.
That's why we have the ground brackets now in here.
We are going to be getting the context as a parameter.
So this is provided from this one right here, and this context needs to be sent to this on click function.
So we'll pass it over here saying.
Context.
All right.
So that looks good.
Let me just go ahead and see if this one now and if I just and if I just go to the implementation of
book movie, we can see that as soon as we click on book movie, we are going to be canceling log the
entire booking object.
So let's just go ahead and see if things are working as expected.
So I'm just going back to my browser.
Let's go back to our homepage from the start and let's just give this refresh.
And in here, if I just click on the book button, let me first clear the console and then click right
here.
We, in fact, see that the movie is number one along with the date.
And if I am selected in case I go ahead and change this and try to click on book again.
We can see that the movie, it has changed and the date and time remains the same.
So we got our booking thing to work.
Now the only thing that we need to be doing is navigating to the new place.
So what I can do over here is just going back to the code.
I can use this context that we had provided as a parameter so I can see context.
And in here, I can see context dot history.
Don't push and inhale.
We need to be pushing the booking base.
I'll just say book.
All right, so that's done.
Let's just save this and see if things are working.
So I'm coming back to my browser, and then I'm going to click on the book page.
And in fact, we are taken to the booking page.
Now we know it seems really, really complicated, but this is the sort of little bit complexity that
comes in when you are working with the micro frontend.
You need to keep track of the instances of the objects and also see that you know when you need to be
initializing new objects, they need to be using the same objects.
So these are this small complexity that do come in with the micro frontend, but it also brings in a
lot of benefits.
Okay, so I assume we need a short break.
This is a very long video, so let's take a short break and then we are going to be continuing on and
announcing our application for the.