Welcome to another topic on the micro frank discussion.
Now we have already seen how to be doing the routing between the applications.
Now we also need to know how do we doing this data management?
First, let's just get a brief of what exactly is state management and in our application, where will
we be needing the state management?
So for example, we have this homepage application running here and we had this quick booking component
running on top.
Now in the quick booking comprend, you can select the date and you can select the time and the movie
and then click on the book button.
Now, once you click on the book button, you are redirected to the seed selection page.
So everything was working fine until here.
Now the question is, how do we pass this data which we have selected or here to this component running
in a separate application altogether?
So we need some sort of mechanism to do this, right?
Now, the purpose of getting the data loaded over here is so that we can show the movie name, the date
selected, as well as the time selected for that movie.
Now, once that is done, you can just come here and select the seats and then click on the book button.
And that's how you're going to be doing the booking.
Okay.
The same thing also needs to be implemented on another page.
That's our detail page.
So if I just come down over here, we will navigate to the detail page when we click on any of the movie
cards.
Now, again, we have the movie, we have the date and the time.
And when we click on this, we need to be taken to the movie booking page or our seat selection page.
And in here we need to be passing all the data.
So this data is basically the state that we need to be passing.
Now, state can also be things such as maybe noting a data from your server or any sort of JavaScript
object can be considered as a state.
And when you want to be passing the state between applications, you need some sort of mechanism for
doing that.
Okay.
So that is about what is this state that we need to be managing in our application.
Now, let me show you how it works using one of the libraries.
Now, when you are accessing the data in JavaScript, generally two ways of accessing it.
So let me just switch over to my diagram here.
And there are two mechanisms are either the push mechanism or the pull mechanism.
So for example, in the pull mechanism, just consider a simple JavaScript function.
You just have like a helloworld function.
And when you invoked that function or when you explicitly call that function, only then that function
is executed and whatever's written within the function gets called.
So this is the consumer who is going to be calling that function.
Similar thing can be done for objects.
Suppose you have some object that needs to be initialized and so on.
Again, it's somewhat like a pull mechanism where you're going to be initializing it only when the consumer
wants it.
So this is sort of a mechanism in which the function does not really know when it's going to be called.
And it all depends on the consumer.
Now, in the case of push mechanism, we have a very popular implementation and that is using the promise
button.
So if you have already worked in JavaScript, you might have heard of promises and we have used them
already when you are supposed calling your APIs from a server.
That is all wire promises.
So it takes some time and then the promise resolves and that's how you get the data.
So generally when you have the promise, you have like a promise object and that object might either
resolve or reject after some time.
So this is, again, a synchronous pattern.
And the consumer really does not know when the data is going to be returned from this promise object.
It might be after a couple of seconds or it might be within a few milliseconds.
So this is a push mechanism in which the data is sort of pushed to the consumer after the consumer sort
subscribed to it.
All right.
So this is the promise mechanism.
Now, one another approach of implementing the push mechanism is using observables.
So in here we can see how it works.
So in this, we have a observable object and this can be also considered somewhat like a normal JavaScript
object.
Now, the difference away here is now this object is sort of connected to a producer and a consumer.
So you can sort of consider this like an attic.
So let me just, you know, probably type it out here.
So let's suppose we have like an array here and let's suppose they have a couple of numbers here.
Now, this can be sort of considered like an observable object.
Now, in this, the producer is going to be modifying this object.
And as soon as someone is going to be modifying this object, all the consumers who are subscribed to
this observable object are going to be notified that, hey, there's some change in this object and
you can go ahead and access this data.
So this is, again, a push mechanism in which the consumer does not really know when the data is going
to be sent and the producer can push the data as and when required.
So this is the pattern that we are going to be using.
Now, just to put this into the implementation as how this is going to be implemented on our previous
page.
So if I just switch back here now, as soon as we click on this book button, we are going to be updating
a observable object.
Now, as soon as the updated observe rule object, it is going to be subscribed on the seed selection
page and automatically all the data is going to be pushed to the seed selection page.
Similarly, when we make any changes to the same observable object from the details page, again, the
data is going to be updated and sent back to the seed selection page.
So this is on a very high level how things are going to be implemented using the observable pattern.
Now, there might be one question here.
If you already worked with single page application, maybe React will Angular that many of those applications
generally give inbuilt or an external library for managing the state.
So for example, in React, you got like Redux and in Angular you got its own state management simply
in view or so you have its own state management.
So you can sort of leverage those state management libraries.
But since you are working on the micro frontend architecture, you are not really guaranteed that all
the applications that are running in the micro frontend are all react angular of you.
So you need to be using some sort of library that can be used across all the kind of frameworks that
you have to.
For example, if you have one application running on React, the second application working on Angular
if using this library called are yes, you do not really have to worry about it because it's going to
be supported by anything that can run JavaScript.
And that is exactly what we are going to be using.
Okay.
So that was on a very high level, the theory.
So let's just get overview of what is this audio test library and how do we using some of the methods
that are implemented by it?