So let's start creating our React application using a custom Webpack build.
So I've already created a project bit.
As you can see, this is the number on button and this is going to be our starting point for building
this entire section.
So I've also duplicated this folder and this is where I'm going to be doing this setup.
Okay, so I have already navigated within the folder and before I go ahead and do any of the installations,
let me just give you an overview of what's in here and what's not.
Okay.
So within the mean folder, we are going to be finding SRT directory.
We have also the package.
Dear Jason.
Now the package that Jason contains all the dependencies that it's going to be required for the section.
Now I've just done this or that.
We all are on the same module versions.
If we are not, we might be facing some issues when you are building the application.
Okay.
With that said, let's go to the SRT folder.
In the SRT, we have a couple of policy.
As of the first one is the asset.
This contains nothing but just a couple of images that we are using on our website.
Moving on.
We have the components within which we have some smaller level components like the button.
Then we have like icons like the input box and so on.
We do not really need to be concerned as what are the components and we can also go to the pages.
We have two pages.
One was the login page and second one was the movies page.
So basically the spaces are using the components internally.
Okay.
So that was the pages.
And we also have the app Node.js, which also contains the routing logic.
So as you can see, we have the older setup and it shows what are the components that need to be loaded
on each of the IT out.
Okay, so that looks good.
That was an overview of what exactly exist for us.
Now we need to be building the file that is going to be using to bootstrap this entire application.
So in React, we are going to be having a index start article and we need a index years.
Now this is going to be also our entry file, as I told you earlier in React or any other single page
application.
This is going to be one entry file.
So for that, I'm going to be creating index cards within the SRT folder.
So let's right click on SD and see a new file and let's call this as index dot.
That's HTML.
Okay.
So I'm just going to be adding some basic HTML here.
We have the head section and the body.
Now we need also element in which our entire React application is going to render.
So for that, I'm going to be creating our development and let's give this an idea of, let's say app.
Okay, so we have our starting HTML file now.
We also need another starting GC file so we can again click on source and see a new file.
And let's call this as index start.
Yes.
Okay.
So for bootstrapping a reactor application, we need a couple of dependencies.
So we'll say import react from react than we also need the react dom.
So the react dom from React Dom.
And for using the navigation functionality in React.
We also need the browser out as a browser outlet is basically on top of all the other routing.
So we have this rich component, so it sits on top of this entire thing.
So we need to be first having the browser outer also imported.
So I would say import then the braces from React Rotterdam.
Dom So this is the library we are using for routing and in here I see browser counter.
Okay, so that's done.
We also need the app Georges to be imported here.
So that's actually the application which is going to be loaded.
So we'll say import app from dark slash app.
Okay.
So that looks good.
Now we can start writing our function to bootstrap the React application.
So I'll say react.
Dom Dart render.
And in here we need to be first passing in the element that we would like to render.
So in our case, we need the browser window.
And within the browser window we are going to be having the app component.
So I can actually be removing that and put it like this.
Okay.
The second thing that we need to be passing, all we heard is where does this element need to be placed
on the ML file?
So we already have the estimate file ready and we have the app ready.
So we can just pointed to that.
So I can just put up a comma and say document or get element bitey.
And in this we put the app.
So basically React will go ahead, find this element called app.
And within that, it's going to be putting all this components.
Okay, so that looks good.
I can just go ahead and save this, and that's pretty much it.
That's all the bootstrapping logic we need for bootstrapping a React application.
Now for the next part, we need to be creating of a backfire because right now nothing is going to work.
As you know, Node.js does not really understand what to be doing with all this importance.
One, so we need to be sort of teaching it using the back file.
So I'm going to be taking a short break here.
And in the next video, we're going to be start creating our back file.