Welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be seeing how to be taking the excess to the production level.
So far, when we are loading any of the excess, it will automatically getting injected into the diamond
file.
And things were working pretty well.
We saw website loading with all this, he says.
But there are a couple of issues here.
Since our CSF is bundled with our estimate, we cannot really leverage the functionality of caching
of our browser.
So just to give you a recap of how things work at the browser level.
So for example, we have our index statistical file here, which has the HTML markup as well as the
access that needs to be applied.
Now, let's suppose we are going to be changing some text on the Steamvr file.
So let's suppose there's some heading like this and you're just going to be updating the text value.
What will happen here is the browser is going to be sending the request back to the server, and since
there's a change in the DML file, the entire estimated file is going to be coming back to the browser.
Now, as you can imagine, we did not make any access changes, so what's the point of bringing this
S's back?
So for that reason, if you are able to sort of split the XHTML in this here says we need to be just
bringing back the part which has got changed.
So for example, if you updated the estimate, we would be fighting the estimate from the server.
And if you made some changes on this basis, we are just going to be putting that CSEs from the browser
and this is how you can really optimize your website.
So this was one of the reasons why we need to be splitting the sixes.
And there's also one more reason.
So for that I need to be getting my web back.
So we're running.
So let me just switch back to my code and type in here as an open brand serve, and let's just give
that a second how browser opens up so we can see how things are loading currently.
Okay, so going to our website, this was our page.
Everything looks good.
Now if I go to the courses page now if you noticed, we just got a flicker while loading this page.
So what happened?
All we had was all the email content got loaded and after a delay only this has got applied.
Similarly, if I just to go back to the home, you can see that there's a small flicker here as well.
Now, just to make it really apparent, I can also slow down the internet settings just by going to
the network and throttle the Internet, make it like slow 3D.
And now if I try to read the navigation, you can really see that, you know, I would I still be loaded
here without access.
So once we have DC S's in a different file, the loading of this is going to happen asynchronously in
the browser and is going to be applied and we should not be able to see this flicker anymore.
Okay, so these are the two things that we're looking to solve.
Let's see how we can be doing that in our code.
Let me switch back to my code here.
Stop this out from running and let's clear that and let me just give an overview of from there.
We're going to be starting now.
If you are following along with me, you can just continue on in the same folder, if not or if you
will, facing some issues.
You can just use this folder called as production build underscore bit.
And this is going to be the starting point for the section where we are going to be doing all the production
level optimization.
I've also created another folder with the split and course at the end, and in this we are going to
be adding the configurations for splitting boxes.
Okay, let's get started now for doing the splitting of the sixes, we need to install additional plug
in.
So what's the plug in?
We can just come to the terminal and see npm install save dev and the plug in is called us mini dash
60 dash extract dash plug in.
So that's the name.
Okay, let's get that installed.
And let's give that a second.
Let me just quickly fix the name.
So my plug in spelling was wrong, so I'll just put it as plug in and let's keep that installation running.
Now, I got my plug in successfully installed too.
Let's go ahead and use this plug in.
I'm going to be importing it first.
So as a caused many CCS extract plug in equals two required and then many as this extract plug in.
Okay, we got the plug in, import it.
Let's go ahead and use that as usual.
We need to be going to our plug in section.
Let's come here and see new mini CST extract plug in.
Okay.
So that's done.
I'm just going to be disabling my module analyzer plug in for now since we're not using it.
Really.
So let's disable that as well.
Okay.
So that's pretty much it for the plug in configuration.
We do not really need to be passing an additional configuration over here.
Now, if I do see NPM run Dev, let's see what happens.
Okay.
My build was successful and I also got the disk folder here.
But if I open up my disk folder, we do not really see any Stasi SS files here.
So if you notice there are no CAC files here.
So what is the problem?
Do you remember how we loaded our cases when we uses the CAC loader?
Right.
And then we also used one additional loader there, if you remember.
So the loader was called as the style loader.
Now, what was the purpose of this day loader?
The purpose of the style loader was to get all the compile seizes from the CFS loader and inject it
to the steam file.
Now, in our case, we do not want to be injecting it anymore to the steam.
Instead, we want a separate CSS file here.
Right to what we are going to be doing over here is actually be removing the style loader.
So let's get rid of that.
And we ought to be using the Minix extract plugin in the loader section for the first time.
And in here we'll say dart loader.
So that's one of the property provided by this plugin.
And Estee Lauder, similar thing we are going to be doing for the SS as well.
So let's get rid of this and see how many cases extract plug in dart loader.
So just to give a recap of what's going to happen here.
So for example, in the Explorer, we compile all the SPSS files and once it's compiled, we give it
to the access loaders.
And once that is done and we get the compile results, we pass it to the exit extract plugin.
So it can just create a new cases file with all that loaded status.
Okay.
So that's all the configuration required.
Let's see if that file cleared the console and see and beam run dev.
Let's give that a second.
Okay.
With that done.
Now you can see that we have actually got two additional case files.
So we got like this model dot cases and also a bundle cases.
Now, this is really cool.
Our plugin also identifies what all of these cases that it needs to be combining and can be used in
multiple places.
So the bundles are also optimized over here.
Okay.
So with that said, let's try to run this in our browser.
So I'm just going to be saying and PM ran serve to get our browser opened up.
Okay.
Our website works like before.
If I go to the inspect and if I go to the network during a refresh, we should be seeing the new CSIS
files loaded here.
And I can see here that we have this as our C underscore render and this is the CSIS file that just
got loaded.
So that's great.
That's really good.
And let's see if it also solve the issue where we are having the flickering when we are switching between
the pages.
So let me just clear that off.
Go to the process page.
And in here you can see that we are on the slow 3D, so we do not really see any flicker and the page
was loaded as it should, and this gives a much better user experience.
So just going back to the homepage as well, we should not be seeing any flicker and things are working
pretty well here as well.
Okay, so that's about it, how you're going to be splitting your scissors into a separate file.
Let's take a short break and see what other optimizations we can be doing at the production level.