You guys will come back in the last few days.
We saw the website that we're going to be optimizing.
Now, let's get started with this.
And before we start off, let me just give you an overview of how the website structure looks like.
Now, when you download the source code for this entire course, you're going to be finding a folder
called US Course Project, Underscore Base, and this is going to be the starting point for this particular
section.
Now, I wanted to created on the fold of my mike, if in which I'm going to be starting the optimization
and trying to keep things organized in case you get stuck.
All right.
So with that, let's get started and explore what exactly that inside this folder.
So in this folder, you're going to be finding the starting file that is the index artist email, which
contains all the data that was there on the main front page.
Now, this also has associated indexed ideas for loading and making things dynamic here, and we also
have a CSV file attached to that.
Now we also have another folder called pages in which we have the cold storage animal and the Associated
Ghost Dogs file.
Along with that we have a Libs folder.
Within that we have the library called Twist and in that it also has the to start CFS.
Now you can immediately notice that we are going to be using both X's as well as this uses format and
this is going to help us explore the full potential of that back.
Okay.
Moving on, we have a decent file as well that is going to be loaded.
And finally, we have a search folder in which you have some of the X files and some of the formats
file.
As you can see here, we also have kept image file and that is the main banner that was used on the
website.
Okay.
So that's about the folder structure.
Let me quickly minimize all of this and let's see what is going to be the approach for optimizing this
entire project.
So first of all, I'm going to be installing the basic dependencies and then do the basic configuration
file, the pack file.
So once we have that done, we are going to be setting up the stable file.
That was the dynamic edge HTML directly in our best folder and then get developed.
Baghdad Solar started now designed to keep the Webpack dev server in the start because as in when we
start fixing and modifying it, I can immediately see what's happening in the browser as well as automatically
building the bundle and fix the errors on the way.
Okay.
Once that is done, we are going to be fixing all our imports and then move all our assets and dependencies
via NPM.
And finally, we are going to be moving the assets in the disk folder.
Okay.
So all that history does on a very high level what we are going to be doing, let's move on and do some
implementation.
So I'm going to be starting off the implementation with the index start HTML file.
Now if you go at the bottom, you can see that all the dependencies for now are being loaded with CDM.
So we got like the bootstrap because jQuery we have typed, then we have validate roster and load.
Now, the number one thing that I want to be doing is move all the dependencies that we see or hear
into the index cards file.
Now, this is exactly where the full potential of the pack is going to be used.
So let's get started with that.
So what are we opening up the terminal on this folder?
So let's hit the terminal command and we have the terminal started here.
Okay.
Now, with the terminal started, I'm going to be moving over to that folder.
So there's the 8.1 folder.
So let's go to the CD, 8.1.
And now we're in the folder.
Okay.
Now, as you can see, we do not even have a package or decent file here.
So to initialize this as a NPM repository so that we can add the dependencies via NPM, we can use to
come on and beam in it.
So I see NPM in it.
And then it's going to be asking you a couple of questions, such as what is the name of the package
and so on.
So for now, I'm just going to be using the default value for all the options.
Okay.
So as soon as I do that, I should be having the package that Jason created for me.
Okay, so that looks pretty good.
Now we have the basic package addition, and now we can start installing the dependencies.
So by installing the dependencies, I'll type in npm install.
Then I'll say save.
And the dependencies that we need are Lord.
So we'll put in the spelling.
Right, Lord Ash.
Then we also need jiggery.
Then we are going to be using the typed dogs that typed dot g's.
Now, if you want to be validating any of the names, what you can do is you can just go to the NPM
repository and and I actually have all of them open here.
So, for example, for typed, we can follow that.
You need to be installing NPM, install typed dogs.
That's what we have done for the equity.
We just need to be using the words equity.
We have done that as well.
For validated dogs, we just need to be adding value to Georgia.
So I'm just currently copying this from here.
And then we can put it right here.
So space and then validate ideas and then let's see what else is required.
We need another dependency called toaster.
So let's copy that name and edit right here and let's move on to the next one.
So that's loads and then finally bootstrap.
So I'll just install both of them as well.
We already have added loads so we can just proceed with bootstrap.
Okay.
So all of my dependencies have been added.
Let's go ahead and install of them.
Now, it might take a couple of seconds as there were a lot of dependencies and now we can see our package
addition has been updated with all the dependencies.
Okay.
So that was the dependencies for the project.
The next dependency is for that pack.
So for now, we are just going to be installing two of them.
So that is the default one.
One is NPM install save dev.
We are going to be installing this as dev dependencies and that is going to be the back and the back
CLIA.
Awesome.
So these are the two basic dependencies that is required by the pack.
Now what we are going to be doing next is we are going to be creating our basic VAT back file.
So in here I can just right click and see a new file and we can call this as well.
Backdoored config dot.
Yes.
Okay.
So that's done for now.
I'm not going to be adding any of this.
But we can just close this for now, close the package or Jason and close those instructions as we have
gone through it once.
And finally, we are going to be moving to our index charges.
And in our index charges, we can start importing all those dependencies.
So via scroll on the top, this is where we are going to be adding our dependencies.
So in here we can say import and then you can be adding all the import statements or one was for g equity.
So I can see dollar from.
J.
So is the equity generally denoted by the dollar sign?
So I've used that over here and then we can import loads.
So let's just quickly make sure that we are using Lordship.
So as you can see, we are using it for the build for our items.
So we need Lord Asher as well.
So I say import underscore from Lord Ash.
Then we also need booster for the styling.
So I would say import boot strap from bootstrap.
Okay.
Last but not the least, we need to define a dependency that is for type.
So import type.
From typed dogs.
Okay, now for tape, just make sure that you're using the capital t o here, because we can see that
we're using this motif and we are initializing the type library.
So just make sure that you have the capital T when you're importing it.
Okay.
So with that done, if we try to run the build, everything is going to be breaking because we do not
have any configuration done yet.
Endeavor back file.
So let's take a short break and start making basic configuration in the Webpack file.