You guys.
Welcome back.
In this video, we are going to be seeing what exactly is the concept of loaders?
You know, this is one of the biggest concept in Webpack and this is really important whenever are going
to be riding your backpack configuration.
So before that, let's have a look at the dependency graph.
This is the graph that we had seen earlier as well and show exactly how the Webpack file works behind
the scene.
Now, we have already seen this and we saw that when we read on our web back, build a few files, outputted.
We had the bundled ideas.
We did not really have a separate thesis and develop our cases, but we're going to be seeing that later
on.
Then we saw that we were using this bundled ideas file in the next RHD and then our application was
working well.
There's an addition here.
Now, if I have created another diagram here, so let's see exactly where Loader fits in.
Now in this let's take the example of this mean dodgers in this year was important additional dependencies
of the SS and an image.
So as you can see we have written import style from index start the SS and import logo from the assets
folder and the logo dot PNG.
Now there's one fundamental concept here.
The pack does not really know how to be dealing with files other than JavaScript, so we need to be
teaching the pack exactly how to be loading these other types of files, and that is exactly where loaders
come in, as the name suggests.
So what happens here?
Well, again, the web page goes through all our files here, and then when comes doing the index studies,
it sees that, well, okay, there's a thesis file that needs to be loaded.
And how do I load that file?
Well, that configuration is written in the web back file, and that is exactly how it works.
So we need to be defining different loaders for each and every file types that we need.
So, for example, if you're using the access file type, you need to be having a couple of things as
loaders, which are going to be seen shortly.
And similarly, if you're using some thesis pre processes maybe as the or less, then you need to be
having those appropriate loaders in place.
Those are going to be getting an error that does not understand how to be loading these files.
Similar thing is going to be done for the images as well.
So if you want to be loading any sort of images in your JavaScript, you need to be having those image
loaders in place.
Now, if you explore on the backside itself, I want to make you familiar with the documentation as
well so that you do not really have to depend just on this course, but you can always refer the official
documentation and that is going to be very helpful when you're doing the real development.
So let's head over to the Webpack concept.
So the website is about Baghdad security.
And in this we have this section on top.
So as you can see, these are the concept configuration guide loaders migrate and plug in.
So right now we are looking at the loader section.
So if you go to the loaders, it gives you a brief introduction of exactly what are loaders and so on
this you do not really have to worry about.
We're going to be seeing all of this in this course, but there are different file types.
So you can see here these are all the loaders that are available.
You got like your Babel loader, you have coffee script loaders, then you have like loaders, node
loaders, then you've got some specific things as loaders.
So we are going to be seeing a couple of the cases loaders in this particular schools.
So we have this uses less loader than we have your SPSS or SPSS loaders and so on.
But just go through this documentation.
As you can see, there are a lot of loaders that are available.
You can also load files, you can load your Jason and so on.
So if you have maybe some configurations in your Jason file, you can be loading those as well directly
in JavaScript and all these configurations need to be done.
Now when you're going through any loader you can just for example, click on the loader itself and it
will exactly tell you how to be using it.
So you can see the recommended usage is listed here.
Now don't really worry about this right now we are going to be seeing how this is working behind the
scenes.
Going back to our Webpack.
Now, as soon as our loader kicks in, it's going to be loading those files and then it's going to be
creating those bundles.
Now, please note that you can also have multiple loaders for a single file type, and we're going to
be seeing that shortly.
So, for example, for us, we are just going to be using the access loader that we saw in the documentations
of example.
Let me just go back.
So we had this use as a lawyer.
So we are going to be using a combination of things as lot of we are going to be using C loader as well
as you are s6's loaders.
And we are also going to be using another one called style loader.
So we are going to be using all of this in conjunction not just one single loader and that's about it.
So once you have those loaders in place, you're going to be having the same bundle created and then
you're going to be using them in your main indexed file.
All right.
So that was all about the theory.
Let's go ahead and write some code and really understand exactly how loaders work.