All right.
Now, before we start off and do anything related to my girlfriend and let's let's try to understand
what is this concept?
Why do we need it?
And what is this trying to solve?
So I've developed a diagram here and I've taken the example of a normal e-commerce website, done development
without any micro random concept.
So we are maybe using a React application or Angular application, any other single page application
that might be coming up in the future.
So let's take the example here.
You can see that I've denoted this entire application by this yellow box that shows that it's a single
application here.
And in this application, you might be having multiple single components.
So, for example, you have like this header component, you might be having a couple of image components,
then you have some components to render these boxes along with the title of the product and many more
here.
Okay.
So that's the general approach.
Now, if I just scroll down, we can see that we have sort of given an overview of how things work here.
Now generally you're going to be having a package.
Dodgson Now, in this package or design, it's going to be containing all the dependencies that are
required for your application to work.
So, for example, I've taken three dependencies here.
You have your components, the dependency utils and your auto library.
Now the components might be something like your material UI components or maybe some components that
have been developed within your company.
Now, let's take the example here.
Your repository, your e-commerce repository depends on three other repositories.
So you have the frontend and the utils repository.
And there was a version bump up on the frontend component.
There was a new component that was released.
And you would like to use that component in your repository.
So not even that list.
For example, there was a bug in one of the components.
Maybe they had a component here and things were not aligned within that component.
Now how are you going to be fixing it?
So generally the team who's going to be working on the frontend component library, they're going to
be fixing that issue.
And they're going to be doing a version bump up.
They're going to be doing the testing, basically pipeline and finally, a deployment.
And then you finally have the version two of that frontend component repository.
So things looks good here.
Now my e-commerce team comes up and says that, okay, I need to be fixing this in my application as
well.
So what they need to be doing is they need to be sort of pulling this new version, too, into their
e-commerce repository.
They need to come to this package audition and probably make this version as version two.
And that's when the issue is going to be fixed.
That was released by the frontend component repository team.
So if you understand here, there's a big dependency.
First dependency is I need to be informing this e-commerce team that he thinks has been fixed and you
need to be updating your application as well.
Now we know the problem arises right here.
Now, as soon as I do that, I need to be going through the entire CD pipeline myself as also being
the part of the ecommerce repository.
So in the e-commerce repository also, I need to do a version bump up.
I need to be doing the testing, this CD.
Finally, the deployment and then release to the production environment so that my customers get the
latest fix to ocean of that component.
Now, as you can imagine, this is a lot of tedious work.
Just for a small upgrade, you need to be going through the entire CSC pipeline for both of the repository.
And this is exactly where Michael Franklin can be very useful.
You do not have a very tight dependency on the different repositories that you're working with, and
things are very loosely coupled here.
So let's see how the same thing would work in a micro frontend approach.
Now let me switch my page.
Now let's see how things work in the micro frontend approach when we're doing the deployment.
So let's say for example again we arrived at the same problem that there was some issue in the header
and that needed to be fixed.
So if we go to the architecture, we are going to be having the e-commerce applications running separately.
So this might be having a domain such as this homepage dot e-commerce dot com, and you have another
repository or another application running separately called the components repository.
And this would be hosted on another endpoint called component dot e-commerce dot com.
Now e-commerce is having its own deployment cycle and it gets deployed on a separate namespace and the
components get deployed on a different namespace following a different or the same development cycle.
Now, once this is done, we are going to be merging both of them on a single website called the e-commerce
dot com.
And as you can imagine, if there's any issue in the components repository, the components team can
just pick up that particular issue, do the fixes, do the deployment on this particular end point and
things are going to be automatically merged on the main website.
They do not even really need to be telling the e-commerce team that there was an issue in the header.
They can just go ahead and fix it by themselves.
Now this is a very big advantage and it can really speed up your development cycle of your application.
So with that said, let's just see from the competitive perspective as well.
So if I just come down here, I have the homepage here so you can see we have the homepage on the homepage
dot e-commerce dot com.
And by this, I want to sort of tell you that it's not really mandatory that you need to be dividing
your application by components.
And as an application, you might even be deciding in your company that you need to be managing your
components page perspective.
So for example, let's suppose one team is going to be maintaining the homepage.
They can be under the team that can be managing the accounts page.
So you can make your application not just components but perspective.
You one page perspective.
So different teams can be managing different pages.
And in the end, all the pages are going to be missed and a single website is going to be created.
So internally, these pages can be using more comprehensive example as homepage dot e-commerce, which
itself is a different application, is internally using this component dot e-commerce com.
And similarly, if you can see that we have this account page.
So this is using the comprehensive e-commerce as well as another application called auto e-commerce
dot com.
So as you can see, we can really mix and match and gives us a lot of flexibility when you're doing
the development.
Now, this might seem really daunting, but so do not really worry about this.
We are going to be actually implementing all of this and things are going to get really clear.
Now, finally, before we close off, I would just like to really go over the advantages and disadvantages
of doing all of this.
So I have that listed here as well.
So the advantages of following the micro frontend approach is first of all performance.
Since we're sharing a lot of code among the pages, there is definitely a performance boost.
Here you have the faster production rollout.
So since you do not have a tight dependency on the other teams, you can roll out the application to
production much faster.
Then you have the easier code usability.
So since you can sort of share the components or the code between the pages, you can have a very good
code reusability.
Then finally you have the reduced dependency, as I mentioned earlier.
You do not have to wait on the teams for follow up and so on.
But there is a couple of drawbacks associated with the micro frontend approach.
First of all is the lack of control.
Now let's say for example, there is some UI upgrade that's happening in one team and the other team
is not really aware of it.
So once you are in the production environment, you might be seeing sort of different devices on the
two pages.
So you need to really have a better communication between the teams and at the organization level itself
as what needs to be implemented.
Then you also need more coordination between the teams and that is the contract.
So let's suppose there's communication between the two pages and this is maintained by two different
team.
So let's suppose the API contract or the communication contract has been changed, then things can definitely
feel.
So you need to be taking care and also have a very good coordination between the teams.
The final drawback is basically the complexity of the overall application sort of increases since you
need to be maintaining multiple pipelines for each of the applications.
So this can again, sort of add the complexity of your final application.
So I confronted is generally very good if you are working on a bigger application but but does not have
a lot of advantages if you're just trying to build a smaller application.
So if that information was a lot, do not really worry about it.
We are going to be seeing all of this impractical and things are going to get really clear about it.
Again, I'm just going to take a break and then present to you what is the project that we're going
to be working on using the micro frontend approach?