In this video, we're just going to get a very high level overview of what is optics and how to be using
few of the functions that is given by context years.
Now you can just come to this website called as called Sandbox Studio.
So this is online editor we can where you can be running JavaScript very easily.
So in this, once you open it up, you should see something like this and we're just going to be starting
off with the raw JavaScript.
So again, just click on the script button and you're going to be taken up to the sample page.
Now I'm just going to be clearing of all of this content.
We do not really need to be working with that.
Stephen For now, and just open up your console to see what's happening when we write some code.
Okay.
So this is done.
We also need to be installing a dependency but are going to be using and that is audit.
Yes.
So let me just add the dependency and this is going to be called as I text.
And just get this thing installed.
Okay.
So just give it a second.
Now we have the dependency area.
Now we can go ahead and import this dependency.
So as they import curly braces from Oryx Gas.
Okay, so what are we trying to import from our text?
Yes.
Now, I do support a lot of things.
You can do things such as adding observables, you can add subject, you can add some delays, you can
add bounds.
There are a lot of things which can be added using the RTX dev library.
I'm not going to be going a lot into depth into year.
We're just going to be seeing those things that we will be needing for our project.
So just to give you an overview, let's see, the first one is called as observable.
So how do you be using this observable?
So first of all, we need to be creating a observable object.
So let's say const, let's say all be s observable in chart equals to new observable.
All right.
And then we need to be passing in something.
So what are we passing here?
So this is going to be just one parameter here and that's called as subscriber.
So let's just busty subscriber and this is going to be a function.
So this is the pattern that we need to be following.
So it's new observable.
And in this we were passing a function with one parameter which is the subscriber.
Now this subscriber can be used for sort of publishing any of the data.
So let's see how that works.
So I can see a subscriber dot next to next is used when we want to be pushing a new data to that event.
Q So when I see this, you can consider something like an added as before, and when you say next is
going to be pushing a value into that area so it can be one, then you say next, then again two and
so on.
So let's do the exact same thing.
So I say next one, then I'm just going to be saying subscriber dot next to and this is all the values
that I want to be adding to this observable object.
Okay, so we have the object right now.
Let's suppose you have some file.
I'm just going to be adding some dummy file here to let's call this as file a or file consumer probably
that's going to be more apt name.
And in this I want to be observing all the things that are happening in this observable object.
So what I can do is I can say obs dart subscribe and in this I can be passing an observer and observer
is basically an object.
Now in this object we need a couple of keys.
So one of the keys that we want to be subscribing on is the next function.
So as you saw, we have used this next function here.
So we are going to passing that as the key.
So we'll say next, that's the property name.
And in this we can pass in our function just like that.
Okay.
So what we are trying to say is I want to be subscribing to this object called observable.
And in this whenever the next function is called, just like it's called or here I want to be executing
this function that we are going to be typing here.
So for example, let's say console.
Consolidate log.
Then we say subscribed.
And I received.
So in this policy, I'm going to be putting some value so I can just put up the back picks and per dollar,
and then we need to be adding the value here.
Now, where do we get the value from?
The value is received in this function itself.
So I can just put up as value and then we can type in Val here as well.
Okay.
So let me just clear off my console and in this and what are we just refreshing this page once so that
it picks up the latest?
Good.
And as you can see over here, we received the two events that were published from here.
So these were the two events right here.
Now I can do things such as also delayed even publishing.
So for example, let's say I want to be publishing event after couple of seconds or less of 3 seconds
so I can see again subscriber dot next and then I can see let's say delayed.
Message.
All right.
So that can also be done.
Now, if I just clear off the console, log in and let's give this a refresh.
And we can see those two messages were published immediately.
And the last message was published after 3 seconds.
So this is how the things work over here.
And you can also see that since we have used set interval is publishing this message after every 3 seconds.
Now, this is the difference between promises and observables.
In the case of promise, once you do the publishing of the message or once you resolve the promise,
the entire scope of that function is done.
You cannot be doing something like set interval.
In the case of promises, you cannot be resolving the promise again and again once that the result is
done.
So that's the main difference between an observable.
Observable is basically observing what's happening in this and that object.
Now you can use a subscriber in multiple places.
It's not necessary that there should be just one subscriber.
So let's say, for example, you have a file consumer over here.
Then in the case of, let's say movie about booking application, you also need to be collecting the
analytics whenever a movie is booked.
So let's say, for example, this was your movie booking object, right?
So in your analytics, so let's suppose you had like a analytics file.
So in this also you can be observing any changes done over here.
So let's suppose we just copy and paste the same thing.
And over here you can see that, you know, I'm going to be publishing.
So you publish analytics data, something that, you know.
So basically one, one subscriber is used for maybe checking out your customer, whatever the movie
is booked.
And the second observer is basically doing a publishing or collecting the analytics and publishing it
to this hour.
So one observer can have multiple consumers.
Okay.
So that was about observable, but we are not going to be using observable in our case.
The reason for that is once this observable is made, the next function can only be called within it.
We need a feature wherein I can see or be bought next.
Something like this so that, you know, I can sort of publish the message from any of the files.
So this is my requirement.
So what I'm going to be doing for that is we're not going to be using observable.
Exactly.
I just told about this because this is the main concept on which the other function also depends on.
So for now, I can just probably comment all of this out.
I'm not going to be deleting it.
And instead what I'll do is I'm going to be importing a new object.
So the other named export given by next year is called US subject.
So what a subject.
Well, let's say we have concert movie data equals to a new subject.
So once you declare it as a new subject, it behind the scene becomes like an observable object.
So you can sort of add value to this object as well as subscribe to this object.
So let me just, first of all, refresh my screen so that it stops running the old record.
Okay, so that looks good.
Now, what I can do over here is I can say movie data dot next.
And then it can just pass any value.
So let's say movie booked, something like that.
Okay, so all here, what happened is we just published some message to this movie data object.
Now, we can also have a consumer on this.
So I can also say movie data, not subscribe.
And then this I can pass in the observable.
So again, I can see or here as next.
And I can pass in a asynchronous function.
So I can see we had us console dart log.
And then data received.
Is.
And then again I replaced it with back picks and in here I'll put up the value that was received.
So again, we can put Toyota's value and then we put the value here as well.
Okay.
So if I just clear the console, if I just give this a refresh and we see that no data was received.
Well, the problem over here as I'm passing in the next before subscribing, so basically what happened,
it just pushed it over here and there was no subscribers or they did not really consume it.
So for that reason, I need to actually be publishing it afterwards.
So once you have the subscription done, then we can be publishing some data and then we get the data
was received in the movie booked.
All right.
So you need to have the subscriptions ready and only then you should be publishing the data so that
all the subscriptions are going to be getting your data that you have just published.
And again, as we had seen earlier, you can also have multiple subscribers.
So I can just basically have this in multiple places.
If I would like in two places, I should be seeing the two logs.
So let's just say we had as log to.
And we can see that the log to movie power was booked.
So basically, if you want to have in multiple files, that is also possible.
Now, I just wanted to show this because once we have the full fledged application, it might get a
little confusing.
So just to show you on a very small application as what we are going to be doing and implementing in
the micro frontend.
So that's that's pretty much it.
We are going to be publishing the all the movie that is booked when we are clicking on the book button
and we are going to be having this subscription in the seat booking application and then we are going
to be getting all the data of the booking.
Okay.
So that's about it for our next year.
Let's move on back to our micro frontend application and see how to be implementing this in the.