We are finally at the end of our course.
I hope you have learned a lot from this about and you are very comfortable using it in your next project.
So we have covered a lot of things in this entire course.
We started off from right from the basics in which we had no idea of what exactly is Webpack and ought
to be doing the configurations.
And we have finally, in the end, seen how to be using multiple applications, running Webpack and
combining all of them into a single application using micro frontend.
So this was a very good overview of the pack and how to be using it in your next project.
I'm going to be keeping the schools up to date as and when new versions of the pack is released.
So do keep subscribed to discourse.
And last but not least, if you are not given a review for this course, I would really, really appreciate
if you can give me a review of this course.
This is going to help me keep motivated and help improve on making this course even better.
So that's it for now.
That's me signing off.