Hey, guys, welcome back.
And in this video, we're going to be really analyzing what's happening in the bundles.
So let's get started with that.
Now, I want you to created a new folder here.
As you can see, it's called an 8.5 course project optimization base.
And this is going to be our starting point for this section.
In case you faced issues with any of the previous videos, you can either go ahead and copy one of those
folders.
And if you want to get started with me, you can just use this particular folder.
And this is going to be our starting point.
Okay.
With that said, let's just head over to these folders.
Dumbness.
As you can see, I'm already in the 8.5 folder.
I'm one of the quickly installing all my dependencies since it's not there right now.
But darn, I'm also going to be running NPM Branch Dev.
So let's get our disk folder so that we can analyze it.
Okay.
Our build has ran successfully and if I open up my best folder, I want to be analyzing what's happening
in the course bundle as well as in my index bundle.
Let me quickly to make the smaller.
And if I go to my courses dot g's file.
So in the pages we have the course says Dot.
Yes, we had a lot of dependencies imported here.
So, for example, let's take up the dependency of Lord Ash.
So if I just go to the course bundle and search for Lord Ash, you can see that the Lord Ash dependency
was imported here and all discord quarters, something related to Lord Ash, which we cannot really
understand.
But this is the Lord Ash Library getting loaded here.
Okay, similarly, if you want, you can also be finding the other libraries.
So for example, if I search for validate, that should also be there somewhere.
And in fact, you see that know something related to validate is that.
Okay.
The problem here is if I go to my index bundle and try to search for Lord Ash here as well, you can
see that even in my index model, the Lord Ash is getting loaded.
So as you can imagine, if you have a lot of gas fires, the Lord ash dependency is going to be loaded
multiple times and this is not the best way of using the pack.
And this is what we are going to be actually fixing.
Okay.
Now, this was just one of the dependency loads, but imagine you have a lot of dependencies in and.
These are just like V6 dependencies.
But lesser you have like 1015.
Then it is going to be really difficult to analyze which are the dependencies getting used in multiple
files.
So right now we just have like courses and index so we can sort of figure out that, okay, these are
the common dependencies, but imagine if you have like a big project, how do you figure out that,
you know, which are the major dependencies that I should try to minimize all the dependencies that
are getting replicated?
So for that, the page gives an awesome plug in and we are going to be using that to analyze our base.
So we're going to be installing that.
Now for that, we are just going to say NPM, install, save dev and the plug in is called us that back.
So there's that back then bundle.
And later.
All right.
Just make sure you have the spelling right.
So there's an laser right there.
So let's go ahead and install that and let's see, how can we be using it?
Okay.
The bundle, the dependency is now installed.
Now, as usual, whenever you are using any of the plugin, we need to be going to our that back file.
So going back to have a pack file, let's go ahead and import that first so we can see const, then
we can see we had as bundle analyzer.
Equals to required.
And there's that bag bundle and laser dart bundle and laser plugin.
So you can either write it in this way, dart bundle and laser plugin, or there's also another way.
So instead of naming it as bundle and laser, what I can do is I can make a named import.
And we had I can put it as bundle and laser plugin and get rid of this.
Right.
Yeah.
Okay.
So we have this dependency importing now let's go ahead and use this plugin now for using the plugin.
As usual, we go to our plugins section.
So that's right here now to be using the plugin after the copy plugin, I'm just going to be adding
it.
So I'll say new bundle analyzer plugin and we just pass in an empty object for now.
Okay.
So with that done, I can actually start of my application once again.
So let's see how that works.
So I'm just going to be running again as NPM run dev.
So let's just give it a minute.
All right.
So this time you can see when I ran NPM Run Dev, we did not actually see our web page.
Instead, we saw this stuff looking all we have with a lot of boxes.
And this is the beauty of using this plugin.
Now, what is it?
Let's try to really understand what's happening here.
Now on the top, you can see that we have the course dart bundle dogs.
And on the right, we have the index start bundle ideas.
Now, these are the two major bundles that has been created by the Web back file.
Now, within this bundle, what are the dependencies?
Well, that tells us that we have a folder called as node modules.
And within node modules, you have all of this stuff right here.
Now, as you can see or hear directly without a lot of effort, that load is the biggest dependency
that is there here.
Now, please note that this size that we see over here also represents the size of the bundle.
So load is the biggest library that we're using in our entire project and it is also being duplicated
in both places.
Similarly, you can also see that the query is also being used and this is also quite a big bundle.
So we need to be doing something about this as well.
Now I know that you can see that there are a lot of small, small libraries being used over here, like,
for example, flip dodges.
And this is again used in both places.
So basically it's being imported by this another library called as properties within which it has a
lot of sub dependencies.
And this is basically how the node modules work in which you have a lot of dependencies and within that
you have like a sub dependencies.
And this is what we need to be optimizing for though.
Okay.
So this is what we are looking at.
And on the right hand side, you can see that we have this source folder.
Within that, we have the vendor dart access.
Now you can also see that the vendor file is being duplicated as well.
So if you remember, we had imported this vendor file in both of the JavaScript, so both in the courses
and the indexed ideas.
And that is why this duplication is present.
All right.
So that's about it.
As you can see, this is a very beautiful plugin and it gives you a very high level overview of what
are the things that you need to be optimizing.
And as in, soon when we are going to be optimizing the things, we are going to be coming back to this
page and see how well we have optimized our application.
Alright, that's about it.
Now we know what to be optimizing.
Let's take a short break and start optimizing the things and make this even better.