Continuing on from the last video, we only got all the dependencies installed via NPM.
Now it's time to actually remove the dependencies from the index start estimate file.
So for that, I'm just going to be going to the index start estimate.
And from this, I'm going to be removing all the tags that we see here.
So we have the bootstrap dependency query typed.
We have the validate toaster and load hash dependencies removed from our estimate file.
All right, that looks pretty good.
Our steel mill file is now a bit compact, and that's a good thing.
Okay, so with that done, now what we're going to be doing next is we're going to be adding the configurations
in our Webpack file.
So as usual, we import the path modules.
So in say two particles do require path.
And with that done, we can start exporting the object for configuration.
So that will be module dart export equals to a new object.
And in here we're going to be adding the basic configuration entry.
And in the entry, we can define the entry file.
So since we have two entries over here, one is going to be for our index page and the second entry
is going to be for our courses page.
I can actually go ahead and define the two entry files here.
So what I'll do, I'll create an object here and we are going to be having to place parameters.
The first one is going to be called US Index and the second one is called as quarters.
Okay.
So we have the two things done now we have to be specifying the part.
So it's going to be dot slash as RC.
And in this we are going to be pointing to our index dodgers.
So it's going to be index start?
Yes.
Okay.
For the second one, it's going to be, again, dark slash SRT.
But this is in the previous section.
And in that we have the courses dot.
Yes.
Just to validate, we can open it up and we have the courses Dodgers right there.
Okay.
So our notify looks good.
The next important parameter is, if you guessed it, it's output.
Okay.
So we define the output.
And in the output, we need to define the file name.
So what is going to be the file name?
Now, if you remember from the last section, the file name is going to be dynamic because we have two
entry points here.
We cannot be just naming it as Mandelbrot.
Yes.
So in here, we are going to be defining the file name as name dot bundle.
Okay.
Next, we need to be defining the path for the output.
So that will be part.
And in the part we'll put it as.
But not resolve.
And inhale is here directly.
Nim coma.
And then we see this.
Okay.
I'm also going to be adding an additional parameter in the output for clean as true.
Now I'm doing this because I want that the best for the is being cleaned on every single build.
And this is going to be very important, as in when we start adding more and more configurations to
all that back file.
Okay.
So that's pretty much done, the basic configuration for the event.
But let's try to run this and see on what stage are we currently?
What are the things that are breaking so we can start fixing all of them now before we start executing
all that back file, although we can do it using the map boxes.
It's better to have the script created in packages.
And so moving to the package georgeson file.
We'll just add the script here.
So I would say dev and in here we'll save a pack and config.
And the configuration is present in the Webpack dart config dart.
Yes.
Okay.
So that looks good.
Let's try to run our dev script by saying npm.
Run Dev.
Okay.
So that park is initializing our repository for the first time.
So it might take a couple of seconds.
And as you can see, a couple of things have broken.
So the first thing that we see is the mode option was not set.
So that's quite easy to fix.
You can just come to a script and say dash dash mode and this can be set as development.
We are missing shortly.
What is the development and production mode?
But for now you can just put it as development.
Okay, so that's done.
The next thing is, does it error in resolving the toaster that says no?
Can you guess why this is coming?
Well, this is because we do not have any of the loader setup right now.
We just have the basic configuration done in the back file but does not really know what to be doing
with the Access Odyssey Assist file.
In fact, now let's take a short break and I, in fact, want you to be setting up the loaders, because
this is the repetition, what we had done in the loader section trying to get this access and the access
loader set up in the configuration file.
Now, if you are successful, that's great.
You can validate it along with what I am going to be doing in the next lecture.
Let's take a short break and continue on.
And I started announcing this Web back file for the.