Welcome back to another video.
In this video, we're going to be seeing how to be loading external cases files.
So far, we have already been dealing with these files, but this is a new file type and we are going
to be seeing the concept of loaders and how they work.
So to proceed, we are going to be using the folder that was already created by us to getting started.
So what you can do is you can just copy this folder.
So I'll say Control C and we can copy and paste it right here.
It might take a couple of seconds, but it has to copy all the dependencies.
Next, we're going to be renaming this.
So let's give it a name like three and SS loaders.
All right, that looks good.
Now, what we are going to be doing here, let's have a recap first of exactly what was happening in
this application.
Let's right click and say Reveal in Finder and let's double click this file.
And we can see that this was nothing but just a title.
And when we clicked on the button, it was updating the title and rendering a list.
So nothing fancy here.
All right.
So let's go ahead and make it a little bit fancy, add some colors, maybe some background color and
so on using a thesis file.
So switching back to our code, I'm going to be adding a new access file in the SRT folder.
So I'll just say a new file.
Let's call this as index dot thesis.
All right.
What I'm going to be doing here is let's open up our indexed our email file as well.
We already have IDG one as header, so maybe we can have some styling on the header, maybe like an
underline or so on.
So I'll come here, I'll pick it up by the class name unless I find something else.
So it's a text decoration as underlined.
All right.
And we can also change probably the color.
So I'll make it maybe like a blue color.
Okay.
That looks pretty good.
Now, how do we be importing this to this file?
Well, earlier, what we used to do is we used to go to the index Tata Steel Mill and just import the
CAC file directly.
And we are not going to be doing that anymore.
We need to be importing it in the JavaScript so that we can enable all the optimizations that are provided
by that part to us.
So I just go to the index file in here.
We are going to be calling the import statement.
So it'll say import and then dark slash index dot ccis.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
For the import and the court, you feed on this as it is.
So if I just open up my terminal by going to terminal, new terminal and going to the folder that is
created by us, see us as lawyers.
And if I say NPM, run, build.
You can see that the Web starts off, but it fails at one particular point.
And it will tell us the exact message.
What we need to be fixing.
You need the appropriate loader to handle this file type.
So as you can see here, when it was trying to load this index, see this file, there was an error
and it was not able to load this file.
So let's go and fix up the PackBot.
So we are able to now load excess files.
So for that, let's set all to be the pack configuration.
And when know you want to be using the loaders, you're going to be adding a new parameter here.
So in our object, we just have the entry and the output defined.
Now fighting the loaders, we need to be using another our key here.
So that's called as module.
And in this module, we are going to be defining the different ruleset that is going to be used for
the loaders.
So in here you need to be defining it as.
Ruth and INEOS are going to be defining an array of rules that we are going to be using.
So the first rule that we are going to be using is for diseases.
So I will say test and let's put up a comma and there's another parameter and this is called as use.
All right, so what are these two barometers?
The test barometer defines as what are the file types that it needs to match.
So this takes up a regular expression.
So let's define a regular expression right here.
So you need to be putting up two slash and indigo in said dot thesis and then are doing the same.
So that's pretty much it.
So we're defining that when you're trying to load a file.
So for example, the one that was getting loaded over here was index starts versus it's going to be
matching the DOT CFS part at the end of that particular file.
So the dollar specifies that it has to be at the end of the file.
We also have covered some of the basic regular expressions so you can head over to the JavaScript and
the node introduction in which I have also covered slightly on the regular expression path is going
to be giving you a heads up on how regular expressions work.
Okay.
With that said, let's all my road to the next perimeter, which is the used perimeter.
So in this, we need to be putting up an I.D. so the IRS is going to be using all the loaders that are
going to be used for loading these.
We're going to be using two special loaders for this.
The first is going to be this style loader and the second is going to be the excess loader.
Now, please note this loader which are using is not built into the bag.
We need to be explicitly installing it from NPM.
So let's clear off our console and say NPM.
I dashed out save dev theses loader and tile loader.
All right, let's give it a second.
And we have now installed successfully.
Nine here.
We are going to be using them.
So we just put it as tail loader and the second one as the SS loader.
Pretty straightforward.
Now, there's one very important point to note here.
The order in which you're going to be putting this.
So let's say, for example, you think that I can just take this and put it in the starting and this
style loader can come second.
Well, this is not going to work.
When we are loaders execute, they execute from the right side to the left side.
So first off, yes, that's going to be executed.
And then your style loader.
So what does the user's loader does internally?
So what it does is it whenever you are in next year's file is encountered, it sees this indexed arceus
as being imported and it knows how to be resolving this dependency.
Now, once it has loaded that particular dependency does not really know what to be doing with it.
So that data basically passes on to this style loader.
The style loader takes all the data that was processed by the exit loader and it loaded into the stable
document.
So it's going to be creating like a style tag in your estimate document, and that's how your thesis
is going to work.
So that is pretty much the configuration that we need for now.
Let's try to save this file and execute it.
So I'll just clear off the console and see NPM run bed once again.
Cool.
So everything seems to be running.
Let's head back to our web browser and see if things work as expected.
So I'm refreshing.
And voila, we do see our says looking.
That's just amazing.
We are successfully able to load our thesis using this year loader.
Now the couple of things that we should be seeing.
So I'm going to be right clicking and seeing inspect and let's see what happened behind the scenes.
Now this.
If I open up the code section, you can see that I have a style tag automatically injected.
So this is where your style loader came in from.
So it injected this style tag in your estimate document and you can see that we have this header CSS
with all these years as that property that we had added in that particular file.
All right.
So this is really great.
We understood how the SS loaders work behind the scene and we only successfully able to load our access
file.
Now we're going to be taking a short break and we are going to be exploring a little bit more about
this uses loader, especially because this module, since this module is the newer approach of implementing
the SS in your application and this is widely used if you're using some framework such as React and
so on.
So it's also important to understand how those things work behind the scene.
All right.
Let's take a short break and continue on from there.
Thank you.