I'm super excited.
I'm going to be presenting you the project that we're going to be working on and developing using the
micro frontend approach.
Now as you can see in front of me, this is going to be like a movie booking application that we're
going to be developing.
Now we are not going to be doing a lot of HTML, CSS and the basic Webpack stuff, which we have already
covered in the past.
We are going to be seeing things specifically just for this micro frontend.
So before that, let me give you a tour of what we are going to be developing.
So this is going to be our main page or the homepage in which it shows all the movies that are available
and are going to be playing in our theaters.
And we also have another component on this page, which is the quick booking component.
So in the quick booking component, who can just select the movie that you would like to watch?
You can select the date and time.
Now, if you click on any of the movie posters of example, let's click on Captain America.
And in this you can see we have the details about this movie, and you can also book the movie from
here.
So you also have a drop down here to select the movies, select the time, and then click on the book
button.
Now let's go back.
So one fun fact our theater only plays Marvel movies, so that's pretty cool, right?
Okay, so if I just click on my booking button right here on the top.
So let's say, for example, I select Spiderman, select some data, and let's click on the book button.
So we're taking out our booking page.
So this is our booking page where we select our seats.
So we have the movie name listed here, the date and the time that we had selected as the poster of
that movie.
We also have the seat selection, so you can just click on this and the seat gets ticked.
And also, we have this date getting updated here.
So you have currently selected three seats and the total cost of $30.
And if you just click on the book button, we can see that it is the movie has been booked and this
huge selected number three.
So that's pretty much it for our application.
It looks quite simple.
It's quite straightforward.
But trust me, we are going to be learning a lot of the basics that are covered in micro funding and
that are going to be used for developing this application.
Okay.
So that's good.
Let me just go back to my homepage.
So that's right here.
And please note that all the data that we are loading or here is all dynamic.
We are actually using a server to load all this data.
Nothing has been hardcoded as such.
So let me just show you how the data is coming in here.
So if I just open up another tab and run localhost, double, five, double five slash.
Movies so we can see that we are returned with all the movies that are playing.
We got like the name, the image, you are all some description and this was actually running on my
local computer.
So we are going to be running couple of ways actually to run this and that application.
Now, with that said, let me also give you a showcase of how everything is being architected in this
application.
What are the different applications that are running?
And then we will see exactly how to be developing this.
All right, so I have my diagram created as what are the different applications that are running?
Please note and think applications.
These are not just components.
So the different applications are one the homepage we have the details page, we have the booking application,
which is the main application which is going to be containing all the other applications here.
Then we have a server application and also a React components application.
So a little couple of servers are going to be running on our local computer.
Now, let me just show you where are all these applications in a visual way.
So if I just come here.
So this was our homepage in which we had the quick booking on top.
Then we had this movies, you know, containers.
So as you can see, this quick booking is just a component.
That's why it's been marked in blue.
And this yellow is denoted by the homepage application.
So if I just see here, this is yellow as well.
So that's the homepage application running.
Now in the homepage application you can see that I have this red bordered box here and if you just compare
here, red bordered box is our React component application.
So this is actually a other application that is running within our homepage.
So that's pretty cool, right?
Okay.
Let's see the other pages that we have.
So the other applications that we have is the details page.
So as you can see, the details page has been marked in green.
So if we just go up, the green is our details page application.
Now if I just go down and we see what other components are being used here, so we can see that there's
no other components as such being used to directly the UI component.
So that's like a clean page, no other dependencies as such, but let's see the other pages or the other
components that we have.
So let's see the other applications that we have running.
So we have the booking application again in the booking application, all the things are being done
locally in this application itself and no other UI dependency as such.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
So we are going to be seeing how to be putting up all this application using micro frontend.
So I'm really excited.
Let's move on to the next video and see the code structure, how things are going and what do you need
to be doing on your local computer to be following along with me?