You guys.
Welcome back.
And let's continue our journey to become a vet back ninja.
So to become a ninja, we need to be first doing some basic stuff.
So that starts with installing few of the softwares on our computer.
So let's go ahead and do that.
The first after that we'll be needing is get some what are we navigating to the get website?
So if you just search for get on Google, we can see that we navigated to this.
I get ACM dotcom so you can just open this up, go for the download version and you can download it
specific to your operating system.
I already have this downloaded, so I'm just going to be skipping this.
The second important thing that you're going to be needing is Node.js.
So once you have Node.js website open up, you'll be prompted to download again for your appropriate
operating system, and you can go ahead and install this as well.
Make sure using the latest version of Node.js, because some of the features that are required for the
pack is supported only by the latest version.
So once you have both of these things downloaded, let's go and verify that all the things are been
downloaded properly and installed properly on our system.
So for that, I'm just going to be opening up terminal.
If you're on a Windows operating system, you can open your PowerShell or your CMT.
And in this, I'm just going to be checking the version of the installed node.
So I'll say node dash.
And as you can see, I have the Norwegian 14 running all the latest one and 16, but it's not really
necessary to upgrade to 16 for now.
All right.
You can also check the NPR questions by typing in and PM Dash and I have the version 7.16 running,
so that's pretty good.
And the last one is get version.
So let's get Wuzhen, I suppose.
Yes, that's right.
And I already have ghettoization of 2.32 installed.
So that looks pretty good.
All right.
So that is pretty much what we need.
Now, the additional thing that you will be needing when you're doing a development is via code.
I strongly recommend to use V is.
So we can go to the V as code website and we have this code dot Visual Studio dot com and you can install
this for your computer as well.
Now, it's not a required specification to continue on with this course, but you can use whatever you're
comfortable with when you're doing the development or actually that is pretty much just what is required
to be installed on our system.
Let's continue on in the next video and write some code.