Welcome back to another video.
And in this, let's see the theory of exactly how plug ins fit in to the concept of their ecosystem.
So we had already seen this particular diagram in which we saw where the load has come in.
So we had the dependency graph.
Within that, we have the loader for loading the additional file tapes which were backwards, not able
to understand by default.
So once that was done, we were able to get the output of that back.
So this was working.
Now let's see where plug ins come in.
Now, if I scroll down, I have one other diagram regarding plug ins.
So as you can see, we have the VAT back dependency graph created again, and then we have the loaders.
Now, once all the loaders have done their job, they have compiled all the output that was given by
the dependency graph.
Then that is where the plug ins come in.
Plug ins are basically used for enhancing the functionality that is going to be outputted in the Webpack
output folder.
So we already have the Webpack output folder and all the JavaScript files are created, but we are going
to be announcing what is going to be outputted over here.
So just to give you an example, let's see what are the some of the plugins available by default in
Webpack?
So we have something called as the Steam plugin.
So what exactly the estimate of our plugins is going to be doing is it's going to be injecting all the
dependencies directly in the ML file.
So if we had to be adding those dependencies manually, that is the bundle files manually in our estimate.
And this is going to be helping us to automatically inject those files.
Next, we also have another plugin called Environment Plugin.
Now let's suppose you want to be hosting your application in multiple environments.
You have like your dev, your production environment and your queue environment.
You can set up some environment variables and this can be also done using the environment plugin.
Next we have the HTML minimizing plugin.
So whenever you're going to be giving a production output, you need to make sure your bundle size is
very small.
So this is going to be helping us to manipulate that bundle size.
Then finally, we are going to be seeing another very important and useful plugin, which is the main
thesis extract plugin.
Now if you remember when all of you were loading all this cases while they were just going to be getting
injected into our index start in the shadow section.
Now, from the performance perspective, this is not very good because we cannot be really caching all
the thesis files here.
Every time you are going to be loading that particular page, you also need to be pulling up all these
cases.
And it's going to be very useful if you can extract all of this thesis into a separate file.
And this is exactly what is going to be done by this plugin.
Now, once you apply this plugin, we are going to be having another file created that has the bundled
cases and that can be loaded into our steam and.
Okay.
So that is pretty much it of what is plug ins.
Let's continue on in the next video and see how we're going to be optimizing the last application using
plug ins.