Let's continue on from the last video and start adding a few more configurations to our back file.
Now we got the entry output and the plug in set up.
Now the next part that I would like to set up is the loaders.
Now, as you know, the loaders are using the module, so we need to be entering the parameter as module.
And this is going to be of type object.
And within this, it takes a parameter or an key called as rules, which is going to be of the type
added.
Now, within this, we again need to be creating an object and here we are going to be specifying all
our loaders.
So first of all, I would like to load all my access and the easiest files.
So let's see how we can be doing the setup.
So we put all here as test and we need to be entering our regular expression so we can type our regular
expression like this and put up a dollar sign here.
And next, we need to be specifying the loaders that are going to be used here so that can be defined
using the use added.
And in here we define all our loaders.
Now I already have all the loaders added to the package or adjacent, so we can just go ahead and add
those loaders right here.
So the first loader is going to be our CCS loader.
Then in this start, we need our style loader.
So that's going to be the style loader.
So if you remember, instead of the style loader, we used to be using another loader during optimization,
which is to give us a separate file.
Now, in this case, I already have that set up, so I'm going to be using that particular loader.
So that was done using the Minsk's extract plugin.
So for that, I'm just going to be importing that.
Let's go on top and say const Menzies extract plugin equals to required men thesis extract plugin.
Okay.
So I'm going to be replacing the style loader.
So in case you want directly, things to be added to the animals head.
So that can be done using style loader.
But for now I'm going to be using the C users extract plugin and the loader.
Okay.
So our CSR is part of the set up now.
We need to be creating the same thing for CSR since we have a lot of X files here as well.
So if you just open up any of the pages, you can see.
Yes, yes.
Now we do not really have courses, but in general you need to be keeping the support for both of them.
So for that reason, we are going to be adding both of those lawyers.
So as usual, we need to be putting our regular expression first.
So that is a CSR that CSR or here and these are the two formats.
So I can just also write this as this as I generally prefer this format.
Okay.
So we have the loader, we have this CSS loader as as we know, we need to be adding another loader
here.
So that is our CSR loader.
Okay.
So that's also done.
We have our modules set up.
We also need a module for loading the images.
So as we know, we have a lot of assets for the images.
So for that, I can just copy this loader one more time and add support for all the images so that can
be done using this format.
So we'll say jpg png.
Then we have the JPEG, then we have the gif.
And I think that's it for now.
Okay.
We can remove disclosures since we are going to be using the in-built loader now in bootloader can be
accessed using the type property.
And in here we see a third flash resource.
Cool.
So all this is done.
Now we have the base set up, sort of ready, actually.
Now, another thing that I would like to add over here is my dev.
So.
So when we are using our application, we need all those hotkey loadings and stuff to work, right?
So for that we need our dev.
So it'll be set up now using our estimate of a pack plugin.
We are already going to be getting the dest folder within which we have the index such html.
So we can just go ahead and add the dev.
So here.
So let's name this as dev server and this is going to be of type object.
Let me put up a comma here.
And in this we need to be specifying where our that's always going to be running, first of all, so
that can be specified using the static property.
And in this we are going to be specifying directory.
So there's a directory and in this will support.
Dot resolve underscore this name comma defect.
So this is where all our assets are going to be.
Okay.
We can also add additional properties here which are not added earlier.
So you can also specify things like be put.
So where you want to be running your dev.
So, so let's say for example, this time I won't be running it on the port 9000 and we can also specify
things such as open as true.
Now if you remember last time we used to add it in the package addition.
So this is also another way of adding your properties to your dev server.
Now there's also one more property that I would like to add to the config, and that is the mode in
which you are going to be running this entire configuration.
So I want to be running it in the development mode.
So in the module dot exports right on top, let's add the mode and this is going to be of mode development.
Okay.
So that's good.
So the basic things are now sort of set up now.
We're going to be taking a short break and I'm going to be running this pack configuration and we will
see that things are not really working as expected.
So we are going to be debugging why it did not work and how do we resolving that?
What are the additional configurations required in the event back file?
So see you after a short break.