So how did things go setting up this year?
Says Lauder.
Well, you're successful.
So if there are some issues, you can just follow along with me in this video and we're going to be
seeing how do we adding those lawyers in place?
Now, as usual, I'm going to be creating another folder here.
So as I told you earlier multiple times, this is just for tracking purpose, so that if you get stuck,
you can just come to the appropriate folder and load up from there.
Okay.
So I'm going to be naming this as the RSS loaders.
So that's done.
Let's quickly save that.
And I'm going to be moving up one folder that's CD 8.2 project caseloads.
Okay.
With that done, let me just close off all my tabs, open up my folder and open up diva pack configuration.
So as we've seen earlier, we need to be installing couple of loaders, possibly SS.
So let's go ahead install those first.
So it's going to be NPM, install there, send PMI in chart, then we can see save.
Dev and I just need the two dashes also in front.
And after that we can install all the loads.
So the first one is going to be the excess loader.
Then we need the second one as style loader.
And we also need the SPSS loader.
And finally, we also need the code package that is SC SS.
Okay, so these are all the loaders that are going to be required and we can now start updating the
configuration in other back file.
Now, I know you want to be averaging the loaders.
We need to add another section.
Yeah, that's called as module.
And in the module, we are going to be setting up the rules.
So these are the rules.
And in the rules we are going to be adding a nati which takes in an object.
So in the object we need to be adding the perimeter.
The first one is going to be the test section and the second one is the loaders.
So in this case, we are going to be using the loaders, so we'll type in use and then we can define
the loaders that we need.
All right.
In the test section, I can just add the regular expression for testing so I can just put in the slash
then or here, I'll say dot theses.
So that's our CSC file getting tested.
Now, the loaders that we're going to be using over here is the style loader.
So there's the style loader and then we need to use the CAS loader just like that.
Okay.
So we have the excess rules set up.
We also need to be doing the same thing for access.
Since I told you that we're using both of those types of format.
Now, in this case, it's going to be a little bit different.
So we will say s e and then.
See.
SS Alright.
So that took some time, but we are there.
All right, so we have the access and access supported over here using this loader.
The only additional thing that we need, all we had is to define that.
We also need to be using the SC SS loader.
Okay.
So that looks pretty good.
We have all the loaders in place now.
We can quickly try to run this file once again.
So I just saved this file and close this and see and PM run.
Dev okay.
All that pack configuration is starting off and this time we do not actually get this CSS errors.
So things looks pretty great.
We are able to create the dest folder in that we have the two bundle files and this is also is getting
loaded now.
Now what are we going to be doing next is we are going to be moving the cases file into our index file.
So if we just open our four SRT folder, open up the index start edge HTML.
Now in the next hour, we can see that a couple of the easiest files we have, the index starts here
says we have font awesome and also bootstrap.
Now let's see how we can be importing this using the import statement and remove it from the steam file.
So for doing that, what we need to be doing is so first of all, let's fix this font or some dortmunder
cases.
So for that, what I'll do is instead of directly importing it in the DC file, let's go to our index
start CSS file.
Now, we have not seen this earlier, but you can also import one cases into another cases.
So what I can say is at the root import and in this I can just point to that particular file so we can
say dot slash and then we can go to the assets and in that we have the cases font.
Awesome.
Not mandatory.
Yes.
So with that done, as soon as our index starts, this file is loaded in our browser, it's going to
be pulling up all the font.
Awesome.
And Garcia says as well.
Okay, so that's done with the font.
Awesome Dortmund.
Garcia says, Now let's close this file and remove this dependency from our index start estimate.
Let's see the next one, which is the bootstrap dortmunder cases.
Now, another approach that people generally follow is having a separate vendor Nazi SS file and just
importing that when the Nazi SS.
Now let's see what I'm trying to say here.
I'm going to be first creating a new file here.
So I'll say new file and let's call this as maybe underscore render.
Dot SCA says so I'm going to be using all my SCA says dependencies of the event is added right here
so if I just open up the bootstrap documentation so this is the documentation opened up you can see
that we have a section called importing styles and in that you can actually be importing bootstrap just
like this.
So you have the bootstrap, then it goes to the SC assets folder and it loads all the bootstrap styles
so we can just copy all of this import statement and add it to our vendor dot access.
So that's import.
Then we have a timeline bootstrap this does that we need to be going to the node modules folder and
then finding out the bootstrap dependency.
And within that we should be having the access folder.
Within that we have the bootstrap dependency of the access.
Okay with that then let's just see if this closed this file and remove the bootstrap dependency from
here as well.
All right, so that looks good.
Now, finally, the question comes in.
We need to be loading our index Nazi SS and also our access file that we had created.
So for that, we can also be removing our index Nazi SS dependency from here.
Go back to our index, start guys and load all our dependencies right here so I can say import and then
we can be calling the index dot thesis.
So that's our index Nazi SS.
And then we can also be importing our access.
So that is not slash vendor underscore vendor nazi SS.
Okay, so we have all our things as dependencies added here.
Now you can also see that we also have a toaster dart access file.
So actually you can be moving this also in the same folder as we had earlier.
So that was the vendor.
So this is also a dependency that was installed externally.
So what I'll do is I'll just copy this dependency from here.
And in this case, we'll just go to our vendor dot access file, add in another import statement and
then just paste that location just like that.
Okay, so that's done.
We also need to be just fixing up a little bit our vendor diseases.
So as you can see right now, this vendor DOT accesses altered our CRC folder so you can just drag this
and move it to our SLC folder, making sure that it's at the same level.
Now with that done, everything should be dissolving automatically.
Okay.
So I can just see if this file and closes and we have our index start file, we can also remove this
toaster dependency from here and everything should work as expected.
So let's try to run our build once again.
So I'll just clear the console and PM run dev.
And with that done, let's wait for it.
And there you go.
We see that Albert is now successful and things should be looking much better.
So what I'm going to be doing now is let's try to load our index start HTML.
Now, if I just open up the index start estimate file and let's try to see what happens here.
So if I just go at the bottom of the page and in here right now, you can see that it's pointing to
the index start.
Yes.
Let's do some manual work right now.
And in here, we need to be pointing to the index start bundle dogs.
So instead of this, I'm going to be moving up on folder dist and then see index start bundled out.
Yes.
Okay.
So we are going to be automating all of this soon.
But for now, let's just make sure things are working as expected.
Right click and set will in finder and let's double click to open.
And things are looking pretty well.
We can see that our type library was working.
And if I just inspect this, you can also see all the dependencies loading in.
So I just say refresh and we are loading our index start bundle, which contains all our dependencies
that reloaded via NPM.
All right.
Things looks pretty good after adding this process loaders.
But this one problem here.
So if I scroll down and we have this subscribe to newsletter and if I just enter a dummy email ID here
and try to click on subscribe, did not see the error message that was shown earlier.
Now if I just try to inspect and see what's going on wrong here, go to the console and in here you
can see that the validate was not defined and this basically means that the library was not imported.
So let's go back to our code and try to fix this off.
So going back to our index start, yes, we are going to be adding the additional dependencies to that
as of validate.
So are import validate from validate dodges.
And we also need another dependency that is for showing that toaster icon.
So we need to import that as well so as to import toaster from toaster.
Okay.
So that looks pretty good.
Let me see if that off.
Clear the console and try to ring the build once again.
Okay.
The build as successful, if I go back to my browser, hit on refresh and this time you see that we
have the email address and if I enter some wrong email address and click unsubscribe, we do see the
error message.
So that's fantastic.
Things are looking pretty good now.
All right.
So that's pretty much it for this video.
And what are you going to be doing next is going to be copying this HTML file into the DIST folder and
we are also going to be running the Webpack dev server.
So we do not need to be actually running the build again and again manually.
So I want you to try to do this by yourself, as have already covered this in the previous videos.
As a heads up, we are going to be installing two dependencies.
One is going to be a steamvr backed plugin, and the second one is going to be the Webpack dev server.
And you also need to be doing the configurations in the Webpack file as well as the package Node.js.
And so that's about it.
Let's take a short break and continue on in the next video.