Welcome back.
In the last video, we saw how to be importing books in our JavaScript file, and that was pretty cool.
But I'm going to be showing you something even more color.
So let's see how theses modules work.
So what I see is as modules and where are they useful?
So to showcase that, I need to be creating an additional file.
So what I want you to be doing is go to the SRT folder and let's go ahead and create a new component
here.
So we are going to be calling this component as clear button dot GS.
So basically the concept is if I just switch over to my browser, I want a new button to be coming up
here.
And when I click on that, I need to be clearing up the list that gets created here.
Well, for now, you're not going to be clearing the list, but we're just going to be showcasing that
particular button.
So let's switch back to our code here.
And in this, what we're going to be doing is creating the button.
So will a contest element equal to document or create element?
And in this, we are going to be creating a button.
So let me just type in button.
So element dot in our achievements or we can also give it a label.
Let's call this as clear.
Cool.
Now we also need to be appending this to a particular DOM element.
So what I'm going to be doing is if I go to the index start estimable, you can see that we have the
body section in which all the other elements are there.
So I'm just going to be appending it after this button.
So just going back to our clear button Roger's, we can see document, dot, body, dot, apparent child
and in here you can just see as element.
The final thing that I want to be doing is adding a click listener.
So I'll say doc element dot on click and that's equal to a function.
And in the function we are not going to be doing the largest C alert as clear clicked.
Cool.
So that looks good just to make sure that things are working as expected.
I need to be first obviously importing this player, but yeah, so what I'll do, I'll go back to the
index ideas and let's import this file here to say import dart slash player button.
Okay.
So as soon as I got here, that code, all these files are going to be called as well.
That's our dependency graph kicking in.
Okay, so let's clear the console.
Let's run and beam, run, build.
Last one.
Let's switch over to a browser refresh and we have a clear button.
If I click on it, it is clear.
Click.
So far, so good.
All right.
Now for the interesting part, let's switch back and ask you first to our buttons.
Now I'm going to be going to the index darts.
Yes.
And I'm going to be adding a class called as button.
And in this let's give it a background as maybe a loop and of a dart.
Then we also need to be applying this and I need to be going to my index dart edge HTML.
And in this we have the button called button one.
And I'm going to be adding a class here.
Let's call this class as button, which you had just declared.
I'm also going to be doing the same thing for our clear button.
So we are going to be adding a dynamic class here as well.
So as the element DART class list, DART added and in this you can put up added within which you are
going to be defining as button.
So this is the class that reacting.
Okay, so far so good.
Let's try to run this once again to make sure things are working out as expected.
So switch back.
We can see that both the buttons are getting a color yellow.
That's matching exactly my shirt.
All right, fine.
Let's switch back to things now.
You can see that where the problem lies.
Let's suppose I want to be giving this clear button another class.
So let's suppose I define another CSS file here.
Imagine that clear button is like a separate component altogether.
It does not know that there is going to be injected and so on.
So I've created a clear button dart thesis and this developer comes in and it creates another class
with the name button.
So what?
Obama But that's what he has done.
So I'll just create another class called Button and this guy gave it a background of non background
color, just background as maybe a red.
All right, so that's done.
Now, if I come to my clear button, I need to be importing that case file.
So I'll say import dart slash, clear button, dart thesis.
Okay, so that's done.
Clear the console, run, npm, run, build.
Once again, switch back to our browser and click on refresh.
Oh.
As you can see, both our buttons have become red.
So that was not expected, right?
Well, let's try to understand what's happening here.
If I take out my head section, you can see that we have the style tag integrated here.
In this, we had the button called as background yellow.
And we also have another style tag in which we had the class button which has a background red.
Now, as you can see, due to this class, being at the lower level is having a higher precedence.
That's why both of the buttons have become red.
Now, this is exactly the place that the SS modules are very helpful.
We are going to be using the Axis model to be segregating both these classes so that they are identified
uniquely.
So let's see how that is done.
Now for using the US model.
One fundamental change need to be done to our configuration.
So let's switch back to over paddock config dodgers and we're going to be changing the way we're using
our access loaders.
So in this, we are going to be seeing as use somewhat a bit of moving all of this.
But just for comparison, I'm keeping it.
And this is going to be an ADI.
And instead of directly putting the string values, we are going to be defining objects in this.
So the first object is going to be defined here.
We are going to be putting the property as loader and this is going to be style loaders.
I can just cut and paste it right here.
Okay.
Let me just fix my columns, and that's perfect.
The second is also going to be a loader and this is going to be this year as loader.
So let's cut that and put it right here and remove all of this unused coal.
Okay.
So far, nothing has changed the course loader and style loaders as before.
Now, the additional thing that we need to be doing by enabling theses modules is putting up the options
properties.
So in here you say options and in this field to be defining as modules and then through.
So that's pretty much it.
So, insists Lauda.
We have added another property called Options, in that we have created an object with modules property
as group.
So that's all required to enable C.
S modules.
Now, with that done, how to think look different.
So I'm going to be running once again the build.
So let's run, NPM, run, build.
Everything passes.
So that path configuration is correct.
Switching back to the browser, I click on refresh and we have lost all this users.
Why is that?
Let's switch to our console and check what's happening here.
Now, if I were one of these static tags, you can see that we no longer see the names that were given
for the classes, but we see some random characters here.
Now, what Webpack has done, it has basically made up names of its own.
And these are the names that we are going to be using for our classes.
We have already added the body section in which we are using the class as button, but since there's
no class called Button anymore, these styles are not applied.
Now, as you can see, every style that has been created over here are having unique characters, and
that is exactly where it's going to be very helpful.
Now, how do we using this classes that have been created?
Let's go back to our code.
And in this we go to our index dogs.
Okay.
Now, instead of just importing the access file, we're going to be importing it as a style.
So I would say style from index starts, the says.
Now, whenever I wanted to be using this style, I need to be putting it using the dot operator.
So what exactly is in this style?
Well, using the SS module, all the class that is there is going to be exported as an object.
So what are we controlling this out to show you and make it more clear?
So I just say consolidate log.
So how do you use this style?
Well, for example, we wanted to apply the style on the button one.
So instead of just adding a directly what I say convert button one equals to this one.
And then we can just put it a little bit refactoring and then add the event listener.
Now I also want to be doing another thing, so I'll say button one dot class list, dot add.
And in this, I need to be passing in that now to be adding the class.
What I'll be doing is style dot button.
So this is how we are going to be applying this style.
So we'll use the dot operator and then apply these styles.
A similar thing can be done for the clear button as well.
So instead of just directly importing this.
Yes, I say import style from.
And please note this is a variable.
You can just name it as you like.
Okay.
Now introducing button, we are going to be doing this similar thing.
So this is style dot and then we say button.
Cool.
So that's pretty much it.
Now, if I just try to refresh once again, so I would say NPM, run, build and things have been properly.
Let's try to refresh our page and voila we do see our is getting applied.
So that's really good.
We have learned how we were using the access modules.
Now this one more special feature of this module that I would like to show you.
So for example, let's suppose you are not really having this uses now.
I do have used x styled or button.
Now what do you expect to happen?
So for example, if I run NPM, run, build, what do you expect would happen?
Will it be applying this style or not?
Well, if you expect this style to be applied, well, that's not going to happen.
So if you just switch back here, you can see that the button did not get rendered itself well, it
did not get rendered because it was not able to find the styles against the style is not defined.
And this is exactly why the application sort of broke at that place while we are going to be fixing
that shortly.
Let's suppose you want to be using all the styles that were there in the indexed audience.
So how do we do that?
Well, you can do that as well.
So as you know, we already have defined the index study of cases in that we had the button style and
only use the same style in the clear button.
Now what you can do here is you can remove all of this.
And you can use the concept of global studies.
So how do you define global styles for defining global styles?
What you can be doing is you can go back to the index, talk to the masses, and you can put up the
keyword as X column and then say global and move all of this class in a bracket just like that.
I write the dart and what happens is this particular style is going to be exported as a global style.
Now, if I can come back in my career button now I can just add up the array and just put or here as
button just like that.
So if I refresh my build once again and be build and if I come back to my browser C refresh, we can
see that our status is getting applied on both the element because we made it as a global style.
Now we can see that we're just getting one more error there.
It comes over here because we are trying to use this index.
Yes.
And we are trying to use the style element.
Now, since we had made it global, this does not exist anymore and that is presented by this console.log
log.
So if you see the consolidated log, we just have one style that is there in our space object that is
the header style.
Since that was not made as the global object.
So this was not made as the global.
That's why it's available over here.
All the global objects have been removed from their style object.
That's why it is being applied on the A.T.M. page.
So that is how we are going to be using these as modules.
I hope this gave you a good overview of how do we importing these styles as components in the ideas
file and how do we using the DART operator and then apply any of these styles on any of your elements
if you use React?
This is a very popular approach over there.
Okay.
If you would like to learn more about this module and what other features that you can be using, I
will point to the documentation as well.
So this is on GitHub slash thesis dash modules and then again six modules.
I'm going to be adding this along with the lecture so you can just check it out if you wish to.
So this has all the documentation on how do we use the next module, what are global styles, what are
local styles and so on.
And this can be very helpful for your next project.
All right.
So that's about it for theses modules.
So let me take a short break and see how do we dealing with some pre processes, especially the SSP
process that's about it and see you in the next video.