In the last video, we were able to analyze what's happening in our bundle.
Now, just to give a recap, let's see what was our bundle looking like?
So let me go to my browser and we saw that we had two bundles and there were a lot of dependencies that
were getting replicated across the bundles.
So in this video, we're going to be seeing how to be optimizing all of this.
So let's go back to our code.
And in this, I've already created a new folder here.
As you can see, it's 8.6.
If you want, you can just continue on with the previous folder and you're going to be using this optimization
base as your root folder.
Okay.
But that's it.
Let's start ahead and do the optimization.
Now, surprisingly, the optimization is quite straightforward.
You do not need to install any plugin as such.
So how does it work?
Now in the back it gives in-built optimization tool.
So this is specific for Webpack five.
So make sure you're using the latest version of a pack.
Now what I'm going to be doing here, we have seen the plugin section.
I'll just minimize this for now.
And I'm going to be adding a new section here.
So this is called as optimization.
So that's optimization right there.
And this is, again, going to be of type object.
Now, we are going to be adding some optimizations here.
And the optimization that we're looking for is called split chunks.
So as the name suggest, we are going to be splitting and creating additional chunks.
We yeah.
Now we also need to be specifying one additional property within it, and that is which are the chunks
that we need to split.
So by default, we are going to be splitting all the chunks that were created.
So in our case, there were two chunks that were created or two bundles that were created, I would
say.
And those are the courses and the index bundle ideas.
So any of you would say as chunks and this is going to be of type string and we are putting up here
as all now this property takes in multiple values so you can pass in all, you can pass it async and
so on.
And we are going to be seeing that later on.
What are the differences?
But for the most part, they are going to be just setting it as on.
Now, believe it or not, that's all we need to be doing for getting started with the optimization.
Now what I'm going to do here is I just open up my console, save my Webpack file, and we're going
to be running NPM run dev.
Now, before we go ahead and Randy, NPM run Dev, I want to be disabling one of the plugin.
And that is going to be our plugin for analyzing the bundle.
So this is the blog in.
I'm going to be disabling for now.
So let's just save that and C and B, Imran Dev.
Okay.
Let's just give that a second.
So my Brendan was successful.
You can see it compiled successfully.
And let's check out what's that in our test folder?
This folder is going to be quite different than what we had seen earlier.
Now, as you can see earlier, we used to be having a bundle called us course dot bundle dodgers and
we had the index start bundle not.
Now you can see things have shifted quite a lot.
We do have the coaster bundle, but it does not have any of the duplicate dependencies.
For example, if I tried to search for Lord Edge, I do not really see the Lord Ash Library getting
loaded.
The one that we are seeing or here is the implementation of the Lord Edge, but not the actual library,
which we're seeing earlier.
Now, where is Lord Ash?
Well, Lord Ash is going to be present in another bundle of example.
Let's check out this bundle over here and let's try to find Lord Ash in this bundle.
And you can see that it's loaded in this bundle.
So this is the node module's Lord Ash Library getting loaded right here.
Similarly, if you check out our index store bundle, this should not also contain the Lord Ash.
So let's just quickly search for Lord.
And we do not see Lord Ash getting implemented here as well.
And that's fantastic.
That means our bundle is now sort of optimized.
Now, let's just make sure that things are still working in our solo.
So I'm just going to be running as NPM run search.
So let's just get our bill started.
Browser opens up and let's just give it a second and we can see our application is loading as before.
But this time if I go to the inspector, let's open that up and go to a network and give it a refresh
so that we can see the dependencies getting loaded.
Now in here you can see that the index start bundle is getting loaded.
We have the vendor access and we have the node modules of the dependencies.
So our indicator bundles are split into two other bundles over here.
And this is exactly where optimization comes into place.
Now, these are the bundles which are going to be shared with other files as well.
So for example, if I go to the courses page, we can see that Courses page is loading like before and
this time we have the additional bundles getting loaded over here as well.
Now you might be wondering what the advantage I mean, what's the point of splitting it into different
bundles?
Well, this is where the caching of the browser comes into place.
Now, when our our browser recognizes that, okay, there is a file that I already have earlier and
there's nothing changed in the file.
So instead of going into questing the file from the server, it's just going to be loading it from the
cache.
And that's extremely fast.
And this is exactly what's happening over here.
Now, since this contains the vendor dependencies, for example, like bootstrap, now you might be
changing the style on your page.
So for example, if I change this styling or here, so I'm using the bootstrap library, but there's
no change in the bootstrap library itself.
So it does not really make sense to be updating this bundle.
So in that case, it's just going to be loading it from cache and only the course bundle radius is going
to be pulled from the server so that you have the new dependencies pulled in.
And this is going to be saving a lot of time.
And this is the beauty of how these split chunks plug in work.
Now, let's do one more thing.
Let me go back to my VS code.
What are we stopping this out by saying control C and then we're going to be enabling the bundle analyzer
plugin.
So let's have that and then see NPM run dev.
All right.
My plugin shows the all the dependencies and you can see things have changed dramatically over here.
So here we have this huge bundle vendor bundle area.
And this contains all the Lord Ash Library.
It contains the equity.
And it contains all the things that are going to be shared across the files.
Similarly, it also created another bundle for index start theses that are bundle ideas and this contains
the excess files.
So as you can see, it has the vendor access, it has default to some and also our index uses.
So it is very smart.
It knows how to be categorizing the files as well.
So all the JavaScript is in one bundle.
You got like your CSRs in another bundle and you can see that they were like some individual bundles
like this one right here, index, start, bundle, and it contains all the JavaScript that is specific
to the course bundle and this contains all the JavaScript that is specific to the index bundle.
There's no sharing required between these bundles.
And this gives a very good overview of how well we have optimized our bundles using Webpack.
All right.
I hope you learned a lot from this.
And we're going to be seeing further how to be optimizing it more.
And right now, as you can see, we are loading the entire load library, although we are just using
one or two functions of load.
So how well, we're going to be optimizing that.
We're going to be seeing that soon in the upcoming videos.
All right.
So let's take a short break and continue on becoming of Apache Ninja.