Welcome back.
So were you able to install the festival backpack plugin along with the dev server?
Well, if you got stuck anywhere.
Let's continue on with this video ante to get those things installed and started.
So I have already created a new folder here so you can see Google's project dev software and this is
going to be having all the configuration regarding the Def Solar.
So for that, what we are going to be doing next is going to be installing the dependencies first so
I can see NPM install save dev.
The first one is the Mel left back plugin.
And the second one is the Webpack dev server.
Okay.
So both of this dependencies are going to be installed and we can go to the package, Jason, and add
a new script to start of our dev server.
So I can add it right here, call this as server and in here we'll see that back serve the configuration
of the web back file.
And there's that back door config that yes, the mode is going to be development as usual and we have
the open flag for opening up the browser.
Okay.
So that's pretty standard.
We saw that earlier as well.
Now we can disclose of this package addition as we have done all the configurations required.
Next thing we can do here is at the dev server side, see dev server and this is going to be an object.
The thing we need to be specifying is the port so I can define the static parameter and that is going
to be in the disk folder.
Okay.
So we have set up the dev server, but we need to be also adding the ML file.
So as you see right now, we do not have the original file and the dev, so is not going to be running
as expected.
So for that, we need to be having the plug in section also.
So after the modules are before wherever you like, you can just have in a plug in section and this
is going to be of type added.
And in this we define our plugins.
So I would say new HTML web back plugin.
And in here we are going to be specifying our options.
Now, before that, let me just make sure that we have the file imported the library important.
So it's a cost estimate Webpack plugin equals to required.
And this is the HTML plugin.
Okay.
So we have the plug in right here.
Now we need to be doing the configurations template.
So that's the first configuration defining where is going to be the template for this.
So the two files that we need to be solving are the index stardust HTML.
That is right here.
And the second one is this go start item.
So what we'll do is a dart slash as I see index dart html.
And we also need to define the chunks which are going to be loaded when we load this file.
So the chunks in this case is going to be this entry file right here, which is the index.
So let me just probably minimize this little bit.
And if you go down, we can point to that junk.
So that's the index junk.
The second thing we need to be adding for the course file so we can just copy this plugin and add a
new one right here.
And instead of the index, we can just go to the pages and in here we can see courses dart edge HTML.
So let me just verify the file and yes, it has courses dart HTML and the chunks is going to be updated
as well.
So this is not the entry file we need for that demon.
It is this one.
So you just copy that and be straight here.
Now, please notice one more thing.
Let's suppose you want multiple chunks to be loaded.
So let's say, for example, there are two entry files for a single file.
Generally won't do that, but for some reason let's suppose there is some particular file.
You can also add dart here.
So let's suppose it was dependent on index as well as courses.
They could just add courses here as well.
So in our application we do not need it.
So I'll just keep it as index.
Okay.
The last thing that we need to fix all your ready file.
Now, we had already encountered this error earlier.
Since we have two times the estimate of a pack plugin, it's going to give us an error that it cannot
be keeping the file name as theme.
So for that, we need to be also giving our, I would say, file name.
Let's call this as the index start adjustment.
And this file name can be called as.
The courses that each team will.
Perfect.
So that looks pretty good.
Now, what I can do or here is try to run this build.
So I'll say npm.
Run, Dev.
And let's see if the belt works properly first.
Now we can see that a couple of errors.
Let's try to quickly fix this.
So the error here is we forgot to put a comma.
So we need to come after the parameters.
Now, if I just save that and try to run the command once again and we see that we have a new error,
so let's just quickly fix the errors one by one.
So it says invalid configuration object that has been initialized does not match this schema.
And I've seen that delay issue in the plug ins.
Now, I am not really editing this because I want you to see how I figured out the errors and how I
fix them.
So this might prove to be helpful in your case as well.
So I'll just scroll to the plugins section.
So this is all plug ins and the problem Toyota's it says the unknown property plug in.
Well, that's because plug in is not the property, it is plug ins.
And that's defined by the idea parsing multiple plug ins.
So let's save that the console and I do run it the third time.
So this time the error is with the communicating.
So if I just called to the top, let's try to fix that as well.
And fingers crossed, hopefully things work out this time and it's taking some time.
So I'm really hoping this should work properly and we in fact see that it was successful.
So after a lot of trial and error, we was successfully able to create the Webpack file.
All right, great.
That's good.
Now, we also have to make sure that the things are working.
If I go to the test folder, I, in fact see that the two SDL files are present here.
So let's give it a try and run our dev several thousand pm.
Run.
Serve.
Okay.
Diva pack def.
So we're starting off.
It opens up the browser aspect of our configurations.
So running on localhost, AT&amp;T and voila, we see our page here.
Now there are a couple of issues here which I can notice immediately.
One is the banner image is missing and let's see if our routing is working as well.
And we see that our routing is breaking as well.
So why are things not working here?
Well, let's figure that out in the next video.