All right.
In the last video, we got things working, but there was one problem that the thesis was not getting
copied.
Now, I'm going to be telling you the reason why it did not work.
But we're going to be fixing this properly in the upcoming section and we're going to be automating
all of this what we are going to be doing now manually.
So going back to our code and if you go to the index statistics in the test folder, we can see that
we have the reference for the excess.
That's right here.
But the difference is still to the local folder.
So as you can see, this dot slash index starts the SS.
And as you can see, we do not really have devices cases in the test folder.
So how do we fix it?
Well, for now it's quite straightforward.
I'm just going to be copying both the cases files and pasting it right here.
Okay.
So with those the SS files present, if I go back to my browser C refresh and we can see that things
are looking better, we have the cases loaded, the things like the images are still breaking.
So if I go back to the code and try to go to the GC files, so if you go to the index store these file
and if you check out the image source, it was located in dot slash asserts and then it goes to the
image name.
So for that reason we need to be creating a third folder and then we need to be basically copying all
of this that we have and moving it into this other folder.
So just copy and paste it right here.
Okay.
So with that done, let me just close this and try to go back to my browser and hit refresh and voila,
we see that things are working as required.
Now I'm doing all of this manually because I want you to understand behind the scene what back is going
to be helping us with now later on, what we are going to be seeing is how we can be moving the assets
directly from the CRC folder to the DEST folder.
Now will end object.
It should be that the disk folder should be containing all the assets, all the resources that are required
for running our application independently, and we are going to be achieving that very soon.
So for now you saw that.
What are the steps that we had to do manually to get our application working?
Alright with that fix, let's take a short break and in the next video we are going to be using one
of the most important part of that back and that is hot reloading or reloading.
So in that we do not really have to be coming again and again and running the build and this is going
to be really helpful when we are doing our development.
So see you soon in the next video.