Hey there.
In this video, I would just like to do one small announcement to our bed.
So we're outputting multiple window files.
We so as you can see, we got this render node modules or indexes and the index bundle.
Now this one problem here and I wouldn't really call it a problem, rather it's an announcement and
that is the hash version of this build.
Now how would the browser caching works is whenever the name of the bundle gets changed, is automatically
going to be sending the request to the server.
So in that case, we are going to be changing the hash version only and only when there is a change
in the bundle itself.
So for example, if are pulling up a new version of the bootstrap only, then the hash version is going
to be changed and then the browser is going to be sending the request to the server for the new file.
So in short, we need to be adding the hash to this bundle logs.
Okay.
So to do that, it's quite simple.
We just go back to our code and in our code we had the output port here and in this we are already using
the name as the output.
And I just want to add additional property here and the additional property is called S content hash
so we can put O'Hara's content hash dot bundled nodes.
Now we do not really need the DOT bundle also, so I can probably get rid of that.
So let me just remove that from here.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And I'm just going to be stopping my backside and starting it off again.
Now, please remember, if you're making them change to the web back file itself, you need to be restarting
your web back.
So okay, with that said, let's say NPM run.
So once again.
Our browser opens up and we're going to be inspecting and seeing if the file names have changed.
Now I also have the analyzer plugin running, so this also is getting started.
So let's close that off and inspect our website.
And in our Web site, if I go to the network tab, hit refresh once again.
Now we see that we have the vendor node modules, but we also have the hash version right here.
So we have both for the vendor node modules as well as for the vendor X modules.
And we also have it for the index dodgers.
And this acquisition is going to be changing only if any of the dependencies that are inside those bundles
get changed.
Alright, so that's a small announcement right here, but this is going to be helping a lot with the
browser caching so that unnecessary request are not sent to ourselves.
So that's about it for this video.
Let's move on to the next one.