In this video.
Let's see how we can be exposing those components that we need to be using on the home bed application.
So the one that we're interested in is the movie card component.
So I've already opened up this React component.
And within this, let me just give you an overview of how things are structured here.
So if I just open the source folder, we have the component folder and within this we have like this
buttons, dropdown, movie card and typography.
Now if I just open up the button component, there's something interesting here.
In the button folder, we have a couple of buttons here.
So we go out like this by button glitch, simple.
And this no button.
And all of this have been sort of combined and exported from this index cards for simplicity.
If I just go to the ideas and see how things have been important here.
Now, in the app, yes, we have like this import button and these things have been imported from the
index dogs and that's how our application has been loaded here.
So this is our our dogs working and this is how we are displaying all the buttons and the card component.
Now, if I just go back to the code now when we exporting, we are not really interested in this app,
not just because Abdulaziz is the entire file.
We are not really interested.
We are just interested in those couple of components that are being created separately here.
Okay.
So if you want to be exporting this as usual, we need to be going to have a pack configuration and
all the magic happens here.
Let me make this a bit smaller and mean to first import our component.
So I would say contact and put up the collaborators equals to require and this is going to be imported
from the pack dot container.
And in here we can be finding it as module federation, plug in, make sure that you have all your capitalization
in place because this is a named export and if you try to use some of the capitalization is not going
to really work.
Okay.
So we have the plug in imported, which is directly being exported by the pack.
No external installation is required here.
As usual, we when we want to be using our plug in, we go to our plug in section and start writing
the configurations.
So NERC as new model for plug in and pass in the configuration object.
Okay.
So what are the configuration object we need to be passing?
The first one is called us name.
The second one is called as the file name.
Then we have the third one, which is the exposes, and that's it actually for exposing something.
Now, let me tell you what these three properties that we just created here.
The first one name is the application name by which you want to be exposing this entire application
to the outer world.
So for example, this is called as react component.
So probably I can just make a short and call this and pad application as component.
Or maybe components since it's multiple.
Okay, so that's done.
Now, the second one is called if by limb.
And this quite important, if I just switch back to on my diagram, we had this remote entry last year
and this was the file that was being found by the other application which was importing it.
And this remote entry is exactly what is the file name.
So if I just go back, the file name is going to be called as remote and three dot gas.
Now please note it does not really have to be mentioned as a remote control.
You can just give it any name you want.
But this is generally the convention that's been followed.
Okay, so we have the file name setup.
Finally, we need to be putting up the exposes property.
So exposes is going to be an type of object and it need to be defined as the key value pair.
The first is the key, which is the component name.
Now for the component name, we need to be starting it with a dot slash and then give it a name.
So for example, I can give it as a movie card and then we need to specify the entire path for it.
So this is going to be in dot slash as our C slash component slash.
Movie card slash.
If I just go open up the memory card, we have this movie card, not gsx.
So I'll put it up here as a movie card dot gsx.
Now, just to make sure that you don't make any spelling mistakes, there's another way to do it.
So you can just right click on the movie card and you can see whereas copy relative bought and just
pasted over here.
So you know, it gives you the entire part and then you can sort of just cut it from here.
So we can we need it from the SRT locations.
I can just see control C remove all of this and then if I just be a store here, I can just really make
sure that, you know, I don't have any typing mistakes here.
Okay, so that was the movie card.
The second component is a simple example, the buttons that we've created.
Now, there's one very important factor here.
When will you exposing the component?
You cannot be exposing it as the named export.
You need to be exposing only default component.
So what do I mean by that?
Now, if I just open up the buy button and just open up one of the components, for example, this one
by button and scroll all the way to the bottom, we can see that is exported as a default component.
And this is exactly what we need when we're using module federation.
For example, if I go to the index cards, we are exporting this as the AMP components and this is not
really going to work when we're going to try to export it from here, from the exposes property.
So make sure that you have already full components created.
As closer.
Now I can be exposing the individual buttons here so I can say dot slash.
And then let's say you want to be exposing this by button.
So I would say by button.
And then we can also give the location for it.
So I'm just going to copy and paste here and change the things.
So this is from the button folder.
Then within the button folder, we have the buy button folder.
And within the by button folder we have the G6.
So by.
Button dot G6.
Okay.
So for now, I'm just going to be exporting these two components and see how things work.
I'm just going to be saving this file.
Open up our terminal and we need to be restarting ourselves.
Because since we have made some changes in the configuration itself, it's not going to automatically
pick it up.
So I already have my react components or terminal open up.
Just navigate around and find your react components.
And the second Rosie to stop this as well as clear the console off and see and PM her on.
So.
Let's give that a second.
Our browser opens up and loading this micro frontend.
We have the application running on port 3000.
Two things work pretty much as before, but now if you just go to the new orders, slash remote entry
dogs, press enter and voila we see a remote entry file created by default for us using this Webpack
plugin.
So that's pretty cool.
Now, one more thing to notice in this particular output is the components that we expose.
So we expose this component called as movie card.
So if I just come back to the browser and the dart slash movie card, we can see that this component
is being exported from this remote entry, and that's how all the communication channel works.
So our second application is going to be hitting this remote entry, Dodge's.
It's going to be searching for this movie card and that's how it's going to be loading this component
in the other application.
And that's pretty cool once we get all the things set up.
Okay, so that's about how we're going to be exposing the components.
I'm going to be taking a short break and then we'll see how do we importing this component in the homepage
application?