Things seem to be working pretty well.
We got our application running in the browser, but there's one particular issue that I'd still like
to fix.
So first, to demonstrate the issue, let me just get myself started.
So I'd say NPM, run, serve.
So let's get that opened up in the browser.
Okay.
So my application now started.
If I click on Sign In, I look at the page by classic example.
I use the browser's back button and the front button.
We can still see things are working, but if I sent a request, you can see that it is not cannot get
these flash movies.
Similarly, if I go back, you can see on the log in as well and if I just try to click enter as well,
nothing works.
Well, what's happening here now to explain what's happening here, we have the event Dev Silver running
right.
And we also have a React application running.
Now generally what happens in our client relation is the browser sends the request to our so that I
want this login page and it returns I will file in return.
Now in our case we do not have individual achievement files for every note as we had earlier, so the
dev server does not really know what to be returning back.
So we need a way in which you can sort of tell that backed up so that here we're using client side routing
or our routing is basically managed by react application and do not try to basically mess up the data
out.
So how do you configure that?
It sounds complicated, but it's quite straightforward.
So let me just go back to the configuration in the dev server.
So this is how our application is being served locally.
So in the dev, so we just need to be adding an additional configuration.
And in here we can see as history.
EPA.
Fall back.
As true.
So this is basically the configuration that we need to be adding to the dev.
So let's see if that stop also and try to run the application once again.
Okay.
So our new application starts off.
Let me sign in.
We have the page added here.
Let me use the browser's back button and just maybe try to enter or maybe like go to the movies it out.
And we do see that these movies are out as added and we do not really get that cannot get flash movies.
So now we can see that our routing is working pretty well.
We can move between the notes when using the browser's front and the back button.
So that was about a small configuration update in our dev.
So let's take a short break and continue on adding some more configurations.