This is a very important video, and please do not skip this.
You're going to be needing this project structure for following along in many of these actions.
Now already uploaded the entire project structure on my GitHub account.
So you just can come to this GitHub account called got only one slash about back to me and you're going
to be finding the entire project source code over here.
Now to be using this, you can just come to this code and say download zip.
Now this is going to be downloading the entire source code on your local and it is also going to be
the starting point for many of these actions.
So let's just give that a second while it downloads.
Okay.
So once you have that, download it up so I can just shorten finder extract this folder here.
And you can just open up this folder and you're going to be finding the entire source code for all the
sections that we're going to be covering in this entire course.
So in many of these sections, you are going to be hearing me say that this is going to be our base
for starting off this section, and you need to be basically using this folder for doing the development.
Similarly, you can see that I have a couple of base folders here.
So for example, I have this project base.
Then we also have this production build base and so on.
So we can either do the development within the same folder, or you can just clone this and create a
new folder for yourself.
Now you can also see that I have some additional folder here.
So in case you get stuck in any of the places.
So for example, you get stuck in this place called as split cases, one of the lectures in the course.
So you can just go inside this and compare the source code along with what source code you have written.
And this can help you in debugging if something is not working as expected.
Okay.
So just make sure that you had this folder structure downloaded.
So whenever you want to be doing some development, you can just open up your best code.
So for example, I have my voice code already open here and you can just drag and drop this entire folder,
for example, right here.
And then you can start doing your development.
Now, just to give you an overview, you can start your terminal in voice by going to this dominant
command on top and saying New terminal.
So this is going to be opening up your terminal.
In this, you are going to be writing all the commands for executing your other pack configurations.
So that is about it.
A quick overview.
So just make sure that you have this project repository downloaded.