Here, guys.
Welcome back to another video.
So in this video, we are going to be seeing how to be loading images.
Now, earlier, when do we want to be adding some load as we used to go to NPM repository and install
the specific loaders for it.
So we install the style and see us as loaders for loading the cases and also additional loader for the
SS.
Now there are a couple of built in loaders and Webpack vite knows exactly how to be dealing with those
files.
So let's see how those work.
Now I'm going to be copying and pasting this folder here, but if you want you can be continuing on
with the previous folder.
I'm just keeping it so that things are organized and in case you are stuck, you can just go to my GitHub
repository and use the particular folders.
So let me just copy that and pasted right here.
Okay.
So that's done.
Let me rename this to five and let's call this as image loaders.
All right, so that's done.
Let's open that up and we have all the configuration already done.
Now, what we're going to be doing is let's go ahead and open up logo.
So we're going to be downloading image file.
So maybe the image file can be of the back itself or probably of a PAC logo.
Let's quickly search for that and download any image that you like.
So for example, I'm going to be downloading this image on my desktop.
Let's call that as Webpack underscore logo.
Okay, so that's done.
If I come back to my discord, I can be importing that file here.
So let's go to my finder.
I'm going to the desktop and let's pull that right here.
Okay.
So we have the Rat Pack logo imported here.
I'm going to be moving this into my SRT.
Let's go ahead and create a new folder here.
That's called this as a said.
And let's move this BND file here, and that's pretty good.
All right, so we have a new asset added to our ASIC folder.
Now to be using this asset.
So what I'll do is I'll go to my index, start HTML and in this I'm going to be adding a new section
within which I'm going to be adding that image that we just downloaded.
So let's put the image probably right here.
I'm going to be adding an image tag and I'm going to be giving this an I.D. as a logo.
Just like that.
Okay, so we have a mistake added.
So now I can go to my index dodgers file and add that particular element.
So, first of all, let's go ahead and clear off all the unwanted things and let's import our file that
we just added.
So I'll say import.
Logo from.
And in this, we are going to be pointing to a search folder.
And within that, we had the file name as the pack underscore logos.
I'll just copy the entire file name from here and paste it right here.
Okay.
So our logo is now imported in ideas file now to be using that particular logo.
So I'll say concept.
Logo element equals do document dot get element by EDI and that is logo.
Okay, so that's pretty good.
Now I can just be adding that file there so I can see.
Logo element dot as RC equals two.
And in this we can be pointing to this logo right here.
I'll just say logo.
That's it.
That's pretty much it.
If you just try to run this particular build once again and let's see what happens.
So I'll just move up a one folder, go to the fifth folder, which I just created and say, NPM, run,
build.
And you might be pretty much aware by now what's going to happen that our world is going to break.
Because as you can see, it does not really understand what to be doing with this logo file or the BND
file.
Now let's make the configuration in our pack and make it understand what exactly to be doing with that
Now, again, as you can assume, we are loading a file type, so we need to be making some changes
in this module section.
So that's it.
We are going to be adding another object here.
So we add an object here and put up the test conditions.
And in this we are going to be using the loaders.
So in the U.S., it's going to be a little bit different.
Instead of typing in use, we are going to be using another parameter called as type.
So in this type, we are going to be seeing a third.
And slash resource.
That's it.
And in our test condition, we are going to be adding all the image file types.
So this can be PNG, it can be a JPG.
It can be a gif or probably a swig as well.
So all this file types are going to be supported by our dollars and idea.
And that's pretty much it.
If I just save it and if I just go to my console and try to run the build once again, we can see that
we have successfully imported that file.
So that's right here.
All right.
Now we can open up our index, start a student files, file, right click and see who will in Finder.
Let's double click on that file.
And things seems to be not working as expected.
So let's check out what's happening.
So we go to the Inspect tab now to understand exactly why our image is not loading.
We can come to our console and see that we are getting one error on the DOM list.
And this is exactly why our image is not loading for now.
Now, I could have all this behind the scene, but no, I really wanted to see what are the kind of
problems that one can face and how we resolving them.
Now, as you can see, it's failed to execute.
Add on the bottom left so the token provided must not be empty.
So this appeared on the index Dodgers line number 28.
So let's go to our indexed audience.
And if you come here, we can see that we don't see the line number 28 because basically what's happening
is compiling it and it's showing a compiled output.
So we do not see the exact line numbers, but it is somewhere at the end to as you can see here, it
is basically on this particular line.
That is where the problem is coming.
Now, what we're trying to do here is we are adding the style object and in that we are trying to find
the class called button.
Now, if I open up the style object, so this is from where this style is coming up and this is in the
index darts access.
So if I go to the index, dot the thesis, we can see that it's been marked as a global module and that
is exactly why we are not able to be adding their dialogue button variable.
So to be fixing this, we can just remove this global property because as you remember, once you are
the global property, it is not exposed on this style object rather is going to be exposed directly
on the DOM.
So if I just go back to my index dot years now, it should be able to find this style property and that's
when this line of code is going to be executed and our logo should be appearing.
So let me just save all of those files, clear the console and try to run the build once again.
Now, if I switch back to my browser, hit refresh, we can see that the error message is gone and our
logo has now appeared and congratulations, you have successfully added image using the image module.
Now the few things that you can be doing for there to be enhancing your build.
So let's see what can be done here.
Now if I go to my vs code and check out the dist folder, we can see that it did not just compile the
file.
It also imported that file into the dist folder and it also gave it a random name along with the extension.
That was the file type.
Also, if you come back to your console, check out the location in Inspect.
You can see that it's actually using the file from the test folder.
So you have this location slash dist and then the file name which was generated by the pack automatically.
So you can see how things are playing along when you are using all this loaders in the web pack.
Okay.
Now the thing that I like to show you is what if you want to be changing the file name all you want
to be putting it in a folder, how does those things work?
So if you can imagine you have like a huge application, then you have a lot of images floating around.
So the number of files in the disk folder is going to be ramped up quite quickly.
And you need to keep things organized so that in case you need to debug, it's possible to do so.
So let's see what can be done in our Webpack config.
Now we can add a property in our output, which is going to be helping us change the name of the files
that have been generated by this particular plugin.
So what I can I do it is set module file name and in here we can name it as.
Images flash and then our film that is there now instead of our film, it's going to be generating a
hash.
So we're going to be putting up square back it.
Then we say hash and then another square bracket with the extension.
Okay.
So what we're seeing here, what are the assets generated?
We are going to be placing them in the images folder and this is going to be the filing that is going
to be created.
So the file name does not in is the same, but we are also creating it in this particular folder.
So let's try to run this build once again and we say NPM, run, build.
And with that done you can see that our images folder has been created and we have the asset moved over
here.
Now you also see that we have our set created here as well.
Now how can you be cleaning up all this output which is not being used anymore?
What you can be doing is you can be adding another property in the output and say clean.
And then here we specify the value as true.
Okay with that.
Let me just run the bill once again.
Okay.
So as you can see, our build was successful and it actually removed the file that was not being used
anymore.
So now you just have the image in the images folder just to make sure that things are working as expected.
We can go back to our browser, just refresh the page and we can see that the image is still loading,
but this time it's loaded from the images folder, so that's pretty much it.
How do we loading the images in the JavaScript file?
Let's take a short break and see how we can be using the same module to also load the fonts as fonts
also directly supported by the back five.
So see in a short break.