Yeah.
Guys, welcome back.
In this video we're going to be seeing, what are the differences between the development and the production
mode?
In the past couple of sections, we installed a lot of plug ins, we did a lot of configurations.
And in the end, we also saw that some of the configurations were only applicable when we are running
in production and some of the tools were more helpful when we are doing the development.
So how do we segregate all of this and what are these aggregations that we should be doing?
Okay, so I've just created a small table here just to analyze what are the differences between the
development and the production mode.
So for example, in production we will be using plugins such as the modification of DML.
We are going to be implementing tree shaking, copying of the asset to the disk directly so that all
the references do not break.
We are going to be setting up some variables that might be specific to the production environment,
maybe connecting to our production server and so on.
And finally, we also might be splitting into chunks only when we are in the production mode.
Okay.
So these are the production specific configurations that we would be following and there are some development
specific things.
So for example, the Webpack dev saw and this is really helpful when we are doing the development.
So this should only be running when we are in the development mode.
We are also going to be having the dev environment specific variables.
And we are also going to be having like the bundle analyzer, which is also helpful only in the development
mode.
So these are the development specific configurations.
Now those are going to be some configurations which are going to be shared across both the production
and the development mode.
So what are they?
So we are going to be having things common, such as setting up of the loaders.
So if you want to be loading the image or thesis, it has to be done in both the base right there you
are in the production on the development mode.
So this is going to be common.
We also need to be specifying the entry and output specification.
Again, this is also the common because it's the same application.
They should be having the same entry and output.
Right.
And finally, the DML file creation.
So this was the ML Webpack plugin specifically, which was helping us to automatically create the estimate
file using the template and so on.
So these are some of the things that are going to be shared across both the production and the development
mode.
So how do we configure our entire Webpack file?
So for example, if I just switch back to my Vila scored and open up the Webpack config, we can see
that all the configurations have just been dump here.
Now I need some way to be basically telling the pack that, hey, if I'm in development mode, just
run a couple of plugins.
If I'm in the production mode.
Run another set of plug ins.
So how can we be doing that kind of configurations?
So we're going to be seeing how to be configuring this in the next video.