You guys, welcome to another video.
And this is going to be a first for that video in which you're going to be writing some code.
Now, I'm really excited to show you what we're can do for us.
Now we are just going to be creating a blank folder in here and start with some of the basics.
Now, please remember you can always go to the kit repository, and in there you're going to be finding
the final version of what you're going to be writing right here.
All right.
So let's start off.
We have a blank folder.
Let's click on a new folder.
And this is going to be as high as the folder in which you're going to be hosting all of our files.
We'll be needing to file.
This one is going to be the index start, HDMI, DML, and the second file is going to be a JavaScript
file.
So let's call that as index start.
Yes.
In our estimate file, let's put in some boilerplate.
So I'll just put in using this estimate of five syntax.
And as you can see, it added the head and the body section along with some other metadata.
All right.
So not a lot of things need to be done here.
We're just going to be adding a twin tag.
Let's see here.
This is my first left back application.
Cool.
So that looks good.
And I'm also going to be adding a button in which you're going to be adding a function that is going
to be called from our JavaScript file.
So let's say on click equals to button clicked.
Just like that.
All right.
Now, when I click on this button, I'm going to be updating the text that we see here.
So for that, I need to be also adding, I need to buy this.
So that's how I'm going to be picking up this particular H1 tag.
So let's give this MIDI as maybe head of.
All right.
So that is pretty much it.
Now we can head over to our JavaScript file.
So I just copied this function as well because we are going to be defining it over there.
So in here we can see function.
And we put in the name of the function and then define the block.
So first of all, I need to be getting the element right here.
So let's say const element equals to document dot get element by.
And in this we can go ahead and copy the ID that was held up.
Once we have the element, we can go ahead and change the inner demon.
So I would say in our estimate equals to.
Here.
I have updated the code.
All right.
So nothing fancy here.
Let's just go ahead and include this JavaScript file in our estimate so that it can get loaded.
So I'll put in the script tag.
Let's put in the sa c as dark slash index dog.
Yes.
Okay.
So now to check whether things are working properly, I can just right click on the estimate they reveal
in finder and just double click on the estimate.
Alright, that looks good.
I do not have any button text so I just need to be quickly adding that as well.
So let's go back to a button and see.
Click me.
Okay.
Let's go back and refresh our page.
And things work as expected.
So nothing fancy here.
Now, to make things a bit fancy, as we know that the pack can be used for loading some dependencies.
I'm going to be adding an additional dependency.
So let's open up a new tab.
And in this we are going to be searching for a library called as Lord Ash.
So let's search for Lord Ash.
And where are we loading this via CD.
And so CD and as the content delivery network basically it provides you with this descriptor hosted
at some under this hour.
So we have this CD and copies here now in this hidden copies, you can just copy from the clipboard.
So we have this copy you are in.
And if you switch back to our code, we're going to be including this under the script tag.
So let's say script as RC and in here we paste what we had just copied and Laura should be included
next time we load our index stardust html.
So to just verify that, let's switch back to our browser.
Go to our application.
Let's right click inspect and let's go to the network tab.
Now please remember I prefer to use Chrome and that gives a lot of good debugging whenever you're going
to be loading any of your remote files and so on.
And this is really going to be helping us verify that things are working and expected when we're building
our web back application.
So for now, let's just click on refresh.
And in here you can see that the load start menu dogs was in fact loaded and this took approximately
13 milliseconds.
So that's not too bad.
Let's go back to our codebase and in our code base, we are going to be going to the index start use.
Now what I want to be doing here to make things a little bit dynamic, I'm going to be going back to
the next order estimate and in here let's add a useful tag.
So basically we are going to be adding a few items and we're going to be rendering them dynamically.
So let's call this ID as shopping list.
So that looks good.
And this is going to be used in our index cards.
So what I'm going to be doing here is.
I see.
Concert ul equals to same thing as before.
Document Art Get Element VI I.D. Shopping List.
So we have the UL tag now.
What are we creating a list as well?
So let's say concert list items equals to and add it.
Now in here we can add a couple of items that we need to be shopping for.
Let's say we want to be shopping for a list of fruits and vegetables.
So let's say apple.
Orange and banana.
All right.
Nothing very fancy here, but no worries.
So in here we are going to be using the underscore operator.
So underscore is automatically exposed by Lord Ash on the global scope.
As soon as you load Lord in the index, start steaming.
So I can say underscore dot.
For each.
So in this, we can specify exactly what you want to be iterating over.
So what we need to be iterating or is the list item?
So I'd say list items.
And in this we need to be passing in a function.
So we'll put up here as function and this takes up an.
Item.
So this is going to be each individual item that is present in this list.
So what we're going to be doing here is will create an element.
So let's say cause an element equal to document, dot create element.
And in here we need a like tag.
That is what we're going to be creating an element dot in our HTML equals to item.
So I see this is quite basic and we do not really are we not going to be really going into a lot of
depth as what's happening here, but it's quite self-explanatory.
Now what we are going to be doing is once we have the element created, we need to be appending this
to our UL.
So we already have the world tag here you will append child and in here we are going to be appending
the temp element that we had just created.
All right.
So that is pretty much it.
Let's go back to our estimates page and see what happens.
So if we go back to actual page due to refresh and if I click right here, we can see that the text
last updated and the elements caught up in it as well.
So all this was done using the traditional approach in which you are loading the files, using this
Eden and using the script tags.
And this is not what do you mean to enable?
As you can see, as we have a lot of dependencies, we are going to be just adding dependencies one
after the other.
And we are also going to be loading those dependencies again and again when we start switching the pages.
Now, that is not the most efficient way of managing things.
So this is exactly where Webpack comes in.
So let's take a short break, and we are going to be creating our first Webpack file.
And in that, we are going to be seeing how we can be loading this load dependency which we loaded in
the index.
Start a steel mill and move it to the index.
Start JS file.
So see you after a short break.