All right.
Welcome back.
And in this video, we're going to be starting off some integration between our different applications
that have been started off to give you an overview of what is our objective.
So we have already this page loaded up.
This is our homepage.
And in this homepage we are trying to load all this movies list to follow trending all this movie list.
We need to first of all, get the list of movies from our soap that's running locally.
So let's see how we can be implementing that.
I'm just going to be switching all to my code base and in this, just make sure that you have the three
applications.
So is running.
We have it already here.
We have the Mozilla, we have the homepage as well as the React component.
Okay, let's open up the homepage component.
And in this we have the SRT folder component, home page content and the home content dot gsx.
Now you do not really need to worry about what all is happening over here.
This is just some rendering logic that's happening for rendering that page, some component in some
cases, and so on.
The thing that we are interested in is this right here.
I've already read the comment, so we need to add the logical here to load all the data from this over
to our React application.
Okay, now I'm not going to be using some external service and there's a particular reason for that.
So I'm not going to be using a package called as Axios and so on.
And what are we using the native fetch API?
So let's see how we can be implementing the get logic using that.
So I'm just going to be saying convert.
A response he called to fetch.
Now, in here, I need to be entering the location of my API.
So that's going to be as SDP double column slash slash local host.
And that's five, five, five.
Slash movies.
So this is our end point.
Now, when you get the response, we need to actually be making it into adjacent format.
So what I'll do is I'll say const data equal to.
Response dot Jason.
All right.
So this is how it's going to be loaded.
Now fetches a async API.
That means we need to use promises in this case.
Now, I'm going to be using the easing of it for this.
So what I see here is after use effect and this starting of this function, I'll put in async and we'll
hear.
And what do we think of it, this response.
Now, the response to Jason is also going to be returning a promise.
So I need to await this as well.
So as they await the response start, Jason.
Now, once we get the data, I'm just going to be controlling and logging this funnel.
So I also consolidate log data.
And that's pretty much it.
Now we can just verify on which board this application is running by coming here.
So we this is our homepage application.
So if I just come here homepage, I can see that is running on port number 3000.
So let me just go to my browser and have this localhost port 3000 open up.
Hit refresh and nothing really loads up.
So let's try to inspect what's happening.
Why are we not seeing our quick looking part over here, which was working earlier?
Right.
So just right click and inspect over console.
And in the console you can see that I've got an error called as regenerator runtime not defined.
Then we also got some error in the home content.
This is the one that we're trying to modify where we had put our you think of it and so on.
And things are not really working as expected.
Now, let me try to explain why this is happening.
If I just go back to my code views, this is think of it now you think of it is not really understood
by Webpack.
If I just go to my Webpack configurations and if you just check it out over here, we have all these
files and in this we are using our be able loader.
Now just to sort of transpire this you think of it into the language that it understands.
So for that, if I just go back to my homepage content now to make things work, I need to be adding
a new Babel configuration that will help us to transport all this async, await into the thing that
it understands.
So for that, I need to be going to the index dogs and in the index dogs I'm going to be importing one
of the policies to right on top of before all the other component import I'm going to say import and
then it will here you say it Babel and then slash by level.
So this is the configuration that is required.
Now, you might be wondering why in the index dogs file.
Well, it's because this is our entry file.
So if I just go to developer configuration and if you just check it out over here, what is our entry
file?
So this is the index dog.
This.
So you are this Babel polypill has to be at the entry.
Fine.
If it is anywhere else, your application might not work as expected.
Okay.
So we have to just be a bit powerful.
And one more point to note over here, this has already been installed in the package.
Jason, that's why it is working.
So if I just search for ADD, that'd be built by little.
You can see it right here.
So in case you're starting off with a new project, make sure that you have this dependency installed.
Okay.
With that configuration updated, let me go to my browser and if I just give it a refresh, you can
see that we have the quick bookings again back loaded here and in my console I also see that the data
is coming.
So here you can expand and we see all the JSON data available to us.
So that's pretty cool.
We got to know how do we using the table policy and how do we using the async await syntax along with
the fetch API?
Okay.
I'm just going to be taking a short break so we won't be using all this data that has been returned
to us and load the cards using the React Components application.