In the last couple of videos, we were successfully able to make our pack built for our React application.
Now in this video, I would like to show you one more thing that we can be doing with this CSS.
Now, when we were writing this, he says, and if we're using some sort of new syntax in it.
So if I just take an example here, if I go to the icon slider dot x, we can see that we are using
some AppKit specific case configurations and this configuration might not really work on every browser.
So in general, you need to be adding some qualifiers and this is used for supporting businesses on
multiple browsers.
Now you can go ahead and add this manually, but there's a shortcut to do this using the plugins.
So let's see how we can be doing that.
So let me go back to my web back configuration file.
And in this case, we are going to be adding an additional loader, which is going to be helping us
with this bolivars.
So what are we going to be doing here is we are going to be adding an additional configuration after
the success loader.
So first, this loader is going to be coming in and then we are going to be using this.
Yes.
As Loader.
So let me object here, because we are not just going to be using it plainly.
We need to also pass in some configurations to that loader.
So first of all, we need to define the load name.
So I would say loader and this loaders called us post C SS Loader.
So that's the name.
Then we need to be passing it in some options.
So this is again going to be an object within which we have the post thesis options.
So just make sure you take care of the capitalization.
So it is post thesis in small letters and then we have the option starting with capital.
Okay.
But then this.
We also need to be passing in another parameter.
So that is the plugins.
And this is going to be of type added.
Now within the array, we also need to be passing in a list of area.
So this is going to be another area.
And within this, we pass in the first plugin.
So the plugin is called us post thesis preset.
There's pre said TNB.
So that is the name of the plugin that is going to be using.
And then we just pass in a blank configuration object for this plugin.
Okay.
So this seems a little bit complicated.
And just note that there are two things that are being used here.
One is the postseason order and the policy is preset.
And we.
Now both of these things are already been installed in a package or Jason.
So if you just come here, search for post C.
So I already had this installed as a dependency.
Now so you do not really need to install it explicitly, but just take a note in case you're using it
on your some personal project.
Look, let's go back to our PAC config.
Now, this is all the configuration that we need to be doing.
Now, we can just copy this entire loader just like that.
And since we have just added it to our access loader, we also need to be adding it to our access loader.
That that's right here.
So we have the Minix extract plugin used, see us as Loader and the SARS as loader.
So I need to be adding it just after the SCA says loader to that right here.
Now just add a comma as well, do the formatting and just make sure that you are following the correct
format.
Those loaders are not going to work.
So what do you need your minix as extract, then this SS loader, then the post the SS and finally the
a SS.
Well, guess what?
That looks good.
Let me just go ahead and save this and try to run the configuration.
So I'd say NPM hat on build.
Let's give that a second.
And we see that our build was successful.
In case you're facing some failure, just make sure that Austin, Texas got it because the thing can
get tricky at times.
Just make sure that your spelling is correct and the capitalization is also correct.
Okay.
With that, then let's explore what happened in our test folder.
So we our test folder already opened up and if I open up main, Garcia says, so this is where all access
is kept.
Now, let me just quickly make this model.
Now, in case of the place folder, as you can see or hear, many things have been replaced and added
by the plugin.
So in this case it has already added the Polish L5 for example, the zip file mozzarella firefox.
So this is the policy that was added and a couple of other policies added here as well.
So this is exactly how both cases can definitely help you in speeding up your development.
So you can go ahead and use this in your next project so that you do not really have to write all the
code for.
Yes.
Okay.
So that's about it.
Let's take a short break and explode the last plugin that we're going to be applying on our React application
that is for easy length.