So just going back to how we scored the approach is going to be quite simple.
So we just open up the core, start streaming file.
So in pages we have the course HTML file and I need to be removing all of this dependencies from here.
So let me do one thing.
I'm just going to be opening it side by side to make the things a bit easier.
So I have the courses gorgias on the left and I have the courses dot on the right.
Okay, let's go ahead and import all the data.
So first of all, we have the course data that can be imported.
So let me just uncomment that.
So we have the course data imported here, then we can also do the import.
So that is import bootstrap from bootstrap.
Then we need to import the typed library.
So basically for reference, I'm using all the guest files that are present right here.
So that's bootstrap then we need equity.
So dollar from.
jQuery.
Okay.
Then we need the typed.
So I'll say import typed from typed dodges.
Then we quickly do the other stuff as well.
So we got validate in there.
Then we got toast.
And finally we also need the load library.
So I would say import.
On the score from Lord Ash.
Okay.
So with that done, I can actually go ahead and remove all the things from my estimate files so we can
get rid of all those dependencies.
And we also need to be updating the course says dots file.
So since, you know, estimate of attack plug in is being used and the bundle is automatically going
to be injected in the HTML, we can actually get rid of this as well.
All right.
Just going back up and seeing what all our diseases inputs required.
So we need a CSS import for bootstrap and we also need the index nazi SS.
Okay, let's fix that as well quickly.
So I will say import dot, dot slash.
And we have the index start thesis now for bootstrap.
If you remember from our previous lectures, we have imported bootstrap in this render dot access.
So I'm just going to be importing this file in my code.
So instead of importing them one by one, so I'll say import dada slash underscore render dot as the
RSS.
Okay.
So that's great.
We can go ahead and remove both of these dependencies.
Define a dependency is often awesome.
So this is not imported in any other files per say.
So we need to be importing explicitly.
So I go to the assets folder thesis and in there I'm just going to be copying this name.
So let's copy that from here and put it right here.
Okay.
With that done, I can go ahead and move this file as well.
So everything looks good.
My courses estimate and the JavaScript has been updated.
My server is automatically updated as well.
Let's go back to our browser.
Hit refresh.
Let's close off this console and we can see that all these tailings are applied as well.
So we have all equals has been rendered here and we do not have any errors as such in the console as
well.
So this project gave us a very good overview of how we are going to be taking a normalized malicious
JavaScript file and really converting it to make it and being friendly and Webpack friendly so that
we can utilize all the features of that back.
Let's take a short break and continue on with some new features of Webpack.