You guys.
Welcome to our final video on loaders.
We have learned a lot in this module.
We saw how to be loading different types of files.
We also saw how to be loading different types of CFS.
That is the CFS and the normal CSS files.
We saw the concept of modules and so on.
Now before we close up this section, I would like to just make you go through the documentation where
you can be getting more information about the loaders.
Now, if you head over to the VAT bags dot what documentation, you can see that we have one section
on loaders which had already seen earlier in this.
You have a variety of loaders but you have not seen as well.
We have not yet cover the Jason loader, but the concepts are pretty much the same.
So you can just have this loader implemented and now you know what exactly this modules section does
and how to be using this loaders.
Moving on.
We also saw one of the building modules that were there in the loaders and that was using the asset
slash resources.
Now if you want to be exploring more on this, you can come to this guide submenu and in this you are
going to be finding one section called as the asset module.
And this is exactly what we are using.
And you can just go to this documentation to get more information about on what are the other different
types of things that are going to be loading using the built in asset module.
So that's about it for loaders.
So let's move on to the next section in which you are going to be covering another important topic of
Webpack, and that is the plug ins.
So let's move ahead and see what is plugins and how it can make our day one better.