Let's continue on from where we left off in the last video.
We got Ivar back running.
But there was one problem that we were facing when I was trying to click on this button, nothing worked.
So let's try to understand what exactly is happening behind the scene.
Now check out the console right here.
We can see that the button clicked is undefined.
Well, why this is happening?
Well, this is one of the more core concepts of the script.
And let's see exactly why this happens.
So I'm just going to be switching over to my voice code.
And you do not really need to be coding along with me, but do take note of what's happening here.
So I'm just going to switch over to another code base.
So that's right here.
And we're going to be exploring what is immediately in what functions in JavaScript.
Now, if you check over here, it's nothing fancy.
We just have like a button called ADD.
And when you click on that, a function is going to be called as sum.
Now if I open up the main dodges, this is the file right here.
We can see that we have defined a function called sum and it does nothing, just the consolidated log
of two variables.
So it's quite straightforward.
Let's open up this file in our browser.
So what are we seeing as short in browser?
Where is it really in finder and double click to open it up?
All right.
So that's a button right there.
Let's click on Inspect.
And if we check out our console when we click on ADD, we can see that this is five.
Now let's make some changes in the code.
I'm just going to be zooming in a little bit more clear.
All right.
Now in here, what I'm going to be doing is I'm going to be creating a immediately invoked function.
So I'm going to be putting up two brackets, then create a function within it.
And this is going to be having the braces in the end to invoke this function.
And I'm one of them moving all of this within this.
Great now.
All right.
So that's all things that are made.
So what happens here exactly is as soon as they start a stimulus called this JavaScript file is going
to be loaded in our browser, and this function gets executed in which we have defined another function
called sum.
And this is going to be initialized.
Now, if I try to run this again in the browser, so if I go back to my browser, click on refresh and
click on Add, we can see exactly the same error that the same function is not defined.
Well, this is what happens when you have immediately invoke functions immediately and work functions
have a separate scope in the browser and this is done so that it does not pollute the entire namespace
or the entire global space in your browser.
So for example, suppose someone has defined a function called sum as well.
It's going to be conflicting with that particular function.
So for that purpose, we define it as we immediately invoke function.
This was a very popular approach back in the equity days as well.
They used to be loading the equity library using the immediately invoked function.
All right.
So that was a quick overview of what exactly are immediately invoked function the switch back to our
actual code base.
So that's right here.
Now in this, we should be looking up in the bundle dogs.
And if I scroll all the way to the top and as you can see or here is the exact same thing text that
we saw earlier, if you have this bracket here, then we have the immediately invoked function being
created.
And if you scroll all the way to the bottom, we can see that is closed and then executed in the browser.
So what Webpack is doing is creating an entire scope of its own so that it isolates itself from all
the other things that are running in the browser.
Now, this is a good approach, actually, so that it does not create conflict with any of the files
that are loaded other than Webpack or any other JavaScript file that's being loaded in the mail file.
All right.
Now, if I just see how can be solving this, there's a couple of ways to be solving it.
So for that, let's head over to our indexed ideas and you can follow along with me now.
So to fix this, what we're going to be doing is we're going to be binding it directly to a HTML element.
Now to do that, I need to be opening up the mail file first so that right here we had attached a click
listener that is called Button Clicked.
So instead of this, I'm going to be removing all of this and I'm just going to be assigning an idea
to it.
So let's assign it called as button one.
So it's quite simple, and let's go back to our indexed ideas and make the changes.
Now I'm going to be changing this into a document or get element by already put in the ID of the button
and then say add event listener.
And the event that we are going to be listening for is the Click Event, and then we can define our
callback function when this click event gets executed.
Now we can just take up all the code that was there earlier in that function and put it right here and
delete of that previous function that we had.
So that is all the change that we need.
So what will happen here is when we create stability, it is going to be adding all of this into that
immediately invoked function.
And as soon as this function gets executed, it's going to be trying to find that button, which has
an idea of.
Button one and artist, event listener and everything should work as expected.
Now, to make sure that things do work as expected, let me clear off the console.
Let me just see if this index strategy has failed and let's try to run the build once again.
So I'll say NPM, run, build, and we have the new build created for us.
Let's switch back to our browser.
And in our browser we can just go back to our application and click on refresh and let's try to click
on the button this time.
And in fact, this time our application works as expected.
Now, this was a very small point that was there, but it was very important to understand why did that
button not work?
And this is going to be somewhat painful for you if you do not really understand the concept behind
it.
And now we hope it's clear how actually that back works behind the scene.
And we will be seeing what it wants, the usage of all of this very soon.
All right.
So that's about it for this.
Let's move on to the next video and explore a few more concepts of that back.