In this section we're going to make our basketball la the app is pretty self-explanatory.
Just try to score the ball.
So open up X code create a new project a single application call the project a hoops press next and
create like always go to the main storyboard and to your initial view controller add an A or kid scene.
If you expend the arcade scene kid view to the edges of your super view and pin it to the top leading
bottom and trailing space add a button in the middle of your etiquettes view and align it horizontally
and vertically add the two constraints and make a new image asset into your assets assets folder new
image set call the image set Plus
an inside of your resources folder there are assets of a plus button once you download them add them
to your assets folder.
Re maximize my X code project and back to the storyboard take off this button text inside of your attributes
and Spector set the plus image as your image.
There you go.
Now inside of your controller linked the arcade scene view with an ideal scene view
clothes the assistant editor and back to the View Controller import a kit in the next couple of steps
is something we've done many times before.
First it was to declare a constant configuration equal to a role tracking session configuration.
Run a scene view session with that configuration by writing self-deceit view session.
Run configuration debug options to your scene view by writing self-deceit view debug options equal to
an array type of debug options such that we want to show the world origin and we also want to show feature
points and other stuff.
We've done a million times before as go to your input output list and add the property privacy camera
uses description.
This simply displays an alert to the user prompting him to enable the camera.
A descriptive message to the alert saying you need the camera to display cool air.
Contact back to your controller.
One more thing I want to add is lighting.
So that itself does seem to view the auto enables default lighting is equal to true.
In fact it's always a good idea.
Tear it just makes everything look better in general.
So first order of business is we're going to build our basketball net so right click on your project
folder press 1 new file and scroll down until you find your scene Kitsune file press.
Next call you're seeing a scene file basketball or something related to the UP.
Create and expand this navigator and delete the scammer.
No we won't be needing it.
I don't know the tear seen it called the empty node basket into your scene.
INSPECTOR.
I'm just going to change this from a color of great color of white since that's easier to work with.
Your basket no.
First things first I just want to position it in the middle of the scene because it's easier to work
with that way.
I don't know why this is so hard to click on.
They should really fix that.
So it was 0
0 Anzur
Okay now to just go on the front prospective
click the play button twice and then double click on your basket.
There you go.
So to your basket node first we're going to add a floor.
So right.
Floor and this floor to your seat of view.
Or you know instead of just adding it to the scene view make it a direct child of our basket note and
make sure it's positioned exactly where the basket note is which it already is.
Zero 0 0 perfect alignment.
OK.
This is our first time using a floor.
So in the attributes inspector give the floor a width of 0.5.
They should really make these easier to click on.
So 0.5 and a length of 1
I just drag it to one.
This is much easier.
There you go.
One.
OK.
And now give the floor a diffuse color of gray.
So magnesium I guess right here is our floor.
And now back to your attributes and Specter.
It's not very clear the effect of this reflective property right now but you'll see what it does in
a minute.
So now in front of the floor we need to add our basket.
So start with the back board which will be a box add the box here scene view in the material inspector
give the box a color of lemon yellow and in the attributes inspector give it a width of 1.5 metre is
a height of 1 metres which is already there and a depth of 0.01 metres.
We want the board to be really thin 0.01.
There you go.
And let me just fix the front perspective.
OK.
So first off we want to make this buckboard a child of the basket.
And once you do that place it about two metres above the parent node and let's say negative three metres
behind it or 3.4 metres behind our Basken our floor.
If I just fix the perspective to be perspective instead of front
and this looks really good.
Notice the floor is a reflective property.
The higher this value the more the floor reflects 0.35 is a good value.
So I'm just going to keep it at that.
And finally we need to ring the hoop into which the user will shoot the ball.
The ring will be at Taurus cerate Taurus and we went over what a Taurus was in the introductory section
of the course.
So I had a Taurus and make it a child of the empty node basket as well.
And before proceeding let me just rename this from box to blackboard
and cat.
And now this Taurus give it a ring radius of 0.4 meters and a pipe radius of about 0.01 metres.
We want to make it very thin like so now into the material inspector give the Taurus a diffused color
of red.
Now we want to position the running about 1.5 metres from the floor or from the basket node for that
matter.
And about three metres behind the floor so negative Threet
this is looking pretty good.
This really does look like a cool basketball court.
So now before we play this basketball court into our scene view we need to place this scene file into
an SDN assets folder.
So add a new file to your projects folder.
Make sure the file is an asset catalog call the asset catalog basketball and create instead of this
being an X C assets make it a C and that's and for some reason all these crosses when I do that so let
me just reopen it.
The app is called a are Hoopes right here.
Everything is in good working order still.
Let me just drag this into my folder and we're good to go.
Now to just display this basketball court into our scene view.
So where we tap on a horizontal surface we want to display this basketball court.
We just did this two lectures ago and we've done it in many other lectures.
I want you to pause the video and use whatever resources you have to try this one alone.
So assuming that you've already tried it first off.
We need that configuration to detect horizontal surfaces.
So right self duct configuration that plane detection is equal to a dot horizontal.
Now we need an indicator to tell us when a plane was detected.
So inside of your story board add a label to the top of your view controller called the label plane
detected
align it horizontally to your controller.
That constraint and pin it about 40 feet from the top go to your attributes and Specter and where it's
us Funt.
I'm going to give it a font of your next by just going on custom and then family venir next and it's
going to be a bold font with a size of about 22 and done so open up the assistant editor and link this
label to your view controller with an IBM plained detected close the assistant editor and make sure
that this label is hidden first.
We only want to unhide this label when a plane is detected.
So back to your view controller inherit from a.r.
I see and we delegate and call the delegate function did an anchor this delegate function gets called
whenever an anchor is added Whenever an anchor is detected only when it detects a plain anchor.
We want to unhide our label so Guard anchor is of type A plain anchor.
Else return.
So if a plain anchor was detected if a surface is detected then unhide the label.
So self the plane detected is hidden is equal to false and hide it and now make sure you do this on
the main thread.
So right dispatch.
Q. Does it mean that a sink can put this block of code inside of the main thread.
OK.
Now three seconds later you want to hide the label again.
So right.
Dispatch.
Q. Does it mean that a sink after Darton now plus three so three seconds later we want to unhide the
label.
So right here just right self up plane detected is head and is equal to true now to activate this function
just re self seeing view.
DOD delegate is equal to self and run the app to make sure that there are no bugs.
And everything seems to work fine.
Now would just place the basketball court on the horizontal surface.
This is simply hit us thing.
We've done this a million times.
So entier if you controller make a tap gesture recognizer.
So right let top gesture recognizer is equal to UI tab gesture recognizer the target will be self and
the actual function that will be triggered is handled top.
So right phunk handle top with arguments sunder of type UI type gesture recognizer and make sure to
expose this function to Objective C before putting it into our selector.
Now right the selector handle type.
OK.
Now register this recognizer into your scene view by writing self scene view gesture recognizer UI or
just type just recognizer.
So whenever you tap the scene view this function will get triggered and now declare the scene viewed
that you tapped on by guard letting scene view is equal to sender view.
As you see in view else return
declare the location that you touched by writing touch location is equal to sender location inside of
the scene view.
Now check if the location that you touched matches the location of an existing plane by doing a hit
test.
So hit test result is equal to seen.
View the hit test first argument is the touch location and types dot existing plane using extent.
If the location you touched matches died of a horizontal plane your hate test results array will have
one element of results.
If the location you touch doesn't not start of a horizontal plane your head test array will be empty.
So if his test result is empty and make sure to add the exclamation mark to say if his test result is
not empty.
So if we touched a horizontal surface then we're going to add our basketball court right here else.
If the test result is empty do nothing.
Actually why not just remove this Alstad mean we don't even need it.
So if we do indeed touch a horizontal surface first we want to declare a function func basket with argument.
Hit test result of type A are.
Test result.
In past your hit test result into your function by writing self.
Add basket and I seem to have made an error instead of putting top gesture recognizer I put you on top
just a recognizer which makes zero sense.
So let me just fix that up.
And now to just pass our test result destroyed his test result.
First.
Remember there is only one element of results and it's the first element.
OK now an odd basket.
First let's load the basket seen by writing let basket's seen is equal to see and seen Nemed to access
your scene.
First go into its directory which is this one copy slash basketball scene.
Now that we loaded our scene we need the basket node.
The basket node is a child of the scene root node.
So just right left basket node is equal to basket.
The root node child node with name and the name of our node is simply basket's.
So make sure to copy this right here and set recursively as false since the basket node is an immediate
child of the scenes root node.
We need to place our basket node exactly where we top the horizontal surface.
We can get that position from the hit test results transform matrix as we discussed before the position
is in the transforms.
Third column.
So right let position of plane is equal to hit.
Test result that world transform doc columns 3.
Now try it.
X position is equal to position of plane x y position is equal to position of plane 1 and that position
is equal to position of plane.
And now just right Baskett node position is equal to as the end of vector 3
and just fill out your X Y and Z positions such that they match the exact position of the plane that
you detected.
Now you just have to add it to the scene view by writing self seen view seen root node dot child node
Baskett node
going to forcefully unwrap and then you're done.
Just run the up
wait for the world origin to load.
Once the world origin loads the touched a surface top surface and there is your basketball court.
This is really cool.
In the next video we're going to start shooting a basketball into our hoop.