In the section we're going to interact with our nodes using head testing.
So to understand hit testing we're going to make a game called Whack a jellyfish.
The game works like this.
The user has a limited amount of time to tap a jellyfish.
Once you tap a jellyfish it pops in another random position.
You have to look for it and tap it before the time runs out.
If it takes you too long to tap that jelly fish you lose the game.
So start a new school project by opening up X code create a new project a single application called
me Project Walk a jelly fish press next and create.
So like always go to the main storyboard and added a Arquette scene view to the middle of the initial
view controller.
Now I'm going to assume that you already know what an A Our kids seem to give us by now.
So I'm just going to expand it to the edges and pin it to the bottom top leading and trailing space
for constraints.
And now add a button to the bottom left of The View Controller.
Pin it 20 pixels to the bottom and 20 pixels to the leading space.
Give it a width and height of 100 pixels.
Add those two constraints as well.
And now add another button to the bottom right.
Twenty pixels from the trailing space and 20 pixel from the bottom space and it will have the same dimensions
as the other one.
Add these four constraints.
Now I place these image assets into your resources folder.
So back to X code go to your assets folder and make a new image asset called play and make another one
called Reesa reset and right into your resources folder.
Drag reset to its respective assets folder and do the same thing for play.
Now back to your main story board.
Click on the first button and remove this button labeled make the button aspect fit.
You almost never want you scale to fail as it rescaled the button to fit the image which is not something
that's going to look at it and make the background image play by going up right here just right play
and there is our play on do the same thing for the other but by removing the will make that aspect fit
and right here put the reset button in a.
All right.
Now open up the assistant editor and connect the scene view with an IBM that same view.
Connect the play with an action call the I.B. action plan and do the same thing for a reset.
Make it an action and call it reset.
Now close the assistant editor and back to the controller import market so that we can use the A-okay
framework.
This error goes away.
And just like always you need world tracking to track the position and orientation of the device.
So right leg configuration configuration is equal to our world tracking session configuration and run
a session with that configuration by writing self does seem view.
Does session run configuration and we don't need any options right now so leave that blank debug options
to view a little by writing self does seem.
View does debug options.
The above options is equal to an array type of debug options such that we can show the world origin
and we can show feature points into scene view.
All right.
We've done all of this before and the next step is also a step that you've done before and it has to
go into your info up close to your input list.
Add the property privacy camera users description and to that property display an alert saying you need
the camera to display.
They are quite content content.
All right.
So we've been through this before.
This property displays an alert to the user prompting him to enable the camera and this displays a descriptive
message to the user.
All right.
Now to the good stuff.
We're going to have to stop when the user presses play.
It shows a box node right in front of them.
So when the user taps the box a prince gets triggered.
So I a function called I had no right to the bottom of the Wii controller funk I had no with no return
or argument type and so write let known as equal to CNN and with a geometry of an A C inbox.
So geometry I see and box and has a way of zero point two metres zero point two metres and a chamfer
radius of zero position the box right in front of you by writing no the opposition is equal to a C and
vector 3 0 0 and negative 1 meters behind the center axis and the no to the scene view by making it
a child of the scenes Drew.
No that's all right self-deceit if you've seen the route no child no no now call the function inside
of play self-taught node and run the app.
And so this is nothing new.
You press play and it shows a box in front of you.
Now when you do a way to detect when the box is being pressed on.
So in view did load you need a tap gesture recognizer.
So a way to detect when the box has been tapped so right left tap gesture recognizer is equal to you
I tap just a recognizer with the target as self.
So Target the current Wii controller an action is basically when a tap occurs what function is going
to get triggered.
So make a function called Hendel to.
So fun.
Handled top with no arguments and no return value and call this in the action argument by writing selector.
And so the function we're going to select to be triggered is Hendel type.
Now selector is an objective See argument.
So just click fix to expose handle top to objective see.
It's that simple.
Now we want the tap recognizer to recognize any taps that occur in the scene view to do that right.
Self self the scene view that I gesture recognize her tap gesture recognize her now put a printed team
in and handle top called tapped the scene view.
So every time you type in the scene you handle taps that get triggered and print this.
So run the app so press play to display the box.
And if I press anywhere on the scene view or even on the box it prints top the scene view.
Now I want it such that only when you type on the box it prints tap tap on the scene view.
It doesn't tap anything.
And one more thing to notice is that the box is by default a color of white.
If you don't give it a diffuse color.
So back in X code every time the same view is tap's the gesture recognizer actually gives us information
on what was tapped.
And to get that information in the function that's an action of the gesture recognizer.
So Hendel tap make an argument sender of type you have josher recognizer.
So every time you tap on the scene view the tap just recognize sends this information with the sender.
So we know that the view we tapped on is the same view.
So right let's see if you tapped on is equal to sender does view as seen via.
OK so now you need to get the coordinates of where the user typed in the scene.
So right let's touch coordinates so the coordinates of where the user touched is equal to sender the
location in scene view top on.
So this variable tells us where the user tapped on in the scene view by getting it from the sender.
So now we can check if the user tapped on an object by writing Lochhead test
is equal to seeing you top down hit test touch coordinates and leave the options as blank.
All right.
So hit us checks if the coordinates you touched correspond to the coordinates of an object that's inside
of the scene you tapped on.
So basically if there is a match then it will give you his test results and information about what you
touched.
If there is no match.
So if the location you touched in this scene doesn't correspond to a location of an object then this
hit us variable will be empty.
So if his test
is empty print didn't touch anything.
Else.
So if there is his test results if we did touch something that's inside of the scene view print touched
a box.
All right.
Now before I run this I'm just going to give this a diffused color because I'm not a big fan of the
default white color.
So right that fuse up content is equal to you.
Eye color.
Dark blue.
And before running the app just remove this print statement and run it.
So press play to display the box.
And first if I just touch the empty seat view the coordinates I touch don't match any object in the
sim view.
There won't be a match so the hit test result will be empty.
And notice in the debugger it says didn't touch anything.
So everything works accordingly.
However now if I touch the box it prints touched a box.
The hit test finds a match between the coordinates you touched and the coordinates of the box and puts
results and information on what you touched into the hit test array.
Therefore the test variable is not empty and it has results.
Now here is a challenge.
So in X code when you touch a box and it goes to the state because the hit does variable is not empty
it has results to try and extract the results out of the hit us variable such that it tells us the geometry
of the note that we touched.
Pause the video and try to.
So the first thing you should note is that the hit test is an array.
So if I were to touch nothing.
So if the coordinates you touch don't match the coordinates of an object in the scene we're giving this
array an empty value.
If there is a match the coordinates you touch match coordinates of an object in the scene then we're
setting this array to a value system.
It only has one element of results such that the element is the object that we touched.
So since the hit test array only has one element of the results we need get the first element by writing
let.
Results is equal to hit.
Test does first unwrap it since we know we touch something because we're in the else statement.
And now right.
Let geometry is equal to results don't no geometry and printer print the geometry.
OK.
Now run the app press play touch the box and right here in the debugger it tells us that we touched
and see in box with width height and length of 0.2 meters and cheff radius of zero which matches exactly
the box that we created.
All right.
So you finally learned his testing and the next video we're going to replace this box with a 3-D model.