In your section we learn how to place household objects on horizontal planes.
In this section we're going to build a vehicle that drives on horizontal pavement how it works.
First you have to discover horizontal planes in your environment and put concrete on top of these planes.
Once you have enough concrete place the car on top of it
and have it Newf
now discovering horizontal planes and placing concrete in their place we did something very similar
to that in the last section when we did the floor is lava up the finished code for floor as lava is
in your resources folder.
So make sure to download it.
I'm going to open mine up right here anyway.
Run the app
if you ever get a crash like this.
Just make sure to clean your app
so in case you forgot how it works.
As I move around horizontal planes are replaced with loving.
However since we're going to be driving we need to replace the lava with concrete.
So first changed the name from Flores lover to vehicle.
Do it by going to the project navigator and right here on the page icon instead of Florez lover right.
Vehicle
press rename.
OK.
And do the same thing for the project folder.
Rename it from Florez lover to vehicle.
We're going to be reusing this code instead of reinventing the wheel.
Now if I build the app
there is one error.
The error is that could not read data from users floor level and put up the list to fix that.
Go with your project Navigator.
And we need to choose our end put up this fight click on your input up list and choose.
This should be fixed by now.
And the last thing we want to do is go to your project folder and just to keep things consistent.
Rename the whole directory as vehicle as well.
Click receive OK click on vehicle.
Now we're officially loading a vehicle project not Floras lover.
So rerun the app to make sure there are no crashes and everything works fine.
There are no crashes and everything still works the way it should work.
Ok back to our ex-cult project.
So we've already done all of this code in section 6.
If you're confused about this code in any way make sure to watch the first two videos of the last section.
So first go to the assets folder and delete this image US-CERT make a new image set called concrete
this image of concrete is in your resources folder.
So make sure to download it in place your concrete image back into your assets folder.
OK.
And now in your view controller where we are setting the detected plane as lava set it to concrete instead
by just replacing it with the concrete image we for auto complete to work there you go.
Rerun the app to see how this works.
I'm going to wait for the world origin to load.
And as you've guessed if I place this on a horizontal surface instead of lover it places concrete.
So right now I'm standing on top of concrete.
We need to place our vehicle our car right in front of the phone back to code go to the main storyboard
add a bunch to the Wii controller by writing button drag the button to the bottom left of your Wii controller
pin it to the bottom spaced by 20 pixels and to the leading space by 28 pixels This will give it a what
50 pixels and a height of 30
had the four constraints go to the attributes and Specter scroll to the color tag the background color
tag and give the button any background color you want.
I'm going to give it a color of yellow and call this button and now open up the assistant editor and
link the button to the View Controller with an IB action.
So drag this button by pressing control on left click instead of I put action and call the IAB action
ad car connect the IAB action close the assistant editor and back to your controller.
Whenever we press the add on the add carbon we have to add a car in the current position of the phone.
However for now we're just going to add a box in the current position of the phone.
So right left box is equal to see a node with geometry I see in box with dimensions zero point one for
the width height and length the chamfer radius will just be zero.
Give the box a color of blue by writing books that geometry that first material that diffuse contents
is equal to you color it up blue.
You should know by now that the fuse is the color that spread across the surface of a node the color
or texture.
Now you need the current position of the camera since it is at that point in the scene view that you
will add your box if you're a member from the drawing up
this right here is the ex-cult project for the drawing up that we made in section 2 right here and will
render a scene we discuss that position is a combination of orientation and location.
We need to extract the location and orientation of the camera whenever we press this button.
So the code I'm about to write in this IAB action should look very familiar to you because we are already
did it in the drawing up we already did get the current position of the camera in the drawing up and
we're about to do it again.
OK.
So back to your project we need to place the box in the current position of the camera.
So before I declare my node First you need the point of view of the scene view.
So Gardley at points of view is equal to scene view point of view.
Else return we're unwrapping the point of view safely with a guard statement.
And the point of you can change the current location and orientation of the camera view combining the
location and orientation of the camera you get the current position.
So if you remember from before location and orientation are encoded inside of the point of view and
a transform matrix get the transform matrix by writing that transform is equal to a point of view does
transform ex-drug the current orientation of your camera by writing like orientation is the will to
see and vector 3 for now I'll just leave them at 0 0 and 0 and you remember from before that orientation
is always encoded in this transform matrix such that it's in column 3.
We already did it right here.
So let's do it again by writing for The X field transform.
And 3.
So we're in the third column of The Matrix.
And one third column of The Matrix row 1.
This is where the x value of the Camors orientation is located.
We've been through this before the Y and Zed fields of your orientation are placed in the second and
third row respectively.
So simply write transform that and 3:2.
Second row is where the wind field is and transform that and 3:3 the third row is where these at fielders
of the orientation.
Also if you remember from before we concluded that this orientation is reversed so to reverse it all
we did was add a negative value to each transform.
So just put a negative for each one.
And if you for and if you forget why we did this.
Make sure to revisit lecture 2 of section 3.
Now you need the current location of the camera.
So right location is equal to SDN vector 3 0 0 and 0.
The location of the X field is located in column 401.
So just write transform dot and for one the location for the Y field is located in column 4 road to
Tusa Detroit transform that and 4:2 and the said field as in column 4 row 3.
Now we need to get the current position of the camera by combining location and orientation.
So right let current position of camera is equal to orientation plus location.
Now I could have just copied and pasted all of this.
But for the sake of review I just decided to go through this a little more quickly this time.
And as for this error we've already gone before and the air was that we cannot add to and vector 3 operands
to fix this we made a function which modified the plus operator such that it can accept to SDN vectors
or three types.
So make sure to copy it from your A-R drawing project the way you are drawing.
Our project is also in your resources folder.
OK now that we added the location and orientation we have the current position of the camera in one
variable placed the box in the current position of the camera by a writing box.
That position is equal to current position of camera.
And finally add the box to the scene view by writing self does scene view that scene.
The root node thought actual node box.
Run the app.
Wait till the world origin loads
I'm going to start detecting some planes.
Pressed odd and the box shows up right in front of us were the cameras facing.
No I notice that the boxes actually drop on the concrete for something to drop.
You need gravity.
Right now the boxes are weightless nodes and there are no forces being applied to them back in X code.
We're going to give the box a physical body
inside of our car.
Right.
Body is equal to se and physics body with a type of dynamic dynamic.
So by putting dynamic we're seeing that we want the box to be affected by forces.
Gravity is a force.
We want the box to be affected by gravity.
And as for the shape.
Right.
See in physics shape and the node is just going to be our box node.
We need to place our body after we declare the box nodes and that we can use the box node right here.
And as for the options we're going to write as S.N. physics shape options keep ask compound is equal
to true whether this is true or false right now.
Doesn't really make a difference.
Basically if it's true it converts separate geometries into separate shapes and then joins them.
If false it combines all of the geometry of your node into one shape the box node only has one shape
one geometry so it doesn't really matter what we put for this value.
But make sure that it's true.
Since we're going to need it to be true once we add a car the car is going to have many geometries and
we don't want them to be combined all into one.
Since we're going to give the wheels a specific function.
So anyway now just Redbox the physics body is equal to body.
So all the physics that we apply to this body is now applied to our box node the box node is going to
be affected by gravity and fall down.
So we're on the up
try and find some planes and replace them with concrete
press Add in the box fall down.
Gravity worked.
Gravity was applied to the box.
However the box just falls into oblivion.
We need to give the concrete physical features such that when the box falls on it the concrete is able
to support it and create lava is where we are adding concrete.
So change this function from create lava to create concrete since we're not dealing with lava anymore.
And instead of love no would change this to a concrete node.
Do the same thing for anything else that needs the lava node right here and return the concrete node
instead of the lava node.
We should be get to go in we get an error right here telling us that create lava is an unresolved identifier.
That's because it is it's now called create concrete and instead of this being the law of a node making
a concrete node instead do the same thing for a did update.
Right here it is named love a node change that the concrete note as well.
This is not create Lovett's create concrete's do the same thing for love note right here.
And we should be good to go for the rest.
So I'm hoping that right now there are no traces of lava anywhere because we renamed our project vehicle
and we replaced everything that lava no to concrete.
So just like we gave the box a physics body we need to give the concrete for a physics body such that
its static.
So right less static body is equal to seen physics body not static and apply this physical body to our
concrete floor by writing concrete node that physical body is equal to static body.
Here is how this works.
Static is designed for fixtures.
Anything that's going to be fixed in one place.
Something that does not move.
But it needs to collide with other bodies it needs to support other bodies.
We need our concrete floor to collide with the box to support the box.
Static bodies are not affected by forces for example since we gave the concrete node a static body its
able to interact with other physical bodies like the box but gravity won't affect it otherwise the floor
would just fall into oblivion.
The concrete floor is going to remain in its fixed position but it will be able to collide with any
physical body that hits it.
So in summary our concrete node is a fixture by making a static.
Its not going to move and gravity won't affect it.
However it will be able to collide with other objects so when the box falls on the concrete floor there
will be an actual physical impact between the two.
So run the
wait till the origin loads detect horizontal surfaces.
Now that you've detected a large enough concrete surface drop your box and the box actually lands on
your concrete floor.
There is an impact.
So your box has a normal physics body such that it can interact with forces like gravity it can move
and can collide with other physical bodies like the concrete floor.
The concrete floor is static.
Its a static body its not affected by gravity or any other forces.
If it was affected by gravity the concrete floor would just fall into oblivion and wouldn't stay still
like it is right now.
However its static and the fact that its static it can't move but it can collide with other objects
just like it's colliding with our box right now.
And the next video we're going to turn this box node into an actual car.