The last video we customized a box and placed it in random positions of the scene view and this video
we're going to look at more default and custom shapes.
Aside from the box first we're going to start with the capsule.
So a capsule and C-n capsule looks like a cylinder but it has two spherical ends we can modify the height
of the capsule as well as its radius its thickness.
So I can X code instead of declaring the box.
Let me just comment.
All of this so.
And right node geometry is equal to a seat and capsule and the capsule's dimensions are going to be
the following.
First we're going to change the cap radius.
Let me just fix the autocomplete.
So as I said before the cap radius is simply how thick the capsule is.
So I'm going to make it about 0.1 meters thick and its height will be about 0.3 meters.
So let me just keep the specular and diffuse colors and run the UP WAIT TILL THE WORLD origin loads
as soon as it detects the environment.
Once it does the capsule and you know what one thing I want to change before anything is place the capsule
right in front of me were done with this random positioning stuff.
Align it horizontally and vertically in place at zero point three meters behind these axis and that
is easier to work with just rerun the and so if I just wait till the world origin loads once touched
all the surfaces there it is press add and there is our capsule right in front of us.
It looks pretty cool it looks like a basic cylinder with a rounded caps which is essentially what it
is.
OK.
Now on to our next default shape the next one is going to be the cone and as cone has a bottom radius
that we can modify a top radius as well as height.
So back into our ex-coach project instead of giving a geometry of a cop so let's give it a geometry
of a cone.
So no geometry is equal to c and cone.
And like I said before we can modify the top radius here the top radius is pointy because it has a value
of zero meters.
I am going to make my top pretty is a value of zero point 1 meters the bottom radius will be about 0.3
meters with a height of let's say 0.3 meters.
Run up to see what the cone looks like when it's in the scene.
View.
So if I just wait till the world origin loads once the film attacks its environment and the cone and
there it is.
Notice how the top is not pointy since we give it a radius of 0.1 metres.
And the bottom radius is 0.3 metres much bigger than the top.
Now here's a challenge.
Try and make the cone look like a cylinder paused the video and give it a try.
So to make the cone look like a cylinder All you have to do is make the top equal to the bottom.
So 0.3 for the top radius or you know what let's just make both of them 0.1 metres.
Does it really matter as long as these are the same run up.
Just wait till the world origin loads for the film to detect its environment.
Press.
And there is our cone or cylinder for that matter.
OK.
So the next shape we're going to look at is the cylinder itself.
Ironically we just made a cylinder out of a cone.
But this time we're going to mess around with the actual cylinder shape.
And there is not much to a cylinder you can control its radius basically how thick it is as well as
its height.
So instead of declaring a cone declare a cylinder.
So right.
No geometry is equal to c and cylinder with a radius of a bow zero point two meters 20 centimeters and
a height of point 2 meters.
And you probably already know what this is going to look like so let's just run the app as soon as my
world order loads.
I'm just going to do the cylinder mean back off a little bit.
There is our cylinder.
It has a radius of zero point two meters so a diameter of 40 centimeters which is why it's so wide.
Let me just get a better angle of it and it has a height of 20 centimeters as well.
OK.
Now the next shape we're going to look at.
Let me just go to the Apple documentation is an A C and sphere and a C and sphere is a pretty basic
shape.
You've probably seen that before.
All we can modify for the sphere is the radius itself.
So why don't you pause the video and try to make your own sphere node.
OK so here's how I would do it.
Node geometry is equal to c and sphere with a radius.
I'm going to give it a radius of 0.1 metres so a diameter of 20 centimeters run the app
is going to say to my world orange and loads so that the phone properly detects its environment.
Once it does press and there is our sphere there is not much to it.
It simply has a circular radius.
Now onto our next object.
And the reason that we're looking at all of these shapes is because in future apps we're actually going
to use all of these shapes to make 3-D models.
So the next shape we're going to look for now is we're s.c and tube.
That tube is almost the exact same thing as a cylinder.
However a cylinder only has one radius where as the tube has two of them one to control the inner radius.
So how wide the hole is and one outer radius how thick the entire tube is in general back to X code.
Let me declare this a C and to know what geometry is equal to a C and tube and the inner radius how
wide the hole is is going to be zero point two meters make the outer radius about 0.3 metres.
So the tube is going to have a hole with a radius of 0.2 metres so the whole in general is going to
have a diameter of point four meters.
And from the center all the way to the edge of the tube we're going to have an outer radius of zero
point three meters the height will be about zero point five meters.
And let's run the app to see how this looks.
So if I just wait till my world origin loads and then press add let me just step away from this a little
bit.
And there is our tube.
The hole has a radius of 0.2 meters.
And the tube in general has an entire radius of 0.3.
So the tube has a diameter of 0.6 meters.
And the hole has the diameter of point four meters.
Now the next shape we're going to look at is a Taurus.
So back to our Apple documentation
the tourists kind of looks like a ring.
It has a ring radius which extends from the middle to the edge of the ring and a pipe radius which controls
the thickness of the ring.
We're going to use this Taurus shape in the future to make our basketball hoop.
So for now let's just declare a Taurus inside of our X called Project No.
Geometry is equal to c and Taurus.
And the ring ready.
So how wide the Taurus is from the center all the way to the edge is going to be about zero point three
meters and the pipe radius which controls the thickness of the ring is going to be about Dero point
two meters or you know what 0.1 metres your pipe radius should always be smaller than your ring radius
because your ring radius minus your pipe radius is basically how big the whole of your tourist.
So if you had a ring radius of let's say zero point two meters and a pipe radius of point three your
whole would be negative point 1 meters wide.
Which makes no sense you would kind of have an inverted hole of some sort.
Your Taurus would just look really weird whenever you're building a 3-D model that requires a Taurus.
Just make sure that your ring radius is always larger than your pipe radius and before running the app
let me just start placing the nodes about negative zero point seven meters behind the world origin.
Now let me just run it OK.
So I'm going to wait till the world origin loads and then press add.
So here is our Taurus.
It has a ring radius of point 3 which extends from the center all the way to the edge and a pipe radius.
So the thickness of the ring has a radius of 0.1 meters.
Now the next shape we're going to look at is a plane to find the plane in the Apple documentation just
right a C and plane and right here you'll see that the plane is simply a vertical surface with a width
and height and it has no extrusion depth whatsoever.
It's simply a flat surface with no depth.
So let's declare a plane and the plane is something we're going to use a lot in the course especially
for our vehicle up when we have to build a road so the width of the plane is going to be about point
two meters.
And do the same thing for the height run up.
Just wait till the world orange and loans and then my plane.
Here it is from here it looks like a box.
But if I go from the side you'll notice that the plane has no depth.
It's just a flat surface.
Well the width and height of zero point two meters.
OK.
Now onto our pyramid.
Find the pyramid.
I'm just going to write a C and pyramid to find it in our apple documentation.
And the pyramid is exactly what you would expect it to be.
It has a length to control its depth a width and the height.
So let's declare a pyramid right into our project.
No geometry is equal to see a pyramid.
The pyramid is going to have a width of point 1 metres a height of point 1 metres and the length a depth
of point 1 metres.
Let's run up to see how this looks OK.
Now if I just press add here is our pyramid.
From here it looks like a triangle.
But this pyramid actually has a depth.
So if I just go from the side it has a depth of 0.1 meters which we specified right here.
OK.
Now we're going to go into some cool stuff which is the bezier path the bezier path is used to create
custom shapes from a path that you draw.
So what do I mean by this.
First off right path is equal to you bezier path.
We're going to start our path 0 meters from where you positioned so to C.G. point X is 0.
Then why is zero think of the game.
Connect the dots.
If you connect every dot with a line eventually are going to form and drawn.
This is the same concept.
We're going to draw lines from one point to another until we form a custom shape to remove this node
geometry since we're not going to put it period any more.
So we're aligning our path exactly where our node is currently positioned and then we're going to add
a line from this position or path dot line to see G point X being 0 and now will be zero point two.
So we're starting our path wherever it's positioned so right here and then we're adding a line that
goes 0.2 meters upwards.
So let's assign this to our geometry and to do the right leg shape is equal to se and shape the path
is simply going to be the path that you ger and the extrusion depth basically gives your drawing a certain
thickness.
We're going to give it a thickness of zero point two meters and now assign this shape to the geometry
of I already know geometry is equal to shape.
And if you're not sure what happened it will be more clear to you once I run the app and explain it
just going to wait till the world orange and low as soon as it loads your bezier path.
And this is the line that we drew the line start to zero meters from the current position that you gave
it.
And it goes 0.2 meters upwards.
So we drew a line from 0 meters of the position that you gave it such that it goes point two meters
upwards and the line has a thickness an extrusion depth of point two meters.
And from the top we're going to go diagonally up.
I want you to pause the video and try and do that one yourself.
So we need to add another line that goes diagonally upwards from this position.
So what she would do is the right path that add line to C.G. point since we want to go diagonally.
That means that we have to change its horizontal positioning.
So right next 0.2 and Y is 0.3.
So here is what would happen.
Our path first was horizontally aligned to the current position.
So now our path is going to end up being 0.2 meters to the right of this position and zero point three
meters above it which is basically going to be zero point two meters to the right of the previous point.
And the path and 0.1 meters above the previous point and the path which is essentially going to form
a diagonal line that goes there a point two meters to the right in 0.1 metres above run the up
your path and this makes perfect sense the shape is perfectly aligned with where we positioned our node
and then you're drawing a line that goes 0.2 metres upwards from the current position.
So now we're going 0.2 metres to the right and 0.1 metres above the current vertical position which
is 0.3.
Therefore drawing a diagonal path from that current point.
Now from this point we want to draw a diagonal path that goes downwards.
So how would you do this.
Pause the video and give this one to try.
So we need to go diagonally downwards our x value has to change such that it goes to the right and our
Y value has to change as well such that it goes back down from this point.
We're going to add another line.
So right path dot line to C.G. point
and now from the position that's 0.2 meters to the right of the origin we're going to go another is
there a point 2 meters so 0.4.
But this time we're going to travel back downwards.
We're going to travel back to 0.2 metres above the origin so we're starting off that the path is exactly
where the node is positioned perfectly aligned horizontally and vertically but then we're moving 0.2
metres upwards.
Such that the path is now 0.2 metres from the Y axis of the origin and then we're moving 0.2 metres
to the right as well as 0.1 metres upwards from the previous point.
So we're moving at an upwards diagonal and then from there we're moving another 0.2 metres to the right.
So point metres from the origin and we're moving back downwards by 0.1 metres.
So this is going to lead to us drawing a diagonal path downwards 0.2 metres to the right and zero point
1 metres downwards.
Let's run the app to see how this looks OK.
So I'm going to wait till my world orange and loads
and as soon as it does my path and this makes sense as well.
So we're starting at the current position 0 0 and then we're moving 0.2 metres above the position and
then we're moving 0.2 metres to the right as well as 0.1 metres above the current vertical position.
So now we're 0.2 meters to the right of the origin and zero point three meters above.
Then we're moving another 0.2 meters to the right such that we're 0.4 in the for the right of the origin.
But we're moving 0.1 metres back down.
So now our position is 0.4 meters to the right of this position and 0.2 metres above it.
Now we want to go back down such that where is zero meters vertically from this position but we're still
0.4 meters to the right.
So why don't you try and do that yourself and see what kind of results you come up with.
So paused the video and try to.
Here is what you should have come up with past that line to see point
our x value will remain the same since we're not going to be moving in the horizontal direction.
But we want to go back down to the previous position.
So put zero right here for the final position.
We're moving 0.2 meters down and the horizontal positioning stays the same.
So run the app to see what this looks like.
Let me just wait till the world orange and load's do your best your path and look at what this forms
a house.
So let's go over this.
We're starting off at the current position perfectly aligned horizontally and vertically then we're
going 0.2 metres up.
Then we're moving a diagonal distance 0.2 metres to the right and 0.1 metres above.
So right now where is there a point two metres to the right of this position and zero point three metres
above it.
And from this point we're going back down 0.1 metres.
So now we're 0.2 metres above this position but we're 0.4 metres to the right of it.
So 0.2 metres to the right of this one which makes for a downwards diagonal line and then from this
distance the horizontal positioning stays the same but we're drawing a line that goes downwards.
And with our extrusion depth of 0.2 metres which is giving this bezier path a depth it forms a perfect
house so we just made our first custom shape by drawing lines from one point to another.
And there are a lot of softwares where you can make custom shapes softwares such as this one.
If you were to use it you would manually make your own custom shape and once you make it it would convert
that custom shape for you.
In code you white bezier a path code that you would just copy into your ex-school project to load the
custom shape that you made.
There are many apps just like this one for example.
There as deep as your code vector drawing to objective c code.
There are some apps for swift code but it's really hard to convert objective c to Swift.
There are many tools to do that.
So this is another example of it converting images to you bezier path code right here.
And that is it for this video point and this video was to show you all of the default shapes that we're
going to use later on in the course to build many complex 3D models look like our portal and our basketball
court.
And the next video we're going to look at relative positioning.