Last video we were able to drive our car forward.
Now we're going to look at reversing it and applying a braking force before we get to reversing and
braking our car.
I want to make our steering smoother the steering angle gets smoother if this value better reflects
the acceleration due to gravity.
So what do I mean by this.
The accelerometer sure is detecting the acceleration due to gravity in the y direction and from that
acceleration due to gravity we're converting that to the steering angle by setting the acceleration
equal to the steering angle of the wheels the wheels turn accordingly.
But the accelerometer is also detecting other minor accelerations being applied on the phone for instance
as I'm physically moving the phone.
I'm giving it an applied acceleration on top of the gravitational acceleration.
We want to filter out any applied acceleration and we only want the acceleration due to gravity.
Nothing else.
So in your resources folder there is a function which filters out any acceleration that's not gravitational.
Make sure to copy it into your project and right here on top of your view controller make a variable
var acceleration values is equal to an array type of acceleration values.
So you get acceleration values 0
and another you want acceleration value of 0.
So these are just double values both of which equals zero.
The first element of the first double value we're going to have that represent the acceleration due
to gravity in the x direction.
The second element we're going to have it represent the acceleration due to gravity in the wind direction
right now let's just focus on the y value.
The second element.
So access the second element by writing acceleration values 1.
So the second inducts in our array is equal to filtered
your current acceleration value is the following acceleration values 1 and the updated acceleration
is whatever the accelerometer updates us on what the acceleration due to gravity is.
So acceleration why.
So here's what I'm doing.
Don't worry too much about this complex return value.
Just know that this function takes into acceleration due to gravity is your current one.
So first we're giving our current acceleration due to gravity.
A default value.
Zero.
Right here you acceleration value is zero.
And then we're putting the acceleration that the accelerometer updates a sun.
So your vertical acceleration not why this function then returns an acceleration due to gravity that's
filtered out using a filtering factor and we're giving the second element in the acceleration values
array that filtered acceleration due to gravity.
So instead of using this value to represent our acceleration due to gravity use the one that's filtered
out.
So just put acceleration values one.
The second element this value better represents the acceleration due to gravity in the y direction and
therefore better reflects how the phone is oriented which will cause for a smoother steering angle.
If you're still confused think about this let's just say that at one point in time while I'm running
the OP the phone is completely vertical and this equals one the current acceleration is one.
Then I reorient my phone the accelerometer updates us on the new acceleration due to gravity acceleration
not Y which could be something very close to one like 0.9 or something.
However we need to filter this 0.9 value from any accelerations that aren't gravitational.
And we do that by putting our previous acceleration value which was one hour of did it.
Acceleration values since we moved the film which is 0.9 or something we would put both of these accelerations
into our function and through a very complex equation it would return a filtered acceleration due to
gravity that better reflects the orientation of the phone.
Now as long as we're filtering the vertical acceleration.
Make sure to also filter your horizontal acceleration by accessing the first inducts and your acceleration
values array and making that equal to filtered your current acceleration will just be the falling acceleration
values at zero.
Remember we said that the first index is the horizontal acceleration and the second one is the vertical
and put your updated horizontal acceleration.
And instead of checking if acceleration X is zero check if acceleration values zero bigger than zero.
This simply represents a more accurate description of what our horizontal acceleration due to gravity
is.
So we're on the up wait till the world orange and those once the world orange and those start detecting
some surfaces once you detect a large enough surface
and your car start driving and everything works pretty well.
The steering is a lot smoother.
Now you could have not even added this function and left everything the same as it was before everything
would have still worked fine.
However this function simply makes for a smoother experience when driving in a car.
Now finally there are two more features that I want to add.
If I tap the device with two fingers I want the car to reverse if I type it with three fingers.
I want the car to stop to start braking so instead of a bool value make touching an integer
equal to zero in the now inside of touches begin.
Delete this.
Guard let is equal to touch the first else for turn.
So if there is at least one finger touching the screen then increment your touched variable by how many
fingers are touching the screen touches the top count.
So if I touch the screen with two fingers this will equal two if I touch the screen with three fingers
that will equal three.
And inside of touch is ended when I release my fingers says self touched is equal to zero and now in
that simulate physics time.
Let me just try and find this function right here.
If self touched is equal to 1.
So if I only have one finger on the screen.
Dr normally now right.
Else if self-taught touched is equal to two.
So if I have two fingers on the screen I want the car to drive in the reverse direction.
Pause the video and I want you to try and do that
to drive the car in the reverse direction.
Just set the engine for us to a negative value.
And if touch count is equal to 3.
If self touched is equal to three if I'm touching the screen with three fingers we need the card to
break.
So declare var braking force
of type C.G. float is equal to zero.
If the user has three fingers on the screen put a braking force of 100 Newtons so braking force is equal
to 100.
And apply this braking force to the back wheels of the car by riding self.
The vehicle does apply braking force
the braking force itself and we're going to apply it to the back wheels.
We already concluded that the back wheels are located in zero and one of our wheels are right.
So make sure to add that to wheel number one as well.
So first the braking force is zero and if you touch the screen with three fingers the car will break
out a force of 100 Newtons.
Run the UP WAIT TILL THE WORLD origin loads as soon as the world origin loads start detecting some surfaces.
Once you've detected a large enough surface make sure to rotate your phone horizontally so that your
car's orientation at first is straight.
Your car will drive in the forward direction.
Touch the screen with one finger and the car drives normally.
Touch it with two fingers and the car reverses and the engine for us is negative as you're driving.
Touch the car with three fingers and the car stops at a force of 100 Newtons and that is it for the
car up.
We were able to convert a normal node to a vehicle and applied orientation engine forces and braking
forces to that vehicle.
You learn how to figure out the orientation of the phone based on the Phelan's acceleration due to gravity.
In that section we're going to make our ruler up.