This section we're going to learn how to measure distances in the real world.
ESOP is very simple when you type on the scene.
It places a starting point and from the starting point you can measure the distance traveled.
Open up X code create a new project a single application called the project.
They are measuring press next.
And create like always go to the main storyboard into your controller and they are kids in view.
I hope you know what an etiquette scene give you is by now.
We've used it in every single app.
Expand it to the edges of your super view and pin the market scene to the top bottom leading and trailing
space inside of our seat of view we need a stock view to place all of our labels in the stock view is
just going to be on top inside of the stack.
For labels one here another label.
There you go.
Once you add your four labels go to your stock view and we're going to need a spacing of 25 pixels between
each label.
Align the stock view horizontally inside of the scene of view and place it a bow 30 pixels from the
top for each label.
I'm going to put a background color of white.
So good to the attributes Inspektor into your background.
Put a background of white or whatever color you choose.
I've found white to be a good color for this up background snow.
There you go for this label as well.
The first label I will call distance the other 3 x y and now I have been to the middle of your extreme
view and align it horizontally and vertically to your scene view
give the bun a width and height of 40 pixels by going to your constraints spar with a 40 height of 40.
Remove the text we have at the moment and in your assets folder an image set called AD and inside of
your resources folder there are image assets of a plus symbol.
Drag those images into your assets folder.
This didn't work out so well.
Let me just add them all individually.
This one out of 12 something is going to drop times two times three back into your main storyboard give
the above the image that we just put in the assets folder by going to the attributes inspector and inside
of image.
Put the odd button and make sure the burn is aspect fit.
Now open up the assistant editor and connect every label to your controller with an idea.
Start with this one.
Call this label distance
this one will be named X X label
y label
and Zed label and lastly connect you're seeing view within IBM that as well call this one scene view
close up the assistant editor and back to our Wii controller.
The next step to get Eric working is something we've done a million times before.
I want you to pause the video and try to do it yourself this time.
First off we need to import a kit to use the air framework and declare a constant configuration equal
to our world tracking session configuration.
In order to track the phones orientation and position at all times now we need to run a scene view session
with that configuration
and it's always good to debug options to see if every feature points are working and we're our world
origin is.
So make it equal to an array type of debug options.
Or C and debug options does show a world origin and a r s n d about other options does show feature
points
now into your input list.
Declare a property privacy camera a user's description this property prompts the user to give the phone
access to the camera at a descriptive message of your choice such as you need the camera for cool market
content.
Now run your app to make sure that everything is fine.
And everything looks pretty good so far.
Now whenever you tap on the screen we want to display a note right in front of the camera to indicate
the user starting position.
To trigger a tap on a screen we need a tap just a recognizer.
So go to your view controller in the right leg tap gesture
recognizer is equal to UI type gesture recognizer.
The target will be self.
And as for the action the function that we want to trigger when we tap the screen is the following phunk
handle top with arguments sender of type you tap gesture recognizer and no return value.
I had this tier action by writing selector handle type
and since selector is an objective argument we just have to expose handle top to Objective-C by just
writing the following.
And we're good to go now.
And this tab just to recognize or to the scene view by writing self scene view does it add gesture recognizer
top just to recognize So whenever we tap the scene view this function will get triggered and remember
that whenever the top just recognizer gets triggered.
It gives us information in the form of a sender.
We're going to use the sender to clear the view that we tapped on by writing Gardella scene.
View is equal to sender view as a cricket scene if you else return if the view that was topped on is
in our kids same view then proceed otherwise return.
Now I'm sure that the view that was tacked on is in a case of you since we registered this register
recognize your to obscene view.
So only if we tap the scene view will this function get triggered.
But this guard statement is just for good practice it's not always good to forcefully interrupt things
anyway.
Whenever the user taps the scene we want to display a note right in front of where the phone is already
positioned.
This is something we've done before in the drawing up.
I'm not going to reuse the code from the drawing up since I want you to get more familiar with other
types of matrices as you will be dealing with them a lot when making a circuit ops.
So first off declare a sphere node by writing the sphere is equal to.
I see a node with geometry as CN sphere
with a radius zero point zero zero five meters that's five millimeters give the sphere a diffuse color
of yellow by writing sphere geometry the first material that diffuse the contents is equal to you color
dot yellow.
Now how do we position this fear right in front of the camera.
So with your current knowledge and from what you've learned and suction to this is what you would do
you would get the point of view of the scene view since the point of view can change the current location
and orientation of your camera view.
However I'm going to approach this another way instead of getting the current point of view of the same
view.
We're just going to get the current frame by guard letting guard let current friend is equal to seeing
view that session current friend else return
the current frame represents the frame that was just rendered from the current frame you can access
the camera property.
So right like camera is equal to
current friend dock camera and this camera property gives us information about the current position
orientation and imaging parameters of the camera.
All of this information is encoded in a transformed matrix.
So right let transform is equal to camera that transform this transform is a four by four matrix and
therefore encodes the exact position of our phone.
Now our Sfeir node also has a transform matrix to encode its position however its transformed matrix
at the moment is just a standard linearly independent matrix.
It contains no information on the nodes position.
Now if I set the nodes transform matrix equal to the transform matrix of the phone's current position
Sarette sphere.
SIMD transform.
This is how you access the transfer matrix of the sphere.
It's a 4 by 4 Matrix just like this one and set it equal to the transform which encodes the current
position of the phone.
Then the node is going to be positioned exactly where the phone is currently positioned.
Since its transfer matrix now also encoded the current position of the phone therefore the node will
be positioned exactly where the phone is.
Finally just add the note to the scene view by writing self does scene view that scene a root node.
Add child node sphere and now just run the app
wait till the world origin loads once it loads top the screen view.
Right now the node is positioned exactly where my phone is so if I go back I should be able to see it.
And here is our starting position.
Now it's a bit annoying that every time I tap on the scene of view like right now I have to go back
to see the starting position.
I want the starting position to show up right in front of my camera view right in front of me were this
plus sign.
So instead of putting the know exactly where your phone is why not just move it about 10 centimeters
away.
How would I even do this.
First off print the transformer of the camera print transform run the app
move away from your old origin.
Top on the screen and this right here is your transform matrix back to your debugger.
This right here is the transform of the camera.
It is a matrix.
And I remember that we said the transform of the camera encodes the exact position of the camera whereas
that position encoded it's inside of the third column.
This right here is called them the Missouri column number one column number two.
And this is call them number three.
All we care about is this column in this column.
This represents the phone's current exposition relative to the world origin.
This isn't the y position Zad position and we don't care about the fourth argument.
All we've ever dealt with was X Y and Z.
So when I tap the scene view the phone was currently zero point to seven meters to the right of the
world origin.
It was 0.07 meters above the world origin.
And it was zero point two meters away from the world origin behind it.
Notice the negative.
And since we're giving the sphere nodes transform these exact same values the sphere know will also
be 0.7 meters so the rest of the world origin 0.07 meters above it and 0.2 metres behind it so exactly
where the is I don't want to position the sphere exactly where my phone is.
I want to position in the point of view of my camera which is by default 0.1 metres away from the current
position of the phone.
So had we just copied the code we had for the drawing up which already places the node and the point
of view of the camera it would have already placed our sphere 0.1 metres away from the current position
of the phone in the point of view.
But for the sake of learning more about matrices let's do it the hard way.
So instead of putting our sphere exactly where my phone is I'm going to put it 0.1 metres away from
the current position behind it.
How will I do this while I need to modify the zent position of this matrix.
Remember that these that position controls how far or how close you are to your apparent node.
In our case the parent node is the seen news world origin.
I'm going to modify the value of this transform matrix by subtracting negative points 0 2 with 0.1.
So finally everything the same the node will be positioned exactly where the phone is which is 0.2 meters
behind the world origin.
And if I substracted by 0.1 the node will be in the point of view of the camera 0.1 meters behind the
current position of the phone which would be negative zero point three meters behind the world origin.
Now to modify a matrix you need another matrix.
So declare in other matrix by writing Vire translation matrix is equal to Matrix
identity four by four.
So we just declared a four by four matrix.
We're going to multiply this matrix to modify this one.
Right now this matrix is linearly independent which means that we didn't give this matrix any values
right now which equals 1.
If you multiply anything by 1 nothing with change five times one is still five.
So by multiplying this transform matrix by 1 this transform matrix would not change at all.
So we need to modify this one access the third column of this transform matrix by writing translation
matrix
Daut columns 3 and change its value to negative 0.1.
Now declare a new matrix var modified matrix is equal to
SIMD Muhl.
So we're going to multiply two matrices.
We're going to multiply the transform of the camera's current position by the translation transform.
Now this is not a linear algebra course.
I won't teach you how transform multiplication works just know that the only value we changed in this
matrix is the said field in the third column which makes sense since we want to modify the value of
this Zed field which is in the third column.
So by multiplying these two matrices these two values since they are both in the same column and are
both Zad values are going to be added.
So a negative 0.2 plus minus 0.1 which is simply negative 0.2 minus 0.1 would equal negative 0.3.
None of these other values will change since we only modified these add value of the third column.
And so by giving the sphere know this transform it will now be 0.1 metres away from the current position
of the phone.
As soon as we tap on the scene view run the app to see if that's the case.
If I just wait till the world origin loads and then tap on the scene view
the sphere shows up right in the point of view of the camera 10 centimeters away from the current position
of the phone.
Now that we set up the starting position of our node in the next video we're going to start making measurements
relative to our starting position.