Welcome to your first lesson in this course we're going to set up the camera so that it can track the
phone's orientation and position relative to the world around it.
Ex code is the platform you'll be using to set up your apricot apps.
So open it up create a new project a single application.
Call the project world tracking press next and create the first thing you want to do is go to the main
storyboard
and to the initial controller and market sync if you the market view gives a camera a view of the real
world such that the user can display three dimensional content inside of this camera view.
So expand the market scene get you to the edges of your purview and make sure to pin it to the bottom
top leading and trailing space
open up the assistant editor and make sure to link here kids seen you to the controller with an IBM
it called Scene view.
Connect the IAB outlet close the assistant editor and back to your view controller.
Import a market to use the market framework and get rid of this error and declare a constant configuration
of type A-R role tracking configuration.
So the configuration is equal to our role tracking session configuration we're all tracking is used
to track the position and orientation of your device relative to the real world at all times.
This is very important because if the phone doesn't know where it's position relative to the world around
it then it wouldn't be able to effectively display three dimensional content in certain places of the
world.
So make sure that as soon as the view loads your scene he runs a session says that it has this configuration
to do that right itself does seem view that scene does session run configuration
now when the device is able to track its position and orientation at all times.
Now add debug options to the scene view by writing self does seem VM that debug options is equal to
an array type of debug options such that the same view is going to show feature points so C and debug
options that show feature points in the scene view is also going to show the world origin.
A R S C and debug options does show world origin
in the book options doesn't really do anything in terms of functionality.
It simply helps us debug the app by showing us if the world Orangemen was properly detected and if the
feature points are constantly being discovered the world origin is your starting position in the real
world.
So as soon as you launch the app world tracking detects everything in your environment and keeps track
of where you started the starting position is your world origin feature points are simply information
about features in the world around you that the device detected.
The device remembers all of that information to precisely pinpoint to your position at all times.
This will be more clear to you when I run the app but before running it there is one last step we have
to do which is to go to your food list.
Since you're using the camera you need the property privacy press on the plus one privacy camera usage
description.
This property displays an alert to the user asking him or her to allow the app to use the camera.
If you don't put this property your app will simply crash.
A descriptive message to that property saying you need the camera to display cool a arcade content.
This message is going to pop up to the user prompting him to enable the camera.
So run the app.
Notice the alert prompting user to allow the app to use the camera as well as the descriptive message
you give it.
You need the camera to display cool air get caught and so enable the camera by pressing OK and give
the device a few seconds to figure out its position in the real world.
So now if I move backwards you should notice this three dimensional coordinate system will go over this
coordinate system in more depth.
In other lectures.
But for now just know that this is the world origin and represents the starting position of the device
relative to the real world.
Once you launch the map the scene view runs a session such that it is configured to track the devices
orientation and position.
After a couple of seconds after it analyzes and it recognizes the environment around it it's able to
track where my starting position is.
If I move towards the origin walk around it or even rotate my device.
The device is still able to pinpoint where my starting position is.
In other words seeing these configuration is able to track where I started and this could only mean
that the phone is always keeping track of its current position and orientation.
This is awesome.
Now see these yellow dots.
These are called feature points.
One of the ways the device can always keep track of its position is by detecting features in its surrounding
environment as unique pieces of information that information is used to precisely pinpoint the current
position and orientation of your device in the next video you're going to display a three dimensional
virtual object in the physical world.