In the last video you were able to place a box onto a horizontal concrete floor.
Now it's time to turn this box into an actual car.
So right click on the vehicle folder.
Click on new file.
Scroll down till you find your Schene kit seen file press next and create your scene.
OK so you'll notice that inside of the seen File we're given a camera or a node.
We don't need this camera or a node so make sure to delete it.
Now add a box to your scene view by a writing box.
Drag it to your scene and to change the color of the scene.
I'm not a big fan of the great color.
Go to the scene inspector and put a background of white.
Now that the scene is white it's a little hard to see our box.
So click on your box and give it a diffuse color of blue.
Now I want to see how the box looks like from the front.
So click on the front perspective and the box just disappears.
Double click on the box and it still doesn't show up.
This is the next code bug.
The way I fixed it was simply click on the play button and then click on it again then double click
your node and your box shows up.
So if I go from perspective and back to front everything works fine.
But note that the box is a little too big.
It currently has a with height and length of 1 meter.
That's about the size of a table.
So give it a width length and height of zero point two meters.
And right under it we're going to place another box.
Go to the size inspector and give this box a width of 0.4 a height of 0.1 and the length of 0.4 as well.
Give this box a background color or are a diffuse color of red.
Now imagine that this is a truck.
This would be the frame of the truck and not the head.
So rename this blue box to head.
And this one to frame we want to position the head relative to our friend to do that make the had a
child of the frame by just dragging it right under our frame like so.
So now the frame is the parent node of the head.
If you're a member from before the child node is always positioned relative to its parent node.
So go to the node Inspektor of our head and you can see that the head is positioned 0.7 to two metres
above our friend.
So one thing I want to make sure is that the head is positioned almost right on top of the frame.
So about 0.1 8 metres above this is looking better and I want the head to be perfectly horizontally
aligned with the Phryne.
It already kind of is aligned with the frame since it's close to zero.
But make sure it's perfectly aligned.
There you go.
And as for the Zed value it refers to how far the head is from the frame center.
If I put this at 0
the head is positioned exactly at the frame center.
I want the had to be at the frame's edge so position is 0.1 metres from the frame center.
This is looking pretty good.
Now we need wheels for our truck.
The wheels are simply cylinders.
So I had a cylinder right cylinder and drag it to your scene give the cylinder a radius of zero point
zero four meters and a height of 0.1 meters.
The size looks a lot better to me.
Now we want to rotate the cylinder 90 degrees clockwise so that it looks like an actual wheel.
So in the no inspector in your Euler angles rotate the cylinder 90 degrees clockwise and that looks
a lot better to me.
Now give the cylinder a color of black since that is the standard color for a wheel.
So now we need to position our will relative to the frame.
So make do wheel a child of the frame as well.
OK.
Now position this wheel such that is 0.1 metres to the frame center.
So 0.1.
Let me just fix the perspective of this.
It's not very clear what's going on right now.
So now the wheel is 0.1 metres to the right of the frame center.
Now I need the wheel to be 0.1 metres right under our frame.
So for the why field just put negative 0.1 it's a little hard to click on.
So just negative 0.1.
Now our wheel is almost right under our frame and the last thing I want to do is that I want this wheel
to be closer to the frame's edge.
So a negative zero point one two meters behind the frame center so further that field just right.
Negative 0.1 to fix the perspective back to its original one.
This is looking pretty good.
Copy and paste three more cylinders make them all.
Children of the frame OK.
So right now the rest of the wheels or the cylinders for that motor are positioned exactly where the
first one is.
So it looks like there is only one but they're all there.
We need to reposition the other wheels for the second wheel.
We need that wheel to be 0.1 metres to the left of the frame center.
Right now it's 0.1 metres to the right.
So just putting negative 0.1 to change the direction there is our second wheel position perfectly.
As for our third wheel the third cylinder we need that wheel to be zero point 1 2 meters in front of
the frame center away from it.
Right now with 0.1 0.22 meters behind the frame center to make it in front just remove this the negative
value.
And there is our third wheel.
And for the fourth cylinder we need that one to be 0.1 two meters in front of the frame center away
from it and 0.2 meters to the left of the Freema center.
So click on your fourth cylinder.
Change this to negative zero point once such that it's to the left and put it Zero Point 1 2 meters
in front of the frame center.
And there is our fourth wheel.
Now we have what looks like a car in the view controller.
Instead of adding a box on top of the concrete we're going to add our car.
So first rename this two car scene car dash seen as CN and so it doesn't fall in back into our Iby action.
Load the scene by writing a lot scene is equal to c and c and the scene is named just copy and paste
the following right into your screen name as a string.
And from the scene we have to get our car Noad this car note right here.
No the car is an immediate child of the scenes root note.
So back into your view controller just right leg car node is equal to seen a root node dot child node
with name the child nodes name itself is frame.
So copy and paste the right into your child node name know as we've always done before leave recursively
as false since the car is an immediate child of the scene the root node.
So I'd just leave this as false parentheses to your car node and forcefully unwrap it since we know
that everything here is correct.
And make sure the body no references are cardno would not the box input car door physics body is equal
to body.
So we're applying physics to our carno not the box know it anymore.
And finally the car note to the scene view and make sure that the car node is positioned exactly where
the camera is not the box.
You know what let's just delete this box node entirely since we don't need it anymore.
So when the app
wait for the world origin to load start detecting some planes
once you detected a big enough surface.
Like I just did.
Now I had your car and there it is now.
I want to be able to see the wheels from the top.
To do that we have to make the top of the car transparent.
So back to your ex could project into your scene file go on to frame and into your node.
Scroll down till you find the passage city and change the opacity to about 0.75.
The smaller the opacity value the less opaque something is the more transparent.
So we made the frame more transparent and since the frame is the parent node of the head and the wheels
they become transparent as well.
So run the app.
It's important that you wait till the world origin loads.
Once it does start detecting some surfaces once you're done detecting surfaces on your car and this
looks pretty good.
In fact to code.
One more thing to note is that we're not actually loading the entire car.
We're loading the frame and it's true that by adding the frame to the scene view the whole car shows
up but that's not exactly the case.
All you're doing is adding the frame.
However if you go to your scene file the wheels and we had our children of the frame.
So by displaying the parent the children the wheels in the head are displayed as well.
It's kind of like Real-Life wherever the parent goes.
The children follow.
So just rename the frame for the sake of clarity instead of car Noad and change it accordingly.
Everywhere else here as well.
In the next video we're going to set up the accelerometer of the car.