And the last video we simply set up our up such that we place the eggs in the scene and bullets to shoot
those acts.
Now when you do that when you shoot an egg the egg blows up.
So first we need a way to detect when the egg and the bullet collide with one another.
To do that we need the help of a certain delegate function to get the delegate function and we need
to inherit from C in physics contact delegate so do just that inherit from a C in physics.
By inheriting from this delegate we can call the function physics world did begin contact this function
gets called whenever two physics bodies come into contact.
Let's test that by putting a print statement came into contact and now to execute this delta-V function.
And if you did load right stuff that scene view seen scene physics world doc contact delegate is equal
to self run the app
just going to wait till the world origin Lote's soon as it loads your targets
should target and the print statement does not get called.
Nothing is happening.
So to trigger this function we need to assign collision bit masks to each physics body.
In other words I need to tell the physics world I need to tell the delegate function to watch out for
collisions between the egg and the bullet.
To do that first I need to categorize the egg as the target and the sphere.
I'm applying a force to the bullet to start the sauf let me just run the up and make an enemy bit mass
category will be the name of your enemy
category.
Of type integer with two cases.
Case bullet will equal our random integer Q And case target is equal to 3.
You can leave these integers as anything you want as long as they are different.
I'll explain this in a second.
And now inside of handle type when we are shooting our bullet give the bullet a category mask by writing
bullet dot physics body
category mask is equal to big mass category dark bullet don't raw value.
So all I did was I categorized the bullet and I gave it a value of bullet.
So a value of two bit mass category dot bullet and now do the same thing for the.
We're going to categorize the so right egg node
the physics body that category bit mask is equal to mass category the that we declared that target the
AG will be the target the raw value.
So we just categorized the AG.
We gave it a value of target a value of three so category a bit mask defines which categories that a
physics body belongs to.
The bullet belongs to the category bullet which is represented by the number two and the egg.
We give it a category of the target which is represented by the number three.
So now we place the bullet node as well as the egg node inside of categories.
And so now that we placed these notes in categories I can now specify to this delegate function.
Watch out for collisions between the target and the bullet.
To do that further bullet right bullet does physics body contact Biton ask is equal to bitmaps.
Category
target the raw value.
So we're telling the physics world to watch out for any collisions for any contact between a bullet
and anything which has the target raw value.
And in our case the egg and if such a collision is detected trigger this delegate function and now do
the same thing for the egg right egg physics body contact bit mask is equal to pit mask category of
bullet dart raw value.
So we're telling the physics world to watch out for any collisions any contact between the egg and anything
which has the bullet raw value which is the bullet itself.
So if such a collision is detected trigger this delegate function run the EP
and your eggs shoot one of the eggs and the delegate function gets triggered and then gets triggered
many times because it's getting triggered for both.
And coming into contact with the bullet and the bullet coming into contact with the cat.
So now when the delegate function gets triggered blow up the egg into confetti.
So we're given this contact variable and the contact contains the two notes that came into contact.
So right let no day is equal to contact data no day and right let no be is equal to contact.
That would be.
And now node A could either be the bullet or the fact that we hit a node B could also either be the
bullet or the egg that was hit.
It's one of the nodes that came into contact.
But we want to only blow up the egg not the bullet.
So here's how to accomplish this.
On top of your controller right var target of type I see a node
and back into here if not a tough physics body doc category bit mask is equal to fitness category.
The ENM target the raw value.
So if node A has the big category of a target then we know it's the egg.
So self target is equal to node.
And now nowhere else if no be tough physics body category bit ask is equal to fitness category.
Target the wrong value.
So if no B is the target.
So we know that no B was the act that was hit.
So right self the target is equal to Node B.
So in our target whether or not node is the egg or node B is the egg target is going to be the egg that
was hit.
So now we want to blow up this target node the egg that was hit into confetti.
Adding a confetti animation requires a particle system a particle system manages the animation of small
images and high level simulations.
So animations like smoke rain confetti or fireworks to add a particle system.
Click on new file.
Scroll down until you find the particle system file.
This one will be a confetti particle system call the confetti and create it.
And I'm just going to place it right into my media as CNT assets file and delete these remove references
and we're good to go.
Now when you click on this you're supposed to see an animation of confetti.
But for some reason it doesn't show.
So for example if I add the fire particle system so let me just scroll down to this if I add the fire
1 press next and call this one fire and notice that the fire animation shows.
I'm not sure why the confetti one doesn't show it.
It must be a simple X bug.
But let me just put this right into my media.
I see an asset file and remove the references for this one.
And now that we have a particle system animation let's access it by writing let confetti is equal to
s c and particle system named the name will simply be us accessing the particle system.
So media c sets slosh.
We want the confetti one for now slash confetti dot s c and p seen particle system and directory leave
this as no since there are no subdirectories that we need to access and write confetti that loops is
equal to false.
We don't want the confetti animation to last forever we only want it to happen for four seconds so right
confetti dot particle lifespan is equal to four.
So now it will last four seconds.
And now the confetti animation is going to take the shape of the egg.
So right confetti dot emitter shape is equal to target geometry.
So basically in the boundaries of the egg you'll see all the confetti flying now declare a confetti
node.
So like confetti node is equal to a C and node and Deacon free animation the particle system to that
note by writing confetti Noad
dawn and particle system confetti.
And make sure to unwrap this place the confetti.
Exactly where the collision occurred.
So any contact point by writing confetti node position is equal to contact contact point.
So exactly where the bullet came into contact.
The confetti animation will occur.
And now finally just the confetti to the scene of you by writing itself to us seeing you seen the root
node child node confetti node run the up
going to wait till the world origin loads soon as it loads the targets.
And if I shoot one of the eggs the confetti animation occurs.
However we need the box to disappear as soon as the animation occurs.
To give the illusion that the box is blowing up into confetti.
So to your controller.
Right target which is the egg that was hit the target.
Remove from parent node.
We're on the up
we're told the world origin loads than your targets.
Shoot one of the eggs and it looks like the egg blows up into confetti.
This is pretty cool.
One more thing I want to add is back into your controller.
We want to make sure that as soon as the bullet is shot it disappears.
After two seconds since we don't want a clutter of bullets forming into our scene if we shoot a lot
of them so to do that we need to give the bullet to se and actions when action such that the bullet
which two seconds and the other action is the bullet being removed from the scene view.
So right node or bullet for that matter.
Daut run action and we want to trigger a sequence of actions inside of this action.
So see an action sequence and the sequence of actions that are going to occur is first the node is going
to wait two seconds.
So wait a duration of 2.0 seconds and after the weight of two seconds we want the node to be removed
from its parent node sir as CNH action remove from parent node.
So what will happen is the node waiting two seconds after it was shot and after two seconds that will
be removed from my machine and just run the up to test this.
Let me just add the eggs and if I shoot one of the eggs everything still seems to work pretty well.
One more thing I want to try out is let's try the fire particle system.
So right here instead of loading the I and Pete let me try and load the fire particle system run the
app.
So if I wait till the world orange and LOTES and then add the targets if I shoot one of them it gives
a fire animation.
This is pretty cool.
Personally myself I'm a bigger fan of the confetti animations.
So let me just leave it at that.
And now we're done with our shooter up.
This was the last video you learned how to detect when two nodes collide and apply animations to these
nodes upon collision with all the apps you've made over this course.
I hope you found the confidence to build any kit up that you put your mind to.
It was a great pleasure teaching you.
Good luck.