The last video we built our basketball net in this video we're going to shoot a ball.
The idea is simple.
Whenever you touch the screen it shoots the ball into your net.
The longer you touch the screen the further your ball goes.
So override touches begin now as you remember from before it touches began gets triggered whenever you
touch the screen.
And before we shoot the ball we need to check and see if there is a basketball not to do that make a
computed property.
Var Baskett added of type bool when they return value and return self scene view the scene a node with
name and the name that we're going to check for the basket node.
Copy and paste it into your view controller recursively as false is not equal to no.
So this checks if there is a basketball on the inside of your scene view and if there is this value
will be true if there isn't a basketball not inside of your scene views root node.
If it's no this value will be false.
So in touch begin if self Baskett added is equal to true.
So if there is a basketball court then we're going to shoot the ball.
Now we're going to shoot the ball right where the camera is facing and the point of view of the camera.
This is something we already did in the drawing up in the vehicle up and in the ruler up having practice
at least three times pause the video and try this one on your own.
So what you would do is get the point of view of the scene view by writing.
Guard let point of view is equal to self does scene view point of view point of view as you remember
from before has the current orientation and location of the film camera view point of view.
We discussed in section two that the location is in Column number four of the transform matrix.
So location is equal to c and vector 3 and I seem to have forgotten to put my else return clause.
So SDN vector 3 point of view transform.
And you know what.
Instead of always the clearing point of view right here.
Let me just make a transform variable equal to point of view transform and right here or just put transform
dot and for one the X of the location is located in column for row 1.
As we discussed before the why isn't column 4 road 2 and the Zad field is in column for row 3.
Now we need the orientation of the camera view which would simply be left orientation is equal to c
and vector 3 transform.
M3 1 orientation is in the third column transform not M3 to transform.
And 3:3 and we discussed before that the orientation is reversed.
So to honor reverse it just add a negative to each field.
And now finally to get the current position just right.
Position is equal to location plus orientation.
And we should get an error very soon telling us that we cannot combine these two types and it's right
there.
The binary operator cannot be applied between two of the vector three operands.
And to fix that we made a certain function which modified this binary operator.
So right phunk Plus which takes an to see and vector 3 types a left hand side and a right hand side
and from the two LCN vectors.
3. you're adding simply return another third dimensional vector
and just return a C and vector 3 make.
So from the two vectors that we're adding make a new vector such that we're adding the X fields of both
vectors left dot X plus right dot X we're adding the y fields as well.
And the set fields left outside plus right outside cat.
Now the error should be gone and we have the current orientation and location in one variable.
We have the position of the camera.
So we want to position our basketball in this exact position.
First we have to make a basketball note.
So let ball is equal to C.A. with a geometry of C and sphere which has a radius of about zero point
three meters 30 centimeters.
And now give the ball a diffuse color of blue by writing Balado geometry first material dot to fuse
contents is equal to you like colored dark blue.
And finally just position the ball exactly in the position of the camera view by writing ball up position
equal to position.
Now just on the ball to the scene view by writing self-deceit you'd seen a root node dot ChildNet and
ball.
So I just want to test this bool value first and foremost so run the app.
So if I try and place a ball right now it should not get placed because a Baskett was not added.
So if I detect a surface and then on a basketball court right here now I can add my basketball.
It's right here in front of me.
It's just floating.
Now the ball looks kind of blend at the moment in your resources folder.
I'm just on the run up in your resources folder.
There is a picture of a basketball or a texture of a basketball I should say so in X code making new
images called the ball
and your basketball texture right into it back into your view can truly set the diffuse equal to your
ball.
Instead let me just run the see how that looks.
Trying to tuck a horizontal surface it just started talking once your real orange and loaded loaded
your court now your ball and there is are about skiable it looks pretty darn cool.
Now how do we actually launched this ball towards the net.
To launch something we need to apply a force on it to apply a force on the Snoad it needs to be a physics
body.
So back to your controller
right here.
Right.
Body is equal to c in physics body
the type will be dynamic dynamic simply means that the body will be affected by forces like gravity
and other applied forces.
And as for the shape.
Right.
See C and physics shape
and it will have the shape of a ball.
So the node will simply be our ball
and we don't need any options.
Now give our ball node this physics body by writing ball the physics body is equal to body.
Now that the node has a physics body we can apply a force to it.
And before I go into any of this if you're confused by physics bodies in any way make sure to visit
the vehicle section of this course we covered them very Thorley.
Anyway now we need to apply a force on our ball to do that simply right ball physics body apply force.
The first argument is the direction the direction at which we're going to launch the ball the direction
in which we're going to launch the ball is simply the direction the film is facing.
So the orientation of the phone.
So just right as CN vectors 3
orientation dot X orientation dot Y and orientation dot said and such as impulse to true if as impulse
is set to true the ball accelerates immediately which is exactly what we want as soon as we touch the
screen.
We want the ball to be launched immediately.
Whenever you're launching projectiles like we are right now we're launching the ball.
We need this to be true to simulate an instantaneous effect.
So run up
trying to attack the horizontal surface to start detecting very soon.
There we go once in your court.
If I tap the screen it should launch the ball it launches it but it launches it at a very small force
at this rate.
The ball will never reach the hoop unless I get really close.
And it still doesn't reach it.
So what if I wanted the force being applied on the ball to be much more powerful just make it variable
var power of type float is equal to 1.0.
And now inside of touch is begin where we are launching the ball.
I mean just do it right here actually right here self up power is equal to 10 and now multiply every
single direction in which the force is being applied by the power.
So time's power in this case by ten than the force being applied on the ball will be ten times more
powerful in every direction that it's being launched.
So let me just do it.
Time is power right here as well and run the app
trying to detect the horizontal surface once it starts detecting it and your CT shoot your ball
can't.
Let me just try and aim better.
And the ball reaches the net.
However it doesn't bounce off of it.
The reason being is that right now the hoop and the buckboard are just weightless hollow nodes.
We need to give them a physics body so that they can interact with the ball.
So back to your view controller inside of basket.
Right.
Baskett node does physics body is equal to a C in physics body that's static.
We've used static before.
Basically it means that the basket node can collide with other physical bodies but it will not be affected
by forces like gravity or applied forces it will stay in its place which is exactly what we need.
We need our back porch to stay in one place.
We don't want it moving around.
So run the up
start detecting some surfaces as soon as your warlord's and load's detecting.
Now if I try and shoot the ball that means aim really well at about board.
If I shoot it bounces off but the ball can never actually go in.
And the reason being is that air kit at the moment is not able to recognize the detail in the basket.
Node such that this Taurus right here has a hole.
It treats the whole as another shape but a hole is hollow.
It shouldn't be a shape.
So objects like our ball are able to interact and collide with the hole when they should simply just
be going through it.
So back to the view controller instead of putting static expand the argument for C and physics body
and the type of the body will still be a static body.
We still don't want it to be affected by external forces.
And for the shape just put a C in physics shape the node will simply be our basket node.
And as for the option right as you see in physics shape that option.
Keep ask compound is equal to true.
I've explained this one before.
This should be a colon not an equal sign.
Anyway I've explained this before by putting this archaic treat separate geometries separate shapes
and joins them to make the resulting shape.
So we'll treat the box in Taurus as separate shapes.
The default value is true.
So it doesn't matter if you put this or not.
I just thought it was good for review.
I mean just fix the error whatever it is.
Now here's the important part.
Put us in physics shape option.
Type will equal an S C and physics shape.
Does shape type concave polyhedron.
This option provides the highest level of detail.
It can detect precise collision behavior.
So now Eric KITT can recognize the finest detail in our basket node such that the Taurus and the Taurus
has a hole and nothing can collide with the hole only with the highest level of detail.
Can a kit recognize that.
So run the app detecting some planes.
Once you've detected a plane your court now shoot the ball and he actually scored.
The balls can finally go through the hole if you think the balls are a bit too big you can change them
to whatever size you want it's up to you.
And so finally I want to do one more thing I want is that the longer I tap on the screen the more powerful
the shot gets into Google.
Right on to Google Chrome right.
Each get hub timer.
The second thing is what you need where it says each timer click on the page and scroll down right here
to install the framework you'll see that it requires cocoa pods and if you still don't have cocoa pods
installed.
Go to Cocoa pods dark and copy this pseudo gem command right into your terminal press command space
and do a spotlight search terminal.
Press enter and just copy this right here.
Press enter.
Put your computer password and all that.
I'm not going to reinstall cocoa pods because I already have it installed but if you don't make sure
to put your password in then press enter.
So I'm going to cancel this command by pressing control X and once you're done installing cocoa pods
navigate to your project's directory by writing CD.
Drag your project right on to here.
Hoops and now that we are in the projects directory We want to initialize a pod file so right pod and
net and now that we initialized a pod file access to your part file by writing and notepad file and
right here we want to install our pod so you'll find the pod we need to install right here part each.
Make sure to copy and paste what you have in front of you.
Copy rights into your part file press control access to exit press the Wike you to save and POD install
to install your pod.
So once you're finished installing the pods close your X code project and now make sure to open up the
workspace not the project just resize this.
OK now into our view controller
import each.
If I just build the code this error should go away.
Since I'm sure that we installed each pod
so everything works out fine.
And before I do anything all of this logic put inside of a function so make a new function func shoot
ball with no argument and no return value and just copy all this logic right here and remove all of
this
first off the Klare a timer var timer is equal to each 0.05 seconds.
Let me just make this a constant instead.
We're not going to be modifying it.
And so this timer once we activate it is going to trigger a block of code every 0.05 seconds and to
trigger a block of code just right timer perform.
And inside of it.
Right.
Self power plus equals one.
So as soon as you touch the screen the timer will start.
Let's try to then 1.0 to get rid of this error.
So as I was saying and it's Tell me that the plus equal binary operator cannot be applied with a float.
So let me just make this an integer instead.
And we should be good to go so soon as you touch the screen this time or we'll start and it will trigger
this block of code once every 0.05 seconds.
So our power variable will increase by one every 0.05 seconds.
So if you touch the screen for an entire second the power variable will equal 120 so the power of the
shot will be and times more powerful.
Finally just return does continue.
So we want this block of code to keep getting activated and as soon as touch is and it gets triggered.
So as soon as you release your fingers from the screen if there is a basketball court if self-taught
basket it is equal to true stop the timer self timer stop and shoot the ball.
Self don't shoot ball.
And at the very end set the power right back to one so that it restarts.
Finally when the view controller DNA realizes stop the timer as well.
Self timer stop.
We only have one view controller so our view controller will never be initialized and DNA will never
get called.
But I'm just going to leave this there as a reference.
If you do end up using this part in the future.
So before I run up I've noticed that the ball is a bit too big.
Let me just change its size to about zero point to five meters and run the up and the build fails because
I cannot multiply an integer by a float.
So you know what let me just convert this back to a float.
And we don't need the plus equals operator.
Just make this equal to self-taught power plus one.
This is the exact same thing as before.
It's just that it's not letting us use the plus equal binary operator.
And now we should be get to go run the app going to wait till the world origin loads should have loaded
by now.
Let me just detect some surfaces and your basketball court.
Now if I shoot the ball nothing gets triggered and that's because touches and it never gets triggered.
The reason being the top gesture recognizer interferes with the touch is functions that we override
to fix that just right.
Top right here.
Tap josher recognizer cancels touches and view is equal to false.
So this is true.
Touches ended is considered a pending gesture and any pending gestures are canceled through retouches
cancelled function by setting this to false.
The touches ended function will not be cancelled and the view will receive every touch gesture and a
multi-touch sequence.
So touches end and will get sugared and our ball will be shot and before running the app let me just
remove this hard coded self-talk power and we should be good to go.
Run it.
Going to wait till the world orange and loads once it loads.
I'm going to add my surface.
I mean my basketball court.
They seem to have thrown a basketball too early.
But let me just take a shot right now.
If I hold the screen for a really long time the ball should go at a massive speed this is really strong.
If I simply just tappet it's pretty low and if I just hold it for a little bit that is a fair shot.
OK so there's three more books.
The first one as soon as I tap the place the basketball court a ball gets placed right after.
So let's focus on this book first and that's because as soon as you touch the screen both touches begin
and touches ended as well as handle top.
All of them get triggered.
Hendel top as your basketball court which makes this computed property equal to true.
And since this is true your ball is added.
So instead of this being a computed property make it a simple Boole's value equal to false
and so only once you add your basketball court
set Baskett added equal to true only after 0.2 seconds or some small number like.
So dispatch cue up Main.
A sync after that.
Now Plus 0.2 and after 0.2 seconds Foskett added equal to half true.
So here is what would happen.
Haendel top would get triggered as your basket then touches began and touches ended would get triggered.
This would be false only up until 0.2 seconds but this would have already gone triggered and nothing
would happen.
The ball wouldn't get shot.
This is false.
So one more thing we want to add.
Only if there isn't a basketball court already added then.
A basketball court.
So if Baskett is equal to false then a basketball court.
Otherwise do nothing.
OK one more thing I want to do.
Every time I shoot the ball it just clutters more and more balls into the scene view we want to make
sure that as soon as we shoot a ball it removes every single other ball from the scene view.
So here is what you would do.
Make a function phunk remove every other ball
and just do self seen view seen root node.
Numerous child notes.
First argument.
Note we don't care about the second argument and just student Noad dot removed from parent node.
Now be careful the basketball court is also a child of the scene views root node.
So here is how I would fix this.
Every ball you shoot.
Give it a name of basketball.
So where it says shoot ball when we're declaring the ball right.
Ball.
Name and set the name equal to basketball.
And now if no name is equal to basketball
then remove that from the parent node.
Now right before we shoot our ball.
Make sure to remove every other ball.
It's as simple as the run up can't wait till the world origin loads tucked a surface right now.
Your basketball court.
OK.
Notice that a ball was not added as you are your court and now every time I shoot a ball
it removes the ball that was previously shot.
Now I can actually control how far the ball bounces back from the back board back to the controller.
Just set body that restitution is equal to 0.2.
So here is how this works.
Restitution controls the energy that's lost when two objects collide.
If the value is 1 then the basketball is not going to lose any energy when it collides with the back
board.
So it's going to bounce back at the same speed that it collided with the buckboard.
If the value is 0 then the ball is going to lose all of its kinetic energy as soon as it collides with
the buckboard and it's going to bounce back at a really low speed.
So if we set it to zero point two the ball is not going to lose all of its energy.
It's going to lose most of its kinetic energy and is going to bounce back at a pretty low speed.
Let's run the app to see this in action.
Wait till the world origin loads are detecting a surface.
Put your basketball court and if you shoot the ball the ball balances out a pretty good speed.
This is a very realistic bounce and that's it for the basketball up.
This is one of the cooler ups.
You learned how to apply forces on nodes and have them collide with other objects in the next section
we're going to look into collisions by making our final op the shooter up.
I'll see you there.