In this video you're going to learn how to use a 3D model.
So instead of a box we're going to make it into a jelly fish.
So I'm going to take you through how to download a 3-D model so the site I get 3D models from as Turbo's
dot com.
This Web site sells 3-D models and gives some of them up for free.
We're going to get one of the three 3-D models.
So first you have to make an account with them.
I'm already logged in as myself.
And once you do make an account type jellyfish
the a DA is the file format that 3-D models come in and you file.
And right here is the free 3-D model that we are going to use.
It's the jellyfish from SpongeBob.
So click on it.
This freedom model is free.
So download it
close this check the box and press download
once you're done downloading it show it in the Finder
unlock the zip file and into your folder.
We want the file.
So we're going to drag this to ex-coach But first opening up our project which was whack a jellyfish.
Minimize the project and find the folder where we set our EDAC file drag this DNG file into our tax
code right here.
Press finish expand the project back and this is the file that we're going to use to modify our jellyfish.
So this is basically the storyboard for 3D models.
This is where we can modify our models.
So if you click on this button right here it shows us everything that we have in our scene.
So the model has been given a virtual camera.
This is something you would use just for a Simca.
We have our own camera with a kids so we don't need this.
Make sure to delete it.
The blue and area are simply extra lighting that we don't need.
So remove those as well.
All right.
Now it's important to note that this is a node with a geometry of a sphere that has been modified to
look like a jellyfish.
If you click right here you can see that the jellyfish has been given a diffuse color of paint.
Remember that the fuse is the color or texture that's been spread across a surface.
So the jellyfish is spread with a color of pink.
However we've been given a diffuse texture so back into your folder right here is your texture.
Make sure to drag it into your next coat project like so create fuller references and finish spend the
project back and ferde the fuse instead of setting a color.
We're going to set the jelly fish dock PMG as the fuse.
So this texture wrapped and read its content all over the surface of the node.
And notice how the texture wrap itself around the jelly fish perfectly.
All right.
Now finally convert the DEA e-file to a scene kit format by going to editor and pressing on convert
to secret file and convert.
The reason we're doing this is because this is the recommended format to optimize ex-cult performance.
I'm going to keep the X code version and save anyway.
And now this isn't a C and file.
All right.
So a point to note that this entire thing is a sin and to be able to load this scene in our view controller
we need to have it in an asset folder.
So click on new file and scroll all the way down till you find the asset catalog which is right here.
Press on next call the asset catalog the following art dot I see and assets.
It's a point that you get the same right click create and use that as CN assets and now drag the same
file right into your assets folder like so and so now we can load the jellyfish into our scene.
So go to the controller and inside of our no comment all of the so
and then right.
Let jellyfish scene
is equal to see unseen
named and in the string navigate your sim file by writing art don't see and assets which is your assets
folder slash jellyfish
end which is your file name.
All right.
So now we have the entire jellyfish scene.
I'm just going to delete this first because it seems to be slowing down my tax code.
We want only the jellyfish inside of the scene.
And the reason why this has no specific defuse is because we moved our jellyfish does seem foul to a
new folder.
So we lost track of the texture.
So to fix that just reset the texture itself and we're good to go.
So back to the controller to convert the scene to a node just right.
Let jellyfish node is equal to jelly fish seen dot root node.
Remember that the root node is the parent node of all other nodes our jellyfish known as a child of
that root node.
So just right child node with name the name of the child of the root node is fear call the child jellyfish
and.
And back to the Wii controller it just right.
Jellyfish right here.
And recursively.
So if this is not true it will search every single node that's in the root node subtree to find the
jellyfish node.
If it's false it will search only the root node.
Immediate children the jellyfish node is an immediate child of the root node.
So certain defaults we don't need to search every single node in the whole subtree OK now placed the
jellyfish right in front of us by writing jellyfish node.
The position is equal to a C and vector 3 horizontally and vertically aligned to the origin and one
metre away from the side access behind it.
And the jellyfish know that the seam view by writing self seen view does seen the root node on actual
node jellyfish node.
So now instead of a box we should get a jellyfish right in front of us.
So run the app and it's failing because the jellyfish node is an optional type.
The reason it's an optional type is because X code doesn't know for sure that the string you put is
an actual node.
So we know for sure that this is an actual node since we named it ourselves.
So just forcefully unwrap it and we should be good to go run the press play and it looks like the jellyfish
node is right behind this well the jellyfish is not actually behind us.
It's just that it's oriented the wrong way and the jellyfish itself is way too big.
So in our scene file we need to fix the orientation of the jellyfish sex which way it's facing.
So click on perspective and onto the front.
So if the jellyfish is in front of us according to this we would only be able to see its head.
We want to be able to see the entire jellyfish when it's in front of us.
So to do that we need to rotate the jellyfish 90 degrees vertically.
So remember Royler angles we use them in letra seven of the getting started section.
So if we rotate the jellyfish 90 degrees across the X-axis it will rotate vertically so just right 90
so it rotates vertically.
But the other direction.
So instead of 90 degrees put it back to zero and make sure you rotate it 90 degrees the other direction
by writing negative nine.
All right so now we can properly see the jelly fish when it's in front of us.
We were able to rotate it 90 degrees vertically around the x axis in the other direction by putting
the negative value.
If you're unfamiliar with Euler angles make sure to revisit the getting started section in lecture 7.
All right so now the orientation is good but the size of the jellyfish.
If you remember from when we were in the UP is still way too big the size is actually two point three
times one.
So two point three meters wide two point two meters long and has a depth of three meters.
So this jellyfish is basically the size of a smaller room.
So if you multiply all of these dimensions by point one so point one for the X point one for the Y.
This is kind of hard to click on
one for the Y and point one for the Zad.
Now we get dimensions of zero point two or three meters zero point two two meters for height and zero
point three four meters for that depth.
Since this is multiplied by the scale that we give it and this is a very fair size.
Also if you find it hard to click on these fields I'm using ex-coach nine data.
So for me this might not be a problem but if it is just right click on the fields that study highlights
and then left click to modify the field.
All right so now we can run the press play.
OK so the jelly fish is oriented the right way and it has the perfect size.
Notice how perfectly the texture wrap around our node.
This is looking really good.
We finally know how to load 3D models in the next video we're going to add animations to the jellyfish.