This video we're going to start measuring distances First off make a variable starting position of type.
I see a node and as soon as we add our sphere know to the scene view set the starting position equal
to the sphere node.
Now inherit from a R-S.C. entry delegate when you inherit from SDN if you delegate you can access the
function render a data type.
This elegant like you delegate We used for the physics simulations and the last section also gets called
once per frim.
And since I received a few session runs that 60 frames per second this function will get triggered at
60 frames per second as well.
Now so far we've looked at three delegate functions will run your scene.
We used in the drawing up which makes sense since Wilborn nursing is made specifically for custom drawing.
We also looked at did simulate physics.
So in our vehicle up did simulate physics is made specifically for physical simulations.
In our case the car was a physics body.
However now we're not doing any physics simulations which is why we're using this function only to perform
updates on our labels at 60 frames per second.
So this function like the two other delegate functions is a rendering loop.
It's always getting triggered 60 times a second one it's getting triggered.
We want to update the labels as distance traveled by the phone relative to the starting position.
So guard let starting position is equal to the imagery spell the starting position is equal to self
starting position or else return.
So basically only if the user top on the scene view and added a starting position then proceed with
whatever we're about to do.
Now we need the current position of the camera's point of view.
We already did that in the last tutorial.
We concluded that the camera's point of view is located 0.1 metres away from the film's current position.
This time try to get the current location of the camera's point of view by doing it the same way we
did it in the drawing up paused the video and give it a try.
So what you would do first is get the point of view of the scene view by writing guard let point of
view is equal to self the scene view point of view the point of view as you remember from before has
the current orientation and location of the phone's camera view its point of view.
We only care about the location and I seem to have an error because I forgot to put the else return
clause.
Now the location and orientation are encoded in the transform matrix.
So right transform is equal to a point of view Daut transform.
Now to access the location make it equal to SDN vector 3 and the location for the X field is located
in column for a 1 Sarette transform dot and for one the location for the Y field is in column 4 to Sarette
transform that and for 2 and the location for the Zad field is in column 4 of 3.
Now if I subtract the current location of the camera's point of view by the starting location I should
get the distance traveled by the phone in meters.
So let x distance the horizontal distance traveled is equal to location X minus starting position dot
position x.
Let me just make this a constant since this is a bit annoying.
Now back to here let y distance the vertical distance traveled equal to location Y minus starting position
dot position dot Y and finally is that distance how far or how close you are from the starting position.
The depth Zad distance is equal to location Zad minus starting position dot position data.
Now set each label equal to its respective distance traveled self-taught.
Actually I will not text is equal to the string value of x distance self-doubt y label that taxed is
equal to the string value of r y distance and self-doubting Zed label.
That text is equal to the string value of the XY distance
before we were in the OP.
Make sure to set the scene views delegate self in order for the delegate function to get triggered.
Run the app
place your starting position
move away from it and nothing happens because we are updating our labels on a background thread.
Anything in this delegate function happens in the background.
So make sure to update your labels on the main.
Copy and paste all of this code right into your dispatch.
Up main.
Rerun the up
top the screen for your starting position.
Move away from it and it's measuring the distance.
This is really cool.
But there are way too many decimal places.
It doesn't look that great.
So back into your controller take all of this off
we want a string with a format of two decimal places.
So write string
with a format of percent point to f..
So what this will do is from a float value.
So from these float values it's going to use only two decimal places.
Point to and the float value will be the distance itself.
So x distance
and do the same thing for every other label except here it will be the wind distance and the distance
to each label we're going to add the letter M to indicate ammeters
rerun the up
so place your starting position.
If I move away from it way over here I just move 0.2 meters to the right of the starting position.
0.1 meters above 10 centimeters above in 0.22 meters are 0.1 three meters or something behind the starting
position.
So now I need it so that when I'm done measuring If I tap on the scene view again it should stop measuring
the distance itself thus starting position is not equal to nil they remove the starting position from
the scene view or remove it from the parent node remove from parent node and set it to nil
and returned.
So if I tap on the scene view and there is already starting position remove the starting position and
set it to nil.
And now since the starting position is nil this guard statement is going to fail.
It's going to return and it's not going to measure the distance anymore.
So run the up
place your starting position.
If I move away from it and then stop here it stops measuring.
And in the position that we stopped we traveled 0.3 seven metres to the right point two or three metres
above and point one three metres in the front of the starting position.
Now what if I were to measure this couch if I put my strt note at the bottom left of the coach and move
to the left of our starting position and from the bottom to the top
I can conclude that the couch is 0.9 three metres wide.
Since we traveled 0.9 three meters to the left of our starting position according to the y value the
couch is also 0.8 two metres high.
I can also conclude from the Zad value the couch is 1.4 metres long.
At one point four meters deep.
So if I tap the screen right here in place my starting position and then I'll walk a certain distance
diagonally.
Then I reach top the screen to stop the measuring according to this I moved the 1.9 six meters in the
horizontal to the left of my starting position about zero meters in the vertical which makes sense since
I'm not flying and away from my starting position I move zero point zero three metres.
Now how do I get the diagonal distance that I traveled.
Well it's simple.
This function right here is in your resources folder.
You probably saw this function in grade 9 math.
This is just the Pythagorean theorem.
If you're not familiar with the Pythagorean theorem don't worry just know that by combining the square
of all the distances which form the diagonal distance in our case the X Y and Z distance and then get
the square root.
We can get the diagonal distance traveled.
So inside of a big time set the distance.
So self-taught distance label dot text is equal to the return value of our distance function.
And you know what these names actually coincide with each other.
So let me just read this to distance traveled and Studd
self-direct distance label that text is equal to self-direct distance traveled the x value is simply
x distance your y distance near that distance.
And we want as we get a distance to only two decimal places.
So copy this right here please your distance traveled as your flow Velia rerun the up way till the real
origin.
Once it loads top on your scene view.
And if I walk this way top on the scene you go again to stop measuring I logged 0.1 8 meters in the
horizontal and about 2.2 9 meters behind the starting position which ultimately combined in me walking
a total distance of 2.3 metres and that's it for the measurement up.
You learn how to work better with matrices ultimately making the measurement up
in the next section we're going to make a virtual portal.