In this video we're going to add some more planets to the solar system and position them all are relative
to the sun.
So in the solar system scope website that we looked at in the last video download this texture for the
sun.
Once you download it show it in the Finder and the dear ex-coach project in the assets folder make a
new image assets called Sun
diffuse the sun the fuse image to your X code project right into your assets folder and back to your
view controller not us file in view did appear less sun less sun is equal to C.A. with a geometry of
an SDN sphere since a sun has its physical shape and give it a radius of zero point three five meters.
I found that to be a good default radius.
So remember that the is the color or texture spread across the surface of the sphere.
We're going to give the sphere of the sun texture.
So right so in geometry darf first material that diffused content's is equal to Sun diffuse.
So this image of the sun to fuse is going to wrap itself around the sphere so that the sphere can look
like the sun position the sun relative to the world origin one metre away from it by writing sun position
is equal to seeing that two or three leave it horizontally and vertically aligned with X and Y axis
of the origin and position at 1 metres away behind it to the seam view by writing self does scene view
thus seen a route know that dot child node the sign.
Now there is one problem.
The sun is going to be the central node in the solar system.
So all the other planets have to be positioned relative to the sun.
So instead of positioning earth relative to the scene view position relative to the sun by removing
this line of code in bright sun dot our child no old earth.
So now the earth is positioned relative to the sun one metre away behind the sun.
However instead of positioning it one metres behind the axis of the sun we're going to position the
earth one point two metres to the right of the sun since that will be easier to work with when we run
the up remove the earth's animation for now.
We're going to go into animation in more depth in the next video.
Run the way for the rural origin to load and everything to stabilize and right here is our son.
The image wrapped around the sphere perfectly the diffuse image.
And if I move around it to the right.
Right here is the earth is one point two meters to the right of the sun.
Now before I had the next planet back into your next project noticed that here every time you want to
declare a planet you have to write all of these lines of code.
Now imagine if you wanted to add the entire solar system that would become about 70 lines of code of
the same repetition.
So to avoid this mess make a planet function which has the argument geometry of type I see geometry
and argument the use of type II image specular as well emission
and the normal texture and it's also going to have a argument to know how it's position relative to
the sun or the scene view and what the distance is and have a return value.
I see no such that dysfunction is going to make every planet for us and we're just going to call it
in if you did appear.
So instead of writing all this remove equals to see a node instead left earth is equal to planets with
the geometry that we do that for the diffuse will remain the same Earth Day.
The specular as Earth specular respectively.
You mention earth.
You mention the normal Earth normal and its physicians at one point two metres away from the sun.
So as an actor three one point two metres to the right and I right now delete all of this code and noticed
how much cleaner everything else.
Now we need to make the snow in the planet function.
So inside the function declare a planet no less planet is he called to see a node with a geometry of
the geometry that we give it and planet geometry of first material dark diffuse dark content's is simply
going to be called the diffuse that we get it do the same thing for the specular value.
So replace the fuse with specular copy and paste stuff for the machine as well.
And lastly for the normal copy paste this and normal instead of the emission.
And lastly for the position right planet top position is equal to the position that we give it.
And so we have just returned the planets.
So now right here we're passing all of the info we need to the planet function.
It makes the planet for us and passes it back.
This is much cleaner.
Now instead of writing out all those lines of code I can just say let Venus is equal to planets with
a geometry.
Venus is going to equal a geometry of an S C sphere with a radius of zero point 1.
Since Venus is smaller than Earth and we don't have any images for it so go back to the solar system
scope website and right here we have the surface of Venus as well as the atmosphere down low.
Both of them show them in the Finder.
Now back to X code into your assets make two new image assets called Venus
surface
and Venus.
Mr. and the atmosphere and surface to the respective assets folders
and you know what.
Before making our Venus planet we are going to just stick with the Earth planet for now and run the
app to see if the planet function worked work without any bugs so it rang me up.
So right here is our sign and to your right should be the earth.
So everything is the same as before.
There are no bugs and it's always a good habit to run the app every time you do something to make sure
that you're not building on top of erroneous code.
So back to the ex-coach project we were making the Venus planet and we added to our assets folder to
images the atmosphere and the surface.
Now to finish our constructor your challenge is to get the surface and atmosphere in one of these values
paused the video and give it a try.
So the fuse is when you want to cover the surface of the sphere where the texture we don't want to cover
the surface with the atmosphere.
We want to add the atmosphere on top of the surface not cover the surface.
However we do want to cover the surface of the node with the venous surface texture so that is I refuse
specular we don't have any textures that control the lighting.
In this scenario.
So leave that as no.
And for this to accept a null value we need to make this argument an optional type.
And do the same thing for any mission.
And normal since not all planets will have any mission and normal texture.
So the mission will be our atmosphere.
The reason being if you remember the mission is when you're emitting something on top of the surface
and the last video we emitted clouds on top of the earth's surface.
Now were you made it an atmosphere on top of Venus surface So Venus atmosphere and we don't have any
textures controlling the geometrical shape of each point in the texture so I leave that as No.
And as for the mission we are going to position Venus zero point seven meters to the right of the sun.
So it's that it's vertically aligned with the sun and 0 meters away from these that axis to position
Venus relative to the sun just right.
Sun does child know Venus and run the so just wait for the world origin to load and right here is Venus.
Notice how detail the atmosphere is right behind it is our Earth in the next video we're going to apply
a relative rotation to these planets.