In the last video you were able to cover the portal room with images creating the illusion that the
user is going inside of the new world.
In this video we need to make the walls invisible from the outside.
We need to make them translucent.
We need to mask them enough with the synonyms.
Entire file We're going to start off by masking all of these walls.
So start with side door B SO side door B give it a child know of a box.
So drag this box right under side Dorby and give this box the exact dimensions as its parent.
So side door B has it with a point seven five a height of two and a length of 0.03.
So do the same thing for the box.
A What of 0.75 a height of.
I think it was to any length a depth of zero point zero three and give this a diffuse color of black
position the box exactly where its parent node is by making this zero this zero and there's zero as
well.
And finally remove this 90 degree rotation to make it vertical.
OK.
Now we have the box covering our side door.
Now you want to place this mask just a little bit in front of our side door about zero point zero three
meters in front
and there you go.
Now the mask is officially in front of either side door.
Do the same thing for side door and drag a box right under it and give the box the exact same dimensions
as a side door which is again point seven five meters wide two meters high and zero point zero three
meters deep.
So 0.75 two meters high and zero point zero three meters deep or long.
It's positioned exactly where the door is already.
It's not rotated in any way which is perfect.
Now just place that zero point zero three meters in front of either side door to mask it and give it
a diffuse color of black as well.
You can give them any diffuse color you want.
Just make sure that the diffused color is uniform so that we can distinguish between what's a wall and
what's the mask.
We're not going to give the roof or the floor any masks.
We'll discuss that later.
The back wall is going to have a mass so I add another box right under your back wall and we just try
and get it to be a child of the back wall shouldn't be that hard.
There you go.
The back wall has dimensions to to end point is there are three do the same thing for the box to two
and 0.03 position exactly where our wall is which it already is and zero point zero or three metres
behind the back wall so that it covers it.
OK.
Now just make this black
and this didn't work out because it's not behind the back wall it's in front of it.
Make sure it's behind it by reading negative 0.03.
There you go.
Now we just have our sidewalls.
So two boxes here as well want the sidewall eight and we'll go one box at a time.
This box will have the same dimensions as this wall.
So two two and zero point zero three for the length give it a diffused color of black.
Now place this mask also in front of our sidewall 0.03 meters in front of it.
And do the same thing for this one.
First match its walls dimensions.
So two meters wide is really hard to click on two metres high
and the length will just be the same length as the wall.
0.03 give it a diffuse color of black as well and place it right in front of your sidewall.
Since the orientation is reversed for this wall put at negatived 0.03.
There you go.
Now we just covered every single part of our room with a mask instead of calling it box called mask
for every single note.
There you go.
So somehow every one of these masks has to be invisible and it has to make the wall behind it invisible
as well.
How will we do this.
First off we only added masks to the walls not to the roof or the floor.
So in the View Controller whenever we load the image for the wall in our wall load the mask of the wall
as well whether its the back wall the side of the wall load its mask by a writing flap mask is equal
to child the child being a certain wall that was specified right here that child node with name remember
the mask is a child of the tool and we gave every single one of them the name.
So back into your controller the name of each mask belong to a wall is just mask and recursively is
false since the mask is an immediate child of its respective wall.
Now the whole point of this was to make the walls translucent such that I can't see them from the outside.
Remember this as a rule of thump for something to be translucent it depends heavily on rendering order.
So if I make the mask completely transparent by writing mask geometry that first material transparency
is equal to zero point 0 0 0 0 0 1.
So this mask is almost completely transparent.
Welcome back to this.
Now if I go to the portal scene and when we load this portal into the scene view everything the walls
the roof and the floor.
They're all loaded.
They're all rendered at the same time.
Since the rendering order of every single one of these nodes is 0.
So if I put the rendering order of every single wall to be a crazy number like 200.
So child rendering order remember child is simply any wall that has been specified right here.
So child rendering order is equal to 200.
The mask which has a default rendering order of 0 is going to be rendered way before the walls will
since nodes with smaller rendering orders are rendered first.
So the walls will be rendered a way after the massacres.
Why is this important.
While the mask is basically completely transparent it's translucent and the walls are opaque.
Remember this as a rule of thumb.
If a translucent object is rendered first such that it's in front of an opaque object.
Their colors will be mixed so the color of the mask and the color of the walls now are going to be mixed.
And since the mask is extremely translucent almost transparent and by mixing the color of the walls
with the mask the walls are also going to be extremely transparent.
You'll be able to see right through them to the point that they're almost invisible.
So run the UP
WAIT TILL THE WORLD origin loads as soon as it loads the.
The horizontal surface.
Place your portal on that surface.
There is our portal and you can barely see the walls anymore.
In fact they're invisible.
However you can still see the roof and the floor
and this makes sense since we did not add a mask to the roof or the floor.
Well we don't really need to the roof and the floor are already surrounded by all of these masks so
we don't need to give them their own mask.
So all we have to do is in the View Controller mummer the rule of thumb up if an opaque object is behind
a translucent object and is rendered after it then the colors will mix.
So the roof and the floor are already behind all of these masks.
So all you have to do now is make sure that they're rendered after the masks by giving the floor and
the ceiling a rendering order of 200.
So child rendering order is equal to 200.
Why would this work.
Well remember the rule if we render this after the masks are rendered then both of their colors will
mix and since the mask is extremely transparent this will make the roof and the floor extremely transparent
as well.
And we're finally done the app run
wait till the world origin loads once it loads start detecting a surface.
Place your portal on this surface.
And this portal looks pretty great.
It really does look like a real life and one dimensional portal
and it really does feel like that I'm going inside of a new world.
There are many possibilities with the portal.
You could make this world into anything you want as long as you have the proper cube map to cover every
part of the room.
Next up we're making is the basketball up which is just as awesome as this one.
We'll make it in the next section.