In the last video we set up the user interface of our up.
Now it's time to start placing items on horizontal surfaces.
First off I placed these 3D models in your resources folder.
If you don't know how to download or use 3D models make sure you visit lecture two of the 3D models
section of this course before proceeding with this video anyway into your school project.
Make sure to drag this folder create folder references and press vinous.
Now your first challenge is to apply what you learned in lecture 2 of the 3D model section and fix the
orientation of these models as the video and give it a try.
Now that you've tried it I'm going to start with the boxing bag.
So click on perspective and we want to see how the boxing bag looks like when it's in front of us.
So from this you can conclude that when the boxing bag is in front of us you can only see the bottom
of it.
We need to rotate the bag 90 degrees such that it's in front of us vertically.
So click on the boxing bag and go to the node inspector and rotate it 90 degrees in the field to get
a horizontal rotation so right 90 it's vertical but it's facing the wrong direction it's upside down.
So instead of rotating it at 90 degrees towards us rotate it 90 degrees in the other direction by putting
in negative.
Now things still look a little bit off and the reason is that the boxing bag is made up of four cylinders
one cylinder on top and three on the bottom.
We need to rotate the bottom cylinders as well by negative 90 to keep things consistent.
So start with this one and instead of zero.
Put negative 90 do the same thing for the second cylinder.
This is the inner cylinder of the bottom.
And this is also another cylinder that's on the bottom so make sure to rotate that by negative 90 degrees
and things are looking good.
Now it's important to note that I didn't purposely mess up the orientation of this boxing bag for this
lesson.
Whenever you download a 3D model.
More often than not it's going to be disoriented.
So now to fix the girl on the front perspective to see how the cup looks like when it's in front of
us and the cup looks good it oriented the right way.
Now to try the table click on the front respective and the table top is pointing towards us.
Go to the table.
No inspector.
And it looks like the tables are already rotated 9 degrees and fire remove this 90 degree rotation.
Everything should look fine.
I mean these reinsertion that OK and the table is now oriented the right way.
Now for the vase.
Click on the front perspective of the vase to see how it looks like in front of us and it looks like
the top of the vase is what shows up when it's in front of us.
So go to the node inspector and notice that it's rotated 90 degrees.
Change that to zero remove the rotation and everything works fine.
If this ever happens to us that DeMeo just disappears.
Just click on the title and it should pop up in front of me and notice that now it's oriented the right
way.
Now we can place these models on a horizontal surface.
Back to the Wii controller we need to be able to detect horizontal surfaces simply by writing self configuration.
The plane detection is equal to horizontal
and place starting with loads of started before the the session running before proceeding with this
video.
I'm going to rerun the finished version of the app so first I need to detect a horizontal surface when
there is a lot of feature points for me around the surface like right now.
You just detected a horizontal surface tap on it and the item shows up to our controller.
We need to detect when to use your taps on the horizontal surface.
We need a tap gesture recognized so declare a function func register gesture recognizers with no argument
type and no return on inside of it.
The Clarie top just recognizers lap top gesture recognizer is equal to you typed up gesture recognizer
with target itself and the action.
As I explained before is simply when you tap on something.
What function gets triggered.
Make a function taps on taps with no argument and no return value and set that as the action by writing
selector to now selector is an objective argument.
So just expose top to Objective C by clicking on the air and clicking on effects and the function is
not exposed to Objective-C at the top just to recognize her to the scene to you by writing self does
that add just the recognizer tab gesture recognition.
Now whenever you touch on the scene view this function gets called.
Put a print statement of taps on the scene you make sure you register the gesture recognizers into that
load and run the.
So whenever I tap on the scene view the function gets called and it prints out the scene view.
This is working out pretty well.
Now I need it such that only a fight on a horizontal plane like this for it should print top a horizontal
plane.
So back to X code.
Delete this print statement and as we've seen before in a previous lecture at the top just the recognizer
sends its auction top.
In this case information on what was tapped it sends that information in the form of a sender of type
you tap just a recognizer.
First off we know that this seems top down is an aortic Simkins you're so right.
Less is equal to sender dot viewed as a Arcade's seen it.
Now we need to know where the user tapped in the scene view.
So right like top location is equal to sender that location in the scene you know we need to know if
the location in which the user tapped matches the location of a horizontal plane to do that.
Remember his tests were about to use them again.
So right like head test is equal to seen you hit test.
The point that we're testing is where you tapped the top location.
And these types will be existing or not existing plane using extents.
What this line of code does is it checks if the location where you tapped matches the location of a
plane a horizontal surface.
If it does the hit task array is going to have results.
One element of results is the location you touched doesn't match data.
The horizontal surface then this test will be empty.
So if the test array is not empty if test is empty and make sure to add the exclamation mark since the
exclamation mark makes it such that if you hit us or right is not empty then print touched the horizontal
surface touched a horizontal surface.
However if the array is indeed empty and you didn't touch a horizontal surface just print no match run
the app to see if this works.
I'm going to wait till my device recognizes its environment and fire point my phone to the floor and
wait till it be time for work.
On the surface I think I just did because of all the feature points.
And then if I tap it it should say touch a horizontal surface.
Now if I point it anywhere and see you I'm not typing on a horizontal surface so it should say you know
this works perfectly.
Now what I need is just that if I select a certain item like the cup and tap on a horizontal surface
it should display that in X code declare a function item.
So func item where the argument had test results
of type they are test results
for some reason my autocomplete doesn't work with no return value.
Call this function whenever you tap on a horizontal surface.
So when we hit test array is not empty.
So right here call self dot an item in array.
Here we have to put our result.
So when the top location the place where you tapped matches with a horizontal surface it's going to
give this head test array one element of results such that it's the first element to access that element
of results just right.
Hit test does first start it's unwrapped.
Delete these print statements.
We don't need them anymore.
They were just for demonstration purposes.
Now in item we need to load the scene of the item that we want to place so the entire scene of the vase
for example to do the right let's see is equal to c and c namely to access the name of the scene you
have to start with the folder.
So right model dot C and assets.
Now how do we know which item to go to.
Well it's based on which item the user selected.
So first make sure that these strings match exactly your file names in terms of spelling.
In my case they do match.
You'll see quite a bit make a variable var selected item
of type optional string and in that select set the selected item equal to whatever the user selected.
So self selected item is equal to items array index.
Dara and inside of an item if selected item is equal to self selected item.
So if the user did select an item to place if the selected item variable is not know then navigate to
the scene which has that item.
So slash selected item.
I see.
So if I selected the item boxing it would go to model SDN assets and then to boxing s.c.i.
And so from the scene we need to extract our note.
So if I choose Vai's it would get the Vaizey seen.
Now I need to get the vase.
No that's inside of the see the vase is a child of the root node.
So in the Wii controller or right node is equal to the root node child node and the child know what
we want is what we select so selected make sure that the elements in your items Uren match your child
notes.
For example make sure that the child no Vinnies is spelled exactly the way this is spelled.
Otherwise if I did let's say an extra e here and that was the selected item the name wouldn't match
any of the child nodes and you wouldn't get any results.
So it's really important that these names match with your child node so veins should be spelled exactly
as Vai's and table is called and exactly as table is right here.
So let's remove that and set recursively false.
Remember that if recursively is true it checks the entire subtree of the root node.
So basically that child of the child of a child of the root node etc..
Whereas if it's false it only checks for the immediate children of the Rowton album.
All these nodes so vains Cup are boxing are immediate children of their respective scenes rutin up.
So we don't need to check the whole subthread so leave this as false.
Now how do I position the items such that it's exactly on top of the horizontal surface.
Well the hit test result has a transform matrix.
We looked at transfer matrices when we did the drawing up to get the transform right.
Let transform let transform is equal to it.
Test results that world transform just like the other transform matrix we used before.
This one also encodes information inside of columns and wraps.
However this transformed matrix in particular encodes the position of a detected surface in the third
column.
That's exactly what we want.
The position of the horizontal surface we detected.
So right left there Calo is called to transform doc columns does three.
So the third call now position the No.
Right worthy detected surface is by writing no that position is equal to a C and vector three
for the x value point third column X for the y of value as well.
Third column not Y.
And third column nonsense for these Belang.
So now the item is positioned exactly where the plane was detected.
Now that we positioned our nodes makes sure that the nodes aren't also positioned in nursing.
This could mess up the positioning overall.
For example if I go on the table scene and click on the table itself and the node inspector you'll see
that the table also has nice positions on top of what we already have in the controller.
Make sure to set everything here to zero.
We don't want any of these positions.
As for the cup.
Click on the cup and everything seems fine here.
Go to the vase.
The vase is fine as well but as for the vase.
Let me just go on the front perspective.
Now I would rather the vase to be a color of brown instead of red.
Since to me that makes a lot more sense.
Click on the material inspector and inside of the fuse instead of having it being read go with something
like Mocha
and ask for the boxing bag.
The boxing bag has many cylinders Chuck on each cylinder.
Go to the note inspector and this one has positioning as well.
Make sure this is juror and he said is 0 as well.
Do it for the other cylinder 0 and 0 0 for the third cylinder.
Do the same thing for the top cylinder.
Ok everything should work fine right now.
One more thing to note is that the boxing bag dimensions are way too big.
The height is nine years.
That is crazy.
So make sure to scale everything down to a size of 0.2 of its original scale so zero point two times
its original with your 0.2 times its original height and zero point two times its original.
Now back to the Wii controller and the island to the scene by writing self.
That scene here does seem that a root node that our child node node and finally we can run the app.
There seems to be a problem this node is an optional.
So make sure to wrap it by setting this in a parenthesis and unwrapping it like so.
Remove this question mark and run the app again.
I'm going to point my phone to the table once it recognizes it.
I will choose a cup and it shows a cup.
I will place the Vaizey right here and onto the floor.
I'm going to find a good place for the boxing bag.
Add another place for the table and there you go.
We're actually placing household items inside of our house or in this case my office in the next video
we're going to learn how to resize and rotate our items.