Hello welcome back to the course on Tablo.
In today's tutorial are we going to solve the first part of the challenge and we'll identify which of
the two regions is outperforming the other.
Specifically we will talk about measuring these three or assessing these three metrics and plotting
them on a map and in order to solve this challenge we're going to learn how to create custom geographical
regions or custom territories in Tablo.
So it's gonna be a fun story.
Let's get straight to it.
All right.
Here is Tablo.
And let's open up our dataset which is an excel file so there it is start up expansion.
And if you have a look here you'll see that indeed this is our file at the bottom we've got 150 rows
and 10 of them are the new locations of the new cities where the company opened up recently.
All right so let's proceed to solving this part a challenge.
How are we going to visualize our different sales regions.
Well first of all let's create a map will drag state onto the blank area and we will change this to
a field map as you can see here.
Now we've got the states where the company does operate so you can see that they don't operate everywhere
in the U.S. but probably in the majority of states they are present.
Now how do we even for ourselves identify how these states are broken up into those two sales regions
so how do we know which states belong to sell region one and which states big sales are going to.
Well the fastest way is to just sell the region and put it into color.
And there we go we can see that there are our two sales regions which are kind of like competing for
performers which are trying to grow faster and always is it's a way to structure a company or a startup
to split it into two parts and then see kind of put them against each other so that they strive for
the better growth and things like that.
So that's great.
And now how do we assess those metrics.
So for example one of the metrics that we're assessing is the average revenue per city.
How do we how we measure that or how do we assess it.
Well let's give it a try.
We'll take revenue and put it onto label.
Now we will change this label very quickly so we'll click here click in side to form and the liberal
may break out of 14.
So now you can see the some of the revenue for every state.
Now we can quickly change it to measure some let's change it to average So now you can see the average
revenue per state.
So what does that mean.
Well for example in Texas you can see that it's thirty seven thousand six hundred eighty one so that's
the average of all the revenues in the state of Texas for all the cities in the state of Texas.
If you go to the top you'll see that in Texas we've got at least two cities so there's Midland as dentin
and probably some more cities in Texas.
And so they all have their revenue.
And what we see here is the average of all the cities in Texas.
But what we are actually after is the average revenue for all the cities in sales region 1 and the average
revenue for all the cities in sells region to.
So actually we don't want the grouping the aggregation that just occurred.
And even if we take the averages of these averages that's not exactly what we're after.
We just want Tablo to recognize this orange territory as a separate geographical object and then aggregate
in that object.
And then also recognize the blue territories or territory as one geographical object and group or aggregate
all the cities inside that territory and aggregate over them as well.
So we just want two numbers not that mean numbers.
So how would we go about doing this.
Well this is where we are talking about creating our custom territories so basically we want table to
recognize a custom search and this is a custom target.
And in Tablo there are two ways for creating custom territories.
Today we'll look at approach number one.
All right.
So how would we do it.
Well it's actually pretty simple.
We're going to need to use a group.
Now I know we haven't spoken about groups in this course and groups are a topic that we cover often
the advanced Claassen on table but nevertheless we're going to need them now.
So I'm going to give you a quick preview of groups and you'll see how you can use them to solve this
challenge.
And if you're interested in further developing knowledge then you can always learn more about groups
in the advanced course.
All right so what we're going to do is we're going to hold on control and select all of the states that
we want to put into one of these regions.
So there they are.
And now we're going to just hold our mouse over this.
And one of them and you'll see that we've got some options here and grouping is actually this option
here which looks like a a little staple or something like that.
And the other option is View right click and you slide group and you just in case we just disliked all
dimensions.
So now we've created a group you can see the group on the left there these sales regions and states
so that's how the group was created.
That's what's included.
And if you right click it and select added group you'll see that it has two parts to it.
Now I'm not going to go into detail about groups not part of what we're focusing on right now.
We actually just want to understand the custom territories.
So in order to create the custom territory from here there's just one more step left.
All you have to do is take state out of your resolution from here and voila.
As you can see now Tablo has created two custom territories which is going to move this over here and
you can see that this is one huge custom territory which is cels region number two.
And this is huge.
And once you can see that even it's not even those noncontiguous So it's like broken down into three
bits.
Tablas recognizing it as a separate territory which is a very very powerful thing to have and the have
the average really has been calculated.
Now if you want to restore the previous callers very simple just click Edit color select here Orange
sightseer blue click OK.
There they are.
And so now you can see that that is our average revenue.
So right now are these two custom territories discussing chercher is performing better.
So region 1 is outperforming region 2.
Now we have to check the other two metrics as well.
So let's put marketing spend in here as well we'll see average by the way.
Here's a quick tip.
So instead of sort of doing this instead of dragging the label or the object the measure into the label
and then selecting from the drop down measure average which you can do to speed up the process is right
click when you're about to drag instead of left clicking right click drag it into label and right away
you're given this window where you can select is a pretty cool shortcut.
So it all allows you to save a bit of time on that one step and narrow it right away we've selected
the average marketing spend.
And finally.
So let's let's actually also put in the sales region into the label and what other thing are we wanted
the roaming right.
So we wanted the return on marketing investment which is revenue divided by marketing spend.
Let's create a calculated field.
It's going to be Roll Me and marketing spend revenue divided by marketing spend.
Click OK.
Romey put that into the label as well.
Or again this is a shortcut.
Right click putting the label average Romey And let's just tidy up this label a bit.
We're going to take sales region and put it at the top and then get rid of this and then it say average
revenue average marketing spend.
And finally average Romey and all of these should be centered.
OK.
So it's good.
So you can see right away we've got some stats already region to average revenue 38 region 1 average
revenue 40.
So a region or one is a head in that sense then in terms of marketing spend got two thousand in Region
2 and in Region 1 we got two thousand eight hundred eighty nine.
So in this sense Region 1 is ahead as well because average markets spend less it is the better.
And finally average Romey the more the better in Region 1 it's a bit better because it's $14 revenue
per dollar marketing spend in Region 2.
It's only thirteen point four.
All right so that is how we come up with these of course you can tidy these up a little bit.
So that sort of look a bit better.
So you can always change the font and size.
And for example let's just click on the label and if you can change this to let's say 12 probably will
be better and bold something that's all very really looks better than of course getting rid of the zeros.
You can also round your average marking Spens apply some calculations but when average folks are not
the main focus for today's Sterle was to how to create this custom tertiary.
And so we discussed the method for CASM territories through creating a group.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and it is a very very powerful feature that she can use in your mapping
techniques.
So definitely keep it in mind and I'll look for you next time.
Until then happy coding.