Hello and welcome back to the course on Tobler.
In today's the Tauriel we'll just take a quick look at PDAF documents and ensure that we are all on
the same page with what they are before we continue any further.
This will just be a quick and short tutorial for us to touch on the basics.
Now we all might be very familiar with PTF and it's icon now pedia of documents nobody can contain a
number of different elements.
The most common would be images text and it we know know that it's quite a static document as well.
Not the PTF format was actually conceived in 1990 and the acronym PTF actually refers to a portable
document format.
Now it's called like that.
Seeing as each records or formatting the font and images and also it's independent of the hardware or
OS.
So you are able to open it on any operating system.
Anything you need to have is a PDA reader so it's also a very nice bridge or a way for us to access
data from systems that would not have been able for us to be accessing if we didn't have the required
software installed to read such information so really handy indeed.
But enough talking.
Have a look an example.
So we've got two examples Elvia.
The first is quite a very portable matter.
So this is from the New Zealand water authority and what you'll see is this quite a lot of images and
text in there.
This is typical to a report format that you can expect.
As you can see is also signature's a table of contents a whole lot of information and text.
Not that much of data but also some graphs.
And as you can see even some tables in there.
So this is typical what you might find in a report type format.
All right.
Another top for example would be perhaps a bit more simple one way we've got some tables graphs and
then just tables worth of data to some of the characteristics of PTF documents or that these are not
idiots.
Obviously we can only read the information from here as well as that it concedes that it stores all
of the rich content as we saw in the specific example in them and it's quite helpful because we have
no idea what way in which type of system or application this graph was generated.
And if it wasn't for PTF we would not have been able to see it all in such a nice instance all grouped
together in a very nicely presented format.
Now typically you don't associate PDA with storing data for machine readable information but sometimes
they might be some cases way that like the way that happens for instance in this case over here we might
have to analyze this data and we don't have access to the source that hasn't been published in a different
format.
Furthermore you might also face instances way the delegate supply in a PDA format to ensure the data
is secured and not altered with during the process.
And that's yet another instance of when you might encounter this not tableaus been very kind.
They've added a connector in the ten point three version of tabbouleh and this allows us to easily connect
to the PTF documents as we would have done with any other fault up that we are used to like an Excel
or a C is before.
One important note however is that the document doesn't contain any meta data as we might be used to
in connecting to a sequel database.
Or we might have to do some clean up during this process.
And that's also a very important part in working with bidi of documents.
But let's have a look at our fall that will be working with in this section.
So it's the New York Boch crime statistics and we can see that if we just scroll through it it's basically
a table that the format stays the same so it shouldn't be too difficult to read in.
But we have a couple of different columns.
We've got some headers at the top and we've got some footers and some page numbers so hopefully using
Tablo will be able to import this without too much hassle and be careful also off the total line at
the bottom of the fall.
And that is of follow will be working with the next section in the next to Tauriel will actually look
at how to connect to the PTF documents herad from with into bloat and also look at some clean up procedures.
I'm looking forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.