Hello this is curial from superdad assigns dot com.
And welcome back to the course on Tablo.
So what's up with the timer you ask.
Well the thing is that I'm super excited about you taking this course.
In fact I'm so excited that I really really want you to get to the end and get the maximum value out
of this course and learn how to use tabel like a pro.
And so therefore I've challenged myself to get you enthusiastic about this course in under five minutes
and that's exactly what we're going to do today.
And I'll just give you a quick overview.
We're going to look at a massive data set.
And I will show you what you can do using the power of Tablo in a very very short limited time and I
hope that'll get you excited.
All right let's get started.
First of all we'll need a browser.
I'm going to use Chrome and at the top just type in the address bar.
You need to go to super Dahdah science dot com slash Tablo and that's where all the data sets for this
course are located.
And here you can get the one for today.
It's called the superstore Yes.
So just download that.
I'm going to save that into my Tablo coarse folder.
That's good.
And let's bring on that folder.
So there is the data set.
You don't need the browser anymore and we still have three minutes 45 seconds let's open the data set
and have a look.
So what this data center presents is a list of transactions for a store for 2015 from the start of the
year until now.
So for the first half of 2015.
And here you can see every single transaction the store has made for this year.
Akron's every transaction is represented by a row here.
So for instance the row IDs tells you the number of the transaction the discount unit price shipping
cost customarily a lot a lot of information.
And at the end here it's got the profit for this specific transaction.
So here for instance it's $4000 or minus $53 and it's also broken down in by column it says this is
all United States and we go to region state or province city.
And if you look at this data it's actually quite massive is gotte 1953 arrows.
And the question has been asked is can you quickly tell us what are the most profitable and the least
profitable States according to this data set and also plot us a map right now.
Create a map that will show us very quickly how the states are performing.
And you have to do that in a very limited time in fact in under two and a half minutes.
So let's get straight at it.
It is going to close the Excel spreadsheet here close this folder and now I'm going to open Tablo and
we'll see how quickly we can do this.
Two minutes left continue.
OK so just follow my steps.
I won't explain every single step but through this course you will learn all of this and even more so
now we can connect our data source over here on the left click Excel find your data set double click
on it.
It's opened up now.
Now on the left choose the orders tab and dragged into this whitespace and right away you can see a
preview of the spreadsheet appear in front of you.
Next click this orange part on here which says sheet 1.
And here you've got to Tablo workspace which right now is empty.
We need to put some stuff in here.
How much time.
1 minute 40 seconds OK let's do this.
All right so what are we going to do is we're going to find country and we're going to drag it in the
middle of this white space here.
Oh look at a map here.
Wow.
Tablo is quite smart.
OK.
So now we're going to look for state or province.
And we are also going to drag it onto the map.
Oh well look at all these dots appeared in the different states of the US.
OK.
So what are we going to do now we're going to take profit because we were asked about profitability.
And we going to drag it onto color.
And next we're going to take profit arrogant Dragon also onto label.
Now we're going to click label and we're going to click the font and we're going to change the font
size to 12 and that's it.
How much time do we have.
We have 58 seconds so that was all under four minutes.
And what can we see here.
We can see that right away just by looking at this map.
It's so intuitive we didn't have to specify any colors or anything.
Right away we can see the least profitable state that will the most losses were incurred in North Carolina
and the most profitable state is California right away.
You can tell those things and also you can even give more insights according to the map.
These southern states are not doing well in this region except for maybe Georgia and the northern states.
And over here the West and the Western states are doing better except for Montana.
And all of that was done in under five minutes.
Hope you're super pumped super excited.
We will learn all of this in this course and much much more and you will definitely have fun through
the way I look forward to seeing you in the next session.
And until next time happy analyzing.