Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And today we will create a map for our data set.
But first things first let's go ahead and save our workbook.
So just press control s and this one is going to be Section 6.
So as we usually do what we look for where it map is that little globe I can that we can drag onto.
So the dimension that can drag onto our Tablo workspace and that way the map will be created for us.
But today we've got a bit of a conundrum.
We don't have the globe icon.
Everything here is either a numeric value or a text field.
And here as well so we can create a map and moreover we don't have those latitude and longitude measures
that are usually generated for us.
So how do we create a map in this case.
Well we know that region is our locational variable here and maybe Let's try dragging that into the
workbook but once we drag it in nothing happens just creates this table for us.
So how do we create a map in this case.
Well this is a good example of when Tablo doesn't automatically recognize Geographic roles and you have
to set them up for your workbook yourself.
So we're just going to take that out of our worksheet and now what are we what we need to do is we need
to right click on region and we need to set a geographic crawl so if we go down here this geographic
roll and we can select what geographic role we want region to play.
So in this case it's cold region in the data set.
But what Tablo recognizes as region is different.
What we are implying on the region in the data set is actually cold state in Tablo because it's different
for UK Tablo deems what we call region in the data set it dimsum States so we're going to Slyke state
and now we have a global can and now we have latitude and longitude generated.
Okay good.
So now we can drag a region into a worksheet.
And what happens now.
Well we see the whole map of the world for some reason and we don't see UK we don't see our customer
base we don't see anything like it did and just built a map of the world for us but didn't map any or
put anything onto this map.
So what else we can see here is on the bottom right there is an indicator showing us that there is four
unknown values in this geographic classification.
So let's go ahead and look at that.
If you click on the four unknowns and you click Edit locations what you'll find is that England Northern
Ireland Scotland and Wales have not been recognised.
Well this can easily be fixed if you tell Tablo which country there is supposed to be looking in.
The reason is that right now Tablo is looking in Namibia for an unknown unknown reason it's just looking
to maybe have to change that too.
Obviously to the UK so Tablo knows that these states or provinces are actually located in the U.K. And
that's where it should be looking.
So we're going to go and find the United Kingdom or here.
Click on that and right away you can see that tablet has now matched them up and click ok here and there
you go right away we're taken to the map of the U.K. and what we need to do now is we need to change
this from automatic to field map.
And there you go that's how we created a map of the UK.
So we will talk a bit more about the errors that can occur when you're creating maps in the next section
of the course and the section on data preparation.
But for now that was a good intro and now you know how you create your own geographic roles or assign
your own geographic roles in your data set what we're going to do now is what we want to justice or
add some information to this map.
Well first of all we'll just assign random colors for now to our four states so we can see we can see
them separately.
So we're just going to take region and we're going to instead of keeping it in detail which is dragged
into color.
And now what we're going to do next is we're going to add information we want to see the total number
of customers in each of these regions that we're looking at.
And how do we do that.
How do we add the total number of customers.
Well we don't have a measure which corresponds to the total number of customers but we do have and what
is automatically added to every workbook and Tablo is a field a generated field that counts and a number
of barrels.
And it's cold number of records and that is a very very powerful tool because in our case we know that
the number of rows is exactly the number of customers.
So we can use these generated feel to our advantage.
So we're going to take a number of records and we're going to drag it into label and right away you
can see the total number of custom has appeared on our map.
So all we have to do now is kind of format it a bit.
So let's go we have 12 and bold let's just kind of reposition these labels so that they're working well
and we can see them well OK.
And now we will probably prepare our map a little bit for the future.
So if you want to zoom moon you have to pull the out of control.
We want our map to be as compact as possible so there you go.
And that is pretty much it for the map.
Whoa.
Let's control that.
I just wanted to move this label.
That's very much for the map for now.
So we did assign some random colors and they might not work well if our dashboard when we created so
we'll change those a bit later.
That's all for today.
In the next tutorial we will start looking at some charts to complement this map and you'll see how
all this is going to be coming together slowly into one amazing dashboard.
So that's all for today.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.