Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo today we're going to start slowly moving into the second
part of the challenge which is to understand are those 10 new cities into which the company should start
investing heavily in terms of marketing where the return on that investment will be the highest.
And secondly we're going to talk about highlighting.
So the heiling feature Tablo which will help us slowly transition into this part of the challenge.
It's going to be quite an interesting tutorial.
So let's get straight into it.
All right I'm going to create a new worksheet and here I'm going to create yet another map and right
off the bat.
Here's a quick quiz for you.
What happens if I just drag a city into the map.
Do I have all a hundred and fifty cities here.
Is this the correct way to visualize the cities of this company where the company operates just pauses
video.
Have a think about it for a second.
If you're following along then look around and look for hints.
And in three to one now we're going to have a look at the answer.
The answer is No.
Because we're here at the bottom you can see unknown values.
If we click here you'll see that they are ambiguous locations.
For example Augusta Aurora and so on because they are actually a few of these cities in the U.S..
So all of these cities are ambiguous and Tablo doesn't know which one to pick out of all of them.
So there we go.
That is not the proper approach to visualize these cities.
The proper approach is to take this out and we'll track state into here real estate into the map.
And now if we click the plus now we expand so we have both state and city in the geographies.
And now you can see that there is no unknowns.
There are known knowns.
That is because now Tablo knows exactly which city to pick in case if there is in the US a city with
the same name in several locations it'll just look at the state and then pick the city in that state.
So that was a quick fun quiz.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to just add up a little bit so we're going to add revenue
as the size then we're going to add revenue as a color as well.
And as you can see already we are seeing some of these cities pop up.
So what else we can do to make this more aesthetic transparency Maybe set it at 80 something percent
just a little transparency give it a border.
So now we can already see where the city is located it's a lot smaller cities have brought less revenue.
Large cities bring more revenue.
And the question is Where are our 10 new cities.
How do I identify them here.
Well the quickest way is to take our parameter which is a new expansion and just drag it onto color
so that way we can see right away whether in 10 cities are located so there is rock Ford there is Patterson
Joliet.
Chattanooga didn't even know these cities were in the US college station.
So there we go.
So if you're from one of these cities in a big a huge shout out to you you're a part of our Weasel's
nation.
All right.
But the thing here is that now we've lost that wonderful information where the caller was also linked
to revenue.
So this is indeed one of the ways to visualize the cities and then you can click here to highlight them
like that as we've discussed.
But now how do we do the same.
But at the same time don't use this color as the way we are identifying the cities.
Is there a different way to do it.
And there is a way it's called the highlighting feature so let's contrails at that and return back to
the previous version.
Now what we can do is we can take the new expansion parameter and put it into detail a set of color
and notes in detail and it's not really doing anything it is affecting aggregation but it's not adding
much because we already have the CD which is unique for our aggregation.
You could even put store Id into here and won't do anything new because there is no two cities with
the same name in our data set.
That's why store ID and new expansion don't really change aggregation but they are now being taken to
account.
But how do we now use this new expansion in order to quickly identify the new stores.
Well if you click drop down here and you select show highlighter Nacho filter but Schoharie letter then
a Heiler will appear here.
Some are actually going to move it over here.
And what I can do now is I can just select if I click here you can either type it up or because we only
have two categories here.
It's very simple just like new as you can see it highlights those when it gets old.
It highlights all the old cities and you can actually just click that way you've highlighted all of
the new cities very easy like that so they can see one two three four five six seven eight nine ten
cities we've highlighted very easy and very non intrusive.
So it's not actually using up any of our other features on causation like color or shape or size we're
not using them we just want to subtly highlight something and then just drag it into detail and then
use the highlighter option very powerful tool for daughter exploration.
So you can very quickly identify those objects that you want to pinpoint.
So there you go.
Hopefully this will be another new tool in your arsenal when you're working with Tablo.
And I can't wait to see the next tutorial where we will dive more into the analysis and understand what's
the difference between these series and what's kind of trends are going on there.
Conway to see there until next time happy analyzing.