Hello to welcome back to the course on Tablo in the previous tutorial we imported our personal vehicle
sales data into Tablo and we used the dot interpreter tool to help us out.
And this is what the data looks like so it looks great.
It's it's clean it's all in the information that we need.
But the problem here is that as we discussed this kind of format is still more oriented at humans because
it's got the years in separate columns whereas in a machine in a machine format the years would be in
their own column.
And then you would just have the values in another column.
So ideally this data set should be presented before Kwame's region country year and total sales for
that year rather than this on pivoted view.
So what are we going to do now is we're going to learn how to pivoted right here in tablet.
And as you can imagine I'll just bring up the spreadsheet here which we work with before as you can
imagine to achieve what we want to achieve by adjusting this.
It would take us quite some effort to move from this kind of format to a format where we just have a
cold for year and then a column for the value.
But the beauty of Tablo is that it can do all this for you and it's very simple.
Just observe how quickly this can be done.
We're just going to select the columns that we want to pivot.
We select all of these columns and then you just select one or one of the dropdown and you click pivot
and there you go.
It's all done as easy as that.
So now you've got region country pivot or the year and the value or the total sales total number of
cars sold for that year.
So as you can see we can also just just to make sure we can compare to what we see in our spreadsheet.
So let's pick a random random row from this new table and say let's say somewhere Europe Europe Greece
2007.
Two hundred and seventy nine thousand cars.
So now I'm going to bring up the spreadsheet since I can find it here it is.
So Europe Greece.
Two thousand seven hundred seventy nine thousand cars.
Perfect.
So that means it's working.
And as expected and that is how you pivot Dadda in Tablo.
So we'll continue with our daughter preparation the next Tauriel and Alec Facinelli someone till then.
Happy idolising.