Forms long see a lot.
Hey guys welcome back to the Tablo ADAs course.
Hope you're enjoying the turtle so far.
And in this video we're going on a walk through Africa now now while we're on this quick walk I also
wanted to give you a heads up.
You to me will very soon ask you to leave early for this course.
Now I know it can be difficult to judge the quality and value of a course this early on.
However the review system has simply changed and they are asking you to leave review earlier and earlier
on in the course.
Now if that don't mind we're not going to ask you to leave a five sort of view.
But what I would like to ask is that if you're not yet familiar enough with the contents of the course
of the tutorials then please scroll through the different topics.
Have a look at all of the different case studies that will have all of the different interesting and
exciting things that you will learn inside the course and hopefully that will give you the confidence
to rate this course of course.
If on the other hand you feel something is wrong with the course if you're unsatisfied about something
then please do let us know before you rate the course.
You can contact the super and support team directly or you can leave a message a short message in the
course Q&amp;A.
Your feedback is very valuable to us and we will get back to you or we will fix up whatever the issue
is and then get back to you.
And hopefully that will give you the confidence to rate this course of course.
So now having said that if something's wrong please do let us know.
But if you're satisfied about everything if you feel that you're excited about upcoming Charles about
everything you learn in this class you feel that this is a five star course.
Then please do rate it appropriately.
Please help the rest of the world know that this is a five star course on Tablo and that they can learn
it learn this amazing tool from here.
So on that note thanks so much guys for being part of Tablo it is that I'm very excited very pumped
about this journey that you have ahead of you and all the amazing things that you all are.
And I can't wait to see that other girl.
And I hope you enjoyed this quick walk through Africa.
And until next time I'll be analyzing.