Hello and welcome back to the Course I'm Tablo.
And in today's tutorial we will be talking about the differences between daughter joining and daughter
blending to get that topic out of the way once and for all.
And also we will look at when it is appropriate to do a door to blend in Tablo.
So let's get straight to it.
For today we will need our data set.
We need to go to superdog assigns dot com slash Tablo.
If you scroll down here to Section 5 joining in blending data you will need the second dhaba set which
is amazing Mart EU.
Now I won't download it because I already have it.
It's basically the same one that we worked with in Section 4.
So let's open that up and have a look at it.
There it is.
So here you can see here you can see that this Stata said has three tabs.
He talked about it but we'll just quickly recap so the list of orders tells us give us a list of orders
that had been conducted for the store the date when the order was placed.
Customer Name the city country region whether it was a home office that the daughter was placed for
or it was a consumer or a corporate office.
Different types of customers basically shipping day shipping mode.
And the State of the country order breakdown gives us a breakdown of each order by the product that
was contained within that order.
So basically this field order idea is not unique in this because sometimes orders have multiple items
within them so here you can see an example that this order had both posted markers and Eldin folders.
And then the discount on the order of the sales the profit not not on the order action on the product
the discount on the product the sales and the product profit on the product quantity category.
So whether it was office supplies furniture or technology and subcategory.
So what we will be interested in today is actually this field category it will be important for us.
And also we've got the sales target tab which gives us a target for the three different departments
which are furniture office supplies and technology and it gives us the targets for the different months
of the data set so what the dollar value targets were for each of these departments for a certain month.
So that's how data set and what we will be looking to do today is we will want to compare how the departments
are meeting or not meeting their targets.
But the caveat here is that that is not the only thing that we want to visualize So it is only part
of a greater dashboard that we're creating So remember that dashboard that we created previously with
the map was showing us different items so I'll just bring it up actually just to so we remember what
we're talking about.
So I'll open up Tablo And remember this dashboard here in Section 4 that we created which had the different
maps of the different regions and then how the customers were which customers were profitable which
were profitable and so on.
So we still want to be able to create all of this information but at the same time we want to be able
to analyze how the departments are performing how the different departments are performing.
So let's go ahead and do that so I'm going to close this workbook and we'll start a new one and that's
just because I want every section to be independent so you can just pick up from any section and start
working on it.
So we're going to create a new connection.
We're going to create a connection to our excel file and the excel file is amazing aren't you.
And here we've got all three tabs.
So we will recreate the join that we created previously.
So basically we obviously we want order breakdown because here it's got the sales and those are the
values of the sales and we need to compare the sales to the targets but the order breakdown tab does
not have information on the date.
It does have the category which is good but doesn't have the date of the order so we need the list of
orders file so we'll take a list of orders we'll connected to order breakdown that creates an inner
join.
And now we have the order date then we have the sale that was generated on that item and we have the
category under which the item falls which is perfect and we still have all this other information that
we need for the rest of the dashboard which we just looked at.
Now the question is how do we add sales targets into here.
And the thing is that we can just simply drag it in and create another join here.
Well it does work but we're actually doing a very incorrect thing by doing that.
And I have created a few slides a few PowerPoint slides just to explain exactly what's going on so let's
have a look.
Here we've got two tables everyone to join so the table A-plus B that we've already created through
a join and the table see which is our sales targets table A-plus B has information on order ID has the
date has some more information has the item within that order has the category within which the item
falls and it has the sales that was generated on the item.
And also of course there's lots and lots of other columns in there.
And as you can see here there are rare instances where the order IDs have duplicated because it might
consist of many items.
So that's how our table looks in the table that we've created.
Table A plus.
Now we've also got Table C which we want to connect or somehow we want to link these two so that we
can compare the sales to the targets.
But the thing is that the tables see has a very different level of granularity level of granularity
here is not item.
So here the level of granularity is actually at an item level for each individual order.
Whereas here the table is much less granular it's it's got a month.
It's got category and has got the target.
So what that means is that if we do want to connect these two tables then what will happen is we will
have to roll this table up.
We'll have to roll it up by date and category in order to match this level of granularity.
So basically we will lose information on order ID and we will lose information on an item we will lose
all of the information except for date and category and then we'll be able take the some of the sales
for that specific month for that specific category and compared to target.
And basically that was what it means we're losing all the other information if we're going to roll this
table up and that would have been fine if that is what we were looking for if that is the only thing
that we wanted to compare the total sales for a certain month for certain category to their target.
That would have been fine.
But we can't do that because we still need to create the rest of the dashboard.
Remember that caveat that we need to be able to create the rest of the dashboard so we need the rest
of this information so that way we can just roll up the table and join it to this table.
And moreover just going to end this so.
Moreover in Tablo if we were to drug sales targets here it doesn't actually roll the daughter up for
us what it does is just performs an inner join.
And as you recall when there are many fields suits joining here you can see is joining on category equals
characters on even including month.
And when when that happens it is duplicating lots of rows.
So basically this what just happened here is a whole another mess.
And if we wanted to even perform that rolled up join we would have to work on this a little bit.
But the good news is we don't have to do that because we can use a blend and that's exactly what we're
going to do.
We're going to see how we can use data blending in order to connect these these two data sources so
now right now we have one data source which is called list of orders plus.
So I'm just going to rename this list of orders plus order breakdown
that's good.
And now we're going to create another data source excel and the same file.
But this time only the sales targets.
And now if we go to our sheet you'll see we have two data sources list of orders plus order breakdown
and sales targets.
So remember we talked about blending in the previous tutorial.
Well now we know that blending is a very smart join that can happen on the fly and we're going to take
advantage of that we're going to create the visualization that is required through blending rather than
joining.
And we're going to do that in the next tutorial.
And today we're going to finish up on this on the reason why we won't be doing unjoin but rather be
we're going to be doing and blend.
And just to recap the reason is that in this particular case we would have had to aggregate our data
set.
We would have had to aggregate our data set and we would lose information.
So basically the level of granularity of the two data sets is different and therefore we cannot perform
a joint.
And so that's one of the reason why you would ever want to do a blend rather enjoyed.
And there's also a second reason why you would want to do a join and that is actually a bit more straightforward.
When you are not able to do a join because the data sources are different.
So if for example your other data source is not an X is not the same Excel file but as rather say a
CACP file or a tablet or a file or a Microsoft to secure all database or something that if the data
sources are different than Tablo won't let you do it.
And you will have to be blending the data.
So just keep that in mind that there's two reasons why you would want to do a blend.
One is a different level of granularity of the data sets.
And number two is the data sets are just basically different types of data sources.
So that's all for today.
Hope you enjoy the Tauriel and next time we will create this blend it'll be quite an exciting and very
visual tutorial so I'll look for it and then and until next I'm happy analyzing.