Hello welcome back to the course on Tablo in the previous tutorial we did all the ground work in connecting
to our data sources.
And today we get to do the fun part.
We get to create the visual Zeshan.
So what will we be talking about today.
Well first of all of course we'll be talking about blending and more advanced blending so you'll see
a real life example of how to apply blending and get results.
And also you will learn how to do a dual axis chart so well we'll show you how to create a dual axis
charge today which is quite a valuable skill to have in terms of your Tablo dash boarding and creating
cool visuals.
So let's get straight to it here.
As you recall we have two daughters sets more doors sources list of orders plus order breakdown which
will tell us the dates when certain items were sold or when orders were made and how those orders are
broken down and of two different items and what's the sales on those items were.
And also we have the sales targets data set which gives us the targets for our sales for the different
departments for the separate months.
So as you recall the level of granularity for these two data sources different sales targets are at
the level of detail of a category and list of orders plus order breakdown are actually at a much more
granular level.
They are at the level of items which constitute orders.
So let's go ahead and start creating our visual to start off with we're going to want to visualize by
a month.
So we're going to track the order date into columns and we're going to convert this into month.
So we're already used to that we know what's going on here.
Next we're going to look for sales so we've got the sales here in the measures and we're going to put
sales on Charlie Rose And right now that gives us automatically a line chart.
But we're going to change that to a bar chart because that is a bit more presented in our case a better
representation.
So there we go.
It might be a bit in this particular instance about me a bit too cluttered so will make it the reduce
the size and give some room between the bars.
OK.
So that's our sales for that for every single month.
The total sales for all of the departments.
So what else we can do now is we can take the category and drag the category into let's say we can drag
it into color which will give us these bars like the bars in our coloreds into three colors because
of the different categories but we want to visualize the categories separately so we can take categories
again and we're going to drag them into rows and this gives us categories separately here.
Now this is a bit too big to fit in so we'll reduce the size and there you go.
So there you have how the categories or the different departments furniture office supplies and technology
have been performing since the start of 2011 all the way up to 2015.
So what we want to do now is we want to add in the sales targets for these departments and see how they
have or have not been meeting those sales targets.
So where is that data located.
Well it's located in our second data source cell starting this week on that here right away you can
see that familiar Orange Line on the left meaning that this is a potential secondary data source to
us viz. where we have a primary data source.
I is Mark here with a blue little checkmark and right away Tablo has already recognized that category
is a potential field that it can join these two data sets on because once again the name of the field
is the same in both data says we have category here and we have category here.
And the reason why this link is already orange not gray is because as you recall category is already
part of our vessels.
So if category weren't in viz. this link would be great.
So we can have a look at that if we just whoops if we just take category out momentarily you can see
that the link is great because Tablo recognizes that this field is not a part of the visit Zeshan so
they might not be a need to join in this field.
So we're going to put category back by pressing controls that.
Okay.
So how do we get our dates into this or sorry no dates how do we get our targets into this position.
Well first things first we know that our joint has to be performed not only on category but also on
month of order date.
And that is because as you recall Sometimes we have to join in many fields and in this particular case
the sales targets are set at the month level so they said four categories or for the different departments
but they're set at the month level.
So let's go back to the data source and have a look here you can see that for every single month for
the category furniture there's a separate sales target for every single month.
So therefore when we are joining two or blending to our existing data we have to blend not just a rolled
up category level but also we have to include the month of order date granularity.
If we just blend right now with only category as our field that tablet will be blending on what will
happen is Tablo will as you remember Tablo sends separate queries to each data set.
It aggregates to the required level of granularity and then it brings the data back and blends it.
So in this case what would happen is Tablo would go back.
It would take all of these roles for furniture.
It would roll them up so to take some of the target it would disregard month and would bring back some
of the target for furniture and it would blend into every single row here.
So that's not what we want we can have a look at that.
So if we take target and we're dragged into in here you will see.
And let's just make it.
So if we open up the target control panel we'll just take out the category from color and we'll just
drag it into detail so that it doesn't affect the color.
Sure you can see that the target is always the same 620 1000 which is unreal it's not the right target
here it's also the same.
And here is also the same.
So it's not changing month to month.
And that is because we're not aggregating at month of order data has been aggregated it's not been considered
as a level of granularity for our chart.
So let's go ahead and fix that as you recall.
We can control the blend or the how the blend is being created through this control box here.
So we're going to go to data edit relationships and here you can see we've got the automatic field that
has been selected so now we're going to change it to a custom we'll keep category but also we'll add
in a new one here we want to use order date but we want to use month of order date and join on Also
month of order date.
That's good but also month is not just enough because as I remember these are categorical variables
we need to also take the one above month which is year so we have to make sure that the year is also
included.
Others all mix up different months from different years so we'll take your order date on this side and
here we'll also take your order date.
And if we click OK now as you can see there's a link and now the category or the targets have been adjusted
and as you can see they're reflecting what is the reality and we can easily check that.
So let's say January 2011 sales target for furniture was 5000 or 10000 dollars.
If we go to the data source sales target for furniture and generally in 2011 was $10000 and is gradually
increasing.
So that is great.
And now let's just quickly change this from a bar chart to an area chart because it looks better like
that.
And let's quickly have a look at the different targets that these different departments have set themselves.
So you can see that the furniture department has a very lean year growing target.
So it's basically got a coefficient that every month the sales should increase by a certain amount.
Then the office supplies Department has a quarterly target so every three months the target is different.
The monthly target is different so they basically review their targets every quarter and adjust them
according basically to Susya not seasonality or expect expected supplies and things like that.
And finally the technology department reviews their targets annually and sets them sets the same target
for the whole year so every month we'll have the same target.
So it's very interesting how the different departments have different targets and different ways of
setting them and you can see this right away through the data even without talking to management and
understanding their takes on it right away.
You already have this information.
So that's a very core part of data discovery that is.
The targets below the actuals.
What we want to do now is we want to combine these charts so we can actually visually compare them very
easily and seamlessly.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a dual axis chart and it is actually much easier
than it sounds.
So it might be very hard to do in Excel in Tablo it is extremely simple and I'm going to show you right
now how to do it.
So all you have to do is you just right click on your target here and you click dual access and then
one more thing which a lot of people forget.
Very important second step in a dual access chart right away.
You're right click on this access on the right here and you click synchronize access.
That is very very important.
Because if you don't as you can see right now they're aligned.
So 40000 of the top 40000 at the top here.
But if you don't synchronize you like I press controls here so this is synchronized.
This is not synchronized.
You can see that they have separate accesses.
And that way you can get really confused and the people reading the chart can get the wrong insights.
So we're going to synchronize access.
Make sure you do that every time.
And that finalizes the process of creating a dual axis chart.
Of course you can make adjustments further down the track but this is pretty much what it looks like.
And from here you can get insights into each one of the departments so you can see when they're above
the above their target are meeting the target or exceeding it when they're below they're not.
So here again you can see the same thing right now the gray area chart is in front of the Voller bar
chart.
We once put it if you want to put it behind we have to just take some target here and drag it to the
left and that'll switch places and as you can see it looks much better now.
The gray chart is behind and you can visually compare for every department to kind of see how they're
performing along the way.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to make a bigger.
So the chart looks.
So we can see the chart a bit better with bigger bars and increase the size of the bars so go to sales
size increase so as you can see that it already looks really good starting to look very good.
That's how you create a dual axis chart and Tablo remember about synchronizing the axes.
It's very important.
And that brings us to the conclusion for today.
Next time we will take this chart one step further and we'll introduce a calculated field within the
blend which is a whole different whole separate topic and tabbouleh and it's important to know how to
do that and that will hopefully finalize this chart for us.
So I hope you enjoy today's tutorial.
I look forward See you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.