Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo and in the Perras tutorial we created this dashboard.
And what are we going to do today is we'll make it interactive and fix it up a little bit to make sure
that the colors look great.
OK so now if I click around on the dashboard nothing happens which makes sense because it's not interactive
The only thing we can interact here with is the balance groups.
And that's because we created all parameters and one of the previous tutorials.
Well very quickly let's make it interactive we already know that we have a fast and efficient shortcut
to doing that.
If we click on the drop down here and we click users filter right away in our dashboard actions a filter
has been generated a select filter.
And if we click Edit it's using the map to affect all of the other elements of our dashboard.
So let's go back and see how this works.
If I click on Scotland now you can see the rest of the dashboard adjusts United or England Wales Northern
Ireland.
You can see that the dashboard is adjusting.
We can really gather insights for instance in Scotland our gender split is much more very different
to our overall split in the UK and 2 percent of male and in Northern Ireland 74 percent of our customers
are actually female.
Very interesting stuff.
OK so now let's do the same for the rest of them.
Use a filter uses filter if you don't want to use something as filtered and just don't use.
Don't do this for that Ellner dashboard but our kids were going to use all these filters and now we
can click on anything Saillant want to look at all of the female customers of the bank we just click
on that.
And now we can see all of them or we want to look at all the male customers or we want to look at all
of the white collar workers that bank with us and we will also want to overlay white collar workers
with males that have a look where where they're situated you can see right away they're most in the
UK.
What about males and blue collar workers.
So most of them are actually in Scotland very powerful stuff.
And same thing with bouncers if you want to have a look at the highest balances say everybody above
100000 so you just select these.
And there you go.
You can see their age where exactly they're located and so on.
And to check under a filter you just click somewhere and then what else you can see right away is this
little annoying pop up.
Sometimes it's useful but in this particular case not really because we can see everything from the
dashboard we don't need to have this pop up following all malls all the time and it can get in the way
so if I'm looking at these charts now this pop up is covering up my parameter control some other of
some other bars and so on and I put my mouse here it's covering up the number.
So let's go ahead and get rid of these pop up so you need to go to each of the worksheets and switch
it off.
So go to this sort with map.
And here if you go to a worksheet show tool tip and then just uncheck show tell to OK now if you go
back to the dashboard they see no more tilter still here and you have to for the other ones as well.
But sort of going to the sheet you can just click on it go to work sheet here tooltip and check this
same thing worksheet tool tip uncheck.
No there's none here so worksheet tool to uncheck and the last one worksheet to to uncheck voila.
So now whenever I put my mouse over something I don't see any tool tips which is great.
All that happens is I can select So that's how dashboard ready in the next tutorial will do some analysis.
And then in the tutorial after that we will start putting everything into a storyline.
I look forward to seeing you next.
And until then happy analyzing.