Hello and welcome back to the course in Tablo.
In today's Tauriel.
We're going to look at more well features of Tablo what we're actually going do is look at all of this
in practice.
So let's bring up our dashboard.
There have been creating So there are some installations right so let's say we want to create a dashboard.
Let's put some of these visualizations into a dashboard while one of the ones that we had was powerful
is of course our cluster analysis of some trend lines.
And also let's that map that we created over here.
So let's say we have this dashboard and now we want to see what it would look like or optimize it for
different mobile devices.
How would we do it.
Well over here in the top left corner now you have about device preview and you could just click that
and you can select from a desktop tablet phone.
So let's keep it on tablets for now.
And you can actually select specific different tablets that you or your managers or people in your company
might be using.
So for instance you can set generic tablet or let's say iPad.
That's what it will look like on an iPad iPad mini case and thing.
So Amazon Kindle Fire got more space.
Google Nexus 7.
OK so it's more stretched out.
So it's giving you this box which you can adjust your dashboard to so you can recreate a dashboard in
a way that it will actually fit into this type of layout so they can see now it's kind of like just
show you what it would look like.
You can also flip your flip the device what it would look like and also you can say if you have the
mobile app or not.
So say iPad this iPad and then we'll flip it and let's say No this is some some Galaxy Tab.
And then you have the mobile app or not.
It's also different than you can change a phone and you can like let's say iPhone 6 6 apps.
You can also adjust that if you like.
So it's a very very powerful feature.
And now if you also go into the size of a sort of fixed size you can select automatic and then it will
fit your dashboard into the device so let's say for instance you don't need any of these because there
are non-informative then this is what a look like on an iPhone 6.
If you select automatic then let's say if you go back to tablets this is what it look like on a Samsung
Galaxy Tab or HTC nexus so you can see that if you leave it on automatic and adjust to that to the layout.
And that is also a powerful feature just to kind of show you what that would look like.
But at the same time you can always modify your dashboard and make it look fantastic on the device that
you're targeting or make it so versatile that regardless of the device So for instance if you don't
select automatic you set a fixed size or for answers you could even do range right so you could do range
and you could set some different sizes where in between which the dashboard would adjust.
But that's kind of like more of an advanced feature so to start off with you would probably play around
with the fixed size.
Select a look and feel for a dashboard such that it would look good on different types of devices that
potentially can be used in your organization.
So that would definitely be helpful in terms of just understanding what exactly to expect from the different
devices because a lot of the time you might know that some device is used but you don't have it handy.
You don't have to drive in front of you to test these things out.
And this feature this new feature actually allows you to very quickly assess what exactly is going to
happen if your dashboard is open on this device or on another device.
So hopefully you'll find this feature useful.
And I look for see next time.
Until then happy analyzing.