Welcome back in this section of the course we're going to be talking about deploying your dashboards
lives to the Web.
But before we talk about deployment is probably a good idea to talk about authentication and authorization
for your dashboards.
Often when you deploy your dashboards to the Web you're not going to want them to be available to the
public and dashboard has a separate library that allows you to have a little bit of authentication capability
with your dashboards.
So let's discuss your options as I just mentioned authentication for Dash apps is actually provided
three separate dash off package and dash off provides two methods of authentication.
One is the basic auth and the other is Plumley.
Olof ECP basic auth is one of the simplest forms of authentication available on the web as a dash developer.
What you do is you hard code a set of username and password combinations in your actual code and then
send those user Mansa passwords to your viewers.
There's definitely a few limitations to HTP basic authorization.
One is that user can't really log out of an application.
Two is that you're actually responsible for sending the usernames and passwords to your viewers over
a secure channel.
So in your code once you've set up your username and password combination it's up to you to figure out
how to get those username and passwords to your actual users the other limitations.
Our Your viewers can create their own accounts and they cannot change the password and you're responsible
for safely storing the username and password pairs in your code.
Now the other alternative is using Motley's oath and that provides authentication through your online
plotless account or through your company's partly on premise server and as a developer that actually
requires a paid plotless subscription.
So this is a big part of how plotless actually runs a business and a service as we just saw basic HTP
authorization has a lot of limitations.
So plotless service is to really give you a full authentication platform through their paid subscription
or we're going to do now is because we are not going to assume that you want to do a paid subscription
is going to show you how to add a basic HTP authorisation to your dashboard.
It's actually quite simple.
Just essentially a few lines of code so we're going to take an already existing application and then
show you how you could add the import statements and the username password pairs in order to have users
log in and be authorized to use your dashboard.
Let's get started by jumping over to our text editor.
All right here I am at my dash application.
Notice I have dash dash core components ex-teammate components and my dependencies import input and
output.
So as a quick note we've already set this up for you as a file in the actual authorization folder section
and the basic idea here is we have a range slider and it creates some sort of product.
We've actually created this before.
Let's quickly run this make sure it works well say Python and I've called that basic pie so I'm going
you hit enter.
Let's see if it runs and then we're going to go visit this dashboard in our browser or here we are a
browser with this product range slider.
We've actually seen this before and it appears to be working but right now if I were to deploy this
life to the Web anyone would have access to this dashboard.
As long as they knew what your L to visit So it's that we're going to do now is show you how you can
add authorization to your dashboard using the dash off the package if you want more secure authorization.
Praties off well you're going to have to do is pay and sign up for their service.
And at that point it's actually quite easy to implement.
Essentially you just follow these instructions there.
But let's go back to our text editor and show you how this can be done.
OK.
So here we are back at our text editor.
We're going to first start doing is our import a dash underscore Auth. and it's quick.
In case you haven't installed it yet.
All you need to say is Pipp install dash off at your command line keep in mind when you import it it's
an underscore when you actually Pippin's Thall It's dash.
Once you've important dash off after you've installed it we want to do is set up your username password
pairs.
Technically this can be any variable name but by convention and in the documentation they call it username
password pairs in all caps.
And then this is where you're actually going to store the list pairs of username and password combinations
and you'll first provide the username and then you'll provide the password that works for it.
Here for example we can see that if someone went with a username they would need to provide the string
password to log into the dashboard.
Let's do one more.
He will say James Bond and will say their password is the string 0 7 and that's the basic idea behind
your username password pairs.
You set up a username password and then it's going to be up to you how you're actually going to store
this username password combination.
Right now we're just storing it as a list inside or a script which may or may not be secure enough for
your use case.
And then it's up to you also to send this username and password pair to whoever is going to be using
your application.
So you can already see that there are definitely limitations here.
And the big reason for that is because plotless service for the dashboard is kind of taking care of
all these issues with HTP authorization now that we've imported dash off and set up a username password
pairs.
The last step that we need to do is create a variable called off and then set that equal to dash off
dot and we're going to say basic auth and then we will say pass the application and pass our username
password pairs.
Now all you have to do in order to register these username password pairs to your application for basic
authorization.
Once you've done that we're going to run this and see what the dashboard looks like.
Now let's head over to her browser OK once you're in your browser you're going to notice now it's asking
for authentication required so let's provide a username and then I'm going to type out password here.
Click log in and then you'll have access to what you have here.
And Google Chrome may ask you when as you say never here but that's the basic idea behind authorization.
You just store your username password combinations in your code or maybe on your environment variable
somehow it's really up to you.
And then you send that to wherever your users are and then log in for plotless own authorization.
All you need to do is sign up for their services and they basically have a graphical user interface
free to use to really quickly and easily set up your dashboards there.
And often they have an onboarding process to help you of that as well.
I should just clarify I don't work for Lee.
So it's really up to you if you want to buy their services or not.
OK.
Thanks.
And you can check out the guidebook for more information as far as accessing authorization and also
signing up for the oath.
We'll see you at the next lecture where we go over the placement.