Welcome back.
As previously discussed one of her main goals at the end of this section is for you to be able to visit
the platies documentation and reproduce any plot type from the documentation with your own data in order
to successfully do this.
Let's have a quick tour of the poly documentation for Python.
Go to plot l y slash Python or Google search party Python to get to the documentation.
Let's go to our browser now and explore a little further.
All right so here we are.
Plot Elwha I-Slash python.
And there's two main aspects of the partly Python documentation that I want to show you.
The first one is the main examples library.
And basically here there's going to display various examples of pretty much any kind of visualization
you can think of.
It starts off with partly fundamentals and these are main overview in concepts things like using plotless
if a Jupiter notebook or using plot leiu of a dashboard and doory we're going to covered that in a lot
more detail later on in this course and you can click here for more portly fundamentals.
But more importantly if you scroll down you'll notice that there are sections such as basic charts and
then statistical and Seaborn charts as well as scientific charts financial charts maps and more.
And if you click on one of these it's basically just going to give you some examples.
So for instance if we wanted to learn about box plots we could open that in a new tab and here we see
box plots and I'll show you how to create a basic plot box plot at least to code for it and then horizontal
box plot and so on.
So our main goal is for you to understand what's actually going on with these examples.
So if you're new to plot line and you were just to come to this example it may be a little unclear what's
happening with things like go Dropbox or this data list or what's actually being passed in here.
So we want to do is fill in those gaps for you.
And that way you'd be able to come back to the main page visit any of these charts for instance Click
here for more basic charts view the one that you want.
So if you wanted a field area plot something we don't specifically go over but we do go over line plots
and after we go over this section you should be able to come here choose any of these plots and then
fully understand how to replace For instance x and y here with your own data and understand what the
parameters are doing.
So again we want to give you the skills so that you don't need to memorize information but instead become
an expert at looking up information and applying it to your own data sets.
So to be able to then actually leverage these examples to what you want to accomplish.
All right.
The last thing I want to know is besides these really nice examples that the poly documentation has
as far as creating basic charts scientific charts or financial charts is underneath QuickStart getting
started cheat sheet you'll see full reference and this one is really useful especially when you begin
to really understand and become an expert implicitly.
You'll be referencing full reference instead of those actual examples and we'll think your reference
allows you to do is actually understand what parameters you can pass in.
So for example if you're building out a color skill we can do a search for color scale and then you'll
see color skill in regards to different plot types such as a heat map.
So then you can click on heat map color scale and it will tell you how to set your own custom color
scale.
So as you get better and better of politely you'll find yourself at this reference page a lot more to
see what you can passen for the various parameters.
So a lot of times will say during our lectures check out the documentation for other parameters you
can pasan what we're really saying is check this reference here.
And then you can look up the parameters match it up to the plot type that you're looking at and then
see what options you have.
And again you can find this at plot Alwi slash Python slash reference.
OK.
That's really all we need to know about the documentation.
By the end of this section you should feel comfortable going to the documentation and being able to
recreate any of the plot types there understanding what the parameters are doing with that plot type
and then leveraging that plot type with your own data.
Thanks and we'll see what the next lecture.