Welcome back everyone.
Now it's time to talk about bubble charts.
Bubble charts are actually very similar to scatterplot except we're now conveying a third variable's
information through the size of the actual markers.
So the typical scatterplot all those markers are the same size.
What we can do for a bubble chart is connected diameter of the markers to some other feature in our
dataset and then we can also continue to add a variable information by coloring points based off a category.
So let's see some basic examples right now and images here.
We have a basic plot of vehicle per gallon usage versus horsepower.
So in a typical scatterplot all these points would be the same size.
And right now we can just tell it right off the bat even though these axes aren't labeled along the
y axis we have miles per gallon.
X-Fi of horsepower.
And as you increase horsepower your MPG ends up dropping which makes sense because you have a larger
engine which isn't going to be as efficient.
Now you'll also notice that the diameters themselves are larger towards the right hand side and smaller
towards the upper left hand side.
And that's because the diameter is going to be connected to another feature.
In this case it was connected to represent the number of cylinders in the engine.
So as you have more horsepower you have more cylinders I those markers are going to have a larger diameter.
And we're actually going to dive into this particular plot in more detail by recreating it in just a
little bit.
But I want to show you one more example of a bubble chart which makes really clear the abilities to
display multiple features of information on a to d image.
So this is an example from the plotted documentation and what we see here is life expectancy per capita
GDP from 2007.
And if you want the code for this you can just check out the bubble chart stocks on plotless documentation
and they have the code that goes along with this image.
But let's see all the different features and all the information that is being displayed to the image.
So right off the bat we can see life expectancy on the y axis and GDP per capita on the x axis and we
can already see there's a bit of a trend between higher having higher GDP per capita and having a higher
life expectancy which intuitively to some degree makes sense that if you have a richer country your
people are probably more well-off and they'll probably live longer.
But we can also see here that we've been able to group these points by categories using colors.
So I can see the blue points for African countries orange for Americas green for Asia and so on.
And then we add another feature of information by actually sizing these markers to some other feature.
And in this case their size to population.
So if you take a look right in the middle of this image you'll notice two large green points and those
points are India and China because they have some of the largest populations in the world.
They can really stand out.
And so here we're getting a plethora of information we're able to see life expectancy GDP per capita
the actual continent the countries based in and then you can also see the population.
And if this was an interactive version of this plot you'd be able to hover over and get even more information
when you hover over a particular point.
So let's go ahead and explore how we can create our own charts with plot lead.
You'll notice that it's actually quite easy.
It's going to look a lot like a scatterplot just with an extra argument.
As far as the marker size.
So let's head over to our text editor and get started.
OK.
So we've already imported plotline off line and polygraph objects and since we're going to be using
a real data set.
We've gone ahead and imported pandas as PD.
Let's read in our dataset we'll say PD read CXXVI and we'll reach toward data folder and we're going
to grab the MPG thought CSB data file.
Let's go ahead and print it out.
And let's also print out the columns for this data frame.
So we get a better understanding of what it actually represents.
So I'm going to expand this right here.
Call Python basic thought PI enter and check out that data frame.
So here you'll notice we have various columns mpg cylinders displacement horsepower weight model year
origin name.
And if you take a little glance at the actual results when you print out the data frame you'll notice
that essentially every row is a particular model of car for a year.
So we have a Chevy Plymouth AMC Ford.
So all these different model cars the years and then information about those particular cars as far
as there are things like MPG how many cylinders they had the number of horsepower we had their acceleration
and some metric et cetera.
So we're just basically going to plot out this information of these actual vehicles so you can explore
that data frame a little more if you want.
Hopefully you get the idea what this is representing.
And this is a very common data set.
This mpg that we file is very proper for people who are learning our programming language as well.
OK.
So let's get focus now on how do we actually plot this and how do we make this into a bubble chart.
The first thing we're going to do is set up our data list where inside of this we're going to say go
out scatter and we need an X for our x axis we will plot out the horsepower along the x axis and then
for the y axis we're going to do is say plot out the MPG
and then the other parameter going to provide is text.
So what text allows you to do it allows you to link up a column of values to what you want to display
when you're hovering over something with your cursor.
So for example right now were just to hover over without specifying text it would by default giving
back the y value.
But let's imagine that I actually want it to show the model of the car or in instance the name of the
car.
I could say the F name.
And when you're hovering over something it's going to display the name of the actual model of car that
that marker represents.
So that's what you can use text for whole play around that a little further in just a second.
But then we're also going to provide mode equals markers just like we did for the normal scatterplot
and then to make this into a bubble chart.
But we need to do is call a marker and then we're going to pass in a dictionary.
And as always you can decide what style of dictionary you like will stick with the plotless style which
is actually called the ICC function and we'll set the size equal to some column value.
So in this case let's start off by plotting based off the cylinders.
So the cylinder's column if we take a closer look at it it looks like it's going to be for 8 or 6.
So here we can see the cylinder's And that's basically going to Coralee a value for this column to the
actual diameter of the marker.
And if these are pretty small values what you may want to do is really show the difference by multiplying
that value by some sort of integer unit.
So you can double it because remember we're not actually going to be displaying the cylinder information.
Instead what we're displaying is just the relevant size.
So you can see that some markers of more Sillars are going to be larger.
So if you want to really make that difference more obvious you can multiply by the cylinder's.
However if you have a really large value for example if you're going to plot marker size based on the
weight of the car if you take a look at the weight of the car that's actually already in the thousands
itself.
So for this sort of thing you may want to make it smaller since it's basically translating that into
pixel pixels for the ammeter.
All right.
So we have our data.
Let's go ahead and define our lay out.
So right now we'll just say go lay out and we're going to set the title equal to but will chert and
let's plot this out will create or figure object.
So go figure.
Pasan data equals data and layout equals Leo and then we'll save the bio plot that figure and you can
always provide a file name if you want.
So right now we create our simple data and this looks a lot like scatterplot.
We just introduced a couple more things.
The fact that we can choose what text we want to display when you're hovering over something and the
fact that we can set the marker size for the diameter based off a column of information here.
So let's plot this out by calling Python basic that pi.
Hit enter and you should get a new plot in your browser pop up this template here and we can already
see that we get the same thing that we just saw from before.
And as you hover over this you'll also notice that you get information about the actual car models.
If I zoom in for you guys you'll notice as I'm hovering over it might be a little small on your screen
but if you view this on your own computer you'll be able to see it.
I can see here Pontiac Grand Prix seems to be the worst performing car as far as mpg.
And I had a Pontiac so I can attest to that.
So let me close this and let's try experimenting with setting the bubble chart size to some other value.
So as I mentioned we could choose the weight of the car so the weight of the car is actually quite large
for the value.
So let's go ahead and divide that by 100 That way we don't get these huge marker sizes.
So we're going to say weights and I want to divide this by 100.
Let's save that and run this again Python basic that pie.
And this is something you sometimes have to experiment with as far as finding the right integer value
to multiply by or divide by.
And if you were just a passing weight by itself here you actually might get a blink chart because the
diameters may be too big for poly to show.
So keep that in mind if you're getting issues with the sizing of your markers.
Play around with either multiplying it so it's larger or dividing it so it's smaller.
So we'll run Python basic pie here.
And you should see a plot that looks something like this.
You can experiment with foot sizing you prefer.
You'll notice we get the heavier cars towards the lower MPG and the lighter cars towards the more or
excuse me heavy occurs have less mpg and the lighter cars have more MPG which makes sense.
Have your car.
Going to take more gasoline to move it.
So here we're actually displaying a lot of information very nicely in our bubble chart Altes experiment
by adding in a category of data such as those cylinder values.
So for categories like cylinders where we're going to have only a few categories we're going to try
to color by the actual cylinders to display one more level of information here to move this back and
just close this.
OK so let's add in a color column and we're going to do that inside our marker dictionary.
So we're going to add a couple more lines here and be careful here Princess here.
Remember one of these princes is for the scatter call and another princess here is for the dictionary
call and we're going to do is inside of this dictionary.
We're going to add in another call here.
We're going to say color and set that equal to the column.
And you can play around with this and experiment.
We'll start off with cylinder's save that and let's check out what that looks like.
We'll say Python they set up PI enter and then you should see now colored by the number of cylinders.
So if you take a look at this you now see that the cild their colors have been displayed as well.
So now we're getting a lot of information we're getting the weight of the car cylinder information mpg
information and the horsepower.
So you getting a ton of information for features worth on just a to the plot.
So it's pretty interesting use of how you can use color size of the markers and just the normal x and
y axis to display a lot of information to your users and sometimes what people like to do is also add
in a scale bar here.
And luckily Polly actually makes that pretty easy.
And we need to do is again inside of this marker dictionary after size and after Add in and color.
Well we're also going to do here and we can add in show scale is equal to true.
Save that.
Make sure that's all inside the dictionary.
Be careful of your princes here.
And if you run that again we should now see a scale pop up showing the number of cylinders.
So here you can see towards the top range of eight cylinders and towards the bottom we have three cylinders.
Even though I only see a few three sell their cars here which is kind of interesting when you think
about the actual numbers cylinders to have that kind of double checked this data make sure that's actually
correct.
But that's how you can easily add in a color bar to tell you what the colors actually represent.
All right.
That's it for basic bubble charts.
You can check out the notes because we also provide a little more information if you want to group together
different text columns.
It's simply adding the text columns together so you can get a longer string when you're hovering over.
There's also other options like hover mode to choose what actually gets displayed when you're hovering
over something or really not what gets displayed.
But what actual marker gets chosen.
Sometimes it defaults to why sometimes it defaults to x.
So you can play around with the options on their layout.
We can do is say hover mode is equal to and there's various parameters you can choose.
You can choose X to try to hover over the closest X to your cursor hover mode over Y.
So based off the y position of the cursor hover over that and then there's also closest or it tries
to determine what the closest marker next to your cursor is and it's going to display information off
of that particular marker.
So experiment hover mode and see what works best for you.
It's usually going to depend on where you're trying to convey.
OK.
So again hope to those useful information.
Really we're just working on top of what we already know about the scatterplot by adding in a dictionary
for the marker and you're going to see that a lot in this course when you're working if slightly.
They can really hone in on specifics by adding in dictionaries to specific parameters inside your pluck
call.
OK.
Are you on.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see at the next lecture.