Welcome back.
Let's quickly go over the solution for the bubble chart exercise.
OK here we are at the exercise file.
The main objective was really just create a bubble chart from the NPG that CXXVI data set and you had
a lot of leeway over what the three features you wanted to use were.
So let's go ahead and walk over or walk through one quick example of how you may have done that.
First we want to do our imports.
I will just copy and paste this from the solution.
It's as always Polly off line graph objects empanadas.
PD then we want to create a data frame from RC A C file.
So PD read C S V and we'll go ahead and say from that data folder and Peachi that CSP and then we want
to create our data.
So here we creer data lists and inside of this we'll have a call to scatter.
And for example we'll use the displacement column.
So we'll say if displacement and then we'll say why is acceleration so acceleration.
And then finally let's say text is going to be equal to f name.
And now it's up to us to really decide what we're going to choose for that marker in order to do that.
We first need to set our mode to be equal to marker or markers and then we can decide what we're going
to find that marker by.
So for this we pass in a dictionary and we'll say size is equal to.
And let's go ahead and use the weight of the car.
So we'll say weights and because weights is such a large value in that column we're going to need to
divide it by some factor in order for the diameters to make sense.
So we can divide it by for instance 400 and you can play around with that division and you can play
around with this marker size really.
It's up to you which one of these fields or columns you want to use so please wait.
And we did an example of this very similar intellectual lecture and then we'll create our layout.
So we'll say lay out is equal to go that way.
And here we'll just say hover mode is equal to closest
closest and we can also give it a title.
So it's that as well.
We'll say titles equal to my bubble solution.
OK we'll save that.
And if you want you can also add an x axis and y axis title.
But really this is almost the recreation of what we did in the actual lecture.
So say figure is equal to go figure.
Passing data equal to data and lay out equal to lay out helps and we'll plot this out.
We'll say plot and plot out that figure.
Let's save this and make sure it works.
Basic thought PI run that.
And here I can see my solution.
So your solution may look differently the pending on what you actually decided to plot but you can see
here as we hover over we get to see the actual differences between the three features that we decided
on.
Weight displacement and acceleration.
OK.
So that's really all there was to it.
It was kind of up to you what's the pasand for x y.
And then how to deal this size.
If you were having issues of the bubbles not showing up or the bubbles being too small it's most likely
that you need to adjust the actual size parameter there either by dividing it or by multiplying it depending
on what actual values that column or feature had.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to check out the solution that postscript or post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.