Welcome back everyone.
And this lecture we're going to talk about box plot's box plots visualize the variation of a feature
by depicting the continuous numerical data through core tiles.
We could then separate data based on a categorical feature to compare the continuous feature based off
the category.
So basically what this means is you may have a case where you have one column of continuous data such
as the weights of a person then right next to it you have another column of a category such as gender
male or female.
What you would then be able to do using a box plot is compare the distribution of weights between the
territories male weights versus female weights.
So we're going to see a visual example very similar to that in just a little bit but let's talk a little
more detail about this quartiles.
So the box plot is a way of visually displaying that data distribution through their core tiles where
core tiles separate the data into four equal parts.
So you have your bottom 25 percent then the next upper 25 percent.
The 25 percent of data points on top of that and then your top 25 percent.
And what the box plot likes do is show the top and bottom 25 percent and then it fills in the little
box of the middle 50 percent.
So you have 25 top 50 middle and then 25 bottom.
So let's see what that actually looks like visually.
Here you can see the box plots where we're doing a comparison of two categories.
Sample a and sample B all the x axis and we have a continuous y axis feature.
So there's some continuous scale feature we want to compare between sample A and sample B.
And we can already see here some information about the distributions in comparison to each other.
So let's talk about what these actual lines and markers mean on your box.
What's nice about plot Li is that as you hover over one of these boxes it's going to show you the actual
information of this box plot.
So the middle line that's the median So the median recall that's the values separating the higher half
of a data sample from the lower half.
So that's kind of right in the middle of your data that we have.
Q1 and Q3.
So between between Q1 and Q3 that's the filled in box that's where the middle 50 percent of your data
lies.
And then you have the min and the max and those are sometimes called wiskers so often a box plot is
called a box and a whisker plot because you have that middle 50 percent inside the box and then the
wiskers that expand to the top and bottom 25 percent.
Up for 100 percent of your data.
So that box range between Q3 and Q1 that's often known as IQ.
So that's the intercourse tile range and that's basically the middle 50 percent of your data.
Now depending on the styling max and min values are going to be shown with whiskers.
So we can see here those whiskers that extend from that box we that minimum value and the maximum value
a box plot identifies outliers from the median compared to the rest of the data.
So in this particular image there are no outliers but in just a second where we actually start coating
the box plots we'll be able to see examples of outliers that are displayed as markers beyond the whisker
so outliers for box plots those are defined for the upper outliers.
Those are values that are larger than the Q3 value bet least 1.5 times the IQ are.
So recall the I.Q. are that's going to be Q3 minus Q1.
So the actual length of that box.
And if you're an outlier then if you multiply the value of Q3 minus Q1 otherwise known as I.Q. are by
1.5 times you have to be larger than Q3 by at least 1.5 times the IQ are.
So those are upper outliers and for smaller or lower outliers so things that go below that bottom whisker
there's going to be values that are smaller than Q1 the bottom of the box by at least 1.5 times the
I.Q. or so outliers are going to be displayed as singular markers outside the wiskers.
What's really cool about box plots is that we can actually use box plots to perform a real analysis.
So we're going to be exploring not just how to create the box plots but also how to apply them to a
real problem.
To discuss this problem for a second it really classic forensic example of using Box plots and Applied
Statistics is there's this famous case where Mark Twain was accused of being a confederate deserter
during the Civil War.
And the evidence that was given for that were 10 essays that were published in the New Orleans daily
daily Crescent under the name Quintus Curtius Snodgrass.
However in 1963 a researcher published an article in The Journal of American Statistical Association
where he used word frequencies and a chi squared test to show that the essays were almost certainly
not Mark Twain's because of the different usage of the length of words.
And what we can do is we can use box plots to compare to collections of samples to each other and analyze
or distributions for example in this case for Mark Twain and this other author that people are saying
is also Mark Twain.
What we can do is compare the word length accounts between the two authors and see how related there
are.
And if we notice that one author uses word lengths that are much higher than another author then we
can begin to make an analysis depicting that these are probably two different authors or at least two
very different writing styles.
So we're going to start off of some simple examples of Bach's plot features and then we'll show the
Mark Twain analysis for the data used in these examples look at the lists created underneath the box
plot folder inside the box plot that PI script.
So instead of having really small CXXVI files instead we're just going to manually copy and paste the
Python list that's already provided for you underneath the box plot that PI script.
So there in the coding if you see me suddenly copy and paste something it's coming from the top Paice
group that's underneath the box plot folder.
So just be aware that as you follow along with the coding.
OK let's hop over to the text editor.
OK.
Here we are at the text editor.
I've gone ahead and put it off line and graph objects when I'm going to do now is set up an array of
20 data points.
Again you can just copy and paste these from box 1 pi.
So I will do that now.
And then we're going to start off by creating a very simple box plot and adding more and more features
to it.
So for a box plot you create our data list and say go box
and in this case we're gonna just say Y is equal to y notice and we just have one array of data.
We don't need to specify some categorical X column.
So then we're just going to do that and say p p so that plot and pass in our data and that's all we
do.
So I'll say Python basic about pi enter and check out the plot that comes out of this so Uno's as you
bring in your plot we have a very simple box plot and you can see those minimum values and those max
values.
And the reason we have a minimax values is because that middle value is at least 1.5 times IQ are less
than the bottom of q 1.
So that allows us to set these little points here so we can see 54 and 1 on the bottom and then we have
the median values Q One.
Q 3 and then what they call the upper fence and lower fence in order to clearly show where are the actual
25 percent 50 percent.
That middle box of your data is.
So we're going to add a couple more features.
Box plot to give it a little more kick.
So we're going to do now instead of just saying why is equal to y.
We can say something like Bach's points is equal to all.
And what this does is it's going to display all the original data points.
So now when you run this you'll be able to see dots for every point which gives you a little more insight
into the distribution and it's going to if you just do box points all will show all the points right
next to them here.
So you can see the various points here to the left of the actual box plus.
So you get see now both all the data and essentially a summary of the data which is kind of nice and
we can continue doing here is adding more features.
And one of them is called jitter so jitter what it's going to do is you can choose a value somewhere
between like 0 and 1.
So it's going to spread them all out so they all appear.
If you have a lot of data points that's actually a really nice thing to do.
And what you can do is you can actually choose their offset position.
So if you want.
You can say points POS.
So that's point position and set that equal to.
If it's negative it's going to be offset from the box.
If it's positive it's going to be offset to the right.
So negative is offset to the left positive is offset to the right.
And if you set 0 here what it's going to do is it should put them right on top of that box.
So let's run Python based on PI again.
And now we can see here that we have the points right on top of the box.
So sometimes that's not really useful.
So maybe we want to move to the right.
What I can do is say point position is equal to something like 2.0 and that's going to position them
over to the right of that box plot.
And there we can see positions to the right.
So the more jitter value add the more spread out these points are going to be left and right.
So illin they'll maintain the y values.
But if you have a lot of points if they're kind of stacked right next to each other you'll just see
a bunch of points on top of each other.
So you can use jittered to add a little bit of noise to spread them out.
OK.
So that's the very basics of the options that are available to you.
For a box plot we're going to do now is move on to the code for box to that pi and we're going to do
is set box points to only display outliers.
And then we run this.
It basically shows you what we had before.
So it's a python base but PI and now typically this is what you're going to do for a box plot you'll
just say okay only show me the outliers as points sometimes you want to see all the results for the
box points sometimes you don't.
It's really up to you.
But keep in mind if you see this box points equal to outliers you're basically specifically asking to
only show me the outliers on those points.
So now we're going to do is finally do that Mark Twain analysis.
So for that we're going to grab some data from a box 3 that pi.
So I have Snodgrass and Twain and what these numbers actually represent.
These are the relative frequencies of three letter words from the Snodgrass letters.
So we have basically each number here represents the relative frequency of using three letter words
per each letter that Snodgrass wrote.
And here we have the same calculation.
But first some other works that we know are Barnhardt by Mark Twain.
So again this is the relative frequency of three letter words from various letters of Snodgrass and
here various works of Mark Twain.
And you can check out the google doc for a link to the publication that we're actually referring to.
For Snodgrass versus Twain.
And then we're going to do here is do a little bit of plotting.
So for this we're going to need to box plots.
So we'll say for the first one that y is equal to Snodgrass and then another thing we can passen for
our box plot is give it a name so I'll say the name is Snodgrass and then we'll add in a box plot to
this list go the box and here will set Y is equal to Twain.
And we'll get this name Twain.
So when we hover over it we can see the twain.
OK so if you want you can do a layout to give this a title.
But since we already know what's happening here Lucias go ahead and plot this out.
We'll say Python basic but PI enter analyse this comparison.
So if we take a look again the relative frequencies of three letter words in their writing we can see
here that it looks like there's a different distribution between Snodgrass and Twain.
And so just by this simple analysis we can probably start getting an idea that these two people are
not the same author.
So Snodgrass is probably not Mark Twain unless Twain really specifically changed his writing style for
three letter words for writing letters by Snodgrass which is quite a complex and difficult thing to
do.
So you'll be able to check out the link to the publication from that researcher from 1960s to actually
see his full analysis of comparing these two authors and showing that distinctly Twain is probably most
likely not Snodgrass.
And here we can see even just through a simple example of their relative frequencies of using three
letter words that Twain is probably not going to be Snodgrass based off their usage.
OK so that's an example of using a real analysis with a visualization.
And there's much more complex examples that we could do for Bach's plots but hopefully this is a nice
easy one to understand.
And later on in the exercises you'll get your own data sets to play around with for box plots.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I'll see you at the next lecture.