Welcome back in this lecture we're going to go over the solution for the box plus exercise.
Let's get started.
All right so here we are at the exercise file.
The you wanted to make a data frame using that abalone data set and then we wanted to take two independent
random samples of different sizes and we gave you a couple of hints here about how to actually do this.
So let's start off and we'll say import.
First off when you plot the off line as pujo And as always we also need plot the graph objects and we'll
have those as go.
Then finally we'll import pi as p as well as pantless then we'll read in the dataset so will say create
data from the physical to PD that read CXXVI
an insight or data folder.
We have the ability thought see every file and now it's time to take two random samples of different
sizes.
So we wanted to do this from the Rings column.
So if you look here we gave you kind of an example of how to do this.
So let's copy right here this line and we'll set two samples we'll say a is equal to any random thought
choice.
And for this one I'll choose 30 samples and for B I can choose any other number of samples.
Again it's really up to you how many samples you wanted to actually grab.
So let's choose let's say 20 here you could have also done 10.
Other number.
It's really up to you.
Basically the main idea here is just create two box blocks and the box plots are similar enough.
Then we can assume that both of these were taken from the same sample group or same population that
we have created a variable of two box plots.
So two this will say data is equal to.
And I will say that our list here first box plot is just going to say why is equal to a.
And we'll get the name of capital-T then for our second box plot in this list essentially the same thing
except Y is now equal to B and name is equal to we'll say capital B.
So we have two samples there.
Well create a really an object with go that lay out and give this a title we'll say two random samples
we'll create our figure.
Go figure.
And say that is equal to data and lay out is equal to LEO and enough for all this we'll just plot out
the figure save it and run it.
And let's see what we get.
Again you will get slightly different results depending on what you actually got as a random sample
and how many values you chose.
So we'll enter here by some basic pie.
And overall you should see something that looks similar to this depending on how large of samples you've
got your box plots may be slightly different than each other but they should more or less be around
the same range.
So here I can see that it looks like 50 percent of my samples from sample A are somewhere between 9
and 11 and it looks like I had a little more variation on B which makes sense because it was a larger
draw.
And these tend to be between seven and maybe 10 and a half ish.
OK.
So I can see right here that the populations do seem to be similar enough.
This is something you can play around with by grabbing different size X samples so maybe you can grab
a 100 here and 30 here save this.
Run it again and see how that changes your results.
Mean idea being that you were able to create two box plots again.
Here we can see that these samples tend to be even more in line of each other because we grabbed even
more samples.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums but hopefully you're able to get that.
We'll see at the next lecture.