Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to talk about distribution plots distribution plots or plots for short typically layer 3
plots on top of one another.
The first plot is a histogram for each datapoint is placed inside of bin of similar values.
The second is a rogue plot.
This is where marks are placed along the x axis for every single data point which lets you see the actual
distribution of values inside each bin.
Then the third plot the distribution plot shows is going to include a kernel density estimate plot or
Kaytee for short and this is basically just a line that tries to describe the general shape of the distribution.
So this is what this plot actually looks like here.
And we can see the three plots on top of each other and if we look at the very bottom of this chart
we can actually see the plot and the plot is just a very simple idea.
You're going to have a mark where each data points value is.
So remember here we're just plotting out one continuous single variable.
So at the very bottom we have that scale and we're just going to draw a mark for every single point.
So you can see where the actual marks are per been.
For example if we look at the histogram all the way on the left hand side we have a bin that goes from
like negative 3 to negative 2.
However within the bin we don't know the distribution from just the histogram alone.
However that Roug plot actually lets us see that we have more values towards negative 2 than we have
towards negative 3.
So that's the difference or what the rogue shark trying to show you that the histogram itself cannot
show.
Then on top of the histogram we see this curve.
And this is basically showing us what a general distribution looks like for all the data points and
here we can see a distribution plot for various sets of data.
Essentially we see the same continuous value but now based on four different categories.
So this is sometimes commonly shown to see the various distributions between two categories for the
same variable.
All right let's go ahead and explore the distribution plot further with plotless.
All right.
Here we are at the text editor something I want to point out is that our imports and our labels are
going to be slightly different than before.
So first we're going to import like we've done before.
Plot lead off line as Pyu wyo.
But now we're going to say import plot lead dots and we're going to call figure underscore factory which
is basically a special special section of poly that does more complex figures like distribution plot.
We're going to import this as F-F and then create some data we'll say important up-I as N.P..
So let's create our actual random data.
Remember we just need some continuous variable so to do this will say we thought random thought Rand
and to create some normally distributed data that's random and will create a thousand data points.
And then what we need here is similar to overcalling calling go dot and then a particular plot type
where we had a list with data.
We're going to say just underscore data and set that equal to a list.
And here is where you would pass in your data points.
So we just have one.
So we're just going to have a list of a single set of data which will call hist underscored data.
So our histogram data and then the other thing we need to define is group labels.
And this is just the actual label for this x so we're going to call this for now this plot kind of up
to you what you want to label that string later on we'll see.
Kind of a more real realistic example of actually naming that x.
But here we're going to say figure is equal to.
And then we say f f dot and we call create underscore.
And you notice already that underscore has a lot of different advance plot types like violin plots bullit
plots chart's open high low close plots for stock market stuff.
But instead we're just going to say this the plot and using this we're going to pass in our data and
say his state is equal to his data and then we can just pass on his data like this instead.
And then we'll pass in our group labels as well.
So we'll say group labels OK and then we just need a plot that will say plot and plot that figure.
And as always you can say file name if you want.
So now it's called Python basic thought pi.
Haven't changed the name of that file yet.
We're going to run this and we're going to see our distribution plot.
So when I bring this over I could see my distribution plot and I get to see the values along my actual
KDE or kernel density estimation which is essentially just trying to make some sort of probability distribution
that goes along with your discrete data points and then on here we can see the actual points themselves.
So what's nice about this is I can now tell the distribution within a bin.
So like I was saying before for this first then from three to negative two I can see that most of the
points are actually closer to negative 2 than to negative 3.
So is where you can really explore your data through that distribution.
Let's go out and see some other examples.
So we just created a very basic distribution plot.
Let's move on by adding in some multiple groups.
So I won't say X-1 and that ran them that ran then.
And let's just make 200 points.
So not a whole lot here and we're going to copy and paste this to get multiple groups here.
Let's create four groups of data.
There we go and we'll label these X1 x 2 x 3 and x 4.
And we're going to shift them just a little bit.
They're not all on top of each other.
We're going to subtract two from this first one.
Add two to this one and let's add 4 to that one.
If we didn't do this then they would basically be all right on top of each other and it would look so
great.
So here is our actual data sets.
And then we just make a list of the data sets will say x 1 x 2 x 3 x 4.
And then you're going to need group labels for each of these.
So something we could do is just make string versions of this x1 x2 x3 and x for.
OK so these are the names that correspond to these sets of data and then basically the same thing down
here we're just passing in that list of data points for the histograms and the group labels.
So let's see what this looks like now.
A-plot Python base that PI run that and then that's going to create the plot that we saw again earlier.
We're now we have these four distributions here now something you may be wondering is how do you actually
affect the bin size for each of these histograms so you can do that individually.
And you actually do that inside this create this plot call.
So as an argument here you can specify bin size and then you just pasan a list of the actual bin sizes
for each of these.
So for X-1 we can say Give me a bin size of 2 4 x 2.
Give me a bin size of 1 and so on.
So you can kind of play around with these and then if we run this again we should see some different
bin sizes.
So let's run that.
And now we can see the actual bin sizes.
So here we made them probably quite too large.
So let's make them quite a bit smaller.
So we get an idea we'll say point to point one point three and point four.
Save that.
Run it again.
And then we can see the different been with here.
So you can see how they correspond to the bin sizes we chose how this last one the next four has a much
larger science than for instance point one and point two.
So that's how you can change the science for each of these different distributions individually or to
finish off this lecture.
Let's go ahead and revisit that problem are we had Mark Twain versus the Snodgrass data.
What I'm going to do is just copy and paste that over from the notes again so he can copy and paste
this from the 3 PI file.
But basically we have those distributions for Snodgrass versus Twain.
And hopefully when we plot this out we'll be able to tell even more clearly not just from the box plots
but from distribution plots that these are definitely different authors or at least very distinct writing
styles.
So for his data instead of being X when X 2 and so on we're going to say Snodgrass and Twain and then
let's give these proper labels.
So the first one is Snodgrass writings and then the second one will say Mark Twain writings and then
for the bin sizes here.
After some experimentation what probably works that I noticed is zero point zero or five and 0.00 five
looks.
There we go because you'll notice here that these are actually quite small values.
Serbin sizes should be pretty small as well.
I'm going to save this.
And let's check out the distribution and see if we can clearly see how separate these are.
All right so BREENE over our histograms.
You'll notice that are bin sizes aren't really that great.
But unfortunately we don't have enough data points to make some nice histograms.
And because of that issue history by themselves would not really have been enough for this sort of analysis.
But we can see here from the distribution that we have some nice Kaytee plots and the rug point plot
themselves that clearly there's a different distribution between these two sets of authors.
So you can see the mark twain writings over here in orange and the Snodgrass writings in blue.
Now we can see how they stack up against each other again leading us to conclude that whoever wrote
these writings from Snodgrass is probably not the same person who wrote Mark Twain's writings.
OK so you can play around that further because Mussar out the size and see if you can figure out a better
one.
But unfortunately for this particular problem since the points are so small and we actually don't have
that many points it becomes difficult to choose a nice histogram which is why the distribution plot
is really nice because we get to see those other layers of information including that Kaytee plot and
the plot.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
Thanks.