Welcome back.
Now that we've seen how to connect two components of a simple dash callback Let's expand on this idea
to use Dasch callbacks with graphs.
I'm first going to show you with the finished dashboard we're going to create looks like.
And then we will code it out in our text editor.
Keep in mind this is going to be one of the more complex codes we've done so far.
Let's check at the dashboard now.
All right here we can see our actual dashboard.
Notice how we have essentially a scatterplot and this is the life expectancy and GDP per capita.
And notice we also have a logarithmic scale.
So it goes from 10000 to 10 k to 100 K because of the differences between some of these countries.
So you'll also notice there's a drop down menu.
And the drop down menu is actually directly connected to the data behind this plot.
So I can choose something like 1992 and the plot will automatically update to show the life expectancy
and GDP per capita for these countries for 1992.
You'll also notice that this is actually a mini scatterplot on the same figure.
Which means I can then adjust by clicking on this legend for different continents.
So if I only want in Asia and Europe I could select these and then I can also double click to only select
that one or click them all to bring them all back in.
And again we also have this dropdown menu that's connected for any year we're interested in.
OK let's code this out by jumping toward text editor.
Right.
Here we are at the text editor to save a little bit of time.
I've already done the imports and I've read in the CSP File we've imported Dasch core components and
each team l components input and output from dasht dependencies.
And since we're going to be applauding that scatterplot We've also imported polygraph objects and pand
those in order to read in the data set.
So the data is that we're going to be using is the gap minder data five year that CXXVI let's print
it out at least ahead of the dataset so we can get an idea of what it looks like I'm going to run Python.
Well first let me say this then I'm going to run Python and I've called this file basic about pi.
So I run this and we print out those first few lines of the actual dataset.
So every row represents a country in a particular year the population has what continent it belongs
to.
The life expectancy during that year and the GDP per capita.
So you'll notice in the very beginning it's all Afghanistan but later on once you've done all the years
for Afghanistan they'll move on to the next country and so on.
You'll also notice that the years have five year jumps between them.
So another way understand what the status looks like.
Really what we're interested in is grabbing all this data and then filtering out based on the year or
at the continent.
So let's expand on this.
We have our data set ready to go.
We're going to create our application by saying dash dash.
And then we will begin by actually creating our LEO or it's going to be quite simple.
It's going to be an aged female div..
And this is going to be a list of essentially just two components one is going to be the graph.
So they'll be Dash core graph.
And here we're just going to give it an ID so we'll call this ID.
And then the second component we're going to create is that the core components drop down
and this drop down will go ahead and say call it year picker and if we take a look at the actual dropdown
documentation we bring it over.
You'll notice that for just a normal default drop down a dash core component drop down.
If we zoom in here it's going to have an I.D. which you're going to use later on to connect for the
actual callback.
And then it has a list of options and each thing in the option is essentially a label.
That's what the actual user sees and the value that's what we're going to work with inside of our dashboard
code.
So we need to somehow create this options list for every year inside of that data frame and luckily
we can use a for loop along the little bit of this code to make that relatively simple.
Let's jump back toward sex ed. to make that happen.
So inside of this dropdown again what we want is to create that options.
So say options is equal to.
And we're going to say year underscore options and let's define a year underscore options above this
layout call when Create a couple more lines here and I will do the following.
I will say that your options is going to start off as an empty list and then for every year in DMF year
unique because remember years are going to be repeated per country.
So for every unique year essentially every five years I'm going to grab your options and I will append
to it that one of those dictionaries.
So remember that dictionary takes in a label and the label will have the string version of the year
and then the value will just be the integer version of the year.
The reason I'm passing this in as a string here is because we wanted to split a string in the dashboard
and then the value we want to play around with that as the actual integer.
So the data type of this column happens to be an integer for the year if you want to show it as label
will want to convert that to a string here.
And now we have our year options.
So that's the options here.
And let's finally give it a default value will say the default value is just the minimum year say the
full value is year min save that and we have earlier.
So really simple.
Most of the code that we need to update is actually in our function.
So we'll come down here and we'll create our function we'll create an up figure function this figure
function is essentially going to connect that drop down to the actual figure.
So we will say selected ear.
And then at the end we want to return something.
So right now we'll just have it commented out and we might as well fill this out now since we're at
the bottom will say if name is equal to main ticker app and run the server.
All right.
So we figure we're going to have a bunch of code in here.
But before we add in that code let's add in the callback will see at at the callback and let's see what
we actually want to connect.
I want to connect the input from the dropdown menu to the output of this graph so our callback will
start the output.
We're going to grab graph that's our component ID and then the property we want to connect.
So it's actually going to be connecting to a figure.
We're going to pass and figure here and then for the input.
Remember that goes inside of a list will say input here and then that one is called Year picker
and then the thing we want to adjust there.
Basically as our input is the value chosen so we'll say value.
So all this is saying is that you want the input to be this year Pickert drop down selection and you
want to grab the value that's the property you're grabbing from this component ID.
So we're saying grab the year picker value and then you'll put that in the output for this graph and
then the figure is what we have left to create in this update figure.
So what we will do here is based off the selected year that's passed in as an input.
We're going to filter our data frame for that.
So I'll say that the filtered data frame is going to be equal to our data frame where the Year
is equal to that passed and selected year.
So right now for this step this is data only for selected year from the dropdown menu.
So now we have our filtered data frame.
It's time to actually create the traces for each continent.
So I will say Trace's is an empty list.
And then for every continent's name wherever you want to call this variable in my filtered data from
four continents unique
what I'm going to do is create a scatter plot.
So I'll say DSF by continents
is equal to that filter T.F. where the filter T.F. content column is equal to that continent name.
So what this is saying right now is for every continent name in the list of unique continents.
Essentially this is just going to be for America for Asia for Africa and so on.
Take that data frame filtered again.
Now by that content.
So we've already filtered it by ear.
Now we're going to filter it by that particular continent and for each of these continents we're going
to create a trace so grab our traces list and we're going to pen go that scatter.
And this is we're going to pass in our x y values so X that's going to be DMF by continents.
And our x axis that's the GDP per capita the y values repassing in that's going to be the life expectancy.
So again that death by continents and I will say life expectancy.
And we want this to be a scatterplot.
So we'll say mode is equal to marker's.
Hopefully this feels really familiar from everything we learned about plotless.
Essentially all we're doing right now is creating a scatterplot and then appending that to the trace
for every single continent after it's been filtered by the year.
And you can do this essentially updating each time a new year are selected.
So we have moed markers and let's give them some opacity.
So that way we can see through them a little bit.
So I'll leave that as like 0.7 and you can add more styling if you want.
We'll increase the marker size a little bit by passing in a dictionary here where the size will set
it to 15 and then finally the name will have it be linked to a consonant name.
So remember a continent name right here at this variable is essentially going to be America's Oceana
Africa Asia and so on.
So that is our main update function I will zoom out a little bit so we can see the entire picture.
Now we still need to return something.
So what we need to return is the actual dictionary that's going to go inside of this graph.
Call.
So that's how we're going to do the following.
We'll return the dictionary.
Mean are these dictionaries for these graphs that take in a data and a layout.
So let's first do the data.
That one's easy.
That's just the Trace's list then for the lay out what we can do is we pasan it go that way outcall
and then it's up to you how much detail you want to go in here.
Let's go ahead and give it a title.
We'll say the title is just equal to my plot and let's give it a title for the x axis and the title
for the y axis so x axis.
Remember this one's a little different.
You passen a dictionary here.
So the x axis that's GDP per capita.
And we want this to be logarithmic.
So the way we do that is we say type and pass and log in just in case you're wondering.
I definitely don't memorize all these parameter calls.
I'm always referencing the documentation and dash for things like lay out and scatter plots.
So keep that in mind.
We want to become experts in looking up information not having to memorize all these calls.
And let's give a Y-axis title as well.
So the title for this.
That one's going to be life expectancy.
OK so we have life expectancy there.
Let's make sure I spell that right.
There you go.
Save it.
And that should be all we need.
Let's make sure this actually runs and then we'll do a final review of it.
My basic thought PI make sure I'll have any errors or typos there.
All right let's go to our browsers see if it's running.
All right so here I am at the browser.
It looks like all traces ended up on the scatterplot we can see the x and y axis.
I can see that I have my logarithmic scale and let's see if our dropdown actually affects this.
So I'll choose something like 2007 and then we can see definitely the changes.
And let's go pick another year 1982 and it looks like it is updating for all the years.
So we can see here Kuwait over at the very right end of the scale in 1982 shoes a different year in
1952 we could see Kuwait now much much further ahead in 1952 versus all the other countries.
And that actually has to do more with the fact that it has such a low population that year and it comes
back closer to everyone else as everyone else as populations ends up growing.
OK.
So let's do a final review of all the code that actually created all of this.
And we can also check to see here if traces can be isolated.
Looks like they can be.
So let's do a final review.
All right a lot going on here.
First off we have all our imports so that should be pretty straightforward.
Then we read in our data then we create our application and then we had to create these your options
specifically for this drop them component.
So let's skip ahead and look at lay out our app.
It's actually very simple.
It's just a graph and a dropdown and this dropdown needed the options and the options needed to be in
this dictionary format of label and value.
So we created this little for loop here in order to conveniently put that as the options then the default
value.
It was just the minimum year then we have this update figure function.
We connected a callback so that the output would connect to the figure of this graph and the input would
be whatever value was chosen in this dropdown year picker.
Then we have this update figure that takes that selected here from the dropdown menu.
It filters the data frame by that year and then it's going to create traces for every continent.
I remember now we've already filtered by that year.
So this is the main thing that's updating all the traces.
When you pick a specific year because you're essentially running this command of filtering that data
frame.
So for every continent in the list of continents in that filter data frame you're going to then grab
the data frame by a particular continents and then you're going to append a new scatter.
The reason we're doing this by continent is that we each continent can have its own trace meaning we
can have that little Legin that we can click on and off so that legend is actually created automatically
by politely when you have many scatter plots in the same Trace's list.
We are x and y values.
We set the mode to markers and then we set some style calls here.
Finally we need to return what the figure is actually going to look like.
So remember this is essentially the dictionary that's going to be inserted into this graph right here.
So that's the figure for this graph.
So we have our data traces just as we've done before.
And then we have our ileo.
And again you can say whatever really you want in this layout.
We just did the title the x axis and the y axis.
OK.
So that's definitely a lot of code you're going to want to check out the guidebook for a breakdown of
all these lines.
But if you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums.
If you are getting the syntax errors.
Make sure to copy and paste our code to make sure you weren't making a typo.
It's very easy to make a typo give given how many open and close print season bracket calls there are
when using plot line dash.
Thanks everyone and we'll see you at the next lecture.