Welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about heat maps heat maps allow the visualization of
three features categorical or continuous features along the x and y axis to make up a grid and then
a third continuous feature.
This blade three color scale.
So here we see on the x and y axis some arbitrary continuous features and then we separate them into
intervals in order to form a grid.
And then if we want to show the value of a third variable for points that fall within each of these
grid blocks where we can do is have a color scale.
So this is for continuous features.
And often this example for heat map is really clear with categorical features instead.
So here is another example for categorical features.
So on the y axis we have morning afternoon and evening and then on the x axis we have weekdays Monday
through Friday and we can imagine that this color scale is something like temperatures.
So we could say it's really hot on Thursday afternoons and it's really cold on Monday mornings or Thursday
evenings.
And this is just fake data.
But hopefully you can get an idea of what the heat map is trying to display.
We have three features that we're showing here.
One on the x axis one on the y axis and then one three color scale.
So this is some real data points here and we can see we have Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday
Sunday Monday on our x axis.
So the days of the week there and then on the y axis we actually have the hour block of the day.
So from 0 to 1 From wanted to 2 to 3 and so on.
And then what we're showing here are hourly temperatures from June 1st through the 7th in 2010 in Arizona
so we can see here that these temperatures are in Celsius and that it was really hot on Sunday around
late afternoon and that it was really quite colder.
And Wednesday towards the very early in the morning hour like 4:00 a.m. 5:00 a.m. And now we can see
just visually what times of the week and what days it was really hot for this particular week and what
time of the day and what days of the week that it was particularly cold.
So we're actually going to use this data set to plot out our own heat maps and remember heat maps.
It doesn't have to be related to temperature.
It's just that temperature is a nice thing to display visually with color.
Let's go ahead and jump toward sex ed..
All right.
Here we are back with a text editor I've already imported partly off line as go.
The next thing going to do is import plot Lee and then graph objects as we've done in the past as go.
And since we're going to be using real data I'm going to import pandas as PD so the data we're going
to start off with is a temperature data set for Santa Barbara California.
We're going to say PD read CSP and underneath are data folder.
We're going to say 20 10 Santa Barbara
capital C capital in California.
That's CSC.
And as always you can copy and paste these commands from the provided notes.
OK so the first thing I want to do is set up our data list and then just as we've done many times in
the past we'll say go dots and for maps as you may have guessed it's just heat map.
So we need provide three things here need provide the X column the Y column and the Z column.
So for X we're going to do is provide if we take a look real quick at this data set just to show you
what it looks like going to print it out.
Let's also print out the columns as well.
The columns save that if I run this now Python basic apply those we have in Ellas to date a day tee
time and T our average.
So what does that actually mean when we take a look at our dataset.
Well from our dataset I can see that I have a date week weekday and then the time and the temperature
Our average.
So what this actually means is we're going to be using the day of the week for part of our grid.
So the day of a week is going to be our x axis so I can actually comment this out and start providing
this here.
So X-axis that's going to be the day of the week and for our Y-axis we're going to use the hour.
So the hour for that that's going to be this elist tea time column.
So for.
We'll go ahead and say DMF Ellis t underscore time.
We don't really need that here because it's already kind of implied with day or here if you wanted to.
If you want to weigh more grid's you could say the date but were you going to use that instead.
And then for easy access remember that's going to be the color.
So for this look we're going to say Z is equal to f and I will say t underscore h r underscore average
which just reports back the temperature for the hour.
The average of that.
So if you're reading this you can see on Tuesday of this particular day at zero hundred hours the average
temperature for that hour was twelve point seven degrees Celsius.
Then the next one that same date on that same Tuesday at 1:00 a.m. the temperature on average was twelve
point seven.
And so on.
So that's how this data is organized.
Now something to know because Z is actually going to be a color scale.
It can't actually except a Pandurs column.
Instead what you need to do for this is have a python list and the way you can convert a panda's column
to a Python list is by adding on the commands values dot and then to list open close parentheses.
So the reason we're doing this is because for this heat map Z needs to be a python list.
It won't be able to accept the pan this column.
So that's why we're converting it as such.
So let me now expand on this a little bit.
And what kind of Z on its own separate line here.
Just so it's a little more readable.
And then we can define ileo as well just as we've done in the past we'll say go that way out and here
it just provide a title will say Santa Barbara California tops and we'll create a figure object.
Go figure.
And here would just say the sequel to data and Aralia is equal to the LIA and let's plot this figure.
Why plot has and the figure and as always if you want you can provide a file name so I will call Python
basic pi.
Run that and I should see a temperature plot.
So right here we have the temperature plot and you'll notice though we can see the actual temperature
and the x y and z information as we hover over this so I can see at Wednesday.
Y is equal to 3 so that's at 3 am.
The temperature on average for that hour on that Wednesday was ten point five degrees.
So you can hover around and see more information but what's really nice about this is just visually
from kind of a bird's eye view.
I can get an idea of what days and what times were the hottest and what days and what times were the
coolest.
So definitely it looks like it got hotter on Saturday and Sunday.
A little bit Monday and also Wednesday afternoon was little hot and I can see definitely the coolest
time was around Wednesday in the morning and that Sunday and Monday and those were actually quite warm
mornings there.
So that's the kind of information you can gleam from a heat map very quickly.
Going to close this.
Something else I want to point out is you can choose different color skills.
So instead of just saying X Y Z inside your heat map as another parameter here we can say color scale
and you can check out the documentation for all the various color skills that are available to you.
But one really common one to use jet.
So if you use jet and run this again you'll get kind of this brighter color between essentially the
rainbow blue and red.
So some of it is a little extreme but this definitely points out very clearly the coldest and hottest
temperatures.
So that's another option for you to begin playing around if the color scales.
You can check out the partly documentation for what color scales are available.
Let me close this now so let's move on and expand on this.
So I'm going to expand on.
Is having multiple heat maps on one plot.
In general we just want to expand the idea of having subplots So multiple plots on the same thing especially
of heat maps.
So you'll notice that we don't just have Santa Barbara data.
If you take a look at our data folder we'll set other files.
So if I were to say copy this and paste this I'm going to comment this line out of control forward slash.
All we can do here is.
We don't know what we need to print that out.
I'm going to use the other dataset that we provided which is 2010 Uma azy.
So Yuma Arizona to really hop place specially for these time stamps that we're working with.
So now if we run this we'll be able to see that city's heat map so you can see here that city's heat
map right now this all scaled to that particular city looks like actually than it changed the title
but hopefully get the idea what I want to do now is plot various cities on the same plot with plots.
All right so now let's go ahead and work on the problem of showing multiple heat maps in the same figure
in an order to do that.
We're going to need to work with subplots.
So this is going to be one of the more demanding visualizations that we've done so far.
First off we need our three data sets so we have this data set for three cities for their temperatures
and we'll use a very similar command for all of them.
We're going to read them all in.
We've read CSFB and let's make sure that's a string inside that data folder.
There's some data from a city in Alaska.
So this one's going to be probably the call the city C S V and then we have the Santa Barbara City that
we've been working with.
So again read C S V and then 2010 Santa Barbara lets make sure you spell that right.
Barbara California see as we can always copy and paste these from the notes and then read C S we will
say data.
And this last one is from Yuma.
So that really hot city.
Yuma Arizona.
OK so let's set up traces for each of these.
We're going to say trace one is equal to.
We're going to call her heat map again.
We'll see X equal to just like before except the one day why it's going to be equal to the one ls t
time and then Z is going to be equal to the F one and the string was t underscore h r underscore average
whip's underscore.
So that was that hourly temperature average.
So now that we have are X Y and Z Well we should also set up is our color scale to make it look a little
nicer.
We'll go ahead and choose again.
Again lots of different options there in the documentation you can check out color scale.
And since we're going to be plotting multiple heap maps we should also add max and min color values
to make each plot consistent with each other.
So we will say Zeeman is equal to 5 and Z Max is equal to 40 degrees.
And then I'm going to copy and paste this trace two more times.
Since we are going to have it for each dataset and what I need to do now is go ahead and rename these
traces to trace 2 and trace 3 as well as edit the data from calls.
So the to the to the to.
Looks like I forgot the one here in this first one.
And let's change this one to three.
The three and the three or so I have my three heap maps and now I need to organize them using subplots.
So the way we need to do this is actually import from Plumley set up at the top.
I will save from plot Lee import tools and the tools library of politely allows us to create these subplots.
So let's see how that works.
Well say figure.
Or fig is equal to tools and then underneath tools there is a make subplots function and the make subplots
function is going to take an a rose argument and a column's argument so you can decide how you wanted
this play.
These heat maps if you want one row with three columns that means you're going to have the three heat
maps right next to each other in a horizontal line.
If we do it the other way with three rows and one column then you'll see the heat maps kind of on top
of each other.
So one right below the other let's go ahead and give it one row we'll say Rose is equal to 1.
And since we have three heat maps we'll say columns is equal to three and then the other thing I can
provide is subplot titles.
So subplot underscore titles and set that equal to a list of titles corresponding to each of these traces
you're going to pass.
So since we passing them in order we'll say that the first one will be Sitka AK for Alaska.
The second one we'll just say SB California Santa Barbara California and the last one is Yuma Arizona.
OK.
So there is a subplot titles.
And finally the last thing you want to ask are passen here is shared underscore y axes a set that equal
to true.
So this makes the hours appear only on the left.
So what that means is all of these heat maps they're actually going to share at the same time stamps
on the y axis because every single one of these places has hours 0 to 1 1 to 2 AM 3 or 4 am and so on.
If we didn't say shared why access equals to true then it would have a separate y axis for each of these.
And we don't actually really need that.
So we can set the stickle to true.
So we each share the y axis.
At least visually you can go ahead and play around with that and said equal to false to experiment and
see what you prefer as far as your looks.
Now the thing that's going to be a little different here is from the figure object we're going to call
append the trace and then we pass in the trace we want to append and then we pass in the coordinates
of where it goes.
Inside of this make subplots So recall that we have rows equal to 1 and columns equal to three.
So what you do here when you're appending the trace is you decide OK where do you want ptrace want to
go.
I wanted to go in row 1 in column 1.
So that's the one all the way to the left.
And then we can say Fig.
Append trace portrays to.
I want that one to again also be in row 1.
We only have one row but then it's going to go in the second column right in the middle.
And then we'll say Fig.
A pen trace and then we'll say trace 3 and again we only have one row so that goes for 1 and then it's
going to go in the third column.
So somebody to know here is that indexing is basically starting at 1 instead of 0 which is more typical
of Python.
So keep that in mind.
So again it's just the trace you want to pass in the row.
It belongs in the makes up subplots come in in the column it belongs in.
And once you've set up that fig with a pen trace where we can say is Io plot Fig.
So let's see what this looks like and come we'll come back and actually affect the lay out.
So let's run Python basic pie and whip's.
Let's make sure it looks like 20 human Asie doesn't exist.
I think I forgot C S V here C S V We save that.
Now tremoring that again.
OK perfect.
So it actually reports back the format of your plot grade which is kind of nice but if we just bring
it over and check it out we'll be able to see the temperatures.
So notice now they're all sharing the same Y scale.
So over here on this model heat map I don't see the Y scale here.
Neither do I on the right because I said shared y.
If we were to come back and turn that to false.
So then here we go ahead and say this is false.
Save that and run it again.
Then what you'll end up seeing is that they each have their own y axis.
It's really up to you which you prefer.
Sometimes if you have lots of these different subplots it might be nice for them to all share the same
y axis but it also it's nice to imply that they're all sharing the same y axis along all the way to
the left so it's really up to you which style you prefer.
And what I also want to know is now we can clearly see which is the hottest city.
Yuma Arizona which is called the city here in Alaska.
And they're all sharing the same colored bar and you'll also notice that they're all sharing that same
men value of five and the max value of 40 because we said Zeeman and Z max for all of them.
And we didn't really want a separate color scale for each of these maps.
Something else you can do is if you wanted to give a title to this entire plot so something here at
the very top that is how they each have their own basic subtitles there.
Well we can do is come back here.
So we gave them their all separate subplot titles if you want to edit the actual layout of the entire
object.
We can say is Fig and just like a dictionary call.
You can actually call lay out from this figure object.
So I will say Fig.
Lay out and then call the up command as is essentially allowing us to access the layout that rectally.
So I can set the title here.
So I could say temp's for three cities save it and when I run this again I should now see a title pop
up at the very top.
So bring that in and I can see temp's for three cities right here on the top.
OK.
So let's quickly review because this was a more complex plot in regards to plot Lee but we just did.
We ended up doing as we read in three data sets and then we created 3 heat maps or three traces essentially
the same data for all of them.
We set the color scale and the Zeeman and C-Max and then the thing that we introduced that was new was
this makes subplots come in where you define how many rows and how many columns you want what the plot
titles are going to be or regards to how these titles match up they're going to be matched up in the
same order that you appended the traces in.
So keep that in mind and it's up to you whether you want to share the y axis and set that to a false
or true.
And you can check out the make subplots documentation for a few other useful parameters to.
But once you've set up your subplots then you just append traces and you say passing the trace and you
decide what roads going in and what column it's going in.
And if you want to update the figures lay out as a total You just call figlio and then update ampacity
whatever you want to update there and then plot your figure.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Kewaunee forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.