Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss line charts a line chart displays a series of data
points called markers connected by line segments.
So this actually means that a lighter is essentially the same thing as a scatterplot except this time
we're just having line segments that connect each of the points.
One of the main differences however between a typical line chert versus just taking a scatterplot and
connecting all those points together is that the x value on the x axis is going to be sorted or ordered
in some way.
So that makes it really useful to use a line chart to visualize a trend then data over an interval of
time which is known as a time series.
So that's typically why you see an actual difference between a light chert versus just a scatterplot
with lines connecting the points.
It's that on the x axis there's some sort of designation of order from left to right.
So here's an example of a simple white Chur that we can see here that essentially we have some sort
of series of points that have all been connected with lines.
And in this case we're actually not even designating those points of markers.
Instead we're just showing the line and the x axis is ordered.
So we can think that as we go from left to right the x axis goes and grows bigger.
Now we can use different styles for the line charts.
And here we can see the three styles that are available to us with Clottey.
And that's just lines.
So just a line by itself here and blue at top lines and the markers we can see here.
Each marker point and the line segment that connects them.
Or if you want.
You can stick with just markers and the recall that's essentially just a scatterplot like we did before.
And in fact when we work on the off line charts completely it's going to be the same and go scatterplot
call that we saw in the previous scatterplot lecture.
Except now we're going to add in things like calling lines or lines plus markers as her actual mode
instead of just saying markers.
OK.
So let's explore all of this with her actual code inside of a text editor.
All right so here we are our text editor.
I've already imported some pies and P as well as partly off line and plot lead graph objects as go and
if a random seed again you can choose whatever random seed you want but if you want your results to
look exactly like they are in our notes go ahead and choose the number 56.
In this case because that's the number that gave me a nice scatter that I could connect with.
So we have that random seed.
So let's go ahead and create some x values and y values will say x values for this.
We're going to use NPE lens space which is going to allow us create 100 evenly spaced values so I'll
say from 0 to 1.
Give me 100 evenly spaced values.
So that's going to be our ordered x axis to use for our line chart and for y values or we're going to
say just a bunch of random points we'll say and P random and we'll go from a random normal distribution
random end and which can pass and 100 there.
So give me 100 random values for those y values.
And now it's time to actually create the line charts.
So the syntax that platies documentation likes to use is that every single line chart we're going to
put on to our figure is called a trace.
So you usually see something like this you'll see a trace and then that will be assigned from Go-Kart
scatter your x value your y values and then you can give it a mode and a name.
So we're going to start off of one trace.
Put that into our data call edit the layout a little bit and then plot that figure.
And hopefully this will start to bring some sort of clarification to using data and layout.
So we have trace go that scatter.
And what I'm going to do here is provide the arguments.
So for ex that's going to be x values then for the Y on the scatterplot it's going to be let's say oops
Y is equal to y values and we're going to say y values plus 5.
So what is going to do is it's going to add 5 to every single value from that random set of numbers.
So we have X and Y and we're also going to then say the following will add in mode is equal to.
And in this case we'll just keep it as markers and the name we're going to keep here is markers as well.
So right now I just have one trace and then what platies documentation likes to do is inside our data
list.
We just pass in that trace.
So before we were passing in Go-Kart scattered directly into this list now for organization we're going
to just set it as a variable.
Trace and then put in that trace into this data variable then we're going to continue on with our lay
out call and our layout is just going to be go lay out and we'll give this tidal just like chart's
OK.
So then we just say our figure object is equal to go figure we'll say data is equal to that data list
and lay out is equal to earlier options that we just created.
Now we're ready to actually plot this.
So we say Wyo. plot passen that figure and you can give this a file name if you want.
I'll go in and get the file name.
So it's just going to overwrite temp Dasch plot each time.
So let's say this emic sure we see what we've done.
We created some random data for line chart we need x values and y values.
We went ahead and we still use Go-Kart scatter and we'll see how we can edit this in just a minute to
actually create the line chart.
Right now our mode is just markers that we take taken that go scatter put insider data list creator
to layer object which technically is optional.
It's just added things like the title the x axis the y axis titles then we pass that into data and layout
in this figure object and we plot that figure object.
So hopefully it's starting to make sense the separation between data and layout and then using figure
and dot plot with that figure let's make sure to save this and run the file we run Python basic that
pie or whatever you happen to actually call this file and then that should bring up the age T.M. and
automatically open it for you.
So we're going to bring over the actual plot we just created.
And right now it looks like a scatterplot which makes sense because we set the mode equal to just markers.
So now let's explore how we could add in the actual line segments themselves.
So we'll come back to our code and what we're going to do here is we're going to instead of editing
our trace right here.
Well we're going to do is create another trace we'll say trace 0 is equal to this first scatter call
and then I'm going to make trace one equal to another scatterplot.
But this time when I'm going to say is X X values y is equal to y values.
And now instead of saying mode is equal to marker's I'm going to say that the mode is equal two lines
and we'll give it the same name.
Technically the name can be whatever you want it to be called.
So you can say like my lines.
That's not a special string code.
There is just the name.
As you hover over it what slightly thinks the sexual figure plot is called.
OK.
So right now hopefully you have an understanding that this first plot we created is just the markers
themselves.
And it took the y values and added five of them.
So the original value is now kind of in the middle of our graph.
It's just going to be the straight lines.
And now we can see that data.
The reason it's a list here is because this allows me to easily add in multiple plots.
So now I can have a list of plots like Trace's 0 trace 1 in my data list and that's the real reason
why it was a list.
When you're plotting just a single plot it kind of doesn't make sense that it's a list of a single item
but it really makes sense when you want to put in multiple plots onto the same figure.
So again just adding another scatterplot except this time they didn't.
The mode is lines.
So we're going to save this and run our file again.
Then it should overwrite that temp plot that each T.M. and open it up for you.
So let's go ahead and grab this guy and bring it over.
And now we can see the line plot that we just created and you'll notice as you hover over you can see
the actual name you can see my lines on that orange It may be a little small free to see on my screen
but if you're following along on your screen you'll be able to see that name you gave the plot so you
can move along and see the difference between just using markers versus calling lines.
And finally we're going to do here is add in one more trace so you can see the last option which is
lines and markers put together.
So we'll just copy and paste here.
We'll say trace 2 0 1 2 and the mode that we're going to specify here is going to be equal to instead
of just lines all sight lines plus markers.
And I can give this name again whatever I want so we'll say we can even say like my favorite save that
and then we just need to add in that trace to our data that we're passing in we'll say traced to save
this.
And if we run this again then we should see three different line charts on that same plot.
And whoops looks like I forgot to actually subtract five.
So let me subtract 5 from this y.
Otherwise these two plots are going to be right on top of each other.
Let me save that again.
Run that.
So again just to reiterate I have plus five the original values and minus 5 because if we set them all
as y values then they're all going to be right on top of each other in Knoxville to see all three of
them.
So that's where we have the plus five and minus five.
So it's going to run that again.
Some basic pi.
And let me grab that each time I'll file so we can show it off here.
So grabbing that HTML file here we can see the markers the my lines.
And then at the bottom that green my favorite.
And you can see that now has zoom in closer.
Here it shows the points and the line segments.
OK.
So that's the very basics of creating line charts with Motley.