Welcome everyone to the general installation and setup lecture here we're going to get you set up with
Python a development environment or ID and then we're also going to show you how to get the required
libraries.
So in general we'll set up Python.
Anaconda we'll set up the Adam text editor and also set up plotlines and dash environments.
Something I want to make clear is as an experienced user of Python you've enrolled in this course and
you probably already have Python on your computer and you may already have a developer environment that
you prefer because of this.
We've set time stamps here that you can jump ahead to whatever part of this lecture works for you.
And if you've already set up Python and you know how to install libraries and you already have your
own preferred developer environment you are probably going to be able to skip this lecture entirely.
So I just want to make that clear.
If you're in this course you've probably already done a lot of this and you may or may not find this
useful because of that.
We set up timestamps so you can jump ahead and visit the sections that are most relevant to you.
OK let's get started with setting up Python and we'll move on to then setting up Adam as well as our
environment.
All right.
Here we are at the Anaconda dot com slash download page and it may look slightly different for you.
As far as styling is concerned but there should be three main links one for Windows one for Mac OS and
one for Linux.
On this page Anaconda's going to come with lots of data science packages.
That's why it's a distribution.
It also comes with package management as well as environment management with Conda.
So that's a tool we're going to be using as well.
So go ahead and click on the operating system that's relevant to you.
For Windows you're going to want to install the Python 3 version and I recommend the graphical installer.
There's a 64 bit version and a 32 bit version that depends on your computer.
Then for Mac OS if you're a Mac OS I would also recommend doing the graphical installer here.
So go ahead and download that graphical installer.
And if you're on Linux there is an installer here for you.
For 64 bit as well as an installer for 32 bit.
OK so once you've downloaded that actual installer in order to receive instructions on how to download
it after you click on whatever your relevant operating system is you should notice that there's a link
here.
How to install Anaconda.
Go ahead and click on that link and it will take you to Dock's and Akala dot com slash Anaconda slash
install and then slash your operating system.
So here we have the instructions for installing on Windows and for most of these it's quite straightforward.
Especially for the graphical installers you're just clicking along.
The only thing I want to clarify is as you go along you'll notice that there's an advanced installation
option set and this is going to ask you if you want to add anaconda to my path environment variable.
If you click on this it will turn red and say Not recommended we personally recommend clicking on that
and adding anaconda to your path environment variable.
That way you can actually call Python and Konda at your command line.
So again we highly recommend that you add anaconda to my path environment variable.
That way you can call Python at your command line.
So even though it says not recommended go ahead and check that box anyways you'll see the text turned
red and then hit install.
So again if you're ever asked to add anaconda to my path var. var..
Make sure you select that option.
OK so that's the option for Windows.
Again if you click on here for any of the other operating system such a Mac OS and click on how to install
Anaconda it will take you to the Mac OS graphical install instructions page which is right here again.
Essentially it is following along.
And again if it ever asks you to add anaconda to your path go ahead and select yes to that.
Even if it says it's not recommended for Linux users it's not going to be a graphical installer.
If you click on how to install anaconda it's basically just going to be a bash command to wherever you
happen to have downloaded that s h file.
OK so that's the very basics of downloading.
Anaconda.
Once you've downloaded anaconda you should be able to run Python at your command line after you've finished
the installation process.
So let's go ahead and show you what that should look like.
OK we're going to quickly show you how to run Python.
This is going to be a confirmation that you've already downloaded and gone through the installer for
Anaconda.
All we need to do here is open up our command line for Windows users.
We are going to do a search for see M.D on your computer and that will open up your command prompt.
If you're on Mac OS or Linux you can search for terminal and that will open up your command line.
Let's do this.
I'm going to win this computer right now so I will search for ACMD and then open up my command prompt
All right here I am at my command prompt.
If you're on a Mac OS or Linux you should be at your terminal in order to check that Anaconda installed
correctly directly into your command line.
Type the word Python.
Hit enter and then you should see Python.
The version number and then some sort of clarification of Anaconda.
And once you've done this then you've successfully installed Anaconda in Python on your computer.
And if you want to keep testing things out you can print something like Hello hit enter and you have
hello.
Hopefully you've already worked with Python by the time you reach this course since this is a course
for more experienced Python users.
I'm going to quit out of this and we're ready to go.
Remember that for basic command lines in order to actually change directories you can use the see the
command.
And this works in either Mac OS Linux or Windows.
To go back up at the rectory you just say change directory thought and that will move back up a directory
to move forward into another folder.
You can say CD and then the name of the folder.
So for example I can move back into that folder where I was by using CD.
That's really the main command you need to know for this course just change in rectory that way you
can run your python script wherever it's located.
Let's now move on to setting up our environment since we've already set up Anaconda and Python.
All right.
Now let's set up our development environment and this course we use the Adam text editor.
If you already have your preferred development environment such as sublime or pi charm or any other
number of ideas that are available Feel free to stick with those as long as you can run a high script
at your command line.
You're pretty much good to go and you can skip this part of the lecture.
If you do want to explore falling along the fence in this course with the Adam text editor.
Keep watching and go to Adam.
Oh and let's show you how you can install Adam and set up the plug in as well as the terminal command
line there.
OK.
Here am Adam.
I.
You shouldn't notice that somewhere on the screen there's going to be a download button that's going
to automatically detect your operating system and you can just click here on this download and it should
download some sort of executable installer file and then you'll just double click that.
Follow all the defaults and install Adam.
It's a simple text editor comes off a lot of really useful features especially if you're a big get user
Adams open source and it was created by it.
So that's one of our reasons for choosing it for this course.
As I mentioned you're free to use any platform you like.
They also notice there's packages and themes so packages are basically other packages that can help
you work with out them things like Python autocomplete.
So we'll be using those as well.
Themes are things that can help you change the appearance of Adam such as fonts or coloring so you can
do that.
All of it.
Adam as well.
So there's packages and themes.
Go ahead and download and install Adam onto your computer.
And then let's open it up and show you how you can install plug ins and packages.
All right.
Once you've downloaded and installed Adam following along the defaults for the graphical installer you
should see something like this when you open at them.
However you may notice that my font or coloring is a little different than what you see as the default.
And that's because I've customized Adam to my liking.
So let's show you how you can do the same for your installation.
You'll just come to file and then go down where it says settings and you should see the core settings.
Open up and you'll notice you have here package's themes.
And then install as well as updates so packages are things that help you actually work better with whatever
programming environment or programming languages you're using.
So I have autocomplete Python which we're going to be using during this course.
I will show you how to install it in just a second.
Theme's that's going to be things like colorization or syntax themes.
So I have added material in one dark as my user interface theme and as my syntax theme.
So you can copy and use those as well.
Then you have updates once you've installed packages or themes you can update them and then you have
install.
So go ahead and come to install and then we need two main packages.
Go ahead and search for Python with packages selected here.
It's going to search packages for Python and then you'll eventually see somewhere at the very top autocomplete
python.
And I've already have it installed so you don't see the install button here but you're going to something
like this install button.
So go ahead and install autocomplete Python as I'm coding along with this course.
You'll notice a little bit of a drop down selection that helps you autocomplete your Python functions
or Python commands.
That's the package that allows me to do that.
The next package you'll probably want is the a terminal package.
So go ahead and search for terminal with packages selected and the one we like to use is platform you
dash ID dashed terminal and again install this package.
What this allows you to do is once you've installed this if you click here on this plus button it will
open up a new terminal inside of Adam.
That way you can call Python here right from inside of Adam without having to change anything.
So I can quit here.
And then what we're going to be doing is we're going to say Python and then be running scripts inside
of Adam as such.
What I want to point out is for Windows users by default it uses the power shell and usually the power
shell has issues with the Anaconda installation.
So what you're going to want to do is after you've installed the platform in the terminal what you should
do is especially if you're on a Windows computer edit this so that instead of using your power shell
by default eases your command prompt by default again this is only for Windows users.
It's a very quick fix.
You just come to packages and either search for a terminal or scroll down to find terminal number you
already installed terminal at this point click on settings and then somewhere along this you should
see Shell override where you're going to do is write this command right here.
You're going to want to have it point to see Windows system 32 C and D E x e because by default it's
going to point to power shell.
Again this is only for Windows users if you're a Mac OS or Linux it's going to automatically point to
a terminal and you shouldn't have any issues.
All right so that's the shell override.
And that's an important step for Windows users using the terminal inside of Adam.
The last thing I want to point out is editing colors and themes as I mentioned.
If you come over to the core settings and click on themes I'm using atom material and one dark as my
syntax theme if you ever want to install those you just come to install click on themes and then search
whatever themes you want such as one dark enter and you can see the one dark you find that I have installed.
So that's an option for you.
A lot of times you can play around if you like a light setting you can do that as well if you like a
darker setting.
You can do that.
And if you google search more Adam actually has the ability to put custom CSSA scripts so you can color
this however you see it.
OK that's really all there is to Adam.
The main thing here we're just installing it setting up Python autocomplete setting up this terminal
so you can call Adam and show you how to install themes and syntax themes.
All right.
Now they've installed Anaconda in Python to computer.
It's time to set up the environment.
Now technically it's optional to set up a virtual environment with the com the command line tool a virtual
environment basically allows you to create a version of Python and certain library installations on
your computer that will hold that actual versioning of the pip installed libraries.
That way you don't need to worry in case Dasch has an upgrade later on into the future.
You're going to be able to run our notes securely and make sure they work in your virtual environment.
So we're going to be using Pipp install to install the required libraries.
You can use Pitman's stall with or without that virtual environment.
However we do recommend using that virtual environment where you basically have a container that can
hold specific versions of dash and you can player on future versions of plotline in a separate virtual
environment.
So for convenience we've already created a requirements that textfile that you can use this requirements
that textfile is essentially just a list of libraries to install with Pip.
So it'll be really easy to use that your command line to just have a single line that installs all the
libraries will be using in order to actually use that requirements that text file at the command line
you're going to need to CD or change directory at your command line to wherever you say the unzipped
version of the court's notes or files.
So make sure you've already downloaded the unzipped version of the course notes files.
So usually we provide them as a zip file.
You'll download them unzip and then there should be a requirement that text file in that actual folder
that was unzipped.
So let's go to our command line find that requirements that text file and show you create a virtual
environment and then easily Pipp install all the libraries required for the course.
All right.
Here I am at my downloads folder.
You'll notice 40 unzipped the notes for this course and I have it in this folder plotless dashboards
of dash.
If you double click on that you'll notice all the folders and all are notes and if you go all the way
down you'll see a requirements that text file.
If you actually open up this requirements a text file it's just a list of libraries to install with
a Pipp install command.
So that's what we're going to be doing here.
We're going to create a virtual environment and then we're going to install all these requirements.
So it's just a few steps at your command line.
The actual step of creating a virtual environment that's technically not necessary.
You could just say pipin stall for these requirements text without creating the virtual environment.
We'll leave that as an option to you in case you didn't install Khanda or you already had Python installed
and don't really want to create virtual environments.
However we do recommend using virtual environments.
That way you can always activate and deactivate these specific versions of the libraries.
Let's head over to our command line.
OK.
Here I am at my command line.
I'm going to CD or change directory into downloads and then I'm going to change directory again into
that plot folder.
So now I will have access to that requirements that text file.
Now the next step is to actually create a virtual environment.
We're going to use Konda create and that's the Anaconda command line tool for creating a virtual environment.
If you already have Python installed and decided not to actually use Anaconda that's totally OK.
You can do our next steps without doing.
This virtual environment.
So just skip this step of Conda create and move on to the pipin small step that we're going to show.
And just a little bit.
But for Anaconda's users I would suggest creating a virtual environment.
So we'll go ahead and say Konda create dash dash name.
I want to say this is my dash ESV that's the name of our environment.
You can name it whatever you want.
And we're going to set up this environment with Python.
We'll say 3.6 enter and it will solve for the environment and basically create a virtual environment
with Python 3.6.
Ready to go for you.
They'll ask you if you want to set some things up.
Go ahead and say yes and we'll go ahead and install those packages for you.
I'm going to skip forward in time until this is done OK.
Everything was just installed.
Now I can activate and deactivate this environment.
If you're on a Windows you're going to say activate and then the environment name which is my dash envy
if you're using bash or Power Shell Well you need to say is source activate tool say source space activate
if you're on Mac OS Linux or using bash in general.
So since I'm just on a Windows computer I will say activate my dash envy again.
Mac OS Linux users say.
Source.
Space.
Activate the name of your environment.
So once you've activated that environment you should see in parentheses a little showing up of the name
of your environment.
This means that currently our environment is activated.
So this is where we want to install all the libraries from that requirements textfile.
All right once we've activated my dash in vi you should notice imprint sees my dash in a V on the left.
The next step is simply pipin stall all the requirement files.
What we need to do is make sure you cd into the specific unzipped folder that contains the requirements
that text file.
So again to do that if you ever want to go up a directory it should see the dot dot and if you ever
want to go into a directory it's CD and then you can begin typing out the actual name of your directory.
You should be able to tab autocomplete that enter and now we're in that folder.
OK so let's actually now say Pipp install Dasch are and then we're going to type out requirements that
txt file.
If you're in the right location you should be able to tab autocomplete this so that it says requirements
stop text as a quick note.
If you hit tab here and you notice it's not auto completing.
That means you either haven't unzipped the folder or you're in the wrong location and it doesn't contain
the requirements text file.
So if you ever get an issue with requirements text not found it means you're in the wrong location and
you need to CD into the location like we just showed.
So let's hit enter here and then you should get a bunch of commands reporting back collecting files
and installing the libraries.
So basically what we're installing Here are the main components for Dash the main components for flask
which Dash's built upon and then some pie and panderers.
I'm going to skip forward in time until all of these have finished downloading and installing.
All right we've jumped forward in time.
You should see it say something like successfully installed as an alternative.
You can always install the libraries as you go along this course by simply saying Pip install and then
the name of the library.
Let's make sure that this all worked by saying Python enter.
Make sure your environment was activated when you called Python and then say import dash enter and if
you don't get any error then you're good to go.
If you do get some sort of error saying dasht not found then I would recommend as you go along through
the course.
Just say Pipp install and then the library you need throughout the course will be reminding you of the
libraries were going to be using such as them pie panderers and dash.
It will tell you the instructions to install them one by one.
Either way it's not a huge inconvenience to install them one by one.
There's really not that many libraries that we use.