Welcome back.
Now that we've learned how to work with multiple inputs Let's expand our understanding for multiple
outputs.
So we just saw how we can connect multiple inputs simply by adding to the list for that input function
to obtain multiple outputs.
We will need to add multiple function and call back decorator pairs to our dashboard script.
So for this example our dashboard is going to take in two inputs one for a number of wheels and another
for a color selection.
And we're going to have two versions of the dashboard.
The first version is just going to be very simple.
It's going to display two outputs and return that back as text in your dashboard.
The second version is then going to collect information from the two inputs and display a single corresponding
output in the form of an image.
So we've already set up a data frame in this format.
We have one column which represents number of wheels.
In other column which represents a color and then a linked jpg file.
So what we're going to do is based on the inputs of wheels and colors we'll look up an image and return
that image that's going to be the second version of the dashboard.
So the images are already stored in the data folder and set up for you.
So we're going to be able to connect the input selection of colors and wheels to the appropriate image.
Let's go ahead and see what the final results are going to look like and then build it for ourselves.
We're going to build out a simpler version of the dashboard and then the second one will have the actual
images displayed back.
OK here we have the simpler first version of our dashboard here we just have two inputs and two outputs
the first input just a radio button.
It's going to return back what you've selected.
And the second one has another output and it returns back again we selected red blue yellow.
So two inputs and two separate outputs.
Then let's see what the second version of this dashboard is going to look like.
OK here we have the second version of the dashboard.
And now essentially actually have three outputs.
We do show the number so you select that one two three.
We also show the colors of that red blue or yellow.
And then the final output is an image that corresponds if your selection pair.
So you can select two wheels and then the color blue and you should see some two wheeled blue vehicle
or if we say red and the number three there we can see three wheels on a red tricycle.
So that's the main idea we've already selected all these images for you and that's why that data frame
has the column that corresponds with some JPEG name.
Let's get started by jumping to the text editor and coding this out.
We're going to start with that first version and then add the image to it.
OK here we are the text editor to save a little bit of time.
I already have the inputs for that.
Both core NHT HTL components the input and output dependencies as well as Pandurs.
And I've read in the data wheels not CSP file.
So underneath the provided data folder the CSP file has the color the wheel and the image name is wheels
that CXVII.
Let's get started by creating our application.
We will say app is equal to national cash as we've done before.
And then we'll start working with the layout going to expand this just to get a couple more lines here
and we'll say app lay out is equal to.
And we're going to create a division here.
Remember that takes an a list and we essentially just have four things right now.
We have two radio items and then two outputs.
So we will say the following from core components grab radio items.
And right now we'll just have that as an item in the list.
Then we also want something to display the output of the chosen number of wheels.
So we'll say we'll actually make that a div in itself and that will just take in some text.
Now we have another set of radio items that's going to be for the color.
And again we're going to report back what the color selection was.
And in order to make sure that we have a nice break what we can do is in-between this div and the radio
items we can add an h tim l dot capital H R and that adds kind of a horizontal rule which gives you
that little line separator.
It's up to you whether you want to add this but it gives it a nice separation between the set of items
and the Stiv and the set of items and that div..
Let's go ahead and give these IDs so we can later call them in our callbacks.
So we'll say the first one is wheels.
So that's the number of wheels.
The second one will be the output of that.
So we'll say the idea here is wheels cash output.
And then for the second pair of radio items will say that this is colors and then the output here is
just going to be colour's output this horizontal rule doesn't need anything because we won't actually
be using it in our callbacks.
So we have a radio items in our div..
Now it's time to adjust the radio items themselves to give them some options.
So this is very similar to using a dropdown.
Remember that the dropdown had this parameter called options and it was essentially a list of dictionaries
where there was a label value and there was a value value so to speak.
So we're going to construct this dictionary with list comprehension for the number of wheels.
We essentially want the label in value to be the same.
So the user sees either 1 2 or 3 and then the value is going to be the same.
So we're going to say label is I value as I.
And then we're going to construct this dictionary for I in and you have essentially two options here
you can just easily make a list.
One two three.
So that's in general if you only had three numbers which in this case we only have three wheels but
let's say you had a data frame with many more unique options we could also do is just grab the wheels
column and then ask for that unique values.
I mean sure sort of spell that right.
OK so this is essentially going to say grab me all the unique values from the wheels and in our case
we only have one two and three as the unique values in that wheels column.
And you can print out the data frame and check that out yourself.
But this is going to be kind of more generic than just saying one two three.
All right so we had the idea or idea for the wheels.
The options we're going to construct this list of dictionaries using list comprehensions.
And finally let's give it a default value.
So I want to zoom out just a little bit so we can see the whole thing.
So the value itself we're going to say value is just a default.
We'll have it start as one and we're going to do a very similar thing for the second pair of radio items.
So it's copy options and values and then edit it to what we need.
So say color here enter.
Get some type of spacing here and I'm going to copy paste options and the value.
Except this time it's going to be colors.
So it's sort of being numbers for the value.
I will say that the default value for the colors is blue and then we're going to have the same I label
value.
But in this case we don't want unique wheels.
We want unique color which is just red blue and yellow.
Alternatively you could have manually written out a list of strings with red blue and yellow but this
is more generic.
And they'll work better for us in the future.
OK.
So that's basically all we need for our particular layout.
We're going to add a little bit of style to it to this overall div and that's just an optional style
so it looks a little nicer.
So we can add a font family to this and you can technically add in whatever you want.
So this is just to show you how you would edit the fonts.
So shoes Helvetica and then we'll also say adjust the font size and let's make it 18 again.
This is totally optional.
It's just styling elements kind of going to introduce these slowly throughout the course so you can
get an idea of how to customize your dashboards through style calls.
Remember the style is now associated with this outermost div So we just took care of the layout.
Now we need to do is create two functions one for the wheels and then one for the color values.
Then after that we should be done and be able to run our server.
So let's connect these will say the F and we'll have this be a back a and this is going to take in some
value for the wheels.
And this is going to return you chose and then we'll just say that format's whatever that wheel's value
was.
So that's the number that was chosen.
So that's called back a and we'll make another one called call back be it's really up to you what you
want to call these functions but Colback B that's going to correspond with the colors values will say
colors value and it's going to be the same thing return you chose and then I'll tell you for formatting
what colors value chose will say colors value.
All right.
Now currently These functions are actually connected to any inputs or outputs and specifically we want
to connect these IDs for wheels and wheels output as well as colors and colors output.
So we'll see that through the use of callbacks.
So this first one will say at app that callback
and this is going to take in an output and also an input I remember input goes inside of a list.
So it's copy and paste that template because we're also going to be applying it to our second callback.
Now the output for this first one that's the wheels value.
So we want the output to be in this div..
So I'll say the output ID is going to be wheels output to make sure we put it as a string.
There we go.
And then the actual parameter to be adjusted inside that div is going to be children which is essentially
just when you pass a string into a div then the input that we're going to do remember that's going to
be wheels right here and then it's going to be value.
So I'll say wheels and value.
So we have our component IDs and the component properties that are supposed to be linked and then the
input it goes into this function and then it does something.
In this case it just returns back the value for the children which is just a string here and we're going
to do the same thing here except now it's going to be colour's output as the id and then it goes to
the children of that year.
So this is the Stiv right here.
And then the input is going to be the colors ID for the value so we'll say colors and then value.
All right.
So that should be it.
Let's say if name is equal to main We'll take her app and we'll run the server.
Let's run this make sure we didn't do any typos but I'm going to zoom out just so we can see the entirety
of the code.
We have our imports read in our data creator that application set up our layout with kind of these pairs
of radio items and give a little break.
Another set of radio items in the div..
And then we have our two outputs again for outputs.
You're going to need a separate decorator for each output because output is just singular for the inputs
as we saw we could stack them up.
So let's say this and run it and see if everything worked out by some basic thought PI enter.
Looks like I got a typo somewhere.
Invalid syntax for.
Value equal to 1.
And I can see here I already forgot the commas.
So let's add those commas in because two items taking a list of parameters.
Save that again.
It's really easy to make common typos so happens to everyone.
OK so it looks like a running.
I'm going to copy this.
Put it in my browser and see if it worked ok at my browser.
I can see the two inputs as well as my horizontal brake bar.
So you chose one two three you chose red blue and yellow perfect.
Now go ahead and add the second part where we can change up the image.
So that's going to be one last function call so let's add that in.
All right.
Back here at the text editor I'm going to control C.
Kill that server right now and we add in a few things we need to add in a function that will allow us
to actually decode or encode I should say an image file.
So we're going to come back in here and import one more thing in order to work with images in Python.
And that's going to be import base 64 and mixer using Python 3.6 or above in order for this to work
and we're going to create an image here that's going to allow us to encode our image file in order to
display it in the HTML.
And this is where are you going to do.
In general to this blate Jay Peggs and your dashboard will say DMF we'll create a function called encode
image.
It takes in some image file and it's going to create an encoded version of it.
So say in code it is equal to and then we call that base 64 library and call B 6 for in code.
And we're going to open that image file with the parameter.
RB So that's read binary and then right off of that open call will say read.
Remember you can always copy and paste this from our provided files because I know there's a lot here
that can easily cause a typo.
After this we're just going to return the string data colon image forward slash P ngi semi colon base
64 comma curly braces and then we'll say that format and we will say encoded and then say decode open
close parentheses.
So what this is doing is it's going to read in that image file using this command.
Open that image file read binary.
It's going to read it.
We're going to that in code it looks like I actually wrote this twice.
We're going to encode it with be 64 in code.
And then once encoded Well we're going to do is return this specific string which is how platies a simple
file or similar call is going to be able to display the image so it's going to be data Colan image for
Slash P and G.
So my colon base 64 comma and then the actual code for the decoded version of that file.
All right.
So a lot to do here.
Make sure.
I would really suggest that you copy and paste this from the notes.
It's really easy text only make a typo here.
So we're going to continue by adding And one more div into our layout.
So at the very bottom of this we'll say color output comma and then in order to display an image we
can say HVM L I M G will give this in ID display image
and then we'll say source is equal to children and we'll see why in a second.
And we're going to adjust the height of the image will say height is equal to 300 that way in case the
images are widely varying in size.
We don't get any errors there.
Let's save that.
And then at the very bottom we're going to add in a function to actually call back those images.
So say T.F. callback image and Colbeck image is going to take a parameter wheels and the color in order
to display the correct image.
So we'll say we'll end color in right now where I am my path to the images is in my data folder on their
images forward slash.
Remember the Pentagon on where you're located with the script you may need to say Dot dot dot to go
back up at the Rectory but I'm right now located in the same directory as my data folder.
So I need to say data images and then we're going to say return in code image and we'll say path Plus
we're going to concatenate this with the string value.
I'm actually going to copy and paste this from the provided that postscript because this one's really
easy to make a typo on just because it has so many brackets.
Certainly not impossible type out but I want to make sure for the purpose of filming this I don't mess
this up so I'm going to copy and paste this from the notes and you can do it as well.
And I put it all in one line so I can explain what's happening here.
So essentially what we're doing is we're saying the following.
This callback image takes in a wheel that's going to be a number and a color that's going to be red
blue or yellow.
Then we have our default path.
So underneath the data folder I have another folder called images and then I want to return the encoded
version of the image.
So it's going to take that path and then what I want to do is grab that actual last column where it
says something like Blue unicycle dot J peg to do that.
When you do the following with pandas we to say get me back the data frame where data frame wheels is
equal to the wheel provided and data frame color is equal to the color provided.
Then grab the image column and then since that returns back a whole data frame when you say values of
zero.
So this is a lot of pand this code.
And remember our focus is with plot line.
But the way we've organized the data file for you so you don't need to make a bunch of manual calls
the jpeg or else we've organized it that way for you.
So keep in mind a lot of pandas here but all this is saying is grab that specific value from the image
column or the number of wheels matches up and the color matches up.
So that's what this entire line is doing is just going to grab that string and then append it or concatenate
it with that path to the images.
Once you have this callback image.
All we need to do is add the actual callback through the decorator will say app that callback
we set up our output and we'll say display image is the ID and the source is what we want to adjust
because remember if we come back up here this last one has the ID display image and we want to adjust
the source of wherever the image is coming from which is what we're going to return here with the encoded
version of that image.
So right now we have that source and now it's time to add in the inputs and we're actually taken into
inputs the color and the wheels.
So inside this list will have two inputs.
Let's put this on a new line for the second one.
The first input that's going to correspond to the wheel.
So the idea for that one is wheels.
And then we just want to grab the value selected from that radio button.
And the second one is going to be the colors and we'll grab the values select that they're OK.
So let's save this.
We'll run it and once we see that it's working we'll go ahead and do a quick review of everything we
just typed out.
But let's make sure we don't have any typos especially if so many commas everywhere will run enter.
And it looks like it's running so let's head over to our Chrome browser OK.
Headed over to the browser.
Looks like it's working with the default soulis shoes something like 3 am red or yellow and 3 and it
looks like it's connecting to the right images in the actual folder so you can play around with this
and see all those images that are available to you.
OK.
Back at the text editor.
Let's go ahead and do a quick rundown.
We have all our imports we've read in the data we've created our dash application and then to work with
images you need to use the sort of functionality.
That way the HTL image can be accepted the correct way.
Then we created this layout has the radio items and the div or horizontal break.
Another set of radio items and a div and then the female component that's displaying the image and we
add a little bit of styling here.
Then for the callbacks and the functions we have one callback for actually reporting back what we'll
value is chosen then we have another output input combo for the colors value that was chosen and then
we have a callback for displaying the image takes in two inputs the wheels and colors value.
Then it uses panels to look it up.
So that's what this entire line is doing here.
Just looking up the value of pens that string to the path for your images.
So at the end you get something like data slash images flash red unicycle dot Japan.
And that can be converted back to display to this image and then we run the whole server.
OK.
Definitely check out the guidebook for this one.
And we'll see you at the next lecture.