Welcome back to this quick lecture on Mark and dash so dash dashboards can also display a marked down
tax indication of familiar if marked down text it allows for things like links italics bold text bootlace
and a lot more functionality.
More than just a normal string.
And if you want to quickly learn about mark down a great Web site to learn about it is common Mark dot
org slash help.
And we also link that in the guidebook.
So we're just going to quickly see how this works with Dasch we actually won't be typing anything out
in this particular lecture.
We're just going to show you the actual mark down that PI script that's associated with this lecture.
So let's check it out and see how it works.
OK so here I have opened the mark down PI file that goes along with this lecture.
The only things you really need to be concerned about here are basic imports.
We created the dash application and then we create a multi-line string with sets of triple quotes and
here's where we can put in marked down syntax so Keeshan familiar.
Again go ahead and go to common mark or slash help.
And there's a great 60 second mark on tutorial but essentially allows you to do syntax such as embedding
links through particular calls.
So for example here you can see Square braces combin mark and then you can see a web site.
If you come over to the actual running of this dashboard you'll see that common Mark is now an actual
link.
They can then click open a new tab to get help.
So there's links there's 60 second tutorials lots of really helpful stuff here so you can learn markdown
very quickly.
This is more just a reference for you to understand that it's available in dashboards.
So how do you actually implement this sort of thing in a dashboard.
Well from Dasch core components all you need to call is DCC the markdown and then set children equal
to whatever the markdown text is.
And typically you're going to be creating a variable to hold your markdown text as we've done here instead
of having to write it all inside of this markdown court component.
That's really all there is to this lecture.
If you're already familiar mark them they should have been a helpful study in how you can just insert
it to this core component call.
If you're not familiar mark them it's really not a big deal.
We won't really be using it that thoroughly throughout the rest of the Course.
This is more just to show you what's available.
Ok thanks and we'll see at the next lecture.