Welcome back everyone.
Now that we know how to create light charts of plotless.
Let's test your new skills for quick exercise.
In this lecture we'll have an overview of the exercise that PI strip and then we'll also explain the
dataset you're going to be using.
After that we'll show an example of what the finished exercise should look like.
As far as the team I'll file that in the next lecture.
We'll go over the solution.
Let's get started.
OK so here we are at the exercise for the line chart lifestyle and we need to do here is you're going
to be using the 2010 Asie that CSC file which is a file containing some information about the temperatures
in Yuma Arizona in 2010.
And you're going to develop a white shirt that plots out seven days worth of temperature data on one
craft and you can use a for loop to assign each day to its own trace and you cannot do that with a list
comprehension as we've done in the past.
So you're going to do your imports then you're going to create a panel the state of Freyne from this
2010 human ACTC file.
It's in the data folder.
We've also created a list of days for you for your convenience and then it's up to you how you want
to do this.
You can either use a for loop or a list comprehension to create the Trace's that is going to go inside
that list for that data.
So here it kind of set up a skeleton for you.
We have data is equal to an empty list and then for day in days that's Tuesday Wednesday Thursday and
so on.
You should be creating a scatter trace.
And remember you need ads are and thinks this to make it hurt.
Then you can append that particular trace to your data list.
Then you can find the layout and create a figure from that data and the layout.
So let's quickly show you what we would expect the finished product to look like.
And then we can also describe this dataset in a little more detail for you.
So first off let's see what that finished product of likely.
All right.
So once you've actually run your script the solution file should look something like this.
Here you can see a separate color line for each day.
Tuesday Wednesday Thursday and so on.
And then we still see on the X-axis the time in on the Y-axis is the temperature.
So we're basically showing you over these seven days how the temperature tends to go down during the
early mornings and then tends to peak around mid afternoon.
So now it's described to state in just a little more detail to help you out and figure out what columns
are going to be relevant for this sort of plot.
OK.
So if you read in that data frame in the 2010 Yuma Arizona that see every file you should see something
that looks like this.
We have elist dates.
So that's the actual dates of the row.
Then we have the day that's the day of the week Tuesday.
We have elist tea time which is the actual time.
And then t our average which is the average temperature for that hour.
And essentially what this is saying is that you have the day of the week you have that last time noted
there.
And then you have the hourly average temperature.
So the hourly average temperature that's where you're going to want to be using for that Y-axis the
time that's going to be the x axis and then you're going to want to use this date column in order to
actually figure out what day of the week for each separate trace.
And we've kind of already set that framework for you with that day's list up here that we set up.
And with that for a loop as well.
So in general you won't really be needing to use this elist date column.
You should only really be needing to use day Pelosi time and T or temp hour average.
And then you should be able to use some sort of conditional filtering such as Day column equal to equal
to the specific day and then grab the T hour or temp our average.
So there's going to be a little bit of pantless there.
And if you're stuck on that go ahead and check out the solution lecture are going to describe in more
detail how you can separate by day.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the community forum.
But again this is what the dataset looks like.
You're really only going to be needing these three columns.
Please do a little bit of Panas work in order to get the trace data that you need for each of those
seven days.
Best of luck and we'll see at the next lecture where we go over the solutions.