Welcome back.
In part five of this milestone project we're going to use callback with state in order to add a submit
button that we can then click when we want our plot update.
Let's head over to our text editor and get started.
All right here we are back at our file.
We need to make sure to do is from dashed out dependencies also import state which you may have done
already.
Or in just case you haven't McCreevy imported it then we're going to do is we're going to add a button
element and we're going to do that inside it's own div.
So remember we have this div with H-3 and input later on I'll change that to be a dropdown but continuing
on that you have H-3 and date picker with its own style.
What we'll do is after that H team L that second one the second div I'm going say H team l div here
and then add one on my own and it's just going to contain an H team I'll button inside of it.
So let's set that up.
Zoom in inside this div I'm going to call h t m l dot button and let's give this ID of Submit button
we'll say and clicks is equal to zero.
All say children is equal to submit and we can give it its own style dictionary here.
Such as editing the font size to match up with what we have for some of the other components and to
give it a little bit of space we'll see margin left and we'll that to 30 pixels.
Now that we have our button set up we're going to do is also set the div to be have some styling basically
just inline block.
So I'll say style here.
Display to inline block
that way that button is right next to that picker as well as that input lock.
So we set up our style.
We set up that div.
Now it's time to edit the state.
So come back down here.
So right now if you look at our callback we have three inputs the value start and end dates.
However we don't actually want to process these until we click on that button.
So instead we're going to change these from being inputs to being state calls.
So all three of these are properties and component IDS will stay the same but we're going to change
them to be states then then after output I'm going to add in an input call here inside of its list
put a comma there and then.
Here is where we're going to call submit button ID.
And then just take in and clicks
so we'll save that.
Basically we're doing is keep the value start and end date registered in that state but don't actually
send it to update graph until we input or click on that submit button and then we'll need to do here
is we have to make sure these are all going into the same order and of clicks values start.
And they so value here that stock ticker start and they line up here.
But that input button and clicks that's going to be sent first.
So we need to provide.
And click here.
All right so then we have.
And clicks are going to pass that into the output function.
Save that and that should be all we need to do here.
So let's restart our dashboard make sure we didn't have any typos here.
All right.
Perfect.
So it looks like it's running.
Let's check that it's working.
I'm back at my dashboard.
I'm going to try editing the stock symbol as well as the dates just to make sure nothing is being updated.
OK so it looks like it's not being updated.
Let's check if I hit submit now that it is being updated.
So it's a myth and there we go.
It does update.
Notice how since I chose a various are quite a short time line I don't have as many markers here but
if I choose a much longer time line and then put this one further into the future and hit submit then
I get the Slyne plot.
OK.
So it looks like we're able to successfully add and they submit button and then edit the stock symbol
and the start end dates to then be part of the state instead of directly part of the input for the last
part of this series of lectures.
We're going to do is change this input to be a drop down and we're going to connect it to a C as we
file of NASDAQ listed companies.
That way we can actually select multiple stocks at the same time.
We'll see what the next lecture.