Welcome back to the final part of updating graphs on interactions.
Previously we saw how we could edit that acceleration plot so that the pitch of the plot changes on
its acceleration depending on what car was being hovered over.
Now let's go ahead and edit the thickness of that line to have a visual representation of the number
of cylinders the car has as well as adding a little bit of mark down information.
So we have text data for the car itself.
Let's head back over toward text editor and finish off the project.
OK here we are back at R-TX Ed..
We have all our imports and then we have our lay out where we have two divs right now.
One for that scatterplot graph.
Another one for the acceleration.
We're going to do now is add one more div for our markdown.
So let's zoom into that last live come back down here.
So this is going to be T.M. div..
Again Rohrer to put in this comma here and then we will say a list.
And this is going to take in a core component.
I will say this is see markdown and technically you don't need another day here.
This is just if you want to edit styles and we'll give this an ID of MPG underscore stat's and we're
going to do here is for the Stiv.
We'll give it a style dictionary.
We'll set the width to be 20 percent just like the acceleration plot to make sure that's a string and
then we'll also say give it a height of let's say 50 percent just like we did for the plot and then
it's display is also going to be in line display and this will be in line the block.
All right.
So we have our mark down recall from our multiple outputs lecture that right now we have a single output
to this graph.
But if we want to add in another output that means we actually need to add a second callback that can
take multiple inputs in a single callback foot for multiple outputs.
We need another callback.
So we're going to do here is essentially create another function call say the F and this is going to
be we'll call this callback underscore stats.
So we're going to report back stats about the car that's being hovered over the hover data and let's
go out and grab our actual callback values our output is now going to go to the markdown that we just
created.
So the idea we gave it was mpg stats so let's grab this and stick it in that MPG stats and we're going
to overwrite it's children
and then we want the input to come from mpg scatterplot that we made.
So that's the same input as before.
Essentially it's the same lines right here and you scatter.
Now we're taking in the hover data than that however that is going to go inside this function.
So we need to do is return back the actual text we want displayed in that markdown the way we do that
is we'll save the underscore index just as it did before is that hover data.
In the points key I want to grab the first item in that list and then grab the points index value from
that we can actually set up a large markdown text and to do this we're going to set up a multi-line
text and I'm actually going to just copy and paste this from the solutions.
It's really up to you how you want to format this.
This is again just to reiterate that you can't use markdown text formatting.
I'm going to copy and paste this here.
From our notes.
So this is what I'm copying and pasting noticed I have some values here that need to be filled in over
this multi-line but I have some number of cylinders some CCC displacement and zero to 60 in some number
of seconds using markdown.
I'm actually going to be able to keep these on a separate line if I was just returning back a normal
string that mark down.
It would show up all on one line.
So once you've done that I can say that format and start inserting the values.
So first I want to grab the number of cylinders to do that I can say DMF I location of that particular
vehicle index grab the value for the Sillars column then the next thing I want to grab is the displacement
value.
So very similar thing.
That vehicle index grab the displacement value
and then lastly I went from zero to 60 in seconds.
So that's going to be Dia.
I'll see at the vehicle index.
Go ahead and grab it's acceleration value.
OK so then those are going to be inserted into this multi-line string.
And because it's marked down it's actually going to be able to understand that you have multiple lines
here.
OK.
The last thing I want to do is add a little bit to this acceleration plot.
So it was crawling back up here.
Remember this acceleration plot.
What we want to do is actually at its thickness based on the number of cylinders.
So to do that we actually go back down and edit our layout excuse me.
Our data here in this figure mode is equal to lines and then the line we're going to set it's with upon
update equal to two times the number of cylinders.
So we can say just as before the location of that particular vehicle index grabbed the number of cylinders.
And the reason we say to X is just to make the effects a little more noticeable.
In fact if you really want to make a noticeable You can choose a larger value such as 3 x so let's zoom
out and do a quick review of everything we just did.
Probably one of our largest projects so far and this is a good prep for our code along milestone project
but remember really what we're showing you here is how you can interact with other graphs when you have
hover data selected data or click data.
The main idea being is you just say hover data and then return back a figure.
Basically just combining two ideas that we've already seen in the past.
OK.
So what we did here is we let our imports read in the data fix one of the columns and often for real
data such you'll have to do that.
Then we set up or lay out two giant outermost div and then we have now three divs first div that's the
scatterplot of MPG versus a year.
Then we have a second div That's the plot that shows the line of acceleration and then we have marked
down text that we're going to return to this first function.
What it does is based on the hover data it grabs the vehicle index you're looking at and then it turns
back a figure at edits its data and edits its layout and then adjust the actual slope of the figure.
This is kind of a unique example and it's a little more complex than what you would probably normally
be doing but hopefully it's a good example of what partly in-dash are actually capable of.
I would imagine that.
And your more real world examples you won't have to be editing the pitch of a plot or a line but it
is possible.
Then for this last one we went ahead and set up the callback to actually return back some sort of information
stats to that markdown.
And lastly we actually need to return that.
So let's do that now at the very bottom of this.
We're going to say return stats and in case you're wondering where this princes is matching up to it's
for this format call.
So let's make sure return stats is indented properly it should line up right here of this first level
of indentation for the function.
Ok save this lots of code.
So let's make sure we don't make any errors or run Python basic about pi enter and wait a little bit.
If you're waiting a little bit that's a good sign because it means it's running the app.
OK let's go to our dashboard and see if it worked.
All right here's our dashboard right now.
Sets the defaults on that layout.
As we hover over this we now get to see the information being displayed back something to those right
now is I'm actually not seeing that information of the car itself.
So let's make sure that we save that return stats that we just edited.
However I do see the thickness of the line changing depending on the number of cylinders.
So let's go back here I want to close this.
Let's come back here and do a little debugging.
Looks like callback stat's is taking hover data.
I am returning stats right now.
So let me save this.
I'm going to troll see here and it looks like there may have been an error.
It looks like points index was not found.
So let's make sure that we're doing the right one it should be point index.
OK so news here is actually pretty capable of still running the dashboard even if there's an error on
your script.
And so there's a key error here actually typed points index at a point index.
So let's fix that.
I'm going to save it.
And now let's run this again.
Hopefully now that fixes that markdown issue.
So that's running.
Let's head back toward dashboard.
OK restarted the dashboard now as they hover over this.
Now I'm actually seeing the data and the format is a little different right now because I'm actually
quite zoomed in to this dashboard.
You can see the number of cylinders the displacement and how many seconds it takes to go from 0 to 60.
If you choose a really recent car.
Well recent from 1982.
It goes from zero and 4.6 or maybe 18 Fenn's on the MPG.
You can see here some of these 1970s cars definitely changes in the cylinders.
OK.
So that's the entire dashboard project really.
All you really need to get out of this lecture is the fact that you can hover over data select data
or click data and use that to effect an update.
Another figure in your plot.
So we're going to be working on all these ideas combining them all together multiple outputs multiple
inputs dealing with data frames.
In our next project which is going to be a code along milestone project that will update depending on
what stock market information we want to look up.
Do you have any questions on this project makes you check out the guidebook or post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.