Welcome back to the final part of our milestone project where we're going to replace our input component
with a drop down component and connect that to a c a c file that contains a list of NASDAQ ticker and
company names.
That way a person can actually go to the dropdown menu select the tickers are interested in and then
hit the submit button and see the historical price information.
Let's get started.
OK here we are back our text editor what we need to do is actually just import pandas.
As PD and then we're going to read and see as we file and construct a list of options.
So to do that let's create a variable called an SD Q for Nasdaq.
Now we're going to read in the CXXVI file from the data folder to the Nasdaq company list that cxxviii
essentially this is a CXVII file that has a list of symbols and then a list of company names.
Or I should say a column of company names and a column of symbols.
We're going to take that column of symbols and set that to the index we'll type out.
And as the queue set the index and we're going to set it to be the symbol column and we can say in place
is equal to true which allows us to not need to reassign this.
So if you didn't say in place it equals a true you need to say and as the queue is equal to an SD queue
set index symbol.
So essentially this line and this line are actually the same thing except with this one.
If you say in places equal to true you don't need to do the re-assignment.
So that's where we do that right now that we have our set index.
The index is now the symbol meaning that column represents the name we're going to create a list of
options.
We'll say options is equal to a list and then we're going to go for every tick in the queue index.
We'll say whoops options and we need to append a dictionary and this dictionary remember it's in the
form that looks something like this.
It's going to have a label which is the string the user sees and then a value which is what our script
sees.
So let's actually construct this dictionary and then append it.
So my dictionary we're going to set that equal to an empty dictionary first and then we're going to
grab the actual label so label is going to be what the user sees.
Let's have that be both a concatenation of the symbol and the name of the company.
So we're going to do the following.
We'll say that the label is equal to N.S. dequeue I EHLO see tick.
So that's the company name.
And then we're going to concatenate that.
Let's actually make that into a string.
So that's the company name and then we're going to concatenate it with a space and then add on the tick.
So what does that actually mean.
It means the label should look something like this.
It should say maybe Apple company and then APL.
So that's going to be the label the user sees in the dropdown as far as the value we're going to pass
back.
For that we just need the actual Ticker.
So we're just get that synthetical to tick and then we're going to pen that.
So now this options is a list of dictionaries of labels and values for our dropdown menu.
And you can check out the guidebook.
We did this in a kind of Wisam a little bit jujitsu we did it in one line but for explanation purposes
I think it's a little clearer over multiple lines.
But check out the guidebook for a way to do this all in just one line.
Going to save that will come back down here.
Change is input to be a drop down.
We'll go ahead and keep the same ID my ticker symbol the value the sexy note needs to be inside of a
list due to the weight dropped on works.
And we're also going to add in the options list will say options as you go to the options list we just
constructed and we can actually take away these style calls and instead right here for this style We're
going to keep it inline block as well as vertical line but we're going to give it a little more room.
Since now a person can choose more than one stock we're going to say that the width of this.
Let's put this in as a string is going to be 30 percent with.
All right.
So now that we set that up the only thing that's left to do.
There's actually one more thing we want to do and that's that set multiply equal to true.
It's going to allow someone to choose more than just one option in the drop down.
All right so we have the options value multa is equal to true.
We've edited to give a little bit of a wider width since they can now choose multiple stocks in that
drop down will come back down here and now we just need to add our function to take in those stocks.
Right now we're just grabbing a single stock ticker.
But now the stock ticker coming from that drop down menu instead of the input is going to be a list
meaning we want to create a set of Trace's for every stock ticker in that list will say Trace's is a
list and then for tick in stock ticker take my data frame and say actually we can just use this come
in right here.
So we already constructed that take my data frame and build out that for that particular tick.
So no longer stock ticker but instead we will say tick and then we're going to append the trace.
So we'll say Trace's append and we're going to append a dictionary that essentially looks like this.
This X will be that different index and then that data frame is close.
So we're going to pin that there and we can say close either of these methods is okay.
And let's also then give it a name attribute we'll say name is tick that way when someone's hovering
over it they get to see the name as well.
And this Trace's is already a list.
So this data instead of being a list is just going to be the traces be constructed and that should be
all we need to do.
Let's do a quick review make sure we didn't miss anything coming back from the top that we're doing
here.
We're reading in a CSP file of company illis then setting the index to be the symbol and then creating
our empty options list then for every ticker that's now in that index we're going to construct a dictionary
that looks like this and append that to this list of options.
We create an empty dictionary the label we want that to be the name and then the company's ticker.
So we're saying grab that location and this is actually just b l o c.
In fact they messed that up a little bit here.
There should be name.
There we go.
So this is now saying saying Nasdaq at the location of this particular ticker index value grabbed the
value of the name column and that itself should then be a string.
We'll see if this works then put a space and then put in the ticker.
OK.
That's the correct code.
My apologies for that.
And then we're going to do here is say my dictionary values equal to tick and then we're appending it
passing that into the options in this dropdown and then all the way down here is creating all the traces
for every stock chosen.
Let's see this and see if we need to debug any further say Pythonesque the API looks like it's running.
So let's head over toward dashboard.
OK here I am.
My dashboard looks like Tesla is the default.
And now when I click on this I get to see that company name followed by their stock ticker.
So then I can click on alphabet Google and then if I hit submit this updates and then I get to see Google
versus Tesla here and I can change the dates to get more information hit submit to update that they'll
update that those dates and I can choose multiple things such as a bunch of other stocks from the drop
down and I can also type them out.
So if I'm interested in Microsoft I can begin typing up Microsoft and eventually I'll see it Microsoft
Corporation hit submit.
And then depending on how many stocks you deal take a little bit of time.
But there we go.
We get to see him all in our dashboard.
OK.
So that's it for the mouse some project.
I hope it gave you lots of ideas of the kind of dashboards you can create with all your plotline and
dash skills.
We'll see you at the next lecture.