I think what we can do now is folks that want to take
the plunge can start doing that.
I'll come around and help anybody who wants to go through
the actual deploy process and/or answer any questions about
anything else that we had today.
If you are planning on doing the Elastic Beanstalk deployment,
we just sat and did it for a good 30 minutes,
so that's probably about the budget that you would set
at this point for getting that going, which is totally cool,
and it's kind of why we're here, or one of the reasons why we're here.
So if you're down to give it a shot,
I will handhold all of your way through that process as best I can.
And you're planning on writing some documentation about this too?
Yeah, as part of the written materials,
I'd like to do some written stuff on this as well.
So all the stuff that was just deployed,
is that all free then to run, or is it hourly?
Is there any hourly?
All the stuff that I used was within the Free Tier,
like all of the instances were t2.
micros.
So yeah, this was within the Free Tier,
but you can sort of dial up any of the individual pieces to more expensive.
So you could run a ton of little application like this on Free Tier,
and then it's just when you want to dial them up is
when the charges will start coming in?
Yeah, yeah,
and I think like the Free Tier is --- my understanding is like
you have 12 months with it or something,
and then you start paying regardless.
It's --- but yeah, I think at this level,
and I think there might be limitations on numbers as well.
You can have 750 hours.
Seven hundred and fifty hours a month is the Free Tier limit.
So it's one instance in 31 days.
If you've got two instances, it's 15 days.
Of computer time essentially.
Yeah.
Gotcha.
So you want to make sure you aren't just spinning these up all the time.
Not willy-nilly, no.
I'd be lying if I said I didn't have like a monthly like $15.
00 Amazon bill that I just have no idea like where I got it from.
That's what I'm afraid of.
You can just opt for the $15 thousand enterprise one.
Yeah, I don't know man.
But no,
I think I just have enough little stuff where I've ran out
of the Free Tier on a couple accounts.
For those of us that wanted to go through this,
I mean could you go through that list like slower,
the whole setup?
You went through it fast,
and I thought there was no way I could be here and watching at the same time.
Yep, absolutely.
I can definitely do that.
I can kind of go back into the environment that we just created and
show you some of the bits that we had to configure,
like kind of from the beginning, if that helps.
Alright,
so great request is to kind of retrace the steps of that deploy now that we,
like we --- there's a lot of down time in there where
we might have missed some things,
so I'll just go through and retrace the steps of the
deployment from top to bottom, or provisioning the new environment.
So the first thing that I did was here in the console I go down
to my Identity & Access Management interface,
and if I don't have one already,
I'm going to create a user for use in essentially deploying stuff,
like getting credentials to deploy stuff to Amazon.
So we create a new user with a username,
and I'll just delete that one right away.
So we create the user,
and then we download the security credentials for that
user so we can use that authenticate the Elastic Beanstalk
command line interface later.
After we create that user --- here I'll just --- I'm
going to delete that right away.
Alright, so after we create that user, we want to add that user to a group,
so we check that user, and then we say Add User to Groups.
I think I actually already added it to the only group that I had, like this one.
But if I do like … So how do you download the credentials?
After you create, I'll do it one more time,
so after you create the user,
there's a button here that says Download Credentials.
Okay, I was trying to get it from an existing user, so I have to.
Yeah,
from an existing --- you only have one opportunity to download
credentials for a user after you create them; otherwise,
you have to like regenerate credentials for a user.
And then for a new user that's been created, you add them to group.
In my case, I only have one group, and that's like the super admin group,
so you would choose to add them to that.
Did you have to create that ahead of time,
or is that something that we'll have to do?
Yes, you will have to create that group.
So when you create the new group, you can say like,
you can call it SomeGroup, and then after you create the group,
you can choose like a preset policy from a list that will apply to that group.
AdministratorAccess is the GodMode policy.
And then there are lots of other more granular
policies you can choose from as well.
So you create that group,
and then you can --- all the users you assign to that
group will have that set of permissions.
So it doesn't matter the name of the group really.
It just matters that that user is a member of that
group and that have admin privileges?
Yep,
and that they have whatever privileges on whatever
AWS resources they need to access,
and using the super admin policy means that they have everything.
So once you have a user created who's assigned to a group
with a sufficiently permissive policy, then you're ready to start cranking out some actual stuff.