Now I'm going to talk a little bit about a few tools that we
found really useful in monitoring and sort of preparing our
applications for production.
The two aspects that I'm going to focus on and give you a little
demo of this afternoon are a load testing tool called Locust and
an error tracking service that lots of teens use at Twilio
actually called Rollbar,
which will take exceptions in our application and put them in a
service that will notify us if bad things happen in our
application while it's running in production.
So I'll do a quick demo of Locust,
and then I'll turn you all loose on starting to add in some error
handling in our application on the server-side,
which we haven't actually done yet, if you might have noticed.
So, the first thing I'm going to show you is a tool called Locust.
There are load testing tools for just about every platform.
This particular one is a Python-based tool that I've
favored because it's relatively easy to use,
it gives really good reporting output and is
configurable through a web interface, which I'll show you here in a second.
It's got a large community around it,
and it allows you using Python code to actually simulate
different types of usage scenarios on your website.
So the flexibility of the configuration,
and the maturity of the tool,
as well as sort of the general usability are some reasons why I
favor it over other things that are out there.
The production monitoring tool we're going to take a look at is called Rollbar.
It's a third-party service whose API you integrate into your application.
And when handled exceptions are raised,
you can send that exception data to this service and it'll send out
notifications to whatever provider you happen to have configured.
At Twilio,
we use PagerDuty to create a schedule of folks that are response for
responding to issues and outages on the website.
So Rollbar does server-side stuff too?
It's fully server-side.
I mean yeah I think you might be able to do client-side,
but we only use it for the server-side.
You can use TrackJS on the client-side.
I know you can use TrackJS on the client-side.
Minor plug for our hometown hero, Todd Gardner.
But yeah,
so Rollbar is used across many services at Twilio to
notify folks that things are going wrong,
and it's something that I've really come to enjoy.
If you have identifying information about a user at
the time an exception is thrown, you can,
in your Rollbar output,
see which user and exception was generated from the origin.
If you have Rollbar configured correctly,
you can get a lot of very useful information about
any exception in your application.
So, definitely worth checking out,
and it integrates very nicely with Express applications, as you will find out when you check out the exercise.