We did a little bit of hacking on Express.
Now we're going to move into a part of the stack that we've already been using,
but we're going to try to dive in a little bit to understand better
how these things work and what they can do for us.
We've been executing these commands, these migration commands,
these Grunt commands,
and these are provided by some of the build tooling
that we have in this project.
Now build tooling, there's a lot of different choices out there,
but the two that I keep coming back to are npm scripts and Grunt,
and Grunt tasks in general.
And I'll kind of take you through what each of these things do.
So, npm scripts are commands that you register in the package.
json of your Node project and can execute arbitrary shell commands.
So,
it's essentially like adding aliases for commands that you
could run from the command line yourself.
However,
there's a couple things that you get for free when
you do an npm script like this.
Probably the most notable one is that if you have npm installed locally,
any modules which should be command line utilities that
have some kind of command line option,
those utilities will be added to your system path when
you run a script through an npm script.
And we'll see what we mean by that here in a moment.
It's also a conventional way of interacting with Node projects.
So the npm defines a set of, I don't know,
about 15 different scripts that it sort of expects to
possibly be present in a package.
json.
There's a npm start, a npm test, a npm after install.
There's a few like lifecycle hooks and other bits that npm will sort of
conventionally expect to possibly be present in a package.
json.
So by conforming to that convention,
another Node developer who may or may not have ever seen your
project before knows well if I execute npm start,
like probably something is suppose to happen.
And in fact, lots of Platform as a Service providers including Elastic Beanstalk,
which is the bit that we'll be using later on this afternoon,
will look for that npm start script as the primary way to kick off your Node.
js web application process.
So having these npm scripts is usually a good idea anyway.
And then the other one that I use is Grunt.
And I'm already seeing some questions in the chat
about Grunt over gulp or whatever, and we'll talk about some of the conventions.
It largely does come down to preference.
Gulp, in some scenarios, you know, performs really well, so that's really great.
Webpack you can actually use with Grunt,
and it's really good at doing like a subset of frontendy stuff.
So there's lots of different choices out there,
but the reason why I kind of stick with Grunt is the mature plugin ecosystem.
There's a ton of plugins out there that do 99% of the things that I want to do,
and it's better than other solutions out there,
I think, at like synchronously orchestrating tasks.
So if you want to do this, then this,
then this or do a couple things concurrently and then another thing,
Grunt makes that easiest.
And there are other tools out there all that stuff is still totally possible,
but the code becomes, for at least for my simple brain,
possibly a little bit more confusing.
And it's, you know, --- there are lots of people out there,
in fact,
like the Lloyd who lives here in town in the Twin
Cities does Node DevOps for Walmart, and he,
for most of their orchestration stuff, his like method,
his weapon of choice is like Bash scripts.
Like they just have like a ton of like really Bash scripts,
which like run all of their deployments and do all that stuff.
So ultimately it comes down to preference,
but the thing that I think Grunt helps with over like just
pure Bash scripts and npm scripts is orchestrating and like building tasks that work together.