We've got two more big meaty sections here this
afternoon before I turn you loose.
The first is digging into the data tier of the
application that we've been looking at today.
And the --- in this case, we're actually going be looking at how to use Node.
js with a relational database.
Anyway,
so the stack we're going to look at is one that's actually less heralded in
Node because most of the NoSQL databases out there are,
because they sort of natively speak JSON,
they end up being a really good fit for Node.
js.
But for certain use cases, there are, you know,
a relational database does make a lot of sense,
and particularly Postgres is actually a really feature-rich relational database,
which can do a lot of interesting stuff that JavaScript can take advantage of,
particularly with its JSON fields allowing you within a table
to have a rich query --- or like an unstructured queryable
column with JSON data embedded in it.
So, Postgres still a really great choice for Node.
js development, and specifically, it allows us to use RDS,
which is the managed relational database service from
Amazon which is very performant, highly available,
all those things.
So if you're going to be using a relational database of any kind with Node.
js, the chances are you're probably going to go one of two routes.
You're going to either use a driver for your database directly,
so just use PG or Postgres or a MySQL driver directly,
maybe execute raw SQL against it or maybe use a SQL builder.
But if you're using a ORM in Node.
js, you're probably going to use Sequelize.
Sequelize is definitely the most feature-rich ORM that's out there for Node.
js today.
So,
if you're looking for the type of experience that you
might've enjoyed with say Active Record,
which is kind of, for me,
like the gold standard to which I will compare all ORMs,
it definitely has its problems, but I feel like it's a great piece of software,
it's probably the closest you're going to get to that in the Node.
js world.
That said, this is another situation where if you choose to use Sequelize,
the support that you're going to find out there on the Interwebs is not awesome,
like there aren't a lot of tutorials, there aren't a lot of resources,
there aren't a lot of sample apps that have been built using Sequelize,
so you're going to be a little bit in the wilderness if you use Sequelize.
The documentation is pretty okay,
but there are a lot of things that go unsaid that you occasionally
have to dive into the source to figure it out.
But all that said,
it definitely is of all the ORMs out there on top of a relational database,
I think it's definitely the creme de la creme.
But yeah, as I mentioned, isn't SQL for old people?
Like shouldn't we be using NoSQL databases?
And there's some reasons why you might want to consider
going with a NoSQL database for Node,
mostly because the support for NoSQL databases in Node is much better,
like there's a lot more folks using those technologies,
a lot more resources available, and the libraries are a little bit better.
For instance, like Mongoose, which is the ODM,
the Object Document Mapper, for MongoDB I think is particularly good.
But the main reason that I've gone with SQL is that Postgres
itself is an awesome feature-rich database,
and RDS was a good choice within our Amazon-centric ecosystem.
It was going to be the best data store solution for us.
So the opportunity to go with RDS was definitely a driving factor in making that choice.