The next challenge that we have is to start adding some real-time
user interface capabilities to the application.
And I think we'll probably take this one and like work
into lunch if we're having lunch at noon.
So we'll talk about this and set up the exercise,
and then we can work on that kind of over lunch and maybe pick
back up again at like right around 1:00 p.
m.
local time.
So, Socket.
IO is the one library I'll present here during the day
for which there is no alternate.
It's pretty much the de facto standard for adding
real-time capabilities to a node app.
There are a couple others out there that you can use, but Socket.
IO is by far the most popular.
And Socket.
IO essentially provides two things to your application.
It provides a client-side library that you'll load up in your HTML that will
allow you to communicate with the server over a WebSocket,
and it also provides a server-side API that you can use in your Node.
js code to push data to connected clients over a WebSocket.
And I think the best way to kind of go through this is to,
again, show you the sort of HelloWorld of Socket. IO, which is a simple chat application.