If you want to build something similar, the Socket.
IO documentation is actually fairly good on this front.
So if you just go to socket.
io, and click on Getting Started,
you can do pretty much what I'm about to do here by going through this
tutorial in setting up a basic chat application.
So, what we're going to need to do to use Socket.
IO --- I'll use it in a simple sort of stand-alone project first,
and then I'll pose a challenge to the group to integrate Socket.
IO in our TODO list application as well.
So, first thing we're going to need to do,
we already have, if memory serves,
we have an Express module installed in this directory.
Yep, there we go.
But we don't yet have Socket.
IO.
So I'm going to install that now.
And Socket.
IO works alongside pretty much every node web framework.
It requires an HTTP server instance to do things like serve up the client-side
interface JavaScript to the browser and a few other bits.
And I'll show you how to kind of set that up on the server-side first.
So, if we open this up,
this is the simple Express example that we looked at yesterday
that showed us the basics of creating middleware.
And in that application, we let Express create an HTTP server for us,
but in this instance, we're actually not going to be doing that.
So, let's go ahead and require the HTTP module from core node.
And, we're also going to require the Socket.
IO module.
We're actually just going to create --- I'll require that,
we'll actually require that here in a little bit.
So now instead of calling listen on our Express app
after we create our Express app, we're going to create an HTTP server.
(Creating) And then, we're going to have that server listen on port 3000.
And this time we'll pass in a little function that's going to say that our
server is running just so we know that it's working fine.
Alright, so we have our server there.
Now that we have our Express application set up,
we're also going to serve up some static assets so we can see
what's happening on the HTML side of things.
So we're going to use the built-in Express static server.
And,
we're going to server up the public directory which has yet to
be created from within the current directory.
So if there's any HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
other assets, they'll be loaded from this public folder.
Here, let me just pull this up.
(Typing) Alright, so once we get that piece all set up,
we have our regular, old Express app.
Now we need to --- let's maybe start by creating that HTML
application next that will be using the Socket.
IO stuff on the client-side.
So we'll create an index.
html.
And we'll just have some basic markup here,
maybe an unordered list which will have our messages.
And then we'll have a form or maybe even just an input type text.
And then this is going to be the way in which users are going to interact
with our application by typing in some chat messages.
And then we'll have a button to actually send that message out to some folks.
Alright, so we have our basic Express app running here.
We actually don't need any of this anymore.
And, if we've done everything correctly, we should have an Express app running.
Oh yeah, we already have one running on port 3000 over here.
Alright,
so we should have a server running on port 3000 that just has basic HTML UI here that eventually will become a chat application.