What I'd like to now is take you through some of the
database code in the sample application and talk about how
some of these things are laid out.
I know we've kind of dug into this a little bit,
but I want to take a moment to sort of step you through the key
bits that make this go in our TodoMVC application.
So, the first thing I'm going to point out is this file,
the sequelizerc dot file at the top level of the directory.
So,
when you're using the Sequelize CLI to execute commands in your dev environment,
this file configures some of the key bits about that experience,
like where your database configuration is going to live,
when the CLI tool generates migrations, where it's going to put those migrations,
and where it's going to look for models that have been
defined or that will be defined using the CLI.
So this file is there for when you do execute those Sequelize
CLI commands at the top-level directory.
It's going to take these settings into effect.
The other places where you'll find like database related logic in
the application is here in the db directory.
Sequelize requires like database configuration to be
specified in kind of a specific way,
which is kind of incongruent with how we're doing
configuration elsewhere in the app.
So we have this database.
js file,
which spoon feeds Sequelize configuration in the
format in which it is more comfortable.
So we actually read in the real configuration values from our
config setup as we've been doing already so far,
but then we populate these things,
like the databaseUrl and the dialect that we use for Sequelize here.
The other bit you'll notice is the migration's folder.
So this is where when you generate a new model or you generate a new migration,
which mutates the state of a database from one state to another,
those files are going to be generated here.
Much like other migration systems that you might've used in other environments,
a migration file name is built of a couple different bits.
The first is a timestamp,
which is the actual identifier of record for this migration,
and this is how the Sequelize, or the ORM engine,
knows which migrations have been applied and which
migrations have not been applied.
So this is important and is generated by the --- by
Sequelize when you create a new migration.
And then the second part is simply descriptive.
So create-todo could be any string, you know, fluffy bunny one, two, three.
It doesn't really matter.
It should be descriptive to say what the migration is about,
so second part of the migration is for humans.
And every migration exports a JavaScript object that has two functions on it.
One is called up, and the other is called down.
So when we are migrating the database to the next version,
the up function is called,
and that function is passed a Sequelize query interface,
which has methods that let you create tables or add columns to existing tables.
So as you're mutating the data model over time,
you'll be able to specify these functions to go up and down.
So here, right now this application only has one migration,
but all of you are going to change that in just a little while by
adding --- updating the data model a little bit.
So we're creating a new table called Todos for our todo items,
and then we're also specifying the down command so when
we're rolling back this migration we're just going to
drop the table that we created.
So, when you generate migrations to update the data model,
you'll be using these migration files to do it.
Now the other place where you'll run into database code in
the application is in the models folder.
And there's a couple things that happen here which are
kind of a twist on like how you'll see things structured
in the Sequelize documentation.
So, this file, db.
js, creates a single instance of a Sequelize object,
and that Sequelize object takes in the constructor a Postgres databaseUrl that
will have the username and password embedded inside of it.
So this is where we're authenticating against the database,
and we're also passing in the options for that connection to the database,
which we're loading in from our configuration.
And in our case,
the configuration that we're passing in is pretty much
the defaults that Sequelize provides.
The development Postgres URL is configured here,
and these database options are arguments to the Sequelize
constructor saying we want to use the Postgres dialect,
we don't want --- by default we don't want to log
every SQL statement out the console,
although in the development environment you can see that we
actually override that and say yes we do want to log SQL
statements out to the console.
And then we also configure Sequelize's connection pool,
which specifies how long a connection is held that's
idle before it's deleted from the pool,
and then the maximum number and the minimum number of concurrent
connections to the database that are allowed,
and those are the default values for Sequelize which you can tune to
your requirements if you feel that is necessary.
So,
this database object is used to define all the other models in our application,
and right now there's only one.
We have a Todo model where again we're going to be requiring the
Sequelize module because we're going to need some class-level
variables off of that as we define the model,
and here we're going to create a new model.
And right now the only attribute we're adding is title,
although the models by default also have an ID,
which is an auto-incrementing primary key in the database,
and it also has a created at and an updated at timestamp,
which is added automatically by Sequelize.
So, we export that model object,
and then that model object is what we use elsewhere in our
application to actually do queries and update data.
So, here in the todos controller we require that model,
and when we fetch all Todos we use the query interface attached to the
model to find all the Todos with a certain limit,
and then we can findById, create,
and destroy and do all those other operations within our backend API here.
So, this is the, kind of the interface that we have put together.
We're going to be expanding on this data model a little bit with a migration.
Some of the gotchas to be aware of here,
so rather than something like Active Record where this sort of canonical
source of truth about the current state of the model and the properties
that its supports lives in the database.
In the model itself, you don't actually configure what all the properties are.
Like you might configure validations and other logic about the model,
but you don't sort of enumerate here are all the
properties that are a part of the model.
In Sequelize, you actually do have to do that.
So as you're creating migrations that mutate the state of the
underlying tables that back your models,
you'll have to keep that in sync with what is
actually defined here in the model.
So if you create a migration that adds a property to a model,
you'll have to make sure to add that same property
here in your model declaration.
So one thing that is potentially somewhat onerous,
it's that way in other ORM systems, but again,
if you're coming from Active Record,
that might be a little different than what you're used to.
Now the --- when we had you set up your development environment,
the two command line utilities that you set up were
the Sequelize CLI and the Grunt CLI.
We installed those globally.
So the Sequelize command line utility, if you just run sequelize --help,
you'll see all the different generators and other options
that the command line interface gives you.
And the help text is actually pretty good.
Like that's where I go to a lot to see what is going to be
possible with the command line utility.
Most of the commands have some decent help text that show
you how to use these different commands,
actually give you some examples of how to generate models of various kinds.
So as you're kind of exploring this,
I would definitely recommend that you take advantage of these help operations.
So for example, for model:create,
which I suspect is something that you're going to be interested in,
sequelize, and then we can just basically append help to the beginning of that,
that's going to actually show you the commands that you pass in to
generate like say a user model with certain attributes,
and it'll show you like the actual JavaScript that'll
get spat out by that command as well.
So,
definitely make use of those help texts as you're going
through and doing stuff with the ORM.
The other bit that you'll want to take advantage of while you're hacking on
it is the Sequelize documentation posted on Read the Docs.
Specifically,
I'll point you to the migrations documentation because we will be
looking at expanding on our model a little bit.
So you're going to be generating migration,
updating the model, running the migration,
and enhancing what the application is --- or what the model is capable of.
So, definitely will be a resource worth consulting.
So,
are there any questions right away about Sequelize and kind of how it
fits into this application or other general questions?
Obviously, there's a lot to learn about the Sequelize API,
which is why we're going to start off with a task that will get
you familiar with that by actually wrestling with a real task
rather than putting a bunch of method names in slides that none
of you will remember.
I'm going to be giving you a task that will require acquiring an operational knowledge of how this ORM works.