So now we're going to be moving on to our third exercise of the day,
which is enhancing our data model to use some additional properties.
So, if we head out to GitHub, you'll notice that there are two issues remaining.
Both are tagged with exercise3,
and both will get you into a little bit meatier parts of this application.
The first is --- and it could be that you'll be able to knock these out
both at once because maybe you'll want to write a test which exercises
your new functionality that you're adding.
But the first issue that I have is that right now there's no way to track
the status of a Todo model once you mark it as complete.
So,
many of you were astute enough to note that when we actually
run our application here in development mode,
when you mark a todo item as complete and refresh the page,
it doesn't actually do anything.
Now the user interface part of this we'll actually get to tomorrow.
That'll be sort of our entree into learning a little bit about how Vue.
js works.
However,
the backend part of this is something that I'd like for us to address today.
So,
what I would like for folks to do is to take the model for the todo and
add Boolean flag for whether or not it's been completed.
And in addition to adding that flag, we also need to modify our API in Express,
implemented with Express,
to accept a completed field along with the current title field,
which is the only one that's persistent at the moment.
And again, I wouldn't spend too much time,
or I wouldn't spend any time, because we'll do that tomorrow,
trying to update the user interface.
I would just look to test these URLs directly.
And if you're into doing that, the go-to for me --- if you like cURL,
that's great, but if you're using Chrome,
there is an app called Postman.
And Postman I feel is kind of the bee's knees if you're testing a REST API
because it gives you a nice GUI that let's you construct HTTP requests with
different HTTP methods against your backend.
So here, and it sort of saves your history as well, which is also kind of nice.
So here we can do a GET request against /todos and hit Send,
and then we can see the JSON that comes back from the server.
We can do a POST request to todos,
and then along with that pass in some form encoded.
And they do need to be form encoded, by the way,
if you do decide to use this tool because that's the
way that we're parsing the body.
If we pass in some values like hey there Front End Masters and hit Send,
we can create a todo that way.
We get that representation back.
And if we list them out again,
we can see that the Front End Master's record is in the database.
So after you add that property,
using something like Postman to test the API would be useful.
In addition to that,
the second issue that I would like for folks to take a look at
during this time dovetails kind of nicely into that,
which is adding some integration tests which we
don't have yet in the application.
We have like one kind of crappy unit test for our backend right now.
Test coverage in this application is not great yet.
So we could definitely do more unit tests as we add
more functionality to the application,
but if our test pyramid should be fat at the bottom with unit tests and
kind of skinnier in the middle with integration tests,
that's the part of the pyramid that we're going to be implementing next.
And then, of course, at the top of the pyramid you have some end-to-end tests,
which we will talk about later.
But we're, at this point, looking to add to the middle of that test pyramid.
Adding an integration test where we're testing that controller logic
is working model logic in the way that we expect.
So,
I would like for us to write an integration test
that covers our controller logic.
So, write at least one test.
The challenge here is to write at least one test for the todos
controller that exercises one of the CRUD operations.
Now to do that,
you're going to have mock an Express request and response object and provide
some values that can be used to satisfy the requirements of the controller
logic that we have in that we have in that file.
So that'll be part of the challenge there.
So we'll probably for this, since this is a meatier task,
we'll take for sure 30 minutes.
We'll probably say 40 minutes to tackle this because this will be the
first time that you've engaged with these technologies.
And you have any questions on the testing front,
you can just create --- if you'd like,
you can create a new file in the test directory here,
and if you npm test, any test logic that you run will be picked up and executed.
So,
if you'd like to take a crack at that first before modifying the model at all,
you can certainly do that,
or if you'd like to modify the model first and update
the API with this new property, you can take a crack at that first.
But I think it would be good opportunity to try to
take a crack at both of these tasks.
So,
adding one integration test for the controller and then also the addition to the Todo model that we've been talking about.