The first part that we'll start to break down in our application stack is one
of the most important components that we have in the stack,
which is the Express web server.
It handles incoming HTTP requests and renders HTTP responses with HTML and JSON
and is kind of a core component of this and any other Node.
js web application.
It's very similar --- it's very similar in style to say Sinatra,
if you've worked with that framework in the Ruby world or maybe
Nancy from the C# world or any number of other HTTP
microframeworks out there in that it is very,
very minimal,
and it's also by far the most popular HTTP request handling library out there.
And loath to call it a web framework because it's not really a framework.
It's a module that's really good at routing HTTP requests to a chunk of
JavaScript code that you would like to run on the server.
Unlike a framework like Rails or ASP.
NET MVC or Spring, batteries are absolutely not included with Express.
Anything you want Express to do,
you have to install as an additional middleware or
some other add-on to the software.
So, there's good things and bad things about this.
The good thing is that you never end up with more bloat in your
application than you absolutely require because you're consciously
choosing every single piece of software that's executed when
you're handling an HTTP request.
The downside is that there are no intelligent defaults.
So, if you want to do something like, oh,
I don't know, parse incoming post requests from a client,
you need to install an extra piece of middleware to do that,
which we have in our sample application.
So there's good things and bad things about that design.
The reason why I still like it very much today is because it's not magical.
It's very easy for me to reason about what this
piece of software is actually doing.
And the reason for that is it's all based on a middleware stack.
Before we go any further,
does anybody know what this picture is a reference to by any chance?
No?
Alright.
So what you all need to do today when you go home is fire up your Kindle
and download Ready Player One is the name of the book,
and this is the stacks, which is a vertical trailer home --- trailer park,
which is featured in Ready Player One.
Fantastic book.
You will not be sorry that you did that.
But the middleware stack is all Express is.
It's just executing a set of JavaScript functions to
process an incoming HTTP request, which is coming into your web application.
So,
when your web app receives a HTTP request on port 3000 or wherever it's running,
usually what happens is Express will execute something called a middleware,
and that's just a fancy name for a JavaScript
function which takes in a HTTP request, executes some logic,
and either returns a response or passes it ahead to the
next handler in the middleware stack.
So in a typical Express application you have some number
of global middleware that are going to run on almost
every request or every request,
and we'll see how we configure that here in a second.
We'll also have some specific routes in our applications,
so we'll want to handle specific URLs with specific logic for maybe
getting a todo item out our database or executing other logic when a
certain path is requested within the application.
And then if the global middleware and the application routes are
unable to process the request or God forbid an error happens
during the execution of those middleware,
we can have other middleware that's lower down in our stack
that will catch errors like a 404 Not Found,
like if we don't have a handler to handle a certain kind of request,
or a 500 error if one of our other middlewares throws an exception.
So we have this stack of JavaScript functions that are executed sequentially.
At some point, someone is going to return a response of some kind,
hopefully, is kind of how this works.
And if you've done any server programming or
developed rack applications for Ruby, you might be kind of familiar with this concept of a middleware stack.