Now it's time for the next exercise portion of our morning,
where you fix more stuff in the example code project.
So to correspond with exercise #2,
we've got some more GitHub issues for you to take a look at.
They are tagged with exercise2.
And the first one is a bit that probably needs to be implemented
before we take this thing fully to production,
which is a task which will --- or a task to modify our collect_static task,
which we already have,
in addition to running our application JavaScript through
Browserify to then run it through Uglify as well.
So compressing the JavaScript source into a minified JavaScript source file
that we can use in production and putting it into the public directory just
like we do with the rest of the collect_static command.
So spoiler alert, there is a Grunt plugin called Uglify,
which is probably the place to start barking up if you
want to take a crack at that task.
So that is number 1.
For bonus point actually on this task, I didn't actually call it out here,
but if you look in the EJS template, which renders our TodoMVC page,
there's a little bit of conditional logic in there
that inserts a minified script,
or like a script tag to the minified version of like app.
css if we're in the production environment.
But the JavaScript is just app.
js every time,
so maybe we also want to in the production environment include the minified.
js file rather than fully inflated one with the source maps and everything.
So that is another bit you might want to take care
of during this particular issue.
The other one that I put out there was to add a npm start script
that is dedicated just for running migrations.
I think you'll probably notice something in the package.
json that already does run the migrations,
but poststart, which is what it's currently assigned to,
can do lots of other things.
So it might be nice to have a npm script which just runs
migrations using the Sequelize command line tool.
So for that you'll have to learn a slightly different
incantation to actually run that and make it work.
So adding a special purpose migration command to our npm
scripts will be another thing you could work on.
And those are the two I've got,
but I'm getting like unsolicated pull requests for all kinds of stuff,
which is awesome. I'm very stoked at what you guys are doing with this.