Before I went to break,
I was kind of working a little bit on figuring out why my Vue.
js theme switcher that I had attempted to demo a few minutes ago wasn't working,
and it was a silly mistake, as you might imagine.
Here if we pull this up again, I moved the location of the radio buttons,
and now when I click them, I switch between a light and a dark CSS theme.
And, if we take a look at the elements,
we can see that the class changes from light to dark when I go back and forth.
So the issue at play was I had added the radio buttons here above the footer,
but it actually wasn't a part of this same element,
the section element, that we attached our Vue.
js component to.
So the events that I was firing and the model I was trying to
bind to was not actually part of the component.
And so by moving the inputs inside the actual component,
they were able to bind to the same model.
So it was just the location of my markup in the DOM was misplaced.
The rest of the code was working fine.
So that is the piece for the TODO app for the theme switcher using Vue.
js that we had before.
And,
the other bit that we asked you to take a look at
going into the break was a Socket.
IO and trying to incorporate Socket.
IO into the updating flow of a todo item.
The challenge that I placed to you guys going into the break ---
and I didn't see any pull requests come in,
which is okay.
You're out having some Tai food, chowing down on a sandwich,
catching up, totally fine.
But the challenge I posed to you guys was using Socket.
IO, update the Vue.
js based user interface based on some activity that was going on on the server.
Whenever a new todo was added, push an event using Socket.
IO up to the server.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I didn't see the pull requests come in so over lunch I tried to get this going,
so we can take a look at that.
If we reload here, we have a list of todos.
Maybe knock out a couple of those there.
And there's our list.
And we can still see that it is working and persisting stuff to a database,
but now what we would like to have happen is when I add a todo list
item over here and I just implement it for the add,
I get another item showing up over here.
Yo yo, if I add that over here, oh no!
We do have a little.
js error, so --- oh oops!
A minor problem as I was finishing this up.
One moment please.
Just need to change that up right quick,
reload both of these, and with any luck that will be the end of it.
So, we add a todo list yup yup,
and then we see that added on our other tab as well.
So,
the way that we implemented this was wiring up a socket
server with our REST API endpoint, and when that add operation is executed,
emit a message back up to the client with that todo that was added.
So, let's break down that code here real quick.
We'll start on the back-end.
Now, here in the command where we actually start up our server,
we added a little bit of logic here to actually initialize a Socket.
IO server and associate that with the HTTP server for the application.
So, we created our HTTP server like before,
and now we create an instance of Socket.
IO that we can use to manage incoming socket connections from our users.
And then I pass that to a utility module that I created for
handling socket communication over here,
which has a method called init.
And then we pass to that a Socket.
IO object.
Now if we look at that socket object defined at the same level as webapp.
js, that init function just passes the Socket.
IO instance and assigns that to a module-scoped variable called io.
And then we export another function called todoAdded,
which we intend to be called from our controller.
It's going to be passed a todo item and then it's going to use that Socket.
IO instance to emit this event, todoAdded, to the other connected clients.
So,
I guess the other bit on the server-side to point out is we just
required that module here in our controller,
and then in our create function if the todo was created successfully,
then we call that function and emit that event in our Socket.
IO server.
Back in the Vue.
js view,
right now this is all implemented within the constructor for the Vue component.
There are a few ways we could approach this,
but I created a property that's not going to be
observable on this Vue instance called socket,
and I call that io function,
which is added into the window global scope by including this Socket.
IO JavaScript file, which is served up by Socket.
IO on the server.
And, after I create that socket, I add a listener for todoAdded.
And because the scope of this does change within this function,
I just stashed it away in a variable called self.
And then when that todoAdded item is fired,
I'm going to check the list of todos that I already
have to see if I have that todo item.
So I'll check the ID of all of the ones that have been
successfully created against the one that just got added.
And if I don't already have it in my list of todo items,
I go ahead and push that into that array,
which then will update the UI with the latest list of todo items.
Any questions on that particular bit of code or Socket.
IO stuff before we keep trucking?
Yes?
What is the of keyword?
Is it basically serving the same purpose there as a foreach loop or
how exactly are you doing that particular loop?
It's sort of a variation on the traditional for loop where
you have an iterator which is incremented.
The primary reason I'm using this here rather than like an
array foreach where you pass in a function with every
element of the array is the foreach, you can't break out of a foreach loop.
It's going to be executed for every member of the array,
whereas in a for-of loop you can break out early,
which I needed to do here.
So, I'm sort of tracking the state there,
I assign the current todo item to that t variable,
and then start to work with it in the for loop.
Other questions?
Alright, cool beans.
Let's keep moving.
If you have any other questions as we go along, that's great.
I'll push up that branch with the Socket. IO changes after we're sort of off to the races on our next exercise.