It looks like we have a couple pull requests in to
take a look at our two challenges.
So, let's see what we've got, see if folks were able to crack this nut.
I did notice that we had one contribution that is what we're
looking for in addition to a couple stylistic fixes that I
had actually mentioned yesterday, so I appreciate the help there.
Well basically what we had to do to add the this Babel set
of presets is number one install the preset set as a
development dependency in our package.
json, which we did here.
So there are the ES2016 presets.
We also added the presets,
or we changed the presets configuration for babelify such
that it would use both of those presets,
both ES2015 and ES2016.
So that is what we were looking for.
And now when we compile our JavaScript,
we'll have the ability to use those ES2016 features,
which I think there's actually only like one or two major ones,
in our Javascript files as well.
So we won't immediately put it to work,
but now our client-side JavaScript capabilities are just that much more elite.
So I'm going to go ahead and +1 this guy,
looks good to me, and I'm going to merge it down.
So thank you very much.
Good work there.
Alright, we also have a pull request for the SCSS changes.
We have the font color defined as a variable here,
looks to be a gray, I'm sure it's perfectly readable,
and then we're changing the color of the h1 to that,
and then in the info we're actually changing all of the
color to that rather than just the anchors,
which I guess is fine.
That's pretty close.
I think what I was hoping for was we'd actually just get the anchors themselves,
but that's pretty close.
So, I'm going to say partial credit there.
The primary bit is here.
We define this shared color that we're then going to use two
different places in our CSS declarations. So that is definitely what we're looking for there.