You can now use assertions to handle and expect an exception being thrown.
The other nice feature of the way that they are being programmed now
and the main reason that they were moved to the assertions class and
not the test annotation is that you can now use lambdas to write the
expected outcome of the test.
Let's look at a demo of JUnit 4 exception handling versus JUnit 5.
I've gone ahead and created two classes to illustrate the
difference between exception handling in JUnit 5 and 4.
On the left, I have the JUnit 5 test, and on the right, I have the JUnit 4 test.
The key differences here, as you can see on the right on line 7,
we have a test with a value of expected = Exception.
class.
And on the left, we only have the @Test annotation,
and we've moved that code down to the Assertions.
assertThrows on line 12.
So you can see that the assertion here is saying that
we're expecting an exception to be thrown,
and then there's a lambda expression that illustrates what that
exception's going to be and how we should handle that.
Let me combine these two so that you can see the code a
little bit better in the JUnit 5 example.
Now this test does look a little bit more complex than what you had in 4,
and that's because we've started to embrace lambdas in here.
Let's run this test and you can see what this looks like and
the code that gets returned based off of whether it was a
successful code or an error code.
So let's right-click and say Run As, JUnit Test.
And our error came back handled,
and we got a green test because the exception was expected to be thrown,
and the assertion caught it.
Now let's look at a little slightly different example,
and that's at the bottom here, we have a timeout.
So we're saying that we expect a timeout to happen inside of our
application and to handle that accordingly.
So we can say if this longer than 10 ms,
then we want to catch an exception being thrown or an
interrupted exception being thrown,
so the thread is going to wake up if it's a duration of 10 ms.
And what that would look like in JUnit 4 is a little bit different.
It wasn't exactly clear what the timeout was,
so we get to use that Duration API and we get to use the Assertions API as well.
If we run this, it's going to work as expected as well.
Right-click, Run As, JUnit Test.
And that will succeed as well.
And you can see that the timeout was handled the correct way.
And the key point that I want to point out here is that we can
begin handling lambdas with our exceptions,
and let's talk a little bit more about assertions and the power of lambdas inside those assertions.