To demonstrate the default method functionality,
I've gone ahead and created a simple little project
here that is defined using four files.
And in the first file, our AppConfig,
we have an interface that defines the configuration for our application.
We have a bean as designated on line 6 using the @Bean
annotation that implements the MessageBean interface.
The MessageBean interface is the code that actually defines
our PostConstruct default method that, just as a simple System.
out.
println for us here, we could do more with it,
but this works for the example that we're trying to illustrate here.
And we have a bean that actually implements this interface,
the ShowMessageBean that has the method for showing our message.
Finally we have an Applicate.
java file that just spins up an instance of the
application context and grabs that instance of the bean
and then calls our ShowMessage method.
So what we're expecting to see here is this test message being printed out,
as well as the System.
out.
println for post construct from that init method.
Let's run this application now and see what gets printed out to the screen.
So we're just going to right-click and say Run As, Java Application.
And you'll see that once it gets created,
it has the post construct message of ShowMessageBean and
then our Test message from calling the.
showMessage method.
So it works very easily,
but you can see that there's a lot of power in being able
to spread this default implementation across any beans
that implement that interface.
So we get that shared functionality without having to go
through and create an abstract class.
You'll notice that our ShowMessageBean just implements this interface,
and it could implement multiple interfaces where we'd get that
same functionality across multiple interfaces.
So very similar to the multiple inheritance that we had back in the C++ days,
this will allow us to have that functionality and have those
default methods in our Spring application.
Works very well.
Spring 5 built upon this by making that selectable,
but for our example,
this works great just to show you how that functionality will be displayed through our application's creation phase.