In some final touches to polish your resume.
Don't include references available upon request.
Wait to be asked.
Hiring managers will assume you have them.
You don't need to tell them you do.
You want to be sure to have your references ready to go when you're asked for them.
Have someone else proofread your resume.
Spelling, grammar and punctuation must be perfect.
It's hard to prove with your own work.
So ask friends or family to also look at.
Sami document is a PDF.
Well, looks like a clean and well-structured document and your computer might look different on another
computer.
A PDF helps you avoid this by saving the page is an image rather than a text file.
Name your file appropriately.
Don't just have it as resume or something.
Equally, remember the person receiving it is going to be getting many resumes.
A better way to save it is your name.
Plus, resume or last name?
Plus, first name plus resume.
Make it easy for the hiring manager to find your information.
Update your resume.
Well, even if you're currently employed, at some point you may find that you need to update your resume.
Also, we often row beyond our original roles, further our qualifications, and we develop new sets
of skills.
Congratulations.
That brings us to the end of the resuming writing course.
While working for your resume.
Press pause and carefully.
Craft each line of your resume.
Go through all resources available and make sure you get some feedback before we send it out.
Well, I wish you the best of luck and plenty of interviews.