Let's start with why your resume is so important.
First, your resume is a marketing document that represents you when you are not there.
Most of resumes fall into the everything I've done camp.
There's a lot of I've done these.
I've been responsible for that.
This is certainly very important.
But don't stop it here.
Explain.
How did you help the company achieve this or that when listing a list of duties and responsibilities?
You are missing the opportunity to sell yourself.
You've got to approach this project with a top of mind that you are making a marketing document and
your intent is to capture insurgents.
Audience Attention.
Recruiters want to know what benefits your current skills will bring to their company.
The better your resume explained the situation, the better it will serve the purpose.
The first impression you make on the recruiter is the last.
A strong resume also creates this first impression on behalf of you.
Your resume also convinces the recruiter that you are the right candidate.
A good resume is going to allow you to move forward to the next step in the process, which is interviewing.
You'll likely need to conduct at least one interview to be offered a position.
So having a resume is essential.