What recruiters look at first on your resume.
An easy way to find out what a recruiter looks for on your resume is to put yourself in the recruiters
shoes.
The first thing to know is that recruiters are very busy professionals.
They have to deal with hundreds of resumes before choosing the perfect ones.
Think about what those questions might be and proactively address them in their document.
Don't leave anything to interpretation.
Most recent work experience recruiters are looking for experience in qualifications related to the job
they're considering you for.
Their primary hope is to see relevant experience in your 2 to 3 most recent jobs.
However, that doesn't mean they ignore the rest of your work experience.
They simply look at their first.
Storytelling.
Recruiters are looking for someone whose career progression tells a connected story, as opposed to
someone who worked everywhere without developing a specific skillset relevant to the job they are applying
for.
The biggest challenge today in developing a one page resume is creating a document that will be as effective
when someone scans it very quickly.
Next, facts and numbers.
The best way to do it is to quantify your achievements, results, accomplishments, experiences.
What does it actually mean?
Well, you have to provide straight facts in your prior experiences.
For example, instead of saying I helped my company make the profit, you should write, I created two
new tools that helped my company say 50% cost notice.
The second example helps illustrate your real contribution.
Now, when making your resume, make sure you review every line and identify if there is any way you
can mention numbers.
Next deployment gaps.
That sounds like a problem.
Do not fear recruiters and hiring managers are trained to look for gaps in candidates resumes.
It's totally fine to have gaps in your employment, but you need to make sure you can explain them.
You might fall into the following situations.
Maybe you took some time to work on a personal project, or would take a trip or obtain a diploma a
certificate to participate in charity projects or do some volunteering work.
Make sure you create a link between what you did during this break and the position you are after now.
Overall structure, although recruiters mostly care about your experience, knowledge and skills.
They still notice your resume as overall structure.
Is it easy to read?
Is it well-structured?
Is it visually appealing?
They'll take this all into account when deciding if they want to pursue or not.
Also, don't make your resume too long.
Condense it so that it's no more than two pages.
Let's conclude with what recruiters look at first on your resume.
First, most recent work experience.
Second storytelling.
You are telling the story of your career, so be as concise as possible.
First, facts and numbers.
So be specific and use metrics where possible.
Full employment gaps.
That's fine to have them, but you need to explain.
And the final one, your overall structure, the content, the visual appearance, colors, chronological
order of your work experience.
We will review these points in our next section.