AWS Lightsail has an easy‑to‑use user interface for quickly
bringing solutions to life within AWS.
Lightsail is the easiest way to get a project in AWS up and running.
You can launch a virtual server in Lightsail within
minutes that provides compute power and other useful
features for running a project in AWS.
Lightsail has a concept called blueprints,
which are essentially software packages you can have preinstalled
and configured into your Lightsail environment.
With blueprints,
you can easily create Lightsail environments with software preinstalled,
such as Drupal or WordPress.
These solutions can be used to make websites on AWS with no coding required.
Blueprints can also be used to add stacks to your Lightsail environment,
such as Node.js, or NGINX,
or even Django so that your environment has software
preinstalled and you can quickly begin coding.
Lightsail environments can be linked to Cloud9 instances so that
developers can create their Lightsail environments in the cloud and
then use Cloud9's IDE with all of its enhanced features to change code
directly on the Lightsail instance.
This approach is very fast,
and I recommend leveraging Cloud9 in Lightsail when you need to
get an application in AWS running quickly with minimal
infrastructure or administrative overhead.
The architecture for Lightsail with Cloud9 is fairly simplistic.
From a high level, users access AWS from their personal computer.
Then, within their browser, they can use Cloud9 to read,
write, and debug code as demonstrated before.
From there,
users can create a Lightsail environment with a preconfigured blueprint and
link Cloud9 to the environment so that they can leverage the Cloud9 IDE to
code directly on their Lightsail instance.
It really is that easy.
However, there are some tradeoffs you make when using AWS Lightsail.
Obviously, the benefit is its ease of use.
However, because of this, as a user,
you have far less power for customization and control over
your environment when using Lightsail.
Lightsail is abstracting many AWS services away from you,
such as EC2, IAM, and CloudFormation.
Using these services directly will provide more granular
control to you as a user; however,
using Lightsail will make it much faster to provision private
servers that can host applications in the cloud.
My recommendation would be to use Lightsail if you are new to AWS
or strongly want to minimize the amount of time spent
provisioning services within the AWS console.
In my experience, enterprise applications are rarely created using Lightsail,
but that's not to say it isn't possible.
It's important to understand the tradeoffs of using Lightsail
before you decide using it over a different service.
Lightsail is very easy and fast to use.
If that's extremely important to you, then Lightsail may be the way to go. It's typically something you have to evaluate on a use‑case‑by‑use‑case basis.