The next concept we are going to introduce is environment
variables. Environment variables are named values that are dynamic
and change the way a program is executed.
Environment variables are commonly used in enterprise
systems to create more dynamic applications.
It's important to have a solid understanding of what environment variables are
and how to use them if you're going to create applications in an enterprise
environment. Let's take a quick look at what a standard web application might
look like. A user connects to a website via a URL, which is hosted via content
delivery network, or CDN.
In AWS, this would be a service called CloudFront. The CDN is
synced within object storage to reduce latency and provide a
more widely available website.
The objects stored holds compiled website code and static assets,
which are then served through the CDN and loaded
directly onto the user's browser.
This type of system for a front‑end application is how a
lot of modern websites work today.
In order for the application to grab live data,
the website uses REST APIs to communicate with the backend web server.
This concept works well when a website needs to point to the exact
same backend server every time, but what if we have the same
application that has multiple environments,
for example, a test and production environment?
In this situation,
how would our front‑end know if it was supposed to hit
either the test or production backend server, depending on
which environment it was running on?
This issue is commonly solved with environment variables.
For this example,
our website contained an environment variable called BACKEND_API, r something
similar, that could be updated dynamically to contain the location of either
the test or production backend server endpoint.
This enables us to have the exact same code build for
multiple environments that execute differently due to the
environment variable set within them.
So once our website has hit our backend server, the
backend will process our business logic and gather or
update information from a database.
We've yet again encountered an environment variable problem,
as we will likely need to have different database connections for both our
production and test environments. In this use case, our backend could have an
environment variable called DATABASE_CONNECTION, or something similar, that can
dynamically serve the backend proper information to connect to the database
that's specific to the environment.
This is fairly high‑level,
but this is a common example of how an enterprise application
can leverage environment variables to control execution of a dynamic three‑tiered application.