So now we're ready to deploy a CDK application.
So let's quickly revisit Josh and his proof of concept.
So Josh, like us, just created his first CDK app.
He has access to an AWS account for his proof of concept, and really, here
you should too. You should have access to an account,
ideally an account that just you are working in
where you can deploy this as a test.
Now he has added a resource to his CDK app,
and he's ready to deploy this initial app into this AWS account.
So let's talk about how the workflow goes when you're working with the CDK.
And again, if you've reviewed the previous course,
this is going to be a bit of review.
So first we have init, which is where you create your project,
and we have completed this.
Now the next step is going to be bootstrapping,
which we'll talk about within the next clip. And then we have synth,
which is where you can generate your CloudFormation templates.
Now, even if you don't choose to run the synth command,
this happens behind the scenes. And then we have deploy,
where we actually take those generated templates and we
send them off to CloudFormation.
So over this module,
we're going to be fully realizing this workflow. We're first going to be
reviewing how the CDK integrates with AWS using CloudFormation.
We will then be bootstrapping an AWS environment.
We will be reviewing the generated CloudFormation templates for our CDK app
and then ultimately deploying our CDK app. And then we'll be examining our
CDK app within CloudFormation in the AWS console.
So another quick review for you is just the common CDK
commands for the CLI that you need to know. Now some of these
we have already used, like cdk version,
which just lets us know the version of the CDK CLI that
we're using, as well as cdk init where you pass in both
the template and the language.
We also have cdk bootstrap that we'll be using within this module,
which, again, helps us configure a new AWS environment for use with the CDK.
We can also look at all of the stacks within an app with cdk list.
Once we're ready to deploy, we'll use cdk deploy. And when we're
ready later on to actually destroy our application,
we can use cdk destroy.
We also can launch the docs, which we've already done with cdk docs.
We can compare the differences between the local version of our
application and the deployed version with cdk diff, and we'll be
using this within the next module. You can review those generated CloudFormation templates using cdk synth.