And now we're ready to actually deploy our CDK application.
So here, within this demo,
were first going to be deploying our app, and then we'll be reviewing the
generated CloudFormatin stack within the AWS console.
So, let's dive in.
So first, I want to point out again here,
within the account that we're going to be using and within the
Northern Virginia region, we currently only have the CDKToolkit stack
included. And as a reminder, that is the stack that was generated when
we ran the cdk bootstrap Command.
So now I'm going to go over to the terminal.
So now, here within the terminal, I'm first going to run cdk list.
Now this is going to list all of the stacks that
are included within our CDK app.
So you can see here that we only have a single stack,
which is the TypescriptCdkStack.
Now since we only have a single stack,
any of the commands that we want to run, we can simply just use the command.
We don't have to specify the exact stack.
If we were dealing with a multi‑stack application, in those cases,
we would need to specify the stack that we were going to work with.
But now, since we just have a single stack, we're going to run just cdk deploy.
And now we can see that the deployment has completed.
It even lets us know here what our output value is that we configured.
But let's look at it a little bit more in depth by
diving back over into the AWS Console.
So now we can see that we have two stacks, our
TypescriptCdkStack and the CDKToolkit.
So first, I'm going to click into the stack that we just deployed, and I
want to go now to the Resources tab. And here I can see within the
Resources tab we do have a CDKMetadata item.
Now this is metadata that's associated with our deployment that
lets the CDK know all the specific versions of the different
libraries that we used within our project. And generally you
won't need to mess with this.
This is something that the CDK uses behind the scenes.
But then we can also see our DocumentsBucket that was created, and you can see
here that it does have the logical ID that was used within the generated JSON
template that we reviewed within the last clip.
We also can see here that we have our output configured, so our
DocumentsBucketNameExport is the name of the bucket that's included here.
Now this also uses a name that is consistent with what we have named it, but it
includes the name of the stack and then the name we gave it,
which was DocumentsBucket, and then followed by a unique identifier.
So we have all of those values also included.
Now I'm going to go over to the terminal really quick,
and here we can also see our export if we use aws cloudformation
list‑exports. And we can see that our export,
which is DocumentsBucketName and the value of it have been included here
as well. So we've done a lot here within this module.
We started off with an initialized application where we had our
own generated resources. And then after this,
we were able to first go through the bootstrapping process.
We then reviewed the generated templates, and we deployed
our application to our AWS account.
Now that we have this in place, within the next module,
we're going to go through the process of how we
actually manage a deployed stack, how we push updates,
how we view differences between the deployed stack and
our local stack, and then ultimately, once we move on later, we're going to be building out integrations with Lambda and Fargate.