So now that we have a lambda TypeScript function configured within our project,
we're now ready to implement that lambda function within the CDK.
So here within this particular clip,
we're going to be walking through the process of configuring
our lambda function project within the CDK,
deploying our lambda function, and then,
ultimately, verifying our lambda function within the AWS console.
So let's dive in.
So our first step is actually here within the terminal.
We need to install some of the packages that we
looked at earlier within this module.
So I'm going to go ahead and run npm install,
and I'm going to specify first the aws‑lambda‑nodejs and aws‑lambda packages,
and I want to be sure that we saved both of these.
Now I should mention here I'm in the root of our project,
and I'm not in our specific lambda project.
Now the next thing is, I need to install a specific version of Parcel.
If you remember, this is used within the bundling process with the CDK,
and there is a specific version that they're expecting.
So here, I'm going to run npm install,
and we're going to install Parcel 2.0.0 beta 1.
And I'm going to tell it to save this as a development
dependency and use this exact version.
Now that I have this in place, I'm going to head back over to VS Code.
So if you remember, previously,
we isolated all of our networking resources within a single construct,
and we're going to do the same thing here for the API.
So I'm going to go under the lib directory, and I'm going to create a new file.
We'll call this one api.ts.
And here, I'm going to use the same snippet I used for the networking construct.
And we're going to call this DocumentManagementAPI.
And here within this construct,
this is where we're going to define our lambda function.
But one of the things we're going to need to do here is we're going to need
to import the packages that we installed with npm install.
I'm going to go up here under my CDK core import,
and I'm going to add in two additional values.
So I'm going to pull in everything from the aws‑lambda‑nodejs package as Lambda,
and then I'm going to pull in one specific item from aws‑lambda,
which is runtime.
So the first thing we're going to do here is to give our lambda function a name.
We'll call it getDocumentsFunction.
And then we're going to say new lambda.NodejsFunction.
And just like any other construct,
we're going to need to add in first a reference to the current construct,
which is going to be this particular construct.
And then we're going to need to give it a name,
and I'm going to call this my GetDocumentsFunction.
Now that I have this in place, I can now pass in a props object,
which has all of the different configuration values
that I would be concerned with.
Now one of the first things I want to specify is runtime.
Now depending on your machine, this is probably going to be set properly for you,
but I always want to be explicit.
So in this case, we'll say runtime, and then I'm going to set this to be NODEJS,
and we'll do 12 for the version.
Now the next thing that I want to specify here is the entry point.
Now this is going to be a reference to the TypeScript file that we
created within our API and getDocuments folder.
So to do this, I'm going to need to be able to use the path module,
so I'm going to need to import that.
And so we'll say path.join.
Now in this case, we need to specify the directory name of this file,
so we're going to say dirname.
And then we're going to need to tell it to go up a directory.
And the reason here we're using path.join as opposed to just
writing it out using dots and slashes is we want this to
work in a cross‑platform manner.
And so the path.join function takes care of that for us.
So the next thing we're going to do is in the api directory,
and then within that directory, we're going to go to getDocuments,
and then within that directory, we're going to go to index.ts.
So that should give us a reference into our entry point.
Now the next thing we need to specify is the handler.
So within that particular file, what is the handler?
Well, in this case, it's going to be getDocuments.
And then the next thing we need to specify is the external modules.
Now you remember that this is what we tell Parcel to not
bundle in with our bundled application.
So here, I'm going to specify aws‑sdk.
So once we have these things in place,
we're now ready to go through the process of integrating this in with our stack.
So I'm going to go over to our TypeScript CDK stack.
We're going to go in and create a new instance.
So we're going to call this api.
And now for this to work, we're going to need to import this in.
And then, we can go down here and say new DocumentManagementAPI.
We're going to pass in the construct, and we're going to give it a name.
Now at this point, we don't have any props to pass into it,
but we're going to do one other thing.
We're going to go ahead and add in tags.
We're going to say everything that is within this api construct,
we want to add a tag module and then API.
So now we should be ready to validate our lambda function.
So I'm going to navigate over to the terminal.
So here within the terminal, I'm going to run cdk deploy.
So here, we're going to see something for the first time.
First,
I want to point out that we can see that our function
here actually built in 2.44 seconds.
So this is going to be infinitely faster than if we had used the Docker options.
So again,
this ability to build this locally is baked into the L2 construct
that we're using for Node.js lambda functions.
But the other thing I want to point out here is that because we have IAM
statement changes, the CDK is going to alert us to this fact,
and we're going to have to approve these. Now there is a way to
specify that it shouldn't warn you about these things.
But if you're just deploying from your own machine,
I think it's a good idea to review these anytime they pop up, and we'll see
them multiple times throughout this module. And here, we can see that we're
seeing a change related to the lambda execution role.
So in this case, we're going to say yes,
we do want to deploy these changes. And now we can see that
the deployment process has completed.
So I'm going to jump back over to the browser.
So here I can see that the update is complete for our TypeScript CDK stack.
I'm going to go under Services, and I'm going to go to Lambda.
Now we should see our lambda function being deployed here.
So I'm going to click on the one lambda function that we have.
And then from here, I'm going to click on the option to test the function.
Now here, we're not going to be passing any values into
this. So we can just have a test event that doesn't have
any variables that are passed in.
And then I'm going to go to the bottom and say Create.
Now that I've created this test event,
I should be able to go in and simply do Test. And we can see that
are lambda function has executed, and you can see here that we are
returning the correct status code and the body that we specified within our TypeScript file.