So now that we've shown that we can deploy a Lambda
function and execute it within AWS,
we're now going to go through the process of starting to
integrate it in for our proof of concept.
So here, within this demo,
we're first going to be passing environment variables into our Lambda function,
and we'll be deploying sample documents using S3 deployment within the CDK.
So let's dive in.
So I'm here within the API construct that we created within our project.
One of the things we're going to need to do is we're going to need to
pass a reference to our bucket into our construct.
So the first thing I'm going to do to make that work is I'm going to import S3.
Now I'm going to go into the DocumentManagementAPIProps interface,
and I'm going to specify that we're going to have a documentBucket,
and this is going to be of type s3.IBucket,
which, again, is just an interface that will work as a reference to a bucket.
Now the next thing we're going to need to do is we're
going to need to make this not optional,
because we're going to actually need this value.
Now if we go in and look at IBucket,
I'm going to actually hold down Cmd and hit IBucket,
we can see here that it's going to include values like
the bucketArn and the bucketName.
We'll be using both of those here within this module.
But for now,
we're going to be concerned with the bucketName because our
Lambda function needs to get a reference to that.
Now what we can do after externalModules,
we can actually go in and say environment,
and this is going to allow us to pass in an object
that's basically a string map.
So we're going to have a string key,
which we're going to call DOCUMENTS_BUCKET_NAME.
And then we're going to have the value,
which in this case is going to be props.documentsbucket.bucketname.
Now we can save this file, but we're going to need to navigate over to our stack.
So here within our stack,
we can see that there is an error because that props value is now required.
So I'm going to need to go in after the name,
and I'm going to need to add an object,
and we're going to need to specify the documentBucket,
which, in this case, we're going to tie to our bucket.
Now that we have this in place,
we now have a way to get a reference to that
documentBucket into our Lambda function.
So I'm going to go back over into our API construct.
I'm going to copy the name of this environment variable,
and I'm going to go over into our index.ts file and
into our getDocuments function.
Now what I'm going to do first outside of the function is I'm going to specify
that the bucketName is going to be equal to process.env.
This is how we get access on Lambda to our environment
variables and then the DOCUMENTS_BUCKET_NAME. So here we
actually have a reference to that.
And what we're going to do now is we're just going
to add in a logging statement.
So now that I have this in place, if I save this and we now go to deploy,
we should be able to see our Lambda function include this value.
So I'm going to go over to the terminal. And now I'm going to run cdk deploy.
And now we can see that the deployment has completed.
So now we'll navigate over to the browser.
So now I'm here within the AWS console, and I'm going
to click on our Lambda function.
So I should be able from here to go ahead and run test.
And when I do, I should see that this execution did succeed.
And here I can actually see with the log output that I get
Bucket Name, and I get the name of the bucket.
So this is all working properly.
Now there's another area we can look at this here as well.
If I actually scroll down here past the function code,
we can see that we have specified the environment variables and we can see the
DOCUMENTS_BUCKET_NAME and that value included here also.
So here we've done a great job of connecting in our S3
bucket with our Lambda function.
However, let's navigate now over to our S3 bucket.
So I'm going to go to S3, and I'm going to now go to our bucket.
And here you can see we don't have any documents that are included.
So we're going to use another feature of the CDK.
And that is a function that actually enables us to do S3
deployment as a part of deploying our CDK app.
So lets navigate over to the terminal.
So to make this work,
I'm going to need to install a package called aws‑s3‑deployment,
and we'll save this here within the root of our project.
Now that we have that in place, I'm going to navigate back over to VS Code.
So here, within VS Code, I'm going to navigate over to typescript‑cdk‑stack.
And here, right after my bucket,
I'm going to add in the code that we need to do the deployment.
But to make this work,
I'm first going to need to import the package that we just installed.
So here we've called this one s3Deploy. So we're going to
create a new s3Deploy.BucketDeployment,
and we're going to need to work with this like we would any other construct.
So I'm first going to need to pass in a reference here to this
stack. We're going to need to give it a name.
We're going to call this DocumentsDeployment,
and then we'll need to pass in the configuration object.
Now here we need to specify the sources.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a documents
directory here within the root of the project.
So here we can pass in an array of sources.
We're just going to have one,
and I'm going to say s3Deploy.Source, and this is going to be an asset.
And just like when we worked with specifying the
entry point for our Lambda function,
we're going to use the path module from node.
So here I'm going to need to go in and actually import that.
And now we can use path.join_dirname,
and then we're going to have it go up a directory, and then documents.
Then we're going to need to specify the bucket that we want to deploy it too.
So we'll say destinationBucket, and we'll make this equal our bucket.
The last thing I'm going to specify here is I'm going to
specify the memory limit, and in this case,
we're just going to set this to be 512.
So now that I have this in place,
I'm now ready to get the documents and put them within our project.
So here, within VS Code, I'm going to navigate down.
I'm going to create a new folder,
and we're going to call this documents. Now within this folder,
I'm going to go to Reveal in Finder, and I have some files copied.
I'm just going to paste them in.
And these are all just sample PDF files.
So if we take a look at them,
they just have some basic Lorem Ipsum text that's included.
But once this is in place, I can go back into VS Code.
I can make sure that I've saved my stack, and now I can
navigate over to the terminal for deployment.
So now I can run cdk deploy.
We're going to see that there are some additional permissions that
need to be added for the S3 deployment process.
I'm going to say Yes. Now that our deployment has
completed, let's navigate over to the browser.
And so now if I go in and reload our documents bucket,
we can see that the documents that we had included have been deployed into this particular bucket.