Congratulations on finishing the most
advanced CSS course on the internet.
It was a fun ride going through all these
lectures and concepts and projects together with you.
I hope it was real fun for you, as well,
that you're proud of the projects that you've coded
during the lectures, and, of course,
that you've come out of the course
with a lot more knowledge and tools
in your CSS toolbox than you had before you started.
And now, what's next for you?
Well, I'm gonna tell you what I tell
every single one of my students,
which is that you have to practice, practice, practice.
If you want to become better and better
at CSS and web development in general, of course.
A complete course, like the one
that you just finished, can give an amazing foundation
and a lot of knowledge, of course.
But now it's really your turn to put in the work
and to put that knowledge into practice.
And for that, you just have to build
a lot of projects by yourself.
Now, please don't just copy the code
and the projects that we've built in the course
because that's a mistake I see
a lot of students doing all the time.
Instead, come up with your own ideas, your own layouts,
and your own designs and then, code up everything
using the tools that I gave you in the course.
That is how you become a real CSS master, okay?
And I can't wait to see what you're going to
design and build using all these new tools.
And definitely make sure to share your work
here in the Q&amp;A section on Udemy.
Now, another thing that's really important for you
as a CSS NEF is to keep on top of the most important news
in a fast-paced web development industry.
And then, really know how hard it can be,
with so much stuff going on all the time.
And so in order to help you with that,
I actually started a monthly newsletter
a couple of months ago and my subscribers
really appreciated that because it's been
really helpful for them.
So if you want to check that out,
you can just subscribe to newsletter over at jonas.io.
So to make a long story short,
you should keep practicing all the time,
you should keep on top of the web tech news,
and you should, of course, never stop learning.
All right and that's actually all
I had to show you and to tell you.
So good luck with your new skills,
take care and see you next time.
(upbeat electronic dance music)