This is part two
of building the app's header section.
So, to start this lecture,
let's actually put these three elements
that we have here in the header side by side.
And how do we do that?
Well, you guessed it.
We're gonna use Flexbox.
So, what should be the flex container here in this case?
Well, it should simply be the parent element
of the elements that we want side by side.
And that's these three here.
So, the logo, the search bar,
and the user navigation, right?
And so the parent of these is the header element.
So, here we go.
Now, so in the header.
So, all we have to do is
to set display to flex
and that will put them side by side.
Alright, now let's give them actually some background color
so that we can see what's going on here.
So, the search.
I'm gonna use my orangered favorite here again.
And then on this one here, we can use
like, greenyellow.
Alright, check it out.
So, ah, here we go.
Now, how do we want these to be aligned?
We want this green one here,
so the user navigation,
all the way to the right side, right?
And then this one here in the middle.
And what is the Flexbox property that allows us to do that?
I hope that you printed your cheat sheet
so that you can take a look at it
and find out which property we have to use, okay?
And in case you don't know,
we need to use justify-content.
And of course, that one is again on the flex container,
not on the flex items, okay?
So, justify-content will align the elements
along the main axis.
And that's the one we're talking about here, right?
So, what are the possible values here?
For example, we could use center.
Just to show it to you.
And that's what that would do.
So, it would simply center all of these elements
side by side here in the center of the flex container.
But that's also not what we want.
Because what we really want is space between.
Okay?
And so, it will basically divide the empty space
between these three elements.
And that's what that looks like, and it's perfect.
That's exactly what we want.
We could also do like space-around.
Let me show that to you as well.
It would result in this one,
but that puts way too much space
here on the left side of this one
and here on the right side.
So, we don't want that,
we only want a little space,
and so we're gonna do that later with margins.
But for now, in here, let's do space-between.
And I think that this one
is actually the most useful one of all.
Alright?
So, that is alignment along the main axis,
so from left to right.
But we also want to align these items
along the cross axis, right?
So, basically here from top to bottom.
So that, for example, we can have this image here
nicely centered vertically in the header.
So, if we didn't have Flexbox, we could now use like
margin-top and would then have to experiment
which is the perfect margin.
But Flexbox makes our lives so much easier
and all we have to do is
to use the align-items property, right?
So, remember that one.
So, align-items,
and simply set it to center.
And that's what it will produce.
So, this one is now nicely centered vertically,
so along the cross axis,
and so is this one, and this one.
This one is of course overlapping it
because there is too much content in it,
but still, it is now centered.
So, you saw that before, it was set to stretch.
That's why this element here was occupying the entire space,
so everything here was orange, right?
But now we set it to center,
and so it's vertically centered now.
So, that is align-items.
So, all we have to really do now is
to just format these elements here, okay?
So, let's start with our logo
and simply give it some margin to the left side
of three rem, okay.
And so now that's perfect.
So, really nicely positioned here.
So, starting here with the search element,
let's first give it some width, okay?
And since it's a flex item,
let's do that using the flex property.
So, flex, we don't want it to grow
to fill all its available space, okay?
We also don't want it to shrink.
And we want it to occupy 40% of the header, okay?
Now, as for the input element,
this is how we want it to look like, okay?
So, it's this gray rounded element here
with this gray icon here at the end, okay?
So, let's now do that.
And so we start with the font family,
which on an input element doesn't inherit
the font family of the global document.
And so we have to automatically set it to inherit here
and the same thing for the font size actually.
So, let's set it to inherit here as well.
And then we want the background color,
and again we're gonna use our variables here.
And the one that we want right now is this,
this gray color here, okay?
So, light gray two.
We want it to have no border.
We also want the text color to be inherited, okay?
So, we set all of these here in the same place.
Well, what else can we do?
We can set some padding,
so .7 rem on the top and bottom.
And two rem on the left and on the right side.
So, 20 pixels.
Now, we also can set the border radius
to a really high number, doesn't matter.
Can even set it in pixels, it doesn't really matter,
just a high number so that it has these rounded edges.
And, okay, let's take a look, actually.
And that's what it look like.
Well, still not perfect,
but we're kind of getting there.
We have to actually give it a width here, okay?
And we're not doing 100%,
because we want this to happen when we click it.
You saw that?
So, it expanded when it received the focus,
and when we click outside,
it goes back to the original size.
So, let's set it to,
like, 90%.
Okay?
And then we can also change what we want
to happen when we focus the element.
So, focus.
We don't want an outline, okay?
But instead what we want to happen
is that the width should be set to 100%.
So, that was the effect that we saw earlier.
So, when the input element becomes focused,
it increases from 90% to 100% of its available width.
Which is this 40% here of the parent element.
And we also want it to become a little bit darker,
which is basically the same thing as this
but the light number three.
So, that's a bit darker.
And for the animation here,
transition all and .2 seconds.
So, let's take a look at that now.
And that's much better.
So, when we click it,
it increases to 100%.
Great.
Well, it's still not perfect,
but for now, let's continue
with styling this button here now, okay?
So, here we are, the button.
So, first, we don't want any border on it,
and then we want it to have
the same background color as the input.
Because we basically want it to be
like on top of the input, right?
And actually, in order for that to happen,
we should give the input here
some negative margin on the right side.
So, margin-right, and then like -3.5 rem.
And so this way, the button will move
on top of the input, okay?
Now let's also just remove the focus here from this one.
So, outline none.
But what happens instead
is that basically when we click the button,
we just want it to move a bit down.
So, transform translateY,
and then let's just say two pixels.
Alright, let's take a look now.
And that's much better.
So, now it's actually on top of the search bar,
and when we click this,
we see this nice animation going on.
Now, what's left to do here
is to actually center this icon here vertically
as well as horizontally, right?
Because when the input field is not active,
we want it to be at the center of this element here, right?
So, of the parent element.
So, how do we do that?
Well, the best solution is, once again, to use Flexbox.
And so you see, each time we want to center something,
or to align something, we can always use Flexbox.
For Flexbox is perfect for all of these small situations
where you need to align or center some elements.
So, what should actually be
the flex container of these elements?
Well, of course, it's the search element, right?
And so now, for the first time,
we're doing something that we didn't do before.
Which is that a flex item is becoming a flex container.
And that is perfectly possible.
So, we now have nested Flexbox.
Okay?
So, again, let's take a look.
And it's already centered, you see,
because align-items is set to stretch.
So, align-items, let's move it from stretch
to center, and then justify-content also to center.
So, again, align-items to center
centers the elements along the cross axis
and justify-content center
centers the elements along the main axis.
So, let's check that out.
And, yup, that is exactly what we wanted, right?
So, now I hit this and now it grows to the sides.
So, that's perfect.
Now, this margin here is not perfect here actually,
but that's because of the negative margin
that I gave it here on the other side.
Which is actually a bit too much.
So, it was here.
And actually, another thing that we have to do
is to set the background color of the button
to the same color of this focused here
when the input is focused, right?
So, right now if you look closely,
you will see that if the input is selected,
the background color here of this icon
is slightly lighter, okay?
So, let's fix that.
And we have to actually do it outside here.
So, __input:focus,
and then select the adjacent search button, right?
So, we did that a lot of time in the other project.
So, just to remember,
here we have the input, and here we have the button.
And they are siblings, okay?
And so therefore, we can use the adjacent selector
to select the sibling of the selected input, okay?
So, here in the components.
And now, what we want to happen
is that the button becomes
the same background color as the input, okay?
And so now, it should be perfect.
Alright, now one last thing is
the color of this magnifying glass.
Remember that I told you
that with the way that we included
the svg sprite in the HTML,
we could change the svg color
right in CSS, right?
So, let me now show you how we can do that.
And it's actually very easy.
All we have to do is to use the fill property.
So, fill and that's it.
Now we can specify our color.
And the one that I want is this dark gray here,
the number three.
And that's actually it.
Let's just remove here this background color
and then this component will be completely ready.
Okay, let's just compare it to this one.
Well, this is actually a bit different
because the text is bigger here, and lighter,
and so we should change that as well.
So, basically the placeholder here has a lighter text,
then when we start typing, it becomes the dark text
that we have in our example.
Right?
So, what we have to do here is
to change the placeholder text.
So, let's do that.
So, input.
And then remember, what we want is
the webkit-input-placeholder pseudo-element.
So, webkit
input
placeholder.
Meaning that this only works in WebKit right now.
Which are the Chrome and Safari browsers.
So, we want a font-weight of 100 only,
and a color of a light gray four.
Okay?
And now, just remember
that we put the font size here to inherit.
And so, it inherits the global font size,
which is 10 pixels, remember, so one rem.
But that's quite small, actually,
and so let's set a default font size here on the header.
Okay, so let's go to the header
and set a font size here.
And then it will inherit the font size
from this parent component.
So, let's set it to 14 pixels here, so 1.4 rem,
and then check it out again.
And yeah, that's much better.
Now that looks a lot like our original, right?
So this one here.
So, that was some great progress.
You used a lot more Flexbox in this lecture
to align these smaller elements here in this component,
and also over in this header here, right?
So, Flexbox is perfect for this small kind of situations
where you have to do some simple alignments.
So, instead of messing with margins and translates,
and floats, and text-align center, and all of that stuff,
we just use Flexbox, and it's perfect for that.
Now, next up, we need to fix
this user navigation here, of course,
but I'm leaving that to the next lecture
so that you can take a break right now
and then come back to the next lecture
once you're ready to go.