Welcome back. So the final piece
in the puzzle of responsive images,
is to implement them in CSS now.
And so in this lecture, you're gonna learn
how to do exactly that. By using media queries to
target high resolution displays.
Plus, I will show you how to combine multiple
conditions in media queries, which can be
quite handy sometimes, especially when
trying to implement responsive images.
So what we're going to do in this lecture,
is to make this background image here
for the hero, a bit more responsive, okay?
So again, there are a lot of background images
here on this page. So this one,
then these three here,
as well as, yeah this one here.
So all of these background images can be made
responsive, but I will only take care of this one,
and I will leave the other ones, for you,
such as a I did with responsive images in html, okay?
So I created a smaller version of the hero image,
and it's called hero small, okay?
So the original one is this one,
which has 2000 pixels of width,
and you see that this one here is a lot smaller, so,
260 pixels versus 600, so a huge difference actually.
So, let's go to our header. Which is exactly
where we are going to implement this.
Alright, and so responsive images in CSS
are actually pretty straight forward.
Because all we have to do is to write media queries,
in order to load different images, for different situations.
Now up until this point, we have only ever written
media queries related to the screen,
or the viewport width, right?.
But there are other types of media queries,
and one of them is to target resolution.
Okay, so we can implement different styles
not only depending on different viewport width,
but also depending on other things,
such as the device resolution.
So, let's write a media query like that.
So media, and then the one that we're
going to use, is called min-resolution.
And we're going to set it to a value of 192 dots per inch.
And why is that? Well it is 192 dots per inch,
because that's the resolution of the Apple retina screen.
And so that's a high resolution screen,
that's usually used as a reference here, okay?
So, since this is a min media query,
this is basically the same logic,
as with the min width media query, okay?
So whenever the resolution is higher than 192 dots per inch,
the code that is in here, will be applied.
Okay, and so what we put here, well we put
the background image. Alright.
Now, here in the normal state, lets say,
what we actually want to load is the small hero image, okay?
Because if we have just a normal screen
without the high resolution, then the hero small
with 1200 pixels is perfectly enough,
especially considering that it's hidden behind
this layer of off the green color here, okay.
And so the resolution can be even smaller.
And so for the normal situation,
we're basically considering, that we're using
a small resolution screen, and so there we load the
small hero image. But then we write this media query,
in which we say, if the resolution is higher
then 192 dots per inch, then please load the hero image.
Okay? So let's test that in the browser.
And actually to see the difference,
I will change the color here of this gradient, okay?
So I'm setting this to secondary,
So now we know that when the image looks green,
then we're using the primary color, and therefor
we know that it's the small hero here.
And when it becomes yellow, which is the secondary
color yellow, or orange, well then we know
it's the hero, right? So. Let's check that out.
I'm going to reload it. And so we have the green image
here now. So let's actually inspect this as well.
So the header, and so we have our hero small here.
But now if we increase the pixel density here to two,
well then all of sudden it becomes orange,
and what that means is that we are now using the hero image.
So the bigger version of the image.
Alright, so that already works very well.
But we can even improve on this.
So let's say that the screen is only very small.
So for example, for a screen, so that's
the 600 pixel media query, remember? So imagine
that we have a screen with 600 pixels.
And usually these really small screens,
they're usually phones. And phones, they usually
have a pixel density of two. So they are usually
two x screens always, okay? So we can consider that.
Now if the screen is 600 and if the pixel density is two,
well then the image that we need at this size,
doesn't have to be larger than 1200 pixels, right?
So 600 times 2 is 1200, and so an image,
which has 1200 pixels of width,
is more than enough to display
on a high density screen like this, okay?
Therefor, it's not really logic to load
this huge image, so this 2000 pixel image
here on this really small screen, right?
So, how do we do that? Well we can actually extend
this media query here, and add a second condition.
So what we want is when the resolution is larger
than 192, but at the same time,
the width is larger than 600, right?
So that's the part I just talked about.
So, min width, 600 pixels, all right.
So let's recap what's happening here.
So the large version of the hero image,
is shown when the resolution is higher than
192, so when we have a two x screen,
and at the same time, whenever
the width is larger than 600 pixels.
Because if it's below 600 pixels,
then it doesn't really make sense
to display such a high resolution image, okay?
And so let's now test if that works. And yeah it works.
So we see that in here we now are back to using
the hero small, and so it's green.
But as we approach 600, here you see,
that it is working already. So now,
we are back to using the big hero image.
Because starting at this point, it makes sense,
to have a bigger image. Alright.
And so you just learned two things at the same time.
First, how to target these higher resolution screens
using this part, and then you learned
how to combine multiple conditions in a media query.
Alright, now when else does it make sense
to use the larger image? So let's take a look.
Imagine that we have a lower resolution screen.
So when would it make sense to actually use
the 2000 pixel image? Well, basically
if the screen is really huge. So for example,
starting at 2000 pixels. So why not write
a media query saying that as soon as we hit 2000 pixels,
we want to display the hero image,
so the original, not the small one. Alright?
So that's a small challenge for you right now.
So I want you to pause the video,
and implement what we just said.
So basically we want to see the hero,
as soon as the width becomes larger than 2000 pixels.
So I hope you managed to do that.
So media min width, and that's already it,
because all we have to do now, is to just copy this here.
And why is it a min width? Well very simple because
2000 is basically the minimum width that needs
to happen in order for this to happen. Okay?
And so basically we're asking the question,
"Is the width larger than 2000?"
And if it is, then we apply this hero image.
Okay, so let's now try that and,
yep we reached the 2000 pixels,
and then the larger image gets loaded.
Great. That's fantastic okay. Really cool.
Now of course if we are already at two here,
then this media query doesn't take any effect
because then the image will be the
large version already, anyway. Okay?
Now we can do even better than this,
because this code here is the exact same as this one.
And so we can actually combine these two media queries,
and so basically these two conditions.
So this is a condition, and this is another one.
So let me copy this, and then I can just put a comma here.
And so basically that is like an or.
So we say now, well please apply this code.
If this one here happens, or if this happens.
And so this is the exact same thing, but with less code,
and that's of course way better. Alright.
And just to prove to you that it still works like this,
yeah of course, here we go, on the smaller screen here.
And then of course with the lower resolution,
but it starts working at 2000. Yep. That's what happens.
Now all we have to do is convert this here to em.
Okay so 600 divided by 16, such as we did before,
so 37.5, because remember are media queries
are always in em. And now the same thing for
2000 divide by 16, 125 em.
And just to be 100 percent sure now,
let's reload this, and yeah it still works.
Actually you'll see these min width,
that we implemented here in orange color.
So 125 em and 37.5 em as well.
That's these two conditions, this one and this one.
And actually what we did before
in the index HML, we also had these
media queries here, kind of. And so
let's put them to ems as well.
So this one is 37.5 em and then
900 divided by 16 is 56.25.
Alright. And actually it was 56 not 65.
So 56, alright now it's correct. So back to our CSS.
And actually that is already it.
So that's a couple of techniques for responsive images
with CSS. So basically it's just using
media queries and some logic, in order to
achieve the results that we want, based on
different viewpoint sizes and resolutions, of the screen.
So, that concluded our lectures about responsive images,
which are again, a topic that you shouldn't really ignore,
if you want to get serious with responsive design, okay?
So I'll leave it as a challenge to you,
to implement a similar logic for all the other
background images, that we have in our CSS.
And if you have any problems with that,
then just feel free to post to the Q and A,
so that you can get some help with that.
Alright, so I hope that everything makes sense to you,
and that it was quite fun as well, and then
see you in the next lecture after you finish the challenge.