Let's now learn how we can position grid items
on the grid by naming our grid lines.
So what I showed you in the last lecture
and the ones before that is how to position
grid items on the grid by using
the automatically generated grid line numbers, right?
But we can actually make our lives a bit easier
by naming these grid lines,
so let me show you how to do that.
But first, let's add a couple of comments here.
So, "METHOD 1: LINE NUMBERS."
And now I'm gonna actually comment out
all of this code here, and then start from scratch.
Well actually, not really from scratch,
because I'm gonna copy all of this,
but I want to keep the code that we had before,
so that you can then keep this code for yourself, okay?
So this is "METHOD 2" with "LINE NAMES."
So how do we actually name our grid lines?
And actually, it's really simple.
All we have to do is to use the squared brackets like this,
and then in here, put the name of the line.
So what we want to do here is to write header-start.
and the best practice is to basically describe
the content that will be in the track,
so in this case between lines number 1 and 2,
and then say whether it's the start or the end.
Okay, so we have header-start, and then in here,
we will have header-end, okay, and that's actually it.
And so now, this line number 1
is no longer just called line 1,
but it's also called header-start,
and this one here is called header-end.
But what about these boxes here now?
It doesn't make much sense that this line here
is called header-end, because it's not just
the end of the header, but also
the start of these boxes here, right?
And so for that reason, we can actually give
a line more than one name.
So let's call this one here also, let's say,
boxes-start, well, let's call call it just box-start,
and then the next one we call box-end.
Okay, so these are arbitrary names that we come up with,
at least the first part here, so in this case here, box,
and then we just call the one
before the boxes here the start,
and the one after, the end, right?
So this row line here is now called header-end,
and also, at the same time, box-start,
while this one here is called box-end.
Okay, and so now you can probably guess
that we're also gonna call this one here main-start,
and then the next one, let's call it main-end,
and then after that comes the footer.
So let's call it footer-start,
and then the last line is the footer-end, and that's it.
Let's give it some more space here, actually.
No, doesn't work.
Okay, it's no problem.
So we now have all our row lines here named,
and actually, it's a good practice doing so, okay?
So in a professional layout, usually,
we always name our grid lines like this,
and then use these names to position the items in it.
Okay, and we're gonna do the same thing
for the column tracks in a second,
but first, let me show you how
we can actually use these names.
And, in fact, it's just the same as using the rows, okay?
But instead of using the number here, we just use the names.
And so remember that this one here starts
at this row, which is called boxes-start,
or box-start, actually, and it goes all the way
until content, or main, I think, main-end.
So let's take a look, so yeah, this one is called main-end.
Of course, we could still write span 2,
but just for the fun of it, let's now make it like this.
So main-end, and let's see what happens, and yeah.
So it's working, right?
So it starts here, from this grid line,
which is called box-start, and goes all the way,
just as it did before, until the main-end,
so this row line, right?
And the other ones actually don't really need
the grid-row declaration, so in fact
we wouldn't maybe really have needed all of these names,
okay, but I still wanted to show you how we do it, okay?
Because again, in the future,
and when we start building our real project,
we're gonna do it the same way,
and then you will see that it becomes
really handy doing it like this.
We did it for the row tracks; let's now also
do it for the column tracks.
But in here, we have kind of a different situation, right?
Because we have this repeat function here,
which is gonna create three column tracks here
with this definition here alone, right?
So it wouldn't make much sense
to put the line name here before this one
and then after it, because then only the line
before the 3 and after the 3 would get a name,
but we want all of them to have a name, so what can we do?
Well, we simply put it here, right into the repeat,
and so we do it like this.
And in this case, I'm simply gonna call them col,
which stands for column, and then start, and then col-end.
Okay, and what this will do is that
it will create a so-called named set of grid lines.
So with this, we create three columns,
and each of them starts with a line called col-start
and one with col-end, and that would mean
that we would have conflicting line names, right?
And so what happens is that for the first column,
it's gonna be called col-start 1 and col-end 1,
then for the second column track,
it's gonna be called col-start 2 and col-end 2,
and then, of course, for the third track,
it's gonna be called col-start 3 and col-end 3, all right?
And I'm gonna show that to you in a second.
For now, let's just finish this one here
and call it grid-end.
Okay, and that's actually it.
So again, remember that this is
a named set of grid lines here, okay?
So when we have these names here, these lines names
in the repeat, then it's gonna create
a named set of grid lines.
And to show you how to use this in practice,
let me show it to you.
And so here is the header, and so it goes
all the way from the beginning to the end.
So what's the first column grid line gonna be called?
It's col-start, and then remember that
the first one has the 1, okay?
Remember that I just explained that?
So this line here is called col-start 1,
then this one here is called col-end 1, right,
and at the same time it's also called col-start 2,
and this one here, col-end 2, and so on and so forth,
all the way here until the end, okay?
So this one is col-start 1, here at the beginning,
then we want all the way until the one
which is called grid-end, I think.
Yeah, so grid-end.
And let's see if that works.
And yeah, here we go, so it works just as before.
Now we could still use the -1 trick here
like we had before, but of course,
I wanted to show you how to use
these column line names, right?
Then here, with the sidebar, let's do the same.
So remember the named set of grid lines works like this.
So this is the col-end number 3, right,
so this line here, okay?
So col-end 3, and then once more, it goes to grid-end.
And that's it, and now the main content.
So this one here, and this one
shouldn't be all too hard as well,
so col-start 1, to col-end 3.
And let's check that one out,
and here you see that it still works the same,
so everything is correct.
And here, again, we wanna go from col-start 1 to end,
or actually, grid-end, okay,
and yeah, so that works as well.
All right, and that's actually it.
So this is how naming the grid lines works.
And again, in more professional layouts,
you will usually see it working like this.
So we just name all our tracks,
both the row tracks and the column tracks,
and then use these names to position
our grid items to build our designs, our layouts.
All right, so I hope this made a lot of sense to you,
and in the next video, we're going to see the third method
of how to position these grid items.