[Narrator} Now it's time to style the navigation itself,
and to build that cool hover effect
that I showed you before.
Now first of all, let's actually style the text here
and the icon, so we can then apply this hover effect, okay?
So, starting with that, coming over to our components here.
The first thing that I actually want to do
is to set the font size here on the side navigation.
So, font size one point four rem.
Then I want to get rid of the list style, of course,
such as always, and then also give it
a nice margin to the top, of three point five rem.
All right, and now the link,
we, of course, need to apply the link pseudo class here.
So link, and then of course, also, the visited.
So, first of all, the color,
and this one shouldn't really be white,
so I want it to be this really light gray.
Okay, that looks better than pure white,
on such a dark background.
Next, let's get rid of the underline,
so text decoration none.
Then a text transform to uppercase,
and we should also display them as block or an inline block.
It doesn't really matter, it's really the same.
So let's just say a block.
Okay, then we want some padding on them.
So one point five rem at the top, and three left and right.
Okay, so let's take a look at that.
And that is already much better.
So now all have to do is to style these icons here
and give them the same white color
and some margin here on the right side.
So margin right, two rem and then the fill, okay?
Now we want them to be the same color as the link,
and so I can now go ahead and
just copy this color variable and paste it here.
But we actually can do better
by using something called current color.
Okay, and current color basically is just the color
of the current element or the parent element.
Okay, and so that is really useful.
Current color is really awesome, and I will actually
show you another example of that a bit later.
And also it's really well supported by many browsers.
So I don't know why more people doesn't use it,
because it really can be used all over the place,
not just with fill here, but again I'm gonna
show you another example a bit later.
Okay, so this current color simply means
the color of this element here, or the parent.
So let me show that to you, and yeah,
so now it's white actually.
Okay, and if I were to change now the color on this one here
like to blue, then it will become blue because
that's not the current color of this element.
So, you see that, now it's blue.
Okay, and another awesome application is, for example,
imagine that we had a hover effect on this link here, okay.
Just to show it to you very quickly, so hover.
And on this hover we wanted to change the color
of the link to orange red, of course.
So what would happen then with the icon?
Well, it will become orange as well.
So that is really, really useful, okay.
So, without current color, we then would have
to write some code to make the icon here orange as well,
and that would be a lot of work.
So with current color we can avoid all of that
because it will simply like inherit the color.
So a really useful feature, I just wanted
to show it to you here.
Now if you watch closely here, you see that
these are actually not well aligned.
So this one here, starts a little bit before the tours,
so it's not well aligned, it's not vertically centered.
So, of course, we can use flex box for that.
And what is the flex box container here?
Well, let's just take a look at our markup,
and so here is the icon.
So this svg and here is the text.
So these two elements should be vertically aligned
and therefore our flex container is side nav link.
Okay, so this one here.
So, this is very easy, display flex,
and then align items, right, and set it to center.
And that's it, with just two lines of code,
you can automatically center these elements vertically.
And yep, so, here we go.
So this already looks pretty similar
to this version here, right?
All we have to do now is this effect.
And how do we do that?
Well, we're going to use a before pseudo element,
which we basically place before this list item here
and that is the one that will show
as soon as we hover this item.
Okay, so it will show and then grow to the right side.
So, let's implement that.
So, before the side nav item, we want
to add a pseudo element.
So, item, before.
Okay, and that will be that small line
that becomes visible and then expands to the right side.
So, first off, as always, we have to specify the content,
otherwise it's not even going to show in a browser, okay?
So, the content is that too is set to nothing.
Now in order to position this, let's use absolute position,
and set it right to the top, zero and left, zero.
Okay, and also give it a height of 100%, so that
it has exactly the same height as the list item, okay?
Then we want to give it a whiff of just three pixels,
and of course, a background color.
Which is our primary color, so our primary pink.
All right, now before we can check this out,
we actually have to set the parent element,
which is the item here to position to position relative.
Okay, so that the before pseudo element
is then positioned in relation to that one.
All right, so let's just check that out.
And actually, it's not here, why is that?
Let me see, here in the inspector.
So, the before, ah, what did I do here, position zero?
What's that?
Of course it's positioned absolute
and you probably saw this one coming, okay?
And okay, so now, here it is.
Now what we need here before can continue
is some space between all of these items, right?
So item, and we're gonna use, again, or not pseudo class.
Okay, so, just like this, not last child.
Okay, so then we can add the margin bottom
on all the items except the last one.
So that's pretty standard by now,
we've been using it all the time.
So, take a look again, and yeah here we go.
Now this will, of course, not be visible all the time
but only when we hover the item, right?
And so, let's do that.
So, down here.
Item hover and then before.
Okay, and so what we're gonna do here is
to say transform, scale Y, to one.
Now I'm gonna explain you how this works in a second,
but before that, we have to actually change it to zero,
here and the normal state, right?
So this is the normal state without any hover,
and so we say scale Y, zero.
And when we then hover the item, the before pseudo element
will get to transform Y back to one, so, 100%.
So what is scale Y?
So usually when we use scale, the element scales
in all of the directions so X and Y,
but if we do scale Y, well, then the scale
only occurs in the Y direction, so, from top to bottom.
So let me show you how that looks like.
And actually for you to see it, I need
to specify the transition as well.
So, transition, transform, and this time I'm not going
to put all here because later I want
to add some stuff here, okay?
And just so that you can see it, I'm gonna
make it like really slow, so one second.
So that you can see what happens here.
So you saw that, let me show it to you again.
So basically it starts in the middle and then it grows
to the sides, and so it grows in the Y direction
because we're using scale Y, okay?
And it starts in the center because
that's where he transform origin is set, okay.
Remember, I showed you the transform origin property before,
well let me show it to you again, actually.
So remember the transform origin, we used it,
I think, on the navigation in the natures project.
And I told you that it's usually set to center,
but if we set it, for example, to bottom,
then this is what's going to happen.
It will start scaling at the bottom.
And the same thing here, and the same thing here,
and the same thing here.
And if I set it to top, then, of course,
it will start at the top.
But the default is center, and that's why
it starts scaling at the center.
Alright, and so that's allows for that cool affect,
where it basically starts growing
in the middle to both the sides.
Okay, so that part of the animation is already working now,
so this part here.
Now what we also want is that,
after that, it expands the width, all right?
And so that's not hard to do as well.
So, in here, we need to say that we want
the width of this to be 100%, and that's it.
So, initially it's three pixels,
and then it expands to 100%.
Now in order to actually see this, we need
to add a delay to that width, right?
'Cause if we don't, it will simply look like this.
So it will expand immediately and then
you'll see it's scaling, but that's not what we want.
And so, there's an ability in the transition property
to add different settings for different properties.
So, for transform, let's put point two seconds.
And then, for the width, we can say we want it to happen
in point four seconds, for example, and with a delay.
Remember that one?
So we can set delays in transitions
and in animations in general.
And so we want a delay of point two seconds,
which is exactly the time it takes
for this first transform here to happen.
So, first the transform happens during these
two point seconds, and we wait this time
until we start transitioning the width.
And that's then going to take point four seconds,
so let me show that to you.
And, here we go.
So that's already pretty similar to what
we have in the original demo, right?
But the original demo looks a bit better
because it has different timing functions.
You see, let's take a look.
So it starts like really slow and accelerates,
and that looks like really cool, okay.
So let me show you that, and so I need to show you
that site that I showed you before,
which I don't remember right now.
And the one that I want to show you is this one.
So, where we accelerate real fast in the beginning,
like this, and then at the end it slows down.
So let's take a look at that example,
so this one here, this pink one.
So that's pretty similar to the one
that I showed you in the demo, right?
So, what we want is cubic bezier, let's copy that, okay.
So, what we want here is the cubic bezier.
And well what happened here?
Anyway, I can just type it out.
So one, zero, zero, one, all right?
So that's the way we want it to happen.
So, let's take a look at that, and yep.
So now it's like the example
in the website that I showed you.
So basically it starts really slow, then it accelerates
real fast, and then it slows down again.
And so it looks like really snappy
and really modern, I really this look, okay.
Now one thing, of course, that we have to fix is that
this item here should be on top of this
before a pseudo element, right?
So let's give it some Z and X,
and actually where we want that Z and X
should be here on the link, right?
'Cause what we want is the link to be on top
of the before pseudo element, right?
So, Z and X like ten, just a number that's higher,
and that's not really working.
And that is probably because we don't have
the position here specified, okay.
So, position relative,
because the Z and X only works
if we have specified position, okay?
And so here we go, so now it works perfectly.
And we're actually almost done here, all we need to do now
is to add one item that is already like selected.
So, this one here, right?
And that's, of course, very, very easy,
so all we have to do is to come to our html
and, where is it, oh, here it is.
So all we have to say is that this one should be active.
So we add a modifier here, and say active.
Now we come here and edit here, right.
So the active state should be exactly
the same as the hover state, right?
So, item with the modifier active.
And then, of course, before, so that should work now.
And, in fact, here we go, okay?
Now we just need like an active state,
and what we do is simply like this.
So when we click it, the color gets a little bit brighter.
So it's not a huge difference, but at least
we have some small active state to show the user
that he clicked on the item, okay?
And so that one is really easy as well,
Item.
Of course here it's underscore and now the active state
and then the before pseudo element.
And we simply say that the background color
should be our light primary color.
So color,
primary, light.
And this should also be animated,
and so we can add another line to this one here,
saying that the background color
should be animated in like one point second.
So really fast, just so there is any animation, okay?
And remember this part here, okay.
So we can set different settings for different properties,
and that's really cool because this way we can have like
the staged animations, where first the transform happens
and then the width.
Okay, so, with this delay that we have here.
And, of course, we also have different durations
for different properties, so the background color
in point one then this one in point four and this one
in point two seconds, and also
different animation timing functions.
Where this one is different than the default,
which is happening on a transform and background color.
So we didn't use this one before,
but it's just another thing I wanted to show you here.
All right, and with this, we are really
done with this part here.
So you see, we click and the color turns a bit brighter
with this really fast animation in point one second,
and yeah, that's actually it.
So we have the sidebar now complete, and the header as well.
So all there's left to do now is to actually fill
this entire hotel view, all right?
But for now, let's take a break
and come back to this after that.
So, once you're ready, let's move on.