Hello, great to have you back in the course.
Let's start working on our next section now
where basically customers can tell about
their experience with Natours.
You're gonna learn here how to make text flow
around shapes using the shape outside and float properties
together, and how to apply a filter to images.
Then, you're gonna create a background video
filling the entire section, and for that
you're gonna learn how to use the HTML video element
and how and when to use the object fit property.
So you see that once more, this section is full-packed
with new stuff for you to learn.
This is what the section looks like.
Here we have a testimonial of this person
of Mary Smith, then down here, another one.
Now, what's special about this is that we have
this round image here, so this shape
and then this text flows around that shape.
That's what we're gonna do in this lecture.
You also see that we have this style here
with this non-rectangular design again, so this line
that you see here, and on this side as well
that's a design pattern that's repeating
across this webpage.
And then of course you also see that we have
this background video here going on
you're also gonna learn how to do that.
Then in the end, there's just a small button here
which could then lead to another page
where the user could read more stories, okay?
So let's start once again with the title
so with the H-one element here
then we style this entire section
but not the background video, okay?
We're gonna leave that one to the very end.
Then we can also start styling this component here.
This is gonna be a story component.
So let's do that.
Closing the card here.
Let's create a new section.
Section
Section stories
Then again, we will get our H-two element here
so our secondary heading
let's grab that from here.
This time it says
"we make people genuinely
happy."
All right, and now down here, let's start a new row.
Actually this is all not well formatted.
Okay, let's start a new row now.
Now this time, we're not going to put any columns in the row
We're just using this nicely centered container
that the row gives us, so that we can put
our story component in there, okay?
And we also make use of the margin bottom
that this row here already has.
So we cannot just put columns here in the row
we can also use it for other stuff.
So let's put a story component here
story element
and for now there's nothing really in there
let's just leave it like this, okay?
So once again, let's start by formatting
the section stories here in the home file
give it some padding first
of 15 rem top and bottom, let's say
and zero left and right, of course.
Then, for now, we'll also give it a background color
and why not the same grey as before.
So this is only temporary, because then later on
we're gonna put that background video, okay?
But for now, let's put this color there.
Right, and so now we can add our new component in here
so it's a story in CSS.
And that's not what I wanted, I wanted main, okay
and this one is "story."
And close it, so what do we have in our story?
First, the width is not 100%
because that would be way too wide
so let's put it to 75% then we want to nicely center it
and again it's a block element inside a block element
and so we can use margin zero and auto, right?
Then let's also give it a box shadow
zero
then three in the Y direction, and a nice blur
okay, then RGBA for the color, it's always
and just point one should be enough.
Also background color so that's visible
against our background
so color white.
And now finally, a nice border radius.
We've been using three pixels
so let's do that here again to give it a consistent look.
All right, and so here it is.
Now we just need to fill it up with something, okay?
You can also first give it some padding
six rem let's say
and all right, that should be enough for now.
Let's take a look at what we have here.
This is once again an H-three element
and this is just a simple paragraph.
Then here we have of course this image.
But in order to create this effect where the text flows
around the shape here, let's actually first start with
just a round shape, and then take care of the image later.
So, let's put a shape here in this side
and then, on this side here a box
where we can input the H-three
and the paragraph, so then these two things side-by-side.
All right?
We start with the shape, that will make this one a figure
called story shape
and I'm making this a figure because
it's semantically the best thing to do
because we will have an image together with a caption
and so we have the image and then a caption this Mary Smith
name here is the caption, and so in HTML five we have
this figure element where we can put an image and then
some caption, with a figcaption element.
But again, let's do that later.
For now, let's leave it empty and continue
with the part which contains the text.
So just a div
story
text, and then in here
as I was saying, we have the heading tertiary again
so H-three
heading
tertiary.
"I had the best week ever with my family"
is what it says here.
All right, and then down there just some paragraph.
So let me just copy the ...
random text that we have here.
Well actually ...
no let's get the text, it's better.
I think it's this one here.
And paste it here, okay.
In here, in the heading, in the H-three element
we also have to add that margin to the bottom, right?
Remember that?
And I don't remember quite which class it was.
Let me take a look here at the utilities.
I think we used to use this one here
so margin bottom small.
Give it a save
and take a look.
All right, let's actually now set the font size
here for this entire thing to ...
Here we have this, push this one here to the side
so we can do font size
and then there's a variable for that
let me check out the name ... it's default font size
and so the paragraph will then inherit that.
Okay, so let's now take care of the shape.
This is just a div element for now.
Let's give it some height and some width
so 15 rem and height as well
so it's basically a square for now
and then we want this element sitting on the left side.
So float, left, in order to make
the rest of the content float around it.
That's how it works, right?
And now just so that we can see it
let's give it a background color as well
and orange-red again here my favorite
and let's take a look at that.
Okay, and with that in place, let's actually add a bit
more text here, and then make this content float around
as if it was floating around a circle
so a shape like a circle.
Okay we can do that, this doesn't even have to look
like a circle in order to do that.
All we have to do is to use the shape outside property
and so let me show you how we can do that.
In here, we can use the shape outside property
just like this.
So we have to define a vectorized shape here once more.
We did that already when we used the clip-path property.
We defined a polygon back then, remember?
Well, when we did that back then, I told you that we could
use other things here, like circles or ellipses
and so now this time let's use a circle.
So, a circle, and in here we can define the size
of the circle and the position of the center of the circle.
How does that work?
Well the first number we put here is actually the radius
of the circle, and so if we say 50%, then the radius
will be half the height and the width of the element
and so in this case that will be seven point five rem
and so if the radius is seven point five rem
then the diameter of the circle will, of course, be 15
and that's exactly the size of the shape here, right?
And then we say
50%
because that means that is the center of the circle
so exactly the center horizontally and vertically
all right?
Now I can change this later here in this vector
to show you the difference, but that is what we want here
and in order for this to work, the element must actually
be floated, and that's the case here, right?
And so we have already done that, and another thing
that I should tell you about this is that in Safari
it currently only works with the webkit prefix
so let's do that
okay?
Like this, it works in Chrome and Safari currently
so it doesn't even work in Firefox
neither in Internet Explorer and Microsoft Edge
but of course that's for now as of recording
of this course by the end of 2017
so if you're watching this in the future
this might have changed, okay?
So that is that, the browser support ...
And another thing that I have to tell you is that beside
having to be floated here, this also only works
if the element has defined dimensions, so width and height.
So this is quite a demanding property.
It has to be floated it has to has a height
and a width, only then it works.
Okay, as I was saying let's just add some more text here
like repeating that part.
Okay, let's take a look.
And so you see, it's different already here, right?
So you see, it's like wrapping around a circle.
And instead of just imagining a circle
let's actually put one there, okay?
We can do that by using the clip-path property.
So clip-path, and then we just use the exact same circle.
All right?
Okay, and actually the same thing
also with the webkit prefix.
Okay.
Again, this shape outside, all it does is to define
where the content floats around the element
in this case, a circle, and if we actually want the element
to look like that circle, we can then use
the clip-path property, okay?
And so that should be better now, should look more logical.
And so yeah, actually it's really
flowing around that element, right?
Let's just take a look here, and as I was telling you
let me actually change these values here a bit
so you see if the circle would be bigger than this
but already start stop working.
So 50% is really the best that we can do.
The same thing of course works here.
But here, we can just decrease the radius
then of course the shape decreases.
All right, let's now add some space here between this
and the best way to move around an element that is floated
is to actually not mess with margins or anything like that
we should just use a transform, okay?
So let's do that, transform, and then translate it.
And of course in this case, in the X direction
and let's do it minus three rem
and let's take a look at that.
That didn't do the trick, actually.
Probably because it should be like this.
All right, here we go, that looks much better.
Now the thing is that we had this padding here going on
so these 6 rem, which is the blue color here
in this diagram, but with this transform now, we occupy
the half of the padding there on the left side
so let's add some more padding there
so these three rem that we had here
let's add that padding here on the left side.
After that, we say padding, left
nine rem
so six plus the three.
Okay, and with that taken care of
let's actually now include that image.
In here, inside the figure element
let's put the image.
So the image now will be going into the img folder
and then nat eight, so this is what we want.
And here, let's just say, "person on a tour."
'cause that's what this image will look like.
Now we can get rid of that background color
and take a look at what we see here.
Well, that looks rather strange, doesn't it?
So let's see where that image actually is.
This image is taking all of this entire space.
It's 2000 times 1333 pixels
and that's because we didn't give it a width.
So remember once again, flexible images
for responsive web design, they always need a width.
Always, without exception, okay?
I think we actually didn't give it a class name, did we?
Figure ... No we did not.
It's a story image
just like this
so
the story image.
Let's just give it a width of 100%.
And why is that?
Well, it's because this image is inside of a shape
which has this width here well defined
and so if we say width 100%, that will be
the hundred percent of the parent, so 15 rem.
So now it should look good, but actually it does not
and that's of course, it's obvious, because the image
is wider than it's high, so if we gave it a 100% width
then, of course, it cannot fill this entire circle
that we we put here, so it shouldn't
be width 100%, but height
and now then it should look okay.
That looks much better now.
Now one last thing that we didn't do yet
is this non-rectangular design that I have here, okay?
So let's take care of that, and we actually do it the exact
same way as we did before with the feature section.
So let's do that.
What we're gonna do is to skew this entire story
so transform, and then skew.
Now the difference is that this time we're gonna do it
in the X direction
and 12 degrees.
Let's take a look at that, and here we go.
Actually it should be minus 12 because we want it
in the other direction, so that's what it looks like.
Now we have the same problem that we had before
which is that now, we basically have to skew
this one and this one in the opposite direction.
So how did we do it last time?
Well, we did it like this
we used the direct child selector
and then selected everything.
In this case, that would just be the shape element
as well as the ... well, where is it actually?
Yeah, so here it is, the story text element.
Let me actually define it here, I didn't do it yet.
Okay, and so that would select the shape, and the text.
However, this is not going to work
and I'm gonna show you why.
Let me first put it here, and then show you
why it doesn't work.
Okay, so it does actually work with the text
but not with the story, and that's because
we already have one transform here going on
this translate here is already a transform
and it actually takes precedence over this one
so therefore only the translation applies
and not the skew.
Now in CSS, there's currently no way of having two
transform properties applying at the same time
and that's a shame, but I read that they are working on this
so I think that basically in the future these functions
that we use here, they will be transformed
to real properties, so maybe someday we will have skew X
as a property, and then we can specify 12 degrees
or we can have translate X as a property, and then
specify minus three as a declared value.
But for now, this is what we have, so what I'm gonna do
is to simply add this one here to the text
and then just the skew part
here to this transform
and then it's going to work and so we have to
make it separately so adding the skew now
on both here manually.
And so like this, it is going to work.
All right, so let's take a look at the original
and what is missing here, of course
is this effect that's going on, okay?
But I'm leaving that to the next lecture
so that we can take a break now, okay?
So, see you, bye then.