Welcome to the next part of the project,
which is to finally build the header.
And so in this lecture, you will learn
how to manage vertical spacing
in a completely responsive layout using
some more advanced CSS Grid techniques.
And also, you will use the before and after
pseudo elements as grid items.
So in this header, we have the logo of the company.
Then we have this H3 element here,
which we already styled before.
Then this main text here, which is the H1 element,
so the main heading of this entire page.
And then just this button that we also
already styled before.
And then down here we have this thing
which gives the page some social proof.
So basically these four companies here,
they talked about this website and this company.
And so we're including that on our page here.
And that's how many startups actually do it these days.
So when you see a modern page of startup,
you usually have these icons of some websites
that wrote an article about them.
So let's put all of that in our markup now
so that we can then, after that, style it.
So here in our header, the first thing is the image.
And it's called header logo.
And the source is also simply called logo.
Okay, then next up we have this H3
with the heading three class, right?
And so this one here says
your own home.
And then we have the H1, with the heading one class.
We didn't style this one yet, so we're gonna do that next.
So it says the ultimate personal freedom.
Okay, then the button, view our properties.
Next up we have the text, which says as seen on, right?
So basically we have an element just for this
and then an element which is going to contain
these four logos.
So header, seen on, and I'm gonna call this one here text,
and this one here is just seen on logos.
So image, and right now I'm going to give these
here a class because I think that having
this more complex class here is already more than enough.
And we can then simply select the img in there.
And actually here we're missing the header.
And so yeah, that's correct.
So img and logo BBC.
Okay.
Then we have Forbes, TechCrunch,
and Business Insider, two, three, and four.
All right, let's take a look at that.
And here we go.
Now of course all of this is huge.
But we're gonna take care of that in a second.
Let's start with our H1 element here.
And so let's close the footer and the sidebar
and open our typography file here,
because that's where the heading are.
So the heading number one, we want a font size of 4.5 rem.
We want the color to be the color gray light,
okay, so basically almost white.
And then also, just as we have here in the H2,
we want the line height of one, okay?
So for a situation when we have two lines
here in this text, then we don't want
all the spacing between these two lines.
Okay, and that looks much better.
And now let's take care of these images here
so that we can then lay out this here
using a CSS Grid.
Okay, so it is our header file.
And so let's add our selectors here.
So logo,
the seen on text,
the seen on logos, and then, remember,
in there, we are going to select the image text directly
so we don't have a separate class for them here this time.
Okay, so these images, they should all have the same height.
So let's say 25 pixels.
Okay, and we want them to have the same height
because that's the way it looks better.
So just like this.
Imagine if we were to have them having the same width.
Then it would have different heights,
and that would look weird when they are
side by side like this, okay?
Now, as for the logo, let's give it a height
of let's say three rem, okay?
And so yeah, that looks much better as well.
Also before we move on with the layout part,
let's give this here its background image
so that it looks just like this here,
with this house as the background image.
And so that's directly on the header element.
And so background image.
And again, we're going to use this trick
where we have multiple backgrounds,
where the first one is a linear gradient
in order to make the image darker.
So I'm gonna use RGBA and use the secondary color,
so the blue one, and then give it a 93% alpha value.
So going from this color basically to the same color.
And so that's the best way, again,
of creating an overlay for an image.
And then after that, of course, img,
and this one is called hero.jpeg.
And this is actually not correct
because we need to move out of the CSS folder first
before we can go into the img folder.
Now just set it to cover here, with the background size,
and then we should be good to go.
Okay, maybe just set it to centered, so the background
position to center.
And yeah, that looks a lot better.
Okay, so now comes the time to create
some spacing here between all of these elements
and then also center them both vertically
and horizontally here in this header element.
So how would we have done that in the old days?
So probably we would have just created a container
for all of these elements.
We would then have centered that container
inside of the header.
Then we would have just created some margins here,
like margin bottoms, on these different elements
to create some spacing.
But with CSS Grid, we can do better than that.
And that's because with a grid,
we can define the line heights
instead of having to define some margins.
And so that's a lot easier, and it makes
a lot more sense, I think.
And so let's now go through that
here for this header element.
So this is my grid.
And so we're gonna turn this entire header element
into a grid container.
And then we can define its rows.
So template rows.
Now, how are we going to do this?
Let's take a look again at our final result here.
And so we see that there's a lot of space here
after this logo here and also a lot of space
between this button and between this element here,
which has as seen on, okay?
But let's start here with this space after the logo.
So imagine that we wanted to have the logo
here on the top and then push all of these other
elements here to the bottom.
So how could we do that?
Well, we could use the fractional unit.
So one fr, and then simply allow all the other rows
to be sized automatically.
Okay, so let's take a quick look
at how our grid looks like like this.
Okay, and that's as expected, right?
And let's reload this, because something here
went wrong with the text.
But anyway, this looks exactly as expected.
So let's actually inspect this new grid
that we have here.
So this header, okay.
And so this is how our grid looks like.
So this here.
So all this time, we've been using the fractional unit
for the columns in order to fill up
all the available space that is available, right?
But of course we can do the same with the rows.
And it works, in this case, because the grid container
actually has a very well-defined height.
And that height is this 80% of the view port height, right?
So this entire row that we have here,
this first row, which contains all of this,
remember we defined that as being 80%
of the view port height.
So we have a container.
So let me show that to you, just to remember.
And so here we see.
So the first row has 80% of view port height, okay?
And so this entire row here is what that means.
And therefore this header element here
also has this 80% view port height.
And so, again, this grid container here
has a very well-defined height,
which is 80% of the view port height.
Okay, so if we now come into the header,
and if we hadn't this definition here,
then basically all of that space
would be divided up equally.
But that's not really what we want.
Instead, in this very first example,
we want this first row to occupy all
of the empty space.
And so we give it one fractional unit
and then allow all the other rows
to be sized automatically, okay?
Does that make sense?
Now, in order to add some space in here between them,
we can of course use the grid gap property.
And so that is the big advantage.
Instead of having to add some margins
to all of these child elements,
we can simply do it right on the container,
so right on the grid definition.
And that's a lot easier than using,
for example, something like Flexbox,
or even the even older way
that I described in the beginning.
So grid row gap, and let's set it to 1.5 rem.
Okay, and so that's even better than before.
But we can do better than that.
So let's add some space here after this row here.
And so basically what we want here
is to increase the row size, right?
Because remember, we cannot really style
these gaps here individually.
And instead we can increase the row size.
So let's set this here like to six rem, for example.
And so the first row has this fractional unit.
Then the second one we want to be sized
according to the content.
So let's use min content.
And then the next one is six rem, okay?
So let's check that out now.
And yeah, so you see that now we have this more space
here between these two.
So that's starting to look more like our original.
Now, next up we also want a lot of space here
after this button, right?
So just like this.
And so let's say that we want this row here
to be one fr, such as the row with the logo, okay?
So six rem is this one with the text,
and then the next one should be one fractional unit.
And so that's what this is going to look like.
Now this is, of course, not ideal.
And it happens because this element
always tries to span its entire grid cell, right?
So we've been seeing this behavior here a lot of times.
And so let's fix that.
And we can do that using the align self
and justify self properties here on this button.
So how are we going to do that?
Well, here in our index file,
the button is of course this reusable button.
And so it doesn't have any class.
But right now I think I should give it one
so that i can then apply these two properties
that I just mentioned, so justify self and align self.
So button and header button as well.
So now let's put it here, right after the logo.
And so what do we want here?
We want align self to be start,
and so we want it vertically at the top
of the grid cell, and also horizontally,
so justify self, and also at the start,
so all the way to the left side.
And that should fix it.
And indeed it does.
So this is our grid cell, and this is our grid item.
Now actually let's give all of these here some padding.
Okay, so to move it away here from the sides
of the header.
And so that's up here.
So padding of eight rem, let's say.
And so that's going to look much nicer.
What I just want to change, though,
is that I want to have some last padding here at the top,
okay, so that the logo can be closer to the start
of the page.
And also I want to center this item here
right into its grid cell.
And so of course that should be pretty easy as well.
So first let's say that we want padding at the top
to be just four rem, and then the logo,
let's justify self it to center, okay?
And that makes total sense, right?
All right, now if we remove this
grid, this overlay grid here,
then you will see that it doesn't really
look so centered, right?
So there's a lot of space going on here on this side.
And that is happening because this column here
is occupying all the available space.
And so let's actually change that.
And we're going to do that by saying
that we want the column to only have the width
of the min content.
So template columns, and min content, okay,
so we only have one column, of course,
and we want it to be just the size
that it has to have in order to fit the content.
And well, that's not really right.
But actually it makes total sense, okay?
So remember that min content means
that it's the smallest width possible, okay?
But actually we don't want min content.
We want max content.
And so that is the one we're looking for.
And yeah, that's much better.
And so now it has the size in order to fit the content,
and the largest piece of content is this here,
without having to do any line breaks.
So now, last thing to do is to then
also center this entire grid track
inside of the grid container, right?
And so we do that by using justify content.
Center, of course, and all right.
So here we go.
That's it.
And if we remove, now, this overlay,
then it looks a lot better.
So it actually looks quite a lot like this already,
just of course some more things
that we have to do and to change,
like for example doing this part here at the bottom.
But I'm going to do that in the next video
so that you can take a break if you want to.