Welcome to the last small demo project
in this first intro section of CSS Grids.
So in this lecture, we're gonna learn
some more advanced topics, including min-content,
max-content, and also the minmax() function.
So let's go straight to it.
So once again, we start here from an empty CodePen,
but actually let me go back to the one that we created
in the last couple of lectures
and actually copy all of our markup here.
Okay, so I want the exact same HTML, and also,
I am going to take all of the CSS here
and then remove what I don't want.
Okay, just so we can save some time,
instead of having to write out the same stuff
over and over again, okay?
So I'm gonna remove all of this and okay.
So now we're ready to start from a clean state.
Actually, one that I want to do
is to give each of these items a different background color
so that we can better distinguish what we're gonna do
in this lecture, okay?
So number one, and let me just copy this part in here
and then I'm gonna create eight of these.
So two, three, four, five, six, seven, and eight,
and this one we don't need.
And the colors that I selected for them
are called yellowgreen, this one is called blueviolet,
then this is palevioletred, yeah exactly, then royalblue,
goldenrod,
crimson, and finally darkslategray or something like that,
darkslategray.
All right.
So let's now define our explicit grid, okay,
and I hope you remember from the last couple of lectures
what an explicit grid is.
So it's just the one that we defined
with the template rows and template columns, okay?
So the first thing, display: grid,
and then let's give this just two rows.
So grid-template-rows
and I want them both to be 250 or 150 pixels high, okay?
So that's what we see down here,
and there you see that then
the other six items here of course,
they're added into the implicit grid, okay,
so because right now we only defined two cells
and so the remaining ones are then added
to the implicit grid that we didn't define, all right?
So let's now define the columns,
and here is the new thing.
So, so far we have only used like real units here
in these columns definitions or the row definitions,
so like pixels, percentages, or the fractional unit,
so something like this.
So we could do 1fr, 1fr, and 1fr,
or of course a repeat, so repeat four, and then 1fr.
That would be the same, but I want to show you something now
and so I did it like this.
So up until this point,
we always used these normal units here
but there are some new keywords that are associated
with CSS Grids that we can use here instead
and the first one that I want to show you
is called max-content.
So instead of having here a real unit,
let's just add max-content, and see what happens.
Okay, and so you see that the first track,
so the first column track here which is this one of course
has the exact width so that it can accommodate
here this content, okay?
So this is the largest content that we have in this column
and so therefore that becomes the width
of this entire column, okay,
and so that's what the max keyword does here
with the columns.
It makes this column as wide as it has to be
to fit this content, and in fact, max-content also tries
not to make any line breaks.
So let's also add max-content here to the last one
and so now it has the width of this word Flexbox,
but now, let's see what happens
if we add a bunch of text here to this last field here,
this last cell.
So let's see.
Modern CSS with Flexbox and Grid is great
and amazing
and just awesome to work with.
Okay, so a bunch of text.
And you see what happened now.
It expanded this column and it became really wide
because as I mentioned, it tries to make the column
as wide as possible without having to cause any line break
in the content, and so that's exactly what happened here.
And then of course, the remaining space.
So this one here in the middle is then divided in
for these two columns, so the 1fr and 1fr
are these two columns here.
So that's the remaining space.
Now in this case, it doesn't make much sense here for us
right?
So let's actually change this.
And what we can do is to instead of writing max-content
to just put min-content, so that's another keyword
that was introduced with CSS Grid and that we can use here.
And so what happens now is that the column track
takes the largest width that is needed to fit this content
without overflowing, but actually it does overflow
a bit down here, right?
So the column is just the width of this awesome word here,
right, so that's the minimum width that this column
has to have in order to fit the content,
so without overflowing here on the sides,
but now as we define the rows with a height of 150 pixels,
this content doesn't really fit anymore into the height,
right?
And so what we can do is to use min-content or max-content
also on the rows, okay?
So let me show that to you.
So let's just get rid of that one
and put a new one down here and then instead of saying
that the height should be fixed 150 pixels,
let's put min-content here as well.
And let's see how that works out, and all right.
Now then all of this text fits in the height
and also the width of this grid cell here, right?
Now what also happened is of course
that this first row now also has just a min width
to accommodate, to fit the text here.
So in this case, this is just one line.
Let's just increase this a little bit
like Modern modern modern, I don't know,
something like this.
So actually this column just got wider
because we have max-content here,
but if you put this to min-content, then you would see
that this happens, all right?
So now the column is just as wide as necessary
to fit one of these words and then the row track
also expands in order to fit all of this content in there,
okay?
Now let's get rid of that.
This was just to show you even further how this works.
And on this case, it's really not so different
to having max or min here because it's just one word anyway
and so there's nothing to break, nothing to overflow.
So this is how max-content and min-content work.
Does it make sense to you?
Now suppose that we really wanted this first row track here
to be 150 pixels height, not just the min-content,
so not just to fit these words that we have here.
So we could hard-code it like this.
So grid-template-rows, and we could say 150 pixels here
and then min-content and then this would kind of work
the way we wanted it to be, right?
But now, just suppose that, for some reason,
we add all of this text here to this cell
or actually, not to this one, actually to this one here,
and so now you see that it actually overflows.
So it again no longer fits, right?
So let's go back and let me tell you the solution
to this problem.
And the solution is to use something called
the minmax() function, okay?
So, let's get rid of this one here,
and again add a new one based on the one that we had before.
Okay, so what is the minmax() function?
Well basically the minmax() function is just something
that we pass two values in and then CSS ensures
that the track will always stay between these two values.
So imagine that we pass into the minmax() function
100 pixels and 200 pixels for a column,
and so CSS grid will ensure that no matter what happens,
this grid column will always stay
between 100 and 200 pixels width, okay?
So let me show that to you in practice with this example.
And so we write minmax, and we say that the rows
should be at least 150 pixels and at most min-content.
Okay, and that is exactly what we were talking about before.
So this is what we want.
So again, we want the row to be at least 150 pixels high,
so that's happening here in this first row here, right?
Let's give it some more space here.
So that is happening here.
So this one has now 150 pixels again
but the second one is larger
and that's because we allowed CSS Grid
to size somewhere between 150 pixels and the min-content,
okay, and if we were now to remove this text here,
so I'm gonna cut it and put something else,
like just great, like it was before,
then you see that it is now 150 pixels high, right?
So let's put that back, and you will see
that it now grows again, and the same thing
if I put it here into this pink cell.
So let's see.
And all right.
So now it grew in order to accommodate to fit
all of this content again.
So does that make sense?
Let me actually give you
maybe a more easy-to-understand example
with some columns now, okay?
So let's get rid of all of this huge text that we put here
and so let's get back to the old sentence
that we had before so that I can now show you
some other examples of using the minmax() function
with the columns, okay?
So let me just put a comment here,
Using min-content and max-content,
and now let's do this all again,
and now let's do another part here of the code
where we used the minmax() function.
All right.
So let's say that we want the first column
to always be between 200 and 300 pixels, okay?
So grid-template-columns,
and we can now use the minmax() function
to say exactly that.
So the minimum should be 200 pixels
and the maximum 300 pixels, and then the other ones
should just fill up the remaining space.
So we can use repeat and 3, 1fr.
So nothing new here, right?
So let's check this out now here with the Inspector again
and so yeah, so you see that now this column
has actually 300 pixels of width, right?
Now in order to see this a little bit better,
we should actually give this here, this container,
a relative width so that we can play around
here with the viewport width, okay?
So right now the width is 1,000 pixels
but let me just specify a new one here,
and let's say 90%.
So that's gonna override then the 1,000 pixels, okay?
And so now if we play around here with this viewport width,
we can actually see what will happen.
So let's do that.
And you see that nothing changes this far.
So let's inspect it again.
So this one has still 300 pixels and these other ones
are lot smaller.
So let's decrease this even further and now you see
that it started to change.
You see?
So now it has a width of 200 pixels
and we could put it somewhere in between
and now you see it has 230, okay?
Now it has 271, but it always stays between 300 as it is now
and 200, so even if we make this even, even really small,
so you see that now the grid doesn't even fit anymore,
but the first column, it's never less than 200 pixels.
So you see that?
It is still 200 pixels, and no matter what we do,
this will always be the minimum width of this column, okay?
So this is really powerful here with Grid.
The minmax() function is a great addition
and we're gonna use it all the time actually
and there's some great techniques
that I'm gonna show you also in the next video
where it comes in really handy.
So let's look at another example
because this can be different from pixels of course.
So let me put 50% here, okay, and so yeah.
So now you see that it is 50% here of this entire column.
So let's see the size.
So the container has 1,007 pixels and so this one has 503,
which is half of the entire width.
And so if we now start decreasing this,
then of course the first column track also decreases
it still always has 50%, so you see?
The total is 680 so this one is 340, right?
But at some point, there will come a point
where this is no longer true.
So it's no longer 50%, but it's 200 pixels, right,
because we said that it should never be less
than 200 pixels, right?
So just like before.
And just another example.
We can of course also put a fractional unit here, okay?
And so then, at this state, it is the same width
as all of the other columns, but as we start decreasing it,
at some point, you see that it fixes at this 200 pixels
while all the other ones then divide their remaining space
by these three columns, right?
So this one stays at 200 no matter what happens
and then these take up the remaining space.
Now one interesting thing that we can see here
is that this column here is actually larger than this,
and actually these three have all different width, okay,
even if we set them all to one fractional unit.
So we said that they should be all the same,
that they should be all one fractional unit,
and this behavior actually confused a lot of people
but it really shouldn't because it's really straightforward.
So the CSS Grid specification says that a fractional unit
fills up the entire remaining space but it is never smaller
than the minimum content of a row or a column, okay?
So ideally, these three columns here should be all the same
because they are all 1fr, but at the limit,
when this content here gets too wide,
then this fractional unit simply takes the minimum width
that it needs to fill the column without overflowing, okay?
So that's just an interesting fact
that confused a lot of people,
but now it's not gonna confuse you, okay?
So let's get back to the original size here, and yeah.
So now you know how the minmax() function works,
how min-content and max-content work,
and that's all that I had to show you
in this lecture actually.
Now in the next lecture, we're actually gonna take this
a step further and bring even more stuff
into this grid definition here
so that we can build truly advanced layouts, okay?
But for now, I really hope that you understand
all of this, what we just learned in this lecture
and only if you really did, you should then move on
right on to the next video with me.