Are you excited for the next section
of our app?
I hope so because this is a really cool one.
So, now you're gonna build the hotel description part
of the interface.
And for that, you're gonna continue
using flex-block's properties,
including flex-wrap, to build a multi-column list.
Plus, I will teach you how and why we use CSS masks
with mask-image and mask-size.
So, in this lecture and the next one,
we're gonna take care of this part here of our app.
So this container here, and all the content
that's in here.
But before we can do that,
we have to actually build this layout here.
So, with this column here and this one on the right side,
and format this container element,
which contains these two columns.
Okay.
So that's the first thing that we're gonna do,
and then after that we can take care
of what's here in the hotel description.
Alright, so back to our markup.
Here we are in the hotel view still,
because, remember, that entire part on the right side.
So, all of that here, everything here,
we call the hotel view.
And then in there, we already have the gallery,
the overview, and so now it's time to put
an element called the detail.
So, detail will be this box, which contains
the two columns that I just showed you.
So, detail is all of this part here,
which has the gray background.
Alright, then we have on the left side the description,
and on the right side here, the user reviews.
So, description.
And, user reviews.
Okay, let me just write it here.
So that's now format, these three elements.
And actually, we're gonna do that in the layout file now.
Okay, because this is more concerned about layout.
It's not really about building components.
So we're gonna do the detail,
the description,
as well as the user reviews.
So, we want the description and the user reviews
to be side by side, and so we use flex-blocks
on the container.
So, display flex, and so they will be side by side.
Let me just give them some background colors.
So, orange red for this one.
And, this one I like to put yellow-green.
Okay, so we want this one here
to actually have 60 percent of the available width.
And so, let's do that with our flex property.
And here I'm saying that I don't want it to grow,
so Flex-grow zero.
I also don't want it to shrink, so flex-shrink zero.
And then the 60 percent for the flex basis.
Alright, so usually when I'm using a percentage value here
I set the other two to zero.
Okay?
And in this one, I basically want to occupy
the remaining space by setting flex to one.
And now, also we want some margin between them, of course.
So I can simply say margin right four-point-five rem.
So, let's take a look at that.
And alright, so that's the layout
that we were looking for actually.
Now let's just give this container here a padding.
So padding, and four-point-five rem as well.
So the padding here is the same one
as the right margin on the description.
And that looks like that.
And so, this distance here on this top,
and here on this side, and between the two boxes,
is always the same.
Next up, we want it to have the subtle gray
background color.
So, background color, and let me actually copy
the variable name from here,
and it's this one.
And I also want it to have the border on the bottom.
So, the same one that we've been using all the time.
And actually, since we've been using it all the time,
let's actually create a variable for it.
Okay?
So let me get that.
And so, we can copy all of this here into a new variable.
Then each time we have this border,
no matter if it's on the bottom, or somewhere else,
we can simply then use a variable for that.
Okay, so lets just create a variable here,
and I'm simply gonna call it line.
Alright, now you see that this variable here,
so the line variable, actually contains another variable.
But that's perfectly fine, it's gonna work just fine.
So we can now replace it here with line, alright.
And actually we have this somewhere else, I think.
It's in the...
Right here in the overview, right.
So this here is the exact same thing,
and so we just say line.
And then, of course, we also want it here.
In the detail that we were working on before.
So, lets take a look at that,
and here we go.
So our three lines are still there.
So here, here, and now here as well.
Okay, so we already have the layout
of the detail section here completed.
Now, let's just start to format
this description box here, okay.
So, description, and we want it to have a white background,
and we want it to have a box shadow as well.
And that box shadow is zero, two rem,
then five rem for the blur, RGBA, black,
and then just very subtle here.
So, almost invisible shadow, just like this.
So, let's check that out.
And so, here we go.
So maybe the shadow isn't even visible to you
here in the screen cast.
But I'm sure you're gonna see it on your page
and it will look even better when this element
actually grows a bit bigger.
Let's actually do that already, just by adding some padding.
So, three rem.
And also another thing that I wanna do,
is to create a variable for this.
Because, we're gonna re-use this shadow later
for the review boxes.
Okay, so let me copy that.
Okay, and you see we have already a shadow here.
And so, shadow light.
And it's this one.
So, shadow light.
And alright.
Check that out.
An now you can actually see the shadow here a bit better.
You also see that this one here already grew
to have the same size as the description box.
And that's, once again, because the align items
property is by default set to stretch.
And so, therefore, they're both stretched
to have the same size.
Now, what do we have here in this description box,
Let's take a look.
And what we have is these two paragraphs,
then this list here and then down here,
like this recommend panel, okay.
So there's text in with these pictures here
of the friends who recommend the hotel.
Alright so, let's mark that up here back in the HTML.
So, P, and I'm simply gonna call it paragraph.
And then I actually have a file here called text, TXT,
here in the image folder, where is the text
that I want to put there.
So, for the first paragraph, this is the text that I want.
And so, please go ahead and copy it,
so that it looks exactly the way
that I want it to look, okay.
And then we have another paragraph after that,
with some other text.
Okay.
Next up we have that list, so, an unordered list.
And we're simply gonna call it list.
And so these are basically reusable components,
that could be reusable if our app had another page,
another section.
So for example, on the flight section, or the tours,
or the car rental sections.
So maybe if we had that we could then reuse
these components there.
So, LI...
List item.
So the first one says close to the beach,
and now let me just copy these lines.
Actually, it copied a lot of times.
I think it's eight times, so,
one, two, three, four, eight.
So, breakfast included.
Free airport shuttle.
And then there's actually one thing that I wanna show you.
And I think this is part of embed as well.
But, anyway I have it here in my text editor,
and it is called expand selection.
And what that does, is basically when I'm inside
of this text here, when I hit expand selection like this,
then it will select this entire text, okay.
And now if I hit that again, it will expand the selection
even more, and will select this entire part here.
And if I hit it again, it will expand and select everything.
Okay so, expand selection, maybe you have it in your
text editor as well.
It's a really useful feature.
So I'm jut going to use a shortcut here.
So, that makes it much easier.
So, free Wifi in all rooms.
Next up, air conditioning and heating.
Pets allowed.
And I'm just making this a huge list so that we can use
some flex-blocks on this a bit later.
Until we have to have a couple of list items here,
not just two or three.
We speak all language, and finally, perfect for families.
Okay, so these are just a basic couple of features
of our hotel, basically.
And then, next up finally, we have do you recommend section.
So, just a div code, recommend.
And then we have some text there, so, paragraph,
which is the recommend count.
We're just gonna say, Lucy and three other friends
recommend this hotel.
Well this is not perfect.
So, recommend this hotel, and then we have a div here.
So at container, where we're gonna put the pictures
of these friends.
So an image with the class name,
recommend photo.
With the source, IMG, and user,
I'm going to start here at three.
And we have four pictures, and this one is number four,
five, and six.
Enter here just alternative text.
And that is pretty much it, I believe.
So, let's check that out,
and here we go.
So that's our content.
Let's now just set an overall font size here,
so that we basically format the font
of the entire container at the same time.
So in the description box, font size, 14 pixels, so 1.4 rem.
And so, yeah, I think we're done with this file here.
And so, we can now come to the next one.
Alright, and once again you see that this one here
stretches to fill the entire content.
You know what you also see,
is that the container is now too big.
And that's because we set a fixed height
here on the hotel view container I believe.
So let me check that out and remove it,
because that was just for testing.
Yeah, here you see it?
So the hotel view has this height of 80 rem,
but now we of course don't want that anymore.
We want the content to define the height
of the box as usual.
And so now that should be gone.
And yeah, alright, so now we're ready to format
all of these components that we now have
in our description box.
So let's do that right in the next video.
I hope you'll join me there.