In this lecture and the next one,
we are going to adapt our website to a smaller screens
and so making it truly responsive.
And in order to do that we are going
to write a couple of media queries.
So, I'm now back to Google Chrome as you
can possibly see here because I like the DevTools
for responsive developing much better than the ones
in Firefox and so that's why I'm
using Google Chrome here now.
But before that let's actually take a look
at the web page here in Google Chrome
and we can verify that actually everything works
just the same as in Firefox.
Okay.
So, the grid layout is fully implemented
in the current Chrome and Firefox versions.
So everything works exactly the same.
Okay.
So, that is the mobile view here in the Chrome DevTools.
So, just by clicking this icon here
and that brings us this responsive view here
that we can then play around with.
Now, I have it set here to 50%, we can set it to maybe 75
and so let's take a look what happens
as we decrease the screen and the first thing
that comes into notice immediately
is a problem here on this header, right?
So, you see that these images here
and also the content of the header,
they start overlapping everything
and that is because of these images.
Okay.
So, we set them to a fixed height,
if I remember it correctly,
it was 25 pixels or two point five rem.
Yup, so here you see that
and so therefore they can not really scale.
So, when we reduce this, that images will stay
just the same size and then this entire grid here,
which is defined basically by the size of these images
will also stay the same size.
And the same happens for the entire grid container here
and so therefore all of this content
that overflows and looks crazy like this.
And so the first thing that I'm gonna do is to fix that.
Okay.
And so instead of using height, I'm going to use min-height.
So, let's open the header file here
and come down here to the image.
So, we had to set the max-height to two point five rem.
Now what we also need to specify here
is the actual width of this image
because otherwise this is not going to scale properly.
Okay.
And so we're going to use max-width here as well
and set this one to 100%.
So, what max-height is going to do is
that the height can be two point five rem,
but it can also be less than that
and the same here for the width.
So, usually it should be 100%,
but of course it can be less and that's what
will happen when the height here
gets less than two point five rem.
Okay.
Now, the problem is that this actually not all we have
to do so let's take a look at that now
and so you see that it's still not decreasing.
So, why do you think that happens?
And if you think about it, you will come to the conclusion
that it is because of the definition
that we have here in the header
that the column should be the max-content, right?
So, let me show that to you
here in the header
and down here we say that the column
should be at the max-content.
And so basically it should be as wide as possible
in order to fit all the content,
regardless of the width of the UPort
or the container itself.
And so, what we need to change now is that.
So, what can we do here?
So of course we're going to use a minmax.
So, we have done that a couple of times
and the most wide that this column can be
is of course this max-content.
So, that's the maximum, but the minimum is min-content.
Right?
So, we could have specified like a width here as well,
like saying 10 rem or 20 rem or something like that,
but instead we say here that the column
should never be more narrow than the content.
And that should now fix it and indeed it does fix it.
It creates a couple of other problems, okay,
but at least the main problem here is fixed now.
Now, one thing is that these here
should be vertically aligned.
So, let's add that and that is here in the screen on lowest
of course as well and so here we have to do align-content
or actually align-items because we are talkin'
about individual items inside of each cell
and so that's fixed now as well
and now the only problem that's left is this one here.
So, remember that for the row here we specified
a fixed height, but now this content here
is actually overflowing that height that we defined.
So, let's take a look at that.
And so, here we have the header and the grid-template-rows.
So, this is the first one for the logo
and this is for the heading that we were talkin' about
and so it's this six rem here that is overflowing.
So, let's again add a minmax here
and we say that it should at least be six rem, okay.
And so that's for a situation where the text
doesn't break into a second line,
but it can also be min-content.
Okay.
So, in order to at least fit
the content that we have in the row
and so let's wait and yeah.
That now fixes that issue as well.
So, if we now resize this and it works just very nicely,
at least for the higher view port width.
For these really small screens here,
we will then have to change some more stuff later
with media queries, but for now
it is everything is flexible here in this layout.
And with that done let's now actually start
with the media queries themselves
and the technique I'm going to use
is again the one where we resize the screen
and see where the design breaks
and then that will be where we
will approximately set our break points.
So, if we start doing that here.
Then we see that here at some point probably
we can start to decrease the text size, okay.
So everything starts to look a bit crammed here now.
So like at 1200 pixels here,
so everything starts to look a bit cramped,
there's not much space left here anywhere.
And so let's now decrease our overall font-size
just like we did on our last project
and so that will buy us some more space here.
So, we want to set the first media query at 1200 pixels.
And so what we want to reduce is this font-size here
to let's say 50%, so that instead
of one rem being 10 pixels, it will be eight pixels.
So, how am I going to do that?
Well, just like in the last project again,
I'm going to keep it simple and just create a couple
of variables, each for one break point
and then use these variables to write the media queries.
Okay, so ...
These are our responsive break points.
And we're going to start with the one called largest
and this one is a 1200 pixels,
but remember that we shouldn't really
use the media queries with pixels,
but instead we are going to use em.
And so, we divide 1200
pixels by 16,
which is the default font-size for a browser
and so we end up with 75em.
So, just like we did in the last project, nothing new here.
And so, let's just write down that this one corresponds
to 1200 pixels just to keep it in mind.
Okay.
So, that's done and so let's now
very simply add our media query,
only for the screen
and ...
the max-width
is of course bp-largest.
Okay.
So, again we're going to use max-width media queries here
and so we did once more a desktop first layout
and that's just because I find it a lot easier
to show you all these features that I showed you
with CSS grid on a large screen, okay.
And not on a small screen, like a phone.
It would be very difficult for me to show you this stuff
on a small screen like that and so instead I'm going
with a desktop first layout,
but if you're doing a mobile first layout
then everything really works the same.
So, the styles that you have outside of the media queries
are for the small screen and then you start increasing from
there using min-width media queries.
So, just like we learned in one of the other sections
of the course and if you didn't actually watch that,
so maybe if you jumped right into this part of the course,
then if you are not familiar with that
then please just check out I think it's section six
of the course where you're going to learn all about that.
But anyway, let's now move on here
and what we want to do is to as I said before
reduce the font-size to 50%
and again if you jumped to this part of the course
without taking the other parts of the course
then maybe this doesn't make much sense.
So just to recap, this over font-size here
is just so that one rem is 10 pixels.
So, that we can then use rem throughout all
our designs knowing that one rem is 10 pixels
and the great thing about that is that we can
then automatically reduce our entire layout
simply by changing this font-size.
And that's exactly what we did down here.
So, below a 1200 pixels our font-size changes to 50%
and then all of a sudden one rem becomes eight pixel
and then everything changes,
so everything becomes a bit smaller. Right?
So, let's check that out and already you saw
that it took effect here, I hope.
Okay.
So, that's the initial version and then a 1200, bam.
See everything got a lot smaller.
So, that's the first media query that was a very simple one
just to give us some more space here and some of that we can
then set the next media query a bit more below.
Okay, so let's move on here a bit.
And yeah, so you see that already this here happens
so we change to a two color layout here.
So, let's go up a little bit again.
For example here at a thousand pixels
and everything still looks good at this point, right?
So, no problems anywhere to be found here.
Now if we reduce this even more,
let's say to 900,
just like this.
Well then it's starting to look not so good anymore.
So, I think that, for example here,
there's not enough space at all
and overall I think that this sidebar here
is no longer really at the right place here, okay.
So, for a smaller layout it doesn't really make much sense
to occupy this many space just for this sidebar here,
which doesn't have much function anyway.
And so here at a 1000 pixels
that is when I'm going to change that.
So let's take this sidebar and simply put it up here
and what that means is that we actually
have to change our grid definition
and that's something where CSS grid is really strong.
So, with a simple media query we can completely
change our entire layout simply by
changing our grid definitions, okay.
So, all we have to do is to now add a new row to this grid
and remove this first column, okay.
And so that's what we're going to do now.
But first we need to of course add a new break point
and so,
let's divide a thousand by 16,
which gives us 62.5 rem, okay,
so ...
This one is called bp-large
at 62.5em
just noting down that this is a thousand pixels.
So, let's just copy this one here.
Come down here.
And okay.
So, now let's copy this.
So our entire grid definition.
So, as I was saying we have to just add a new row
and remove the first column.
So, the first column is this one here, this eight rem
and also this line name here and so now our layout is going
to start here at the full-start grid line
and for the row I'm just going to add a new one at the top
with 60 pixels high, well actually no longer 60 pixels,
but six times eight so 48 pixels
because remember one rem is now 8 pixels at this grid width.
So, that is the grid definition, but then we also have
to place the sidebar in the right place, right?
So, let's open it up and now this grid-row here
is no longer correct and neither is the grid-column.
So, let's add a media query here as well
and we're gonna take this one here and copy it
because I'm kind of lazy and don't want to like
to write the same code over and over again
so I'm just copying it.
So, the grid-column is now no longer
sidebar-start sidebar-end but instead
we can actually say that it's from the first to the last.
So, very simple and as for the grid-row
it is from line number one
to line number two and that's actually it.
So, let's take a look at that and alright here we go.
So, the sidebar is now at the top
so it's no longer really a sidebar,
but anyway it's now at the top here
and our design no longer has this bar here on the side
and it goes all the way from the left side of the screen
to the right side
and let's actually see if that changes, yeah.
So, it's just below a thousand pixels
where it moves up there, right?
Now just imagine the nightmare it would have been
if we didn't name our column lines.
So, if we didn't have all of these column lines
and instead would have placed items with line-numbers.
So, now all of these numbers would be completely different
because we took out the first column
and so we would have to rewrite all the code
to place all of the items on our grid, right?
And that would be a terrible experience.
And so that's why it's so great to have the possibility
of naming the grid-lines like this, right?
So, again when you have a huge layout like this one,
which you also want to change with media queries later one,
then please always name your columns.
It's always the best thing to do
and if you need to place elements on the rows
then also name the rows.
In this case, we didn't do that
because basically our mark up follows the logical structure
and so the auto-placement algorithm places them
just where we want them to be.
Now, just one small thing that's not right here
is that this icon I actually want it here to the right side.
So, let's very quickly change that as well
and so we need to say justify-content flex-end
because remember we did this using flex-box
and then also say align-items set to center.
So, vertically center the icon inside of the sidebar.
Okay.
Now, we also need to change some stuff here in this
and that's because we have this margin here,
but we don't want that.
For margin-top zero
and so yeah that looks better.
Instead we actually want the margin on the right side.
So, let's say like three rem.
And okay.
So, that looks a lot better.
Now, we can maybe just decrease here
the space that we have there.
So, let's just quickly do that as well.
Let's say this one to two and this to zero.
Okay.
So, that looks more natural again.
Alright, so I think that is enough for now.
So, I think we are good now for a long time here actually,
so at least here until this 800 pixels
where it starts to look a bit weird in here, but we're going
to take care of that right in the next lecture
so that we don't end up with like a 30 minute video here.