Now that we have our project all set up,
let's talk about three important and fundamental principles
that we need to constantly keep in mind
if we want to build good modern websites or web apps
with HTML and CSS.
And they call them the three pillars
of writing good HTML and CSS.
Now, this lecture is not exactly about coding,
but it's absolutely crucial
that we talk about these principles here
right in the beginning of the course.
So let me start off the project without making any mistakes
you would later then have to fix down the road.
Alright. So the three pillars are responsive design,
writing maintainable and scalable code,
and carrying about web performance.
But let's look at them one by one.
So, the first principle is responsive design,
or responsive web design,
which simply means that we build one website
that works beautifully across all screen sizes
on all devices.
But I'm sure you already know that, right?
So, responsive design is absolutely a standard today,
and so there is no way you're going to build
a non-responsive website in 2017 or even later.
Now, if you're taking this advanced course,
then I assume that you already know
at least the fundamentals of responsive web design.
Things like fluid layouts and media queries.
But we're going to take it one step further in this course
because modern responsive design also include stuff like
responsive images, which is a huge topic itself,
using correct units for things like
font sizes or element dimensions,
and it also includes either desktop-first
or a mobile-first strategy.
We're going to talk about all of that
during the project of this course.
Next up, we need to talk about
writing maintainable and scalable code.
Now, this is actually more important for you,
the developer, than for the final user of the website.
But it's still something we need to follow
if we want to build a good website.
So, writing maintainable and scalable code
means to write code that is clean, easy to understand,
that supports future growth, and above all,
it is reusable for you, as well as for other developers
who might take on your project in the future.
So, if we want to write maintainable and scalable code,
we need to care and think about our CSS architecture,
which is the way we organize our files,
how we name our classes,
and how we structure our mark up in HTML.
Now, don't worry if all these sound weird
or complicated to you, because it's really not.
And we'll talk about these stuff in a separate lecture
a bit later in the section.
What I want you to understand for now
is that this stuff is really important
if you want to step up your game
and become a more professional CSS
or front-end web developer in general.
Writing maintainable code
is something that all professional web developers
care about a lot.
Alright, and last but not least,
let's talk web performance.
Making a website or app more performant
means to make it faster and to make it smaller in size,
so that the user has to download less data.
Now, there are many things that affect performance,
and some factors don't have much to do with our code.
But some of the things that we can do
is to make as little HTTP requests as possible,
meaning that we should include as little as possible files
in our HTML document,
write as little code as possible of course,
compress our code, and use a preprocessor like Sass
that we're going to explore later in this course.
Now, this is all great,
but maybe the biggest impact we can have on performance
is to actually reduce the use of images
because images are usually what makes up by far
the biggest part of the size of a website.
We can do so by using only images that are really necessary
for a website or app.
And also by compressing these images
so that you use less bandwidth for the final user.
Okay, so, these are the three pillars
that we will have in mind all the time
while building our project.
We have to always ask ourselves
if the code we are writing is responsive,
if it is maintainable and scalable,
and if it affects web performance.