So, as I said in the last lecture,
the next step in our project
is to build amazing navigation
that I showed you earlier.
And now that you thought that I was running
out of new stuff to teach you,
well I have a bunch more to show you right now.
So this is what you're gonna learn in this section.
So first of all,
the so called checkbox hack
is how this navigation works.
And so, you learn how that works of course.
Then you'll learn how to create custom
animation timing functions using cubic bezier curves.
Then, how to animate the solid-color gradients
that we talked about before
to create a nice hover effect.
And finally, how and why to use
the transform-origin property.
So that's also new.
Overall, you're just gonna learn
how to create a creative effect in CSS
with about 150 lines of code.
So that's what this navigation needs.
All right, so let's take a detailed look
at how this navigation works.
So first of all, it stays at the same place
no matter where we scroll to on our page.
So this button always stays here.
Then when we hover it,
we have this effect where the lines open
a bit like this.
And then when you click it becomes an X.
You see?
But then of course, you have this huge background here
coming basically from behind this button,
expanding all over the page,
and revealing this navigation here
coming in from the left side, right.
So and then you have, of course,
the navigation with these five links.
And when you hover them,
you have this nice effect here, okay.
And when you close it,
of course the navigation is going to go away,
and the circle will come back here to this place.
All right, let's take a look at that again.
Okay, so what are the main parts of this navigation?
First off here, this button of course,
containing here this icon,
but we'll worry about that later.
Then we have this background here
which comes from here and expands.
So this one.
Then we have an overall container
which occupies the entire page
and which contains then this element,
this unordered list,
which contains this navigation.
And then in there you have the li elements
and a link in each of them.
So just a structure of a usual navigation, okay.
Now, as I was saying earlier,
what makes this entire navigation work,
especially the clicks.
So when we click and the navigation opens,
what makes that work is the so called checkbox hack.
So how does that work?
Well do you remember,
in the other lecture about the form.
So down here
with the radio buttons.
Remember this one here?
So what we had here was a radio button
connected to a label.
And when we clicked on a label,
then the radio button would become selected, okay.
And that's the same thing that we're gonna do right now
but except the radio button,
we're gonna use a checkbox.
So basically, the three steps for this to work
is to first have a checkbox,
which will be hidden later,
then second,
have a label connected to that checkbox,
which is where we click.
And as you can guess, that will be the button here.
And then the third step is to reveal
the entire navigation here in the background
as soon as the checkbox becomes checked.
And we can use the checked pseudo class in CSS
to style this.
Okay, so that's how it will work.
But let's do it by steps.
So we first start by styling
some of the stuff here, okay.
So, of course first in the HTML.
And what we're gonna do is likely put the navigation here
on top of everything else.
So this will be the first element
in our entire web document.
And let's use a div here called navigation.
Then in here, we have the checkbox, okay.
So input,
and I'm gonna call this one the navigation checkbox.
Okay, and the type will be checkbox.
And the id which we need to connect with the label,
remember, is called navi-toggle.
Okay, so that's the first ingredient
for the checkbox hack.
Then we need a label.
This one will be called navigation button.
And it is for the navi-toggle.
And in here we will later have that icon.
But for now, let's just say menu.
Then we need a div which will be our background.
So let's call it navigation_background.
Very simple, and this one will be empty.
So let's just put nbsp here,
which stands for white space basically in HTML.
And we used that before, right.
So this background will be empty
so that we can then, on top of that,
put the navigation itself.
Okay, and so for that we can actually use
the HTML nav element, okay.
And I'll call it navigation_nav, very simple.
And so this one will be the huge container,
spanning the entire page, which I mentioned,
so that we can then in there
vertically and horizontally center
the unordered list, okay.
So navigation_list.
And then in there,
I'm gonna put the navigation item.
And the navigation link inside of that.
And going nowhere once again.
So about Natous is the first one.
And that's now just
copy this a couple times.
Popular tours,
stories,
and finally book now.
So that is our entire markup for the navigation.
Okay, so let's now start by styling the background.
Okay, that's where I'm gonna start.
So the navigation is part of the layout,
for me at least,
and so I'm gonna put it here.
So navigation scss.
Navigation here as well.
Let me just copy this word here.
Because now, need to include it here as well.
Well, there goes the copied word.
But not a problem, okay.
So, navigation.
So let's first of all create all the selectors.
So, checkbox, button, and background.
And then, what else do we have?
We have the nav, list,
item, and link.
So a lot of stuff to style here as you can see.
Okay, but as I was saying,
let's start actually with the background.
So you saw that his background is basically just a circle
expanding from here, right?
So if you see it very slowly,
you see that it's a circle,
and now it comes back.
And so what we need here is this circle
actually behind this whiter circle.
Okay, that's actually why we're doing this first.
So first we do the one behind this white circle,
and then the one on top.
So let's start with style.
So height,
6rem,
width of 6rem because it's a circle.
So, same height and width.
And border-radius, 50%.
So let's just take a look
so that we can see what we need to do next.
So all of the stuff is now right here.
Okay, so we see the navigation here.
We see the menu,
and we see that actually when we click this here,
the checkbox gets selected.
Now our div, it's still here and invisible, okay.
So we need to give it that green color
and then put it up here, right?
So in fact we want all of this here to be fixed right
and to appear in the top right corner.
So let's start by doing that with the button here, okay.
So, how do we do that?
Well, we use something called position fixed.
And that's very similar to position absolute
with the difference that with fixed,
it doesn't change position as we scroll the page.
But it also takes the element out of the flow
and allows us to specify it in relation
to a positioned element
with the top, left, right,
and bottom properties.
So let's do that.
And let's say top.
6.5rem.
And you'll see where that .5 comes from in a second
when we do the button, okay.
So from the top 6.5,
and from the right also 6.5.
So that is nicely in the corner there.
Now we want that background image
with that nice gradient, right.
Now, this time we're going to do a different gradient,
the new one that we didn't talk about before.
So we always use linear gradients, right.
But now we'll use a radial gradient.
And what's the difference?
Well, the linear gradient goes from one side
to the other one
while the radial gradient starts in the middle of an element
and goes from there in all the outside directions basically.
So you will see that in a second.
So we start from the lighter color.
So color,
primary lighter.
Or light, I think it's called.
And then color...
Primary...
dark, okay.
So, we're ready to take a look at that I think.
And yeah, so here it is.
But actually it's not really in the correct position, right.
While it's already fixed,
you see it's fixed,
but not quite where we want it.
So why is that?
Okay, I forgot the rem here.
Sorry about that one.
And so let's check it out again.
And yeah, so now here it goes.
And you see that radial gradient now.
Right, because you're outside it's a lot darker
than here in the middle.
So that's the lighter green,
and that's the darker green here on the outside.
Okay, now one thing I'm noticing here
is that there's probably some mistake in the HTML
because these should be links
which they are not.
And that is because oh yeah, I see.
So I should have put this here of course
after this text, right.
So that's a stupid mistake once again.
But as I was saying earlier,
it's no problem.
It's completely normal that this happens.
It happens to everyone.
So, again, okay.
Now it's good.
Now as we scroll,
you see that this gets hidden here
behind that element.
And so let's just quickly add a z-index as well.
Let's give it a really high one.
So let's say even 1,000 okay.
And so this only works on an element
which has its position defined.
But it already has that and so we're good to go.
And now you see that it stays on top
of everything all the time.
Okay, and now about the button.
Now this one will have a white background color, okay.
So color white.
It will be slightly higher.
We will make this one 7rem.
And of course in width as well,
because it's also a circle.
And we're doing that in order to really cover
the background here in the beginning, okay.
So if it was the same size,
than maybe we would see some green of this background
here behind it.
But we don't want that, okay.
So just to make sure, let's completely cover it.
So height, width 7rem here.
Once again, we want it to be at a fixed position.
Okay, and then from the top,
it will be at 7rem,
and from the right, the same thing.
So, 7rem as well.
Actually, what I want is not seven but six.
Okay, so in order to cover it.
Because this one here is 6.5,
and this one is six.
Okay, and that's because the button is 1rem wider
and higher than the background here.
And that's why it's then half a rem
further to the top and to the right.
Okay, because this half here is half
of the one difference
between the size of the background and the button.
So they're now really on top of each other.
And the border-radius of course,
also 50%.
So take a look at that now.
And well, I would say that here it is.
What we have to do, of course,
is to also give it a z-index.
And this one should be really high.
So even higher.
Let's say 2,000 here.
And now here we go.
Now since it's wide,
you cannot really see it
because we still have this stuff here going on,
sitting before our header here in the DOM.
And so it makes everything white,
and we can see the white circle over there.
So let's now actually take care of that, okay.
But first of all, let's actually hide the checkbox already.
So display none.
Because of course we never want to see this one.
All right, and now the navigation element.
Let me show it in the markup here for you.
So it's this nav element
with the navigation_nav class.
So remember that I said that this would be a huge element
occupying the entire viewport
so that we can then center the navigation list
inside of that, both horizontally and vertically, right.
So let's now do these two steps.
So first off, the nav.
It should have a height of 100 viewport height units.
Basically, so 100% of the viewport height
and a width of 100%.
But I don't really need to specify that.
Well, but I can for now.
Because it's a block level element and so,
it automatically occupies 100% of its width.
Now, the position should also be fixed.
Because remember that with the navigation open,
even if you scroll,
the navigation will stay at the same place, okay.
And so you want it at a zero top,
and a zero right.
So it starts right in the top right corner
of the viewport,
spanning over the entire viewport because of this.
And now finally, we also need to think about its z-index.
So this button here should always be on top, right.
But the nav here should be on top of the background.
And so we have 1,000 here,
2,000 here.
And these numbers, they don't really matter
as long as this one is higher as this one.
And so here we can just say 15 hundred for example.
But we could really do like 10, 20, 30,
it doesn't really matter.
Or 1,000,
2,000, 3,000, for this one.
But for now, what matters here,
is that this one here is in the middle.
So let's just take a look at that.
All right, and so right now we already see
our white circle here, sitting nicely at this place.
Now all we have to do
is to actually center this entire thing here in the middle.
And then later on,
we're gonna of course hide it.
But for now, as for styling it,
we need to keep it visible.
This UL element, so this navigation list,
this is what we're gonna center inside
of this nav container.
So position absolute as we already know.
Top, 50%,
left, 50%,
and then our transform,
translate minus 50 and minus 50, of course.
We could actually write a mixin for this part here
because we've been using it so many times
and it's always the same code.
And so a mixin would be a good thing to do here.
So if you want to try it out,
go to the mixins file here,
create a mixin like center horizontal vertical,
something like that,
and then just copy these lines,
or actually these four lines here,
and then you don't always have to write
this entire code, okay.
Now in here, we could actually have used left for this one.
But it's really the same since it's already
the entire width anyway.
So it doesn't really matter.
Now, what we also want is
to get rid of the bullets.
And the text-align should be center.
All right.
Now, as we're styling this,
let's actually increase the background to a huge size
so that we can see how it will look like
later in the real live.
So the background, where is it?
Okay, it's here.
So what we're gonna do later,
as soon as the navigation is open,
we will scale this entire background, okay.
Like by a huge number.
Let's say it's something like 50 even.
And so this entire circle
will become huge, and it will grow,
and this animation is what will create the effect, okay.
And so for now, we just put it here
for development purposes.
We will then move it to another part of our code later on.
Okay, just to take a look at it.
All right, so this is how it will look like.
Actually, even bigger.
So maybe it will have to be even like 80
or something like that
to also cover bigger screens, okay.
And so that's what it will look like.
And you see that it already stays at the same place, right.
So we're scrolling here,
you see the scroll bar on the right side.
I'm scrolling and this stays at the same place.
So that's great.
Okay, but let's now style these links
in order to make them look like this.
So that's a huge difference, right?
So let's now do that.
And actually, it's not as hard as it may look like.
Let's start with the simple stuff.
Font-size of 3rem.
Font-weight of only 300.
So a nice, thin text.
Then the color is white if you remember.
So color, white.
Of course, there's no text-decoration.
And a text-transform is again to upper case.
Okay, taking a look at that.
So, here we go.
Maybe let's give these some padding here.
And we can actually do that here in the item.
Or better, some margin actually.
So 1rem between the elements.
So something like this here.
So we're getting closer to what we have here.
Now what's really different here of course
is this white background coming in like that.
So take a look at that again.
So it's this slightly rotated edge again that we have
in other places on our page.
And so, let's try to implement that here as well.
And what do you think is the best way of creating this?
So, take a look at it again.
So here you have the edge, okay.
So what do you think is the best way of creating this?
Well, I think it's a solid color gradient,
such as we have used before, okay.
So, do you remember how we do that?
So background-image,
linear-gradient,
and we use a degree here.
And once again, we're outside of the parenthesis.
Okay, and now we can use these percentages again
like we did on the booking section, right.
So let's start with transparent.
And actually to make it visible,
let's get out our favorite orange-red,
which at 0% it is orange-red, okay.
Then at 50%,
it's orange-red again,
only to say that at 50%, we start our color white.
50%, okay.
Now without any animation,
and anything like that,
let's just take a look at what we have here.
And okay.
So that's the starting point really.
And so before we move on,
let's give this here some padding, okay.
So padding, once again,
on the top we have one,
and on the sides then a bit more.
Okay, that always looks good.
And now I'm gonna show you another property
that's not exactly new,
but I'm not sure if you're aware of it.
And that's called background size.
So background size.
And yes of course you're aware of it
because we've used it before.
Actually I showed it to you
with background-size 100% right?
So 100%, that's the starting point here.
So let me show it to you
what happens if we increase that value in this case.
So we start with 100.
And if we increase this,
you see that the entire thing
basically moves to the right side.
And that's because we're basically increasing
the entire thing.
But it's not visible because the box ends here.
But you can imagine that now this entire background
goes like around this entire thing here, okay.
And if we set this all the way to 200,
which is double...
Okay, so 200.
Now it will go all the way until in here, okay.
So basically like here.
So now this entire thing here is the gradient,
but we only see the red side, right?
So only the red part of this gradient is visible.
But we know that the white part is still here
on the right side, right.
And the same thing of course applies to all of these.
So all of these have this wide part now here
going on, on that right side.
And maybe now you can start to see
how this effect is gonna work, right?
Because now, all we have to do
is to move this entire gradient here to the left side
and then the white part will be here.
And the red part, which later will be transparent
will be here on the left side, okay.
So if you basically shift the entire thing 100% to the side,
then we end up with the effect that we're looking for.
Right, so let's now implement that.
And actually in here, this is not correct.
Because this should be for the link pseudo class, right.
And also for the visited,
since we're at that.
So, this is for the normal state.
And then the hover, and active state.
So, remember what I was saying?
If we shift the background completely to the left side,
then we end up with the effect that we want.
And we can do that with background-position.
Okay, and so the entire thing as we were saying
usually means 100%, all right.
And just so that we can see it,
let's actually animate it.
So transition,
all .4 seconds.
So let's take a look now.
Well, what's going on here.
Oh, okay, I didn't change it in the code.
Here it's still 100.
I changed it only in the dev tools,
but of course that doesn't reflect in the code.
And so now it works.
And you see, as we're hovering it,
the background basically shifts to the left side
because the position is now at 100%.
And let me show that to you here in the inspector as well.
So I can say hover.
And then we can take the number and play a bit with it,
so you see.
When I decrease it,
it goes back to where it was.
So zero was the initial state basically.
And so now, as I increase it,
it goes in this direction.
And as I increase it even more,
it goes around like this.
But that doesn't matter, okay.
So 100% here basically is the end.
But anyway, zero is what we actually wanted.
So let's take that away
and hover it.
Well, what's going on now?
Ah, yeah, right.
Now you see that it's not quite right.
Okay, and that's because of these 100%,
sorry but because of this 120 degrees here.
So we rotated this thing a bit.
And so it doesn't quite cover here the entire thing.
And so what we want to do
is to just increase this a bit here, okay.
So just set it to 220%,
and that should fix it.
So you see,
now it's much better.
All right,
and of course we now want to replace that
with transparent.
Because orange-red is always just our testing color.
All right, so transparent.
And here we go.
Now of course, we also need to make our text dark
so we can actually see what's written in there.
So...
color...
and then color-primary.
All right.
Now another thing that we had going on here actually,
let's take a look at that.
Okay, so anyway this works now, right.
Now another thing that we have going on here
is you see that it slightly moves a bit to the right side.
Okay, and that looks even better this way.
Right, so let's do that as well.
And that's pretty easy of course.
You know that already.
So translateX,
and let's say just 1rem.
All right.
So that's the original.
And that's ours here.
Well, it doesn't really work.
Why is that?
Maybe there's an error again here in my terminal.
But actually no,
it seems to just be working just fine.
So what's happening?
Well this animation actually works just fine.
But for some reason, the transition is not working out.
So let's put this to hover here again.
And yeah, actually it is here.
But it's not doing anything.
And I think I know why this is happening.
And actually, I was wondering why the padding
was also not being applied just right.
And that's because we still have to define this here
as inline blocks, okay.
So, the link should be of course,
let me put it at the beginning.
I like to put it at the beginning always.
So display, it should be an inline-block
so that the padding is actually really applied
the way it should.
Ah, yeah, now it looks much better.
And also, it works the way we intended it to.
So here we go.
Much better now.
All right, well this one here also has these numbers.
So let's just add a span
because we also have the spacing here.
So this is just a simple span that I added.
It's nothing really important.
But nevertheless, let's do that, okay.
So it's just a span element saying oh one.
And now I'm breaking the rule here of
every element having to have a class.
But well, I would say that rules are meant
to be broken sometimes okay.
So as long as you have a good reason, then that's okay.
And in this case, that's because
I think it would be really kind of an overkill
to now add even another class to that chain.
Okay, and so in here,
all we have to do is to say span.
'Cause it's inside of these link elements here, right.
And so margin-right,
1rem.
And display,
inline-block.
So that should do it.
And yep, here we go.
Could even make it a bit more like 1.5.
Yeah, that looks really good.
All right, now the problem is that of course
nothing of this works.
We don't have the icon here.
And so we have to take care of all of that,
making a checkbox hack actually work.
And we're gonna do that in the next lecture.
So don't wait, and come with me right there.