So here comes the more exciting part
of building this navigation.
Which, this will actually make it work
as soon as we hit that navigation button.
So, let's do that.
First of all, we need to hide this background here again
and also hide this navigation, right?
Let's do that.
Where is this ... yeah, here.
Remember, we didn't want this one here
so let's make it disappear.
And then here we have the button and actually
we should add some shadows here, okay?
A box shadow of one in the right direction,
a nice blur,
and in the color of, once again, black, right?
Just a very subtle shadow here, right?
That's what it looks like.
And now, of course, we have to get rid
of the navigation here as well.
So, where is that?
Yeah, this is the one.
How are we going to do that?
Well, we can use opacity zero, such as we did before.
Now, there's a problem with that which is that
with this alone, we will actually make it opaque,
but you see that ... well, now I cannot show you.
But the links, okay, they're still here.
So you see that the hand is here at some of these places.
So, they're invisible now, but they're still there.
What we should do here, is to also set the width to a zero.
Actually, we have it up here, so let's remove that.
Now it should work just fine.
The text is now gone.
The only text we have here now is this H1 that we have.
Okay?
We hit the navigation and we hit background.
Now, all we have to do is to actually
bring them back to life.
Let's say so.
And so, this is where we use the check box hack.
How do we do that?
Remember from the booking lecture,
where we did the radio buttons?
This is very similar to that.
We have our checkbox, we have our label,
and we have our background.
We hit the label and the checkbox becomes checked.
Then we want the navigation background here
to become visible.
How do we translate that into a CSS selector?
Well, it's actually not so hard.
We just write checkbox and a checked pseudo-class again,
just as we did with the radio button.
And then use the sibling selector.
Remember that one?
Now this time, it's not an adjacent sibling,
because it's not direct sibling, right?
The one that we want to select here is now this one.
So the adjacent sibling of the checked box would be this one
but that's not the one that we want.
We want this here.
And so we just use the general sibling and then,
with that, we will be able to select the right element.
So, background.
And that's actually it.
Remember how we increase the size of this?
We simply scale it 80 times.
This is what we actually did.
Okay, so let's see if that works.
We hit this, and whoa, here we go.
Now it disappears and it comes back and it appears
and so it is working.
Great, right?
We don't have the animation yet in place,
but we're going to take care of that in a second.
For now, let's do the same for the navigation, okay?
It's the same really and so all we have to do here is
to replace it with "nav."
And then, what happens here is, of course, that we remove
what we did here before.
The opacity is no longer zero
and the width is no longer zero as well.
Opacity one with back to 100%.
Let's take a look at that,
and here we go.
It works, without animation, but it works.
For the animation, this is also very simple.
It's just the transition that we have used before.
We need the transition on the background
as well as on the nav element.
Transition, and what we want to transition here
is just to transform, so let's just put "transform" here
instead of transitioning everything.
And then, let's put a .8 second here, so a very long one.
Now, this time around, we're going to add
a custom transition time and function here.
For now, let's just add the transition to the other element
and just take a look how it looks like, okay?
And so here, transition.
And in here, we only want
to really animate the opacity, okay?
The width, it should be instantaneous.
Instantly it should become 100%,
but the opacity, that's the one
that we actually want to animate.
So we set the opacity and also .8 seconds.
Alright and that should be enough already.
Alright, well, actually, we have to animate the width
as well because now you see it goes here to the side,
in this weird way, right?
Let's put it here to all, right?
Well, now you see this is like weirdly moving
in from the side and moving out like this, okay?
And that's not at all what we want to happen,
but I believe this is because we didn't specify a width
here for this element for this list, okay?
If we set this to 100%, then that should not be happening.
So, navigation list, okay, and we say width 100%.
Let's reload that.
Well, and it actually makes sense that this is happening
because remember, when we closed this,
this entire container here reduces its width from 100%
so everything, all until the way to zero.
Since we fix it here at the right side,
then this thing here also moves to the right side, okay?
Let me demonstrate that to you.
First of all, let's put it to left here, okay?
We want this to move to the left.
At least that will make it look a bit better.
And then background color, and you can guess it,
orange, red.
Let's take a look at that right now.
This is what happens, you saw?
Now when I hit this button, you will see this orange here
moving to that side.
Therefore, since this here's always centered
in this container, it will move to that side.
You saw that?
Okay, and so, that's what happened.
But that's actually not a big problem
because, basically, this automatically gives us
a nice animation effect, right?
This box moving in like that.
Now, I promised you that we would take care
of a custom transition timing function, okay?
Here and here as well.
Let's now do that.
We saw in other lectures, that there are a bunch
of built-in transition timing functions like ease-in
or ease-out or ease-in-out, but this time,
we want to use a more custom one.
For that one, we use something
called cubic-bezier functions, okay?
Now, in here, we have to put four numbers that define
the cubic-bezier curve, but since we don't really know
which numbers to put, there is a nice tool
which can help us with that.
Actually two tools because this one and this one.
Here are a bunch of different functions that we can use.
Again, what an easing function is, is basically
a function that specifies how much change occurs
over time, okay?
And that's exactly what this is here.
Take a look at these red markers.
This one started slow, accelerated, and then
slowed down again.
Take a look again.
This one here mixes even more, and even more in here,
you saw?
Really slow beginning then really fast, you see this here,
and then really slow.
Then we have these ones here, something like this.
But for now, let's use this one here, okay?
I really like this one, so we're going to use that
for the background.
We can just click this here and then all we have to do,
is to copy this curve.
You put it here, or actually, we only need the numbers,
already wrote the function and so,
we just need the numbers.
And now, let's take a look at how it looks like.
Well, that was different, right?
Just as an example, it comes really easy
and then it accelerates like crazy.
You saw that?
Let's stick with that.
Of course, you can use other functions.
If you like another one more, use that.
Just to have this more visually,
this is how these functions actually work,
so these numbers.
If we push this here, or pull them down,
then we have something like this.
This is a bit similar to the function that we have, right?
Well, maybe not exactly like this.
I'm not sure it doesn't really matter.
But in here, we can then compare
these cubic-bezier functions that we draw here,
with one of the built-in ones, okay?
If we hit on "go," then the pink one is the one
that be routing here and the blue one is the built-in.
For example, they're easing out, let's say.
If we compare it with this one,
then you see this one is really slow at the beginning
and at the end, but then it's really fast.
That's like this huge slope that you see here going on.
Now if you did it the other way around, something like this,
you'll now see that this will accelerate pretty fast,
then it will slow down, move actually back a bit,
and then become really fast again at the end.
Let's take a look.
You saw that moving back, it was this part here.
From here to here, it moved back and then really fast
at the end.
Let's take a look again.
There it is.
Yeah, you can really play around with this.
Now this will be even more dramatic, okay?
That's a lot of different functions that we can draw
basically with this.
Let's take a look now at this one, for example.
I really like to play around with this.
Now, in this case, we already have
these pretty fine functions here, which are pretty great,
but you can always, if you want, play around with this one.
Now, for navigation itself, let's add another function.
What I'm going to use is this one.
This one, as you can already see here,
it will move out a little bit.
Let's actually copy the entire thing here now.
Because in here we haven't put it already.
Alright, let's take a look now, refresh.
And here we go.
Now you saw that it actually moved a bit to that side first,
so to the right side.
Why did that happen?
Well, simply because this width, this 100% width here,
it got a bit larger, so it got maybe 110% because
of this curve.
Because the curve here actually comes out of this one here,
let's say, so we have something like this, right?
You will see that this now will probably move a bit
out here, like this actually, so you saw it's moved a bit
in this direction, then it came back.
That's because this here is higher than the 100%.
Actually it says here 105%.
You can see it here as well.
It says, "This curve contains values out of range."
That makes for this effect,
which can be really cool sometimes.
In this case, I think it looks good, and so,
let's keep it that way.
Of course, I invite you to play around with this,
get your own style maybe, and play around with this, okay?
Alright, so this is already pretty similar
to what we have here.
All that's left to do, it to create this button here.
These three lines which open and close and close and open.
Okay?
That's actually a bit more complex than it looks like,
and so we're going to leave that for the next lecture.
If you want to know how to do it, don't take a break,
and come right with me, okay?
See you in a second.