Welcome back to the second part
of the SASS intro lectures.
This time I'm gonna show you how to use SASS mixins,
extends, and functions in practice.
Let's start with mixins.
So what is a mixin?
It's actually very simple.
A mixin is just a reusable piece of code
that we write into a mixin.
And then whenever we use that, that mixin,
that code is then put in the place
where we used or where we called that mixin.
So you can imagine this like a huge variable
with multiple lines of code.
This is how it works.
Imagine that we wanted to use the clearfix
not only on the navigation
but on multiple places throughout the page.
So imagine this would be a huge webpage
and we would have to use the clearfix all over the place.
It would not be really practical
to add this piece of code here
inside all of these elements, right?
So instead, we can just make this a mixin
and then just include the mixin here in this place.
Let me show you how that works.
I'm gonna put the mixin in here.
Then I have to write @mixin, give it a name,
clearfix in this case,
and then I just need to put the code here.
Let me get this one here,
put it there, and all right.
So basically we now have stored
this entire piece of code here
inside of this mixin,
which you can think of a variable called clearfix.
So it's a mixin called clearfix.
Now how do we actually use this mixin?
It's very simple.
All we have to do is to now say @include,
@include, and then the name of the mixin, of course.
Clearfix, and that's it.
Now it should be back and yeah, here it is.
We can now go ahead and use this clearfix here
wherever we want it on our page,
if we had a bigger project.
Again let's take a look at the compiled CSS,
and yeah, here it is.
So indeed, now here is the clearfix.
So these are mixins.
I can actually show you another cool example of mixins
because mixins are actually even more powerful than that.
Take a look at this piece of code here.
For this link here, we have text-decoration,
text-transform, and a color.
But down here when we define these buttons,
we have the exact same thing here as well.
We have text-decoration to none,
text-transform to uppercase, and then a color.
Now, the color is actually different.
But let's think about that later.
What we can do is to simply put these three lines of code
into a mixin and then call this mixin
in each of these declaration blocks, right?
So instead of repeating the code,
we have it in one central place.
This is called the DRY principle,
which means Don't Repeat Yourself.
This again comes back to all this talk that we had
about maintainable and reusable code and all this stuff.
Let's now do that actually.
Put this here.
All right.
This piece of code we gonna put in a new mixin.
Let's call it style-link-text.
All right, so mixin style-link-text.
We can now go ahead and then use it.
We actually just copy the name.
Because now you see the buttons,
they are not styled as they were before.
So let's go back to where we removed this code,
was here.
Let's say @include style-link-text.
And here we go.
We can now do the same in here.
So, @include, style-link-text.
Now what happened here?
This text just turned white, of course,
because here we said that the color
should be the light text color.
So what can we do here?
This is perfect for me to show you something
which we can do with mixins,
which is basically to pass it an argument, like this.
So what is an argument?
An argument is something that we can pass into the mixin,
and the mixin will then use this argument here,
like as a variable.
So what we do here is to define this col variable,
which stands for color, actually call it color.
And then in here, we put color.
And now when we call this mixin,
when we include the mixin,
we will pass into this mixin the color that we want,
which will then be called color.
And this color then becomes this color.
So this one and this one, they are then the same.
But let me show you with an example.
In here, we want to use the variable called text-color-dark.
I think it's actually called color-text.
Now, that's still not working.
Let's take a look here at this error sign that we have here.
Oh, it's gone.
Why is that?
So, color-text-dark and color-text-dark.
Yeah, so it should actually work.
So let's check again what's going on down here.
But it should actually be working.
Maybe I cannot call this col here.
Maybe I cannot call it color, just call it col.
That's also not changing anything.
No, I think I found the error.
And it's not working because down here,
we also used the mixin
but we didn't specify the argument.
So in here, we want color-text-light.
Let's see if it works now.
Let's reload this thing.
Okay, first save it.
And then reload.
All right, so finally now we got it to working.
Now let me explain you again what happens here.
In here, we include the mixin with a variable
which is color-text-dark.
So this is an argument for the mixin.
This will get passed into the mixin
and will be called col in here, inside,
internally in this mixin.
The thing, this variable, this text
or whatever we pass into here, is now called col
here inside in this mixin.
So here we call it col.
So what we passed inside of this style-link-text mixin
is then called col, and we can use it in here.
So in the first example, it was called color-text-dark.
So that's was passed in here
and is then replaced by color-text-dark, which is this.
And down here, where is it?
And down here we pass color-text-light
into the style-link-text mixin.
So this time, col will be that.
So it will be replaced, then, by color-text-light,
which is eee.
So you've got that?
Basically this allows us to pass some information
into this mixin
and then the mixin can use that information.
So these are the two use cases for mixins.
We have normal one without any arguments,
where it is just this code,
which is then pasted wherever we included the mixin.
And in this case, we get to pass an argument as well.
So this is actually a bit similar to functions,
which work in the same way.
Now, I already showed you functions
actually before, down here.
Let me get some more space.
We used functions before,
which is this one, darken and lighten.
This actually works in the same way.
We pass in the arguments which are color-secondary
and 15% in this case,
and then the function does something with this data,
with this information we passed in.
And then it puts the data in here,
it replaces what we wrote here
with the result of the function.
Let's see, for example, in the button main,
for the hover.
So button main, for hover.
The result of that function is this color, ea5717.
Again, a function takes arguments, just like a mixin.
Then it does something with these arguments
and returns them.
If you're familiar with programming in general,
like JavaScript or something,
then it works the exact same way.
Now, we are not restricted to using
the built-in SASS functions.
We can also write our own functions.
I actually personally don't find them so useful.
But of course I'm gonna show you how they work.
Now imagine we just want a very simple function
which simply divides the two arguments
that we passed into the function.
Now, we wouldn't really need a function for this
because in SASS, you can just do math operations like that.
But let's suppose we would find this function useful.
So we can say, @function,
and then we can specify our arguments.
Just like in the mixins,
we can put whatever variable names in here.
So these are the arguments,
not really variables but arguments.
So a and b.
And then what it does is, it will return,
return a divided by b.
And that's it.
So this is how a function works like.
We pass arguments into it,
it then does something with these arguments,
and returns it here with the return keyword.
Now if you want to use it, for example here,
then we can try that.
Well, actually I forgot something here,
which is, of course, the name of the function.
So sorry, let's call it divide.
The function, of course, needs to have a name.
Then we specify the arguments for that function.
Now if we wanted to use it somewhere,
let's try that out.
We can just say divide.
Remember it was 30.
Let's just say 60 and then two.
Let's see what that does.
Actually, it doesn't do anything.
I'm gonna show you why
here in the inspect.
That's because this gives, of course, 30.
But the 30 doesn't have any unit.
So CSS doesn't know what we mean.
So, 30 what?
30% or pixels or centimeters or whatever.
It doesn't really know what the 30 is.
If we wanna fix that,
there's an easy fix.
The best practice to do it in SASS
is by multiplying it by a one pixel.
So if we want pixel,
then we multiply this result by one pixel
and then it's back to working.
Now of course this isn't really practical
because all we really want here is 30 pixels.
But this is just to show you how we could theoretically
use functions to do this kind of calculations.
And we could, of course, do much more complex stuff,
much more complex calculation,
instead of just dividing one number by the other.
All right, so we talked about mixins, about functions,
and now let's take a look at extends.
Let's go down here
because we're going to use the extend feature
here on the buttons.
So what do extends do?
Basically we can write a placeholder
and put a bunch of styles in there,
and then have other selectors extend that placeholder.
If that sounds a bit confusing,
let me show it to you in practice, okay?
The things that are common to these buttons,
I will just put them in a placeholder.
We write a placeholder in SASS like this,
so the percentage sign,
and then I just call it button-placeholder.
Now I'm gonna put all of these styles in there.
I'm doing that because all of this duplicate code here
doesn't look really good, right?
It's really not following
the Don't Repeat Yourself principle here.
You see button-main-link here
and button-main-link here again,
and button-hot-link here
and again button-hot-link in here.
So we're using these selectors, like, twice.
So what we can do instead
is to put all of this here into this placeholder.
And now we're simply going to extend these selectors here
that we already have.
All I have to do is to write extend
and then button-placeholder.
And the same thing down here.
I will now extend this one here as well,
and these buttons are back to working right now.
So great.
Again, we just extended these two selectors here,
so this one and this one,
with the code that we have here in this placeholder.
Now you may ask, "Well, why didn't we just
"make a mixin with this code
"and then simply include this mixin
"in these two selectors?"
Now, let me show you that result is actually different.
First let me save it.
I will see the compiled CSS now.
So this is what happened actually.
It actually created this block of code,
which in practice looks the same way it did before.
So we have this button-main-link and this button-hot-link
together again just as we had before.
But that's no problem.
We're still following the Don't Repeat Yourself principle
because what matters is the source code that we write
and not the compiled final CSS code.
It's not a problem if the same code
appears multiple times in the compiled final file.
But in the source code, that's the one
that we should keep DRY,
so with Don't Repeat Yourself in mind.
So what happened here, in fact, was
that it's really different than a mixin.
This code was in fact not copied to here,
but what happened was that this selector here
was basically copied here.
So if this was a mixin, then all this code
would have been copied here into this selector,
into this one, and here into this one.
So with a mixin, that code would now be here.
But with an extend, it's the other way around.
What happens is that the selector is copied here
to this rule.
So now we have button-main-link and button-hot-link in here,
in this selector.
So this is what we have.
So although they look like they're doing the same,
they're in fact fundamentally different
in the way they work behind the scenes.
Now you should only ever use extends
if the rules that we're extending
are inherently and thematically related.
That's the case with these buttons, right?
They are really related.
So that's not going to cause a maintenance problem
further down the road.
Now personally, I'm not such a big fan of these extends.
Whenever I can, I prefer to just use mixins
to do this kind of stuff.
But in this particular example,
actually the extend would be the correct tool
to do this,
because again, these two buttons
where we used the extends, they are actually related.
Now, if we wanted to extend, like, this link here
and then maybe the nav element
and then also the navigation li elements,
now, then we would mix all these unrelated selectors,
these unrelated elements, all together.
And that wouldn't be a good practice.
So again, just use extends when the selectors
or the elements that you are extending
are actually pretty related to one another.
Okay, once again I want you to review
all the code that we wrote
as well as the final compiled CSS code
so that you understand what's going on here.
What you will notice is that, for example,
the function and the mixin,
they will, just like the variables,
they will not produce any final CSS code, of course,
because their only purpose is to help us writing our code.
After reviewing this, you will then understand
how variables, nesting, mixins,
extends and functions work in SASS.
At least it should give you a pretty good overview.
Of course, from now on in the project,
we are going to use only SASS,
which is going to make our life a lot easier,
especially in conjunction
with the block element modifier methodology.
But I'm gonna talk about that later,
when we continue with the project.
So take a look at the code right now,
and see you next time.