All right, now before we start
really building the rest of the Natours project,
let's just quickly review the three basic
principles of responsive design.
I'm pretty sure that many of you are
already familiar with these,
but I want to make 100% sure that we're all
on the same page before diving deep into this project.
So, the first, let's say, ingredient for responsive design
is to use fluid grids and layouts.
And what this means is that we use percentages
rather than pixels for all layout related length,
and especially width.
We do this, of course, in order to allow
the content to easily adapt to the current view port
that the user is using to browse the website.
The next ingredient are flexible and responsive images.
It's necessary to mention this aspect
because images behave a bit different than text content.
Because they do not scale automatically
as we change the view port and so we need to ensure
that they also adapt nicely to the current view port.
Usually we make images flexible by defining
their dimensions in percentages rather than
fixed units like pixels.
Plus, images usually make up the biggest part
of our website's size, in terms of megabytes,
and so we should optimize the images for different width,
which is something we're gonna do later
when we talk deeper about responsive images.
All right, and the last piece of the puzzle,
because fluid grids and layouts
and flexible images alone aren't enough,
are media queries, which allow us to change styles
on certain view port width, which are called breakpoints.
So, basically, media queries allow developers
to create different versions of a website
for different types of devices, okay?
Now, moving on and taking a closer look
at the first aspect that we talked about,
so fluid grids and layouts.
In modern web design there are currently
three major ways of laying out a webpage or app.
So, for a long time we have been using float based layouts
where we simply put a bunch of boxes
side by side, using floats, simple as that.
This method is still being used in 2017
and it's still how I personally layout my designs today.
And that's because the alternatives are still
not 100% supported by all browsers.
So, about these modern alternatives,
I'm talking about Flexbox and, even more modern,
CSS grid technology.
And you've probably heard of these, right?
So, while Flexbox offers an amazing way
of laying out elements in a one dimensional row,
CSS grid is perfect for creating the overall layout
of a page in a fully-fledged 2D grid,
so two-dimensional grid.
These are great technologies, as I was saying,
and they will make our life a lot easier
in the future, but as of 2017,
I'm not sure we should use them in production.
The thing is that the layout is the single most
fundamental aspect of our design,
and so if a browser does not support a technology
like Flexbox or CSS grid, then that's a major
problem and can ruin our entire designs.
If we choose to only rely on these
new technologies, of course.
So, for all these reasons, we're going to use
float layouts for this project, simply because
this is still used everywhere and will be
used for a long time and so you need
to really know how it works.
But, since you bought the most advanced
CSS course on the market, you will of course
also learn Flexbox and CSS grid.
Not in a Natours project though,
but in future projects later in the course.
So, the next project will be about Flexbox
and a third and last project will be with CSS grid.
So, moving forward in the future,
you will always have to know how to use
all of these three layout types,
because that's really where CSS is moving right now.
For the ones of you who are familiar with JavaScript,
this is a bit like the older JavaScript versions and ES6.
These days you really need to know both JavaScript versions,
because even with ES6 around by now,
you're still going to see a lot of the older ES5
around for a long time.
All right, and that's enough for one lecture.
See you in a second, in the next video.
Back to coding.