This lecture is called
A Brief Intro to the Command Line.
Yeah, you heard that right.
There comes a time in every web developer's life
where you have to learn at least the basics
of the command line.
I know that many, many people are afraid of the command line
for some reason.
I was afraid myself some years ago, I admit that.
But now I love the command line
and really can't live without it.
A so can't any serious web developer.
It's just part of the job.
Now in our case, in this project,
that is because we now want to install
and compile SASS locally and we're gonna do all of that
in the command line.
So you need to know at least the basics,
like moving around in the file system,
creating files and folders, copying files
and stuff like that.
Believe me, it's really easy and at some point,
it even becomes fun because you're gonna look
like a real pro, so that's really cool.
Now if already know this stuff, if you're already familiar
with it, using the command line, then please feel free
to move on to the next lecture as you're probably
not gonna learn anything new here.
But for the rest of us, let's now jump into a command line.
If you're on a Mac, you can just open up
the app called terminal and then you're there.
Maybe it looks different to you,
maybe it's white or something,
but it's essentially the same.
I'm gonna increase this a little bit
so that you can actually see what I'm doing here.
All right, so this is how it works on a Mac.
If you're watching this video on Windows,
which is probably most of the people watching this course,
then you can just right click on the start button
and from there, select the command prompt.
So in Windows, it's called command prompt.
Actually some of the commands are different
and some are the same.
Each time they are different in Windows,
then of course I'm gonna tell you, okay?
So keep paying attention to that.
Now the fundamental aspect of the command line,
is that you're always in a folder.
We use commands to move inside the folder structure
to create files, to move files, to create folders
and all of that stuff.
Right now, I'm here in the home folder.
If I want to see the contents of that folder,
I simply type ls and then hit return.
On Windows, this is different.
On Windows, it's dir, which stands for directory.
So on Windows, don't type ls, type dir.
These are the files or the folders
that are in my home folder.
So applications, documents, library, music,
desktop, downloads, movies and pictures.
For you, it's probably gonna look different,
that's because each system is different.
Now if I wanted to move inside of one of these folders,
then I type cd, which stands for change directory,
and then the name of the folder.
So I write desktop if I want to move to the desktop.
Until now, you can see that here it actually says desktop
and so now we're in a different folder.
Now I can do ls again, to see what's in that folder
and on Windows, don't forget it's dir.
So what I have in here is the Nators folder.
If you take a look at the desktop, that's true
so in here is the Nators folder.
Now if I want to to go back to where I was,
I simply type cd.. and that moves me up
in the folder structure so I'm back to the home folder,
which on a Mac is called this weird symbol here.
So if I type ls now, I am back to what I had before up here.
Right?
Okay, let's suppose I want to move back to the desktop.
I write cd and I start writing d and the e
so now I can hit tab and it will auto complete the name.
That's because they're now on a folder or file in here
which starts with de.
So it knows that this is the only folder
that I can go to and so it auto completes this for me.
So I'm back at the desktop and now I can go to the folder
that I know was there, which is called 1 Natours.
I write cd1, hit tab and it's already there.
And now I'm in the project folder
which we have been working in.
So ls, just as he was in there, and we have the CSS folder,
the IMG folder and the nx.html.
This terminal window is already getting
really crowded for texts, so I can just write clear
and return and it clears up my window.
This is just for aesthetical reasons.
Actually this auto complete function also works on command.
So if I start writing cle, then it already knows
that I want to write clear, so that's it.
Now imagine that in here, in my project folder,
I want to create a new folder for JavaScript.
I can use the command mkdir,
which stands for make directory.
Then, just a name, js and with that,
we created a new directory.
But not ever still in the Natours directory, right?
So let's see, but actually it is there.
So we successfully created a directory.
So let's move into it, so cdjs and we're there.
Now we're in the JavaScript folder.
Let's suppose you want to create a bunch of files.
You could, of course, go to our text editor
and create each of these files one by one.
But we can also use the terminal,
which I think is a lot easier.
You just write the command touch
and on Windows, it's called edit, I believe.
And so then you can write the names
of the files that you want.
Let's say script.js and you can put multiple here
so index.js and test.js.
Hit return and that's it.
Let's now check it out and, in fact,
they're all there.
We can, of course, confirm this in the file system here
so, of course, the JavaScript folder is here
and the three files are there as well.
Another thing that we can do is
to copy or to move files, of course.
Let's say that we actually want the index.js file,
not in here but in the project folder,
in the main project folder.
What we can do is to say cp and on Windows
it's called copy, then just the name of the file, index
and see how I did the (mumbles), so it auto completed,
automatically completed the file name for me
so copy, index.js which is the name of the file
and then the directory where we want it to copy.
If we want the project folder which is one layer above,
we simply type .. and .. always means the folder
that is above.
Remember how we wanted to move up in the file system?
We used cd.. so that's the same.
So .. always means the folder which is above
in the file system.
What this is gonna do, is to copy the file
into the folder above.
All right, let's check it out.
Index.js is still here, and if you're now going up
and check what's in there, then here, the index.js file
is also in there,
so great.
Now suppose we want to move one of the files
that is in the js folder.
Let's go there, let's take a look.
So now we want to move the script.js file also
into the project folder.
So we simply type mv, or on Windows, move.
Now it's the same thing, so let's just say script..
The difference is that the file should be gone
from this folder, so ls
and yeah, it's actually no longer there.
If we now check in the projects folder, one level above
and check it out, ls, then it's indeed there.
So that's the one that we just moved here.
Let's clear this up.
So I actually already showed you a lot of stuff.
Let's just now remove a file, so I'm again
going to move into the js folder, so cdjs
and since I already copied the index.js file
to the project folder so the folder above,
let's just delete it and nothing is simple in that,
because we simply have to write rm and then index.js.
And that's it, and sorry, I forgot to say
that in Windows it's called del, del for delete.
Is not rm, rm is just on a Mac or on Linnux
because it's also running UNIX.
Now please be careful with this rm, with this removing,
because this doesn't go to the trash bin.
No, it's really deleted from your computer.
You cannot get it back, so always use this with great care.
Let's all look if this actually worked, and yeah.
So all that's left here is a test.js.
Maybe we also don't need this file anymore,
so let's just delete it as well.
Or even better, we could to delete the entire folder.
Let's try that, okay?
Let's go back to the folder, and then rm
and then the js folder.
This didn't work because js is not a folder
so we have to do it in a different way.
So how does it work, at least on a Mac?
On Windows, I'm actually not pretty sure
how it's gonna work but don't worry
because it's also not really important.
If we move a directory to a folder,
it's actually pretty much the same.
All you have to do is rm, and then you basically
(mumbles) and option, like this, so dash and then r,
which stands for recursive, which simply means
that it's gonna delete all the files
and then also the folder.
And now, like this, it's gonna work.
So the js folder is now gone,
and let's actually confirm it, and yeah,
we're back to the index.html and the img folder.
Just to clear up all the work that we did,
let's also delete these two files here.
So now we're back to the initial situation
that we started with.
rnindex.js, and then script.js.
Then again, please be careful before hitting return
on this one, because these files, they are gone forever.
If you accidentally typed index.html,
that index.hml file will be gone forever,
you cannot get it back.
So please be careful that the file names you wrote here
are absolutely correct.
Adjust the files you have created and are empty here, okay?
In my case, everything's correct so I'll hit return,
and now the files are gone.
One last thing I want to show you.
This one, I'm also not sure if it works in Windows.
Let's go into the img folder and now let's simply
open one up, these images because here, on the Mac at least,
and in UNIX, you can simply write open, for example
on .jpg and this then going to open the program
in which we usually watch the images.
And that's actually it.
I think this is enough to actually show you
how the command line works.
Now what I want you to do to practice this,
is to just create a new folder called command line
on your desktop, then in there create
a couple of folders and then create a couple of files there.
Maybe you can also copy it around, or move them around,
and do all the kind of stuff that we did here in this video,
so that you get some practice and don't forget immediately
what we just did here.
So, this is enough for this video, this should give you
a good enough grasp of the command line
so now we're good to go
and install SASS in the next lecture.