In this lecture you will learn
what the new fractional unit is
and why it is so useful in CSS Grids.
So first off I want to show you that we can do a bit better
than having to define all of these rows here
one by one.
So image that we had five rows
each of them with 150 pixels.
It wouldn't be really helpful to having to define
all of them one by one like this, right.
That's why instead in CSS Grid
we get a new function called repeat.
So let me show it to you, how it works.
So all we have to do is to write repeat
then the number of rows or columns that we want.
So two and then we want both
with 150 pixels and that's it.
So you'll see that we're back to having two rows here,
each of them with 150 pixels.
So that is exactly the same
as writing 150 and 150 as we had before,
and the same of course could be done down here.
So let's get rid of this,
repeat three and 150 pixels.
So let's see, and all right.
It looks just as before.
Now image we want it to have the third column
with 300 pixels and not 150.
How would you do that?
Well very simple actually.
So just change this one here to two
and then we can add whatever we want here.
So let's say 300 pixels
and let's wait, and here we are.
So what this does is that basically
where it says repeat two
it creates these two column tracks
with 150 pixels each and then
the third one with 300 pixels, right.
So remember again from the first lecture
that these are called the tracks, right.
So what we do here is to create two tracks
for the rows and three tracks for the columns, right.
So again, this is a track here,
this is a track, this one is a track,
and here and here.
Now what if you wanted to make this last column here
occupy the rest of our red container,
because we see right now there's
a lot of empty space here still, right.
So how could we fill this up?
So this is a bit similar to Flexbox
where we had, remember, the flex property
which if we would set it to one
it would basically expand and occupy all the possible space.
Now here in Grid we don't have a property like that,
but we have a similar functionality.
So let me show you how.
So what we're going to use
is the brand new unit that was introduced
with CSS Grids, which is called a fractional unit.
So I can write one fractional unit like this.
So fr and what it does is that it expands
to all the space that it can occupy.
So in this case it occupies all the remaining space.
Okay, does that make sense?
So let's take a look again at what happens here.
So we defined the three column tracks.
So the first one will have 150 pixels,
the second one 150 as well,
and the last one is one fractional unit.
The fractional unit represents
a fraction of the available space
and so it takes all of that up
when we set it here to one fr.
Okay, so fr is very, very handy.
Let me actually show you a different way of using it,
so a different application, let's say.
So let's create some new column tracks here.
So I'm commenting out these ones so that you can keep them
in the code for reference.
So grid template, columns
and let's say we want all of the three columns
to have the same size.
How do you think we would do that?
Well we can use our repeat function.
Say we want three tracks each of them with one fr,
and that's it.
So again, one fr
is a fraction of the available space.
In this case each of them, each of these three column tracks
has the same width, right.
So each of them is one fr.
So with this we can divide the entire space
in three parts.
Okay, does that make sense?
Maybe to understand it even better
let me show it to you in another way yet.
So let's say we want the first one
to be one fractional unit,
the second one two fractional units,
and the last one one fractional unit as well.
So what do you think will happen?
Okay, and so that's the result.
So you see that this one here the one in the middle,
the column in the middle, the second one
is now double the size of the first one and the last one.
So why is that?
Well that's because two is double of one.
So all the empty space here is divided
and then two of the fractions are assigned
to the second column and then one
is assigned to the first one
and one fraction is assigned to the last one.
Let's actually inspect this here
so we can get the sizes.
So the first one you see that it has
235 pixels of width.
So the second one should have double,
which should be 470, right.
So let's take a look if that's true,
and yeah, so you see it's 470
width and 150 height.
So that's exactly as predicted,
and of course the last one is 235.
We can of course take this even further.
So let's set this one to three.
So what's going to happen now?
Of course it's going to get even bigger,
because now the available space
is basically divided into five parts,
three for the column in the middle
and one for the left and one for the right column, right.
So you see that this fractional unit
can actually be very, very helpful, right.
That's exactly why it was developed specifically
for CSS Grids.
We can of course also put this one here two three fr.
So now these two are both three times bigger
than this first one, right.
Now you can play around with this if you want,
so to become a bit more familiar with it,
because there's actually a lot to explore, right.
So let's now set this back to one
and let's experiment with something else.
For example let's set this one to 50%,
because of course we cannot only use pixels
and fractional units,
we can use all kinds of units here
and percentage is no exception.
So right now I set it to 50%.
So let's inspect the width of this element here
and so you see that it has 500 pixels,
which is exactly 50% of the 1,000 pixels
that the container has, right.
So you see it has 1,000 pixels of width
and so this item here with 50%
so that this entire column has now 500 pixels.
So what we see immediately here from that
is that this percentage unit here
doesn't take the gap into account.
Okay, so basically it takes 50% off the entire width
and then the rest is for the other columns,
but also for the gap.
So let's increase for example here this to
80 just to see what happens
and then you'll see that the first column
stays exactly the same and the second and the third column
they are the ones that become a bit narrower,
because now we need more space here for the gap, right.
So the remaining space that's left
is of course divided between these two,
because they both have a one fractional unit,
so this one and this one as well.
If I put this one to two, again,
you can guess what will happen and so yeah
the third column is twice as wide as the second one.
Okay, but let's put this back to thirty.
I will actually comment this one out here
so that you can also keep this code
and then put it back to what we had before.
So repeat, and then I want to make the three columns
all with the same width.
So for that, again, we use our
fr trick, so fractional unit.
So this fractional unit here is something
that you will see all the time
when using CSS Grids, okay,
especially for defining the column tracks,
because this is really handy,
but actually this also works as well here for the rows.
So if we defined like a height for this container.
Let me just very quickly show it to you.
So let's see the height
of the container should be 1,000 pixels,
so not 100, 1,000 of course.
So you see that now it comes all the way down here
and if we now work to put one fr here
then, let's wait for it.
Okay, now you see that each of the rows occupies
all the space it can in order to fill up
the entire height of the container, right.
So the fr, of course, doesn't only work on columns,
but I think it's way more useful there.
Okay, and you will see it and you will use it
more on the columns.
So let's put it back to where it was
and comment out this code here,
because this here is exactly what we want.
All right, so I hope that the
fractional unit here made a lot of sense to you
and if you need to experiment some more with it
then please go ahead, experiment,
try to inspect the width of the columns like it did before,
and make sure that you understand
what the fractional units really represents, okay.
Once you're done with that,
once you really get it down
then we can move on to the next lecture.
We're going to learn how to actually position
these grid items exactly where you want them on the grid,
because right now all of these items
they were just automatically placed
in the order in which we have them here in the source code,
but we can, of course, change that, right.
So once you get this part really down
let's move on together to the next lecture.