So, welcome to our 2nd project in this course.
And without further ado, let me actually show it to you.
And so here it is, this project is called trillo and
it is a fictional all in one booking app.
Okay?
So, the idea is that a user can book a hotel, a flight,
a car, and a tour all in one platform.
Now, of course we are not going to build this app itself,
so in all functionality, but we're going to code this
user interface here.
So all of this app that you see here.
So here in this navigation you can see that we're
right now browsing the hotel section and so here
on this side, you have a hotel overview.
So, some pictures, then the name.
Some stars here.
And then an overview where you have a list
with a couple of features.
And then here on the right side, you have some reviews.
Okay?
Then, down here we have a section where we can book and
then you have this nice hover effect on this button, okay?
And here you probably already saw here on the navigation,
we also have this nice hover effect going on, so this
one here, and the here at the top
we have like this header bar where you have the logo,
then the search bar, and then basically here are
bookmarks, some chat, and the name of the user.
So, that is our project.
So, the main focus of course is on flexbox here.
But, you're also gonna learn a couple of new stuff,
like doing this cool animations here and how to use
these icons because these are actually SPG icons and that's
something really cool and so I'm gonna show you
how to use these.
And so in general, you're gonna learn flexbox, but
also a couple of other techniques that I'm gonna show you.
And once again, I tried to make this a really beautiful,
really modern looking app, so that you not only learn
how to code and not only learn flexbox, but so that you
also get some inspiration for building a beautiful
web app and also that you have some nice thing to show
off after this course.
And so I hope that you really like the look of this app
of this interface.
I know that I really like it.
Okay, I've put a lot of work in this so that you can
be proud of your work by the end of the project.
So, all we need in order to get started with this project
is our starter files that you can download from the course
if you didn't already.
And then just open up that starter files
in your code editor.
So, I already have the starter files here on my desk top.
Okay, so this folder and I also have it opened up already
in vs code.
Okay?
And so, here it is.
So that is the bare bones, html structure just like
we hade in our previous project where all we have is
the title here.
So trillo, your all in one booking app and then the font
which this time is open sans here and then the style
which is already included in here.
Now what we also have is a sass folder because once
again we are going to use sass here.
Okay?
And then an empty sass file where all we have is these
color definitions here.
So, what I also have here is of course images.
So that's the one we're gonna use.
The css, but this is still empty because we're going to
then compile our sass file and so that one is still empty.
Then, I also have this package jason file from
our last project
And so that's actually now start
by changing this one here.
Okay.
And to adapt it to our needs for this project.
Because I don't want to write all of these scripts here
over again and so I just copy this file and so we
can use it here in this project as well because
it's actually really the same thing.
Okay.
So again, we have a main.scss file which is going
to compile to style.css.
We want our devserver here and we want the watch css
to run together with devserver.
And so we have the start script here, right?
Remember that one?
So that is our development set up.
And then down here we also have the build process which
in fact is also exactly the same.
And well actually it's not because we don't have the
icon fonts here.
Okay.
So, there's not really anything to concatenate,
so let's take this one out and then the input
to this one here is style comp.
Right?
So this build process here is a bit smaller than
the one in the previous project.
So, we're gonna compile the sass code here,
then prefix it here, then compress, and yeah.
So our build process is these 3.
So the concat has to go of course.
So compile, prefix, and then compress.
Okay?
But, we're gonna talk about this later because we're
only gonna use this build process in the end
of this project.
Okay?
Okay, so this is also different.
So, let's just say that it's the trillo app.
Okay, it doesn't really matter.
Okay.
So let's actually open up the console here.
And here I'm just gonna write trillo.
Just to see if everything's working, okay.
And so.
The terminal.
So, let me see what we have here.
And so, in my case I have to navigate to the desk top.
And trillo.
And so now this is my project folder.
Just to make sure, it has the css, mg, and sass folders,
and then index and package.jason.
Okay?
So, please do the same.
Navigate to your project folder just like I did.
And then we can run npm, run, start.
Just like we did with our previous project.
And something's not working and of course it's
not working because we actually have to first, install
our packages, okay?
And now remember what I told you in one of the
first lectures where we talked about npm.
So back then, I told you that usually we only copy
the package.jason file, but we don't copy
the node sass folder which is that folder which
contains all of these packages here.
Right?
So, we never copy that folder and share it.
Instead, we just install all the packages over again.
So, we say npm.
Install.
And so, now it gets all of these packages and installs
them in a new node modules folder.
Okay.
Clear.
Now we can write a command again.
So, npm.
Run.
Start.
And yeah, here we go.
So now, it's really working.
Right?
Let's just do some css here or some sass.
Like our global reset.
We can say, margin 0, padding 0.
And then we can also say and just to test, background color.
And then set it to this background color, okay.
Just to see if our sass is working fine, okay.
Okay, so it reloaded the page and
it compiled our sass code.
And so everything is working and so we're now ready
to actually start building the project.
So, let's do exactly that, right in the next lecture.