So let's now continue building
our animated button.
So this is the final page and the final button.
And what we're missing here is this white part
that looks like it zooms out to infinity when we hover,
and it comes back when we hover out.
See.
So this nice effect.
It's not really necessary, of course, to add this.
But it was a great opportunity to show you the power
of CSS and of pseudo-elements.
So let me show you how we do it.
So as I said, we're gonna use pseudo-elements.
And pseudo-elements allow us
to style certain parts of elements.
For example, the after pseudo-element that we're
gonna use adds like a virtual element
right after the element that we're selecting.
And we can then style that element.
And so using this after pseudo-element
can be really powerful to do some cool effects.
And once you master it,
you're gonna want to use it all the time.
So, let me just add
the after pseudo-element.
So the trick here is to add an element
that looks exactly like the button that we already have,
but we put it behind the button.
And when we hover out of the button,
then this hidden pseudo-element
amazingly goes back behind the button.
So let's see how we can do this.
First, in order for an after pseudo-element
to actually appear on the page,
we need to specify its content property.
So that's always necessary.
It doesn't matter what the content is.
It can even be empty like we're gonna do here,
but we have to specify it.
Otherwise it's not going to appear.
And the same thing with the display property.
So we have to specify the display property.
And in this case, we're gonna say it's an inline block
because the button that we have is also an inline block.
And so, again, we want it to be exactly the same.
We want it to look the same.
So we want to have a height of 100%.
And we want to have a width of 100% as well.
And this works because the after pseudo-element
is basically treated like a child of the button.
And so if we say that we want the height to be 100%,
that's 100% of the width of the button.
And so suppose that the button has 100 pixels
of height and 50 pixels of width.
And so this after pseudo-element
will have the exact same dimensions if we set it to 100%.
Now the border rate is, should also be the same.
100 pixels.
So something really big.
And now, we also want it to be white.
But in order for it to be white,
we actually should make another after pseudo-element
but this time for the button, right.
So let's put it here.
And after.
And so background color
should be white.
Alright.
Now let's just see on our page if it actually shows up.
So right now it still looks like it's part of our element.
And so we should change that.
So what we wanna do,
remember,
is to put it behind our actual button.
So how can we do that?
And we use absolute positioning.
So position and absolute.
And then we just say it should be zero from the top
and zero from the left.
Now remember that this absolute positioning
needs to have a reference.
And the reference is the first element
with the relative position that it can find.
Now in this case it would be the header
because remember we did that before.
But we don't want it to be the header.
We want it to be hidden after the button.
And so, the reference should be the button.
Therefore, what we have to do
is to set the position property of the button to relative.
Alright.
And so now it should be hidden behind the button.
Now one more thing that we have to do
is to set the z index.
And we will put it to minus one.
So remember the z index defines the position
of the elements if they are one on top of another.
And so this one has minus one
and so it's definitely behind the button.
Now since it's hidden,
I cannot really show it to you on the page now.
But we're gonna see it in a little bit.
So when do we actually want to see it.
We want to see it when we hover the button.
So what we're gonna do is to write it like this.
And this may seem a bit complicated,
but it's actually not.
So, when we hover the button,
then we want some certain styles
for the after pseudo-element.
So this looks a bit weird but it makes total sense.
So this is an after pseudo-element
only when we have the button on the hover state.
And what do we want to happen?
We want it to be bigger.
Right. Remember.
We want the element to grow and to fade out.
And so, what we first do is to use once again,
the transform property.
And I told you it was really important and,
so yeah, it is.
This time we do a scale.
So what scale does is to simply
increase the element.
So if we do scale two,
then it will appear double the size that it had before.
So now we can actually check if it's working alright.
So reload.
And, whoa.
There it is.
So this white part that you see
outside here is the pseudo-element
that becomes visible as soon as we hover over the button.
Let's actually make it a different color here,
like red,
just so that you can see the difference.
And whoa.
Now it's everything red.
But that's not a problem.
For some reason the original button is also getting red.
But we still can be sure the pseudo-element is behind
the button because we still can see the text.
And so that means that the original button
is still on top of the pseudo-element.
Let's put it back to white, where it was.
And we don't want to scale it this much.
So let's just say one point five.
And we also want this to be animated just like before.
So where do we have to put the transition property?
Exactly.
We do it on the initial state.
In this case the initial state is of course
this after pseudo-element.
So we say
transition,
and again I'm going to use all here,
and then use, let's say, point four seconds in this case.
So here we had point two,
but we want this one to take a little bit longer.
Now what also happens,
is that the element actually fades out.
So opacity zero.
That's the trick for fading something out,
is going to opacity zero.
We did that before in our other animation
in the lecture before,
and so here we're doing it again.
So opacity zero sets something to invisible basically.
So let's check out
if it works already.
Yeah, that's actually it.
It's already working, right?
It comes back.
It goes out and it comes back.
So, really cool, right?
Now we can make this a a little bit better
because if you look closely at the top of the button,
and you see that it looks really small.
So the part that's fading out is like really small.
Take a look.
So let's do this a bit better.
And actually with this I can show you
that there are different scales.
So scale, without any epsilon here,
simply scales the entire element.
But we can do scale x,
and then that's how it's gonna scale on the x direction.
On the x axis.
And here we want to do one point four.
And now scale, epsilon as you can imagine,
in the other direction.
So let's put one point six here.
So they are different scales.
Just like they are different translates,
or rotates, or other functions that we can put
here in the transform.
So, let's check it out.
And, yeah.
So now it looks a bit better.
So, really cool.
There's just one thing left here because,
take a look here what happens when we load the page.
You saw this.
This came up moving from the bottom.
So first, we saw these two elements coming in,
like we coded before.
And then the button came up
from the bottom to this position.
So let's very quickly code up
another animation for that.
And we're gonna put it here after this one.
Actually I'm gonna copy it
'cause it's pretty similar.
So move in,
let's say bottom now,
from the bottom.
This time we don't need any 80%
because it's just from one point to the other.
And now I'm going to leave it to you to specify,
let's see,
what we should put here.
So pause the video,
and try to figure out how this should look like.
So, did you figure it out?
How should the button be positioned
right in the beginning before the animation starts?
It should be a bit lower than its current position, right?
Because it's moving in from the bottom
to its original position.
And so we can do translate epsilon this time.
And put something like 30 pixels in here.
That's because remember,
for the epsilon direction
it goes like this.
So from top to bottom.
So if we want to move it down, it's a positive value.
Alright.
And let's now actually use this animation.
Now again there will be multiple buttons like this.
But I only want this animation to happen
on this particular button.
And so what I'm gonna do
is to create a new class on the button.
So button,
animated.
And only this button will have this class.
Okay?
So let's put it here.
Button.
Animated.
And then in here I will put the animation.
So animation,
and I'm going to use the shorten property
that I showed you before.
And now it's called move in bottom.
And let's use point five, second animation.
And we're gonna use an ease out this time.
Okay?
Now plus what we're gonna do is to have a delay.
So we don't want to start it at the same time as the others.
We want it to start slightly later.
So maybe not one entire second,
which is the animation time of the other two animations,
but maybe just 75% of that.
So .75 seconds.
So I told you that we could put all of
these values in the same animation property.
So this is the animation name, the animation duration,
the animation timing function,
and the animation delay.
So let's take a look at what happens here.
Alright, so you saw that.
Actually the button was visible
before the animation happened.
Let's take a look again.
So it stays visible and then it starts.
Now what could we do in order to prevent this.
We could simply put these initial states on the button.
But that would be highly impractical, right?
Wouldn't make much sense.
So there is another property related to animations.
And this one is called animation fill mode
So animation fill mode.
And now we can set it to backwards.
And what this does,
is that it will automatically apply
the styles up to zero percent before the animation starts.
So, again, these styles will now be applied
before the animation starts simply by using the
animation fill mode and set it to backwards.
So, pretty amazing right?
So it's really simple, simple solution to this problem.
And so let's try it again.
And, yeah, so here it works.
Alright.
And that's it for this lecture,
and actually for this section.
So, we've come a long way so far,
and we already coded a bunch of really cool stuff I think.
We already have the header already completed.
Only what's missing here is this navigation
but it's a bit too complex for now,
so we're gonna leave it for another time.
But for now, we've come far enough with this project
that it's now time to show you a little bit of
how CSS actually works behind the scenes.
So I have a couple of really great lectures
coming up which I spent a lot of time building for you.
But they will be really insightful and helpful,
I hope.
So,
review what we just did in this section maybe.
Or you can just move on to the next one right now.
Anyway, see you next time.