This is the second part
of building the story section.
So let's continue.
And again this is how it looks like.
So we have like this background image here
in the back of course.
And then we have these two images here.
This one here kind of in the center
with this couple here that supposedly just
built a new house for themselves which is this one.
And so this one is on top
and it actually also overlaps a bit
this part of the section
and goes all the way in this here.
And I think this creates kind of a modern
and catchy look.
Okay.
So that's why I went for that.
So how are we gonna do this?
Well, we're just gonna create a (mumbles) grid,
basically occupying this entire area here
and then we're gonna just position these two images
on there.
We could do this in many many different ways.
I choose to just do it like this,
because again,
this is a grid course
and so that's what I'm gonna do here,
using css grids.
So first to mark up,
which is just very simple,
so img and the class is simply story,
img and this one is number one
and the source is image
and story-1,
and the alternative text
is just
Couple with new house let's say,
and then let me just copy this,
story-2
and
yeah.
Let's just say that this is a new house
and change this one to number two as well.
Okay.
And that is it.
So let's now go ahead
to our story file.
So this one is the pictures part.
So the container of this images is the pictures.
So let's now turn this into a grid container.
So,
display grid
and let's also set the styles for the images.
So it's called img--1
and img--2.
So let's set both of them
for now to width 100%.
Okay.
So that is kind of what we always do.
We always should specify a width and percentages
for images so that they save flexible.
Right we're then going to change this here
maybe a bit later,
but for now that's good.
So let's take a look at that.
And so right now of course,
they occupied the entire container.
So the container is this one here.
And so they occupy 100% of that.
But that is of course not the result
that we want to see in the end.
So again let's create a grid here
and then position these items in there.
So and what I want to do
is to create a six by six grid,
and let me show you why
here in the final example.
So with six by six,
basically this space here is one column,
this space here is another column
and then this one here is the other four columns.
And so with this,
basically we have 4/6 of the container as image
and the other 2/6 so 1/3
as the remaining space.
Right.
So basically 66% of this container will be the image
and then 33% will be the remaining space.
So 16.7% here on each side.
On this side and on this side.
Okay.
We could've done it completely different way
but I want it to be like this.
I want a 2/3 of the width of this to be the image.
Okay.
And so a six by six container,
it goes the same thing then
can applied to the rows as well.
Okay.
So.
Very simple.
Grid-template-rows.
Repeat(6,1fr).
So again we use 1fr to create equally sized tracks.
So rows in this case and columns in this case.
Okay so,
let's take a look at that,
just to that we know where we want
to actually position them.
Oh and just see that now already these images
are occupying one grid cell
and no longer the entire parent container.
So where is that,
it's this one here.
You see it's a six by six grid.
And each of these images is now in one of the grid cells
occupying 100% of the width.
Okay so.
Now what do we want to do with this image here.
We want it to start here at the line number two
and going all the way to line number six.
And for the rows,
we want the same.
So going from number two to number six.
Okay.
So let's do that.
So grid-row:2/6
or we could use ban four but,
let's just do it like this.
And then grid-column the same two and six.
So let's now take a look at result.
And it looks like this.
And now what you see here
is kind of a weird behavior right?
And that's because this grid item here
doesn't really fit the grid area.
Okay.
And that is because it is an image.
So regular grid items,
like if this was just a div,
it would fill up it's entire grid area, right?
So this entire area here
that we defined.
But not images.
And that's because images are different.
In a sense that they have an intrinsic aspect ratio
associate of with them.
So meaning that it has some dimensions
and therefore also an aspect ratio.
And what happens is that the image always tries to keep
that aspect ratio,
even if we tell it that it should fill up
this entire grid area here.
So doesn't really do that,
instead it keeps its aspect ratio.
Now if you want this to be truly here in the center,
then we can simply set the align items property
to center right.
That's because,
remember the align items property aligns grid items
to their grid cells in the column access.
So if we do that,
here on the container of course,
align items set to center
and then it is centered in its grid area.
Okay.
So once more,
these properties like align and justify,
they're really useful and helpful
to know them in situations like this.
And you see that also it already happened up here
so this small image here is now also
centered vertically inside of its grid cell.
So next up is then this image here.
We want it to be like
kind of here in the center of this.
So starting like here from this middle point of the grid
and then expanding all the way to this side.
So we're gonna go from column number four.
So number four to seven,
and then from the row,
we go from line number four to line number six.
Alright.
So image number two,
grid-row
we go from four
to six,
and then for the column,
from four to seven,
I believe.
And so let's check that one out.
And yeah, that's right.
Okay.
Now,
here in this situation,
this actually overlaps it a little bit.
Right.
And how do we achieve that?
We'll it's actually quite simple
and we could do it in two ways.
We could use a transform and simply scale it up a little bit
but then it wouldn't really start here
in the middle here anymore.
Unless we then also define the transform origin
but that's a bit too much I believe.
And so let's simply change their width of the image.
So if we change this width to 115,
or something a bit bigger or smaller,
but a font that this one works really well
if we change it to this,
well then it's just going to
increase to the side.
And now we cannot really see it,
but if I inspected,
then you will see that it actually moved to that side.
Okay.
And so why can we now not see it?
Well it's just because of the z-index.
So we have to assign it a bigger z-index.
Any number really works here,
let's just use something big,
so something like 20 and then we should be good to go.
And indeed now it is on top
of this other element here on the side.
All right so looking good already.
Now let's just add a couple of shadows here
to these images.
So,
box-shadow
zero 2rem
then 5rem of blur.
And then an rgba of black,
with just .1.
And then the same here for the image number two.
And this one with .2.
Okay because this one here is actually overlapping
this lighter area.
And so otherwise people not see it at all.
Okay.
And now all we have to do is just this background area here,
which I want to do at the beginning,
but I just forgot about it.
So let's do that now.
So it is here in this pictures container of course.
So let's just background-image
url
and then we have to move up one level,
right because once this is compiled,
we are in the css folder
and from there we need to move up
in the global project folder
and then from there we go into img.
Img,
and then this one is called simply back.jpg.
Now this is actually not all,
because this is just the image like this,
but we have this overlay here.
In order to make it fit better into the overlook
and color scheme of our page right.
So like this it looks a bit out of place.
You know.
And so we need some overlay.
With some color in order to make it
look a bit more in place.
So for that we just use the linear-gradient trick.
Where we then use a color
and in this case our primary color
and give it some value here to make it 50% transparent.
Okay.
So this trick here with linear-gradient
is to give it to equal colors,
so basically the gradient goes from one color
to the other color.
So that is one background image on top
and then after that,
below it basically we have then the image.
Okay.
And so that should work now.
And indeed here it is.
So I hope that it made sense here with the positioning
of the elements into this grid.
Of course I could've had use absolute positioning
to position these images,
but I just want to do it like this,
to use a grid once more for this purpose.
And I think we created a quite a nice look here.
All right.
And so we already finished here with this
and next up
we're gonna tackle this next homes section here.
Okay.
So create these beautifully designed cards.
So let's move on now.