I wanted to do this in one or two lectures,
but I actually need a Part Three to explain
how CSS is parsed.
So this lecture is about inheritance
that we touched upon briefly before, but now we're ready
to really dive in.
So inheritance is a way of propagating property values
from parent elements to their children.
Once more, we have a very simple example here.
This time, we're going to determine what the line-height
off the child element will be.
Start by remembering from our previous lecture
that each and every CSS property must have a value.
Even if neither we, the developer nor the browser
do specify it.
In that case, there's no cascaded value, right?
So when processing certain property
for a certain element, such as line-height,
the first question that the CSS engine asks
is if there is a cascaded value.
And if so, then of course, that's the value that's used.
Now if there's no cascaded value, then the next question
is if the property can be inherited.
And that depends on each property.
There are some properties that are inherited
and others are not.
In the case of line-height, that property gets inherited,
as we can see from the property specification.
So if a property is inherited, then the value
of that property becomes the computed value
of it's parent element.
It's very important to note that the value
that gets inherited is not simply the 150%,
but the computed value.
In this case, that's 150% of 20 pixels, which is 30 pixels.
So the line-height, the child element,
will also be 30 pixels, not 150% of the 25 pixel font size.
Got it?
So again, it's not simply the declared value
that passed, but the computed value.
Now if it's a property that's not inherited,
like for example, padding, then the specified Value
will become the initial value
which is also specific to each property.
In the case of padding, that's just zero pixels
like we actually saw in the last lecture.
Again, you don't need to memorize these initial values
because they're all just rather intuitive.
Just like before, here's a quick summary
of what you need to know.
I guess the most important thing to know about inheritance
is that it's there and that it passes the values
for some specific properties from parents to children.
Again, if you just ignore the jargon,
inheritance is actually pretty straight-forward.
Inheritance allows the developers to write less code
and code that will be more maintainable.
Now in the specification for each and every CSS property,
you will find if the property
is automatically inherited or not.
As a rule of thumb, properties related to text are inherited
so properties like font family, font size, color, et cetera.
Other properties like margins or paddings
are, of course, not inherited
because that would just be extremely impracticable.
Just imagine setting a margin on some section of something,
and then suddenly all of the children would automatically
get the same margin.
That doesn't make any sense, right?
Now it's also important to remember that what gets inherited
is the computed value of a property
and not the declared value.
Also, inheritance of a property of course only works
if no one, neither the developer nor the browser,
declares a value for that property.
Okay, now something else I didn't mention yet
is that we can use the inherit keyword
to force the inheritance of a certain property.
I will actually show you that when we get back to coding.
Also, in the same way, the initial keyword can be used
to reset the property to it's initial value.
And that's actually it about inheritance.
Not hard at all, right?
So let's move on now.