Ready for another session on the Natours Project?
Then get ready to learn how to include
and use an icon font in a project.
You will also learn another way
of creating this "skewed section" design
that is all over our page,
like in our header.
So this non-rectangular design.
And plus, you are gonna learn
how and when to use the direct child selector.
So we have these four columns here going on.
And when we hover, we have this nice effect.
And then in each of these boxes,
we have the four features of this company,
so of Natours.
So Explore the World,
Meet Nature, Find Your Way,
and Live a Healthier Life.
And then below that is the text,
and here on top, an icon.
And you see this grading going on here,
just like we have in here.
So we're gonna do it the same way.
And you see this non-rectangular design here
that I was talking about earlier.
So it's here, and here, and so these lines.
But we're gonna leave that for the end.
Let's actually start by downloading and including
this icon font that we have here,
so that we can use some icons in our webpage.
And the icon font I'm using here
is called Linea Free Iconset.
So just head over to Linea.io,
and then in here you can simply download all sets.
And then just wait for the download to finish.
And so let's take a look at what we have here.
So you can take a look at all of these icons,
but what we want is actually here in this basics section.
So this basics icon pack,
and then we want a font.
We could just use images like these .png images here,
but that is not a good practice.
Because images do not nicely scale up and down
when we scale our webpage.
But if we have an icon font,
then these are vectors,
and then no matter how much we would zoom in on the page,
the icons will always remain nice and sharp and crisp.
And so no problem there.
We could also use this .svg format here.
And actually we're gonna do that in the next project,
but that's even more advanced than using an icon font.
So we're leaving that for the next project.
Okay?
So let's use this icon font here.
And so what we need is the style, so .css file,
and this fonts folder.
Because this is actually where the icons live.
So in this, linea-basic-10 font.
So let me just copy these two,
go to our desktop,
and then to our project folder.
Now I wanna head into css.
And this is where I am copying it.
And now let's just rename this one here to icon-font,
so that it's not too similar here to style.
Okay, and so that's it actually.
Now all we have to do is to, of course,
include it in the XML and our markup.
So let's do that very quickly.
And we'll actually do it here
before our custom CSS.
So link, and then the power of Emmet,
css, and icon-font.css.
And that's it,
our icon font is now included in the page.
Let's just very quickly take a look
at the CSS file,
so that we understand a little bit about
how this actually works.
So this starts by including these fonts
that are here in this fonts folder, right?
So these four fonts,
these are just different formats,
because different browsers can read different font formats.
And so we have to use all of these four,
so that the icon font is gonna work
on all of the browsers.
So what this does is here,
it includes all of these fonts.
And then it defines the font family
as calling "linea-basic-10".
And then basically what happens down here
is that this gives us one class for each of the icons,
which are included in this icon pack.
So it gives us all of these classes,
like icon-basic-accelerator,
icon-basic-alarm,
icon-basic-anchor,
and so on and so forth through all of these.
Now, it's not really important to understand how this works,
it doesn't really matter for us.
We just want to use this, okay?
I just wanted to very quickly give you an overview
about how this works.
So again, all of the fonts are included.
And then based on that font,
it will give us one class for each icon that we can use.
So all we have to do is to include this class,
and it will give us the icon.
Alright?
So let me show you how to do that.
But before, of course,
we need to start writing our section.
So we have a section,
and I'm gonna call it section-features.
Okay, and now in this section,
let me just demonstrate how we can use
the icons that we just included.
So we need to add one of the classes that I just showed you
to an element.
And it doesn't really matter what element it is.
And so it's become a convention to use the i element, okay?
And this doesn't stand for icon, okay?
Some people, they confuse it.
But this i doesn't stand for icon,
it actually stands for italic.
So in previous versions of HTML,
this i was used to make text italic, okay?
Now we no longer use it,
and so we can use the i for our icons.
So let's actually open the folder again
that we downloaded, from the Downloads.
Because in here we have an image,
where we have all our icons.
But well, they don't really have a name.
So, okay, it's not really useful.
But we can still open this icons reference.
And then in here,
it should then work.
So which one do we want to use?
We want to use, for example,
this world icon here.
And okay down here, here it is.
So basic-world.
So I just copy this name,
which is the class name.
And so class, basic-world,
and now let's take a look.
Well nothing really happened, okay.
Reload it again.
And let's go back, okay.
I remember that all of these icons,
they started with an icon prefix, right?
So icon-basic,
icon-basic-book, icon-basic-book-pencil.
So let's add that here, as well.
And on each icon font that you're gonna download,
it's always gonna be a bit different.
So you'll always have to experiment a bit with it.
But now you see it works,
so it's really small (chuckles) down here.
Here in the corner,
but I hope you see it.
So it is actually working.
Now all we have to do
is to actually write all of that markup,
so that it looks like this in the end.
So let's start by actually doing that.
Leave this here,
and we'll come back to it later.
So basically this is very simple, actually.
All we need here is a row with four columns in it.
And then each of these columns
can have a feature box in them.
So with Emmet again,
we do it like this.
.row, then col-1-of-4.
And I could actually do this four times now
to fill everything up at the same time.
But let's just do it like this,
only with one of the columns.
And actually I forgot the dot to make it a class.
And then in here,
let's put a feature-box.
Alright, and there it is.
And so this feature box will be one of these boxes here.
So remember that before,
so in this section here,
we wrote this content here directly into the column.
Remember that?
So here, we had this column in here.
And then in here, we had directly put these elements.
So the h3, the Ps, and so on.
Now this time, we're not doing it like that.
We're creating another box right in here.
And we do that,
first because we want to have more space
between them than the gutter,
but more importantly it's because we want this effect
to happen like this.
And so we want this entire feature box
to scale up when we hover it.
And it's better to then create a separate element for that,
rather than manipulating this kind of stuff on our columns.
So we never wanna touch these columns here, okay?
The code for the grid should remain unchanged,
no scaling on there,
no adding additional padding.
If you want anything like that,
we just add another box in there.
So what do we have in each of these boxes?
We have an icon,
and let's actually grab that one.
What's going on here, okay.
Then we have an h3, so a tertiary heading.
And you see that this one is exactly the same as this.
And so we can reuse this code, of course.
So h3.heading-tertiary,
Explore the world,
it's the first one.
And then after that,
it's simply a paragraph
called feature-box__text.
Alright,
and here we actually should add another class,
because it's a feature-box icon.
So feature-box is the name of the block here, okay.
And then icon is the name of the element.
As for this text,
let's just copy a bit of this text here.
And maybe that's enough already.
And so let's paste it in here.
Alright.
And so this should be enough already.
Now as you can already guess, probably,
this feature-box here should be a component,
so a building block that can be reused throughout our page.
So let's create a new folder for that.
I'm actually copying it,
so I can now just do it like this.
And then don't forget to include it.
Import, components, and feature-box.
Give it a save,
and then we can already close it again.
And here again, feature-box.
And that's it.
Now, the other selector is the feature-box __icon.
And the other one is the feature-box __text, I believe.
And so that should be enough.
Let me just take a look at how this looks in here.
And alright,
so we have the h3, the paragraph, and the icon,
which is still very small, of course.
But they're already sitting here nicely
in one of these columns.
So let's go back and close what we no longer need here,
typography.
Variables, we can keep open.
And now what I want you to do next,
or what we can do together next,
is to actually add this section here.
So the section about the feature-box.
So the section-features.
And let's start by add some padding.
So padding, let's say 20 pixels.
So 20rem, and then 0, left and right.
So it's really modern right now
to have really spacey websites,
with lots of wide space.
That's really modern and trendy right now.
And I think it looks great actually.
So another thing we have in this section here,
in case you haven't noticed yet,
is, once again we have one of these background images
with this grading going on.
Just like here.
And so instead of writing it all over again,
I am actually just going to copy it.
Because we already know how to do that.
So there's not really a need to do it all again.
So what we need is this background-image stuff here,
right.
And so here it is.
So we have linear-gradient
with this green color here.
Now, this color picker here no longer works
because of the SCSS variable.
But don't worry,
everything is right.
So the light green to the dark green to the right bottom.
Now what's different here is the image.
And this time it's called nat-4, nat-4.jpg.
And what we also want,
almost always, I would say,
is the background-size set to cover,
so it nicely covers the entire section.
Alright, let's take a look at that now.
So that's very nice already.
And it's good enough for now.
So let's continue now with these boxes here.
And then as the finishing touch,
we will skew the entire design
to make it look like this one here,
with these non-rectangular sides.
So, the feature-box.
We want it to be white,
and a bit transparent at the same time.
So let's do that.
So background-color.
And so we use an rgba.
Once again, color-white.
And then let's say we want 80 percent of it to be white,
with an opacity of 20 percent.
Because what this means is that
we can see through 80 percent,
and so the remaining 20 percent is
what you can see through the color.
Now the font size that we want is 1.5.
Because I experimented with 1.6rem,
but it's way too big, actually.
It doesn't look really natural,
it doesn't look good.
Now we also want some padding in these boxes.
So 2.5rem, so basically 25 pixels.
We want the text in them to be centered,
if you remember that.
And we want them to have a nice border-radius.
Really a small one,
so nothing too much,
because that would look weird and not modern.
But a very small one,
then again, looks modern.
And now finally, a box shadow.
Because that also is a huge design trend
that's going on right now,
and so that's why I included it in this course.
So you probably already know
that I care a lot about great design.
And that's why I build all my courses,
actually, around these cool designs.
And I try to make these projects
as attractive as possible to you,
so that it's more fun for you to code.
Alright.
So this is all pretty straight-forward and pretty easy.
It's nothing really new to you anymore.
And so, yeah, this looks pretty good already.
Well, what's missing here is to give this some more space,
just like we did up here.
And then to just format the icon.
So first, let's use the utility class that we used up here.
So we want this small margin at the bottom
going on here, as well.
So where is that?
Now yeah, so right here.
Okay,
and now we want to style the feature-box icon.
And so it's already here.
And so let's write some code for it.
First thing we want to do is to increase it.
And so remember that this is effectively a font.
And so we can say font-size,
in order to change the size of the icon.
So font-size: 6rem,
which is a lot,
but it actually is the correct size.
We wanted to add a margin to the bottom,
like 5 pixels, so .5rem.
And so let's now take a look at how it looks,
and what our goal is for this icon.
So I think I mentioned before that once again,
this has this really nice gradient here going on,
just like it has in here.
And do you remember how we do that?
Well, if you do,
then this is the challenge for this section.
So try to code up this gradient here,
just like we did before.
And so pause the video,
and I'll be waiting for you to do that.
So, did you manage to do it?
I really hope so.
Now I am not going to do it,
I will just copy (chuckles) what we did before.
So I'm a bit lazy here this time.
So it's here in the typography, I remember.
And it is here in the heading.
So, background-image.
Actually it starts in here,
because we want the gradient to go
from one side to the other only.
And then all of this.
Close it, put it here,
and it should already be enough.
So it's now an inline-block.
It has this background-image,
which is this gradient from green to green,
light to dark green.
And then it clips that gradient by the text.
And remember that once again,
we can do this because the icon font is text, in fact.
And so once again we can use color,
because it is text.
So let's check out if this is already working.
And indeed here it is,
so, great.
That's exactly how we want this to look like.
The only thing that's missing now is this hover effect.
So it goes up a little bit when we hover,
and then it goes back down.
Actually it doesn't only go up,
it also scales, right?
So what we need here is to add a line of code here,
where we say when we hover the feature-box.
So what happens?
Of course there's a transform.
And you're already noticing
that we're using transform all the time.
And that's because it's really an amazing property,
it allows us to do so many stuff.
So we want it to move up,
and so by now you already know
that we do that by using translateY,
right, so in the Y direction.
And then let's just get it up just a tiny little bit,
like 1.03, just like this.
Alright, now let's check that out.
Okay, and of course, we're missing the transition here.
So transition, and now we can actually write
the property that we wanna animate,
because it's just one.
Transition, and let's do an animation of .3s this time.
Actually we don't even need this selector here,
because we're not formatting the code at all.
So you're maybe asking why this, then,
has the font size that we specified.
And well, it does so because of inheritance.
So we defined the font-size in the feature-box of 1.5rem.
And then the paragraph,
which is a child of the feature-box,
simply inherits this font-size.
So we just have to define it on the parent,
and then it will automatically inherit.
Okay, and so now it should work as expected.
Well, not really.
Let me check out why that is.
Well of course,
it's transform here.
What a silly mistake.
But that happens all the time.
As you're coding,
it's absolutely normal to make mistakes.
And that's something you can't avoid,
and it's really, it's not a problem.
I do these mistakes,
you probably do these mistakes,
and everyone does these kind of silly mistakes.
And so what we have to do now
is to just complete our markup here.
Well, what's going on in here?
I'm not really sure.
I don't think there's any mistakes.
Well, that's this div,
that's this one,
that closes here,
and that closes here.
Well it's a weird formatting,
but I'm not gonna fix that right now.
What I want now is to
check out this font reference here.
So the next one that we want is the compass.
So where is that?
It's probably just called compass, anyway.
So here it is.
So this one here is called compass,
actually no need to even copy anything,
or paste.
So the compass, then the next one.
Let's take a look.
It's the map and then the heart.
So map, that's right.
And then let's just check if there's a heart.
Alright, so, heart.
So, map, and heart.
And the text that we have for these,
the first one was Explore the world.
The next one is Meet nature.
Then we have Find your way.
And finally, Live a healthier life.
So let's check it out.
Alright, so here we go.
Well, something that is weird here
is this really small space
that we have here between these boxes.
It's different than this one here.
So let me just check this out.
So, everything looks good,
but, oh yeah okay, I see.
So here, we have this small margin,
this really small margin, only 2rem.
And I remember that we changed this,
where I demonstrated to you how great it is
to have a variable to set the gutter off the grid.
So it's here.
So I set this to 2,
but it originally was at 6.
So let's set it back to 6 now,
and then take a look.
And okay, yeah,
so this looks better now.
And actually up here,
I also thought before that it was really close.
And now I know why that was,
it was also because of this small gutter.
Now we have a bit too much text here,
let's just delete a couple of words
so that it looks more natural like it did before.
But here, everything is great now.
So the next step is to put it like this,
so to skew this entire section.
Okay?
So this was just a small mistake,
just a small bug that I forgot to fix.
Alright, just delete some words from here.
And so, yeah,
let's go back to the feature-box.
Or actually to the home file,
because it's here in the section-features definition,
where we are going to take care of the skewed design.
So how are we going to do that?
So maybe the first thing that comes to your mind
is to again, use the clip-path property
that we used before on the heading.
And yeah, we could theoretically do that,
and it would be okay.
But I wanted to show you another nice trick,
and that is the following.
So what we can do is to simply skew the entire section.
So we use a transform,
and we used skew before, so skew.
But we want to do it in the Y direction.
So let's set it to -7deg.
Now I'm going to show you the differences in a second
in the inspector, okay?
So let's just check it out here.
And so here we go.
Don't worry about this one,
we're gonna fix it in a second.
But now this is what it looks like.
Alright?
So let me just,
show different values to you.
So -7 looks like this.
So from 0, it would be like this.
And if we put positive values,
it starts skewing in this direction.
Okay?
But with the negative value,
it then moves upwards,
so it skews upwards.
And I chose -7 simply because,
visually, it looks like this is the same inclination now
as this one, okay?
So it's just a visual thing.
Now, two things that we have to fix here.
First up, since we are skewing all of this,
we now created this wide gap here.
So what can we do about that?
We simply move up the entire thing
by a couple of pixels here,
a couple of rems,
so that it covers all of this white.
And the next thing is then to, of course,
put these back in their original position.
And let's actually start with that.
So how do you think we're gonna do that?
Well, the most intuitive thing to do
is to simply skew these in the opposite direction,
right?
And that's what we're gonna do.
So we skewed the entire section by -7deg,
and so let's just skew these boxes by seven degrees,
so they basically just skew back.
And now, we could go ahead and go into the feature-boxes,
and then implement that here.
So put the skew, and put seven degrees.
But we're gonna do it differently.
Because imagine that one day,
we want to put something else here in the section-features.
Okay, so, imagine we add a couple of other boxes
with different names or something.
And then, what would we do?
We would then have to add that transform,
and this new content as well.
And so we don't want to do that.
And so what I'm gonna do
is that I will show you a new selector,
which is a direct child selector.
So let's write it like this.
So ampersand and then direct child.
And the direct childs that I want to select are all of them.
And so the universal selector here.
So universal selector simply selects everything.
But only everything that is a direct child
of the section-features.
Okay, and that's it.
So let me demonstrate to you how it would look like
in compiled CSS.
So basically, section-features and then direct childs,
all of them.
And why do we have to use this direct child?
So if you would just do it like this,
we would select all the childs, right?
Not only the direct childs,
but simply all the children element.
And we don't wanna do that.
We only want to select the direct children.
So in the HTML, let me take a look.
So the direct children is actually only one child,
and it's that one.
So it's the row.
And so basically what this command does
is it takes this element here,
and it skews the row by minus seven degrees.
Well we haven't written that, but we will.
And of course it's here.
And so, let's simply do it like this.
Alright, let's take a look.
And indeed, here we go.
Let me check it in the inspector here, as well.
So you see that in here,
this is where it applies.
In here, it does not apply.
It only applies here, alright?
So if we take this out,
it looks like it did before.
And if we put it back,
then of course it's skewed.
So again, it's skewed basically in the other direction
to compensate for the skewing of the entire section.
Now if we didn't have the selector like this,
let me actually change it.
So without the direct child,
then everything would be skewed as well.
And so now we have this one who is skewed,
so it looks really weird now.
So this one is now skewed, this box.
And then in there,
the three elements are also skewed.
So these here are triple-skewed,
so they are skewed three times.
Because the parent is skewed,
and the parent of that one is skewed as well,
and so it's really weird.
So you see now,
well, it doesn't appear here.
But anyway, so that's what would happen
if you would not have used the direct child.
So again, the direct child will only select
the first child that it comes across basically,
and then apply the styles that we put in there.
Alright?
And so, this was another way
of doing this skewed section design.
And of course this image here is now skewed.
It doesn't look the same way it looked before.
But you don't really notice that,
so it's not really a big problem.
Alright,
and now what we just have to do
is to move up the entire thing a little bit.
And let's do that by trial and error, basically.
So section-features,
let's just simply apply a negative margin here to the top.
So margin-top, -10rem.
So we're starting with 10rem,
and let's see how far we have to go.
And so it already is covering now
the other section,
exactly like we wanted it to look like.
Let me take a look.
Well, this is actually it.
And for some reason,
I cannot manipulate this right now.
Well, what's happening here?
Let me reload the page.
Alright, so for some reason that didn't work.
But it does now.
So with -11, it doesn't really work.
9, so at -9 you already see this white thing here.
So just to be sure,
let's leave it at -10rem, okay?
And so now we're good to go.
Okay.
Now we see that by doing this,
we don't have a lot of space here in this section.
So this is really close,
but I think it's still alright.
We can leave it like that.
And maybe if, in the end,
it does look strange,
we can then do a final adjustment of that, okay?
And so I think that is it,
and that's everything I had to show you for this lecture.
So I'm showing you a lot of different things.
As you can see,
I'm showing you a lot of selectors,
a lot of new properties,
basically a lot of new tools for your CSS toolkit.
And I'm doing that because I want you to be able
to use all these tools in your future websites.
So I hope you're really following this,
and understanding this.
Because I don't want you to just copy my designs
when you start building your own websites.
I want you to truly and deeply understand
exactly what I'm doing,
and the tools I'm giving you,
so that you can then use them in your own designs
and coming up with your own designs, as well.
So with all of this,
I want to give you tools,
and I want to make you think,
think about how everything works.
And in the end,
just make you a capable CSS developer.
So that is really my goal with all of this.
But enough talk, see you next time.