I hope that you managed
to complete the challenge.
Now here goes the solution.
So once more we start from an empty CodePen Project
and I will start with the markup here once again.
So let's call this container a challenge
and so now let's put our elements in there.
So the first one is the header,
the next one I'm going to call the small box
one, so small box one
and then actually three of them,
and I could have done that with Amit
like I showed you before in the other lecture,
but there's only three boxes so it's not
too hard.
Then the next one is called the main content,
then we have the sidebar,
and of course finally the footer.
Okay, so moving over here to our CSS now.
Let's form it or challenge element.
So let's set like some overall settings
like we did before for this container
like giving it a width
and a margin of again
30 pixels top bottom and then auto
just so that it sits nicely
centered here in our view port, okay.
Then let's actually give a background color
to all of these elements here, okay,
and how do we do that, how do we select
all of them at the same time?
Well I just like to do it like this
as I showed you before a million times in the course.
So basically we select all of the direct children
of the challenge.
So using this SAS selector here.
So it's challenge and then direct children
and all of them, right, remember that?
So background color
and again I'm going with the orange-red, okay.
The padding of 20 pixels let's say.
Color should be white.
Font size of 30 pixels and a font family
just as Sans Serif one.
So we don't want to bother
with incorporating some font here, okay,
just so that it looks a bit better than the original.
So this is our layout let's say without any
of the styling.
Now remember that we had four columns basically.
So one for each of these small boxes
and then one on the side for the sidebar, right.
So grid,
template, rows
and if you remember we also had four rows
and the size I gave them was this one.
So 100 pixels for the first one, so for the header,
then 200 pixels for the small boxes
then 400 pixels for the main content
and 100 pixels again for the footer
and then grid, template, columns.
Remember that the sidebar was a bit smaller
than the rest of the columns
and so what we want is basically to have
three equally sized columns and then one smaller one.
So the way I'm going about this
and you can probably guess,
is to have three times one fractal unit
and then the last column with let's say 200 pixels.
So the sidebar will have just 200 pixels of course
and then the rest of the space
will be divided for the three other columns
and the gutter of course that we have.
Now what's missing here, you probably already noticed,
is to actually make this a grid container.
So display, grid,
and now you will see this making effect,
and yeah, you already have now
or four column tracks and or
four row tracks as well.
Let's just give them some gap so we can see it.
So grid gap 30 pixels.
Okay, so you'll see our seven
grid items here, but we don't see the rest of the
of the rows and the column tracks, right.
So let's just inspect this here, such as we did before,
and so this is the layout tab here
and so we can now select here
the challenge grid container,
which is the one here that we're working on.
So you see it down here
is a presentation of the grid that we have
and so here, remember the rows are 100, 200, 400, and 100
and that's what we can see here.
So this is the 100 row,
200, 400, which is much bigger and then 100,
and you see that they are down here.
So we see these empty grid cells,
which were actually created with our grid track declaration.
We just don't have enough grid items
to fill all of these cells up, but don't worry
we're going to care about that right now, okay.
So let's start by positioning all our grid items
exactly in the cells that we want them to be.
So the first thing to do
is to make the header span all the way from
the first column line to the last one, right.
So how do we do that?
Well let's just select the header
and then we can use grid column.
So we start with number one
and then remember the trick that we have
to go all the way to the end of the grid.
So we could just write span over four columns, right,
but I prefer to do it like this
as I showed you in the last lecture.
So from one to minus one
and so now we have the header
going across the entire grid
from left to right, okay.
So that part is already done
and notice that we don't actually have to declare
the grid row property here,
because the automatic placement algorithm takes care
of putting the header right in the first line,
because it's actually the first element here
in the markup as well.
So that's automatically placed here
and we don't have to declare it.
The same actually applies to our small boxes here.
They're also already exactly where they should be
so we don't have to do anything,
because automatic placement again
puts them where we want them to be, okay.
So the next thing that we have then to worry about
is just the sidebar.
So the sidebar should be here in this cell,
but not only this cell.
So remember that it actually spans across
these two cells here, right.
So the sidebar should be starting here
and then go across these two cells
with the main content then occupying
this entire space here
on this left side, okay.
So let's code that up very quick
and I'm not really sure why this grid
overlay is actually overlaying here this entire
CodePen editor I'm sure that's not
that's not really correct,
but it's probably just a bug in Firefox right now,
so it's not a big deal.
All right, so let's worry about the sidebar
and that's actually not correct.
So sidebar,
so grid column, where is it?
It starts as you can see here on number four,
so four to five,
and we could have used minus one here again
to all the way to the end,
but in this case it's
I guess it's not really necessary.
So you have to the sidebar right here now,
but it's not yet exactly where we want it.
We want it to be here
beginning on line number two, right.
So grid, row, it should go from two
and then span across two cells.
So span two and that's it.
You see, so now it starts here
at the top and goes down here,
and this is actually all a bit
to big so I have to do all the scrolling up and down.
Let me just zoom out a bit.
I was in actually the code also
becomes to small to see probably,
but just to get a big overview here of our entire grid.
You can see that it's already taking shape
and becoming more like we want in the end.
So next what we have to do
is to just make this main content here
span these three cells
and then in the end finally
out the footer down here,
which also shouldn't be all too hard.
Putting it back to its original size
and then let's move on.
So main content and now all we have to do here
is to define the column,
because the row is actually already correct, right.
So we can see that it is already in a correct row
and so all we have to do is to
manipulate the position in the column.
So it's going to start at number one
and then I could write once more that it goes to
all the way until number four,
but I think it's more intuitive
to simply say that it spans
across three tracks or three cells.
Okay, and so yeah, that's already looking good.
So the main content is now
exactly in a place where it should be
and now all that's left to do
is to also position the footer,
and nothings easier than that.
Grid, column, and it's just like the header,
so one all the way to minus one
and yeah that's it.
So that's all we have to do.
It's as simple as this, you see.
Just a couple of lines of CSS
to build this great layout
that would have been so complex to build
with the old school float layouts
like we've been doing for way too long actually.
So let me zoom out here again
to see it in it's full glory, right.
So yeah, so that's the final result
and I really hope that you achieved
to do it by yourself, but again if you did not
don't worry about it, it's no problem.
Now remember that I said in one of the earlier lectures
that there are multiple ways
of positioning grid items in the grid.
So I want to use this example to demonstrate to you
the different ways of doing exactly that.
So there are basically two more ways
that I want to show you,
and this example is actually it's really perfect
for that, okay.
So in the two next videos
I'm going to show you two different ways
that you can also use to position grid items on the grid.
So stay tuned for that.