In this section, we will discuss variability.
What do I mean by variability?
Let's find out. Variability, what is it?
Anything that affects the smooth flow of work. As you have likely
gathered by now, anything that causes our flow of work to be
disturbed has significant consequences.
Here are a few examples,
a requirement changing during work in progress that
is midstream in your workflow.
What do you do?
Stop work?
Another example, the size of requirements.
Remember, earlier in this model we looked at the
immense variety of backlog work types.
The goal was to see if we could normalize them so as to be
more similar by using the use case structure.
This technique is used to reduce variability, and hence increase workflow.
Now, of course, there are a lot of other forms of variability, certainly,
but let's look at these in more detail.
Changing requirements, that's a fact of life in system development.
So when your workflow has variability,
it can disrupt the predictability of your work.
Changing requirements is acceptable in Kanban, of course,
but it will affect your throughput, so I want you to be aware of that,
hence, a requirement change that'll affect lead time, the time it takes for
a piece of work to move through your value stream.
Now here are a couple of options that you can mitigate this issue.
You could block the card, that is stop work temporarily.
Maybe you block it if the requirement change is relatively small
and you need to get further clarification and ask some questions
to the people who specified the work or maybe even your
customers, so in this case, maybe blocking would be the best choice.
Or just move the card back to specify.
I would do this if the change was significant and we
really needed to rethink the card.
Maybe the card needs to be decomposed into more
tasks, maybe there are more issues,
and maybe there are significant negative consequences to the business,
so work must stop and the card is pushed back to the
specify step in order to figure things out.
Changing the size of requirements affects predictability.
When your workflow has variability,
it can disrupt the predictability of your work.
Changing or large variation in the size of requirements, certainly,
at a minimum, affects your first step,
which is specify. Use case versus epic, remember,
that's a really big difference,
and we went through this earlier In the module. Size variations of work items
affect lead time, that is the time to get through your value stream, and can
affect each step down the value stream, certainly. Here are a couple of options
to help you mitigate this. Work with your upstream partners to see if you could
normalize the size of the work.
That's the best place to start.
Also,
if your upstream partner is unable to give you better size
requirements, then consider adding a business analyst resource to work
in the customers department or area to help out.
This can be immensely helpful and useful,
since customers or product owners are pressed for time and do not always
have the skills necessary to best populate the backlog.
And, of course,
you could certainly add business analyst resources to the specify step
as well. Here's a silver bullet, allow slack. Well,
nothing is really a silver bullet, but since you may not be able to
influence your upstream partners, then slack is for you,. Enabling slack
helps you deal with any unexpected issues because you'll have more
capacity to be agile to deal with those issues.
Slack helps expedite blockers.
We'll talk more about blockers later in this module.
A blocker is if you are stuck on something, and hence
your smooth workflow is at risk.
Leverage digital tools that will help you shorten lead
time or reduce work in progress.
These tools give you great metrics and reports to
help you identify and solve issues.
Also slack enables improvement opportunities like removing technical debt.
Those with an agile scrum background will be familiar
with the slack concept and usage, since it is a common method to both.
So in summary of this section,
variability affects predictability of your planned
outcomes in the following ways.
As variability goes up, this results in more work in progress.
Also,
variability results in longer lead times. Strive to reduce
sources of variability. Now many times these sources of
variability are, in fact, outside of your control,
so it may not be a trivial challenge, and that is why I encourage the right use of slack.