Let's see how you can deal with bottlenecks because bottlenecks will happen.
Now bottlenecks may sound bad to you,
but there is a silver lining since visual bottlenecks will be
your cue to inspect and improve your workflow.
Let's define bottleneck.
A bottleneck in a process flow is anywhere that an accumulation
of work builds up waiting to be processed.
Sometimes you might also hear the term constraint as well.
It is important to get our terms right since later we will talk about blockers,
and a bottleneck is not a blocker.
Let's see how we can identify a bottleneck.
We have six resources applied, two in Specify,
three in Implement, and one in Validate.
Now let's overlay our cards for some point in time as follows.
Here is our Backlog, our Specify work, our Implement work,
our Validate work, and the work we've delivered.
Can you see where the most significant bottleneck is?
We can see that the cards are stacking up in the DONE column of Implement,
but that step is not the bottleneck step.
The bottleneck is the step after the 'done' step
where the cards are stacking up.
Therefore, the bottleneck is the Validate step.
So in this case,
we do not have enough resources in the Validate step to pull the
Implement 'done' cards forward for a smooth workflow.
So look again at the Implement step.
It is not the bottleneck.
In fact, it is cranking out work very well and even has one free resource.
So it is very easy to visually see any bottlenecks on your
board and then decide your remediation.
Bottlenecks can be easily identified.
If the active work items in a step are less than the work‑in‑progress limit,
then pull a 'done' work item from the preceding step and work on it.
No issue.
This is how you'll want all your steps to work all the time in a perfect world.
If the active work items in a step are equal to the work‑in‑progress limit,
then wait for one of its own items to be completed
before a 'done' work item can be pulled.
Again, no issue,
but the work item will be waiting in the 'done' queue of the preceding step.
If the active work items in a step are greater than the work‑in‑progress limit,
then management and the team have time to intervene and
add capacity or resolve the issue.
So in our previous slide, we had five items in the 'done' column to implement,
but they're not going to show up all at once.
Instead, there will be one extra, then two extra,
then three, and so on,
so you'll be able to see the buildup and decide what
action to take during your standups.
You might decide to take resources from the Implement step and move them
to the Validate step in order to increase throughput.
So easy to observe and easy to take action in real time.
Now let's talk about buffers.
In our running example,
the 'done' swim lanes where the gray arrows are
pointing are also known as buffers,
and controlling the size of the buffer is important.
Too many work items in a buffer is a waste.
And as we all know, waste is what Kanban wants to eliminate.
Buffers are important to have so that the work is immediately available
when the next downstream resource is free to do more work.
What would be the perfect buffer size?
Okay, hold that thought.
What is the ideal buffer size?
Did you figure it out?
The ideal buffer size is 0 since all buffers are a waste
because work is just sitting there.
But it was a trick question.
Zero as a buffer size is impractical, of course,
but you want just the right amount of buffer so that when
the downstream resource is available,
they can immediately pull a unit of work forward.
If a buffer (the 'done' swim lane) is growing,
consider adjusting downward the work in progress of the upstream step.
In our example, it was the Implement step,
and if we did adjust downward,
we could then apply the resources to the step with the biggest
constraint or the biggest buffer building up,
and in our example, it was the Validate step,
Key point: The only goal of a buffer is to create the
appearance of instant availability downstream.
So in summary, watch your buffers every day.
They are the signals telling you work is stacking up, and you need to consider taking action for a smooth workflow.