I would like to quickly suggest several companion courses that can enhance your
skills and capabilities while using kanban. The course, Developing Effective
Agile Sprint Plans, will give you insight into Agile and sprint planning that
you need to help better relate and communicate with your Agile dev teams in
their transition to kanban. The course,
Project Management for Software Engineers, will give you insight into
traditional project management that you need to help better relate and
communicate with your traditional dev teams in their transition to
kanban. It never hurts to hone your estimation skills no matter what
development approach you are taking. You might want to consider this
course, Best Practices for Project Estimation. Leadership and
Communication Skills.
Everything we talked about in this entire course has an
underpinning and requirement for strong and dynamic
leadership and communication skills,
especially when you are trying to influence management and your
dev team during your transition to kanban.
So check out the course, Leadership and
Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
You won't regret it.
It never hurts to brush up on your requirements analysis
skills to help you on the specify step,
so check out the course, Best Practices for Requirements
Gathering. Here are some examples of some of the top tools
that may help you get started.
Please do your own research because everyone's requirements are different.
Also, this should be used just as a starting point,
and I don't promote any of these tools. This is for your reference and further discovery.