Scrum versus Lean.
Scrub is a software development framework following the principles of Agile.
But it is a bit rigid and has rules that you must follow.
Don't get me wrong, I really like Agile/Scum practices,
and they've been a big leap over waterfall or Scrum‑a‑fall
or even if you roll your own process.
Now lean is all about process optimization and waste reduction,
whatever the process is.
And for this course, the process is going to be system development.
But keep in mind lean can apply to any workflow process.
So what you learn in this course can be repurposed to
any workflow from building cars, software,
or even to your personal projects at home.
Now we will contrast Agile/Scrum with kanban in a later module,
so hang in there.
I have worked in the information technology field for a very long time.
In every circumstance, every company, every organization is very different.
People have different experiences, skills, and capabilities.
Projects have different scope, budgets, schedules, and more.
Companies have different customers, suppliers, goals, and markets.
So,
strictly adhering to a prescriptive software development process for our team
is just too rigid and is not as efficient as it should be.
Because everything and everybody is different,
you need a very flexible and adaptable approach,
and that's kanban.
Kanban is a method that can be used to create a process which will always
be unique to the problem and to the resources available.
So kanban is not a process in and of itself.
Kanban is a practice that symbolizes a principle and is flexible and adaptable
based on the challenge at hand and the necessary resources.
Still a little fuzzy understanding kanban?
Well, that is why you're here, and by the end of this course, you will have a very solid grasp of kanban.