In this section,
we will discuss the Agile Scrum roles and how they map and compare into Kanban.
Now for the Scrum Master, the only formal accountability is over the process.
They're not product owners nor project managers,
but only facilitating the Scrum process.
Scrum Master role responsibilities are to enable teams to deliver value,
facilitate the Scrum events, ensure product owner is engaged,
remove process roadblocks, and keep progress visible to
everyone. How about a Kanban coach?
To be clear, there is no Scrum Master role in Kanban at all.
A Kanban coach is not necessary nor is it a recognized Kanban
role, but since Kanban may be new to you,
I recommend a temporary Kanban coach who would act as a team enabler and
maybe spread the role of coach across multiple Kanban teams.
This role is not required as a Scrum Master is for Agile Scrum,
but optional for transitioning. I think it would be a great help.
The product owner is the person responsible for managing
the business requirements and priorities.
Tomato, tomato.
Whether you use the term product owner, customer, or user,
you absolutely need them for populating your backlog and
setting priorities at a minimum. Okay. Here are the product
owner responsibilities in Scrum Agile.
The product owner represents the customers,
manages the business requirements, provides priorities, very important,
provides feedback to delivered features like when you provide a demo,
conveys business value by feature, and by the way,
there could even be multiple product owners.
Okay, now let's keep that role, so to speak.
That really doesn't change with Kanban,
but how we react with product owners does.
So we are nothing without our customers for sure.
Business analysts are usually the main interface to your customers.
The more they know about the business domain and technology,
the better, but also, all team members can engage the product owner.
There are no boundaries. But personally,
I prefer the business analyst to own that responsibility and keep the
rest of the team focused on creating great systems.
Let's explore the role of project manager and Kanban.
Project managers are responsible for managing work of
project teams. The project manager role usage.
Okay, there are no PMs, no project managers in the Scrum model.
Now there are project managers in the Waterfall model, as we
discussed in the Waterfall module. There can be PMs in the Kanban
model, and based on the size of the effort or project, I definitely
recommend using project managers. So please consider adding the
project manager role as needed.
Typically, small teams can manage themselves,
and they may not need project managers.
What is great is that PMs can share progress to all involved,
upstream, downstream, management schedules,
budgets, you name it, absolutely essential to me.
I think the project management role is
underappreciated and needs to be more widespread,
especially on larger projects.
Your resources may be a bit tight, so maybe consider a blended role.
Many business analysts can perform project manager duties as well and
business analysis activities concurrently, that might be a great use of a
resource or consider migrating your X‑Scrum Masters to perform project
management duties or business analysis duties as well. This gives them a transition path to Kanban.