Here are my final words and closing remarks for this course. You don't
need some crack team of high achievers to implement Kanban. A good team
with reasonable talent can easily succeed, if you do the following. Use
the right process with good discipline.
Be supported by strong management and quality
leadership. That can make all the difference.
Think about it.
Why is it that most professional basketball teams have pretty much the same
talent, yet why is it that some coaches continually win?
They probably have the right process with good discipline and strong
leadership. Wherever your career path may take you,
the bottom line is your ability to deliver business value.
Do not forget that. It is your biggest asset as a professional.
So what about Personal Kanban?
Why not?
Are you overwhelmed by home projects?
If you need some help staying more in control of your personal backlog,
you should consider Kanban.
I've been using Personal Kanban for many years.
You could get fancy and use a digital board,
but for me, it's just a bunch of stickies on a wall in my house.
To get started, just sit down and think about all the things you
need to do and list out your backlog.
Maybe one is yard work and another one is to remodel a bedroom.
The yard work one seems the right size,
but the remodel one seems overwhelming to me.
Okay, what do we do?
We decompose it into smaller ones.
You get the idea.
There are many benefits for me and I hope for you, too.
I can relax, since I know all the things I need to do are listed and organized.
I can easily see them and track them.
I can limit the amount of work either than I am doing, or I can see just
where I need to add more capacity, like hire a gardener.
I hope this might help simplify your life.
It sure has for me.
Thank you very much for taking my course.
I, like you, have been challenged over the years in how
best to provide value to the business.
I hope and trust that this course has been able to
provide you with the essential tools,
methods and approaches, and renewed confidence to help you be more
successful in your application and usage of Kanban. And lastly,
I hope to see you again in one of my other courses, and I wish you the best in your professional journey, and never stop learning.