Implementing Kanban.
Okay, so you have management's approval and the team is willing to begin.
Let's discuss some ideas on how to make this happen.
I am a big believer in pilots, which is a small‑scale preliminary activity.
Whether you are starting from scratch or want to enhance
your current usage of Kanban, I would recommend using a
pilot approach to get things started.
The purpose of a pilot is to evaluate feasibility, duration,
cost,
adverse effects, and use the feedback to improve upon the
initial parameters and expectations of the pilot.
Determine your baseline metrics.
Here are a few examples, your current velocity,
that is how much work are you producing now so that you can compare against
your production of work with Kanban, amount of new bugs per week, with
Kanban we expect them to go down certainly, or even customer satisfaction.
Measure your customer satisfaction before the pilot and after the pilot.
Track your pilot project and compare the results with your baseline metrics
to see any improvements.
And in this example we chose three metrics, the amount of work completed,
the number of bugs, and customer satisfaction.
Now this may take time so be patient because it takes time for people to
learn and apply new methods and techniques. Maybe your pilot is between
three and six months. So your pilot is a success.
And here are a few more ideas about a rollout plan. Continue
to brief managers and team members on Kanban, the benefits
and the pilot and usage outcomes,
maybe monthly. Provide Kanban training, in person or online, consultants, and,
most importantly,
hands‑on, real life practical experience using Kanban. Don't wait,
just do it.
Organize the backlog, document your value stream,
set up the board, determine the WIP limits,
create done criteria, and go. Run daily stand‑ups, make
course corrections, review metrics,
status your team and management on performance improvements or issues.
If you're starting from scratch, what kind of team members do you want?
If you have the opportunity to pick and choose your own team members,
this slide will help you do that. Or, since you may not have this luxury,
this slide will also help you frame the message to
them and prepare them for Kanban.
Here are the attributes of team members that may adapt well to Kanban,
people who are comfortable to think for themselves,
people secure to design their own destiny,
those that can make real time reflections on what is happening and
make changes accordingly, those that feel it's okay to evolve the
value stream as necessary, those that can work without a more rigid
process such as Scrum or Waterfall.
Ensure your team is in alignment with your Kanban vision and that they
know your longer‑term vision and outcome as well.
Also,
there are people that like and want to be held
accountable and they embrace responsibility.
I love those kinds of people.
Okay,
people that exhibit most or all of these attributes will serve you well
and your organization. Change can be difficult for people so be aware of
naysayers. A naysayer is someone who criticizes, objects to, or opposes
something, and in this case, Kanban.
Some people may resist change as a political strategy
to prove that the decision is wrong.
They may also resist to show that the person leading the change
is not up to the task, that could be you.
Others may resist because they lose some power in the organization.
So a solution to this may be education, training,
coaching, one‑on‑one support, long term career benefits,
satisfaction of the personal challenge.
Please listen to any naysayers' feedback.
Some may be very important and beneficial. So be a good listener,
incorporate their concerns if possible, and lead them forward.
Here is another tool that might help with major
changes to the way people do things, these are phases to change.
And I really like the change model called ADKAR and here it
is. Awareness of the need for change, desire to support the change,
knowledge of how to change, ability to demonstrate skills and
behaviors, and reinforcement to make the change hold.
Change will happen if these steps are followed.
Awareness and desire alone is not enough.
So when you prepare your communications and implementation planning,
keep these in mind. They will be a very helpful template.
Lastly, if you want to learn more about this topic,
please check out ProSci at the URL below. Do not underestimate how
resistance to change from senior management to the knowledge worker can affect the success of your adoption of Kanban.