Let's talk about work in progress limits and done rules. Completing
features restricted by work in progress limits.
Another big change is limiting our work in progress,
which to me at first didn't seem to make much sense since I was
so used to people just piling on the work.
Please note kanban systems limit work in progress,
not resources. Got more work? Well, add resources. Limiting work in
progress just means that you finish what you are working on before
you pull or start the next piece of work.
Here's another example, though it might be subtle.
Why would a developer take on more work when she could simply
unblock a verify task and further clarify the spec or how the
system behaves for someone else?
If she just keeps pulling work forward,
it really wouldn't matter since the downstream resource was blocked
anyway. Get the point? Small batches and restricting work in progress
enable all the knowledge about the specs and how they were implemented
and tested to be current and on point in the minds to be more easily
remedied and resolved.
You know how it is.
The half life of my memory is not very long at all, so the shorter the
time span between spec writing and delivering code, the better. Done Rules
or When to Do the Next Thing. With waterfall,
you complete the step, such as requirements completely, and then
you move on to the next step, and we really don't go back. In
kanban, work is only pulled forward that has started if the done
rules are satisfied. Well,
what are the done rules you say? Every step in a kanban
system will have its own unique done rules that makes
sense for your workflow and team.
So only when the rules say the work in this step is complete can the
work move forward. Just so you better understand this, here is an
example of a done rule for an implement step.
The rule is comprised of several elements.
Okay, here's the rule.
The code is developed, the code is unit tested, the specs were
updated if they needed to be, the code is checked into a
repository, and a clean bill was created.
You can certainly relate to all these, but the person
downstream would only pull this to verify if in fact all five
of these items were in fact complete.
I will be going into more detail on this topic in the module,
Managing Your Workflow, later in this course. Again,
every organization has different resourcing challenges,
so be flexible, and try to adhere to limiting work in progress and succinct done rules for each value stream step.