How and when to write specs.
How writing specifications should change.
Typically, in the traditional or waterfall approach,
specifications tend to be more formal and structured.
That is not necessarily wrong, but with Kanban,
we need to be open to less structured and informal specs.
I love grabbing a marker and getting on a white board and being creative.
I still recommend that you capture your work,
take pictures, and add it to your requirements wiki.
This approach may allow to develop specs faster so you have some
amount of the more formal structured specs,
but maybe some of the other details can be performed in a more creative,
informal setting yielding better quality.
Every company will be different in terms of who is
responsible for writing the specs.
If the specs are written and provided to you as a backlog item,
that doesn't mean they are the right level of detail or quality.
Take the prewritten upstream specs into your specified step and then apply
your informal approach to further refine those specs.
That would be a good mix of formal and informal.
By no means am I ever suggesting that specs are not needed ever.
I have spent much of my career writing specs.
It is an art and skill to write just the correct amount of detail to ensure
the development team will have enough to be productive,
not too much, not too little.
On the previous slide, we talked about relaxing the formality of writing specs.
And let's now talk about the timing of specifications writing.
In the waterfall world, the time elapse can be months,
and with Kanban just days between the writing of the specs and code
development, the Kanban approach greatly reduces the time from spec
writing to implementation because of the small batch approach to work
we talked about previously.
In this way, the knowledge of the feature is current,
relevant, and fresh in the minds of the team.
This is a huge productivity gain.
This reduces time span for bug remediation. Just as Kanban
reduces the time between initial writing specs and then
implementing the features as code, so too,
is the time span reduced between discovering bugs and correcting
them. In full transparency, I love writing specs,
figuring out the business drivers, where to add value, and
writing those details to make the life of the developer and
tester as easy as possible.
Traditional waterfall teams may also like to continue
writing detailed heavy specs for each feature,
and that is OK.
Let's not disturb your cadence if that's the case.
One reason for detailed specs is that they originally needed a long shelf life
since the timespan between spec and code was lengthy. As the team gets more
comfortable with short time spans and the team works more close and understands
what it needs to be done in real time, the specs can become lighter. Less specs,
more informal whiteboarding, things like that, but always take
pictures and capture the information and put it in a wiki. Never not
capture or document what the specs should be.
Just as I recommended, electronic boards, using electronic
wiki tools to easily aggregate specs, artifacts,
documents, and especially people will be enormously helpful.
What I'm saying is that, in general, you will find
the specifications will be lighter,
less of them because less will be needed, but that doesn't mean
leave out the important business rules either.
Also, detailed specs are not evil.
Some requirements may take very detailed specs,
so do what is best and, if needed, write those detailed specs. Nothing wrong with that.