Hi. My name is Kevin Jones,
and this is the Running Code Securely chapter of the Java Virtual
Machine: Security class from Pluralsight. In this chapter,
we'll delve more into how we manage the security of code and how we
define the permissions the code has and requires to run.
So we'll take a look at Java platform security and, in particular,
the architecture and syntax of the policies that we need to use to execute code.
We'll also look at how we can sign code.
So we saw in the previous module that we can specify
permissions based on where code is loaded from.
We can also specify permissions based on who created the code and
who signed the code. So we'll see how we do that,
how we can sign the code, and how we can specify those permissions.
And we'll also take a look at custom permissions. So the JDK comes
with a set of built‑in permissions that we can use.
But suppose we need other permissions for our own
code. So we'll see how we can do that.
So,
just to recap, in the first module, we saw that Java security
was built on these three things‑‑permissions,
policy, and enforcement.
We also saw that we can specify SecurityManager in one of two ways.
So if you require security to be used,
we have to load our application with a SecurityManager.
We can either specify the SecurityManager on the command line,
or we can load a SecurityManager in code.
So one thing we touched on briefly in the first module, and
we just covered it in a little more depth here, is where the
security checks actually happen.
Something has to say, Is this code allowed to execute?
Typically,
this happens in some library code, so we could call the security
check or often libraries that we use make the security checks, and
the JDK is full of these sorts of checks.
For example,
if we take a look at the sources that we can download now from the JDK,
this is from the FileInputStream.java class as part of the Open JDK,
and we can see here the construct of a FileInputStream tries to get a
reference to the SecurityManager.
So it calls System.getSecurityManager.
If a SecurityManager's been loaded,
so we've either specified on the command line we
want a SecurityManager, or, indeed,
we've created one inside of our application, then this returns a non‑null value.
So we have a SecurityManager,
and at that point we call checkRead. And it's this checkRead call
that checks if this code has permission in this case to read from a
file. If it doesn't have that permission,
it throws an exception. In the next module, we'll take a look
at policy, how the policy file is implemented, and the details that go into the policy file.