So this is the Java policy file.
This is the default policy file we've just created.
So the first I'm going to do is to take a copy of this,
and there in my application in my project,
I'm going to create a new file.
Let's call this my.override.policy.
And I'm going to paste the contents of the full Java policy file into this file,
and, I'll save that.
So to run this, as well as specifying security.manager, I
now need to specify the policy file.
So I say ‑Djava.security.policy==, as I'm doing the
override. And this is up several layers here,
so ..\..\..\my.override.policy.
If I do this,
then the application still runs. Again, to check that I
am using the correct policy file here, let me go and comment out these two lines.
Let me read the user permission and read the file permission, save the file,
go back to the command prompt, and try this again.
And indeed it fails.
So I am definitely using that file.
So if augmentation, if I copy this overridden policy file and paste it in and
call this my.augment, if I can spell that, augment.policy. And in here I get
rid of everything apart from the bits that I need.
So everything is clear here except these two permissions.
And for now,
I'll just leave these commented out, just again, to prove it
doesn't run unless I specify this correctly.
If I go to the command prompt, and now rather than saying == my.override.policy,
I say = my.augment.policy.
So if I run this, this succeeds.
And the reason this succeeds is that these permissions are
still set in the default policy file.
So if I go back into the default policy file and remove
those permissions, and this is the danger,
I've forgotten to remove these before I ran the demo. So let me remove these
from the default policy file, go back to the command prompt,
run the code again,
and it fails. If I go back into my.augment policy file and add
those permissions back in, and then go back to the command prompt
and run the code again, then again, it's working.
But now we're simply augmenting the already built‑in default
policy, so we're adding grants to the default policy.
So in the next module, we'll look in more detail at exactly how this works.
In particular we'll take a look at how the access controller walks
the stack to tell what code is on the stack and whether that code is able to access this resource or not.