So the best way, perhaps, to see this in action is to use
our own security manager. And we'll see why this makes life
slightly easier in a moment.
So here I've defined a class called
MySecurityManager that extends SecurityManager.
And that has a method called listPermissions,
just something we can call to list out all the
permissions at a given point in time.
To use the security manager,
we have to add it into the application and tell the application we
want to use our security manager. And we've seen previously we do
that by calling System.setSecurityManager.
I just passed this new MySecurityManager.
There's a mirror call to this called getSecurityManager.
So, just to see this in action,
I can say MySecurityManager securityManager = System.getSecurityManager.
On this I need the cast to be a MySecurityManager. And then once we have
that I can call securityManager.listPermissions. So it's listPermissions
where we'll do all the work.
So in here the first thing I want to do is to get ahold of the
default Policy class. So I can say Policy policy = Policy.getPolicy.
And this returns me the policy singleton.
So I can say Policy.getPolicy and get back the policy singleton.
Now the reason I want to create my own security manager is that the
security manager has a helper class called getClassContext.
getClassContext returns a list of classes that are currently
involved in security for this application.
I'm being slightly hazy here. We'll explain exactly
what that means in a few moments time.
So what getClassContext returns is an array of classes. So I
can say Class [] classes = getClassContext.
Once I have that I can iterate over all these classes. So I can say for(Class
cls : classes). Then inside here I can get the ProtectionDomain for each class
in this iteration. So cls.getProtectionDomain.
And then from the ProtectionDomain I can get the CodeSource for, again,
each class. So I can say CodeSource cs = pd.getCodeSource.
So once I have the CodeSource I can use the policy to get permissions.
So I can say policy.getPermissions and I can pass it the CodeSource.
And what this returns is a PermissionCollection.
So I can say PermissionCollection permissionCollection = policy.getPermissions.
So once I have the PermissionCollection I want to enumerate them.
The PermissionCollection has an elements method which returns
me an enumeration of Permission objects.
And once I have that I can iterate over these. So, permissions.hasMoreElements
and then just simply print out permissions.nextElement. And I will call
toString on the permission and print out the permission.
I have one last thing to point out. I'm going to
run this with a security manager.
DB set that security manager here.
So I need to make sure the permissions for this application are correct.
So I have a policy file here,
and in this policy file we grant ourselves two further permissions.
We need the permission to allow us to read the policy and we need the
permission to allow us to read the protection domains.
And if we don't grant ourselves these then the code will simply fail to run.
So if I jump to the command prompt here and from here run java,
pointing out that policy file, and then com.pluralsight.Main
is just the main class of the application.
And if I run this it will print out all of our
permissions. We know it's essential that we get here all
the permissions from the policy files.
So we get various property permissions, we can read the specification,
we get the extra permissions we've added, like
getProtectionDomain and getPolicy.
So this is how our code internally,
if we need to, can read and check these permissions
directly. As we'll see later,
this is not actually how permission checks are done, but we can see here this
gives us one way to access all the given permissions if we ever need to do that.
Now that we've seen how to get these permissions,
we need to take a look at one extra thing for the check
and that is something called a code stack walk. And we'll see that in the next module.