So what we have here is a sort of layered application with three layers.
We have the main code, and that's this guy here,
and that's in a project called Runner.
I'm just going to compile that into a set of classes.
This will be com.knowledgespike.main and then the method is
called main and we just run this application.
We also have a data access layer and a data service layer, and the data
service layer uses data access layer. So my main code calls the service and
then the service calls the data access and data access actually does the
write. All we're doing is overcomplicating a write to a file and we specify
the file name here, so temp/message.txt.
So there are three separate projects.
The service layer is this guy here and the service layer gets
given a reference to the data access layer,
and it's simply calls access.write message and the data access layer,
just this one here, when the write method gets called, create a file
writer, and writes to the file stream.
So the data service code and the data access code are compiled into jar files.
So when I compile my code, I have a data access.jar and a
service.jar. So to run this from the command prompt,
we're going to run it with a security manager and with a policy file,
and there is the class path pointed at both the dataaccess.jar
file on the service.jar file and also a com.knowledgespike.main.
The policy file looks like this.
Now notice that we now have three grant blocks in here, one for each code base.
So starting at the bottom,
we have a grand block for the class files in
demos/Callstacks/out/production/runner/*, so that's my
com.knowledgespike.main class and I give that permission to write to the temp/message.txt
file.
We also have a grant entry for the code base with Service.jar and we
give that the same permission and we have a grant for our
DataAccess.jar and we give that the same permission.
So if I go back to the command prompt, and from here,
run the code, the code runs as you'd expect. If I look in the temp folder,
there is the message.txt file that we created, so let me go and delete that.
Now if I go back to the policy file, so remember the runner code calls the
service layer and that calls the data access code.
So we have these three classes on the stack frame at the same time,
which then call down to the file writer and the file
write actually writes to the file.
So if I remove permission from one of these classes, then the call
should fail, so let's just pick one at random.
Let's take my service jar file here and comment out
this permission to write to this file.
Make sure I save that file, go back to the command prompt, and run the
code again, and now we get a security exception.
So the access controller is checking everything that's in
the stack frame and making sure we all have access, we're
all allowed to write to this file, we all have permission.
And if anything in the stack frame fails the check,
then we get the security exception.
So now that we've seen how to grant permissions based on code location,
we can now take a look at how to grant permissions based on signing.
So who actually created this code? And that's what we'll see in the next module.