So previously we saw how to set permissions based on where code was loaded from.
Now we'll see how to set permissions based on who created the code,
that is, who signed the code.
So in Java we can create what are known as signed JARs.
When we do this, we store the signature in the JAR file,
and then we store the public key in the KeyStore.
Now, in this module,
we're not going to go into details about public key
cryptography or any other sort of cryptography.
This is a tricky area, and before you deal with any of these issues,
you need to check with an expert.
So how do we go about this?
So there are two sides to the story.
There's the signer, i.e., the person that's signing the JAR file, and
there's the person that's going to use the JAR file.
So for the signer, we create a JAR file,
obviously. We then generate keys, so we generate a public‑key private‑key pair.
We sign the JAR with these keys,
and then we export the public key in a certificate.
The person that's going to use this JAR file, the receiver,
if you like,
imports the certificate that we send them, it's a
trusted certificate, into the key store.
They then edit the policy file to grant permission to
the person that signed this JAR file, and then they run the code. So let's take a look at how that works in practice.