So to do this, we use something called an AccessControlContext.
And in fact, this is what the underlying JRE uses all along.
So the AccessControlContext provides security context information.
It essentially gives us back the complete security context,
i.e., so if you're on a given thread in a given stack frame,
and we ask for the AccessControlContext,
what we'll get back from this is the complete security
context for where we are currently, so where we are in the stack frame,
where we are inside the call.
And the AccessControlContext is actually what the
AccessController uses when it does its stack walk.
For each stack frame, the AccessController actually reaches out,
obtains an AccessControlContext, and uses that to do its security checks.
And the way it does the security checks is by calling
accessControlContext.checkPermission.
If this call in the current frame succeeds, we go to the next stack frame.
On the next stack frame, we get an AccessControlContext,
we call its checkPermission, and then we keep walking up the stack frame.
And another job of the AccessControlContext is to manage the ProtectionDomains.
So the AccessControlContext will eliminate duplicate ProtectionDomains,
for example, to make sure these things aren't checked multiple times.
So how do we get an AccessControlContext?
Well, we can get one of these things in one of three ways.
We can call AccessController.getContext,
and that gives us the AccessControlContext of the
current thread they'll be running on.
We can also do the new AccessControlContext and pass to
it an the array of ProtectionDomains.
Or we can create a new AccessControlContext and pass it
something called a DomainCombiner. When something tries to
use the AccessControlContext, they call the DomainCombiner's combine method,
and it's the job of the DomainCombiner's combine method to
combine together the ProtectionDomains that are going to be
used by this AccessControlContext.
So you can see in the first case we can give access to the
AccessControlContext that's used by the JRE by default.
In the second case, we can create an AccessControlContext out of clean cloth.
And in the third case,
we can create an AccessControlContext by using information from the current
control context and other information that we provide.
So where's this typically used?
Now we can use this directly,
so we can use the AccessControlContext to do a checkPermission.
And again, just like the AccessController,
it will throw a security exception if the check fails.
However, this does not do a stack walk.
So the AccessControlContext here will just check that
this stack frame has permission.
So if you need that fine‑grained check,
you'd use the accessControlContext.checkPermission rather than the
AccessController checkPermission . And we see some code here.
We're not seeing how we got the AccessControlContext
here; we just know we have one.
Once we have one, we can call this checkPermission,
and we can pass it a PropertyPermission.
So in this case,
we're looking to see if I can read or write for a given property.
Now, the most likely use of AccessControlContext,
though, is to do something called a privileged block execution.
And what this does is,
it sets the context on the call stack and essentially
prevents the stack walk going any further.
The way we do this is by creating something called a PrivilegedAction.
The PrivilegedAction has a run method.
We do the check inside the run method, but that prevents the stack walk,
as we only check things inside the run method.
So the code looks like this.
We call AccessController.doPrivileged and we create a new
PrivilegedAction with a run method.
When we do this, the run method will execute.
Notice that we can pass this an
AccessControlContext to use inside the run method,
or we can just use the current AccessControlContext.
Either way, the code that runs inside this run method,
the AccessController permission check is done here.
We don't try and walk the stack any further.
So earlier, we saw this slide,
and here we said that we have two methods on the stack frame.
We have the Main method,
and then we create a FileWriter, and we have the FileWriter's write method.
And we said that the FileWriter is always trusted because the FileWriter
comes from the JRE libraries, that location's always trusted,
but that the Main method may not be trusted.
And in this case, we said that we have a full stack walk.
So when we call writer.write, that will be trusted.
But that's not good enough, so we walk up the stack
frame, and Main is untrusted, and that throws an exception.
So we said we had this.
We call Main, Main calls writer.write, Main is untrusted,
but FileWriter was trusted.
And this was an issue, and it was an issue because,
as we just said, if one of those things on the stack frame is untrusted,
then we'd like an exception to be thrown.
However, sometimes that's not the scenario.
Sometimes the scenario is that something on the stack frame is
untrusted, but there is something trusted on the stack frame
that you want to always trust, regardless of the context.
So imagine a scenario where you're trying to audit code,
for example. That audit class might always want to be trusted.
You always want to write the audit message out, regardless of
whatever else is on the stack frame. And that's what we get
by using privileged execution. So let's take a look at a demo of that now.