So how does all this hang together?
How do we actually secure calls in the runtime?
Well, we use the SecurityManager.
The SecurityManager is called to check requests to any protected operation.
Now what is protected is up to the library developer.
So we know as part of the Java runtime file access is protected,
network access is protected, some access to threads is protected,
even access to system properties is protected.
If the caller is not allowed to access this protected resource,
is not allowed to execute this protected operation,
then the SecurityManager is going to throw an exception.
The call succeeds or fails, depending on something called a CodeSource,
and we'll take a look at CodeSources in more detail a little later.
But the CodeSource contains a location and information about the call.
So something like this, we have a file system,
we want to access the file system, and in front of that,
we have the SecurityManager.
When something comes along inside an application and
wants to access the file system, they have to pass through the SecurityManager.
So here we're trying to write to a file called system.dat,
and we're creating a new FileOutputStream to do that.
SecurityManager in this case allows access,
so we're allowed to write to this file.
It's possible that the same application loading code from
another location also tries to access this file.
So it makes another call to FileOutputStream, again tries to access system.dat.
But this time, the SecurityManager fails the call. So we can allow or fail
calls to the same resource within the same application,
depending on where the code is loaded.
There are other things that affect whether a call will succeed or fail,
but primarily in this case, it's where the code is loaded from.
So the SecurityManager works together with the AccessController. It's the job
of the SecurityManager to check any sensitive operations.
This thing was originally abstract base class that
we had to implement ourselves.
This is back in the days of Java 1.
But since Java 2, there's a concrete SecurityManager that delegates to a
concrete AccessController, and that AccessController will make use of
policy and permissions to decide whether or not to allow access. By
default, there is no SecurityManager,
so we have to turn it on if we want to use it.
Server processes should almost certainly activate security.
The server processes want to limit the attack area.
They want to follow this principle of least privilege.
And how do we activate security?
Remember, it's off by default, so we have to turn it on.
And there two ways of doing this. One way is from the command line.
We can set a system property.
So if you run the code with this property ‑Djava.security.manager,
that says, I want to use the default SecurityManager to run my code.
We can also activate it explicitly inside our code. So I can
call setSecurityManager and passing it a new
SecurityManager. These two are equivalent.
So now we'll take a look at a demo, and just turning on the SecurityManager and seeing what that allows or disallows within our code.