Welcome back.
Delightful God.
People in this video we're going to plan a heist meissner's which our top down to the stealth game.
We're really excited about this game it's got a lot of really cool features.
And what can I gain on a make.
Well as you might remember I like to start with the essential experience.
For me this means let's start with the play a feeling and build the game from that.
I see the game as that play a feeling so let's create the the best crafted player experience we can.
I see it as us being an expert thief who sneaks through dark and dangerous locations to steal valuables
and going out and detected key words expert thief dark and dangerous get out undetected.
So if we look at a bicycle chart that's what we have.
What kind of gameplay mechanics we're talking about.
Well this is a top down game but it's a stealth game.
And key in stealth games is that the player has to have more information than they would in real life.
If you want to feel like an incredible cat burglar or jewel thief or spy in a video game it's key that
you understand things like guards line of sight.
What's the other side of this wall.
How much danger will be in here.
I want the player to make tactical decisions.
I want to say that the player can be seen briefly.
I can see run past the guard I can sprint.
So there's going to be a concept of detection and the maximum detection threshold.
If you get beyond that the game is over.
It's going to rise pretty fast and fall gently over time.
So the guard of the camera might see a glimpse in the corner of the eye oh it's probably nothing.
And this is going to be very dark going.
The only lights that can be visible are going to be what the guards and cameras can see.
So the play is going to be able to switch from normal vision to night vision.
But there's going to be a penalty for that if you're in night vision mode You're not have access to
key information.
And if your normal vision there's other information you have.
So when to switch views is going to be a critical element of this game.
So if I go into sketching mode like this here is our top down player who's got one big began the other
and is bald it's basically Agent 47 but it's not age of 47.
So it's a bald head and he's got shoulder pads.
And here is a guard who is grumpy.
Why's he grumpy.
It is terrible haircut.
I don't know why the Guard is going to be able to see in a cup and that Khan is going to be made of
light.
Right so we're going to have to see where that is.
This is essentially the guard's torch or flashlight depending on what poll arguing.
There's also going to be other guards which are cameras.
Cameras can't move but they rotate left and right and they're going to have that same come.
So we're going to be using this concept of inheritance with inherits scenes they're going to get behaviour
from classes above them.
All three of these are going to be part of the character class as can be a character class.
Then this can be in pieces.
Player.
And NBC will further break down as soldiers and cameras.
We could keep adding up things right if you want and guard dogs anything like that.
That's how you would do that.
There is behaviour that is true for all characters and will inherit down.
So let's keep going.
Another thing I want is some sort of gameplay flow.
So far all our games have been one level games.
I'd like to extend that so we're going to have a splash screen.
That's the introduction screen with various options are a tutorial.
We need a tutorial level for this because it can be quite difficult game level so a start game.
And acquit.
Which is just taking out of them entirely.
So from the splash screen but we go a level one and then from level 1 which you want to a too.
3 etc..
Maybe we'll let people pick more difficult levels.
We'll see how that goes.
There's some other great features coming including auto tile I'm saying in a weird way because I have
done this six times now and I keep trying to write auto light.
It's not a light it's an auto type what an auto tile.
Well take the concept of a tile map that we did in in Hobby days and extend it further.
What if the game could figure out okay I've drawn this shape like this.
Now apply all the textures and corners and collisions and light occlusion where we can.
Really fun feature.
What else have we got.
We've got line of sight which is very dramatic and useful in lots of cases.
We can play with themes.
It's a theme it's a way of saying to go to work every time I create a button or a panel it should look
like this unless I tell you otherwise.
This is my default font.
These are my colours and it will remember them and apply them.
It's a really great way of making things work.
We're going to have combination locks that are randomly set and these combinations can be variable so
I can say this store has a four digit combination.
This one has a 12 digit combination with no crazy with this.
Lots of cool things to look for.
See in the next video we can get started.