Hello again you wonderful God people.
In this video we're going to start play a detection by the end of this video.
The camera is going to be able to tell if the player is within the field of view.
Now you'll notice this is part one of plate detection.
We're just looking at field of view.
We're not looking at line of sight.
And by line of sight we're not yet going to the test if a player is hiding behind something if the camera
or other NBC site is blocked by an object so can do this in stages but we are coming to that.
So we're doing field of view.
We have to figure out some things.
First thing we need to know is what is the field of view.
Right.
The feel of you is the angle that you can see.
So the purposes of this video when I say you and probably talking about the NBC if you and NBC How far
can you see the field of view is going to match the light beam and ice Meister's.
This is to give the player really clear feedback about what is and what isn't dangerous.
The field of view has to rotate with the non play a character.
If you turn by 13 degrees to your right your field of view has to turn to.
And when he did check of the players in the field of view when we're doing that we should give some
feedback to the player.
It's all very well saying the light beam is dangerous.
The players are able to see instantly you are in a light beam.
So this sounds like quite a lot.
And when you first approach this subject it's very easy to get bogged down especially if like me you're
not that familiar with linear algebra and Vector mathematics.
So if you're somebody who hears the words vector mathematics and that type little shiver of fear happens
inside you don't worry.
It's nowhere near as bad as you might be thinking when it's nice and simple.
Let's break this down into really simple steps.
When we have a difficult problem like are you in my field of view let's break it down to concrete things
we can tell the computer first thing what direction of fixing this sounds silly but actually it's key.
If you've turned 13 degrees to the right you are now facing that direction to the field of you is going
to change to a second.
What direction is the play in.
Never mind can I see you which way my facing and what direction are you in.
Because once we have those two we can see those two things within tolerance.
By that I mean they don't have to perfectly align right we're not making a one pixel line that you touch
and that I see you would have a field of use are you inside that field.
And that's everything the MP needs sooner.
So there's more things we need to talk about but let's not make this one big lecture slides.
Let's actually do something in the engine.
So I want to go into the security camera and I'm going to make a scene on camera body now.
Quick reminder camera body has to be a kinematic body too deep for what I'm about to do to work.
I'm going to give it a script that inherits from character.
Character is a script that extends kinematic body to deep.
So if I look at a play a script player extends character and character extends a note.
It's getting all of the functions and methods and everything else it can do from what is in the note
about what it can do.
That means if I put a script here and this note is not a kinematic what to me is something an area truly
We're going to have a massive problem and it won't let us do it.
So let's put in a new script.
And I'm going to first name them in the right place.
I don't want to be in scenes.
I have some weird scenes to get rid of there.
This is from my beta testing scripts.
I will call this player detection.
Now you might be thinking why aren't you calling it camera.
I could call a camera but camera is not really what the script does is not transmitting the image anywhere.
It's not saying here's what I see.
All it's doing is trying to protect the player and later going to make a soldier who's going to inherit
that scene.
So for now let's call this player detection in the right place.
Hit save.
But before we further going to inherit a character.
So I just clicked this little folder here and it change from kinematic bullet you need to where the
caps ripped us and we are good to go.
Let me get rid of these little fake scripts that I made because you don't need those first things first
we need to define a concept we need f Ovee tolerance o the tolerance not f Ovee ever the field of view
is the angle that you can see.
But that's not really what it gonna be using this for.
I'm not telling you this is the thing you can see in checking is something within that angle.
This is going to be 45.
Why is it 45.
It's 45 because that's the sublets the angle in the image I gave you that like map image.
It's a 45 degree thing.
Actually it's 44 and a half but I'm going to call it 45 for now.
Next up let's grab the player and make a global script right now.
When do we go on ready.
Variable player.
So we need to find the play out let's do get note not make a global script right now.
We can do that little bit later for now which is get this work.
What is this.
This is going to be what has to be a string because that's how get known works.
And we need to go to the root level one player let's make a quick note here this is make this level
neutral.
What I mean by that I mean at the moment this will only work in level 1 and when we want to add multiple
levels we probably will do later.
That's really not good.
So we'll have to fix this later so there's a note to tell us that it that file our player.
We're good to go.
So we're going to check every frame.
So we're going to go.
Function process.
And what do we want to do.
We want to see if player is in F the top.
And I'm using the same capitalization So it's very easy to read.
So that's my next function.
Go get rid of these extra spacing because well it's neater and also Ben doesn't like it so let's give
it a function.
Play is in F over torrents.
What do we need to do here.
Well we need to figure out a couple of things.
Let's go back to the slides.
If we look at a list.
Number one is what direction of my facing.
So to figure that out what I'm going to do is set a default direction.
If we're rotating the ABC we should know what an unprotected NPC is to do that we're going to give it
a property of vector to the vector two is going to be one common zero.
So that's one pixel to the right and zero up and down.
That is everything we need.
Because when we then use dot rotated we can rotate it by our global rotation and we can easily figure
out what that value is.
I'll show you what to me.
Let's make a variable.
And this variable is going to be NPC
facing direction NPC facing direction is going to be a vector too and it's going to be one common zero
got rotated and what have been rotated by now I need to be a little careful here.
I'm going to have to use global rotation.
And the reason I'm having to use global rotation is the way I've organized the folders I've put security
cameras as a child of security cameras folder.
There's no to.
If I say what's your rotation.
It's going to calculate my rotation in relation to security cameras.
That's an inherent bug.
If for some reason something happens to this node.
I don't know I rotate the whole thing and then I go back and move the cameras I have now mess this up.
So let's put everything back and instead rely on global rotation.
We now know which way the NPC is facing.
What else are we to know about the flights willing to know what direction the player is in.
And this is the bit with the mafeking feel a little overwhelming.
Bear with me.
It's not that bad.
Let's imagine that we have a player this dude here and a soldier.
This dude here and we've placed them on an ex-wife it just like the coordinate system and because this
has got the x y grid is going the other way that I would normally think.
Remember positive wires down.
I cannot stress this enough because I cannot stop making this mistake.
Let's give them arbitrary positions so I'm going to say the soldier is a one come to and the player
is it to come or what I now know.
Both of their positions.
What I don't know is where the other one is to do that.
I could measure it and it turns out the difference here is one comment one right.
If I take the player position and subtract off the guard position I get that direction.
This isn't a coincidence.
Those values could be anything and it will still work out.
So we have variable direction to player cook and what's that going to be.
That's going to be clear dot position minus global dot position and there shouldn't be a capital G.
There should be a small G.
We're going to normalize this and if you're a little confused as to what that means.
Don't worry I will link you to the vector maths page on the goddard documentation so look it up.
Basically we're going to make this a lot simpler to do by using normalized.
It's a really helpful thing that vector 2 has a property or.
We now have everything we need all we need to do now is figure out what the angle to is.
Ordinarily we'd have to use a dot product which is a branch of mathematics that I just struggle with.
I find it very difficult but we don't need to do that.
Instead we can use a function or jeanerette function called angle to an angle to is awesome.
It goes like this.
But you make it.
If conditions are.
If direction 2 player dot angle to
NPC facing direction so what does this mean.
It means the angle from the player to to the embassy facing direction which is exactly what we need
is for less than EFO the tolerance.
Let's talk really quickly about why I'm using ever the Torrance rather than Torrance.
And in fact why I am about to change this concept.
Imagine if you will that this is our field of view.
Right now say that's the 44 and a half degrees or 45 degrees whatever it is I can't use this and say
it's 45 degrees because if the player is whether would f of V is going to be fine.
But if I say plus 45 degrees it won't get anything anti clockwise or counterclockwise.
That's because the facing direction is where we're taking this from positive values will be to the clockwise
direction to down and the negative values in the other direction.
We were divided by two and then willing to change the result to an absolute and absolute means were
going to get rid of any negative positive affirmation of tree of a's as positive.
In that case anything that's on this side or on this side up to that tolerance will work.
So let's make that work first ever bittorrent's is not 45.
It's actually twenty two point five but that's a stupid number on a nickel at 22.
We're going to go absolutely.
And that's going a rather negative positive thing will do.
We need to be careful with ffe tolerance because here we are getting.
Lowball rotation.
And this is in degrees level rotation is not in degrees.
It's in radion.
I could do global rotation degrees or I could cast f of tolerance from degrees to radion which will
apply this degree to radion.
Look how simple it is to see if this works as do it.
Frente.
Hello.
And just to make this even easier for ourselves to go to to view and I'm going to for the moment take
the animation player off auto load and move this camera.
To a Ford position just searches for debugging perhaps so save that.
Give that a shot.
Oh there's a small bug I put global dot position.
I mean global underscored position one more time.
OK.
So we're getting lots of Helo's.
Let me move out of the way and press clear and we're not getting any.
And then we move back should be just here.
Look at that.
Right on that line I got here in this corner and hit clear.
Great.
Now helo isn't that useful so as close to that.
And one of the do is sell the chap I'd like you to have the SPCS torch change colour if the player is
in the field of you remember that we need the Cada change back afterwards.
Otherwise the player won't know unless say so.
Pause the video give them a shot and remember if you don't know where a property is you can go in to
the torture scene and under colour mouseover and you can see property colour.
So that's the variable you be changing to pause the video give it a shot.
When you come back I'll show you my solution.
Welcome back.
What I'm going to do is I'm actually going to set up some more Constance somewhat of a constant red
equals unlist set that to colour.
It has American spelling so that rather you colour and I'm honoured to read.
Now this is going to be a red green blue thing that I'll show if I go one comma.
You can see it goes float are float G float b float.
In other words goes there float for the red float for the green float for the blue.
And optionally you Captain the Alpher.
So do is put four red quarter green quarter blue and I don't want any Alpher and ballast your white.
And that's going to be full red full green full blue because that's how a missive light works.
If you're not sure how red green blue values work there's plenty of resources out there.
But essentially one is full zero is off which would make sense.
Great.
Now I'm going to do something a little bit fancy.
I'm going to put in my player is an ever torrance's get the bigger return.
True and no one else can go return fops.
Why am I doing that.
Because I can now go to process and go.
If player is of tolerance look at that.
Now what we need to do.
I'm going to say torch.
And if you're not getting autocomplete here it's because you're in the wrong sense.
That's close the torching and that should work better torch dot colour equals red.
Else.
Torch dot column.
He pulls white or mystical.
How's this doing.
And we now have.
Play a little action.
Look at that.
Okay.
There's been quite a lot going on.
I am.
I'm just enjoying this moody lighting look at this this is awesome.
There's one more thing I need to do.
And let's put the animations back on so let's do that animations auto load.
And when we look at it now.
Ah yes.
In fact that 22 is a bit wrong isn't it let's change that camera body.
Let's call you 20.
Phenomenal.
Now we are going to put a range in this later so that if you're over here you won't be seeing.
But that is a really cool start to what we do in this video.
We've learned how to use angle to determine that is in the field of you.
We've also put in call an atmospheric feedback to let the player know if they're spotted.
This is a major step towards making our game functional so.
Excellent work.
See my next video.