Hello again wonderful God opiate or in this video we're going to bring player to into the game what
we want is to be able to control both players on the same keyboard in one script.
I don't want to second script.
I don't want to inherit from a script that has all the movement.
I want both players use the same script and nice and simply decide what key it has to use before we
do that let's bring the play in.
So I'm actually gonna start with that challenge list mix things up.
I'd like you to bring player to into the scene and the real challenge here is not instancing a player
that's easy.
The real challenge is remember that one of the players should have that blue material.
Unless you've made a material that's a different colour in which case they should have that.
So pause the video give them a shot and when you happy with the results come back and I'll show you
my solution.
I'm ok back.
Okay.
So the first thing we can do is we can just instance in a scene.
There's actually an easy an even easier thing we can do even easier.
It was an easy thing to say.
We can just duplicate the player so there is another instance of the player you know to have player
one facing the right direction so scana does a rotation usually at 90 degrees.
Great.
OK.
So I've decided that this is my blue character in order to make that happen.
There's a couple of things I could do.
I could do this in script that is possible right.
And to do that I would put in the ready function if your play a one how the defining play a one change
that that's doable.
However there's an easier way of doing this.
We have to edit all children.
And that allows me to edit all the children of the instance right so it's still the same instance I'm
just editing the instance itself.
I'm not editing the scene.
So now if I go into cube doods the actual mash and I find the material I can drop in the material so
let's go to models.
Cube dude and there's my blue material.
Areas.
Now this will remain true while editable children's open.
If I make this non-adaptive or children it's not going to get rid of the information but when I press
play.
He's green and I don't want to great.
I want to be blue.
Let's make him eligible children again and press play.
And now it's checking for the differences.
A case of soliloquizing got.
If you're changing something an inspector of an is an editable child of an instance.
You need to keep that innocence editable.
OK so right now we have two players.
However this ball bounces a little bit crazy isn't it.
However they're both using the same control.
So what I've got is a glorified foosball table controller right there.
They're effectively the same character in two places.
Which is kind of weird and slightly awesome.
Let's close this window because the bouncing ball is making me a little bit dizzy and I'm going to just
turn the Bout's down.
You can have a bouts of zero point to five for an hour.
What we do is we can take out the keybindings and say and make a variable called up verbal could down
etc. and then we could bring that script out of here and extend that script to play one and it sent
a different script and play it too.
But I don't want to do that.
I want to get this very simple.
Instead we're going to just slightly alter this part of the script Take a look at how input is working.
Okay so input.
That's a you know basic function is action pressed and then there's a string.
Let's go to the slides.
Input is action is action whether it's pressed or just pressed is checking for a string and that input
not the node but the actual key binding or the joypad direction whatever it is.
We can give that any string name we like.
Okay so it doesn't have to be y up there.
The default one for if you're using UI elements.
If we wanted to we could call it use we could call it high.
We did that before right used disguise whatever it is we can call that string anything we want.
And we know how to can catinat strings because we did that a lot in luny lips that was what that project
was.
So why don't we can castigate the players number in.
We just have to create a variable called something like play idae make an export variable so that we
could just change it the inspector and then do something like this.
Input is action.
Pressed up can cat an 8 player idae.
So let's do exactly that.
First I need to go into project settings and into input map because I need to put those in right because
right now we're using these you line up down left right.
I don't need to delete those I don't need to touch them I'm just going to new you once gonna start with
them up one and then up too.
All I'm doing is typing in the action and adding it and it's showing up here got no keybindings yet.
I'll do that the Second I've done up let's do right it's going clockwise right 1 right two down one
down to
left 1.
Left to great.
So now let's put the binding since I on to press the plus sign.
It's a key.
My left hand side my player ones can have the B C D.
My pleasure to have cursor so pesky B.
Let's be up a while ago a guy looks at the right one.
Yes I have right.
Writes
down.
Do do do do.
I could fast for this but frankly it's actually pretty quick.
It's probably worth it just to show you the entire process and that's it that's all process.
Now we need to replace some strings and this is the bit that gets a little bit tedious because we're
using a dynamic language right so we can't just say okay renamed is variable.
So what I do is I go instead of you I up.
This is now Karpe underscore and then the plate number.
So percentage desk's I am congratulating a string and what string I can catch and eating while going
to make one let's make a new export very we'll put it right here.
But the speed export variable where I d and the default value is 1.
Okay so let's can kasak that in clear eyed.
And you know what there's up so let's just copy that and put it on the next line as well.
Unless you doubt something over here go down a scented show.
S close the string concatenates and play out.
I did.
But another one of those fellas just can't do this.
It's really readable.
I should probably put a space after the percentage because you know it's a little bit easier.
And same thing here.
I'm on the pace that just get myself started this is left.
And let's copy that.
And same thing here.
But now we're doing right.
Now when I run this you'll see that I've missed the crucial part but the expert variable in let's actually
play to play areas.
So play ready to weather.
I'm calling him because his name is cube dude and dude is normally male.
I haven't checked the gender preferences and now wct will control one character cursor errors or the
other.
And we have kaleb's isn't correct.
We have a to play game wasn't correct.
Probably because they didn't bind that correctly is going back to project settings.
What's up to you.
Is the wrong key I was wrong.
Okay so it's now up.
Perfect.
One more time with feeling.
Curse.
There is a deep to play a local multiplayer game now.
As yet there's still something is missing we don't have a sound in the game.
We don't have any way of scoring.
We don't have a scoreboard.
We don't have actual games script but we do have the fundamentals in place.
We're off to a great start.
So in this video.
Nice and simple note quick when we've learned how to can catch any strings in order to make local multiplayer
controls work in one script on one device.
So excellent work.
I'll see you in the next video.