Hello again, you tremendous golf to people, OK?
How game is coming along nicely.
We've got a way of detecting goals and the rest of it, but we want to get the the pitch.
The entire game state back into its original position.
Every time I go to.
That's what winning.
We are resetting the game when a goal is scored.
When you go to school to will do the following things.
We want to stop the ball and the players.
We don't want that thing.
We can keep scoring a scoring and scoring and resetting the timeout.
We need to give the players time to celebrate and or fume.
In other words, we're going freeze the game for about five seconds and let both players understand
what's happened and process what's happened.
Then we need to move the ball and the players back to the start.
Finally, we need to allow the ball and the players to move.
So we're got to freeze the game.
Wait five seconds.
We can move everything back to the start and I'm going to unfreeze the game.
That tells me we need some way of tracking if things can move and we need a place for things to go.
So let's start with a place for things to go as minimize all of these.
I'm like a brand new organization load.
Just give me a simple note.
Come back.
Which go.
La, la, la, la, la.
There it is.
And I'm gonna call it swarm stop positions.
Easy to write.
Start positions.
And what one would do is I'm going to use every entrepreneur.
Right.
That I'm going to use some position.
3D notes.
Okay.
So we've used position to D.
When we were playing a high spice's, we are making high surmises, visual, 3D, exact.
Same thing in 3D space.
That is it is a basic spatial node with a different UI.
That's all this is.
Okay.
So it does.
If I take a look at the documentation.
It literally inherits from spatial, it's spatial with no other stuff.
It's just there so that we can work in the editor, see what's happening.
Let's come out of preview mode right now.
We have a position, 3-D.
I want to call this bowl stop a bowl spot because the bowl will actually small and that's just starting.
And let's move that up to where the bowl is now.
Be a little bit higher.
And that's where that lives.
I won't make too small.
I will make.
Position three.
I'd call it player one, stopped to duplicate that and call it player two stopped.
I'm naming them the same so that we can use that trick of taking the string.
That's the name and bringing in the player I.D..
Right.
That's gonna be really useful.
It.
OK, so let's get the transform of Pleyel one.
Minus five one.
And let's move the plan would start to this transform.
Minus five.
And one, OK, so I went do the exact same thing was planned to start.
And I'm going to guess this is five one.
We also know we're going to need a timer.
Let's bring out Timon and.
And let's set this up.
It's gonna be a one shot.
When you say zero, it's going to stop.
Give me a five second timer.
And then these signals that generate a signal for it on time out.
And this will go to the game script.
Brit.
So on time out, we're going to reset the pitch.
OK, for resettling the patients, make a function that others a function reset, which, as I say,
this is not just the patients being reset while it is reset pitches.
Fine move will stick with that.
OK, first, let's get the bullet's position.
So.
Okay.
Now, I could move the plasma bowl in this function, but that's not a great idea.
The ball needs be responsible for the ball.
Is the player's need for response for the players.
So instead we're going to use a group code.
Okay, so let's get Tre.
Dalt Coal Group.
We haven't named this yet, so I'm Nikola's.
What are they, the actors that agents that things that move in the game?
Game pieces.
As opposed to scenery.
Right.
Game pieces.
And we're going to call reset.
OK, so now let's make a group called Let's add the both players and the ball to the group of game pieces.
Said play one to the game pieces and play two game pieces.
Three.
Now, the ball also needs to be in that group.
So let's add you to the game pieces.
And now they match the groups only go one group.
And if I just double check all play one.
Player two.
Fantastic.
So we now have three things in that group now because the ball doesn't yet have a script.
We have to add that I and double check.
We want a function called reset.
It's okay to go into the main bowl.
So the thing that everything else is instant's from and we're going to add in a bowl dot G.D. and let's
give it a function.
Function.
Reset.
Function reset, and it's also gonna need a variable.
It's going gonna have to track where its spawn is, gonna call it my spawn.
Now, this is going to have to come in when it's ready.
And if I just double check the level right now, the ball is coming in before the stop position.
That's nugatory some input stock positions right at the top above the pitch.
I want that to come in first.
Okay.
So in the bowl script, let's settle already function.
What do we want to happen right at the beginning?
Well, we need to find that node that set mice.
Let's set my spawn, my spawn.
And that's going to be wherever that node happens to be.
Well, let's find it.
Let's go to interlacing tree.
Right.
So we're getting centuries ago right into here and then getting roots go right to the top.
And within that, I want to find note.
And we want.
What do we call it?
List.
Spell check.
You're in stock positions, bull spawn.
And it has to be written exactly as it is that.
And I do want this to be recursive.
I go into every folder and just double check.
We need one more argument, it's take a look at that is is this owned by me?
No, it's not.
That's fine.
So we can put false for that.
OK.
So when the game starts, it's going to set the variable my spawn to be that position node.
Right.
So not the translation.
The actual note.
OK.
So on reset, what's going to happen.
Well we want to set translation.
To be my spawn.
Dot translation.
OK, so if this is right, when this is so, what's gonna happen is we're going to call the reset function
and it's going to move to wherever that position is.
That means we can move this around, have multiple kinds of levels or from one tweak in minutes to Hymie,
that's too low.
Maybe I don't want it.
The center, wherever it happens to be, the game will adapt.
And I like that.
Let's go back to the bull script.
I want to stop the bull from moving.
So if I saw the ball moving, I can use the rigid body, which this is right.
This is a rigid body.
It has a thing called an access lock.
Now we've got angular X, Y and Z.
That's how much it rotates.
That's gonna make no difference to us.
It's a ball and it's not it's rotation doesn't really matter.
But the línea.
How much is it moving in each direction that matters.
So we need to make sure that when the game is reset, all three of these are unlocked.
To do that, let's go.
Axis lock.
Línea X equals false.
This is remember when we reset the pitch?
This is being unlocked.
We've already locked.
It wouldn't do that minute.
I want to get it three times with control, be x, y and set.
Awesome.
OK.
So that's the unlock.
However, I also need a freeze function.
Right.
I need to do the opposite.
So function freeze.
And I was going to take this.
Axis Lochlyn here, that equals false climate change to true.
And let's change it to X and duplicate two more times Y and Z.
Right.
So we also need to call this freeze function.
So when the goal is score, we need to call freeze.
To do that is going to level into the game script.
We've already got this goal detection thing happening.
Right.
So let's go get tree one fact.
You know what?
We just duplicate this lifeless duplicate line fault.
Toby, move, move, move.
And it's sort of calling reset.
We're going to call freeze.
Awesome.
That is gonna be quite useful.
That's gonna lock all three pieces.
Now, it's not gonna start the timer.
So let's start the timer,
which is timer dot start.
And now we can use this time it's time out, right?
Well, that's just gonna be a reset pitch.
We've really got this function in here.
Okay.
Now, as I look at this, I realize that, OK, we have this lovely function.
That is exactly what it says.
But it's one line of code.
We have this function that does exactly what it says and it's the same line.
Honestly, we probably don't need that function.
I'm going to move this down to here.
Get rid of reset pitch entirely and get rid of that function.
OK.
Let's see if this works.
We have a lot at play.
But if we score goal posts, which is not how I love to score, go on.
Score goal.
If I show frightening incompetence, my own game.
Thank you.
There he is.
I get the ball.
It's frozen.
Five seconds later, the ball will come back.
Come back.
The ball will come back.
Okay.
That feels pretty good.
Now it's not the players.
So locking the players that will have to go into play script.
So let's open one of the players.
Does matter which go into the template.
These guys are not rigid bodies.
They don't have access locked.
I mean, you can kind of get in there, but it's actually a little bit difficult to get in there.
So instead, we could use a variable.
I'm gonna make a variable.
Court can move and it's going to start as true.
So now function freeze is going to be can move he calls false function reset.
It's going to allow us to move can move Eagles troop.
Now, we also need to move them back that spawn.
But right now, I've got to freeze it.
Don't do anything.
So let's fix that function.
Move.
All right.
I need to make sure and move and slide.
Only happens if you can move.
If I can move.
Move and slide.
I don't have to define can move because it's a boolean is either true or false.
OK, so if true.
Move and slide it false.
Do nothing.
Let's find out.
We're not gonna play as yet.
Gonna move that kick and.
Okay.
Now we're still animating a facing, but I can fix that.
Let's go over to doo doo doo doo doo.
An animating emotional length is great this zero and can move, then animate.
Hope can be with the scope and I'll face forward.
I mean, we could have them rotating like that, but I suppose a second line if can move.
So same exact test.
Let.
In and it hit it.
Oh, OK.
If motion length is greater than zero and can move.
Right.
So it's that exact test.
I'm going to move blew out the way.
I'm going to run forwards and everything freezes.
Now, we will put in some some stuff in there to make it look at the game hasn't actually crashed.
But that looks fine.
And it's going back in.
OK.
So all that works.
Now we need to actually move the plans.
Now, any of this is gonna be very similar.
We'll make a brand new variable called my spawn.
OK.
And we need a ready function, right?
We need to define this right at the beginning.
So let's put this right at the top.
I mean, we don't have to right at the top.
I like getting ready from the top because I happen right to begin to function.
Ready to do.
OK.
So my spawn equals.
Well, we already have the basics of this, right.
So we can go get tree get roots.
So get the same tree.
Get to the root of the century.
And now I need you to find the node.
With a specific name.
Let's take a look what his name is.
If I go into the level and into the spawn's, which are coming in before the players, we have player
one start.
Player to start.
OK.
So for this to work, we need to get the script into the player, Judy.
And I want to play.
And then we go to concatenated in so percentage.
S stopped.
Could also call it spawn.
But I didn't.
Now, for that to work, we need to actually use that percentage.
So let's modulo player I.D..
And it is recursive and it is not owned by this particular node.
OK.
So that will now define my sport, which means now on reset we have can move equals true and translation.
He calls my spawn dot.
Translation.
Okay, I'm asking for that just before I can move, I'd like you to move before you unfreeze.
I realize that having the same frame, but it just logically feels good and a small wipe there because
I managed to create a little bit of bug on my side while I was fixing the animation bucketed earlier
that I told you about.
Hopefully you don't have to, but if I press play, we should see a real moves correctly and like a
score, a goal and animal stops moving four, five and eventually be coming back about now.
Boop!
Ha!
Now we're not facing the right direction yet, but that's OK.
I'm pretty happy with that and I'm pretty sure that the players will start moving instantly.
That feels like really good progress.
So excellent luck.
And I'll see you in the next video.