Hello again, you superb got to people in this video, we're going to start adding a gooey we're going
to look at how to use Tudi in 3D.
Now, this is one of the cool things about got it right.
It has actual 2D and 3D rendering and you can layer them on top of each other.
So in some engines, if you want to do that, you have to make a plane and it floats in 3D, but you
lock it so it looks like INTUITY and got a you can just have 2D and 3D elements to do that wouldn't
create new scene and are custom node is going to be a canvas layer.
And all this is, is just a layer on the camera, layer on the canvas.
So in that let's make a nine patch rectangle nine patch there.
And you can see of what you got selected on the graphics on the interface.
We've got banner hanging.
That's gonna be my texture.
Now, this is too small.
When it erect aluminum, it is less than big.
What do you think about was my super size with about a thousand pixels on the X?
Is that too much?
I quite like it.
Maybe it's too much.
I could do a thousand for now and 120 feels good.
And we want our patch margins.
So like here you go with 12 hotlist, 12 feet.
I think it might be a bit low on this.
Let's find out.
Well, that's not bad, is it?
Not quite.
They're still missing something so high.
How about 20?
Yeah, I think that's perfect.
OK.
So here is our banner.
Nicole Banner.
And that's what else goes on.
OK.
So I'm to save this on a brand new folder called Gooey.
And want to call it gooey before any further, let's see how that actually works in the game.
You know what?
I need to actually lay this, don't I?
So let's put you anchored to the top center, because that's what it does position it takes.
And, yeah, that looks pretty good.
And actually, let's do the layout to the top center as well.
So send a top.
Awesome.
OK.
Let's see how that looks.
I gonna go in the game and I'm an instance in the Gooey.
OK.
Now, you'll notice I can't see here because we're in 3D view, like a press tutee, if you'd like to
see it.
But look what happens when we actually play the game.
Here's Albanna, right?
And it takes up the right amount of space.
That's looking pretty good.
Now we can make it smaller, we could play around with it, but I'm pretty happy with that.
So all we've done is we've told it there's a canvas layer here, another rendering layer.
And in this case, we just want Tudi information on it so we can have both the same time.
All right.
At this point, I want to play around a little bit.
So I've got this nice font from Kennie that I want to use.
I'm going to put in each box container and I can make it look very pretty.
So let's start with our each box container, which I will put as a child of the matter.
Each box container ships are just.
And let's see, this wants to be a full rectangle.
And I think it can lead to margins, isn't it?
I'm gonna stick with 20, see how that feels.
See me minus 20.
Minus 20.
Okay.
Looking good.
Now, we don't have a theme, and we should probably make one because I want to use these fonts.
We probably will be using them in other places as well.
Let's make a new thing.
And let's in our default font up sites like this default font.
So new dynamic font, no new dynamic font.
There it is.
And let's see, we've got a fund, which I'm Lodin.
France can be bold and we need a good size for this, don't we?
So let's say 40.
Kate is big and chunky.
I like it.
Let's put on the filter and the Mitt maps make it nice and rounded.
And that actually feels really good.
That's gonna be very big for buttons, but I'm going for that feel.
Right.
Big, blocky kind of children's blocks, kind of a game.
So let's put in some labels.
I'm going to put in three labels as a child of each box container.
So new label and this just duplicate that twice.
OK, so we have three labels in here.
And the second one I'm in, right?
Dude, kick about.
It's got to line to the center, and that's looking pretty good.
And I need the actual each box content on the center as well.
So click on the box container and can sense of that.
And there we go.
OK.
So that is going to be my label.
I'm sure to call it a consulate label and call it title.
OK.
So this one one cool player, one school and this one I'm gonna call player to school.
Boop.
That's pretty good.
Now, let's actually put these in as zero and zero.
Now, I do want to say zero cube do give about zero.
We need to split it up.
So it's got a plus container custom, Constance.
And I'm going to just increase a custom separation.
Separation.
Custom separation.
30 pixels feels a be good.
We could go a little higher, 40 maybe.
And I don't know how high we want the game to go.
I feel like three goals should reset the game.
But maybe you want higher.
In which case, you could go to your score and make sure that the right score aligns to the right and
the left hand score like the left.
I'm thinking that's pretty solid.
And that is our basic goal.
Let's see how that looks in game.
Clearly is not working yet, but yeah.
Feels good to have the background in.
We move it down a bit if we wanted to.
But look, it's it's hanging.
Right.
Perfect.
Let's make it actually work to do that.
I need to give the Gooey was rename it Gary.
Whoops, not mine, I guess, a cool you UI graphic user interface.
Yeah, let's give it a script.
Obviously this empty template.
All right.
We are going to call this from the level itself, and the main thing we want is to update the scores
as we get a thing called update score.
And we need to know two things here, right?
We need to know which players score has gone up.
And what is the new school?
Let's do that.
Let's say we have an argument call play an argument called school.
We don't really need to track what the score was before.
We're just replacing the information.
Okay.
We need the label.
So let's make a new variable and call it a school label.
And here we're going to use the same trick we did earlier with passing in the string, but I can't use
dollar to do that.
Which looks like that.
And then I do this.
It's going to cause errors.
It doesn't know that that exists.
She's gonna say there's no such there's no such note here.
So instead of using the shortcut dollar, remember, Dollar is alias Solnik.
Look for an alias.
Forget node, which means get node, because if we use get node, we have to put a string.
Right, a node path as a string.
So here I can drag in my play one score into the script.
I was gonna do that and drag it in.
Huh.
And instead of one I'm going to go for Santa Gests.
Now I can go percentage play.
So you gonna modula that in.
So we're gonna get play one or two from the from the main game function and it's gonna replace player
with that.
I also noticed that these.
How in the wrong place?
And that's looking pretty good.
OK.
Now let's update it.
Well, going to school level, which we've just defined, and we know which player it is because that's
what we've just looked up through the argument.
Now I'm going to change the text property and it's going to be the string or whatever the new score
is.
Now, we have to change it to a string because we using a label.
Right.
So the score is actually an integer.
That's how it's held in memory.
But we're gonna be changing it to a string.
And that should work fine.
Now, we have to do is actually wire it into the main game.
That's got a little.
And in our main game script, we've already got something here that can detect when a goal is being
entered.
So we'll start the timer and we're going to update the score.
Let's make a brand new functional update school.
And update school just needs the goal I.D. They're going to bring that in.
Goal I.D..
We need to know which goal has detected the ball.
Now, we don't really care which player kicked it last because you can score goals.
So that should work fine.
So let's go.
Function update school.
We should not have a capital s. and it takes this argument here.
I'm a good player, remember, it doesn't really matter what the argument was called when it passed.
It just matters the order.
So there is an argument in position zero in here which is referring to it as player.
It doesn't really matter.
I could call this king, Bob, but I'm not going to, especially as King Bob is two words.
So when they call that player, you could call it go idea if you want.
But updating the school for the player makes more logical sense to me.
OK.
So we need a variable to know.
The new score is so new score.
Now, for this to work, we need to actually holding the score in memory.
So we need to make an instant variable.
So it's a new variable.
Michael's player.
One on a score score equals zero.
Duplicate that.
Now just change that, to play.
To score.
OK, so back to update school, OK?
So the next thing to do is to actually figure out who's scores gone up.
So if this player is one update, this score, if it's to up to this, I could use an if else.
I think I want to use a match which works in very similar ways.
A match player.
OK, so if player is one.
Then player one school, player one school.
There it is, goes up by one.
And new school.
Is equal to play player one school.
And I asked you the same exact thing again with two.
So if we've matched player to be the integer two, then player to score goes up by one.
Just make that neater.
And the new score.
Is equal to player to score.
All right.
So we're now tracking the memory now.
Let's actually pass that through.
We've called this function so we know someone has scored so we can go back.
This indentation level and all I need to do is go to the gooey.
Which isn't actually called Gleeks, I renamed it afterwards, isn't it?
Didn't I?
So let's rename you.
There we go.
So.
Let's go to the guri and we want to call the function update score.
Now we need two things, right?
We need the player and we need the new school.
And if I've done this right, and I really hope I have and I press play, which I've just done, I can
over here move the blue, play out the way, kick the ball and it crashes.
And that's because I've done a silly thing.
I put the bracket here, my bad black bracket should be there.
So I get my kidney function.
I need to make sure that I don't actually stop getting that out until I've brought in that player.
And that should work just fine.
Let's redo that.
And now I'm with the blue player.
Score a goal and the number goes up by one and a few seconds later that at that.
Boom.
Yep.
We now have a working school system.
Let's just check the blues.
The blue-black do the same thing on a move.
You score a goal looking good and that is our working score system.
Now, the moment this will just take up forever and we don't yet have any fancy effects that are going
to happen when you score a goal.
But I think that's really good progress.
So excellent luck.
And I'll see you in the next video.