Hello again lovely God people in this video we got to make goals work or them some functional goals.
So we're going to do is we're going to make sure that each goal of got one highlighted here and the
one here is going to have a way of detecting when the ball at us.
So what we do is I mean to go into the goals because all goals are going to have this area.
And I will add an area note.
Now we've seen area study this area.
It works in a very similar way with an important yet pretty obvious distinction.
It's three dimensional.
So now when we add a collision
I need to be a collision shape.
Now you could use a plain shape but I have had mixed results with this and I think the reason for that
is it matters which direction you come from the plane.
I'm not entirely sure if that's it.
It might just be that if you're going too fast it might not notice that you've gone through so only
a box ship and this box is clearly way too big.
So one would do is I'm going to make it oh around.
As I say the same size of this post like a citizen actually have to be the same size of the post.
Let's take a look.
It's currently zero point three or zero point two.
Like move it over to the post I can see it's a little bit wider from the post.
What's important is it can't go in front of this post so I'll say zero point two is actually fine.
On the Z.
Let's move you back to the centre.
So on transforms I put you back on zero on the axe.
It needs to be a little bit wider than that.
There doesn't.
So let's say the X the extant on a X is one point five probably two two is just at the limit there.
But that's going to work to raise it up a bit.
That's going to be my why not buy one.
Maybe that might be a bit much.
I'm thinking that's a little bit high.
But I can probably work with it.
I don't mind if it goes through the floor.
I guess realistically there's very few instances where the ball is going to fly over.
But just in case let's lower the exanta a little bit and say it's oh quite seven five they'll good.
Yeah that looks pretty good.
OK.
So what's that.
That is the zero point seventy five raised by zero point seventy five.
Look at that.
That's pretty good isn't it.
And I was going to move it back to the actual line right up against it.
Now when it crosses that line that's going to counsel the gold.
So let's see where we are.
We are at zero zero point five zero point one to five almost exactly.
So that makes me very happy.
All right.
Next the minister's mission when the correct collision shape.
So my area which I'm going to rename our goal detection
detection.
There it is.
What I want to do is I'm going to go down to collision and I take it off the pitch.
It's not pitch it's not a ball it's not a player it doesn't need any of those bit will detect the ball
not the pitch that's vital and not the play is important.
Why is it vital.
Because it's going to intersect with a pitch immediately.
Right.
It's in the floor.
Not the players because I don't want this to trigger every time the player manages to somehow get in
here.
I don't know quite when they do it but bad practice so.
The only thing I can interact with is the ball.
Let's put that in there and get in the game.
And we should see gold detection is where I on the side right there.
Can't see it against the blue and there should be another one over on goal to give to little children.
OK.
Now we need some form of script.
So let's make a brand new script in our game and I'm going to call this game g-day.
That feels a good name and we put my scrips hold Holder because that's just the structure we've set
up.
No other reason doing this is I want to connect to a signal.
And as you probably know by now you can only connect a signal to a script you can't do it's an empty
note.
Now the key here is that this one has to report a score for player one and this one has a report score
for play too so she can at ellingham say opposites.
So what we do is on a get to my first goal detection so our goal detection is right there.
And I will connect it as a signal.
And I want body entered and I can connect to game and I actually want to pass in an extra argument is
already going to pass embody.
That's fine but I want to identify which gollott is.
So I'm a puzzle an integer and the integer is going to be which goal is being scored.
Now I'm currently working with Goal 1 but I want to carry.
I want to figure out who score has gone up and if Goal 1 is being entered it's play a 2.
So the integer I'm adding is not 1 it's two.
And I'm just going to connect that and do the exact same thing on goal detection too.
So body entered connect and then add the integer and this one is 1.
Whoops.
And I should probably connect that to the correct plexion.
So let's connect it to the game at an integer of value 1.
So let's just double check what's happening in the mouse over it.
So tell me on got what it entered byrns 1.
So that's coming in to goal to and a gold one I should have the exact same thing with a different bind
buy it too.
Great.
So now what I'd like to do is challenge you to make sure this is working.
So here's the deal.
We have this brand new function right on gold a tank should entered body and were actually not just
bringing in body.
We're bringing in gold widely.
You can call it go Eddy.
Call it player idae whatever it is.
I'd like you to use print to show which player scored in the console.
When the ball at the goal area now try and not just print a number right which print one or two I'm
likely to print Player 2 has scored a goal or play on one scored or goal for Player 2 or whatever it
is right.
Try and get the information across.
So possibly the give that a shot and when you're ready come back and I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
OK.
Well in the beginning is quite easy.
We just need a print function and I'm going to concatenate stuff in.
So what I need to do is say player space and then add in and then only this goal I did.
But his goal eddys an integer is a string.
So when it cast it as a string
and then just do that.
And that should be everything I need.
Let's see if I've done this correctly.
So I'm not going to maximize anything to see the console move Player 2 at the way.
Player 1 has scored there was a fun little bug there.
Did you catch it.
The ball went in.
See if I can get the ball back and get killed over there.
Made a game I can't play no.
Come back.
Let's skip forward.
Pretend that I'm competent at my own game.
Check it out.
Every time the ball goes in it's entering at least twice.
Right now I didn't put an extra space in there which is silly.
Some of the space in there but at some point we have to fix this bug.
But right now we have a working goal player one has scored.
So we're off to a good start and that's a nice easy quick win in the next video we're going to figure
out how to stop the ball from bouncing out.
But so far so good.
So nice easy quick video.
And in this video all the done interviews aryana to track when a goal is scored It's very simple but
it's a good building block.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.