Hello again you splendid go to people in this video we're gonna bring in sound effects and music and
I'm going to make a little confession here although this is not a complicated topic it is kind of ironic
because I did manage to record this entire video just now with my mike switched off so I get a sound
effect video with no sound I am the best teacher ever.
OK.
Let's bring the noise using audio stream player.
I'm going get into Gordo and let's go straight into the player scenes.
I'm a press player and click on the open and edits I think and I'm going to bring in a brand new note.
So if I type an audio you'll see that there are actually three different types.
In fact let's look at the slide so I've got an audio stream player and an audio stream play 2D and 3D.
And the difference between these is position audio stream player inherits from node so it doesn't have
any kind of position data it plays equally everywhere audio stream play 2D on the other hand inherits
from no 2D so it has an x position and a Y position or an x value on a y value the closer you get to
the position of that node the louder it'll get audio stream player 3D exactly the same but it also has
a z position or z position entirely up to you.
So let's switch off this annoying red light and get out the slides.
I'm going to add an audio stream play a note for now let's take a look at the Inspector we've got a
few properties can play with the stream.
That's the sound face gonna play.
I've already opened my SFX folder down here so I've got my sound effects my music ready to go volume
and decibel.
Nice and easy pitch how high how low is it playing is it auto playing and so on.
One thing you'll notice is this only one stream I can only play one sound per audio stream player if
I want multiple sounds to be playing simultaneously I'm going to need multiple audio stream playing
notes if I don't need them playing simultaneously I can just change the stream property here.
So let's take a call he sounds I'm saying jump and put it in there and I can listen to it by pressing
play playing rather.
So playing well that's looping maybe I don't want looping in fact if I have a slipping a press space
and unless I tell the sound to stop it's going to loop forever that's gonna get really annoying.
He's a turn looping on and off for sound can make sure I've got my sound effect selected and then the
top left having a press input and you see it says loop.
Turn that off and you must press report.
If I don't press report nothing has changed.
So press report and now the soundtrack will play once and stop.
There are times you will want looping sound effects maybe I don't know the sound of a breeze or a trickling
stream or music but I don't want it for now so I'm gonna just deselect that and get back in my scene
and you know all we hear let's make sure that pain that's the sound effects going to play when he's
hurt is also not looping So switch off loop and re import good coin won't be looping anyway so that's
fine.
And the two pieces of music we can leave looping back to the same view again now have a couple of options
here.
If I want pain and jump to be able to play simultaneously I need to audio string players I'll have to
name them.
However the logic of the game tells me that this will never happen because when I'm jumping I'll play
jump and while when I hit something I'll fly up as if I'm jumping I want the player to hit a sound effect
of pain I want that feedback to be good.
So one thing to do is just have the one audio stream play a note and switch the streaming code.
OK so let's get into the script as my play script and scroll to find.
Jump.
There it is.
OK.
So what is that the first thing to do is set the stream so let's go audio stream player not stream equals.
And I could just well be careful.
You could just drag it in here but this is not a sound.
This is a string that won't work.
In fact I'll say if I press play I jump.
I wait.
You can't put a string there.
Great.
So I need to convert this from a string to an actual file to do that.
I'm going to use load.
Well this is actually doing is costing much in the same way.
If I change a string to an integer or an integer to a float I can put load and change the string from
just a string of characters to an actual place in the file system.
Okay so I can put that in but I'm not playing it.
So let's go.
Audio string player dot play I don't need to put in any kind of check.
Right.
So I could go if audio stream player not playing I actually what the opposite of this right so I could
go if not playing then do this but this makes no sense because it's not looping anyway and it'll only
play if we press jump and we're on the floor.
So just holding down the spacebar won't do anything.
So I don't need this check.
This is meaningless.
I will take that out.
Let's just make sure that we will actually pay some of that when we jump
Haha awesome.
Okay.
That's looking good and now let's switch out the string to paint dot O.G. when we heard something good
that's the heart function and I would put it right to life.
So let's go.
Audio Stream player dot stream equals put as a file and just drag pain in there and make sure we actually
play it so audio stream plan don't play.
Let's see how this works.
That works at
awesome.
OK so these sound effects now working now.
I will put some music in now.
I'm not going to put the music on the player because it doesn't depend on the player.
Instead I'm gonna put it on level one second level one and go right up to the top.
You know let's minimize these hazards that I need to see them.
Let's just use control at our child node and it's a brand new audio stream player and let's call it
B GM.
For background music it's a B G M.
Right.
So you'll notice we've got these two pieces of music and I'll link them to right to in a section but
just to remind you I got them both from open game art dot org and I've got Chip tunes I've actually
picked one of these.
If you want to pick another one go for it.
And I've also picked some a park by Scribe and we can listen to those.
Let's head back over here and have a quick listen.
So Chip tunes whoops.
Click on music player listened chip June and play
very lovely.
And then this summer Park which sounds a bit more like this
great.
So I'm going to clear that up and here's my challenge for you.
I'd like you to pick your background music listen to chip tune adventures one awesome a park one and
make them the background music for you hoppy day's game.
Now you don't have to pick those if you're not planning on distributing your game anyway.
Pick any music you'd like.
If you are planning on distributing it make sure you pick one with with the rights that you can actually
use both of the tunes I've used on the creative commons zero license which means you can use them for
any purpose without attribution without paying anybody.
Go ahead but use whatever you like.
Quick caveat Gordo won't read MP 3s and P3 is proprietary format Gordo is an open source engine.
No one is paying for the licence from P3 so if you do want an MP 3 you'll have to convert it to an O.G.
G file or wildfires and let that pick the background music for your game and make sure that music plays
When the game starts as a couple of different ways you could do that.
But pause the video.
Get that going.
Pick your music.
Get it started when the game starts and when you come back I show you my solution
and welcome back.
Okay I think I'm gonna hit some of polka quite like this one it feels very relaxing.
I realize relaxes into Word but on the knees anyway as a couple of things we could do here we could
make a script for the GM right.
So let me put it right here.
Announcer To show you how this work and I can make a ready function.
There it is.
And I could just go play and that will work fine.
However why would we want to make a script.
There's a much easier way of doing this song is going to close the script.
I don't want to save it discard it.
Great.
Let's make sure I haven't created it here.
I have just delete it out of the tree.
Okay.
I don't actually want any kind of script for this.
I'm compress auto play and now in a press play.
Awesome.
Now there was something on it is just now when we tried that that let me play it for you.
I'm trying to jump and get some time and it's cutting off the sound effect.
I read like that.
So you know what my idea of bringing this streaming with code wasn't a good one.
Let's change it.
So I set of audio stream play at the school this jump SFX and it's put a brand new audio stream plan
note in there and call this pain as effects and not drag the right sound effect into the right one.
So pain has this stream and jump has this stream and now back to the script.
Let's get rid of the bit where I load the stream.
That's now redundant but this is not no longer enough.
There is no note called audio stream.
You are now called Pain SFX.
Got to jump into the exact same thing button.
There it is.
I don't need you an audio stream player is not a known name anymore.
So now you are called Jump SFX and now in the first play
great I can hear both the same time.
Now I'm getting a little bit of distortion here so I could bring the volume down a bit.
So let's say minus five decibels
and just to make absolutely sure on the click on the audio tab here and just make sure that nothing
here goes into the reds let's press play I'm still a bit loud but you know what I think that'll work.
And one more time.
It's not distort anymore.
Maybe my music's a little loud so I could turn that down let's say minus 10
That's too quiet isn't it.
Maybe minus five.
Just bring that line with everything else.
Looking good.
Okay.
And that brings us to the end of this video in this video.
We've looked at the three different audio stream play notes and what you'd use each one.
How to Change of sounds is looping and how to use auto play.
So what music did you use.
I did you could find the entire different How's your game coming along.
I'd love to hear your progress.
Meanwhile great stuff and I'll see you in the next video.