Hello you wonderful people.
Let's finish off lunar lips.
We're going to learn how to export so nice and easy.
I mean I go back in here and before I get started I'm actually gonna make a decision.
I've now got two competing scripts going on right so I've got my Jason solution and I got my storybook
and they're both live.
So I'm going to get rid of one of these.
I'm going to delete my Jason completely I've made the decision.
I want a node based solution.
If you didn't then you would delete the other stuff.
So going to do to do uncommon these I don't need this template one and I don't need this.
Get from Jason function at all.
All right let's just double check that I haven't broken he thinks I may go in here see if the game runs.
Can I have a name.
Bob.
And now pencil an adverb bubbly and an adjective Bob like once upon a time some call Bob a pencil flavored
sandwich which made you feel bubbly inside.
It was a bob like day.
Great.
Now I've also noticed that I haven't actually got all eight of my stories.
That's okay for now I'm going to have my three here.
So the downside of using my note based system is it takes longer to get the stuff in here.
But the advantages it's all in one place and I can see it on with him to do and to go into this Resources
folder and open farm manager because I don't actually need storybook Jason so I could delete it.
So I'm just gonna cut mine and put it on my desktop so I can find it again if I need it for some reason
and later video.
Also Okay so how do we export our project.
Well what it is going to project and hit export and you'll see here there's nothing selected I haven't
downloaded anything.
So what I need is to add a preset for an add a preset I can export for Android.
IOW each team Al Mac OS universe a Windows desktop and Linux I'm running this on a Windows desktop my
laptop is Linux but I want a Windows executable so I won't hit windows.
You'll see here I don't have one I can't get it.
So I can press this little link here manage export templates and it'll automatically link to what I
need.
I'm currently using three point one beta 5 throughput one isn't life at the time and recording this
so I can hit download hit download and it'll select a mirror where I want to get it from here from here
and then I can just wait for to download.
So probably just fast for the spit seed I have to watch it.
Okay so it took about five minutes maybe less and now it's there I could just close this window it's
ready to go.
Now I got a project and we export again and now Windows executable is here.
I've got a bunch of options I could use I could put a path on it but it sure would be good to go.
So all I need to do at this point is just go export project.
Okay.
So because they were on a call it on call it looney lips EMC I'm going to put it in the looney lips
folder.
Save it
and that was it is export it's exported.
Has it exports.
Let's find out has it exported.
Let's find out.
Go back to my file manager and here I've got loony lips stopped EMC and I can double click that and
there's my game.
May I have a thing please.
Happy Yan a name Yan in caps an adjective Yan for a thing Yan's excitement once there was a happy Yan
called Yan that lived as Yan full as Yang's excitement.
Actually that story works quite well.
OK.
So we've now managed to export to the game isn't the sexy and all you have to do is take the EFC and
this package file that should be in the same folder and put them somewhere I can put them on my desktop
folder paste it there and I can run it here and the same thing will happen right.
It'll run just fine.
So when you're exporting it as a Windows file remember that the package file has to be with the XY.
Apart from that that's that bit dumb.
So what do we love from lonely lips.
Just a handful of things we've learned variables functions arrays dictionaries gooey elements signals
randomization and counting and getting child knows we've also talked about some other stuff in the most
essential things we've looked at are variables functions and conditions right with these three things
you can accomplish pretty much anything.
There are more efficient ways of doing things more elegant ways of doing things.
But that's the basics of modern programming.
So excellent work.
I hope you've really enjoyed the section I've really enjoyed teaching it and I'm looking forward to
the next one so I'll see you in the next section.