Hello again, you.
Gigantic.
Got to people.
I don't actually know if they're gigantic or not, but I couldn't think of an adjective in time in this
video.
We'll look at ending the game.
We're not ending section, but we're going to give the game over a chance.
Game over happen.
And my cat is going to yell at me and distract me while trying finish sentences.
So what I wanna do is talk about how the game can be won.
We need a target score, right.
So we need an expert variable or just constant where if either player gets the score, the end game
is triggered.
And we clearly need to check that we need a game over ugly.
When the game is over, what happens?
We also need to stop that time off from respawn in the bowl.
The game or freeze the gooing come off and then we need a way of restarting the game.
Not too complicated, but let's jump into it.
So first thing, we'll be working in the gluey.
So it's Drummonds, that scene.
Hello, Gary.
And I want to add a brand new pop up.
Let's see.
So here's my pop up.
OK, let's add in a nine patch, Recht, and that's looking good.
And of here on the interface we have panel wood looks good.
Let's resize the entire pop up.
So I want you to Recht and I think 500 on the X is a midsize and maybe two hundreds on that one.
Create a nine patch rectangle.
And I'm just gonna give it a full recht and.
And the pop up is going to be anchored to center and positioned in the center.
Great.
Let's make this look a little prettier.
Patch margins on a stick with the 20s.
They worked well.
But on the banner.
And, yeah, it looks nice.
OK.
We need ourselves a label and that can be a child of the pop up itself.
As you know what?
We need to split the text only so we can have one line than the other.
So I'm going to make a V box container and it's a size that probably is a full rectangle and margins
because I don't want Tex to go over the edge.
Let's say 20 pixels again.
Very nice.
And as a child of that, let's have a label.
And.
We're not currently in the style away now.
We could use the same theme, except I want a different font color here because I think white on that
colorism very helps read.
So instead unlabelled going to give a custom font.
New dynamic font I need to load that ends font low.
Doo doo doo doo doo.
And we could stick with the same size.
I think it's 30 points, but let's give it a color, not an outline color, an actual color.
The custom color font color, black, and I can't read it, couldn't say anything, so.
Player zero wins.
You know what?
I think maybe even a little big on that.
Let's let's go the custom side of 40, 40 looks.
And I want to make sure this stays in the center.
So aligned to center.
I've written players zero just so I can see what it is.
It's gonna be one or two, hopefully.
When is that?
Now just rosenblad to put a button and the button is going to theme.
So you know what, I'm actually going to take this thing.
Say, that's that's cool, but I'm going to go yeah, go with God thing, gooey dot theme.
And now I can load that in here.
And the reason I've done that is while these this fund is going to stay the same, because we've overridden
the defaults.
If we got rid of the override it now look like the the white tax because that's going to now be the
same.
I can now use that font in the buttons.
So let's make a button.
And I'm on the right to play again.
And this is important because now I can change the way the button behaves and the things that's open
the thing and I might add class item.
Dot, dot, dot.
And I want button cricked.
Okay, button.
Let's take a look at your stuff as your style's first normal style could be a new start.
Starbucks flat.
And I'd say white.
And we could change the button.
Text to black.
How's that sound?
I think it sounds nice.
We'll do that.
So you're white and you and the button is going to have a custom font.
And we'll have the same font as before.
And in file.
But now the color, the font color will be black.
I'll do that for all of them.
Oh, he's got the settings, don't I?
So that's a 40.
Oh, look at that.
Okay, that's done.
Now take this style and copy it and paste it on hover.
And that should do it.
So now as oppressed as well.
Focus and put in paste.
And now it's it'll work as a button when we put the signal in, but it won't actually change color.
Now I do wanna put a border on that.
So what we do is we go back to my custom styles.
So I went back to the theme, to the theme.
And anyway, these styles, they're all the same one.
So should really matter.
I want a corner detail.
Let's give the border in black the border width of the two.
Now, on that six, that's pretty good.
That might she too much as a three and each.
My bottom one is that she bugs.
That is three.
Doesn't look like it.
And you know what?
I think it needs more of a corner detail right now.
That's not gonna work a corner radius.
Let's say full pixels in the radius.
And I think the button text might be a little bit smaller, so so the button text a little bit smaller.
OK, let's go back to the font, make a little bit smaller and maybe 30.
You know what?
That looks pretty good.
I'm quite happy with that.
Finally on the edge box container.
I wanna make sure this isn't the center of this panel.
And there is pop up.
There's a little bit experimental, so tweaking as I go.
But I'm quite happy with how that looks.
It's got almost a school gym, feel like an American school gym.
Now we see to make this thing work.
First off, I need that button to be it ends.
So let's add a signal and let's connect to the gooey.
Well, this is a restart button, right?
So let's actually do that.
Get tree dot, reset, reload currency.
That's going to restart the game.
We only have one scene that's being played.
That will work nicely.
All right.
So analysis, you make that show up.
And so, you know, that's a level and it's my game script.
Great script.
Let's call it level dot.
Jeannie and I need a brand new function and I need a function that checks if we've reached the maximum
scope.
Well, first, let's bring in a variable for that final score.
So export variable doesn't have to be an expert variable, but it feels good to do it.
What's this called?
Target score.
And let's start with three.
That's nice and easy.
Say that.
Take a look at.
Doesn't target school.
Nice.
OK.
Brand new function.
Check.
Game over.
It's good.
Now I'm going to have to bring through which player has won the game.
That's gonna show and I'll get these.
I need the player and I need the current school.
Let's make some room.
Okay.
And let's see if the score is equal to the target score.
Firstly, one, does it make one, make sure that timer doesn't get to the end?
If a timer keeps going, it's just in response the ball and we can keep moving.
We don't have to interrupt the game.
Also, it's not high spot target.
So if the score is the same target score, then I want to get the timer and I want to remove it from
the game.
It can't finish if it doesn't exist.
Finally, let's go to our gooey.
I'm going to call a new function and put it there called Game Over.
And which player one.
OK.
So we have on U.
Check.
Game over.
Not check.
So was I going go.
Well, we have a date school.
It feels like that's a good place to put it.
So check.
Game over.
And it needs breakthrough.
The player and I need to bring through the new school.
Finally, just to make this all work.
We need to actually put that little bit in here.
So a function called Game Over.
And let's go take the player.
Asking to check this what was called game over with the player.
Perfect.
What do we do?
Well, first, we need to change the details, the label.
Right.
So right here we have this label.
It says Player Zero wins.
It said this is a player.
The player number wins.
Easy enough.
We've done it a few times now.
So let's say.
The label, let's grab the label first.
Is the label that's in the V box container label, dot text.
Equals.
And this could be player space plus.
And Rainbow Eater turns into a string.
Player.
Plus, space wins.
Finally, we need the public to actually show so pop up.
And it needs to show the sense of the screens that pop up centered.
OK, if we've done this right.
And it's possible I've missed something.
After three goals, we should get the game over screen.
So let's just do the traditional thing.
That one.
To make that time a little shorter, as she knows, it'll look better when we get the details in and
three and time doesn't happen.
We have this button.
We press the button.
The game restarts.
Scores are back.
Everything's back to normal.
We have a fully functional game.
Everything from here on in is adding detail in Polish.
Look at that.
We have a local multiplayer fouche game about trying to put this unwieldy wooden bowl into a goal.
Really happy with that.
So far, so great stuff.
And I shall see you in the next video.