Hello lovely God.
People in this video we're going to be finishing our food projectiles now.
That's actually a slight lie later I'm going to add the concept of ammunition.
But for now let's get the actual projectile polished off.
If I run the game five food you can see that we can find Baja food at the same time.
And the food isn't actually making any noise.
So these are the two things were going to get fixed by the end of this video by the end of this video.
When I pressed the button it'll file once and I'll have to wait again before it fires again which also
stop it occasionally firing white.
Every time I press the button occasionally every time.
Not the best grammar rules are going to put in a sound effect that's going to make it sound really cool
and you something called the Doppler effect which I talk about in a little bit.
So what do we need to do to finish it.
Well only to make sure we only file once every X seconds and we need to put a wooshing sound.
So let's get in to our scene.
Specifically on open the character scenes one player and go into character or characters are going to
have a new timer.
This timer is going to be called can fire.
So here is my time record can fire.
For now I won't leave it as one second.
I'm not going to set it to auto start but I will stick to one shot.
It'll just stop when it gets to zero.
Next thing to do is connect as signals as go to node connect the timeout signal to the parent.
So we now have everything ready.
I'm going to start another early challenge because I think you are probably capable of doing this at
this stage but let's see how you go.
I would like you to use this new can fire timer to make sure the character can only fire once every
X seconds.
Once I fire we need to make sure that we can no longer fire until the timer tells me otherwise.
A few different ways you could solve this.
So pause the video.
Find a solution you like and when you ready come on back and I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
Okay so what I'm going to do is I want to give a new variable.
It's going to be a boolean So truffaut's I'm on to call it can add fire and it's a start as true.
The next thing to do is set can fire as true on time.
And that's all that needs to do right.
Okay from here I go into my plagiary which apparently I have twice that and I won't have it twice let's
get rid of one.
One is my plagiary and put it in this script.
I do this because I think it's going to behave slightly differently for the NPC.
However you could also put it in here and very simply go down to my fire.
So my input.
So if the action press is fire instead of fire I'm going to call a new function and call this.
Try to fire.
So let's make that function and make the function.
Tried to fire hoops.
Having a little bit of trouble here.
Let's just give myself some rooms across Europe doing gorillas tabs.
Fantastic function.
Try to fire sawdust try to find it.
It's going to check if can fire.
Okay and that's very simply.
If this I don't need to say.
If can find it is true because that's implicit.
It's also already checking if this is true.
If condition.
Is it saying is this true.
I can see if it's true.
I don't need to if can fire fire but I don't just want to do that.
I do two other things right.
I'm also going to start the timer so it can fire.
Which is a dollar some more can fire.
Double check is what it's called now.
It's not auto completing because I'm in the play a script and player isn't actually in the characters.
So it's not gonna work so it can fire a dot that's the correct node and I just need it to start.
I don't need to say what needs to happen because the moment that time finishes it will trigger can fire
timeout.
Gates has said about the true one more thing I need to do is set to Fox.
So can a fire which hasn't been saved so that save that there can be calls fops.
OK let's Pressplay and see how that works.
Like file once spamming the button.
It's only spamming once a second.
Now once a second might be too much.
But that's okay I can go into my character into can fire and change this to zero point to 5 so four
times a second every quarter of a second how is that like.
See I have a lot of control here and I've set it up so that all characters play characters and non player
characters will have the same restrictions for firing which I think is great.
We don't have to do it this way.
This is when I do it.
I get the other thing I want to do is I want to give projectiles wooshing noise.
So if we go into our scenes.
And we're looking at ammo.
I'm going to put it in the projectile scenes just go here in 3D.
And the reason I put it here is I want all projectiles to have the same sound right they're going to
do the exact same thing.
So let's put it once in here.
All other projectiles all of our models all inherit from here.
So if it does it he'll do it ever or else.
I'm going to use an audio streamed player 3D a positional sound.
And this is important.
Here's what I'm looking for.
Imagine your.
I don't know standing by the side of the road in a car a motorbike is going very fast and it goes past
you.
It's going to make a sound nother sound it's going to make it's going to be something along the lines
of Now which is a technical term.
And if you want to use that in future videos by all means.
Now I am the king of sound effects.
However if you're on that motorbike or in that car the sound is constant.
And this is because of something called the Doppler effect.
Essentially it works like this as an object gets closer the sound it makes RAICES in pitch right so
Carl gets close to you.
Meow.
And then as it goes away it goes down.
Now there is a reason for this.
And you have to forgive me my pen just broke some of his analysis.
If I am standing here with my glasses and a big old grin on my face and my little beard.
Great.
Looks just like me.
If I'm standing here and here is an object that sets a car.
A big car.
But it's a car.
Let's imagine the sound waves.
Okay.
They're travelling from the car.
To me the engine is travelling at a constant speed it's a constant revs per minute.
I realize that this is very hypothetical but I imagine it is the pitch right.
How high or low the sound is is dependent on the wavelength the length of the wave.
Literally the distance between those two pulses of air.
So these are all going to be constant let's call them X..
However the car is moving right.
So when the car is here it's going to do another pulse and it's here it's going to do another pulse.
So in fact the waves are not constant.
They look more like this.
So they're in it here and then here and then a little bit closer and a little bit closer.
And then when it gets to me it's going to start moving further away.
So what happens is if I picture a wave the wave length gets higher and then lower right.
And that's what the picture's doing now.
We could program all of this in but instead going to make this really simple for us selves.
So let's go into our Sound Effects which is SFX as I called it right.
Want to put you.
You are around here and that you're right here.
Buses.
The sound here of made called explosion too.
And it's just a very simple bitmaps for Pressplay.
This is just pink noise.
It doesn't go up.
It doesn't go down.
What I want is for this noise.
Let's put on auto play.
I want this noise to be constant and I want God o to figure out how the pitch should be changing over
time and to do that I'm just going to go into the player.
And to the camera.
And you see right here.
Doppler tracking I'm going to put this to physics.
Be advised that at time of writing there is a bug.
Every time any object with 3-d positional sound comes into your godso right is spawned to God.
And you have Doppler tracking enabled the debugger is going to give you a weird error that says I don't
know where this is.
It does.
And the error is completely harmless.
But the more objects you have that rely on Doppler tracking the more times you'll see this error and
I'll demonstrate that right now.
So the press.
So right here.
Condition is inside tree is true returned transform.
You notice it only played once.
That's great.
It can sometimes there more times I've actually raised this as a bug.
So hopefully it'll be fixed in three point once release.
But just in case you see this error that's what it is.
Don't panic.
Right.
It's no more serious than this one which has to do with the animation tree play loading in animations.
You can ignore those very safely.
So let's test how that lesson sounds.
You know what let's make this camera current.
That'll help too.
Let's just play and we like to tweak the volume a little bit.
So you can just hear it dropping a sound.
Let's just tweak the sound a little bit.
OK so let's get our max distance.
And I think some distance of 50.
Now if I don't have a max distance this won't fade out.
Right.
But I wanted to fade out once too far away so if it's 50 this is metrix or it's 15 meters away you won't
hear it at all.
It's might be a bit higher then we'd put it like that for now.
And also to turn the volume down.
So let's say our unit decibel sound and good minus 10.
I want it to be quite a subtle sound.
It's Pressplay.
Great.
And if I bounce off the wall towards me.
Fantastic.
Now we could do some fancy code with figure out how fast you are going and that's going to be your pitch
or your volume or anything like that.
But I'm really happy with this.
And what you'll find is when the MP sees arrive in the next few videos and they start fi towards us
we're going to hear the sound of wooshing very dramatically as it whistles past our head rushing and
whistles.
That's a fun w sound there.
But look at this.
Which brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we've used the timer and Boolean to make sure we can only fire once every X seconds and
we have control over what the value of x is and we've enabled the Doppler effect on a camera out which
means our food is almost perfect it's just ammunition to go and we can do that much later.
But excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.