Hello lovely God people in this video were going to reset the game when a goal is scored so the goals
scored.
The players in the ball to go back to the beginning.
Otherwise whoever just scored a goal could keep scoring goals.
So let's look at what has to happen when a goal is scored.
I want to stop the ball and the players and their tracks or when to freeze time.
I mean we're not actually freezing time.
We're stopping everything from moving but it's gonna look the same.
Why are we doing that.
Because I want to give whoever just score time to celebrate and whoever didn't time to a few.
I mean no one actually fuming I want the feel good.
But you know when I see them I want to move the ball and the players back to the start positions and
allow them ultimately that's going to go.
And before I even do that there's a small bug I want to fix.
If you're under in the last video and I hope you don't.
When we set up the collision for the gold I brought them right up to the edge here so I can actually
show you see the collision goes right up to the post.
I since discovered something.
So I start the game going and do this.
And when I gently get the ball over into the corner No I can't go into the corner and if I touch the
post it just happened.
If I touch the post from the outside we're still scoring goals so let's go into all the goals I've seen
doesn't really matter.
Both the same one and all I need to do is just shrink the Golden Section down a bit so as to the collision
shape of the extant I said schrank I don't really mean trick and as turning to one point seventy five
there's no way the ball is going to get through that gap but it will have to get in through the actual
pillar.
We can also shrink it down a bit just in case it bounces on top of the net.
It's an edge case but just in case.
Let's do that.
So let's shrink it down on the y axis.
I'm going to say a point seven.
Now let's move it down.
So point seven of a height.
I actually don't mean that do I at say a point five.
Nice and low and so maybe a point six will compromise.
Great.
And that will be a lot better.
So what do we need to do.
Well when the goal is scored I want to freeze time for a bit so the first thing I need to do is at a
time out right.
Because for a bit is my key.
What do we say 2 seconds when you feel like a decent amount of time later in the game going to add some
effects or work and put a sound effect make some lighting some particles happen so we can make it really
clear what just happened but for now let's just pause the game now first thing I do is I'm going to
stop the ball from moving.
When it crosses the golf so let's go into the game script and right here on goal detection entered were
currently printing that somebody has scored.
Let's also stop the ball moving.
Well first we need to get the ball on finding the ball.
Just go there in front of the ball.
I should probably figure out where I need it.
Do I just need it in this function.
Well no because this isn't just going to happen when the goal is scored right when the goal detection
body is entered.
We also need to know where the ball is when we move it and when we free it.
So this is probably going to be right at the top here so unready variable ball equals and in a capital
B because the ball is a..
And only to get only to find that I don't.
So that's a get tree get root and then I need find no ball.
Now I need more than that.
Let's go larger because there's these two extra arguments.
I want recursive and I dont want it so recursive go through hoops Robert and then go through all of
the subbranches at the scene.
True and false.
It doesn't have to be owned by the current note.
It will be on by the current note so I don't know one put it false there but it's going to have to get
into it.
I mean true or false.
So we can now get the ball.
So what needs to happen.
Well first where say you scored.
And actually before we say we scored let's actually freeze the ball so all.
Dart Alright what do we need to happen.
Well we can freeze the ball quite easily.
Now no it's not actually moving itself it's reacting.
But if we look down here to access lock that's what you want.
I can lock the x y and z.
What this will mean.
In fact I can show you in a start the game with these locked.
Loops and or comment out this piece of code let's try that again.
The ball has been told you're not allowed to move in the axes I've locked.
So while physics is still working it's been told Okay you're now locked in these and this axis and I've
lost all three axes so the ball is immobile and just like most other things.
Probably all other things.
If it's an inspector I can reach it in script so ball.
OK so what do we need to find.
Well this mouse over a linear x.
I don't need to worry about angular because I don't care if it rotates.
I just want it to not actually move.
Right so what's linear X is mouseover that and its axis underscore lock on a scale linear underscore
X Brecht
axis on a scale lock on the scale linear underscore X equals true and duplicate duplicate twice and
Y and Z.
So when the ball enters the goal stop moving.
Let's see if that works out.
Nice run up and it as I as they can and it stops immediately which also stops it from bouncing against
the back wall and scoring again.
That's the real reason I want to do this right.
It should now not be possible to keep scoring awesome.
Well now let's do the same with the players.
Let's stop the players from having to do this.
I mean at a boolean into the place.
Go into the poleon know into the player script.
I'm not going to the billion.
That's nonsense and I need a new variable and this variable is going to be called can move.
I set the default to true.
And over here in physics process I am going to add a condition if I can move.
And I'm going to put movin there if he can move.
Move.
Awesome.
So how are we going to get there.
Well let's do a group call because we have the player let's put those players in a group.
So I'm just going to it's probably easier rather than doing this to both players individually let's
just go into the play a scene and add all instances of place the group because we want all players to
be part of the play A group.
Great thing to say that for that change to stick.
And now all players should be part of the playgroup.
OK.
Let's get into this.
The game script.
So get Tre dot.
And well to call the group call group.
It is called the great player.
And what are we.
Okay now here we're going to do it and make a method called can move right which you will recognize
as the actual variable and we can't change the variable as a group Corbel we can do is pass a value
in.
So I'm gonna make a method called Can group and parse in a value.
So let's do that as go function can move value.
And all this is going to do is say can move the variable.
Is this value whatever that value is.
So let's see how that works.
Now summarize my animation is still playing let's take a look at that and the simplest way I can do
this is to change when an inmate is being called to one to do here.
If can move which can move an inmate into canvas.
If you can move an image.
If you can't ducked and that means that the animation will stop the moment it comes to the end of its
cycle.
So here we go and they stop and instantly they stop and again with not something instantly.
I think it is slowing down.
It's good.
Alright so we've stopped the players now.
We need to actually use this timer so back into my game.
Let's start the timer so timer start start alright that time is going to start and we're going to connect
it as a signal or connect it signal rather it's time out back into the game.
The game is going to decide whether we can go again.
So now I want to do is figure out what's going to happen and then make a new function called Reset pitch.
Alright so going to reset the pitch to do that Ops there shouldn't be a colon there to do.
That's what I want to do is create start positions for all these.
So let's make some suppositions and I'm going to put them in their own little note folder so as to make
a new little node folder.
There's a little note and mikkel this start positions
within which I make 3 position loads just like position 2 D.
But the position these because they're in three dimensions.
And let's first move it's the right place so this one can be for the ball and put this right up here.
Ball spawn.
And now I make em go and duplicate that and move it over to here.
I could probably pick a nice grid reference for it's a minus 3 2.
And that's got to be play once born.
You could also call it player 1 Start.
I'm calling a player once born because I don't know why.
Reasons to up and as player to.
Lots of hoops to there and you start there.
Now I've said this in the centre of where the pitch is not the centre where the texture is and that's
not going to look right so much is going to move that very slightly.
If you know what let's move all three in the same mounts I'm going to select all them and just drag
it so that the down arrow.
That sporty pointy thing is going to be right above there and that looks get great analysis use those
make a new function called the reset pitch.
I'm going to call it on Ready set reset pitch.
I get what's going to happen every time the pitches reset.
Well the first thing I want to do is spawn where they go.
Right so let's make a function.
Reset pitch.
Okay.
First they reset pitch is going to do is it's going to move the ball to its spot like we need to get
the spawn point so variable Paul.
Storm Eagles.
And I'm just going to do this.
I'm fine no thanks.
Nice guy nice and big so I can go running.
Copy this get Tre get root find no business and change what Baller's chords or what's it called.
It's called Ball spohn
or spon.
Great.
So we now have that.
We really got the ball so now we need to move the ball to the spawn points.
Let's do that ball dot.
Translation.
So it's X Y and Z information.
Where are you.
Eagles ball spawn.
Translation.
Awesome.
So when this is called The ball will go back there.
Let's make sure we're actually calling it's a reset pitch.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now the players won't be able to move still.
Wrong.
What's wrong.
Not found balls.
Mom it's here.
I hear it.
See the different name up there.
Okay let's give the same name.
Let's.
OK.
So in a move that when have one too.
And there it goes.
I get the ball has moved.
Now I still can't have the players but it's okay now when I do the same thing for the players.
Now what I want to do here is not put this in the games.
The players are responsible for getting that position.
The ball isn't because currently the ball doesn't have a script.
So I'm going to do it and make a new function within each player called Reset.
So let's call that and I've just broken that.
So get tree call group.
He's already got the players in the groups let's use that player recept.
OK let's go back to a cube root script and let's make a reset and win a court.
Use this above move because it feels like an important thing to know right.
Getting so function resets OK one needs to happen.
The first thing needs to happen is we need to get the correct position that each player has its own
spawn point right.
And I want player 1 to go to the player once born to do that.
I'm going to use the same can captivating trick that we used earlier.
So first let's get our sport point vare my spawn
which sounds like I'm a frog but that's okay.
I can be a frog my spawn equals and let's find it so get tree.
Get roots going to the Stones get the tree get the top of the tree and then find a note.
And that node is going to be called Player mikan cat and eating this in so many use percentage s spawn.
Kaplan There pretty sure I did I did.
Now I need to put this in a second bracket like so.
And what I can guarantee it will keep getting into in the play Friday.
It's another space there make nice legible and then Uncle billions.
So that's a yes recursive.
No it's not owned by me.
OK so we've found the sport.
Now what do we do with it now.
Where to tell it moved to this position.
So what I'm doing is I'm going to say.
Translation so my translation where I am at right now on the x y z equals my sporn Dot.
Translation.
So that should mean both players after the time has run out.
Which I think currently 2 seconds should do.
If I can ask you about play my own game.
See I was good at sports school either and I get it runs frozen and Iran's back position now back position.
But they can't move and that is my challenge for you.
I'd like you to game on.
Let the ball and the players know that they can move again once the pitchers reset.
Possibly to give that a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
All right.
Well we start with the ball.
So many go in to the games script.
And as reset pitch I'm going to add is extra of mission or I'm really going to do is copy this.
And paste it here and you could change all three of these truths to false.
So what am I doing.
I'm selling.
Okay.
Whenever the pitches reset make sure that your x y and z axes are not locked.
So you are allowed to move in all three directions.
And that should be enough of the ball.
Now what about the players.
Well the players need to be told you're allowed to move.
I'm already tying them reset so I can put this in the reset function so let's do that.
Let's go into reset and I'm going I can move and we have a function called can right.
I'm going to use that can move true.
I've already got this function.
I may as well use it.
Let's see how that works.
So let's just have a nice run up weighing one two and look at that.
Now one thing I have done wrong is I've allowed this to keep looping which does make for an interesting
game.
Can I kick a score before it gets there.
No it can't know what I want to do.
So to fix that I just need to go into my timer and make it a one shot.
Dunno I didn't think of that before but apparently I didn't.
So now let's play and everything should work exactly as intended.
Excellent.
Now I could play with a bounce I can make you know all the little tweaks I want but we now have a system
whereby I'm not gonna score multiple goals and I can have a nice dramatic moment of this plus scored
which were going to do in later video and that brings us to the end of this video in this video we have
looked at how to use Access LOC and how to move players to the right position nodes like in cats and
ating in the string.
Right so we're using the fact that God is string referencing to our advantage.
So excellent work and I'll see you the next video.