And welcome back you lovely God people.
In this video we're going to make a graphic user interface or as I like to call it gooey.
You don't have to pronounce it gooey.
I'm pronouncing it gooey.
You could say a graphic user interface or user interface or gee you I or you I.
It really doesn't matter.
The whole point is we need a system where the player can understand how many coins and lives they've
got so that's what we're making to do that we need to play with control nodes.
Quick pointer we're not going to go through every possible control node because there's a lot of them
but the basic idea.
So you can then play with them and find out what they all do at the end of this video.
You can have a user interface or a gooey up in the top corner or everyone to put it that can adapt to
how they want to size your screens.
So if I realize the screen you'll see can shift position and keep this aspect ratio.
Here we are in game and I'm going to make my goalie in the camera.
So what do we want.
Well if we look on the graphics and the hard heads up display you'll see I've given you three things
a banner a bronze coin and a life up.
These are the three symbols I'd like to use.
My thinking is this If money is here.
There's going be a banner here within which we'll see.
Quain counts a life counts.
A quaint symbol and a bunny symbol.
So I'm going to make a banner and then put these elements within it.
So let's make a new scene.
And I don't know quite why all the spikes are showing there let's go on.
So let's make a bass note.
And our bass note is going to be a canvas layer.
This is the simplest of background drawing layer right.
The thing that won't move and the let's say about this is it doesn't really have any properties it's
just start here draw from here.
That's what we're seeing within our canvas layer.
I'm going to start using some controls.
Let's look at these controllers.
They're all in green and they're designed for user interface.
I'm going to begin with texture wrecked.
We've used this before.
And this is going to be my banner.
So let's call this plan.
I want the layout of the banner to be anchored from the top right.
Or what does that mean.
It means why look at the margins.
These are calculated from the anchor position.
If you want to see the anchor position go to view and show helper's and you'll see the angle right now
on the top left.
So what this is saying is the texture we put here is zero from the left zero from the top.
So first thing to do is I must set my anchor to the top right.
And you'll see the margins of recalculated.
Let's put in at Texas under graphics under HUD you'll see these three things.
Let's drag the banner into the texture.
I will expand it which can only scale.
And they get a little bit bigger because this is control now by the way you can see all those measurements
a little bit wider.
You can Reece's this to your heart's content.
And now just set my margins so let's set the right margin to zero.
And the left margin too.
Well you know what go over that now.
Great.
Here's my banner.
Let's not put that totally in the right hand corner.
So the right banner is going to be minus 40 and the top banner is going to be minus five but nope not
minus 40.
Going to be 40 because we're calculating from the top left as make the bottom a bit bigger.
Great.
So now if I rename canvas Let's agree and say that in scenes if I run the scene.
You'll see that the banner is in the top right.
If when you were inside the screen you start seeing the aspect ratio changing.
We can fix that.
This is important in the main game right where in the main game and I change the size of the screen
I have an aspect ratio that you didn't think I was going to have like some succeed by 9.
If I resized this look squished bunny is right now.
Let's quickly fix that.
I'm going to project settings and scroll down to we find a window which is here on a display under a
stretch mode with a bunch of options.
We could do keep and that's going to keep the aspect ratio.
But it's going to do that by adding those black letter box things on the side.
So if I pick keep and then I run this.
When size again you'll see these black letter boxes and some people really hate those.
It can look very filmic.
I'm not a huge fan.
So instead under windows which I've lost again there it is.
Let's go to expand and now it's going to do its very best to keep everything at the same aspect ratio
and fill the window which is quite lovely.
Great.
Let's go back into going.
All right we have the banner and I want to put in these numbers and these icons.
Now I can try and do this manually.
But here's a nice trick with imbaba.
We have a new sub a..
And this one is going to be one if we're going to control.
You'll see these containers and these box containers and sent to containers everything else.
What these do is say anything that's within this container.
Try and organize this using the schema.
I guess they're using the method I've told you so if I pick a box container which obviously I could
just type what that means is organize everything in here in a horizontal box.
Okay that's that's a bit weird.
Let's actually talk about that means so in my box container which I'm going to re size.
To fit my banner.
There it is very lovely.
And let's actually make that all white bounds of the banner.
And I'm going to put the anchor in the right hand side so that it will try and recalculate its position
from this right margin.
Within this I can now start putting things.
I start with the texture rectangle and I'm going to give this the coin image and call this coin I can
duplicate that.
Call it life icon and put in their life bunny sign.
We can keep going like this right.
So let's put it in a couple of labels.
And this can be coin count.
And another one saying life counts.
Before I go any further let's make sure we can actually see what's in there so we give these both text
to 0 0.
And let's apply a font to one of those.
So back to my fonts.
This should be pretty familiar right now.
Right.
Custom fonts and custom colour custom font they are new dynamic fonts font it's candles.
And let's give the sites how the size of what you think 40 50 50 is pretty good.
OK.
I can now copy my cost my Coston font my custom font.
Copy that and paste it here.
And now any change I make to one will happen to both.
That's a really nice way of keeping everything nice and centred not centred.
It's a really nice way of keeping everything nice and systematic.
Now if the word was the word where everything is kept all the same and organize.
It's a nice way of doing that.
Great.
The nice thing about Abebooks container is that it'll display based on the order here.
So if I put coin count before coin icon and life count before life I can look at that.
I can even make sure that the alignment is centred.
And now all I need to do is just give bunny here a little bit of an icon so Bunny whereas your anchor
your anchors the right hand side.
Let's give you a minus 10 on your margin.
And books contain a list make it a little smaller.
That's pretty good.
Bunny I think you need to be up again don't you.
When is an and box contain.
Let's move you making sure I move everything not just the child.
That looks pretty good.
And finally the banner could be a little smaller.
Cut it.
And now just eyeballing everything I could start doing the margins again yet as do the margin so top
is 40 right is minus 40.
Great.
Now we have a go.
Let's take a look at it.
Yes there it is.
And when I re size it.
It'll work just fine.
So now we need to do is instance that in my scene less isn't it on the camera.
Yes it's on the camera.
So into the scene and not add new noad instance child node scenes and go out now when to press play.
And it is our go is in place.
It's not currently wired in but that's easy enough to do.
Did I talk about it and if I recycled this window it'll rescale and always be worried let's put it.
God has control nodes are really flexible and you can do a lot of stuff very quickly but there's some
key things to understand.
One get to grips with anchors and anchor towns got to where that margin goes from.
If you don't pay attention to where anchors are margins can do really weird things too.
You can make your anchors visible.
Remember going to a view show helpers and there they are several container nodes can sort things automatically
right.
Box container V box contain a grid contain a list container.
There are some really useful ones.
So play around get to know they do.
Look at the documentation.
The more you play with control nodes the better your user interface is going to be.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I'd like you to share your Gooly.
Show us how you've customize it did you put it in different places you changed the colours.
Have you used different fonts different graphic assets.
The discussion forum on discord and off Facebook.
Let us know.
I'm dying to know the kinds of games you guys are making.
Which brings us to the end of this video.
So in this video we've learned how to make a goalie how to pronounce gooey how to use control nodes
and the joy of a box containing a box container another container.
That's really key stuff because if you can get to learn to love God as gooey system and its container
nodes its control nodes.
You can do amazing things.
It's a great work and I'll see you in the next video.