Hello glorious God.
It is because I feel like guys are any different.
In this video we're going to add to in 3-d.
We're going to add a goofy to our game at some point we need to show the score to The Players.
Let's get started.
So if we have a 3-d scene going on how would we add a 2D app.
And the answer is in God.
You just add it.
It has a true 2D engine and a true 3D engine.
This isn't true in every engine for instance.
Unity can do 2D but it's actually rendering 3D and locking the position so it looks like today that's
fine.
That works great.
But if we want to add to be one amadou's and then add a node that's in too deep and it'll overlay them.
So let's make a brand new scene with a root that's a canvas layer y canvas layer because it'll always
be in the same position on the screen.
So if for any reason we move the camera.
If you decide that your camera has to follow the ball find the median point between the midpoint between
two players and follow that the gooey won't move it'll stay fixed on the camera or other.
It will move the camera whatever it looks stuck to the camera which is what we want and I'm going call
this gooey.
Now if I add any kind of control mode or any to decode.
So let's add in a I don't know let's add in a nine patch Rex that's a good start.
We switched to tuti anything I put in here will appear in 3D just to make sure that's true.
Delete this and put in a Sprite
and a Sprite is going to be there.
Got it I can watch on my screen.
For some reason as corrupted now looks weird and green and yellow with that's fine.
And I'm going to move this to here and save my go missing.
It's not going to look like this in-game.
Don't worry.
An instance in the Gooly.
Get rid of that preview now.
I can't see it because I mean 3D view but if I switch to to see you I can see it when I press play.
There's my sprite.
OK so we know that we can have 2003 Alright.
Well we don't want the God I can hear although it's it's very lovely I come.
Maybe you do.
Maybe that's part of your.
That's fine if you look over in graphics you'll see a folder called interface.
I've given you a banner you can use and if you want a wood panelled you can use and if you go back up
to the root you'll see a font's directory and there's a font I've taken from Kenny.
You don't have to use these you can use any assets you like but I've provided these so you can use them.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I'd like you to make the gooey feel game send this challenge early so you can really personalize this.
Now at the very minimum you should show the score for each player.
How you do that's up to you.
I'm also going to put the words Q Did kick about in there.
So pause the video set up the goofy.
Don't worry about plugging in the score I don't need to be functional yet but have a system so you can
see how much player one has.
How many or how many points.
I guess what's what play 1 score is what played to scorers and any other information you are put in
there.
Go for it.
Suppose the video when you happy with the results come back and I'll show you my agree.
Welcome back.
I said as an usher you may go.
I haven't built it yet and I meant it with you.
You know what it's fine.
Everything is fine so my root node is a canvas layer and within that I'm going to put a 9 patch rectangle.
So let's make a nine patch right.
And I'm thinking make the banner go across the top here and in the middle the right Q did kick about
and the play one score on the left.
Play a two on the right.
I am not going to change colours for it just can keep them nice and simple.
So let's go into graphics and interface and as my name gets wrecked and I'm going to put the banner
on a college banner now.
Obviously this isn't where it goes.
Someone go let out milingo top wide.
It's now gotten rid of the minimum size.
That's okay I could put that back in.
I think the minimum size for erect penis size on the y axis.
I think our hundred and twenty is pretty good.
And now I can start playing around with the patch margins so I need to get up to here to make this not
look blurry so if I try five it's nowhere near enough.
If I try.
10.
Still not looking good.
Let's try 20 20 I can get.
This is a nice clean line so the straight 20 on awful margins.
And that's looking pretty good.
And Bana only has one capital in it because that's how English works now.
Currently this is set to be the top of the screen.
But I want to anchor it properly.
I'm an anchor it to my top centre.
So why play the game.
It's currently taking up this full width maybe I don't want that I can fix at the minute but it's staying
in the centre.
I can play with how wide this is in a moment.
That's fine within the actual banner maybe on top of the banner.
I haven't decided yet.
I must say within it's going to keep things keep things a little simpler in terms of resizing.
I would put the name of the games a cupid kick about and play a 1 and play 2.
I am splitting things horizontally so I want to put in each box container and I want to make this full
rectangle of its parent saying full rectangle.
I actually want some margin so it's put some much in 25 pixels maybe.
I'd say 25 because I think that's 20 because I save by 20 pixels I can actually go by 20 pixels and
see how that looks.
That's pretty good.
I'm happy with that 20 pixels from left to 20 from the top and probably minus 20 from the right.
Yes and minus 20 from the bottom right.
So anything I put in is going to fit within that margin.
And let's view our helpers just Saag make sure the anchor this correctly.
So if I recycled the banner or give that a tell it your only 400 wide or whatever it is it already signs
everything.
That's good.
I like that.
Now within the box container I need to put some things I must start with the label and that's only the
name of my game which in this case is glued kickabout.
OK that font isn't working for me so I'm going go back up to my main banner and I'm going to add a themes
that's got a theme make a new thing.
Click on that and all I really care about right now is a default font so let's add a new dynamic font.
I go back up to the fonts folder and put Kenny bold in it because it's actually open that.
Put Kenny bold into the font and give it a size about 40 is 40 big 40 is very big but that's fine.
I like that it's looking nice and bold and actually kind of sports.
And with the banner everything excellent.
I don't want it aligned the left.
However the text is taking the entire text box if I change this the centre.
Nothing's going to change.
Instead it's got the H box container and an alignment.
Go centre now.
All elements are going to align to the centre.
Well let's put in a couple of elements.
Let's put in another label and a right number zero.
And this is going to be player to play one score so Player 1 score in a live.
This to you right here.
This label because anything goes.
Remember the H box container is going to look at the order that the children are in and place them that
way.
So now that's fine and well duplicate that to be player to score not play or one score or to play a
two score and put that underneath the label.
Okay I need a bit more space here.
Some of my other Abebooks margin and give it a custom constraint.
Let's see a separation of 40 pixels 50.
Great.
And that should work just fine.
So let's take a look at it in go now at the start of the game.
God is saying okay get the size of the screen and set the banner.
Why doesn't know it's about but set the patch rectangle to be the top centre of it.
When I make the screen bigger it's not updating that.
That's fine I'm happy with that.
Maybe though I don't want this to be a hot top centre.
Maybe I'm going to say to it just be this size so let's fix the size of the banner.
I say that to grow the size of the banner is not 1024 pixels it's pixels how that work is too small.
About 900 900 is pretty good.
And now I need to centre it somehow.
So instead of going top wide I want to go centre top and now when I press play the banjo should be fine
and resize it and the banners are the same size.
Maybe this margins are a bit big now because when he scores getting bigger that's going to be a problem.
So instead of 50 pixel suppression of say a 30 pixel separation that's pretty good.
I could even change the size of the fonts for the scores or for the labels so maybe the label isn't
going to be the same size or else but actually right now I'm pretty happy with that.
One more thing to do is I'm going to set up a pop up that's going to come up when the game is over.
When we were in yeah I'm going to set it so on my gooey I'm gonna make a new pop up and ima give that
it's 0 9 patch rectangle So let's give that of my patch RACT 9.
How to say it like Patch wrecked and let's make it visible.
And there we go.
Now it can get wrecked.
I'm so sorry I'll never do that again.
OK.
And let's add our panel would as a Texas give me my background.
I want to give this a minimum size so I'm thinking 400 by 200 decent size so I'm to go to the pop up.
I'm going to say a line to send to you.
Yeah and.
When a line the actual ank etc. as well that should work nicely and I'm Petsch rectangle.
Okay you're in the wrong place.
OK has your full rect OK.
So the pop up size so give a pop up minimum size not size flag racks that were gone.
So when we say we said 400 by 200.
Great.
All I need to do now is put that back in the centre and that should work fine.
This is going to be the little part of the comes up.
Let's give the patch margins something to play with how this 20 picks will sound.
Oh pretty good about tennis tend to few.
Yes tennis too few.
So let's say 20 or 50 maybe.
You know I don't know you know I'm playing with this 20 worked on a stick with 20.
Okay looking nice and shiny with that and put a V box container.
Here we go.
The.
BOX.
Contain and full rectangle.
And give it some margins at say 10 pixels.
Nope.
Let's say 20 pixels.
Twenty bucks better 20 from the left 20 from the top minus 20 from the right minus 20 from the bottom.
So that's going to be the margin.
And I'm a little label.
Just can say game over.
Now this isn't keeping the style they made earlier.
Somebody go back into my banner when I go to thien and save my thien SAVE it right at the top here and
call it theme dot theme because that seems like a good name.
And let's love that it's about to pop up at a clean load thing dot thien.
Why do I have to do it that way.
Because pop is not a child of banner it's a child of gooey which is a canvas layer canvas layers don't
have thin.
So this label is looking good except it's one in the wrong place that's a line that to centre and two
it's the wrong colour.
So let's go.
Custom colours and just enable black.
I'm also going to put a button and so under the box container when I put a button and on the button
I'm going to play again.
The theme is in there but we don't yet have a thing for the button.
I could put one in.
I've only got one button in the game.
I'm not planning on anything more so I could just go to custom styles and let's see.
Probably under normal I'm thinking I'm the saying new style box flat such as the basic flat colourant
border.
Click on that one on.
I want a white button with a black border.
That sounds good and that black border is going to be um look at the preview here the see for pics only
44.
Crazy talk for pixels on each side and I don't want to blend the border blend from black and white.
Its look good.
If I want I can even get a corner radius for pixel corner radius.
Corner nice rounded button.
It's not showing here yet because that's actually not normal that's what we focussed I to save the style
box.
Under.
Probably interface.
It seems a good place to put it so graphics interface.
I'll say button.
Lot of style looks good and let's go back up here find my buttons and I can load them into all of them
so graphics interface style box and keep loading.
Okay I've now got grey on white which is a terrible choice of custom colours.
Let's just enable black for all of these and what the masses are doing is looking like that now.
Right now the font is bleeding into the border.
Don't want that.
So let's go to our button and give it a rest.
Minimum size.
Currently it's 66 let's call it 70 let's give it four pixels seventy at 74 looking better and I can
read this properly.
That looks good.
So now we have a pop up that will say play again.
Right now it doesn't do anything but it will.
And there it is.
There's a good single look at that game.
I have a nice little balance can look great in its background and up at the background in an avid game
and I have everything working just fine.
And that brings us to the end of the video.
In this video we've looked at how to use 2D and 3D nodes at the same time and it turns out and got you
just tell it use them and use them fine which is great.
And we've made a lovely geula of lovingness which is even greater.
We're now ratel Why are the gooey together start showing the score to the players and letting them really
love the game and the rain.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.