Hello you lovely God people in this video we're going to talk about a new script.
We're going make a script called Game state Judy.
Why are we doing that.
Well you know I've been talking about how each script should do one thing in each function should it
do one thing.
What we're talking about here is the single responsibility principle.
This is the idea that every object should be responsible for single behaviour or in the words of Robert
C. Martin who first came up with this class should only have one reason to change.
What does that mean for us.
Well currently we have player g d and player animation Judy.
And they're responsible for a single thing play egd will move the player and play animation well and
make the player.
We're going to create game state we're going to run the game.
It's going to hold the rules right.
How many lives do you start with.
What happens when you lose a life.
How many coins you start with.
What happens when you gain a coin.
So nice and easy.
Let's create a brandnew script.
I'm going to create my script on level 1 now.
This is going to work because this is a one level game if this is a multi-level game I do that little
differently.
When we look at singletons and auto loading scripts and a few videos.
TIME That's where I would do that.
But for now let's put it in level 1.
I'm going to call this game state not level 1
and let's put it like that.
It's going to be a dot g d.
Got in a what kind of script it is.
Also note I'm not putting it in scenes file folder not file folder and put it in the scripts folder.
And I don't want any comments and would just go from there.
So let's start by making this nice and easy.
In the next video and the ones after that will start adding more functionality to it.
But before we start linking it to the gooey in things I'd like you to move the end game function out
of play a dog midi and into game state.
And remember you need to call it from player dog Eady if Bonnie falls by the world limit.
So if Bonnie falls too far we're going to say now call end game in game state is a couple ways you could
do this.
Suppose the video give it a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
And walk back.
First thing I do is I'm going to find end game as a function and I'm going to remove it entirely.
So just cut and let's go to a game say Judy and paste.
Well that was easy.
Now this should still work because we haven't moved this scene but we've got some string referencing
here that Ben has strong feelings about.
He If you've watched any of his code review.
But hollidays if you happen to catch John I'll switch channel.
You'll know that Ben has feelings about String referencing and with good with good reason.
We will fix that in later V.
But for now let's leave it as it is.
So instead of end game I'm just going to get parent figures.
Level 1 is the parent of player and I'm going to call the function and the function is going to be end
game and that's all that needs to happen.
Now you could use a signal for this.
That's perfectly fine but I'm going do this because it's much simpler now.
Note we have a problem here.
This relies on player being a direct child of level 1.
If for some reason we change that lets say that we make player a child of an organizing node.
I don't know I will call it moving things or characters or something else.
If we put player with in another node.
This won't work.
Now we are going to fix that in a in a later video.
But for now this will work fine.
And let's just make sure of that so I'm going to press play.
And let's make bunny fall by fall off the world.
Done nice and easy.
Which brings to the end of the video.
Nice and short but pretty simple with looked at what the single responsibility principle is.
Decided what behaviour each node will track and we've moved end game to the correct script so the weakest
link in the go is the game state.
We can start tracking coins and lines and really getting some functionality in the game by putting everything
in the correct place.
Why do we want to do that because it makes it much easier to debug and to find things.
If you come back to the script in six months you'll very easily be able to track what bit of the code
does what.
Which also makes solving problems easier.
So great work and I'll see you in the next video.