Hello again you Fantastic.
Got a people in this video will make simple doors.
Later on we'll extend them to make locked doors.
But first we'll make simple doors.
Let's take a moment to think about how doors and work on our game.
I want these doors to give a little bit of tension there also and give some gameplay bonuses.
I will talk about that a second.
So how are they going to work.
Well the player has to actually use the door.
I'm not thinking of a door like you would get in let's say Wal-Mart or supermarket where you get close
and a magic eye detects you and they open for you.
You're going to have to physically open the door.
How do you do that.
You're going to left click on them.
So you've got to move the mouse to the door and left click.
And I won't be able to detect the player is in the clickable area.
In other words is the player close enough to actually click on this door.
Now we need to do that because otherwise the play will be able to click on the door from anyone the
level which is not what we want.
Now we also need to make sure that we're checking when the player has left the clickable area.
So we make an error 2D when to check when the players entered it and when they've left it I'm going
to use those to change a variable called can click the player has to be in range of the door but NPC
is just opened the door by getting close.
This means our area is going to do different things depending on what type of character has entered
them.
Those are also in a block light.
Now I mentioned this can be a gameplay bonus at all.
This is the gameplay bonus if the doors close.
I can see there's a guard on the outside of it.
The guard can't see me and the doors have to close automatically.
I don't want to have to click on them again to close them.
All right.
So let's get into the game and what I want to do is get into the template level first song that click
on the little film icon hit to open the template sing and let's make a brand new node for doors so brand
new node you can call it doors say that and get back into Level 1 and you can see we now have this new
thing called doors that's why the doors will live but doors are going to need a brand new scene.
So it's like a brand new scene.
And we need a custom node as our base and our custom node is going to have an area 2D so our doors are
actually area 2D that are going to have collision inside them.
So first here we have our door and let's see we need a brand new collision shape so let's make a collision
shape 2D.
There you are.
Yeah.
And on the shape we'll have a brand new rectangle shape and a click on the rectangle shape and just
set the extents to be 32 by 42.
Where am I getting 32 from.
Well if you look on the graphics under P and G and on the tiles you'll see that I've actually pulled
some of the tiles out from the tile she I'm going to be using this one tough three four seven so I just
drag this in the sprite.
This is 64 pixels.
The extent is from the center to the edge.
So half 64 is 32.
Let's move this sprite to be a direct shot of the doors is not a child the collision shape.
I'm going to rename it to dork sprite.
OK.
So the doll sprite transform 0 0 right in the center there.
That's looking good so this collision shape here is going to be a character detector sector let's call
it that Let's rename it character detectable.
And that's going to be what we gonna use to check.
Is there a player in here.
Is there an NPC in here and when it is going to send some signals first however this is just a sprite.
People will be able to walk through it.
So we have this error to date.
It has its own collision but we have no collision to stop people walking through the doors.
So going at a static body as a child of the sprites static body so anybody 2D which is going to need
its own collision shape collision shape duty and the expense for this it's can be a rectangle shape
makes makes sense.
And this is going to be 32 by 10.
There we go.
We can now hide that before we go any further let's make sure that we've actually set our collision
layers.
This is going to be really important.
So what LaRose we are part of the tile map we could call this layer level inside but we've called a
time up so stick with it.
Doors a part of the tournament and they can interact with players and pieces they can't interact with
time Ms.
The really important one is going to the character detector.
This is vital.
So on the door for the area Judy got a collision and make sure the layer is set to tile map and make
sure the mask is set to player and NPC do not set this as Tama.
If you do it'll detect the level and that's going to cause all kinds of problems.
We don't want to detect the level we just want to detect characters and our characters so far are players
and gods and technically cameras.
But I don't know how a camera would get in here.
OK.
So we can now hide this collision shape.
So we have a collision shape.
We have the sprite and it's a static body so far so good.
I also want to add a light include I'm going to add this is a child of the sprite.
So let's go to light occluded Tutti and we want to make sure that we're hiding what's happening here.
It's a brand new lighter cleaner as a polygon.
There it is.
And let's draw it in.
So at new node I'm going to draw as close to these coins I can.
You could use a grid here but you're going to have to set the snaps to one and I don't really feel like
doing that.
OK.
So there's our door.
I'm going to click on the clutter and I'm going to open it somewhere until closed.
So that would just blocking the three corners We're not blocking the slide so far so good.
This still shows an error it's like click the side.
It shouldn't do but it is.
So we can hide you.
And that's everything to look at two more things you want to do.
Let's go right to the top of door and on to add an animation player and that's what we use to open the
door animation player not animation tree or tree play animation play and one more thing we want is we
want some sort of sound effects effects adult and audio stream play 2D.
And when Al gets to go we can now start making things first thing I do is I make this animation for
the doll set to make the animation for the door and to make it brand new animation and to call it open
and it looks good.
I think this can be a force a confirmation is going to open.
Wait.
Close associate four seconds.
And I'm thinking oh one second snap I'm going to animate this door sprite by moving the sprite it'll
move all of its children.
That's going include the static body and the lighter clutter which is exactly what I want.
So let's go to transform an under position let's make a brand new key and go to one second then I'm
going to move this negative sixty four and there goes and then I click it that and the stay there all
three seconds into a three second mark and make a new key and then four seconds it's gonna go to zero
and we'll make key there.
So if I play this it opens it stays for two seconds and it closes pretty good.
You can play with those times you can play with the speed you can do what you want with that but that's
looking pretty solid.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I want to make some sound effects of audio the audio stream play a 2D so that we shown how to do that.
And I want you to figure out your sound effects before getting further.
I've given you some options here.
So if we go to SFX you've got all these different door open door close ones.
Let's play one
and it's looping.
So before we go any further just go to select all of these go up here to the import tag uncheck loop
and here's the really important bit press re import.
If you don't press re import nothing will happen.
Back to seeing now when you check any of these.
Right.
OK.
So if I guess the animation player I would like you to make the door play a sound when it opens and
it closes pick the sounds you want.
Figure out how you do this.
Now there are different ways you can do this but see how familiar you are with it with the interface
with the animation play See if you figure it out.
Don't go crazy if you get frustrated.
That's OK.
Come back I'll show you my solution.
Meanwhile pause the video give it a shot.
And when you come back I'll show you my solution
and welcome back.
OK.
So how many to do this.
Well what I'm going to do is I'm going to add a brand new track in my track is gonna be an audio playback
track and it's going to say Okay where's the node that I'm going to animate.
I want to animate the audio stream allegedly.
Now this is not the only way we could do this.
Okay.
We could also go to audio stream play 2D animate stream is a key and then animate playing is a key.
So there are a couple ways you could do this but this allows me to do everything in one place.
So on add a brand new key here insert key.
Click on that and so say what's my stream.
I must say door open to maybe see what that sounds like
yeah I quite like that kind of movie.
And then the door closing one so it's insert a key here and stick with twos and they sound.
So when the OS so I'm going to click on that key and see a stream empty press.
Here we go.
How's that.
Oh I don't like that one it's all.
Okay.
How you know even worse.
Let's pick one.
OK.
So those string one it is.
And let's make sure I'm clicking the right key.
CLICKING There.
And I also think it needs to be much later that sound effect should happen when it closes.
So one more time
very nice.
OK.
So that's almost done.
Let's actually say that some say this.
Make a brand new folder.
Call it doors Rosen locked doors in here and save it.
OK.
So we can now put in our door.
I'm going to put in a test of analysis when I open it.
So I'm going to add a new scene put in my doors and click on move and just move it down to here.
Great all I can test right now is does it have collisions.
I mean we'll test that this press play and move past this plot of randomly put here and we now have
a door that doesn't do anything.
Let's make it do stuff.
Let's give it a script.
So back to doors and a brand new script.
Brand new script can be empty.
It's called doors and doors.
It's perfect.
First we need is a variable called can click.
And it's going to default is false.
Now next thing I want to do is add in some signals.
So let's go to the door.
The area Judy gets the note and there's three signals we want body entered physics body body exited
physics body and on the collision shape input event.
Now this is going to detect when some sort of input is happening on the area.
And that's gonna allow us to check if someone's clicking on the door.
What's going to give a little bit of leeway.
Actually check if we click anyway here.
But I'm okay with that.
And the heat of the moment I think that's fine.
So body entered physics putting in a connect that to door Let's just do the other one body exited connect
to the door and finally let's go to input event and that connects the door as well.
OK.
So when we've entered here we need to check.
Are you the player so going to need some sort of if but what are we doing.
We've got this variable coming at this argument body.
Something is entered and if we take a look over done with the door and the collisions only two types
of things can answer players and pieces.
It will not detect anything else.
So we know anything that entering must be either player an NPC as a couple of ways we could do this.
We could say if body whatever the argument is has a property called name which is equal to player then
do a thing.
This is great as long as we don't rename the player the other way they do this and the one that I would
rather do is to use the collision layers if we mouse over the layer you see that the properties called
Collision layer and if we look at these values these are binary values.
So this is one this is two.
This is four.
So if I had this one and this one together that's three.
This one is four.
This is six.
OK.
So basic binary I only care about whatever this value is and that value is 1.
So what I can do is if say I can say if body dot collision layer is equal to one.
This is another way of saying if you're detecting the player please note if we haven't set up these
collision things properly we're going to start checking finding things like the door itself the static
body.
Right.
So this layer and these must must be done properly.
We have to make sure that we're not detecting things like tournaments but if everything set up correctly
this is going to save us a lot of time.
So if you're the player can click is now equal to true else open let's make a function called open for
any fella let's get rid of this thing go away fine.
Function open and this is just animation player dot play what are we playing with the animation open.
There we go all right.
So if something is entered it must be either player on NBC if it's on collision level one then you then
we can change that.
Otherwise just open it and that's going to detect and pieces for us.
OK.
So now if you just say if something has exited the body or we need to do is check if is the Plaza.
If body dot collision layer
is equal to one can click is equal to is now equal to False we'd only spot an Elson here because nothing's
going to happen on nails.
Finally let's take the mouse click and to do that I'm going to use if input is mouse button pressed
his button left which is a constant.
Great but I don't want it that's the text that it's being clicked on to check if we can click.
So speak and can click.
That's the same as saying and can click is true.
So I don't know something else if I can do both of those then open and that should be everything.
Let's test it and I want to go to night vision and walking out the door I can open the door wait for
it and the door will close.
Now did you notice that the door get close enough is over the wall.
I read on like that.
Let's fix that to fix that we're going to use something called z index.
So if I go to the door and we go to the sprite there it is the sprite has a z index or z index.
Imagine you're looking down at a piece of paper the top players have a higher number the bottom layers
have a lower number.
Someone set the z index here for one great but that doesn't help us because the entire tile map isn't
is one layer.
So let's fix the entire time that being one layer.
If I go to template layer and look at the template we need to be careful.
We could set the entire zone decks higher so let's say I set this to my save that and go about the level
the door will vanish.
It's actually still there but it's underneath it's not being drawn.
If I set it back down to 1 it's going to look fine let's just say that it's going to look fine but when
it opens it will walk you show it will still open like that.
Okay.
So what's the solution here.
Well back to template level keep the basic z index is 0 going to go to the tile map.
We're going to go and show the full screen here.
Click on the tile sheet and what I want to do is click on the wall section that's counters a single
tile as an altar tile got a selected tile and changed this selected tile for two.
Now in a press save and minimize this area and go back to the level I can move it and it's above the
floor but below the walls because the wall altar tile has a different z index to everything else.
Now when I look at it
I can run up to the door click on it wait for it and close it.
OK so now all that and we need to do is add some more doors.
OK.
There's a difference.
Let's see how this feels and play the game again nice and moody and a sick look.
The gods should make it through the door.
Except I happen to know that God won't make it through the door because I know that something wrong.
But let's just check it.
Come on God.
Three go.
Nope can't do it.
Why can't the god do it.
Because remember say be very careful.
Collision lines let's open God up TSM.
Take a look at the gods collisions.
So on the physics body the gods a player.
God is not a player.
The god is an NPC that God can interact with players and tile maps.
Now let's try that again.
So now the gods can already go to the doors already gone through really keen.
He likes this door.
Come on God.
You can do this still to
is he going.
Yeah.
Here it comes.
Come on you can do it God.
I believe in you.
You has guards can open doors doors close automatically.
There's still too many torches and in this mode we can fix that.
And next video.
Look at that.
That's looking awesome.
So in this video it looked at how to detect mouse clicks how to change the behavior of your door depending
on who's using it.
Changing audio sources an animation player and using a z index.
So excellent luck and I'll see you in the next video.