Hello again you stupendous go to people in this video we're going to make keypads now the keypads are
gonna be used for locked doors we're gonna have some unlocked doors but the player can get a combination
from a computer for locked all got a locked or pressed and a little no pads gonna come up a keypad is
gonna come up that's what we're gonna make in order to make that easier I'm going to talk about the
awesome power of things before we get started some basic groundwork with themes things are used by any
control mode control mode is anything that does UI so it could be a button a text label and so on it's
basically a way of saying Okay whenever I say a font This is what I mean themes can be inherited by
children so you don't need to apply the theme to every single element in your UI apply it to the top
level and everything below will use it obviously you could have different themes and different elements
but if there's nothing else in there it will use as parents thing.
Which brings us to the third point themes can be overwritten if I tell you that the button has to look
like this but this specific button has its own settings then you use those specific settings for that
button because there's nothing overriding the thing.
Okay so let's take a look at how that works when you get into got it and I'm gonna make a brand new
song.
Now we could call this a user interface node and have it as a child but I only use custom node and use
it pop up now pop ups are specific type of UI a little window that will suddenly appear.
What's interesting about them is when they first arrive they hidden.
So you can't see them by default.
That's what this warning is.
We can show it but when it arrives in game it will be hidden.
Let's call this number pad or number that number has a good name.
And we need to add some stuff.
First we want to add is a background.
Now we have various different ways you can use here but I'm going to use a 9 patch rect and 9 patch
rectangle is a way of splitting up a single texture into little quadrants and then stretching most of
them but not the corners.
Let me show you one way to do that.
I've got my 9 patch rectangle but texture in here.
So let's go to graphics and interface and into PSG and here we've got a whole bunch of different ones.
I'm going to pick one of these and say I'm a pick metal panel PMG that put metal panel PSG in here and
let's give you a minimum size.
So under rectangle what's a good room size I say 300 pixels wide by 400 high zoom in can see it's stretching
right this pixels Asian the corners quite ugly.
But if I go to patch margin which is part of the nine patch rectangle and give us a setting of let's
say five pixels on the left it's now not stretching the first five pixels.
So I can unify fix on the top and it's looking a lot cleaner now this little Was that a bolt screwed
as little circle here isn't quite there so let's make the margin a little wider.
Ten by ten should be right.
And I can do that on the right and at the bottom.
And now this will look clean no matter what size because the first 10 pixels from the top left right
and bottom are not being stretched and everything else is this is a really nice way of scaling PND without
it being obvious that that's what you're doing.
We're not getting that weird distortion.
Now with that done and we could really just close users will close the text region with that done what
we need to do we need to decide what it's going to look like.
I'm sure a sketch very quickly on here using the Windows sketching things.
What's it called is a snip and sketch.
Go.
We're gonna put some gloss here that's going to have what color you black text or numbers whatever it's
going to be.
And underneath we'll have a bunch of buttons which for numbers and drawn red.
One two three four five six seven eight nine zero and.
Okay.
And to make this a little simpler I'm going to put a little light in the corner here that will change
color if you get the code right.
So let's just see what that looks like 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0.
OK so that's your standard configuration for a phone or most number parts right.
Security things.
Now why am I sketching out like this.
I'm doing this.
I could see on my use.
You guys can look like basically I've got two different areas.
I've got the display at the top and the input at the bottom.
And that tells me I'm going to need a v box container a virtual box container.
In other words I'm going to have little subdivisions that can be automatically sorted vertically and
if I put something in there it'll just resize it and reorder it depending on the order it is in the
century.
This here looks like a grid container to me.
We'll look at those in Italy later.
So we'll start with a V box container and then if all the church the all the child elements shop there.
So let's get out of snip and sketch which is a terrible thing.
Although in fairness I think because I find it hard to say and let's start without the box container.
So be a child of no part.
This is a background not investment.
And V box container.
Now there is also the split container.
I'm sure that one real quick the split container which looks the same but what it is actually gonna
do is put a little line here between elements that we can drag in this case I don't want that.
So let's get rid of the V split container and put a v box container add which is control a v box container.
There it is.
This really won't be the same size as the nine patch doesn't it.
Let's get a rectangle and give you a minimum size would be say 300 by 400.
And that's your size now.
OK.
So now there's nine patch rectangle can now have stretch.
So let's say a full rectangle anchors full rectangle.
There we go.
And now there's the box container can have the same thing.
So let's give you the anchors.
No for directions and a full rectangle that's looking much better.
OK.
So everything underneath the box container is going to be split vertically and we can change things
by having things like a separation between them.
Now first thing we want is the display and I want it sent up here.
I want it centered in this area.
So the child I want to use is a center container and I'm going to rename this display container in case
I'm going a little bit fast which I realize I might be all I'm doing to add things pressing here.
Control and typing in the first few letters.
So Santa's containers are a type of control a type of container and it does exactly what you might think.
It takes whatever you put underneath it and centers it in the window it has.
Now you notice here that this layer button is is great out.
That's because it's taking its information from up high which is what we want.
And as a child with a box container I'm going to put another nine patch rectangle so let's pick nine
patch rectangle there it is nine patch rect and the I will use this glass panel right here.
So let's bring in glass panel I'm sure.
Drag it in.
All right.
You'll notice glass panel is not showing because it's tiny.
So we need to give them a minimum size.
So back to rect minimum size I'm going to say 250 by 100.
There we go.
Now it's right up the top is not what I want.
I want a little bit of a margin here where you put the margin.
How about probably in the display container.
So let's go here and get a margin and I think 10 pixels on the top looking pretty good.
We got a little bit low in that about 15 OK.
So that is going to be where that glass panel is.
Now that glass panel is going to need some patch margins what looks good about four pixels not 41 full
pixels in all directions looks pretty cleans.
And we zoom out it's looking pretty good now with in that we're going to have a label.
So let's add the label as a child of display container control eight type and label.
That's my label.
Now you'll notice white or light blue.
Bit of a pain is what I should do.
Go down to the fonts here and start chasing the custom colors right.
However I'm not going to do that here.
I'm going to do that in the theme.
That's the whole point.
So let's go back up to the parent and on the theme.
I'm going to create a new theme enough I click on theme you'll get this little theme Ed. And we can
scale this up if we want but you'll notice this is the default gotta look first it will do is make it
a default font so it's got to font and want a new dynamic font click on it and we have all this stuff
so press the font itself and we can loads of font data if we go to load we're going to graphics go to
interface and go into fonts you'll see two fonts I think a default one is going to be this can vex a
future so there it is and are settings that say a default size of twenty four and it's going to want
the default color to be white.
They can just about see it that's not very useful I could give it an outline in black if I wanted to
but I don't think that looks great if you want to go for it I don't but that's gonna be our default
font.
I've also noticed that the margin has reset itself which is not I want you know the V box container
is what should have the margins so let's give that the margin of ten from the top and if you properly
have a margin of 10 from the bottom which I think B minus 10.
Yes.
OK.
So that's looking a lot better.
However this font right here in these you place all we do is going to custom colors and change the font
default colors to black.
So it's inheriting everything from the theme except for that one thing I have now updated which is going
to be really useful as things go on specifically with the buttons.
All right.
So that's a good solid start before I go any further let's say Fisk's I just realized I haven't saved
it.
So save on the interface element call this number.
Dot TSM done and you know what.
I feel like we're ready to start adding some buttons so I'm gonna add another center container.
Give me a child of the box container and call it center container and there it is.
And you know what this can be.
Let's record this as quick as Button container.
And I feel like that should have the same margins on the left and right.
I'm just getting it into the V box containers a 10 on the left minus 10 from the right.
Just I can see what's happening.
You'll notice a puff on the fact that I've put a lower case b which I shouldn't have done.
Now we got naming convention matters.
You'll notice that it's automatically changed the layout.
And if I drag the button container to be above display container it'll reorder it that way.
Right.
So whatever order things are in in the same tree is how the containers are going to organize things
that can come in really hand if you're doing something like split screen for example you have an H box
container and then player one will be on the left and if you add a new player it'll just scooch things
over.
So pretty great way of doing that but that's a little about what we're doing so let's add in a button.
So as a child of button container I'm going to add in a simple button not only a text button just a
simple button that is not high spec container.
Come on Yan container.
There we go.
Simple button and add in the text.
So on the button now the text 1.
OK that button isn't what I want.
So under my theme which is back in the top here I'm going to add something to the theme.
So here's what the button looks like.
Normally let's go to edit thing and add a class item.
Now to press these dots here I've got all the different classes.
Oh press button and when I add it you'll notice in the theme button just turned up so I can now press
on button.
And here are the default settings for buttons specifically if I go to styles you'll notice here we've
got buttons for pressed normal hover focus and disabled.
I specifically care about normal which is what the button looks like when nothing's touching it hover
and pressed.
And you'll also notice we have all of these little metal panels.
I'm going to pick for example metal red as normal metal blue as hover metal Green is pressed.
I don't normally like using red and blue together so maybe I'll do yellow instead of green.
We'll see now.
I can't just drag in a texture because this is not looking for texture.
This is looking for style box of some kind.
Normal and I want to add a new style box texture right.
I know what a flat color.
I don't want to be empty.
It's not a line little protection.
And that's an annoying bug in this version.
Got it.
If I go to back to the theme and go back to my style box if I try and press this it will go back and
close the theme down.
So how do I fix that or what am I doing to save this.
So I'm going to click on a little arrow next Starbucks texture and go save and under interface I'm going
to call this button normal style dot here.
Yes.
Just don't know what it is.
Now I can open that in the file tree.
So let's go to the file system rather let's go to interface double click on it.
And here it is.
So little irritating but I can do it that way.
So let's here's my texture.
And what do we say.
Not being touched is red.
As you know blue is blue I like that.
So there's my blue look.
There it is.
So now I can go back here and the Starbucks you can get the color the font isn't good so let's overwrite
that font color is black and I might need to hide that and bring it back for to show.
That's looking pretty solid.
I'm going to rename this to button one
button 1.
There we go.
Not Tony button one.
Awesome.
I also want to give this a minimum size.
I think 40 by 40 should be good.
Pretty solid.
It's not in the right place because currently it's centered but we will fix fix that in a little while.
A couple of things I will change from here.
If I go back to my style sheet the button looks like that when we hover or press it it goes back to
the default so we need to add some more.
Same exact thing.
So let's say on hover I need to add a new Starbucks texture sheet.
If I try and click on it it will do the same.
Bugs to open it and save.
That's as save as is this this is hover so button hover
style dotted areas and do the same thing with press.
So new style chic new style box texture save.
And I'm going to call this just click here pressed great.
So now I can go down to my file systems and just do all three of his hover and that's going to have
a texture of my hover color so blue is normal.
Let's say red is hover like that.
See what that looks like.
And we need to change the color for that.
So the color of horribly black the color on be pressed to be black.
There we go.
That's looking better but press still doesn't work.
We don't want that little flicker effect.
So let's go back down and depressed.
We do the same exact thing with a different color yellow maybe or green.
I'm feeling yellow right now.
I don't know why.
Just great.
So now you should have a minimum size not a size a 40 by 40 and the alignment should be in the center
and that's looking pretty solid.
So let's take a look at the texture and that's what our Button's going to look like.
Now clearly we can't press on it until we get in game and we haven't why this ends so even if we bring
this into our scene that's was going to look like when I'm able to press anything.
So instead what I'd like to do is get you guys to add the buttons.
So before we do that I'm going to add in a new node called a grid container and I'd like you to explore
a little bit and see how it feels to do this next part the challenge.
I would like you to add the buttons to through zero and okay to your number pad using the grid container
to make this a little easier.
Now we haven't talked about it so don't worry if it's a little bit outside your comfort zone.
Give it a shot.
And when you're ready come back and I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
So first thing we do is I'm gonna make button 1 a child of grid container.
Now we could just duplicate button one.
But look it's gone underneath what we need to do is here on the columns.
Let's set this of three columns.
So now we add Button 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0.
OK.
Clearly I need to actually change the tax on each of those which won't take long.
So there's two there's three four five six 7 8 9 0 and.
Okay.
I'm actually going to add another thing in a moment.
I just split this up a bit more so let's say a button container.
You need a module from that from the next one here.
So how can we do that we're going to v box container go to custom constant constants not constants and
let's say you need a 16 pixel gap more than that.
How about a 40 pixel gap maybe even a 60 pixel gap note too much like crazy.
50 looks good.
I'm going to add in this dot read this will be my little light is gonna change color and I'm gonna add
it as a texture and so texture rect and that's just a control element that's a texture I don't want
to be a sprite sprites can move around.
It needs to have its element here.
Let's rename you to status light to get name calling and let's give you a texture.
It's in the wrong place.
How do I change the place.
Put it in the right area the scenery.
You'll also notice that's not looking good.
Let's expand.
So that he's looking pretty solid now.
One thing I have noticed is that this font is a little bit big for the buttons.
So I'm going to go back to my theme and under my buttons I'm going to give them a different font so
let's go to New dynamic font click on it.
And the moment I change the font here all this information will change to do that.
I'm going to click on font data and load in on the graphics and interface and the fonts.
This thin one that's much smaller the settings 16 looks good had a 24 bit big 18 20 find a font size
you like.
I want them in black but that's not reset here.
I don't want to give an outline that is looking pretty good I quite like that.
Let's also make sure that the font color is in the buttons font color is in the style for the buttons.
So every button that we create that has the style will now look like this.
However I don't really want the okay button to look like that I'm going to overwrite it.
I'm going to rename button eleven to button.
Okay now you'll notice we've also got these nice corner ones.
I'm going to use those for the okay button just rounded out make it look a little bit more designed.
Don't need to but I quite like the change so on the button.
Okay.
Which was button 11 but I've renamed it.
I'm going to put in these and to do that to override the style I need to override hover pressed and
normals should put new Starbucks texture in each and the bug won't show here.
It only shows when we're making a thing.
I'm not making a theme overwriting.
This will work fine.
So hover is what color is that let's take a look.
Hover is red pressed his yellow.
Okay so hover is going to be the right corner.
And I can pass that again pressed is going to be the yellow corner
that lives here.
Yep there it is.
And normal is going to be the blue corner.
OK.
So there we have a lovely little novel pad.
It's not wide enough.
It doesn't work yet.
But we've used themes to make this look pretty awesome.
And the great thing about using themes is once the thing is set up every time I'm making any control
element that's going to use that theme.
It'll just build upon the elements we have.
So just built from the default phone and onwards and already we've got this lovely looking number pad
and I'm quite happy with that.
Well I think I might do in a good container is just spread the buttons out a bit more let's give them
a two pixel separation in all directions note that's nowhere near big enough.
How about an eight pixel separation all directions so good maybe even a little bigger.
Lewis go crazy with twelve.
How do we feel.
Feels good.
I quite like it.
OK.
That is our number pad.
I'm saving it and I'm pretty happy with it.
So in this video we've looked at how to create a pop up note how to create a thing and how to overwrite
things in specific notes.
That's got me so that is really useful in future games.
So excellent work.
And we'll see you in the next video.