Hello again you.
Gloria's got people in this video.
We're going to start having some fun with furniture.
I enjoyed having fun.
Furniture and HI MY SIS of they're doing in here.
But this is the first stage of it because we're going to have two different types of furniture static
body and rigid body.
And remember static body is not affected by physics right.
So that stuff we don't necessarily want to move.
In fact I want to move at all.
So I'm thinking things like permanent fixtures anything I don't want to be able to push with myself
or an NPC or a bystander or some food.
We also go to some rigid bodies later which is stuff we do want to interact with physics.
Now we could in theory use a grid map for this but Im going to advise against it partially because Grid
Maps are a single node with a single position.
If we wanted to change any of these objects to a rigid body it wouldnt work because Grid Maps only work
with static bodies.
However you could use this with a static body.
Okay so lets get to work.
And the first thing we do is take a look in our models folder in models and furniture as branch of different
measures here.
We're not going to use all of these but they're in here for you.
I'm interested in what this kitchen stuff from kitchen bar through to kitchen cabinet.
And then probably sink the stove.
I might get a fridge in maybe a coffee machine.
I do like coffee and I'm going to put them over here.
One more thing I've noticed by the way is I'm constantly having to rescale everything whether it's the
walls or the robots.
And I suspect it's because I've made this character too short.
I could go in here and recite the character then I have to revise the player immature and the robot
armature then I'm going to have to recite the actual walls right because they're going be half the size.
Then the bystanders that could in theory save me work later because now I'm going to have to recycle
all the furniture.
However I'm okay resizing furniture going forward and this isn't actually cause a game breaking bug
so just be aware that you could if you wanted go and recycles everything that way.
Alright with all that said let's make a new scene and I'm going to start by just bringing in a static
body I would call this static body which we start with a song with Kitchen Bar.
And I'm just gonna bring in a mesh instance and drag the kitchen bar over here.
Now I have to know that this is the wrong size.
I can demonstrate that you very easily by just bringing in a kitchen mesh right.
It should be smaller than this.
Oh snap on.
I don't want that for now.
So let's get to the kitchen bar that you are.
This is too big so let's figure out the sights we want.
I think we're looking at about three quarter size so zero point seventy five all three axes looks looks
actually it's a little bit high than what is zero point five look like.
Actually zero point five looks pretty solid doesn't it.
It's about the height you would expect the kitchen counter to be OK let's call it zero point five.
So let's rescale the mesh instance to zero point five.
And now I need to give the collision shape however I'm going to mesh and do let's just use a convex
gauge and shape doesn't have anything fancy.
Look it's going with the default size so I have to rescale this.
I don't like rescaling it because it can lead to bugs but if I just click on convex it won't actually
give me an easy way of changing that.
It's just going to give me a bunch of separate points and that's going to apply.
So I'm going to give it this right.
Give it this way.
Do it this way.
Well let's save the scene and see how this works got into scenes into furniture which should be empty
unless you downloaded a very early project to this in which case files in but you can delete those new
folder and feel like static body is a good name for this static body and kitchen basken live in there
and we can see what it's going to look like someone at the lead this mission since and inside furniture
which is a nice thing we put the template an instance in.
Bring that in and let's move it to the right place.
You going to scoop that up slightly.
That's right.
Let's skip over to the orwall I'M DOING THIS Bye for now because mine if this goes into the wall once
you start to leave too much of a gap.
Now put the snap back on and I'm just going to drag it over this way.
That looks about right so I'm thinking of some sort of canteen environments so let's just duplicate
a bunch of these.
One two three and you see how I snap it's fantastic for this four five six as a feel good feels pretty
solid to me.
I could put some more over here maybe before I'm okay with these for now.
I could even create a subfolder for kitchen zarmina make a brand new where I note that you are a creep.
You call you a kitchen bar and you go drag all the kitchen bano into that just make it nice and easy
to organise a probably only typical kitchen but typical kitchen bar.
Now one of play.
How's that work.
Pretty solid.
Now I don't necessarily want a player to come behind here because look I can hide from the food and
that's going to be a little bit lame.
So I'm going to restrict the play and movement on the player behind this bar or in front of this line.
I want to create a new node as part of the level and I'm going to go into the template scene make a
new bracket a simple node and call this collisions collision was there at the beginning for a save that
go back into level 1 here's my collision of awls.
So inclusion of all sets make a static body.
And I'm going to call this front wall and it's going to have no mesh instance it's going to be completely
invisible.
But it is going to have a collision shape so give that collision shape.
Lesin Cape.
Awesome.
And we use a box Collider for that.
OK shake.
Now if you're going to collision take it off of torain and have it only interact with the player.
So it is on layer and it only masks the player.
Now when I move this to the centre of the room which is roughly here and start moving it extends a block
the entire room off.
And this if you can line it up against that wall show me or yes that doorway.
I want the player to be able to go right up to the doorway but no further.
That's actually pretty good.
Now if I've done this right the food be able to go through here but not the play.
Let's find out.
Yeah.
I can't go past this line.
Bystanders can hear the shot in here.
And that's pretty awesome.
Now I'm going to duplicate this front we'll call this one back home and just scootch it back here scrooched
scootch.
And I think scootching it right up to where I've put this.
That looks pretty good.
One try to avoid the ability.
I don't want the players to jump on to the counter because then in theory I can avoid a lot of the damage
that way.
So I'm thinking a player can't actually cross this line how I managed it.
Yes I have or some tightens the amount of space I have as a player.
What are your thoughts of furniture in this area.
But that's off to a good start.
OK so now I want to do is make some more décor over here.
I might leave this corner free for now.
We'll see.
But I'd like you to fashion some fun furniture create some static body furniture and design level.
Don't worry about rigid body yet just make the stuff that cannot be moved.
You can make it look like mine.
You might make it completely different maybe yours as a bunch of desks that can't be moved.
Maybe also as an office but have fun with it.
Pause the video.
See what you can come up with and when you're ready come on back and by the way don't forget to share
the level you've made so far.
And welcome back.
Here is my beautiful little kitchen.
I've decided to go full Canteen's I've got two stoves and two sinks needs more light in here don't I.
I've got three fridges and I could probably organize us a bit more so I'm going to do that real quick
with you guys here so let's make our fridges and go to find all three fridges which are not kitchen
bars and they live in here.
And I think cabinets is another one we could use to make cabinets note and call this cabinets.
Everything that says kitchen cabinet on it can live in there.
And that's starting to look a lot more organized as it sinks and stoves should put them in one minute.
Put them in one cord sinks and stoves.
One more thing to do what we hear.
And I wasn't going to do this for the able to feel like we can.
Let's go in to our scene.
You know I can just put a lot on this.
I don't need my furniture but I'm going to look at the player who is here.
And let's open that script.
We need a function called hurt for when the food hits us because the food won't vanish.
That's why we function called hurt and all it's going to do is pass.
And we do the same thing in pieces.
So where's my robot NPC folder script.
There it is.
Let's put a function called hurt
and just pass the reason for doing this is project was going to check.
Do you have this function.
And if you do I'm going to vanish so now in a press play.
Let's go full screen again.
In fact you can press this button.
The food doesn't hang around after it hits me which is reducing the clutter level by people.
Yeah I'm really happy with how this is looking so far.
I feel like that's a good place for the video in this video with continued making level.
And we've looked at designing lots of physics body objects specifically how to keep them organized.
So excellent work.
Don't forget to share your progress and I will see you in the next video.