Hello again you lovely girl.
People in this video.
Let's actually fix this bug right the IS ON FLOOR Buck.
You've been really patient with me.
So let's get it fixed to remind you what it looks like it's getting game and let's run into a spike
doesn't work sometimes works inconsistent.
Why is this happening.
OK.
So a nice little thing you can do when you're trying to fix a bug is go through a little checklist first.
What is the bug and then why is the bug.
So let's actually break down what the bug is.
If Bonnie is on the floor spikes and jump pads don't consistently move money into the air OK.
And is on floor as an issue.
What's happening.
Why is this happening is we're forcing bunnies why motion to zero if bunnies on the ground as a little
bit theoretical that's actually look at it in code.
So back in tomorrow and let's open the play a script.
If we go down to where is it applying gravity here it is.
If IS ON FLOOR OR ELSE IF is on floor we can set motion not why to zero.
I mean if you're on the ground don't fall and don't jump set.
Keep that to zero.
We originally put this in because of gravity right.
We didn't want gravity to be building up.
Otherwise the long we played the game the faster Bunny would fall and the worse jumping would be.
OK now let's look at hurt.
We're going to move up by one to not be off on the ground going away to frame and then we're going to
add negative jump speed or subtract jump speed.
However if we're already on the ground this is going to trigger before anything else happens.
If we're falling we might be falling too fast and we're going to hit the ground before anything happens.
I would point at which point motion dot why is zero before we go anywhere.
So what we need is something on is on the floor an extra condition and another condition here.
What I want to do is say if you're on the floor and you're not trying to move up well how would I do
that.
What what to do is say and motion don't y is greater than zero Y greater than because positive y is
down negative y is up.
Okay.
So if you are falling at all and you're on the ground set motion to dot y to zero.
Otherwise we're just going to skip it.
However before we go any further let's go back down to hurt of this here where we put them top speed
and that's not actually what we mean.
We don't mean negative equals jump speed we need mean equals negative jumps being set it to the jump
speed don't add the jump speed.
So let's try that again
looks good.
Let's make sure this is actually the works I'm back to game state.
I'm a simple Nine Lives to 30 and press play.
Now if I'm right every time I enter this spike it should work
even if I'm on the ground.
And it should work for all jump pads as well as going to jump ahead Boing Boing Boing
looking it up.
Set this fact to three and just make sure that we've got boost set to negative jump speed as opposed
to negative equals jump speed and that's looking good.
So no challenge for this one as just a simple bug fixing video.
But there we go now.
All hazards will be working correctly as well or jump Pat.
So excellent work.
And we'll see when the next video.