Hello again lovely God people in this video are going to finish.
Awesome.
Because eveillard Lots of awesome.
And now his final dose of awesomely the awesome cherry on an awesome cake if you like cherries.
If you don't then find something more awesome and have fun with the metaphor.
Would you add some visual effects and specifically our awesome visual feedback is going to be particles
that the player is going to emit when they score a goal.
I also wanted something funky with the lighting.
I want a spotlight on the player that scored a goal that's only going to appear when that goal is scored
and whenever goals scored.
I'm a dim the main light that big directional like we have going to dim that completely out.
So let's begin with particles of the particles on the plate.
Just got to have a steer over the particles on the player.
Some want to open a play a note a particle right above the head.
That way we couldn't keep the position consistent and not have the coming of the body which can look
really weird.
So let's go into one of the placings doesn't really matter which one because there's only one placing
I'm a high the collision shakes out you need to see it right now.
What I do want is to add a particle node.
Now we're not going to use a particle to deal with these particles and particles emit 3D objects.
So first things first let's move that to just above the player's head.
At about there.
If we go into models and we go into particles you see there's a star mesh right here.
What I did was I found a star object and just exported the mesh directly and save that so here we have
a nice little star mesh and to use it.
We need to put that under draw passes.
We can see an error here and particles and it says nothing is visible because you haven't given me a
draw pass.
I don't know what I'm using So let's just drag the mesh in and as a star is not doing anything yet it's
just hovering there but it's a start.
I also want to give some material so let's go into the mash and find the material.
And you know it will load in the same material as the ball which I believe is in graphics as Ball material.
Perfect.
That way it can have a nice consistency and then we have we have a nice little start.
Now we've drawn a star but this isn't yet being used as a particle So let's go process materials and
other process materials as make a new particle material that's imported.
Okay that's looking a lot more fancy.
First thing I notice these stars are way too big for me.
On about half the size I won't go into the processed material and scroll down so I see scale and I'm
going to put these as zero point five has that look cool would make me smaller.
How does it apply to 5.
It's a little too small.
No I will fix the speed in the direction of stuff.
This is just to get started.
Alright so we're off to a good start.
Go back up to the actual particles note as a couple of other things on a change.
I want this whole Ask for 3 seconds rather than 1.
And you'll notice that the slowing down why they're slowing down because they're only drawing 8 other
times with the wait for one to vanish.
So it's going take three seconds of me redraw.
That's okay I can I can work with that.
Let's now change how these behaves.
We go into particles and let's take a look trail looks good images shape OK.
So we're emitting at a point as various things we could do here as a sphere and then it's just emitting
from a radius of a surface as an imaginary sphere here and it's emitting them.
I quite like point by going emit from a single point.
What I do want though is I want to go up and ask me.
Gravity you see Gravity is set to negative nine point eight minutes at the time nine point eight.
Looking more like it I want a lot more than that so let's change us for a one shot see how it's going
to look when they are emitted so admit you mean it.
But they're all in it at the same time.
OK so let's give them some randomness.
So full randomness and a half explosion he can look up what all these do in the documentation I will
link the documentation policy IMET.
Okay looking a bit better.
Assume it's 64 of them.
Now that's a victory.
Why do want though is the Stars I want to rotate randomly So the first thing we do go to flags and enable
rotate Y.
Now you notice they're still not rotating.
Why.
Because they don't have enough velocity so to do that lets go into angular velocity and going to speed
that by let's say 10.
There they go look at that.
That's much more like it.
Now they're too close to get on to spread out on a spread.
So that's a 180.
Looking a bit better.
And how about some radial bossy less really.
Let's really speed them up another 10 on radial Lossie.
There we go.
Much more explosive.
So you can tweak with these values or you like.
I think they look great.
For now I'm going to switch off emitting because we only wants to a certain types that say that it's
going to cube dude and I'm gonna make a new function called emit particles.
One of the do is I'm going to set particles not to admit I'm missing rather equals true.
They're only going to emit when they get this signal.
There's no brackets on True.
True is a boolean not a function.
They are only going to emit when they receive the signal.
So let's put the signal in.
So game that put this right here on gold attacked as you might expect.
So we're already calling can move to the players.
So let's call a second single assuan a duplicate can move and instead of can move less to emits particles.
Now we're not going to pass the argument fops.
Let's take a look at that.
Make sure of emitting the right thing.
That's good.
Now this isn't going to be perfect just yet because it was going to happen.
Turn the sound off.
You don't have to hear it.
Both players are emitting particles.
That's what I want.
So let's add an extra piece information and the actual piece of motion is goal wide.
So another pass at through is an argument then cube dude.
I would bring the argument and call it player and nounless say if player is the same as play idea.
So equals equals player eidy then emit particles.
You also notice that the particles didn't stop emitting or Istiklal why.
It's pretty simple.
I should put them as a one shot.
I forgot to do that.
Let's take a look at what time.
It's a player wants to score.
Look at that.
They're putting shells on everything.
Now you notice that they lasted too long.
So let's give them a two second timeline.
So that's the first step.
All right now let's do something with the lighting.
I'm going to go into lights which was a fold only you noticed we've only got the one light in.
And I put an animation node under direct and the directional light that's set there.
So animation tree player not animation tree player animation play this important animation play and
make a brand new animation called dim light.
And I think one second is fine.
The first thing to do is I'm gonna grab the key for the energy.
And at the end of one second the energy is going to be zero.
And that's put the key in there.
So let's play that.
OK.
So it's a one second faid that's looking pretty good.
So now I would put a script in directional light let's put a script in there.
And put the script in the script Holder do Derek Rose directional.
Excellent on ready.
I want to make sure that we set the light energy back to want because otherwise when we are going to
have to set it back here in the animation player every time we run the game and I will do that no one
worried about that.
Let us put it in sup white energy equals one because that's our default rate.
Its double check that yet thats default.
OK its on Red is going to do that.
Now I need a function that can be called as part of a group because of function.
Dim light.
And whats going to happen all of the do is play the animation layer.
I am actually thinking Im not going to call the function dim light.
I want to call the function goals scored because we have a second light.
Thats also going to react at the same time in a moment.
So lets put it in the same group call lets put directional light in a group and call this group by lighting.
And now back into games Judy.
And let's actually call that allert needs a mission player anymore.
And let's see.
Yet we're in the right place.
That's what our group calls in one place
and let's get Tre got call grip.
I can type.
OK.
Group is fighting.
And what do we call it we call it goals scored.
Yes it.
OK.
So whatever is in the function call scored in any node with this tag on it with this group name is going
to happen.
If there's anything in that group that doesn't have a goal to add function it's just going to ignore
it.
So that's perfect.
Let's see how that works
and the lights don't dim.
So let's actually lower the animation.
We need to tell it what animation we're playing.
We are playing dim light.
That should work better.
Let's move out the way and score a goal and the lights dim.
Awesome.
Now the lights don't do is come back up but this is way too dim So let's bring lights back up.
We need a new function called recept.
What's it going to do.
That's going to bring the light energy back to one.
Well we're already doing that here so let's just call the reset function.
Ready.
As looking a bit tidier right.
So now we want to make sure we call that reset for the lighting group.
So back at the game and were already resetting the pitch so we'll put it right here get tree call group.
What are we calling we're calling lighting.
And we're telling it reset.
All right.
Let's see how that works.
Get the lights and bring them back.
Awesome.
One more thing I want.
I want a spotlight.
This is a new type of nobody not seen these yet.
They work just like directional lights except they have additional things that look a spotlight.
There it is.
So here's our spotlight announced a high directional light that should hide its actual light source
as well.
So you see a spotlight has a couple of extra things.
It has a range which directional it doesn't.
And it has an angle.
As well as an advanced mom doing put it at zero let's say sex that a good height Zero is in the centre.
Six units up and I need to rotate it down.
I think that's minus 90 on the axis.
Perfect.
And let's tighten this beam a bit so under spot we've got some extra doohickeys right here my range.
I actually need this enough range to hit the corners so one would do is I'm gonna angle it up just to
take a look and try and get to the far corner.
How put into local mode.
Yeah.
You see that's not quite far enough idiots.
Let's make the range.
What is that furthest range is 10 11.
And what's our angle house 30 degree angle.
20 degree angle.
So and get and is not quite quite enough.
Mcginnis And an energy too.
I also want this to have shadows as a neighbor's shadow on it.
Now if it points at a player in a nice dramatic shudder.
There it is.
All right take off global mode and reset its rotation so this reset to mine is 90 0 0.
It's going to points straight down at the ball.
It looks good.
So that's unhide the directional light for now.
Now put the spotlight in the same lighting group so let's add that's lighting.
And I'm going to give it a script.
So spotlight in these script sold a spotlight Judy fantastic and on ready.
I'm going to hide I go.
So I'm going to leave visible for now in the mainstream but I never hide it.
The moment the game starts that's going to help me remember that it's there.
Mike there is a spotlight.
And now it needs to do something.
One of do is make function goals scored because we're already calling that.
I wanted to show on goals scored so let's just do that show.
However I wanted to point at the player that scored the goal which is the challenge.
I'd like you to use look at to aim the spotlight at the player that just scored.
So look at is your hint right if you use.
Look at that the light will just stay where it is an angle itself.
Don't forget you're going to need a vector 3 to tell it which direction up is so poor the video you'll
look at.
In the spotlight at the player that's just scored when you're happy with the results.
Come back and I'll show you my solution.
And Mac Mac.
Its all going to use.
Look at rates so look at.
And look at takes hoops and underscores what it takes.
Takes two things the first thing is what am I looking at.
And the second is which direction is up.
What am I looking at.
Okay so I need to get the two players.
Let's do that now.
So La player 1.
So what's player want.
Let's find out let's do get Tre dot get root find no good player one.
And duplicate that change all the player wants to play it too.
OK.
So with foul play I want to play it too now.
I need some way with this function of figuring out who scored to do that and how to go to game Judy.
And when we call goals scored I need to put in gold.
Now if I was smart what I would have done is put players and lighting all in one group called them something
like victory or something like that and then put goals scored for both of them because were passing
the same information through a pass the goal idea.
It's important that any function that's being called here now has an argument.
Even if he doesn't use it so it's going to directional right now and put goal Heidi we're not using
it but we have to have that argument in.
Otherwise it's going to pass through with an argument that the function isn't expecting and God will
crash well crash just for up.
All right.
So now we have a player in here.
So let's put if condition in if player is one he calls he calls one.
What do we need to do.
We'll do the thing let's just get the rest this conditioning else pass.
I think I need one more variable and the call is variable target targets he calls play out dot translation
right where he's on the x y and z.
That's good.
Duplicate that and put it over here.
Now play to time translation.
And now I look at it's very easy.
I'm going to look at the target and then even up vector is a vector 3 and that's 0 1 0 right.
That's up just before we go any further.
This isn't gonna work because I've forgotten that there's extra booleans in here so let's go.
My big is recursive.
Yes it is.
Do I own it.
No I don't.
I forget that every time.
So if you're using a fine note it's not going to tell you what the error is as your say I haven't found
anything.
Let's see how that works.
Look at that dramatic spotlight.
Everything.
Now the spotlight isn't hiding.
I need a reset function here.
And that's just going to be hide and that should work fine.
Now I'm going to refactor really quickly so play a one.
I don't want to add you to the lighting note let's just rename that lighting group so lighting is going
to go away and I call this celebrants things that celebrate has a weird name.
If he can come up with a better name by all means do so.
So I'm gonna add that group spotlight.
I'm going a from finalizing group and add you to the celebrant group and all players will be added to
their group to keep Dude you are still a player.
Pick a celebrants.
Don't move so you're not going to have your position reset but you're salaried.
Okay now I need to go to the game g script and actually redo those calls.
So Ganji And look they're all using resets so I could actually just put celebrant and remove that.
Do I spell that group right.
Let's find out.
Yes I did emit particles can be renamed and then I can just get rid of that one completely but celebrant
and put goals scored and back to Cube did.
I'm going to rename it particles to goals scored because we pass this information through it right.
In fact if I have a goal scored let's move can move back in us and we get rid of that completely and
on the cube do.
Goals scored can move.
True False rather cultive.
It is going through looking for any other versions of that great.
So now it looks to me go through all the scripts very quickly.
It now looks to me that we don't need a play rebuttal so let's get back to our player and remove him
from the playgroup.
And I think this should work fine.
It does fantastic.
Before we finish one more thing I want to show you what if you want to add a controller to this sort
of project settings and to input map and let's say I want play or want to to work on my control.
So one to do is take up one.
I might add a new mapping to the one that one exists.
I've got various options here and I really care about Joy button and joy access and move the player
on the axis so on a join access device Zero is the four is searched just like an array.
Right so counting from 0 at device Zero is the first joypad or joystiq and then we have these different
axes.
Axis 0 is left stay left and right axis one is left stick up and down axis 2 is right stick left and
right.
Pretty easy right.
So I could just add less stick left for that.
I'm not going to because it's silly.
It's up so let's do that again.
Joy access and not left stick up great and there and joy access and that's left stick right there it
is.
Put these in a strange order have an eye down Joy axis love stick down.
Same thing for left that's the wrong one.
There is left one joy access left stick left.
And if you wanted it to do the same thing but now is of device zero It's device 1.
Ok if I want to use any buttons for anything with a kick or something like that.
Very simply I would go to droit button and then just pick the button I want on the correct device including
the deep end.
Let's just check that works so I'll play my game so my joypad is plugged in.
Let's see how that works play.
And I can move on joypad and it's pretty simple now all we haven't done is put a analogue in but we
dont have any analogue with it anyway right now.
That's a different kind of get a little tricky to move right now.
It's kind of fun.
So if you really wanted to we could do it you can put both players on one joypad and have them wrestling
for it.
I'm not going to do that because I can foresee very violent.
I've actually hit you on the head with your prepared.
But if you wanted to do.
And that brings us to the end of Cube kick about nail polish you could do you can add more sound effects
you could add different models football background then you could change the camera.
But Im going to call this project done.
Which brings us to the end of the video.
In this video with added the final awesomeness so much awesome in this game I think its ready to go.
Weve also introduced 3D particle notes and spotlight nodes and looks at how to aim like notes especially
spotlight notes using a look at.
So dont forget to share your cube did kick about.
What if you added to it what have you done differently.
Have you got a completely different aesthetic.
Are you doing this with two cats.
I'd love to see the game youve made.
Meanwhile excellent work and see in the next video.