Welcome back to life for God.
People in this video are going to limit ammo.
We're going to refill the food fuel by controlling how much ammunition a player is allowed to carry
and tracking how much they are actually carrying as well as loing ammunition when they fire it.
Let's talk about the kinds of limits we want to put on food.
I'm thinking the following one you have a limited amount of food you can only carry X amount whatever
X is we can change with an export variable.
But I'm thinking 5 is a good start.
Number two picking up food should take time you don't just run over something and instantly have more
food.
You have to stay in an area that's home a picking up food risky which adds a risk reward element which
I think will make a more interesting gameplay experience.
Finally robot SPCS won't be limited to the amount of food they can carry just like in real life robots
to be able to throw as much food at you as they like.
Let's start by taking a look at our level and deciding what we want.
I'm thinking a nice area right in the centre downstage Centre right here.
Nice and risky so not too much cover but the potential of cover the is going to be able to move out
the way at times can always move it.
I'm gonna start making a new scene and my route is going to be an area hoodie.
Why.
Because I want to track when something is inside it.
Using collision but I don't want to stop things from entering it so areas are a good way of doing that
and I'm going to give this a mash instance so I can see where this area is.
A simple cube mesh.
Let's scale that down.
So let's say zero point five all three axes.
And let's actually make it look like something we could pick up so I don't want to be in here.
I don't mean material they can use spatial material and I'm thinking a nice transparent onesimus Flags
and switch on transparent and go down to our bideau.
And I think a nice red colour looks good.
Ours put the alfer on so let's put Alpher at about 100 ish
looking a little dark you know what.
I might even switch on a mission less emit are out here.
Yeah that's looking pretty good.
Okay now we also need collision or the area won't work at all.
So let's put in a collision.
Collision shapes.
It is not a new box shape.
And again I want this to be scaled down so when I go into what shape extensor zero point five want all
three axes.
Now I could use the layers here but you know what I'm actually going to use.
If body has Matha trick we used recently.
So let's rename this mythical it refill area with a save that in scenes or mean scenes as handy.
Now I need to put a script in this because I need to connect signals to it so I won't create this the
script inside scripts like so.
And now I have an empty think.
Now I'm going to connect notes.
I will use body entered body exited.
I connect them to itself and I'll explain why in a bit so that one and that one.
Great.
Now I'm going to.
Instance in this area.
So that's just insys it in like so refill area.
Couldn't live like that.
It's a pretty good place on the ground.
You are not on the ground.
Get back on the ground.
Awesome.
Okay that looking pretty good.
So why am I connecting it to itself and not the player.
Well right now we have a player as part of the scene.
But later on were going to put player customization in and what that's going to do is allow the player
to pick between two different Peacey models.
Then were going to all load that p.c model as well as whatever texture the players picked in to this
level which means we can't connect it directly through the inspector would have to connect it through
a script and I can connect through script.
But I'd rather do it by using a simpler method.
So let's just do this.
If body DOT has no method how much we call this rieffel area entered.
And just to be very clear I'm using this capitalisation because that's how he's used nodes and then
underscore entered because that's how he would catalysing scripts.
So if what he has method rieffel area entered then I want to run that method.
What a dot refill area and test would do the exact same thing with a refill area exit so if body part
has method
refeel area exited option a copy that because it was quite hard to write then body refill area exited.
But not with a start.
And this script is basically good to go on.
Get rid of the actual lines that I need and save that most of the rest of work is going to be done in
play.
And before I go any further I've got a whole bunch of scripts I'm not using anymore so I'm going to
close most of these menus control and W on Windows so one that one that one that one that one that wants
that light on lots of things I dont need.
I just want play and refl area for now.
Let's figure out what variables we need and we go right up to the top of player and will put in some
new variables in a new groups.
I'm going to make it a little gap here where I put it here and this is going to be ammo variables and
let's keep this can sense there where I first think it is an export variable called Max ammo.
I must start this office 5 second thing I need to track is how much ammo we actually carrying and I
start at zero.
So the player will not be able to fire ammunition at the beginning.
Right so you will have to pick some up.
Now it's possible that we're going to have to add some more of these boxes around the place.
Maybe just putting it here is simply too dangerous or not fun.
That's okay we can tweak that pretty easily once we're done we can just duplicate this as many times
we like.
One more thing I want to track.
Are we actually able to pick up ammunition right now for that to be true we need to be inside the box
and not at Max m0 but I can track that very simply with can refill as a billion which is starting off
as false code for you to find to this open the player seen so let's open the player saying there you
are.
And I'm going to add a new time in here.
Why am I doing this because we've decided that picking up ammunition should take time so I need to track
that track that by putting a new timer and I'm on call this rethel timer and and let's leave it as a
second for now and it is a one shot kill file once and then have to fire again.
This is going to have to be connected as a signal so let's do a time out connection to itself.
And there it is all the way down the bottom because I wanted to put a bunch of extra lines in now in
a moment and put some logic in here I'll check.
Do I need to restart the first thing that's going to happen at time a time out.
Is ammo.
Plus he calls one.
You know what I should probably put some sort of Gooly it shouldn't.
So let's do that really quickly get to a level one and this is just to be a place holography.
So I mean a make a canvas item capital letter rather a rename to g y.
And it's going to have a sub node that's a label.
And this label I could call it label.
Now I can always change it later it'll live in the top right which is over there.
And let's give it a theme.
Someone load the theman which is in scenes why do I put this in scenes.
I might use it for now and let's just write zero so I could see what it's doing.
I think that needs a margin doesn't it.
Margin the top from 10 Yeah it's looking pretty good.
Save that and let's just see how that zero looks in-game.
Yep there it is.
Awesome.
All right.
Back to scripts.
I'm going back into the play a script in you function and I call this Czech AMA and all this is going
to is say is the ammo less than the max hammer.
I'm doing this because I'm going to be using that quite a lot.
I may need that when I'm picking up ammunition.
I'm saying Can I still pick up ammunition.
He uses a couple times so let's just put that in.
And now I can make a new function and I make this refill area and anted which I may actually have spelled
correctly which is very unusual for me.
Let's double check that.
Wow.
I think I did.
Did I.
Sorry.
I'm very excited about this.
I wasn't expecting it.
No I didn't I miss an L.
I was so close.
I will never move on if check Amazon and I was going to do is run this function here and then return
true if it's true.
So if check ammo then I want to refill time as a start so refill timer got start.
And we also need to say can refill.
Too true.
So what's going to happen.
We'll walk into the area.
It's going to say do you have less than macsyma.
You can't refill IMO if you're at macsyma.
If so start the refill timer and set calorie felt a treat the refill timer will increase the amount.
Now only on time outs after a second of being in there that'll go up one more thing I need to do is
make a whole bunch of spaced and his seal I'm looking at is get rid of that plus have randomly put in
make a new function function refill area existed.
Why am I doing this because I need to stop the time.
So timer rethel timer I think is doing this because I'm not in the right scene isn't it.
Yes it is.
Okay that's fine.
Full time adot Stop.
And can refill he calls phos.
Now that's going to work fine but I'm not going to have to see how much I've got.
Right so right now I've got this gooey label go up here.
I'm not changing this at any point so let's change that in a script.
Let's say Update go is our next function.
Now this is good.
Update The Gooly but the googie is down here in a tree.
The place is here so find do dollar guily even spell it right.
That's going to apply.
This is a sub node of the player.
It's not a subset of the place of some sort of low level one.
Kevin I could do.
I could call a group called gooey or I could use get a..
I will be using a group later but I haven't made this scene yet.
When we design the gooey I make a prop go sing.
So for now I'm going to get a..
And I'm going to drag this in.
What I will do is make a note in here.
Move to group call when you make a ghillie.
And actually what the label don't I got to go is so slash label
dot text he calls Amr except text once a string an M.O. is an integer something that casts this.
Oh I've got insight on this.
I mean to cast this as a string.
So now Pressplay.
Like a stand in here the time or start and the ammo is going up.
So what I want do is really go into the placing and I add a new audio stream player.
I'm not adding a 3D X I don't want to be positional sound.
Make a nice and quiet.
They're going to call this harp and if going to sound effects.
Harp glissando up sounds like this
perfect.
That's a reload sound I've ever heard when I get back into the script and I'm going to play that so
harp don't play.
And when we exit the area I'm going to go harp dot stop again to see how that works.
Now will also put an animation here so you could tell him in the area but that's like pretty good isn't
it.
No I have no doubts that the number isn't actually going on.
What's happening is the time that's happening.
Once I want to keep going.
So I'm going to increase them by one update the gooey and then check if we want to go again.
So if check ammo and then we'll start this time all over again.
And this timer is just called rethel timer.
I don't need to do an else stop because this is not auto starting right.
It's on a one shot timer.
This you have that looks.
I'm going to run into you here.
Lots of ammunition.
Can I get beyond five.
I cannot however look I can keep firing the ammos not going down.
So that brings me to the challenge.
I'd like you to lower the AMA have the ammo count drop by 1 whenever the player fires and make sure
the player can't fire when they have no ammo.
Right.
Because otherwise that's cheating.
Supposedly you give that a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
Okay this is not as complicated as it might look.
So what I want to do is I'm go to try to fire.
So if can fire.
Now that's just telling me have you fired recently.
Right.
A fire at the moment once every second.
But I also can only fire it if we have enough gunfire and ammo is greater than zero.
So if I have zero ammunition this won't happen next.
I want to actually load the ammunition my legal one and update the jury now.
I can't fire pick up a little clinician.
And fire three to one no more firing.
Again I think we are a bit more variety when we could pick these up.
I'm going to put in a couple more of those three areas.
The court refill areas.
So let's duplicate you move one over here and one over here that looks good.
Let's see how that works out.
Now this guy he is still very simplistic but look already this is starting to feel more going still
some more polish to go.
But I'm pretty happy with that.
You guys need to get out that door.
That brings us the video in this video with limited player ammo.
We've put in a brand new scene.
Just a refill area.
Put in a sound effect and a bunch of variables and some very simple logic to make sure that players
can pick up ammunition in certain circumstances and fire in other circumstances.
And we can keep track of how much ammo the player has.
Excellent work.
And I will see you in the next four years.