Welcome back wonderful God people in this video.
Nice and short.
We're just going to get everything ready to start coding.
We're going to download the assets for our platform games.
So what needs to happen.
Well the very first thing is you need to download hobby days assets zip to your computer.
If you look over to the resources for this lecture you'll see there's a whole bunch of things including
hobby days asset starts up.
So the first thing you should do before you go any further down lowder's it file and put it somewhere
you can find it.
I'm going to put mine on the desktop.
You don't have to just put it somewhere nice and easy to find.
Right.
So it's on your desktop or wherever it is here's mine right here.
The best thing to do is open godso an to make myself a new project.
And we're going to call this hobby days.
I'm actually calling to underscore hobby days because that's the second project where you don't have
to you can call it whatever you like.
It's quick.
The folder just like before.
And we are good to go.
At least we will be.
When God is ready.
So right now we have an empty god project so let's get these assets in.
The easiest thing to do is going to be to right click over here and the file system as show in file
manager and then I can minimize God.
And I don't need the terminal window either.
Great.
And I want to open hollidays.
And as you can see we've got a bunch of folders and here I grab them all.
And drag them over copy to hollidays.
Awesome.
So when we are back into god.
Ill import everything for us.
And he is a lovely filesystem.
Before we go any further there is one folder that isn't in here that I would like to have.
Now the reason I didn't include it isn't just I wanted to see if you could right click on stuff.
It's because winds it didn't want me to put in an empty folder.
So let's make the folder for us now going to right click on it to new folder and the folders then called
scripts.
So do we have.
Well we've got the ground work here not just for the assets but for our file structure.
We will make every asset easy to find.
So our fonts are really our one font is in the phone's folder and the G effects you'll find all the
graphics whether it's player sprite's.
And as you can see which you have two variations you can have the pink bunny which I'll be using or
the Brown Bunny.
We also have particles.
The heads up display elements various items and so on.
And the sound effects you find the sound of music and the scenes this is we're going to put all our
scenes and levels and scripts.
We just made our scripts so what's included.
What I've done is I've taken a cut down version of the jumper pack by Kenny.
Now we'll link all these resources so you can find them yourself and use slightly different resources
if you want or just see what they've got available just like Looney lips.
I'm using Kennie's because one I like his artwork and two he's on the creative commons zero licence
which means we can use this for commercial educational and personal products and we don't even need
to attribute it.
We don't need to pay him anything.
Attributing a tribute to him is one of those.
Whatever it is we don't need to cite who did we should.
It's kind We only to the sound effects are also from Kenny.
Now I couldn't pick the music so I've got a selection of two or so and see cesário Licences for chips
used adventure by subspace audio or some a pack by Scribe.
And these are all from open game art.
In fact I found Kenny on open game up to finally the font is candles from default and you can find all
of these.
As I said Linked In the resources for this video by the way you don't have to use any of these resources
I encourage you to customize this game to your heart's content if you want to do a complete different
theme.
Make your own graphics go hunting for deep scary sci fi or Lovecraft because in style go crazy I'd love
to see Peg in fact if we do pick different assets please share them on the forums and on the discord
because I think people will be refacing to see me come up with and that's everything.
So this video was now done.
I'll see the next video where we can start actually using our fancy new assets.