Hello again you wonderful people.
Let's get the assets and get our game started.
Really quick what assets are using using top down shooter space new sounds by Kenny.
This is a filtered down packs.
I've removed a bunch of assets were not using I've left you some options.
You can still choose different things.
But I don't want to like put a whole bunch of stuff you know that we weren't necessarily using.
If you want to make a slightly different game we want to explore.
I found his stuff an open game art.
I've left you the links for the packs I'm using in this letter three resources so feel free to explore
more so using a piece of music by someone called lisboa.
Also an open game.
Open game art called stealth music because it really fits.
And it's also on a Creative Commons you're a licence so we can use it without problems.
Okay let's get this project started.
First thing we do is you'll see I've already downloaded the assets that are right here and I'm an open
godda.
He has.
And only to make a new project and I'm going to call this heist Meister's And just for consistency.
I'm going to put three underscore heiss mice's like that and that's the correct folded document repo
create folder creaton added.
So here we are.
We're in a nice empty project with nothing in it yet when 3D space and all I need to do is get the assets
in here.
My challenge to you is to get your assets into the projects and download them from the link and the
resources you're looking for the heiss masters assets step down of the assets unzipped the folder and
install them in your heiss my AS project portfolio.
Give that a shot and then when you come back I'll show you how to do it just in case you got stockel
confused.
You know just forgot how to do it.
And welcome back.
So installing these assets is nice and easy.
I'm going right click here to show and farm manager and that's just going to bring up the reaper So
I don't have to go finding it again.
Nice is simple.
What do I need to do.
I need to get the assets into this false sense minimize.
Got it for now.
Could even close it to be honest.
It's close.
Gotta just open the file and all I'm a do is drag or cut and paste have you do it.
Or 3 folders directly into the heiss my SAS folder.
And now when I open got go again where I got to.
There you are one.
I close it.
What was I thinking.
Now I open god again.
Everything gets imported for me.
Now we will be making some more folders and we dont have a scene's folder a script folder but just a
quick overview of what we have.
In effect we have a bunch of graphics things were going to be using Sprite sheets and tile sheets the
tushie is interesting.
All of the assets are top now shoot other people are in here.
Those are going to come in very useful when we look at auto tiling and videos underpin G.
You'll also notice that there's a few different people you can use and the individual tiles which were
also going to be using for props so are the hit man you'll see that the player character man red has
a few options in here.
There's a couple of other items he can look at while we're here.
But if you look at the sound effects here all the sound effects and background music finally under light
maps there's a torch map something I made very quickly in Photoshop so that the torch of the flashlight
for the guards and security cameras can actually show on screen and cast light.
It's very simple to make.
All I did was they make a little triangle in in GIMP and then I just did a gradient fill from white
to black white is where there's light black as there isn't very easy so you need to make your own.
That's how you do that.
And that's a set up.
So in this video we've created the project downloaded the assets installed them and had a quick peek
at them were now ready to start programming.
Great work and I'll see you in the next video.