Hi folks welcome back.
OK.
Let's get started.
Making lowney Lips in this video.
We're going to focus on the concept of a raise.
Now the reason we talk about a raise is we want to make our games scalable and we want to be able to
take all of our plug-in words all of our prompts into something called an array and use wild cards in
our story text and then merge the two together.
This will all become clear.
So let's get to it.
First thing we need to do is open god.
So here it is on my desktop.
And he is God.
I got a spanking new project I'm going to put this in my reposeful because we like to put stuff repo's
there and I'm gonna make a project and it's going to be called lunar eclipse.
Create that fall.
And we have got to go so far so familiar we're going to work in 2D.
And let's make a note to decode.
Remember we need a script but a script has to exist on a node it can't exist by itself.
So here's our no too deep.
Let's rename this the convention when you're naming nodes in godot is to capitalize the first letter
of each word and to get rid of spaces so it will let me go Luni spaced level but I'm not going to go
loony lips just like that.
It will let you put something else.
This is a convention so I can look at this in the script and know exactly what I'm talking about.
This is a not great so is my renamed node.
And let's make a script so script and I'm going use the no comments template.
It's exactly like the other one except it doesn't generate all those comments we saw in the Heller world
script.
So what do we need to do.
Well we need to have a story and we need to add in some variables and we need to print it out.
So first let's add our story here's our variable and it's called Story and it's going to go like this
once upon loops a pone a time a person and put it in caps.
So I myself office isn't important.
It's a thing and felt very feeling great.
So here is a nice string variable.
I've seen this before and we've looked at something in a world where we can add in more variables and
it can become a variable person a variable called not a car.
A variable called thing and a variable called feeling.
Now if you use other programming languages you might be wondering why didn't you say this is a string
variable.
I don't need to.
In God I remember I can just make a blank variable and then when I tell it it's a string it'll just
change it to a string and then when I want it to be an integer it'll be an integer and when I want to
be a float it'll be a float.
God can change its type whenever we need it to is a dynamic language so we know how to do this right.
Far I could go on spelling my own name right because that's professional a thing would be a pizza and
a feeling would be full and now I want pizza.
So if you want extra credit feel free to get me a pizza.
There is no extra credit.
Maybe I should take this the wrong place.
There we go.
Forgive Peter not the code important lesson.
Don't think of Peter when you're coding.
So we've looked at a way we could do this right.
I could just get rid of that and concatenate in the variable person spelling it correctly
and do that.
And if I fast forward as I magically add here and press the Expand thing you can see that and then we
could just do this again.
Print.
Story I will of course have to declare these variables before I declare the story and why this won't
work on and highlight them all hold out and press the up arrow and it'll just move everything and it's
lovely.
Now I run this.
Do you want to set 34 scene.
Yes I do.
And there it is.
Once upon a time a yarn 8 a pizza and felt very full.
So this will work but it's not what I would call elegant elegance and code is kind of a slippery concept
but it's important.
We need our code to be able to run efficiently quickly and simply our code needs to be readable.
Don't spend 7 lines of code when you can spend one.
So right here I've declared three variables to put into a different variable to print.
Okay this all works assuming that every story we do has a person a thing and a feeling this will work
fine but what happens if I create a story where we might have 7 variables write three people two things
and two feelings.
Maybe we don't have any feelings maybe we don't have any people.
We need something a lot more expandable a lot more versatile that's the word I'm struggling for.
So instead of using variables I'm going to use a single array and I'm going to call it prompts.
The array is the square brackets.
Now let's take a moment and discuss what an array is.
OK.
Cast your mind back dear lovely people to Ben's idea that a variable is a box right.
And it can be any type of variable we like.
Let's call this one person.
God doesn't mind if it's a string or anything else.
Well he cares about is this is a variable a box called person.
And we can put the contents in and change the contents whenever we need to.
But what happens when I need a whole bunch of these things in one place.
Well then I need an array.
So this is a variable.
This is an array instead of a box we have.
A shelf.
And on that shelf we can put as many boxes as we need.
Now because God is a dynamic language these boxes can all be different types this will be a variable.
This one could be a boolean.
That's a true false statement.
This one could be a float.
That's a number with a decimal point.
And we can add and subtract as many as we need to.
If you're used to static languages you'll probably have the concept that a an array actually generates
with a fixed size.
And even if you don't use all the spaces it still has that size.
That's not true here and Didi's script the array is the size we need it to be and it'll constantly resize
a couple of things you should be aware of for the raise.
If I tell God go go find the box and position one.
It's tempting to think that position one is this one right.
One two three because that's how humans count.
But actually that's not what's happening so here is God.
And God.
If I say position one is going to get this boolean variable and the reason for that is I'm not actually
say go to position one.
I'm saying move this many spaces along.
In fact this is position 0.
That's position 1 that's position too.
This is one of the most common mistakes people make with an array right.
I think I need the third one along with the third one along is not number 3 0 1 2.
The third one long would be here right.
So just be aware of what is often called an off by one error.
So that's an array It's a shelf full of variables.
A bookshelf a list if you prefer.
So how can we make one work.
All I need to do is put my values in the array so I'll need a string.
A person is going to be an I'll spell my own name right because I'm a professional Yeah.
Okay so we now have an array with one value.
It could just be a variable.
But wait there's more.
If I put a comma I can put something else in a thing Peter.
And a feeling form.
And I can keep adding to these and remember I can mix different types so if I need an array to have
strings in it and integers in it and floats in it and booleans in it that is absolutely nil out.
This is expandable.
I just had to add a comment a new value.
And yes there are script commands We'll look at later where we can add things.
Remove things.
Look at things in order.
Whatever we need to is a really useful thing to have an array is great.
Let's have lots of arrays.
So obviously now we have a problem because I'm calling variables that don't exist and God is going to
hate that.
So how can I put these prompts in here.
Don't I need to tell it.
This is this.
This has this name this has this name.
I doubt there's one more concept that's going to make this really awesome God O has format strings strings
that can be used as a template and you can make them slightly differently.
All I need to do is use an escape character.
Operator I'm going to use.
Percent.
S.
What does this mean.
Percent.
S means.
Got 0 pay attention and the s means put in a string.
I will put up a link from the documentation of all of these characters.
All I need to do is go in and change these.
All for let's copy this.
I'm going to do is copy this.
Born here.
And let's get rid of this variable I almost forgot that one.
Okay.
Now remember I told you that God and most programming languages if you use a string it won't try and
make sense of the string.
It won't pass the string right.
It's just going to repeat it back to you.
And less you draw its attention to it so that's what I'm doing here.
So how do we get it to actually put it in.
Well here's the easy bit.
Ready percent percent.
And then what's the percent prompt.
What I'm telling it is TELL THE STORY and add in the prompts.
Is it as easy as that.
Well let's find out.
Once upon a time a yarn a pizza and felt very full.
Now this is really good right.
I don't need to be putting in a whole bunch of concatenations I don't need a whole bunch of variables
in three lines of code.
I'm doing what we were doing in 7 or 8 and it's really expandable.
And to show how expandable it is I'd like to introduce you to this video challenge.
I'd like you to make a bigger story make a story with four or more of these wildcards these escape characters
these operations in it.
Right.
Go for five.
Go for six whatever you need to do.
Make a bigger story using this array and just display in the print function.
Pause the video give that a shot.
And when you come back I'll show you mine.
So I'm just going to copy that because I keep missing on a keyboard.
There it is.
It was a day for all.
It doesn't matter what my story is.
It's just going to work.
Now if I run this I'll get an error.
Not enough arguments.
I'm asking you to put in a bunch of things and I don't have enough things right.
It's saying I have one two three four five of these strings to pull in.
I've only supplied three strings so I just now have to put in two more right sad
cabbages.
Now I can keep adding stuff in here and it doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter if I have too many.
It matches what I have too.
Too few.
So it's double check that works out a distraction free mode press play.
And there it is.
Once upon a time a yanet a pizza and felt very full.
It was a sad day for all good cabbages.
Brilliant really good foundation for our game.
This is going to make it really expandable and look like the advantage here.
I don't need to tell it.
Look for a noun.
I just need to say you have an array.
Just give me the next thing in that array and it's automatically moving forward.
Which brings us to the end of this video.
We've looked at a raise which are key foundational concept here and if you can get your head around
them they're really helpful.
We've looked at the beginning escape characters format strings we started building scalability into
our game.
Really great stuff.
OK folks I'll see you in the next video.