Hello again you marvelous to people.
Let's continue our work on come on computers and combinations.
We're going to have the combination on the computer and while the combination to the locked door.
That's all connected and ready to go.
What do our computers need to do.
Well first thing is they're going to need a combination.
They can have to request a combination from the combination generator.
That combination needs to be on screen when the player uses the computer.
But we also need the combination transmitted to the locked doors that locked doors are going to get
that combination from the computer the computer's going to get the combination from the combination
generator.
OK.
Let's get right into it.
So back into it and let's open the computer scene so into my computer scene I go and we can open script
for you I think that's a good place to go.
OK.
So here's our script so far.
One thing I do want to do.
Actually before I get a script you get back into 2D didn't need to do that.
Just make a little light.
Where the collision ship here when the play is using the computer let's put a little light in I think
it'll be fun.
So I don't make a brand new light notes I go into the top eight and a. and a light 2D like 2D.
Wants a texture.
So let's go down into our graphics and into our tile sheet not tile sheet sorry into our Pinky and then
the tiles.
That's what I meant to say if we score all the way down.
We've got this nice little fluorescent effect here it's how five nights I want to put that in it's a
little hard to see against the black background but if I switch this on you can see here I want to rotate
this by 90 degrees on rotation degrees.
It's going to rotate it and I want to shuffle it over.
Now I know this is 64 by 64 so our position on the x axis is going to be 32.
So there is all light.
Okay.
And it's actually pretty good to go.
One thing I do want to do those switch on and off.
So let's start with it disabled.
And let's go into the script and what I want to do is put it on here.
So when we click on it rather than print click let's switch the lights on so that light 2D dot enabled
and I can tell that by clicking on it and looking at the mouse over it tells me the properties called
enabled and that's going to be true
okay.
And when we exit the body we can disable that light.
So let's do that light to the DOT enabled equals false.
Now in the vast majority of times we're not going to spot this because the screen will be in the way
but on the occasions when we're off the side of the screen this will look good.
And I'm going to need to generate the combination.
This will be done already.
So first let's make a ready function so function ready loop.
Let's just give us a little more space here and go right past to get errors and go into full screen
mode.
OK.
So on ready I did a few things first.
I need to make sure that I'm generating the combination to generate a combination which is a brand new
function does exists something like copy that and let's go and put it right here.
Function generate combination column pass this function here that's going to generate combination which
you probably store that says have a variable called combination and now we can generate the combinations
do that only a combination equals combination generator don't and then there's a function in here right.
Generate combination.
Now generate combination.
If I look at this requires a an argument it's already giving the error and if I open up the combination
generator which is right here it is the length how many digits do I need.
So for now I'm for a length of four.
But I want that to be customizable when we're making the level to do that when we can export variables
that make export variable combination length
equals four.
And now I could change this for for combination length and all that's going to do is X expose this to
the inspector.
So by default this before and when I click on the computer here you can see combination length which
means if I save this and go into the level clicking on the computer which is right here will allow me
to change the combination length not bad.
So let's get back into that and open that script again back into distraction free mode.
OK.
That's looking pretty good.
Now I'm gonna need to use this to change the texture computer right now the key pieces test.
That's no good.
So let's go to the computer pop up.
I'm going to open that scene.
So let's put in a brand new script on computer pop up it's a brand new script boop and I need a function
called set text with combination
OK.
So to do this I want to change the text on the label so I'm going to get the label which is right here.
Dot text equals.
So it's got open brackets.
That's going to full screen loser over brackets and only go down a line and there's two tabs so that
I can see it's all part of the same line and let's say Will you stop forgetting your access code.
I've set it to a little space there.
And now we need to add the combinations.
Plus I only use cool string array which we saw we made the number pad and I need the combination and
all to join all those numbers into string with DOT join and I only use a blank string says no gap between
them plus let's get down line again.
But this is the very last time okay.
So what's gonna happen is when it receives this fuck this calls for the function.
So when it receives the instruction set the text with this combination it will change the word test
on the monitor too will you stop forgetting your access code.
I have set it to blah blah blah blah.
Depending on the length of the combination.
But this is the very last time this number can be any length from one to very large.
So it doesn't have to be four digits.
You can have varying sizes so that it's going to come in really handy.
Okay.
Let's go back to the computer scene so let's save that.
Save that and put this back onto invisible mode back computer see just check that everything's looking
good.
No it's still visible that way.
Good.
OK.
So script for you.
La la la la la.
Sort of hopping around a lot today.
And now I want to set to that pop up text so under generate combination to make a new function called
to set pop up text
OK it's now complaining we don't have a function called set pop up text so it should make that and we
need the computer pop up so it's from the computer pop up computer pop up LA that dot sets text there
it is and then we just need to put into the combination.
All right.
So if I've done everything correct which I hope I have when I press space here the new combination is
it's going to big mode.
The new combination will be here.
But look we're going off screen.
Let's fix that real quick.
I didn't mean to do that so we'll go back into computer pop up.
Let's open the label.
The properties and switch auto wrap on one more time over here.
Will you stop forgetting your access code.
I've set 2 2 9 8 2 6 but this is the very last time.
Now if you wanted to as a little extra challenge you could do this with a rich text labels and on top
of notes so I could just add in a rich text label which works exactly like a normal label except you
can enable VB code so I can get to be the code enable it and write it here.
Not only do that in this video but if you wanted to you could do that look up Bebe code stuff to change
colors make things balance on.
I'm happy with that as it is and I don't need this rich text labels.
Get rid of that save and I'm back in the computer script.
OK.
We have a computer script now and I want to do is connect the computer to the correct door.
So let's go here.
I want to make a brand new signal I want make a signal that doesn't exist so let's create a signal in
code and to do that we use this signal keyword right combination.
That's now a signal that this node can do to show that you're out of here and into my level and go to
nodes and you can see we can now connect this to another objects I want to connect this and I finally
locked door.
So has my locked door and locked door as a script now has on complete function on computer combination.
Now matching up past two pieces information through here I'm going to pass the combination I'm equipped
lock groups so lock group why am I adding that.
Well would probably have more than one locked door and more than one computer.
Not every door is gonna have the same combination.
I need the player to know which computer is talking about which door.
So I'm going to add that as a new piece information.
Let's say that and go into our computer scripts are practically descriptive.
Okay.
So once we've generated the combination when you get into emits the signal says emit the signal combination
and send the combination through and something called Lock group which doesn't yet exist but lock group
in there and you're going to make it as a brand new export variable export block group.
And that is going to be simply this is unset for now is a string say that go back and see the level
Ed and I could see this lock group here and that's got let me know what group I'm playing with.
Right so I can see that this is part of group 1 for example that's part of group 1 2 let's just call
this from moment 1 Remember I'm changing this in the inspector the default value on the script is still
unset.
So when I bring in a new locked door it'll use these default values.
Okay.
Let's go back into a locked door and actually make this work.
I've now realized accommodation is confusing some input numbers you'll receive some numbers you want
to do something with them let's go back and to this pass and you written that and I want to change the
number pad combinations I want to use num pad and we have a property in there a variable called combination
call that numbers.
So let's give that a quick go press play
the exit code is 3 4 7 8 so see if that works
mock and lie.
That felt pretty good.
Now if I restart this
I should get a completely different nomination.
5 6 5 7 5 6 5 7.
Excellent.
Okay now one more thing on day before we finish this video I will show the player what block group things
are part of.
So when I go to the computer as to the mode I'm going to add a quick label here.
So I'm going to get to the root itself.
So add which is control a type and label and this needs to be the same thing doesn't it.
So let's load the theme in theme is right here.
We're going to go load theme and our theme is under you I believe which is interface as my theme.
And let's just write the word test right now so we can see it and I'm just gonna move that 2 up.
He right here is great so I mean let's analyze the right.
Mean it's a rect to make sure it's in the right place.
Let's put you on the same level on the Y minus 100 on the x.
That looks pretty good.
Okay.
So I want to add the same thing to the locked doors.
As for save me guess the main scene and just find a locked door and open the scene that Adelaide will
hit.
So let's go control.
I am contacting the label again la la la.
There's my label and a material test and I need to add this to the theme so it's go to this lost six
flags theme load interface theme.
There it is and I'm gonna write tests as all good and let's just move you to the same place so make
sure it moves letters not drag it to over here get wrecked.
It's minus one hundreds groups minus one hundred zero.
You know what that needs to be a little farther left.
I mean 1 120 because it does bit wider.
Great.
Okay.
I want this to be able to rotate the right direction I'll show you why if I press play right now.
The labels are 1 1 the labels behind the walls.
That's not great.
And 2 they're not angled correctly so let's rotate that.
I won't go into the computer and I'm going to do this on ready.
So after the bit of the signal let's grab the label and what I want to do our set is rotation.
Well let's take a look at label and mouse over the rotation in rect which is wrecked on the school rotation.
Okay rect underscore rotation and I want to make sure this is always facing the right direction.
To do that I'm going to take the rotation of this computer and subtract it.
So negative rotation degrees.
I want to press play now.
The computer's test words are now in the right axis came in the wrong place.
They're in right axis.
Okay.
We can move that just to be a little bit closer.
So let's just go over here and drag you and you now live there.
See how that looks.
Better.
Ok so now let's do the same thing with the door.
Now going to move you to right here.
Okay let's get a locked door and we actually have some information we don't need don't we.
We don't need to be generating accommodation in the in the ready function so get rid of that and let's
get rid of this entire function here that is now handled elsewhere.
Okay.
So let's do the same thing so label dot wrecked on the score rotation
equals negative rotation on the school degrees.
OK so now in a press play
it has it right there can change the offsets and so on with the mess with at the moment.
But now I have a little challenge for you.
So here is my challenge for you.
I'd like you to have both the computer and the door display their lock group I.D. their door number
in the label of the computer and door nodes.
Suppose a video give that a shot and then you come back I'll show you my solution.
I'm OK Mac.
OK.
So back into Gaza we go.
And how many they just change this display.
Well we're sending this information through.
I'm doing the locked door first right here on lock group.
So let's just go label Dot.
Text equals and this is a string so we don't need to convert it.
I should go lock group.
We'll do the same thing with a computer.
So back into my computer scene open computer G.D. label
dot text equals and I just need to put lock groups or lock group
OK so if everything is right this press play that's a big one here about the computer a one here by
the door.
We now have a system we could put lots of locked doors in pressing computer 0 5 9 4.
Let's go test it 0 5 9 4.
Door opens and we get to go look at that.
I think that's excellent progress.
So in this video we've looked at returning the value for another function.
In other words we've we've set a variable as being the results of another function.
We've also got all our computers locked we've got locked doors going.
We've got the we've got the fundamentals of our game play down.
So excellent work.
And I'll see you in the next video.