Hello you marvellous God.
People in this video we're going to boost the bunny with some jump pads.
Let's make the game even more exciting by not making just dangerous but faster and higher.
So what do we need a jump had to do.
I'm picturing a coiled spring and when he touches it it's suddenly uncoiled and Bunny goes higher than
normal and then it resets to its original animation.
It goes back to its state.
So how can you make that happen.
Well let's begin by making a new song and I'm going to zoom in and out a little bit just to get rid
of that weird bug.
And we want a brand new known to do you know we don't want an area to be a life.
We want an area too deep.
I'm going to call it a jump pad because that's what it is I get rid of that we had capital A That I
don't need.
OK it's an area too deep so it wants a collision shape before we give it a collision shape.
Let's Wonderwoman the Scripps folder and then give it Sprite.
You know what let's give an animated Sprite.
All right so to make an animated Sprite work it needs frames let's give it a new Sprite frames.
Click on Sprite frames.
That's what I just said there.
Click on Spike frome's great rename default to Idol because I think default is a bad name.
I don't know why.
I just don't like it going to graphics.
And if you look in items you'll find we have three icons in I'm thinking that if we alternate between
Spring in and spring let's see what that looks like.
Has looking pretty good.
Way too fast though so let's go back into our Sprite frames and change that to two frames per second.
Not bad.
What you will notice is that it's going from the centre that could get irritating because this is going
to go through the bottom of the floor.
Speaking of irritating my stomach playing just for now because that's really distracting.
It's going from the centre.
We could do some stuff using offsets like an offset and switch it off centre and go minus 75 I think
that's how big it is and that's what 50 up and one is 50.
That's pretty good.
How is it playing.
The problem here though is that now it's working so often at the top.
I actually don't mind it from centre.
And it's give it back to 0 0.
I don't mind working from central planning like this is going to go through the floor and maybe hover
a bit but I'm actually fine with that.
If you're not you would have to alter these sprites somehow so give it an alpha sexual rest of it.
For now this feels good.
OK Ellis given the colours and shapes of this needs a collision shaped hoodie I could use a polygon.
I'm not going to and I'm going to give it a simple rectangle shape.
It's not going to be pixel perfect because well look this is a kind of skew If shape isn't it.
But if I go like that that looks pretty good.
And remember use the extant handle's not the scale handles.
If you try and scale a collision shape by dragging that the SCO handles you really are all kinds of
annoying bugs.
That's looking pretty good.
It's a little bit wider.
I'd rather give money a little bit too much run too little.
Let's hide the collision shit for now.
For forget let's hit jump pad and press select the parent not the children the one the moving around
we know what we know.
Second thing let's put this on a collision layer.
So on the jump pad itself under collision make sure the layer is set to something pick ups or train
either of those put on pick ups masking to the player.
If you're going to use these collision masts we have to be consistent and not forget them forgetting
them is going to really mess up the game.
We have a simple animation let's put in a second animation and hit this new animation button right here
and when they call this spring and for this I just need one.
So it's just going to go like this.
So we have two postle animations.
If we look at a meta Sprite and put it on playing from idle to spring.
And back to you I'll great leave that play for now although it is a little bit distracting.
Actually I'm not really but playing.
I lied.
Now the other thing we need to do is go to the spring animation and then return here and I'm going to
do this after a set amount of time.
I'm thinking one and a half seconds to do that.
I need a time an old timer those are awesome.
They do exactly what you think they would do.
They have a few options.
The first is the wait time that there's at one point five six seconds.
Is it a one shot.
What does it mean.
It means it'll stop when the timer reaches zero probably.
I think so.
And auto start does it start the moment the level starts.
No I don't want this stuntin them and the lost lights are right.
If we have a note that's going to connect by signal because it has a time out signal built in which
is exactly what we want.
We'll probably need a script.
Let's make a new script for jump ahead.
And that's going in the script folder because that's what they do.
And I probably don't need a ready function but I do need a couple of signals the first one is going
to be the jump pads area 2D signal and that's going to be body and it would use this quite a bit haven't
we.
So on body entered connect yourself you're going to do the thing this tidy this up a little bit.
The other one I want to use is timer.
And what does this do exactly you'd expect when the time hit zero.
Call this function.
Okay.
What needs to happen.
Well when Bunny enters this area Trudy we need to change what we're elevating so animated Sprite play
and you want to play spring.
I'm just going to double check this what I actually called it because that would be silly.
It is.
I also want to start the timer Let's get that right
timer start.
Time to start will do exactly what expect it's going to start the timer at the time or start from a
point five seconds and it'll take down.
When it gets to zero it'll call this function.
This function is going to reset the animations all it's going to be.
So I made a sprite to play default.
Great.
We have now successfully used our timer and that's looking pretty good.
The other thing it needs to do is move the player.
Well let's save this scene in scenes jump had scenes and let's get to the play a script that is I'm
going to make a new concept.
And this one will be called Jump underscore but sort of not a school that's close brackets.
That's an unschool.
And I mean set this constant to this is a multiplier.
How many times higher than you normal jumps speed do we go.
So if my normal jospeh is negative 1 7 5 0 0 negative 1750.
Multiply that by two and that's give me my boost speed and let's pick a function just after jump.
Take that up a bit.
Main function and we are going to call this boost.
What's going to happen on boost.
Well it's essentially the same as jump isn't it.
Motion dot.
Why does the most not white Eagles jump speed multiplied by Jump bust.
And that should work great.
Let's make sure we're actually calling it set back to jump had global dot player start boost.
Is that what I call it double checking.
It is why I called it great save that okay.
That should now work.
So let's put one on the level and double check it.
Can I make a new container note for it.
No.
2 D.
Which isn't actually contain a node but I'm using it to contain things and I call this jump pads within
which I'm going to instance opes that's not instance this child I'm going to instance at this time I
mean it a jump had.
And let's put one right.
No no no.
Let's move you not scale you.
If you get the thing I just say we actually start scaling things just hit the move.
But let's put you right here and let's make sure you're actually on the right things so animator's Sprite
you are an idol and you are playing save you.
That should work great.
Now you see here where I said it's going above it.
I can live with it.
I think that's pretty good.
Alright let's double check how this works.
It's funny.
Anybody can believe that.
One thing I'm interested in listen carefully is these points.
Every time I pick up a second coin it's restarting the sound.
The reason for that is there is only one audio stream player for all these coins.
Somebody are something that's zavada a on our Q and A for this course pointed out.
We can have an audio stream player on each coin rather than a global sound effect.
So for now let's try that one remove quite a SFX from my sounds delete the node let's remove it from
the global script.
So in two scripts.
Global.
But Judy will remove coiner SFX.
Finally let's get in to one of our quaint scenes.
And add a node full audio stream audio stream player.
There it is back in the sound effects but the coins back and what do we say we said minus 15.
And let's change the script sort of Colobus.
Not quite.
SFX not play.
Let's do audio stream player dot play.
It only has one thing it can play.
So that's what it'll play now when go back in the game.
Each coin should probably play.
Doesn't that sound satisfying.
Great.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I would like you to boost that bunny add some jump to your level.
Don't be afraid to tweak the level so you can take advantage of exciting new opportunities for Bunny.
And if you want to you can lead and lower the play at a certain point with clusters of coins.
Suppose the video give it a shot and when you come back I'll show you my tweak level with Boost pads.
Try and get at least two in there.
I'm shutting up now.
Pause the video.
See when you get back.
And welcome back.
Okay let's make some fun level stuff.
I've got one jump had here.
Do I like it here.
I kind of do but I don't want Bunny to hit its head so I'm going to move this type map here.
Let's get the right ground one to over here.
That looks good right.
Let's get out the tile map.
Let's duplicate this jump pad and I'm sure make sure I'm in mood mood move.
Yes and that way no matter where I press I'm moving the thing I've got selected.
Let's put one here.
This looks like a dramatic spot doesn't it.
That a good place.
That's a great place coins I'm going to select this coin duplicate it and back into move.
I little zigzaggy pattern like that.
That looks exciting.
And let's tempt the player to do something silly.
Are you going to many coins but you might lose the life you're about to get.
And I feel like one more that looks like a really big high jump doesn't it.
I'm going to put the end of the level eventually here so if I can lure the player down this way.
As looking pretty good where should I put this junk pad.
Do do do.
Put you right here next to the spikes set to mean.
Yes that is to me.
Let's move this spike.
Move the spike to.
You know what that looks nice and dangerous doesn't it.
What I might do is just tweak it like that.
Or shall I make a bigger thing bigger platform for it.
Oh no that looks good.
I would leave it like that.
Let's test it.
I want to I can do my own level.
Okay honey make me proud.
Here we go.
I'm the one that annoying when we have a jobs that affect us make that jump all the way.
You almost.
Spike.
You need to move on get a dominant boying.
Very nice.
Put the exit right here.
This be a dramatic finish.
Great Before I forget which Spike was it was this spike.
Spike let's move you into there about one last thing.
I've just realized I made a mistake I made a bug.
No I said I don't like calling things default.
I did just don't know why I didn't like the name so I didn't.
And then I did look and I made a sprite.
The animation is called Idle.
There is no default.
That doesn't work and chase that backed up idle and safe.
There we go.
That feels better in this video we have learned about the time and load we've had a jump has to be days
and we've redesigned a level to take advantage of the jump out share your tweak level shows where you've
put your boot pads and how exciting you can make this.
Can you lower your player into dangerous dramatic jumps and drops don't forget you can make them drop
onto a jump pad they can't see.
So sheil level with us on Facebook group on the community forum or discord.
I'd love to see what you guys have come up with.
And meanwhile great work and I'll see you in the next few.