Hello.
Glorious God to people in this video.
We're going to continue making a gooey.
But this time we're getting a kind of fancy.
See I want to measure how many lives or other display how many lives each robot has.
And we might have a bunch of robots in the level at any given time.
So I don't really want to make a gooey that shows all the different robots and all the different you
know lives they might have is going to clutter everything up.
Instead let's show this in the three dimensional space in this video were going to discuss Sprite 3D
notes and look at how to make truly objects work in three dimensions.
So let's get right to it.
First of all to do is go into this robot snoad an open one of the robot scenes and in here are going
to make a Southern node and call it spatial.
I'm not going to use node in new spatial and I'll tell you why node doesn't have positional information
and spatial does the robots are going to move.
And I'm going to animate some stuff later.
It can get very complicated if I use spatial then the nodes within here are going to use local transforms
and it'll work just fine.
OK I want to call this lives.
And in here I'm going to put some Sprite 3-d Somewhere make a sprite 3D and Sprite 3-d is exactly what
it sounds like some open graphics and get one who's hearts and let's pull on snap and move it up here.
This is a sprite drawn in the 3D world you'll see it has no depth as depth of zero but it's being rendered
as a 3D object must scale this up a bit so let's I'm going to transform and give this a size of two.
All right so here we have a life.
Nicole this wife and I don't want this just to vanish.
I want this to animates a when the robot is hurt.
I want stuff to happen let's make this fancy and put an animation player as a child of life.
And in this animation player I need to put a simple animation on called lose life.
There goes.
And what should we do.
Well let's start by making a key frame for scale.
And I think a nice short animation half a second sounds good.
So like the zero point five.
And at the zero point five mark on a change the scale to 0 0 0 and put a key.
That's not quite enough.
I'd also like some fancy rotation so let's rotate it rotation degrees and put a key frame at 0 0 0 and
half a second.
I'm going to rotate on the y axis by three hundred fifty nine degrees.
Why not 360 degrees because 360 degrees is the same as zero which means it won't actually rotate.
Here's what they look like.
Cool.
I don't just want to have a scale of zero though.
I wanted to vanish at half a second.
So one more track can this add new track but then when I add a call function track and it says where
you want to call the function I want you to call the function on life which is the parent of this animation
player.
So the zero point five let's insert a key and press this green Plus an insert a key there.
Now I need to edit that key So that's at the key click on it and under name right.
Q free I don't need to put brackets.
I'm going to call the function Q free life doesn't have a script but it doesn't need one Q free is a
built in function.
So when this elimination is played this will happen.
It'll run the animation and then remove life from seeing a duplicate this small animal put life.
Let's put it down here.
That look.
Looks pretty good at life 3 and a put down here.
So lose the first life then the second life.
Then the third life.
With these however you want.
You dont have to have a snap I've just done this for simplicity.
You will notice by the way that right now lives as a variable is set to 3 and I happen to have three
sprites.
Dont have a way of automating this.
I am alright with this for now.
I'm okay with all characters having three lives in the.
But if you wanted to automate this you'd have to do something fancy with a script.
But I think it's a little beyond the scope of got of tie to this and it sets off snap sleets lives one
and three and just make up not to come back and just move them a bit more like that make more of a friendly
arc shape.
Okay so let's save that and see how it looks going.
I was looking pretty good.
Let's see how they make.
Awesome.
Now we need to make these things actually vanish right.
I've displayed these sprites when even to vanish.
To do that I'm going to go into the robot script which if I go to script view is right here fantastic.
We have updated lives and we have it in play.
And we have it in roebling we get to our daily lives and player.
And here it does this whole thing in Robot.
I want it to not do pass.
This is we're going to write the information first thing I need to do is check.
Do you have ZERO lives.
Why am I checking this first.
I'll show you.
It's going to character and you'll see on hurt which is this one right here.
Here's what can happen if you've been hurt.
Subtract one life.
Play the hurt sound effect check your lives and then update lives.
This is going to run.
No matter what so if you have one life left and then you lose it.
We're still going to run this.
If you get hit by two things at the same time that's going to be an issue because there isn't going
to be a life to remove from lives.
So let's check if you haven't if lives for greater than zero.
What are art to do.
Well what I want to do is grab the top child of lights and play the animation with an with an outfit
know and play the animation within it.
Okay so I need to grab the top shot of life grab that top child and tell it play this animation.
OK.
Let's get into that.
So first we create a variable and I call this life and this is going to be lives.
Got get child and which are many.
Meaning get zero.
So what does zero means zero means.
Count the children down and we're going to count from 0 9 just like we do with a raise.
We almost always count from zero and programming.
And then what the child of that somebody get child 0.
One more time.
Okay.
Now I want to have a love life stopped play because it's going me an animation and when I'm playing
I'm playing the animation loserville life.
OK.
Let's see how that works.
I going to this nice next you can see it versus grab some.
Look try not to die while doing this.
Grab some ammo and see if I can hit one of these robots.
Boom.
Do they now.
So back to my own game.
There it goes.
Awesome.
Now there's a pause that and show you remotes Let's see who was actually running like right now and
open the robot's folder open robot one.
How many lives do you have.
Yeah three open robot too.
How many lives you have.
You have to like it.
Okay so we know this is working.
Remote is what is actually running live right now and local is what does the scene look like when it's
not running.
So we know that this will now work.
OK.
So right now we have a victory condition which is all the robots are defeated and we have a loose condition
which is the play is defeated and we have screens to go to Windows.
Now what that means is when all the players.
When the player is dead we need to go one way and when the robots are all dead we to go another way.
But right now Di is within the character script which means I don't want to hear and want to put a different
dice script in each set of a dice script for the player.
And what you do is very simply get tree change scene and what scene with the change to.
Well let's go get it.
I want to go to.
When the player is dead we're going to the game over sing live.
So that's going to live right here in those quotes.
And I have missed the bracket.
That's okay.
But more brackets in when a player dies will go to the scene.
Let's just double check that I've done that right.
One two three lives down.
Awesome.
I demand a rematch.
And we're back here.
Great.
A quick note.
If you're running this and got a three point one you might now get an error and the error you're going
to get is that you're calling a function in this script that isn't in this script.
Got a three point o doesn't check that first got a three point one does.
Now this will actually run fine because the script is being inherited and we are never running character
on it's own.
It's always being run from another script.
However if you want to run this one you're probably going to do some sort of workaround.
In this case I would probably use character type right so I would have if character type equals character
type player then do this if it equals robots that do this.
And I would put everything on in a die function within character.
However I'm using God 3.0 So I'm not going to be doing that.
I also need to make a game stick script because now I need to keep track of how many robots we are we
have.
Let's make a game six reps I'm going to go to level 1 and I actually can open the template.
Because all levels will have this script.
So let's add a script to level template and as you might imagine this will live in the script folder.
I want to call it game state Judy.
OK let's quickly function called remove Henley.
And for now you can put a in here and save that.
And just to make it really clear that all robots have a template.
Court robots has got to node.
Let's make a note rather than call it robots and check.
That's what I called it level 1.
I can.
Yes I did save that.
Now I probably should have done that first because if I now look with in this scene tree you might have
a situation.
We have robots and a different robots.
If you do that's fine.
Just run the game.
And you can look at remote and should now find that you only have one robots follow.
Okay so you should be good to go.
So this will sort itself out.
But if you don't want it first you might see two robot notes.
Don't panic.
It's easy to fix.
So now there's robots folder is always part of that script.
I won't make a signal
signal there and call this would move me.
Okay now I want to connect this but I'm going to try to connect it to a specific node that's going to
have a different name each time so I can't use FIND name right.
So I said I'm gonna have to get this by locations of her look at level 1.
All seems have this node here which might be called level 1 level 2 office bank.
What Whatever going to call it right here and the robots are all going to have children of a node called
robots.
Suddenly I get a parrot get parrot.
It's a little messy but I'm okay with it.
So let's do that now in the robot script back to thing.
I'll make it variable called Game.
Let's call it game it get parents got get.
Parent and now I need to connect this notes to connect.
And I should be in the robot scene so I can actually order correct.
So when am I correct I'm going to connect remove anything to connect that to game States.
One more thing I need to tell it and it's tell it what method are you calling.
Well you want to call remove.
And it's exactly the same name just to make it nice and legible.
Great.
So that's my enemy when we are now going to call that signal.
When are we going to call that signal on die.
I need to put die in Robot remember because I've taken it out of character put it in play.
I don't have it here so let's put it in here.
Function guy I need to emit underscored signal.
And the signal I'm emitting is not signal.
That's crazy talk.
Remove enemy.
So I am letting the game state script know an enemy has been removed.
Great.
After I've done that I can remove myself from the game as can be.
Q free some weird things happening there but not much.
Let's push this challenge up a notch.
One thing I was slightly tricky in now is a few more steps in this.
I think you're probably up to it but don't worry if I struggle a bit.
Let's just get that grey matter going and see how comfortable you are.
I would like you to have game state Judy lo the victory scene when all the enemies are defeated and
some say animals not animals the robots enemies are defeated.
Quick tip you can use get child count to find out how many nodes are children of a node.
Robots pause the video give it your best shot and when you've either found a solution or you've got
a little frustrated.
Come back and I'll show you how I would solve this.
And welcome back.
I won't go into my games script and the first thing I need is a variable.
My variable is going to be called Enemy count.
Now I need to fill that value and I'm going to do this in ready.
Why am I doing it.
Ready.
Because every level is going to have a different amount of robots at least potentially right maybe level
one has two enemies making level two has four maybe level 3 has 16 while went to for 16.
I don't know just round numbers.
So on ready I'm going to fill enemy kotzer Enemy count equals and all I need to do is because we know
that this lay aren't going be the same for all levels because this is a template I just need to get
to the robot's node.
So let's grab that and I need to count the children to do that.
I'm going to get child count at all.
That's just going to return an integer of how many direct children the node robots has.
And that's precisely what I want.
Okay now we've received a signal.
An enemy has been removed.
I don't need to recount it.
I can just say enemy count minus equal 1.
Alright so let's call to keep track of how many enemies are on the scene.
But it's not actually going to get us to the victory screen so let's get to the victory screen.
I'm assuming going to the screen not the next level.
Right now which making one level.
If you want to make multiple levels you have to keep track of what level on how many levels there are
and then go from there.
But for now let's just go to the screen so say this is going to be an if statement is going to right
here.
If enemy count there it is is equal to zero.
Now Im hesitating a little here because remember we could in theory lose two robots on exactly the same
frame.
It's almost impossible but it is theoretically possible.
So let's change that a little bit so if the enemy count is less than 1 okay that's 0 and everything
belief beneath it will work fine.
Now I just need to get tree to change scene.
Let's go grab that scene.
So that's going to be in levels in gooey victory.
And now we should have a basic game.
So let's make this nice and big.
And let's see if I actually survive long enough to see a victory to see it all go away.
Giant hamburger at these projec does on much bigger than my version.
This is much harder than it was in the prototype but two is damaged.
I'm hiding behind a table like some sort of table hiding mouse.
Oh they are so close.
Well what vitrines mind.
What.
You have been defeat.
Oh this is the victory screen.
And have left you have been defeated which is a cheap victory screen.
So now let's do that real quick.
Ha.
Okay.
Didn't think of that.
But victorious.
It's exabyte tourist cook.
Okay so we now have a fully functional game.
Right now there's some polish we need to do.
I still wanna put character customization in so we're not done with a section but look at that.
We have a tense game that can quite frankly kick my backside side and there's a lot we can really tweak
with this one he's going to tweak.
To be honest is I'm going to play a scene and the camera back so I can see where I'm doing a bit more.
So let's quickly go in to player grab the camera.
Let's just move back a bit to camera was looking a bit better.
And do you think of that.
No too high.
Was he what would an upset look snap off an.
Too little too little.
Maybe.
See what that looks like.
I have a lot more idea of what's happening now so that feels better.
Cool.
And that brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we've looked at counting lives as objects because our enemy count is a variable but we're
counting them every time we at a level based on how many robots are within a certain node.
We've also looked at three upright notes.
We've come a long way off food fight game is pretty solid.
Little bit more to add but excellent work.
And I will see you in the next video.