Hello again you lovely go to people in this video we're going to continue our work on the suspicion
meter.
We're going to make some suspicious and pieces so what we need to do.
Well first thing let's decide how suspicion works when the player is seen the suspicion meter will go
up if we're out a line of sight.
The suspicion meter will lower and it will lower a slower rate.
I want to be risky right way to hide and if the suspicion meter is completely full we will lose the
game.
So let's get to it.
First thing I do is I make sure that our suspicion meter has a script.
So let's go into our galley which is easiest way to do that is to just click here and I'm going to rename
texture progress to suspicion meter so I can see what I'm working with suspicion meter.
And let's give a script now before we start playing with this let's take a look what we already have
to play with.
If we look in the range here you'll notice that there are some properties.
We have a minimum value a maximum value.
And we've really looked at us at value right.
So if I just draw this up I just hit a 25 because he's 25 out of 100 it's called awful.
And I can drag that value up and down.
Now what's interesting here is we can change things like step.
How much do you got myself I got by 10 and I start dragging the value up so let's put you at 20 you'll
notice that it now goes in increments of 10.
We can use these for our advantage.
We're gonna use max value step and value rather than make our own variables is no reason to make variables
here.
The one variable I do want to use is gonna be an export variable.
I will call suspicion multiplier and this become clear in a moment of analysis as to very fast I'll
do as well set the ready function Ludmilla and just make sure that value is set at zero.
So if you've been playing with it an inspector it'll go back down to zero.
Every single frame I want the suspicion meter to drop so let's go function process.
No reason to do this in the physics lab and I'm going to set the value property which is built in to
be minus equal the step which is built in right We've already looked at these.
What this means is every single frame the value meter whatever this number is will go down by whatever
this number is.
Now we don't need to clamp this because by default we're gonna be clamped between minimum value and
maximum value.
We could enable these to enable greater enable ESA to bypass that but I don't want to do that.
I want this kept in range.
I now don't need to worry about clamping this at all I don't need to make sure don't go below this value
and don't go above that one God is going to handle it for me.
So when the player is seen let's make a function for that we want this value to go up so function play
a scene and I want the value to go up
however this is where the multiplier comes in because for the code on him if we're dropping down by
the same level we're going up we're not actually going to go up.
So this has to be a little bit faster so suspicion multiply by two Halloween you glory has got to people
future Yan here and I have just noticed a weird bug here I'm editing the video getting ready to put
up on the site and I have realized what I've done I have got step multiplied by step multiplier multiplied
by two I've just squared the step multiplier I should not have done that I should have step multiplied
by step multiplier and then stop.
So when it starts going crazy in a while that's why I will fix that next video but just to give you
a quick heads up Don't copy what I've just done.
OK back to present Yan now the moment I'm keeping this very simple all right I'm using integers you
don't have to but if you're not going to I would ask you to do to go to rounded that'll allow you to
use partial values let's say I'm going to be half as fast and it'll still display won't throw the Evaluate
otherwise it'll just throw the value away All right so we're going to go up twice as fast as we drop
now we can say if the value is equal to the max value which is a property within this then and the game
and in our case ending the game at this stage it's just going to quit right out we're not gonna have
to make a screen later of and game screen with a restart in the else but for now let's just drop the
game so get tree and I get a call quit there's a couple of more things that do need to do first I look
put suspicion meter on a group let's go over to Node 2 groups and add it to suspicion meter I'm gonna
copy that into my clipboard press ad and I can now save it.
Now let's head over to characters and we have under NPC these player detection which is the base for
all of our amputees our camera and our guards are using power detection and this is possibly detection
specifically under if player in F Ovi and player in elo s we'll switch the torch codes are red and we're
going to get Tre dot Cole group and the string into the group is suspicion meter and the method is play
a scene.
I don't need brackets for that but I do need to double check.
That's what I actually called it a take look I've got it planned on school scene play on the school
scene.
Awesome.
Never say that if I've done this right.
I press play and let's see we're on 1 0 7 nines is going to 1 0 7 9 Whoops I'll try that again 1 0.
Come on in 1 0 7 9.
I nodded eat buttons okay so what I know is I can go down here and especially it goes right up.
I also know that there is a camera on my level that's too far in the wall.
This one doesn't work.
Can I move this one first.
Select it.
Which camera i.e. your camera going to pull you out to here.
So you actually work because the root of the node was inside the wall it wasn't detecting anything.
Okay so I know that that is far too fast.
What I want.
Let's go back to the suspicion meter and change it.
So what I need to do is I need to tweak my max value and my step and that isn't me my challenge for
you.
Not a particularly difficult challenge but a really important one as a game designer.
You want to get the feel right now you'll be changing this a lot but this is easy.
The changes go to the suspicion meter and alter the values.
So how suspicious are they.
I want you to tweak your step.
You'll multiply variable and your max value properties to make the game feel just right for you.
So pulls the video and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
Okay.
So in my case we're going so fast that I don't really have time to react so I'm gonna change my max
value to 200 and I'm going to change my step two point two five.
This is going to do two things.
First it can take longer to get his max value how much longer.
I don't know.
I can't do that my head but I won't say eight times longer.
It's not going to massively slow down the time before I'm safe.
So now in a press play and I go 7 4 8 3 7 4 8 3 I now have time to run for safety right.
It's dangerous.
I'm stressing out and try to speak but it's not so dangerous that I can't do it.
So I could run through this door here and it's all very safe and then if I try and get into this office
up here which I believe there is a camera up there let's say I have a computer there I want to use it's
now a lot riskier right.
So I can run here run back and then try make his level my needs more cameras.
But we can make that rescue already.
This feels a lot more like a game right.
This is now a failed state and if I wait for this to drop but it drops this might be a little too safe
for me so I might change this to 150 but that is a really good place to end.
So in this video we've looked at using the texture progress notes properties as variables we don't have
to add functionality that got it already has and we've used get tree quit game to end the game.
Excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.