Hello again you glorify God.
People in this video really get started with actually customizing the character.
What we can do is make a play a customization scene.
So let's talk about player customization means and food fight.
The player is going to be able to switch between two pieces which currently I haven't named male and
female.
It's a little bit more binary than I'd really like but these are the assets we've got and frankly we
can make this fun.
The players are also gonna be able to cycle through textures so you can be able to pick which character
you've got and what they look like.
Now this is going to be more of a proof of concept where owning and change want texture but if you had
a character model with several different materials we could just expand this and have for instance something
for the skin colour something for the eyes something for the hair maybe switch the models.
This will work for all of us thanks.
We also want something where the player can customize their character.
So when the game is actually running you'll be able to go to the escape menu and hit that customize
character button that county does nothing and relive that scene.
Speaking of scenes let's make a character customization scene so I'm gonna make a brand new scene and
see 3D.
So I think spatial is a good root node and I call it.
Character customization.
Okay first thing I do and I'm bringing a character I need to scale everything around them so it doesn't
really matter which one I pick.
I'm going to go in two scenes characters.
Players list you play Ethel.
They are excellent.
OK.
So this is just for us to work with.
I'm going to rename this
immature.
Now start building some scenery.
Create a simple note and Nicole this scenery.
Right.
Let's stop putting in some shapes.
So these are only measures since this is a simple mesh instance.
And I would make a poem you must make a poem that's going to be a cylinder there we're going to call
this podium.
And in this case I can just scale it because it's it doesn't have any kind of collision it's not going
to do anything that looks pretty good.
And I may just drag it down a bit.
There's no podium.
Next the spring of floor.
Another measure measurements.
And it would be a plane that at least be a lot bigger than it would to move it down.
But first we see this podium and let's scale this up sort of transform 10 by 10 light and that looks
pretty good.
Now right now I've got no materials and these things are put those in later and I'm going to rename
this floor.
Finally the walls.
Now I'm looking for a nice curved effect it's going to look much better with lighting and a lot more
dramatic.
So all we do is make measurements and I gonna make it a sphere and make this really big let's say 10
by 10 meter
and it's vanished.
Why has it vanished.
It's very well it actually hasn't.
If we zoom out it's right there.
But remember the materials are being cold on the inside insights on what to do is some do is go to the
material and give it a new spatial material so new special material when you click on it.
And on parameters I'm going to call the front.
And now when we look at it we have this very dramatic looking down and that's looking much more like
it.
Let's call it what.
One more thing I do.
And we go back up to character customization and we make a note and recall this lighting.
That's one of my lights because this is going to need some dramatic lighting.
So at this stage I think it's time to let your creativity shine.
Before we begin over here in the materials folder you'll find a bunch of materials that we use for all
kinds of things you can use any of these.
You don't have to.
However what I'd like you to do is decorate your customization see make this look awesome using your
creativity.
Play with textures materials lighting to get the effect of most proud of and share that I'd love to
see what you guys have got so put it in the forum put it in a Facebook group put it in discord wherever
you want it.
Let's get lots of really cool cosmesis customization seems out there.
Well that's hard to say.
Support the media and when you come back I'll show you how I would do it.
And welcome back.
I personally do start with some customers.
Let's start with the podium and the podium is going to have a nice dark wood material.
I think that's going to look good a little bit dark because the lighting there fixed that in a little
while the floor on the other hand I think you want to give this a to.
I think the kavakeb material may be let's find out.
Not looking good is it.
How do you feel about dark metal as do that dark metal floor.
I might have to tweak this as the lighting comes in but that's fine.
And this back home I could give this red mateer I think that look really cool.
However then it's going to mess up the parameters and mess up the flag and I don't really want to mess
with that so something we're going to material have made and just change the beat and hitless.
Give this a nice dark red and have a look at tallack nice and I think lots of roughness and looked to
the roughness up to one.
OK right now this looks dark.
More than awesome So let's put some lighting.
I'm going to make a simple spotlight and one more to do here is use a little bit of the actual training.
I won't use the three point lighting technique frequent lighting techniques as you have lighting from
three directions.
So first let's move this light up to the front and side.
Wouldn't want anything directly in front.
We put it front and side and put the local rotation where it is nice and easy.
So from the sort of 45 that 30 to 45 degree angle and that's looking pretty good and its angle you didn't
come back and let's angry you down.
Yeah that's looking pretty good.
Okay so I'm going to call this my fill it up and let's make you slightly orange.
I only go for a sort of filmic look some of these teal orange here so nice warm orange but I'm must
nice and bright so head up to No.
3.
That's looking pretty good.
Alright so that is my thing like now only the key light the key light is what's going to give this scene
or the subject that really bright focus so let's give you a nice bright fill so that lights a spotlight
angle do a key light and this is going to focus right on the face.
And let's just move you over here ish.
That's good.
And I think it is one about eye level.
You know a little bit more in front not so much the side of us looking very nice.
And I keep this one open white for now.
Put that up too.
OK.
So we can see here.
I've got two very subtle differences.
I've got an orange and a white.
But what I need is one more light.
Right is a three point lighting system and he's a.
Phil light which is giving you the general shape the key light which is highlighted to look at and the
backlight in the back.
It's important because that's going to give things shadow and depth.
So that's going to go as you might expect from the back.
I don't need to snap on because we can be a little bit rough and ready with this.
What I will do is go above the head a little bit but I think that's the wrong one.
How did you do that so many little light things to look at.
That again I'm going to raise that one straight up.
OK.
So my backlight is going to be a nice teal colour.
And let's give this a really strong for.
Now you're not going to notice it immediately but it should if we've picked it right.
Just make the edges of everything pop.
I might even go dark at this I might go for a deep blue as best as he'll.
She's going to add a little bit more shadow under her coat now to put some lights on the wall.
And I want to use another spot and this is going be a very small spot in theatre a very very small spot.
It's called a birdie.
Don't ask why.
It's a really bad golf joke.
Yes it's actually a golf joke.
So do is it that put snap on I'm going to angle this at night.
Whoops angle this 90 degrees straight up.
And let's just move that to here.
Grab the being that narrow the focus a bit and you know I think it should go a little bit closer so
let's put it right up against it.
And what I'm looking for as this go all the way up there we go that looks better.
I'm looking for is this very cinematic kind of picking out the details of the wall.
I'll lower this slightly.
This thing at a snap.
And on to come from almost the floor is going to look like there are little lights hidden here.
There are little lights hidden here but we see them and with duplicate that put snap back on.
Put another one right there and that I think is looking nice and dramatic.
We could put a couple more in if we wanted to let's put one here over here.
And another one.
Over here.
Is looking pretty solid.
Of course that's my lighting for this.
Okay.
Now let's not forget a camera put a camera in the sink
and that's going to live.
You think about here.
Here's that look.
So a little bit.
And so where are we.
That's looking pretty solid.
In fact it might go lower and angled up a bit so we could look up at the character.
Less dramatic.
Up shop they go back on my camera great and make this camera current which I forgot to do last night
and that is the basics crossing.
So first thing I need to do before I go any further is remember to save this because I haven't done
that yet so let's save this in scenes in customisation l'enclos carrot customization doctor.
Yes.
Yeah.
Second thing I do is a bring in the second character some an instance in play em and I want play em.
To be in the same position.
Let's see if I hide play a f and preview that that's in the wrong places and it's another Braves player.
A little bit were cheating slightly but that's okay.
It's too high.
Camera is actually not where I want it so I lied.
Let's go into global mode and he's pulled back a bit down and back.
And down a bit Bob.
You know I'm aiming too high.
I'm trying to get this podium in here.
Cool.
Let's play a comment a preview.
Can I go back there.
Okay cool.
So we've got this character and this character and they are actually the same height remember.
I'm going to move this one over to the top.
They are actually the same height but the animations of the idle animation is different at the moment
then this one image.
And that is a pretty solid start so what we have here.
In fact I might even make this a little bit brighter on this one direction lighton.
So light directional white and I'm just going to make this one when I come back there you are.
Let me use this to wipe the floor.
So let's put you all to the side and put you back in local mode so you're easier to aim.
Yeah.
How's that.
Look let's find out.
I may have wrecked this.
Just look at one character at a time.
Now that's pretty good isn't it.
I like that a lot.
Still a little bit of orange is causing this.
I saw shadows we can angle these a bit differently.
We could put in more and more of these birdies going all the way around the wall if we wanted.
But I'm kind of happy with that so far.
And that brings us to the other video in this video we've looked at creating a customization scene with
exports and basic lighting techniques and we're on to a really good start.
Next up we're going to create a gooey so that we can actually change customization.
Then going to plug the whole thing together so that the customization iterates through the game and
then it's just polish we're almost done.
We're doing really great.
Don't forget to share your customization seen so far and excellent work and I'll see you in the next
video.