Welcome back you lovely people in this video are going to take a pause from adding content to fix a
bug.
I've received this bug report.
Players can waggle on the edge of a coin to pick it up multiple times.
And this can happen by mistake letting players quickly rack up infinite coins.
Well I hadn't noticed this but enough people have.
Let's find out if we can reproduce it.
Right.
This is taken me a few attempts.
This is what I get on this practice can be done.
Observe by 10 coins a 13 coins.
Why.
Because I was able to enter the coin while it was vanishing.
If I leave and enter the coin every time I do that that counts as on body entered.
Okay so what can we do about that.
Well the first thing to do is get the problem from our keyway from our play testers.
So here the problem is that the coins can be picked up while they're vanishings starting the whole process
again.
In other words whenever you enter the coin as long as it exists it's going to start the whole animation.
And when you enter it it'll go back to the beginning and keep doing.
You can loop this indefinitely.
So what's the solution.
Wooden is a variable to check if the coin was taken.
If it's not been taken the player can take it.
Otherwise nothing will happen resolution.
We got to write our code this problem solution resolution is something that I use a lot in board game
design and it's really helpful just to keep track of what exactly needs to be solved.
How can we solve it.
Have we solved it.
So let's get to the resolution.
Can I open the coin seeing.
Everything looks good here let's go into the coin script.
Let's pick a variable called Taken and start as false and on everybody tuti and tillus go if not taken.
Nice and easy to read and then highlight all these three oppressed tab and just shuffle them up one
indentation.
Okay so if it's not taken.
Do these.
There's one more thing I need to do.
I will do this right at the beginning.
The logic taken equals true.
And let's make them actual equals.
Now when I press play Okay let's test the money.
Get a coin.
Having coins we have we have eight coins.
We have nine coins.
Great.
Looks like it's been fixed.
So in this video we've covered two things the first and we've kind of alluded this is the importance
of quality assurance.
Q In other words you need people play testing and not just play testing reporting bugs and you need
them to be as precise as possible and where they can give you as many details on how to reproduce the
bug as they can.
If you have the details and you know the code you can usually figure out where the code is going wrong.
Second thing we've looked at is how to make sure an item can only be triggered once.
If you need a coin to just be picked up once.
Here's how you get that logic.
Great.
We are now officially entomologist vets because we can fix bugs.
The bug is fixed.
Great work and I'll see you on the next video.