Hello again you Gloria's go to people in this video.
We're gonna make the player easier to see.
You see we've got this lovely dark level with this beautiful dark vision mode.
But I can't see myself properly and that's not helping gameplay.
So to highlight the player.
So what do we need to do.
Well first let's think about like 2D nodes.
We know that light two dinos can take a texture.
So we could put the player texture on that is like to denote right so we could just very quickly take
the sprite where we have an overlay it has a light source and include it will take care of everything
else.
We then have to change that texture in the sky.
So all we need to do is add a light to denote but the player is a texture and then a little bit of code
to switch between the player textures light and the box sexual light and back nice and simple.
So let's jump in and get it the first thing we do is open the play a scene Hello play a scene you need
a light to Dino's troll eight and a..
Light 2D and with texture is going to be characters I know it's not going to be graphics it's gonna
be PMG Hit Man 1 There you are.
Boom.
Now we don't have to have it quite that intense so we have an energy of five that should help and let's
just see how that looks.
So in-game and seem a bit more maybe point five is a bit low.
How about points several five it might go the way up to one but it instinctively feels should be a little
lower that's a little better isn't it.
So I can see that.
What would it look like with one
to break like I was right then at that point seventy five.
Great.
Now let's get into the script and I'm going to add a couple of more constants here.
So for somebody then a duplicate the play a sprite constant and call this play a light.
Now I'm not blushing caps now I could just reuse play a Sprite and just call this twice but we might
come to a point in the game where we want to change what the light source actually looks like.
I'm going to give myself that option and it's also good way being very very clear what we're actually
calling here let's do the same thing here with box white is not one could box light.
So we have both.
Now just a quick Control B to duplicate.
Let's split those up.
Now let's get down to reveal and disguise.
OK so when we revealed our sprite texture is going to be the low the player sprite.
And now I want my light to D dot and this is texture again equals load and we call this player light.
Great.
And let's do the exact same thing down here disguise so lights to d not texture equals load box lights
OK.
Let's take a look.
So jumping game wait in line load and what time.
OK I can see myself nice and easily switch to be a box and jump in here I'm still nice and visible and
that works pretty well.
So in this video we've just made the player visible which just putting a light to the.
Just on that nice quick easy win adds quite a lot to the gameplay it's gonna make testing a lot easier
and you can see what I'm doing while still keeping the levels nice and dark.
It's a great stuff and I'll see you the next video.