Hello again you fabulous go to people in this video.
We want to fix a problem we've now created.
You see we've got this lovely box disguise and the box means that they can't see us but we can still
move around.
We can still interact with things there's no penalty.
Why not just play as a box.
We've effectively made the game too easy.
This is because the box isn't really an interesting decision.
And whenever you making a game you will make sure that any decision the player makes is actually interesting
meaningful.
This isn't meaningful being in a box is simply the right choice.
So we're going to add some things to it specifically we're not at risk of the reward players should
move slower when they're disguised.
OK.
So if you're sneaking on the box you should be going slowly.
We'll also limit the amount of disguises you can have.
Now in this video we're not going to add a visual representation of how many disguises you have.
We're just going to know what the number is.
But we gonna build the framework so we can show that in the future video.
And then the disguises will have a maximum duration.
And we need to display that to the player.
So we want our disguises.
I would say five seconds my default would make that nice and easy to tweak.
So that's our goal for this video.
So let's get back into gotto how I got it.
And as you might expect we've been looking to play a scene over the placing an open play a script and
let's zoom right back up to the Top funding I'll do is make an export variable and we'll call this disguised
slowdown.
And this is going to be how much slower you gonna be moving out with zero point to five.
We're gonna be moving at a quarter speed and to make this work I'm going to put one more variable in
here and that's gonna be the velocity multiplier.
That's going to start off as one.
And during gameplay we will change it between 1 and 0 point to 5 to make this work as will move in slide
motion times velocity multiplier by default.
That can be motion times one anything times one is itself right.
One of anything is itself.
As you might guess we're gonna change this value to whatever is in disguise slow down because this is
an export variable if I save it and click on player we can actually change it here.
So if you wanna tweak it nice easy way of tweaking it.
Okay.
So we have a disco slowdown.
Let's put it in so reveal I'm going to put these textures and include is a little bit separately and
let's say velocity multiplier is equal to 1.
And down here let's do the same thing except velocity multiplier multiplier multiplier is equal to disguise
slowdown.
Okay let's quickly test.
So back into the game and I can move around nice and easily disguised I move around at a quarter speed
very nice.
So check that wonderfully.
Second I want to make for that disguises only last a certain at a time which means I'm using time I
should to put in a timer control a timer.
That's my time on make sure I'm set to 1 shot when this timer is done I want you to do something what
I want you to do I want you to to reveal the plants remove the disguise.
Nice and easy.
I to click on timeout and first connect and I'm connected to the player.
I'm not creating a new method.
I'm going to use reveal which is an existing method and there it is.
It's jump right to here.
So when this time it goes off boom we're going right here.
Okay so how long should this time ago feel.
Well I feel like maybe be five second five second five seconds.
However we might wanna change that.
Let's say export variable disguise duration is equal to five.
Let's actually spell that right.
Disguise duration.
Oh my typing is getting lost isn't it.
Okay.
So we're not stuck in this disguise duration except at the moment.
At no point are we actually using this value.
So let's use this value and to do that we need a ready function.
Okay we're in ready.
While we here we should probably set reveal just be very very clear.
So whatever we've done in the edits I make sure that the player can be seen it'll be the game as a player
we should be sorting the box and let's set the timer.
And this has a property called wait time and remember if you're not sure it is.
I've said this before just mouse over it and there it goes.
Great wait time.
He calls this disguise duration.
Fantastic.
We're still not actually triggering the timer.
So in disguise which can put timer dot stopped
OK let's take a quick look.
So I'm going to jump in game.
Let's go into disguise not touch anything after five seconds we should if everything's working right.
Pop right back.
Great.
So that's looking pretty good.
But there's one more thing I want to do I want to give the player a chance to know when that's going
to happen.
To do that we need to add another new node now so I add a boop label Halo label and we should give you
a name should we realistically disguise label disguise timer or something with a not timer as a talent
disguise and I started by putting zero point zero zero and let's just make sure we'll come back because
of exec press return and then remove the return by clicking the extent it came back.
Now we could use a theme for this.
Load off theme load and when we put this interface theme there it is nice and big.
I like that.
Okay.
Now this doesn't wanna be here want to move it a little make sure that when you move it this isn't happening.
Why is this happening.
Let's click on Sky's label.
It's happening again.
It's because of this icon right here.
Right now we're not selecting child knows we're always selecting parents.
Usually that's what you want but in this case it isn't so disliked it remove the label to be here unless
I can get now currently.
That's just a 0 0 0.
There will always be there.
So it's they're not very useful and it's kind of hidden.
So let's make it actually work.
First off in reveal let's hide it.
So we're changing little textures and in the same section same disguise label dot visible equals false
equals false.
That's one way we could do it.
We could also just use the hide function which does the exact same thing right.
So hide it.
And here I could say this guy's level it show which does the opposite.
So now when we get back into the game let's change vision mode.
You can't see it you can't see it you can't see it.
Let's make the label actually work.
Now this is going to happen every frame.
Which means we have to put it in either process or physics process.
We're already using physics process.
Let's put it in here.
Let's say if you're disguised
because this should only be happening with your disguise right.
I want the time to go down anyway.
Then the disguise label lets you get dollar disguise label.
Thank you Dot.
Text is equal to the time a dot time left.
Now be careful this is not a string right.
The timer is using floats.
Text needs a string.
So we're going to have to cast that so string time left.
This can be a little bit messy though because if I press play now and let's change mission mode hide
it.
Look at that that that's a disaster present.
So to do this there's something we can use in string we can use a function put pad decimals and I really
love this.
So let's take a look at pad decimals and control and click on it formats a number.
This is within the string mulloway.
So let's take a look.
This is within.
This is a function built into string formats a number to the exact number of digits.
Let's take a look and change vision mode and hide.
Look at that and my disguise runs out.
Now back again
I love it.
However you'll notice that when I rotate the plane it's going to rotate the label's going to come with
it and that is my challenge you.
I would like you to see if you could figure out a way to make sure that the label for the disguise timer
is always the right way up.
Take a couple minutes see you can find solution and then either way.
Come on back and I'll show you my solutions.
I pulled the video give it a shot and then come back
and welcome back.
OK.
So right now we have this label and the label if we look on the record as a rotation.
If I mouse over it wrecked rotation.
This is the rotation around a pivot in degrees of some.
So we can do is in physics process in the same thing about is that if it's the sky is we can say disguised
label dot rect rotation and then how do we set this what's going to equal to whatever our rotation and
degrees isn't
so we're taking our rotation degrees and we're just inverting it.
Right.
So if we are 90 degrees then subtract 90 degrees.
Let's take a look at how that works
and there it is.
It's working just fine.
All right one more thing I want to do.
We need to limit the amount of lives we have.
So first thing let's go back up.
Here is what's make a little bit of space here.
Export variable number of disguises disguises.
Yes number of fish guises.
Oh my goodness.
Number of disguises is three some of the three disguises.
We can tweak that nice and easily because it's an export variable so look here's our fancy export variables.
Nice and easy to play with.
OK.
Let's go to toggle disguise.
Now at the moment if you're disguise reveal otherwise disguise.
Let's change that and say Elif number of disguises is greater than zero.
You have more than zero moles or disguises go to disguises which means when you disguise.
We're going to have to change that.
So let's change right here.
Number of disguises negative equals 1.
Subtract one from the number of disguises.
Let's just try that works.
So one disguise to disguise three disguise.
No more disguise it's awesome.
Look at that.
We've added a whole bunch of risk and UI elements to our disguises.
Which means they now serve a gameplay purpose.
It's now risky for them to do it which means that the players will have to decide how many times I can
use them as yet there's no onscreen indication to how many guys you have going to work on the next video.
Meanwhile in this video we've displayed a set amount of digits in a string using pad decimals which
is awesome.
We're making a risk match reward.
I've capitalized them because they're serious concepts in the gameplay.
And we've added a cost to using a disguise.
You can move much slower.
Awesome stuff.
And I'll see you in the next video.