Hello lovely God people on welcome to finishing food fight which is a big deal because it's our last
project of the course.
We've done quite in advance stuff so far in this video.
We're going to create a start screen with an exclamation point because I'm excited.
We're going to put music in with another explicit exclamation point which is now getting hard to say.
And we can add more level details and then we're going to celebrate.
Let's get right to it.
I want a scene that we start with.
We did heist mice as we put that splash screen in.
Same deal.
So put in a new screen and going to use the same viewport idea the viewport container we did with the
other screens the game over in the victory screen.
So let's start with a simple control note.
And I'm gonna call this splash screen.
It feels like gardening.
Technically is not a splash screen into a screen.
A splash green is the screen that comes up before you do anything so interesting.
And I want to make that fall rectangle.
That's give them ankit Full rectangles as well.
And this is going to need a background so let's give the contract.
And again that's going to be full rectangle but it's going to be black.
I'm going to make this one pure black.
You're black.
I do wop you're black.
I can change it later.
Dont over think it.
It's fine.
I want everything here in the centre so let's go with a scented container.
Done a few times now so it's getting a little bit easier right.
Nice full screen.
And within that I want food fight round up here and then a subtitle the viewport and a couple of buttons.
So let's do that.
Let's start with the V box container.
And within that I mean put a label at this point I don't remember what I should have in the beginning.
Putting a theme in.
Let's load the theme back up to the top theme load theme.
Put it in scenes default thing.
Fantastic.
Let's call this food fight.
Awesome.
Nother label.
And this was for the music.
Now if you might remember that the music was a Creative Commons attribution licence only to people who
it's by.
So let's go look at who music's by just in case you've forgotten music by metter regarding the copy
that again.
And I haven't included all the tracks.
If you want to I can link to this page again so it'll be up here in the available which you call them
the downloadable resources the available resources and go through this reading nice soundtrack.
And I'm going to put music by and place that.
All right so these two I think want to be aligned to the centre and I'm going to change the font sizes
here.
So label too.
Let's give it your start label one.
Custom fonts.
Going to make a new dynamic font.
Click on that.
Good a font and load in.
Go back up a level fonts.
Kenny bold and let's make you 14.
ISOM big oh that's very dramatic isn't it.
And then too.
You know I go down a little bit with this one.
Maybe I think this is a 20 can't remember.
Let's take a look.
So down to custom fonts load in a new dynamic font.
And just do the exact same thing.
So front load can have old settings 20.
That's what it was before isn't it 15.
Maybe you know what I'm trying to tweak this before I see the full thing but that's a good start.
Next I want a viewport container.
So let's put in a viewport container.
That's me a child of the box container.
And I would put something in here so it's got to have a viewport and the viewport it's going to have
to have some sort of camera which will be active.
The someone to make this current and learn from my mistakes.
Right now this has no size to it.
I will fix that in a moment or put in a couple more buttons.
It's up to viewport container and put in a grid container.
Basically I'm remaking what I did with the other seats.
I could have copy and paste but I didn't want to mix a little differently.
And within that let's change the columns have two columns labelled button label button.
Now start with the label.
And then our play and then a button.
And let's give that a minimum size so wrecked minimum size 30 by 30 k grid container.
I think everything should be in the centre here shouldn't it.
So you know what.
We are back to the view full container of goodness sent to contain and put the grid container within
that March more like a grid container you get another label.
And you should quit.
And then another button.
And that's looking good.
OK.
I'm not a bully Texan these buttons but that's looking pretty solid.
Now the viewport container needs to be bigger.
You know I'm going to go look at the size that I put the other one on the keep this reasonably consistent.
So let's go over to scenes.
Gooey game over and cut up my game over screen.
The open container has a size of three hundred by 300 of so put container to give you a size of 300
by 300.
Now I come out of that scene and go back in it's reduced itself.
I should have put a mint size 300 by 300.
There we go.
Much more like it.
All right.
Viewport.
You are going to have a transparent background.
That's important.
Before I go any further I'm a save this scene scenes Gooly and I put it right here.
Know new folder intro's screen and put it right in there.
And that has now saved.
Awesome result doing that.
Now is I mean let's change what my default scene is going to start with this.
Let's get project settings run.
And I will go find that cilice that file scenes gooey intro scene into a screen.
Done.
Awesome.
So this is now where we'll start for best play.
This is our game now.
Boom boom boom.
These buttons aren't connected.
They don't do anything.
Let's give it some functionality.
Let's put a script on interest screen and that can live in the Scripps folder.
It's going to be called interest greenlight Judy and it's done.
And once that's done I can stuck in its these buttons rename these buttons so it's a little easier to
see a script play button and quit button and let's connect them a signal so node pressed connect can
connect it to the interest screen.
There it is.
And quits the same thing.
So select pressed connect connect to the into a screen and connect.
Awesome.
Quit is probably easier so get tree don't quit.
And on play button I want get tree dot change scene.
And I think we should probably get a customization when you think.
I think customization is a good place to go.
Now if you wanted you could put another button in right so you could go straight into that where you
get to it you go straight into the game or you can customize or you can quit.
So that's absolutely doable.
Just had to put actual buttons in.
But for now I'm gonna go straight into customization.
So.
Well as in scripts that's what it was chase scene.
And I want customization.
Character customization.
TLC an awesome that there.
Let's see if my game runs.
That's how we do a press quit.
Quit works fine.
Secondly thing I do get to go in here and press play.
Play works great.
Let's pick Frey.
I've still got a print going on for debugging.
Awesome.
There he is.
Fantastic.
I should really get rid of that friction.
Let's do that.
Really quickly there's going to be an customization So in my script folder a customer character customization
had a look for print.
Where does it put you where you are.
There was a debugging between videos.
I apologize for that and clear that and pretend we never saw it it didn't happen.
You can't prove a thing.
Fantastic.
Okay now put something in here.
And at this point I'd like to challenge you now.
Draw on any of the things we've learned throughout the course and cast your mind back.
We've covered quite a lot from the early days of Luni lips through Hoppy days through heiss meisters
through kudu kick about into food fight.
Make this as fancy or as simple as you like.
So what I'd like you to do is make your start screen.
Customize it.
You want that view pull container.
Do you change the colours.
Is the button theme.
Remember to go to start game and equip button.
If you want you could put in other stuff as well maybe a character customization maybe a level selected
you get more than one level but really go to town this make it your game.
Suppose the video customize your screen and when you're ready come back and our customize my.
And welcome back.
Okay I want a screen full of food flying towards the user.
Some days I won't go into my viewport.
I'm going to create a particle node so particle as they are.
And I got an error message was this error.
You need to put something in.
OK so what I'm thinking is one for each type of food.
While food is in scenes ammo models there it is.
So all of these sunlike one particle for each one of these.
So as you can see from this error message it's saying that we need a drop pass.
Start with a draw pass and then put my mention here.
Start with the burger boom there's a burger and then move it to snap on it.
One two three four five three maybe.
Take a look at that until it starts running it's going to be hard to see.
Start with a new particle material and now it's doing stuff.
Awesome.
These were some lights in here that I so in my view portlaoise Put in a couple of lights I'm thinking
and onlly light as a nice nice and right and let's put you over to the side and with a brightness and
energy of 4.
Wait you break three and you know what.
Let's make you orange feeling this orange and teal and we make a new light.
And this one is going to live over here and it's going to be teale.
So with an energy of four.
And let's bring you over that way a little more.
I may be slightly behind the particles.
Okay come.
How does that look.
Dramatic but maybe not quite yet.
Now I want to fiddle with these parameters.
I didn't go back to my particles and I'm going to first change how many see I was it 24.
Lots of them but I want them lasting quite a while so let's have them lasting for two seconds.
I think that's a decent start like a so everything else I need to do is going to be in this part or
material so I'm going to get a process matures.
Hit particle material and the most important things in the under gravity.
So right now I see Gravity is at minus nine point eight.
I wasn't going up.
Now what do I like this little lot.
Is it going to take this deep.
Ha ha gay wrong rotation.
So let's go back to the previous thing I should have done this time been.
But I was too excited on the x axis.
I'm rotating you by 90 degrees.
OK.
See how that looks in camera.
Cane not bad now now I think maybe put these a little bit smaller something back it was making me a
little bit noshes that's come in a preview.
Let's go back in to my.
Where do you go.
It's gone back in my part of course and scroll down to particle material.
And let's go for the top emission shape.
Point No no no no sphere airway go a sphere radius of one shot one up.
Now a line I want to align on the Y and rotate on the Y and that's going make them feel like they're
tumbling.
I'm going to play with these and spread the spread.
Forty five yeah.
Feels good.
One thing I might do though is slow these down shrink these down so how's are point to five feet.
Way too small.
Had zero point five feel.
Not bad OK.
And now let's just lift you up.
Move you that way.
OK.
Somebody call this burgers.
And you know what I'm actually going to make a subfolder for.
So that's make a note and call this particle.
And now I'm going to bring particles in to your bergholz antiparticles.
I'm going to duplicate it and call this one cookies and change the metaphor cookie.
So I go over here and change that mash.
We've changed that match.
Now this mash is a little bit big but that's okay.
And I'm just going to fast forward while I duplicate these.
OK.
We have everything in and you know what.
That's actually way too much stuff.
One hand is my grab all of these and move them further back.
Such as drag you out this way and see how that looks in camera.
Preview that.
That's kind of dramatic and scary is that that's your the looks like a TV.
Are you active.
You should be.
I'm not going to run again.
Don't see it when I see it because my view ports the wrong size of course is 300 by 300 straight out.
We've got lots of food.
It's actually too much food isn't it.
So let's go into any one of these particles and select all of them.
And I'm a switch for 24 to 12.
I'm a cat's going to sneeze in the background.
Less you caboodle.
She's going wild and running up and down the stairs by cat.
Awesome.
She's pretty excited by this interest group because let's face it that is pretty good.
I'm not sure why it's not showing here but that's fine.
Did she make this camera work.
I did.
You are current.
Fine.
Just be like that.
All right.
One more thing on it do I mean add some music to each of these songs.
So in every single scene I would put a music player let's put an audio stream player that's not 2D or
three auto play it and find some music so let's go get some music.
I put you on the sound effects didn't I.
I've got a handful of these over here.
I would actually have start with interlude got an auto plate.
Has that sound.
A little bit loud luscious.
Not bad.
I actually need to tell my speakers down.
OK.
Let's save that.
Let's go into the next scene.
So I'm going to go through these.
Now what I could do is have an audio string player as a singleton and then change it playing what seem
we're in.
But I'm feeling it this way it's having to do it this way.
I'll just go in to customization customization.
Seeing is also going to have a music class audio stream player.
You could just press enter could I.
And let's go to SFX which is back here.
And I think this was going to have intro like this one.
It sounds like this.
Yes very dramatic.
And again little out.
OK.
Now we've got game over.
We've got victory.
Let's start with the actual level segunda Scenes into levels.
Doo doo doo doo doo.
I mean put this in template.
All levels will have the same music.
If you don't like that you don't have to have it that's fine.
That's the wrong audio stream.
I wasn't paying attention.
Try that again audio stream player minus 10 seems to be what we're going with this.
By the way quick tips that I should have done earlier.
I'm going to sound effects.
And I'm going to add it to my favourites.
And now we're going to favourites.
It's right there.
A lot easier right.
OK.
Levels are going to have final battle.
Yes.
Get close.
That's close.
Make sure it's also play for that one.
And now I've got this one OK.
We got game over open so let's add in all your string player.
It's going to be game over right.
Let's put you at minus 10 and you're going to sound like this.
Very nice.
One more we need I need a victory scream.
Where are you.
So on to scenes.
Gooly interest screen victory screening.
An all your player.
You Stream player.
I am back to my favourites.
TAR should have been used that this entire time.
Should I give his game over again.
Pitcher minus 10.
OK.
We now have a game.
Let's see how that runs.
Nice comeback customization.
Losing Game 1 2.
3.
I surrender.
Really good stuff.
I get some more things I wanna do on the interest green and of playing quit.
It's really when I want it to say it it's less customizes a bit more.
Let's fight with food.
And on this one.
I have reconsidered.
Get Me Out Of Here.
Wait too long.
Was it put Get Me Out Of Here.
And you know what I want to align the text of the right sort of a grid container a great container of
my label a line up right there.
Awesome Now you Centre.
You should be centred not centred way not centred.
I'm going to put my grid container sentiment there and I'm gonna put the viewport as a centre to that
sort of container.
You will do a full rectangle when I leave and come back.
You should be much better.
OK fine.
Finally level 1 has some gaps in it so I'm going to fix those gaps really quickly.
I opened my waltzing and she'll copy some of these and fast forward while I do.
So here we go.
And there it is.
Moved the spawn is back I deleted the pieces we are using.
I just put those walls in and that's a level that looks like a real game.
One more thing I'm going to do is I'm handling this table.
This has been bugging me for a few videos now.
Someone to take this table this chair and just drag them over to this wall was just making a bit more
of an open space.
And you know what you guys.
You provide way too much cover.
So let's just take you like so.
Moving out of the way the door.
And you.
This area.
I'm going back here a bit ago.
We think of that.
I think that looks pretty pretty shiny.
I think this is cause for celebration.
And that brings us to the end of this video in this video we're finished.
Food fight with design the perfect arena to fight rebels with food.
And there's a lot you could do with he you could add more levels you can make progressively harder you
could add different enemy types.
Maybe change the colour of the robot some move in one way some of another.
Maybe they fired from amounts of food you could add more player types more customization you could add
a story you could put in an option menu and lots of different sound tracks are some which you could
do from here.
Either way please share what you've got.
Because I think at this stage you've got the skills to make something really incredible.
Meanwhile excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.