Hello lovely people.
And welcome back.
In this video we're going to start getting some actual gameplay going.
We got to learn how to get text from the player using the line in it note by the end of this video.
You can have this nice little text box here we can write stuff and then either press return or this
blue button and have the display text change.
So in this video we're going to cover some basic concepts how to get text from the player.
We're going to create a button so that the player can type things in and press enter or a term or they
can press an okay button.
Now theoretically we don't have to do this but I think it's a good habit to get into when people are
using online forms or anything like that.
They'll often just press enter but they might press a button to go forward.
This is expected behaviour.
Well it is only a game we want to keep an eye on that kind of expected behaviour.
The plan is to make the game as easy to play as possible once they're once connected.
We actually have to connect to the script.
So let's get started.
And here we are back in our game.
There's a nice 2D thing there's the blackboard.
Here's the story text area.
What do we need to do.
We need to grab text from the player.
So as you might expect I need a new node.
I'm going to put it as a child to the blackboard node.
I like having my you I elements in one place and this is part of the UI.
So I want to select blackboard and hip plus.
Now we have a couple of choices.
We have a node called text edit text and it is a text box that players can write into and you can press
return and it'll go to the next line.
So really good for long pieces of text right.
Anything with multiple lines paragraphs whatever else it may be.
If you're doing a big game and the players can keep a journal and you want to you want to write it they
want that's the note I would use.
However that's not the node I want for this.
I'm not expecting players to write that kind of text and I want the functionality of when they post
return it's going to send a signal.
So instead of text it I'm going to use the line at it.
Note that line at there it is.
Provides a single line string editing.
That's exactly what we want.
Let's rename this one to call it a text box.
Yeah that's good.
And let's make it a decent size.
Make sure my snap is on it.
Is that wide maybe and near the bottom.
And I'm going to leave a little bit of gap there.
You know what while I'm doing that.
Let's actually see a little fake margin like so.
So now when we're writing our texts in fact let's show you what that does when we're writing our text.
We're not pushing the text right up to the edge of the play a screen is a little bit of a gap as you
might expect later on the course I'll show you how to make real dynamic margins.
But this will define it.
Okay so I have this lovely text box and I'm sure the right text box in here when it looks like and let's
not put random capital Xian and again we have this font thing.
Now you probably remember how to do this.
You go down to custom font create your font drag it over.
But there's an easier way and one I would really recommend.
Let's go to the story text noad and go down to our custom fonts.
This little down arrow was going to hit copy.
Now back to a text box.
Got a custom fonts and paste.
Now this is really useful because any changes I make to the font here let's say I want to change the
font to 40 will change all instances of that font which means if I decide I want to change let's say
the actual font or the size or anything else the colour it'll work.
Every where I've used it.
Really nice piece of consistency.
So don't just like with variables don't make five or six or seven different instances of this font just
make one.
Let's get of the output box.
I don't need that.
And just so I can see what I'm doing.
I'm going to put this default text here.
Great to his story text his text box.
OK so we have our text box now.
I need to get whatever the player writes in here.
Into our script right now.
It does nothing.
Right.
Just the place where I can type.
To do this I'm going to use signals signals are a fundamental concept in God.
So let's spend a little time looking at them while I do some doodling.
So here we have got oh and here is a node.
This particular node is going to be our looney lips node and abalone lips node has a script.
Almost fits perfect.
And he's very cool.
So he has pink eyes and a lovely green hat.
Perfect.
Just what we need.
We have other notes here.
I'm doing all right Luni lips.
As we have in the script we also have a second note down here.
And this one is text box which as you will remember is a line at it note.
Now I could.
Give text box it's own script.
And then we could write some code to get them to set send receive variable switch up and that all worked
fine.
But it's a little bit clumsy.
So instead I'm going to use a signal every node has a list of things that it knows how to do.
And what's going to happen is I'm a tell it when this thing happens.
Get your cellphone and send a text to lunar eclipse.
When lonely lips gets this text.
It'll get a little notification that that has happened and it'll know to update the script.
OK.
So how do I make this happen.
Well I'm a click on text box and by the inspector you'll see things saying node.
Let's click on vote.
Here are the built in signals.
Now we can specify and create our own signals in script.
But right now we don't need to do that.
I don't care about the control ones or the canvas items or any of those.
What I care about is the line and it's specific ones and I want text entered text entered is going to
be triggered whenever we press return.
Now if you want to find out what these signals do the way to do that is to get into the script for you
press classes.
And type in the type of know you're looking up so let's say lying in it.
There it is.
And other signals you'll find what these signals do.
I don't want it when the text changes there's going to be every time a key is pressed.
That's not what we want in this case.
If we wanted something like a sound effect every time you pressed a key.
That's how we do that.
What I want is when you press key to do a thing you know close this with control w and I'm going to
link it so select text entered and hit connect.
Down here the bottom.
And obviously yes there are ways to create connections and signals during the script but we don't need
that yet.
Now you'll notice that text box is raided out is read out a word.
It's a word now.
Text Boxes read it out.
It makes no sense to send a signal from itself to itself.
You'll also notice that if I try to send a signal to an any random note it's a blackboard it's going
to give me an error message.
The easiest way to use a connection is to connect it to a node that has a script.
Now it's going to make a new function here.
We've currently got function ready and wants to make on text box text entered.
Now I can rename this to anything I want but for clarity I'm going to keep it as it is.
And here we are a brand new function.
So on ready it's going to do this.
And then a new function on text box text entered brackets new text this new text is going to be whatever
it is inside the text box.
When that happens so it automatically passes that information into this function.
So here we are.
And I want to make it do something just to check it's working.
Why don't we update the story text with whatever we've typed in we're just going to make it repeat back
what we say.
So blackboard.
Doree Text dot B code underscored text he calls or what does it want to equal the thing that's in the
text box.
By the way I'm not convinced we want to be using the baby code thing.
I don't see any value in it right now some as Switch it back to text.
Why use the code when we don't have to.
Well let's see if this works.
There once was a lonely pineapple whose brother was covered in jam.
He lived atop a ladder.
This poem was written by an excellent.
Not only do we have fully functional script I have written a hot new poem and am available for children's
parties of this teaching gig doesn't work out so the next thing I want to do is create additional usability.
It's all very well having this text box here but some people like to press a button.
So let's let them do that.
Always make it easy for people to want to play your game or if you release in commercial games.
Always make people want to give you money as you might expect.
This is a new node.
So back on my blackboard thing because I wanted to be a child of blackboard.
I want to keep everything in a nice easy defined place new node.
And we want a button.
Now we have a bunch of options here right we clearly don't need touch screen button because I'm not
making a mobile game and I don't have touchscreen enabled and here I am touching my screen right now.
Nothing is happening.
This is very exciting television.
The obvious choice would be button.
However I want to use text you button.
The reason I will use techy Biden is it's going to allow me to put a texture my own texture on the button
and I'm not going to have to rely on whatever is coded in currently for the theme for God.
So let's do a text about that.
And let's get off the signals list.
First thing I do is make it visible.
It's a texture button with no texture.
Not that interesting.
So here are textures and back to a graphics file on my normal texture.
I have the unpressed button.
And then pressed one.
I want this and all that's going to do is when the button is clicked.
It's going to change the texture.
Like so.
By the way these button textures are from Kenny.
I found his stuff on open game after all.
He also has his own website.
I'm going to put the links in there.
Kenny releases a bunch of open source free to use note licence.
Otherwise I can say this game assets mostly graphics some sounds as well really good way of practicing
your games but just getting your own indie project going.
You don't even have to credit him but I'm going to because I think it's great work.
I so this is not why this buttony cilice So make sure my snap is on.
And I'm going to put it down here.
Looks got much better place.
And you know what I'm going to give it a label and I'm gonna put the label as a child of texture.
So let's find out.
Rich tax label and the tax is going to say okay and I'm going to give it a font.
And I'm going to paste the font because that's the last thing I did.
Let's just make that nice MC by the way.
You notice how on this text box didn't appear in the top left.
That's because it's a child of texture button texture but as a child of blackboard texture button takes
its position and all of the other attributes from Blackboard rich text they bought a medical label.
Takes its position and everything else its scale everything else you might need from the location of
text button.
This is a really good thing to understand early on because otherwise you're going to move things and
think you've moved the wrong thing.
Let me put that in less confusing way.
If I move texture button it'll move all of its children with it right.
If I move back to the label it'll just move bottom label because it has no children.
Now imagine will making a 2D.
I don't know platform game scrolling game the 3D game I have animated sprites I can see the player.
I have a collision but shapes so that the game knows where the player is and I have the actual location
of the player which is how it's going to calculate where it is in the game.
I have several times moved the Sprite to the player thinking I am moving the player and then everything
goes wrong.
Okay so make sure you're moving the right thing.
If I want to make sure that I'm not moving the children I can select the parent and then press this
lock down button.
And what this means is I can only move the parent I can't move the children alone and you can see it
right here.
Great.
So we have a button that currently does nothing.
And I wanted to do something.
Well this is another signal.
So back to Saigon.
And I want Prest I don't want to button down because that's while the button is being held down I want
Okay the button has been pressed don't count how long for.
It's just been pressed and I'm going to connect it to the same script.
Now.
What do I want to happen here.
You might think I'm just going to copy what's in here but new text is not Whoops.
The new text is not going to work here.
See my debugger.
I'm getting errors and the reason I'm getting errors is I'm calling you an enemy Magus.
I'm calling an argument in this case new text and it didn't want one.
You see the line edit node text box comes with this method built in button pressed doesn't suck.
What I need to do is tell it when this is pressed.
Go grab that text.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to inside this function in only this function.
They give variable called new underscored text.
It looks familiar doesn't it.
But remember this variable only exists in this room.
It just happens to share a name and what is this variable.
Well it's whatever is in the text box.
So dollar sign or if before I get on the SQL node etc..
But I don't prefer dollar sign text box and it'll find it for me.
That's the one I want.
OK so what do I want to do here.
Now I can't just do equals because I'm going to set it.
So instead I want you don't get on the score text only to put brackets on that because this is actually
a method.
Then I need to call this function.
This function is on text box.
There it is text entered.
And I need to pass this variable from this function to here.
So what I'm doing is I'm saying if you press the button create a new variable and send it over here.
And this place is going oh I've just received this new variable.
If I'm not pressing the button I'm just pressing return then the signal is generating the same thing
so I'm circumventing the fact that the button can't do it.
Now this isn't that legible to me.
I would much rather put this about someone hynek the whole thing.
And I'm just gonna hold out and up arrow just logically for my own peace of mind.
I find that much easier to read.
So let's see if that worked.
Well that's like going to thing and press the button and there it is.
And now what ever I write.
Whether a press return
or press the okay button it will work.
However you know how saying make the behaviour expected.
Will we have unexpected behaviour.
Specifically I'm starting with a text box.
I need to clear that out and then when I enter it.
That text state and that's not expecting to happen so.
I would like you to clear whatever text is in the text box whenever we either pressed return or press
the okay button.
So pause the video and see if you can clear the context of text box.
Every time we enter a new text.
Okay.
Welcome back.
How could we do this.
Well there are a few ways but here's how I would do it.
The first thing I may do is say I don't need to be doing this twice right.
Because no matter how I get here I'm going to end up on this text box text entered function so whatever
I want to do I can just put here.
So my plan is once we've done this function here once we've set the story text the new one.
I'm now going to take the text box noseless to dollar blackboard text box there it is dumped and we've
done this before right.
Text equals and want set an empty string.
I'm also in my text box node.
Going to get rid of this bit as text box.
I don't have to do it this way.
I could also do that in my ready function.
So I could do it this way.
And really that's down to personal preference.
In fact for now all that's wrong isn't it.
Lots of text there we are at for now.
Why don't we do it this way so that when I'm looking at the two day view I can very easily see what
the font is.
But when I press play.
It's going to be empty and we should see this work well.
There it is.
Which brings us to this video in this video with learn how to use both line edit and texture button.
But more important we've learned how to connect and use signals and how to how to create and move between
functions.
So great work and the next video will take this a step further.
So see you then.