Hello you one forgotten to people in this video.
We're going to start showing text to the player now.
So far we've been looking a lot at how to use variables how to use arrays how to combine them all and
use a printout.
Right so we're going to print things in the output.
But that doesn't help us in game.
So in this video we start looking at ways we can display things to the player specifically we need to
look at how to import assets into gotto we don't want that weird blank gray screen that's just the default
background.
We want to show pretty things how do we get pretty things in game.
We've got to create a background texture.
When I say create a background texture I've provided you with a texture we're going to create it in
the game we're going to resize the games display or look at the options of how to do that.
And then we're gonna create a label node and update the label with our script.
So along with this video I provided the download which I have called and we take a look on I've called
it or download it right here looney lips GFA X and J if X is you show for graphics and if I open up
the zip file it's a folder called J effects that's graphics again.
So if hoping that you'll find a blackboard which is what an England we call a chalkboard two different
buttons it's actually one button one is pressed one is not pressed and a font called felt pen I'll provide
the links for all of those he can go look at them the buttons are from Kenny when he's allotted his
work he does great Creative Commons Work Creative Commons Zero's not actually open source but you can
use it even commercially without crediting him or paying him I'm going to credit him because he does
great work.
Okay so I have here this folder How do I import it into gotta.
First thing I do is I'm gonna open up the resource folder right the folder where the the actual project
is the easiest way to do this is to right click on it and do open in file manager.
Okay.
So I'm there now let's go back to this zip file so I'm going to minimize you and find the zip file which
for some reason I managed to close down how do I import this folder.
Well the first we do is I'm going to just copy it over.
I'm going to drag it equals a right click on it do you copy.
You could do control C control V.
I'm going to copy the graphics folder into here and I can close that.
All right so now we have a graphics folder.
How we got it to read it off.
I go again I don't have to.
It does it for me.
Anything that is in the resource folder that can be edited by Godwin or edited in Godot will automatically
import if I click the little dropdown for the graphics thing you'll see this stuff is in here.
Now later on when we start dealing with sounds in the future games specifically hoppy days we're going
to have to look at how to switch looping on and off we want some sound to loop in some not too.
Doesn't really matter with pictures but the principles go to the same and click on the asset we're going
to change.
We're going to import change what needs to happen with it and click report awesome.
So here we have our graphics.
Let's start by making a background to do that on a click on looney lips which remember is a control
node and an add a child to add a child.
I cannot press this button here at child node so this plus button or I can to control a little shortcut
shows up.
I almost never press controls on it do it just for fun.
I was pressed the button quite like shortcuts and what kind of node we want.
I mean we could go through all the controls and look for we don't have to know.
This one is going to be a texture specifically a texture rect control for drawing textures let's create
it and rename it.
So a double click on it and type in background is a nice human readable thing.
Now at the moment we've got this node with no information in it and you can see here this empty texture
I can left click on it load it and go find the texture or I could just drag a blackboard into the texture
and there it is.
And here we have a lovely background.
Now this blue box that's what's going to be rendered to the player.
You'll see the texture is much bigger.
So if I press play here is my textures really zoomed in and when I resize the window I'm not actually
resizing the display.
I would rather not resize in the blackboard.
It almost looks like I've cut a hole into my desktop and I'm widening and shortening the whole.
But what's the other size is the same size.
So let's look at how we can scale that with a display.
The first images on a hit expand this texture scales to fit it's bounding rectangle.
Let's switch that on.
OK.
And I want to press play it's teensy now.
Why didn't it happen here.
Well sometimes gotto doesn't refresh control elements that's anything with a user interface and a UI
element immediately an easy way to fix it.
It's open You seen and come back to it and you'll see it just refresh the display by going away coming
back I won't close that scene.
You don't actually need it and I need this to be the right size.
I want to click this layout button and offer all these different options here.
And if I click anchors and go to full rectangle what's it doing is saying okay I want you to measure
these four corners.
Well how do I know.
Click on View and go to show helpers.
And each of these green things shows you the anchor it's gonna be.
Now it's important to note the right other texture is not actually for the full screen.
So there it is.
And it's just measuring where these corners are.
That's not that useful.
So let's go back to layout and press full wrecked right.
Full rectangle the full display.
And now when I press play this display actually re sizes which is much cooler.
One more thing we can do is we could change the default size that this display.
If we go to project and go to project settings and scroll down to we find Windows on the display you
can see here the width and height.
So if you wanted you could go 10 80 by 800 for example press close and the default some very different
size one of us play.
It actually doesn't fit nicely onto my screen anymore so I'm going to put my back.
But if you want to change the default size you can you can also switch off re sizable.
What does that look like.
Well it means that the player can no longer drag the corners which might be what you want not what I
want but that's how you could do it.
You could go borderless and you can go full screen.
I'm not going to switch full screen on because it changes how my capture program in this case OBSS renders
recordings.
In other words I won't actually be able to record.
So only leave it alone as the defaults but that he can change those.
Okay.
So we have this beautiful background and I want to press play.
There's a lovely background that just gets in the way and all the Texas still here.
So let's put a new note.
I'm going to click on looney lips and I mean to add a new child and I'm gonna type in label which is
spelt with like that.
Why do I click on looney lips first because otherwise the label be a child of the background.
The label isn't a child of the background as a child of Looney lips a way you put your children actually
starts becoming quite important as your game gets bigger and as you can see right now it's just in this
little corner and I'm gonna write the words place hold a text we can see what's happening place holder
and I don't need that return and you'll notice a few things.
One this node takes up very little space to the font is wrong let's change the font first I'm going
to go down to custom font click it I don't need to enable at the moment I pick a font it'll do it anyway
but just for the look of the thing let's click it something click new dynamic font and then when I click
on the font all these extra options come up Firstly you'll notice by the way if I zoom in a text looks
like it's vanished it hasn't vanished the text is still there but we've just overwritten all the font
information there is no font so let's drag felt pen into font data and if I want to know the settings
and change the font size a strike 40 doesn't this nice some big zoom out a bit as looking pretty good
let's press play not bad now at the moment we're just in the top left so let's make this a little bit
better I'm going to again go to layout and I've set my anchors of the full rectangles I'm saying when
you resize check all four corners right don't just check the top left corner if I resize the bottom
right I want everything to resize got a layout and in all honesty full rect again however when a press
play I'm still not happy about how close placeholder text is to the edges let's give them margin so
let's get a margin just click here under control and I want to give it what's good I think 24 pixels
yes 24 pixels the left 24 from the top 24 from the right I don't mean that do I mean negative 24 and
probably negative 24 for the bottom and what this is going to do is it's going to make the text always
be 24 pixels no matter how big it is unless it can't fit.
Few more options we can look at while we're here to see you know what they are.
A line left and V Line top.
This is your horizontal alignment I can put it in the center or on the right or fill.
There's not enough text to fill it doesn't matter.
And V Line works the same way center bottom fill top.
I'm also gonna put auto wrap on I want the text to automatically wrap around and just to see what that
looks like if I make this really narrow boom look at that it automatically moves it we can also change
everything to uppercase such as put something in caps not gonna do that.
It's weird.
All right so this looks good.
How can I actually change what's written here.
How do I know how to change a script.
Let's go into our script and you know what.
I don't need it.
Instead I'm going to get a..
Get node is a function within G.D. script.
So if I hold control and click on it it'll open the documentation.
And this is part of a normal node so every single node everything can use this which is useful because
everything inherits from a node and what to do is get node and then as a string the path to the node
was that mean means I can click in here and just type the path or I can use the dropdown label.
There's a couple of things we can do to make this easier and I'll show you those in a second.
First let me not get myself too distracted and I want to know how do I change this text while I need
to know the property to do that.
I'm going to mouse over the word text and not touch anything.
And it has property text.
What that means is we get back into my script.
If I do dot and then the name of the property which here is text equals.
This is some text.
All right let's go back to 2D mode and just remind ourselves right now this has placeholder text when
I press play it's been updated by the script.
I know why hesitate on the word script.
I just did so we now know how to change this in code.
Couple of things you can do instead of doing get node label.
The first is if I don't want to type it off I'm not sure the spelling I don't know the path I can drag
it into the script which is awesome.
The other thing I can do is I can use a shortcut an alias I can use a dollar and then the name of the
node.
If I'm doing it this way I don't need to use strings.
I can use strings.
Doesn't really make a difference but I don't need to.
The only reason I would want to use strings is if for some reason there was a space in the node name
there shouldn't ever be a space in the node name because it's against the convention and I don't I'm
not gonna put these strings here because I don't need to.
I will point out that because we are using the default name label it's staying it's in this more colors
that there's a sort of lightly I think label is actually not a very useful name so I'm gonna change
this to display text.
What are we displaying to the player.
Well now label is wrong so let's use our nice dollar shortcut.
Display text is right there so it doesn't matter what type of note it is.
It knows that this is a label node and it knows that label nodes have a tax property.
So when I press play this is some text.
Also another thing you could do if you want extra credit is you could use a instead of a display text
we could change this to a different note.
I could have changed type and there there's another label called a rich text label.
We're not gonna be using this because it's just extra complexity that we don't really need.
But just to show you the difference if I open this it behaves very much like a label but it also has
Bebe code I can enable b b code and type B B code in here and the property instead of changing text
which is here would be B.B. code Tex.
You'll also notice all my fonts have reset.
That's because we now have access to bold italics and so on.
If I wanted to change the color or change certain wasn't too bold or underline them.
So the word the play gives me would be for instance bold and red.
I would set up a B.B. code thing.
I'm not going to do that so I'm going to right click on it and change the note back to label and just
check my font is still good.
It's not.
So it's got new dynamic font loaded in and drag it.
Kaboom.
Awesome and placeholder text has gone.
I was right.
Place holder text and list changed my settings to be 40 again.
Great.
He also notices a bunch of other options we can play with.
We could give it an outline color.
I'm not going to because it's a black background with white text giving an outline is just gonna get
fuzzy.
Extra spacing does really care about that but in all these different options and I encourage you to
explore play with it really get to know it all these things.
Okay so far so solid but what's happening is I'm pressing play very nicely changing the text up here
but everything that I need is down here so this is my challenge to you.
I'd like you to make better use of the label node tri to or try displaying the story and the prompts
together in this new display text this new label that we've just created so pulls the video.
Give that a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
Welcome back.
This is actually a lot simpler than it might sound so if I go into the script we've already solved this
problem in fact I can get rid of print entirely because I'm setting the text property to be a string.
And here we have a string that is plugging in strings from an array so all I need to do is go story
which split that percentage prompts and in fact I can just get rid of it entirely.
I will press control.
K It's going to come and tell the line and press play.
Once upon a time someone could someone called Yan hmm.
I didn't.
Who wanted you wrong I know what I did wrong when I changed the type it reset all of these.
So let's just do auto wrap and try that one more time we'll pretend that was good.
Once upon a time.
Look at this someone called Yan a banana flavored sandwich which made him feel all tingly inside.
It was a glorious day.
Look at that.
One more thing I'll points out in this script is when I'm changing the property here I'm changing the
property of a child node right looney lips lives up here and the display text is down here.
So we've actually just learned how to change the properties of a different node which is really good.
His fundamental skill that we'll be using a lot.
And that brings us to the end of the video in this video.
We've learned some really cool fundamental things how to create a background texture how to import that
texture into gotto how to change a know type and then how to change it back because I didn't want to
change anyway.
We've looked at how to resize the games display how to display text using a label node and how to change
the properties of a child node.
Really strong foundational stuff to use again and again and again.
So a really great start and now I will have to say is great stuff and I will see you in the next video.