Welcome back Gloria.
Good people.
Let's actually start making parts of Kuda kick about in this video.
We're going to make the pitch and to do that we're going to have to familiarize ourselves the controls
and some of the concepts will be using in 3-d.
The first thing we need to know is that the 3-d view is very different.
Right we have this nice grid thing in fact the way the grid works is still the.
But there's sort of a nice comforting blank slate of 2D.
We now have these card lines.
These are access.
Now we should talk about how that works in God.
Before we touch anything when you think about an axis in 2D in Godso we've got this very familiar idea
of the X and the Y and the one peculiarity we've got is that is that positive y is down not up.
So if God were not working like we would in basic geometry or mathematics we're working from the top
left of the screen.
And I think the rationale is that's where the computer draws from when it draws it scan lines very quickly
they'll draw from the top left.
But I'm just inferring that I could be wrong if we flip to 3-d then does the Z.
Why is there a Z the Y becomes a Z.
And that's can seem counterintuitive.
And the reason is this is the top view not the front for you.
If we look at the front view we give something a bit more familiar now and positive y is up positive
x is to the right.
Assuming that that's the front to make then a little less abstract to make it a little less abstract.
This is a transform widget.
Yes that's the technical term for a movie thing.
This is the transform widget from godda and I've put the x y and z in their colours or x y and z.
If you like it's up to you in their colours by the respective arrows you're now working environment
where the direction you're facing is all important in 2D.
That's not really an issue.
Right up is always the top of the screen.
But here we can position ourselves anywhere.
If we go into our scene the first middies hold the right mouse button and look around and fact you know
what.
I won't go into distraction free mode just holding right mouse button and moving around.
I am moving the camera.
While holding the right mouse button and I have to hold it down pressing w goes forward and escos back
and ayenda go left and right.
Just like you play a first person shooter.
Remember only when holding the right mouse button I let go the rounds my mouse button.
They don't do that if I want to hover up and down ease up and Q is down right so was just like fly up
fly down or swim up some down in a standard first person shooter while holding the right mouse button.
I can change how fast they are moving.
So I'm just scrolling up and down and that's changing a little run speed on the left while holding the
right mouse button.
I can also hold shift and then move at a sprint speed and that's dependent on how fast I've got the
movement speed set.
So those are the basics of movement.
It can be a little confusing at first but you get the hang of it very quickly.
All right so here we are and we're going to create a brand new scene.
So we've got this empty scene and we need a root node and nothing you'll notice is that the basic to
decode is called No 2D.
But the basic 3D node is called spatial.
Also we've got a new colour to deal with this nice terracotta colour.
Anything in that is a 3D specific node.
Remember anything in blue is to be specific and anything green is control or you I mean there's also
these white ones and a couple of purple pinky ones.
But right now would you be focussing on these.
And I'm going to make a pitch a pitch is going to be a mesh mesh is a 3-d object.
So let's make a brand new node and I type in meche instance there is a simple mash this instance into
a scene and create that.
And I can't see anything that's because I've got this meche instance but down here in the properties
it's set to now.
Well that's okay we can fix that.
Let's click on plane.
A plane is the simplest mesh.
It only exists really in two dimensions.
If I go down here it doesn't really have a Y.
Now I could have a transform which is where transform translation rotation to green scalers little difference
from 2D.
Don't worry it will come quite normal and I give a y of 10.
And you notice it's not actually going up.
The reason for this is the these plane crashes are just meant to be seen from one angle.
They are just there for backgrounds and so on.
They're also the easiest to texture right because the textures supplies evenly.
So they call the node pitch.
All right so what we have right now is this untaken a square by click on the mesh and then look here
material.
When I click on the spatial material not the shape of material we're not making a shader or making a
material that exists in space a special material.
And now we have this nice white matter.
I would click on that.
All right a whole bunch of options.
Let's take these very simply must go to run through the top few flags are little details we can tell.
So this is not late in the season is unshaded right.
Don't worry about shaving it just light it properly transparent this hasn't Alpher texture.
Not going to worry about the rest.
These For now parameters are some useful suffern for amateurs will look at later.
But when we need these albedo this is where the texture is applied.
If we go into graphics we've got this table top and you drag that into the texture and suddenly starts
looking like a game set.
I must say this texture.
Fact let's save the scene.
First let's save the scene.
So when I make a new folder called scenes I'm going to put the pitch as a scene in there and still on
the graphics folder because this particular material can be anywhere because I've defined it which isn't
going to be true later.
But for now it's true.
In this folder I'm going to save this material.
Somebody got this floppy disk.
And if you don't know what a floppy disk is ask your grandparents why click it and go save.
And I'm saving immaterial and just made that really clear a pitch dot material.
You see here it's one of a recognized file extensions and that's put it in scenes.
I really want it in scenes or doing graphics.
I wanna move it to graphics and if we want we can make a subfolder Russert finamore put this here.
Okay we now have a basic pitch.
Now the sizes don't work for me so I'm gonna go back up to the pitch it's after the main note and the
click on the mesh and you see you have got size now.
I made this texture so I'm aware of roughly what the proportions should be and I think they should be
around 20 on the X by.
Or should we say 15 or more why looks good to you.
Looks pretty good to me.
By the way you'll notice I'm dealing in 3D but this only has X and Y because technically a plane is
a two dimensional object is pretending to be 3-d.
Look what happens if I go underneath.
It's not showing.
Now if you need the texture to show underneath there are things you can do that so I can go to material
and parameters and I can go to coal mode which is where it is right there.
Right now it's going the back don't draw the back.
Not going to see I could disable that and no one to go underneath it'll show on if I don't really need
that because our cameras give me an a fixed position so mayors won't call the back and just save a little
bit of processing time.
And that is our pet when I move it up slightly to get rid the grid as a lovely woodgrain to it and work
for some goals here we can make a little bigger if we want but we can tweak that as we go.
But already we have a pitch.
In fact you now have what you need for this challenge.
I'd like you to take all just done and apply it to make a ball cridland you seen call it ball and make
it.
And just in case you get confused.
The key is the meche instance is going to create a mesh but it's not going to be a plane.
Figure out which one it is.
Make a ball and when you're happy with your results come back and show you how harder.
And Mark Mac OK.
So I definitely want a new scene because my ball is not part of the pitches can behave separately.
Some making you scene but I'm going to make this a mesh instance which is already selected is the last
thing we did so great and I'm gonna call it ball because it's a ball.
Under mash I'm going to give it a new sphere.
Look it's almost done.
I'd probably have to re size it a little later but that's okay because he's all innocent sees it's easier
to let's save that for now as ball.
And you know what let's give the material some a click on ammash an on premise of mesh amadu new spatial
material.
And let's see.
I want to put a texture.
I'm going to give it a nice yellow albino texture and that's looking pretty good.
And now I'm just going to save that some a Save As ball material.
And that's probably put that back in scene hasn't it.
Let's move that goes in to our graphics.
Look at that.
We have a ball and a sphere.
And if we got to see what looks like a pitch I can instance that in and there it is.
It is way bigger than the pictures in it but that's okay.
We can shrink that down so I'm going to go into the ball click on mesh.
And you know the radius is going to be zero point five.
Have a look.
Oh and height can be a point five to know the height of be one.
There it go because the radius is half the height of course at this and then go back in here a little
bit better I might even go small.
I might go zero point to five by zero point five.
I don't know why it lets you change the radius and the height.
Technically that's no longer a sphere it's a spheroid But you know whatever and there it is.
The ball is a pretty good size of this pitch.
Yes I know that the line isn't quite centred.
I'm sorry I made it by hand but if you want make you want extra go for it's very easy to make.
So on a day out there and move the ball from the pitch bookstand doesn't belong here and save it.
What I'm not going to do is try and run it one.
This is not the default scene.
And two we don't have a camera set up.
If I try and run it.
There's nothing to look at.
Right.
So I just set the pitch as the default scene.
That's OK.
We know how to change that but we're off to a really good start.
And that brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we have looked at creating a mesh instance creating material and the fundamentals of in
three dimensions.
We've also created a pitch and a ball which let's face it for a kick about game which if you don't or
that means it's just British slang word for an informal football match.
It's pretty important we kind of need those.
And before I send I really want encouraging share which you've got with the community put on the Facebook
the Forum page the discord I'm dying to see what you guys are making.
So what does your ball look like.
Is it a different texture different size.
Have you got someone's face on it.
I reasoned it got a logo.
You know a donkey show what you got because I'm really curious.
It's a great way to encourage yourself to learn.
Meanwhile excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.