Palo you brilliant got people in this video we're gonna make heist meisters more interesting to play.
We're gonna add some polish.
I don't have music playing throughout with this really nice piece of music.
I don't want to play it from the moment game loads all the way through.
We won't have a lobby.
A nice little splash screen that allows players to either play the level with the game and when we make
a tutorial level picks the tutorial and we want to game over screen either when they lose or when they
win.
Okay so let's get into it and this is looking pretty good so far.
Let's start with the easy one to start with background music.
Now if we go over the SFX and we get to the music we have this little stuff in the woods trying to open
that and just play it
nice and moody.
Let's just check those imported correctly when import we do want this looping.
Great.
Okay.
So how do we get this playing no matter what scene we're in.
Well we're going to do it and make a brand new scene.
And this is just a custom note and we just got the audio player audio stream player and I drag that
in and it does won't be particularly loud so it's a minus 10.
And we want it on auto playing and let's say that I I'm to save it on a branding photocopied MUSIC AND
I'M GONNA CALL THIS BACKGROUND MUSIC
Hey you know what.
Let's rename the actual note to background music.
Okay.
So we now have a note called background music.
How do we get that play.
We want this to load automatically and because it's also playing it doesn't need any kind of script
it's just gonna work to do that.
It's got a project and project settings.
We're gonna go to auto load.
We've already got the combination generator in.
So let's do it.
Same thing with the background music.
So let's just go to music.
Background music and attitude.
And now when we start the M
we have music does that change everything.
Okay.
So we've got music done.
We can take that off the list.
Now when I close my background music player and give us a small room we want to make a splash screen.
This is another brand new note and it's gonna be a user interface note and let's rename this to lobby.
It's not really a splash screen is it.
And we want there we go.
Now I'm thinking these are metal panel make it nice and big.
Welcome to heist meisters stock game or quit.
So let's get started by putting everything in the center of the screen.
There's gonna be a center container and I wanna make sure that it's right in the lobby here.
Let's change the anchors of the lobby to full racks to make sure it's always in the right place.
And this is gonna be full racks on anchors and full rectal positioning so everything will be the center
of the screen.
Okay so we have a center container.
Now I want a 9 patch rectangle.
As a child of center container so 9 patch and you'll notice it's got a size of a zero.
Now personally I think a size of 0 is too small so we give a minimum size of 400 on the X and Y.
Let's go to graphics then go into interface and go into PSG and down here we've got a bunch of metal
panels and I'm going to bring in my book.
And let's give it the right match margin so it's gonna be twelve on each side except it's not twelve
at the top here total is it.
So let's give 40 at the top.
And that's looking much cleaner.
Look at that as looking all kinds of awesome.
OK.
So that's all.
Nice.
My patch rectangle that's our background let's call it a background.
Now I want everything inside of that to be split vertically.
And that can be a V box container.
So the box container and let's give that nice full rectangle.
That's good.
But it's only going all the way to the edges.
That's got to margins and let's say twelve from the left.
Negative twelve on the right.
Negative twelve from the bottom.
And I want to go below this blue bar.
Let's say 30.
Look at that.
That's pretty good.
Okay it's time to add the theme so it's going to lobby and we're going to add our theme so load theme
and it's under whereas interface themes.
There goes.
So now inside the box container we can add a label and let's write welcome to and the reason I can't
see it is we got white on white.
That's no good.
So let's do a custom color of black.
Okay.
Little bit better we can align this to the center okay.
That's looking pretty good.
Welcome to have a reason to use ways I want high spices in the different sizes on a duplicate with control
D and chase this one to heist meisters and you know what I'm gonna make this nice big song I write it
like this heist my sis and might give this a custom font new dynamic font click on that let's load the
font in so load and under graphics on the interface under fonts we have thin and feature and use the
feature one and let's give this a much bigger size have a 30 about 40 48 years that's looking pretty
good OK.
So welcome to heist my says in nice big font and that's already looking pretty good.
Save my progress so far so let's save this and I think lobby can go into the levels because it is technically
at levels like this going in there now I want to have some buttons under here.
So back to my box container.
I'm going to use a grid box container.
We've looked at a smart grid container.
We've looked a grid containers.
When we did that the panels and this one I just want to button says have two buttons and right off the
bat you can notice this is really quite white.
It might be too white.
We could fix that for now.
Let's give us a button and that button has no sides.
Let's change that.
How about 24 by 24.
It's probably a little bit small isn't it so let's try 32 by 32.
And you know this is way off the side here.
That's OK.
We can fix that.
Let's go back to the box container and add a center container and drag the grid container to be a child
of the said center container.
And I'd just like to make sure that my minimum size 32 by 32.
So now that button is going to draw.
OK.
So we have a button.
Let's give it a label so we're adding a label and we will need to custom color black for this.
Let's do start.
Mission pretty good.
Let's take both of those and duplicate them.
We'll have to move the button down and this button can be called Quit game
now everything has gone a little bit skewed.
But if we leave and come back it'll it'll realign itself.
So don't worry too much about that.
One thing I don't like though is that these are quite close together.
I want some sort of separator.
Well here's a fun trick you can do the separators.
You'll notice we have these bars here and we've got a left center and our right.
I want to put some sort of split here.
So what I would do in the V box container.
I'm adding a new each box container and then we'll put it up above this center.
Let's make sure my shape the right ones are with the horizontal bars.
Try that again.
OK.
So underneath this each box container I'm going to add in a texture rect.
There he goes.
Let's start with the left duplicate that.
And this one's going to be the center and I'm the duplicate that and this was gonna be the right OK.
Clearly those don't work.
So let's go back to each box container and get a custom constraint a custom constraint of 0 looking
a lot better.
This center one needs to be a lot wider.
So let's give the minimum x all rethink.
One hundred two hundred yeah two hundred.
Good.
But you'll notice it's not a drawing it is.
Let's expand the texture now that expand needs to be checked on all three.
And let's start tweaking the sizes all three which means they're all going to vanish.
So all of them need on their rect a minimum size on the y of 12 medium size in the y of twelve and a
minimum size on the y of 12 the left and right need to actually be visible as well.
So let's give the M. x of twelve
and it's looking better.
Now one more thing I want the centered make sure we've got each x there.
Make sure you've got each box container selected.
Well that was hard to say.
And on the alignment just click center.
Look at that.
Okay.
Looking pretty solid but things are quite bunched up.
That's okay.
And the V box container custom constraints.
I want the separation to be a little bit bigger so let's say about there if we wanted to we could take
this H box container and rename it to split could duplicate it and just put one between the labels as
well.
That's right.
Where is it.
Right there.
Personally that might be a bit much for me.
But if you wanted to you could undo that.
And that's looking pretty solid.
Now let's make it actually work.
To do that we need to connect these buttons and to connect these buttons.
We're going to have to have a script so that's at a script to lobby and it's done.
Now let's rename our buttons.
We have a start button
and we have quick button which button.
Right.
And it's just why those in the stop button is going to be impressed.
Can you connect that to lobby and do the same thing with a button.
The best connects quit awesome.
So at this point it's nice and easy get tree dot change scene and we need to find that scene so let's
close this gap to levels that's my level one and I just need the string and only to load it.
It's expecting a string.
Now quick button isn't expecting a string so we get three dot quits and that's it.
However one tiny problem this lobby isn't going to appear at the start of the game.
Look at play the game.
There's no lobby.
How do I get it to do this.
We gonna go to project settings and go back to general and on the application you've got config and
you've got run.
And it's this one main scene right now is going to level one.
Let's change that main scene.
You go to lobby and let's press play and we've got buttons that are all connected through themes and
I can start my mission or I get a quick I look at that.
We now have a fancy pants looking start menu.
Okay.
So we can have our fancy pants start menu.
What about a victory screen or a losing screen.
So that's my challenge to you.
I would like you to add a victory screen.
Take the team we've got so far and tweak it to be the victory screen and then figure out how to load
that in when the player gets the exit.
Suppose the video give it a shot.
And when you're ready come on back and I'll show you my solution
and welcome back.
OK.
So let's make an instance of this.
Let's go to New inherited scene.
I'm going to inherit from lobby.
I'm going to call this one victory.
OK.
So we've got all of these and we can change the values.
What we can't do is actually delete stuff.
So maybe I don't want welcome too.
But what I can do is I can hide it and hide that.
And now on high spices we can say mission accomplished or victory is yours or yay.
I'm to say
you are victorious.
And we can leave.
Start mission and quick game the same.
Some say that probably with the right name on it.
So victory screen.
Much better save that in the same place.
And where's that coming in that's coming in with the exit.
So let's open up all these exits and just open up the base scene and instead of get Tre quit we're not
going to go.
Get tree dot change scene and I'm going to drag through the victory screen.
So let's just drop that in the and that should be everything we need.
Let's find out.
So here's my lobby.
Start the game.
I'm going to type in 9 0 7 4
9 0 7 for the camera for the past.
I'll just duck down here.
Excuse me everybody
la la la la.
Difficulty Level nice and low which is perfect for testing please this stage of testing.
Got stop and look.
Probably time to use a box.
Who wasn't paying attention.
My suspicion meter the problem with this remote
and you are victorious not game.
Quick look at that we've now added a bunch of Polish and I am really happy with that.
So in this video we've looked at using a scene as a singleton and with polish up the game.
Next thing I have to add is a tutorial to teach players how to play the game at which point we're pretty
much done.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.