Hello again, you.
Fantastic, got two people in this video going to finish off a tutorial and we to do that by giving
text to the player.
I wanna give a little bit of flavor text with some instructions on it.
So what do we need to do with our tutorial text on design this before I start coding it?
First thing I'm going to give the tutorial it's own gooey nice nine patch rectangle in the bottom center
of the screen.
Each stage of the tutorial has its own text.
So it's not just one big wall of text.
It's like little bullet points.
Right?
Here's the link piece of information you need right now.
I don't want to just give like a page full of instructions.
It's really great way to lose players by implication.
Moving onto the next stage will show the next piece of text.
Right.
It should just happen automatically.
And we're also gonna look at multi-line strings and gotta I'll explain that when we get to it.
I'm quite excited and kind of wanted to tease it.
Okay.
In together we go to Okmulgee Dorio level, so into the to do tutorial here and I want the gluey here.
I'm going to create the base of it here.
In this scene and then branch it out without using.
So what I want to do is making you canvas layer.
Can thus lay low.
Now, why am I making a canvas lair for Glee?
Well, the reason for that is canvas.
Leather means stick this to the rendering, to the camera effectively.
Right.
Not to the level, not to the world.
Stick it to my point of view.
If I'm making a gooey element, that's what I want.
And I'm this horrible gooey ants.
Give that a capital T at the beginning.
Great.
And now one, a safe brunches scene.
And I'm gonna put this in the interface.
There we go.
Because it's an interface item.
All right.
So now we're open that.
So here is actually Tauro Gooey.
And I'm going to make the base node followed just so it knows everything.
But beneath this is gooey.
I make that for Recht and I'm an anchor it to the bottom.
Right.
We've done this lots of times.
OK.
Within that I will put a nine patch right tackle nine patch recht seen these before.
So the graphics I get to interface, I'm not a Panji and I won't want these less glass pieces.
I'm going to use to do.
Would you go.
Glass panel.
Not glass panel.
Glass panel projection because it's got a really cool shape.
OK.
So how big do I want this.
I'm gonna say 600 wide by 900.
Not nine hundred twenty one ninety high.
I can't read my notes.
One ninety.
Hi.
Great.
OK.
Now we need to put the patch margins in.
I'd say 12 when each side has been working the past.
That's pretty good.
Maybe a little higher.
The top.
Now.
Twelvetrees.
Now, that storm was expected to be that easy.
OK, so layout's.
Well, first, I need to anchor this to the bottom.
Right.
And I move with the layout in bottom center, which is doo doo doo doo Santa bottom.
And I went right up against the bottom here.
So I'm going to give a margin.
Let's go to margins and let's say negative 12 from the bottom just to get a little bit of space.
OK.
So that is on my patch right tackle.
Let's add the themes.
I'm going to back the control and load in the theme and interface theme.
And the reason I'm doing that is we're about to add a label at the label.
I know what they should be as a child with my patch right tackle.
So we keep it size.
So label and I want this to be full rectangle, but I want some margins on this as well.
So it's a 12 for the left.
Twelve flat top negative.
Twelve from the right negative.
Twelve from the bottom.
So out label.
And let's just test it.
This is working.
There once was a lovely cucumber sandwich called heaven.
You see, now it's important to type in some test, some texts, test text who want to type in some
test text when you're making these things, because I need to know that this is set up correctly.
And one of these I can see right away is auto wrap is non.
So let's just make sure it's back and put the size in.
So full rectangle loop margins.
Well, 12 and negative 12, negative twelve.
And that's looking pretty good.
OK, a save that and head back to the tutorial and make sure it's visible so as much you taurel going.
Let's bring you all a little bit dupatta bidu.
Yeah.
And to run this scene, make this like a big hit tutorial.
OK, so that's not why I anchored correctly, is it?
Had it's overlapping suspicions.
Let's go take a quick look at it.
So if you're getting that error like I was, just make sure that you've laid it properly.
That's my fault.
I anchored to the bottom.
Right.
I should have.
I get it's a full rectangle.
It's just double check that looks in 20.
Turrill make this nice and big and lasting much better.
Now, there's possibly a bit why.
And I can make that narrow.
So do that now.
That's a five hundred wide.
I'm just gonna have to quickly go sente bottom again and bottom and that should be a little bit better.
This screen size.
Okay.
I can live on that.
I'd rather be playing full screen.
But anyway, I can live with that.
So with that done, let's now stop making these text things.
So I'm going to close Munchy Turrill.
And I want to bring in a bunch of text.
Now, we could do this as a Jason file.
We could do it as a bunch of variables over an array.
But I want to separate out the data from the code.
Right.
We want to keep this as separate as possible.
I want to make this easy to add more objective's the rest of it.
Done it here with our areas and our objective positions.
So I'll make a brand new organizing node.
And I'm in a call this objective messages.
I think it's about objective correctly.
Pretty short it.
And let's put you right there.
And you know what?
I don't know why I've got the gooey opened up.
Well, the door was.
Oh, that's OK.
That's looking much better.
So we want to bring in a bunch of messages.
And I want to have each node as a message, just like we did with Allouni lips.
So I'm going to add in a brand new basic node.
Alamdar, call this template, template, message, message, template.
Message.
Template.
Much better grammar.
Analysts save that branch as a scene.
And should that be an interface thing?
It isn't.
It facings.
Want to put it in the interface.
Let's open it now.
Every message template is going to have a very, very, very simple script.
Specifically.
That's got to have something called message, which to export out as a string.
Here's the thing.
When we were doing Looney LEPs, I was OK with that because most of what we're typing was just individual
problems.
Right.
But I can't type of big message in here.
Welcome to the game.
Like, that's really hard to do.
So we are going to start using a little bit of typed G.D. script.
I'm going to tell it what type of variables is.
It's a string.
It can only be a string.
OK.
So that's exactly the same.
Right.
So I click on this is just a string.
But I can do comma and then all in caps, and this is important.
All in caps.
Multi line.
Save that.
And I have a giant tax box, and I'm very happy with that.
So we have this message template that we can just instance in a bunch of times.
So I'm gonna go back to my tutorial thing and I'm going to call this welcome message.
So we need to welcome message.
What else we need a second look what you Turrill script.
We've got the welcome message.
We need another one for the door.
Always want to duplicate you.
And I'm going to call you double message.
So what happens when you get to the door?
And what happens when you get to do to do the night vision Marcus and night vision message?
And then we need one for when he gets the loot for the want to get to the loot.
So there's going to be loot.
Message.
And one more one you need for the exit.
So exit message.
OK, so now.
So now I've got nice multi-line string text boxes that I can write in.
So let's try.
Welcome.
You know what?
I don't want the output.
Oh, welcome.
Iced my stuff to your first day of training.
Please proceed to the.
Objective marker.
Using the.
W.
A.
S.
DTD, Tindouf.
Now I'm using WMD because that's my keyboard layout.
If you're using a different one.
Use a different one.
If I was releasing this commercially and I was letting players pick their own key bindings or create
their own key bindings, I wouldn't do it this way.
Right.
I would make a more complicated script that would look up the correct key parts.
But as I'm not doing that, this will work great.
OK, so there's my first message that's put a door message, click over here.
And I've been excellent.
Now we'll practice interacting with objects, stand close to the door and click on it with the mouse
and left.
Click on it.
Great.
Now we tend to introduce night vision, so he'll be working in the dark a lot, so we've provided you
with a t o u c a an.
Night vision module.
Activate or deactivate it with the.
Base, he was T.O., U.S.A..
That's all.
I've no idea what a fumble for yourself, but I'm quite popular.
So that's that one.
Now, when you lose one before you can leave.
You'll have to grab that suitcase.
Great.
No, I'm not typing great, I say get to the chopper next line.
Sorry, got carried away with the loot acquired.
That's it.
To say now that you the exit is unlocked, head to it.
Awesome.
So we now have these objective markets.
So how do we get in working?
Well, we've kind of done this already.
Have we right here in Update 2.0 position?
Well, we would have the objective number, and it's the same as we have over here in these messages.
So let's just make a new variable for the message.
Terrible message.
Equals objective.
Messages.
Get child.
Objective number.
And when we play the sound, let's also get our tutorial gooey.
Nine patch label, dot text equals message, dot message.
Why message, dot message?
Because that's the name of the string we use.
Right.
If I just write message, I'm going to give it the note.
I don't want the node.
I want the variable within that script.
So let's give it a shot.
So nice big screen tutorial.
Oh, nice.
OK.
Now this Texas too small.
We can fix that in a minute.
Look, it's changing.
Double click on the like a little.
My door's not looking.
OK.
We'll fix that in a moment.
First, I will make that Texel smaller.
So that's what you Turrill gooey.
And let's take a look at Tutee.
OK.
So we are currently using the theme.
And that's good.
But I might make a custom style or custom font.
Let's make a brand new dynamic font.
Click on it's.
So dynamic fault.
Thank you.
Look at.
And click on a font, load the font.
And let's say you're going to be a graphics interface fonts.
I'm going to use the fin font and settings, that's a little too small.
32 is way too big.
20 is pretty good.
18.
Yeah, I can live with that.
That's how that looks
tutorial.
Okay, that's a lot.
Let's look over here now.
I think the reason why this isn't working and after a little bit of debugging, I found the problem.
I don't it's right here in the control node.
I've made this control node cover the entire screen as an invisible piece of gooey.
I would make sure that the mouse knows to ignore it.
Otherwise, I'll never actually click the door.
So one more time, let's quickly check our tutorial.
She Doyel.
Welcome, Heise Meister to your first day of training.
Please proceed to the objective market using the W.
A.
S and D keys to move.
To do keys to move up.
That's good.
Excellent.
Now a practice interacting with objects that close the door preset.
That goes the door.
Fantastic.
You two can transmit to Ken.
La la la la la la.
We can leave it to grab that suitcase.
Awesome.
And now get the exit.
Look at that.
Excellent.
Now the door is a little dark.
This tutorials will do one more thing on this light right here, which is I think this one.
Excellent.
I want to go to Chateau.
Item Como's.
And I'm going to let it right everything, including the inside the doll.
It's called no occlusion.
So let's take a quick look.
And that door is now lit.
I feel pretty good about that.
And that is a great place to stop.
Has a little bit of tweaking still to go.
And I want to animate that.
That gooey message on the bottom.
But that is a working tutorial, so.
Excellent work.
And I'll see you in the next video.