Welcome back you delightful God people to this our lonely Let's wrap up.
And first it's like to hang out and I'm joined by my very old friend Ben.
Ben you look very old how I met her.
Shut up I'm very well thank you.
Yeah feet feeling young and sprightly so don't care.
All right.
What do we got for people what are we seeing in the looney lips.
Well first why don't we share some of the stuff that we've been seeing.
What do to give a particular shout out to find the right thing to do while you're giving a shout out.
I want to give a shout out so those of you who've been busiest on the forum so specifically Keith veltroni
to Bindy Richard to name just a few you guys have been super busy on our community game live TV site
so keep it up.
And also spend some time on discord.
I'm sure you do as well.
The live chat server.
And just one of a look really quickly over on Facebook.
Daniel McPherson who's done some fantastic work in all sections has taken lonely lips and turned it
into hang man up a very brief video of it right here.
Just take the basic concept add a couple of assets and just run with it which just goes to show what
you can do with this very key building block in lowney lips and really make all kinds of fun games.
So I'm really excited to get you guys off the ground learning lists of course is designed to just give
you the very basics of some aspects of the engine and the very basics of Judy's script as well.
I've been doing the C sharp conversion with you.
I hope those more advanced programs are you being getting on well with that and seeing the pros and
cons of C sharp.
That was a quick question of somebody about closing files.
Both applies to both Judy's script and C sharp.
When you do file duclos basically as soon as you can.
As soon as you've read the data file just close it you don't need to keep it open beyond that.
So just to put them to bed there's another site you should be closing them before you return function
otherwise the close doesn't happen so well you got it certainly before you close the function and finish
the function.
But also as soon as you finish writing that data into an instance variable whether you're putting it
into a local variable then you can close the files.
And I want to talk a little bit about what you can do with linae Lips.
I showed you you know his hangmen which is fantastic but if you think about it the key concepts we have
here allow you to make some really complicated games so putting things in Jason files and I've mentioned
this a few times in the videos that doesn't just have to be you know basic text input that can be dialogue.
It can be inventory it can be item descriptions can be lawfully a world if you're making a huge gain.
These are the building blocks you need.
So already we've got some key concepts in there.
So that's luly Lips and we've got some fun stuff happening in the next section.
Then you will talk a little bit about the next action.
Yeah just just before that there was one other thing that comes up a bit which is fine no vs. get no
daryl's get it he asked this so fine noad Looks for their descendants and it looks at them by name so
descendants of the current known by name Get know how does get known work and get noad will still find
ascendants if you want it to but get know you're actually giving it a path.
So instead of saying find a node that has the name Panda you'll saying go here and get a panda so it
can be a descendant but it can be in a completely different part the scenery and you'll set a dollar
symbol.
You say you use that over and judis Script is a shortcut to get node.
Yes because I can't be bothered writing get note every 10 seconds so.
So it's obviously a common function call.
Okay so sorry you were saying we're about to move on to our next section.
Really looking forward to seeing what you guys can do there.
I'll quick advice and this is true in all our courses is you've got to the end of the section before
you take a break.
Start the next section.
Yeah because that means psychologically you're not already be invested in it.
If you stop at the end of the section and take a little break it's much harder to get back into the
course.
So watch a video two from that and then take your break.
The first video is pretty short.
I think it's just getting the assets and planning everything together.
Get started and would love to see you do in that section.
Also I'll see you at the end of it guys and see you later.