Greetings glorious God people and welcome to alliteration day which is a thing I've just made up in
this video.
We want to add a lot of style to the loot.
What's the point of being a heist Meister if the loot doesn't look good so let's make a graphic user
interface for what for when we pick up the briefcase.
I was an oddly poetic moment wasn't it.
Okay.
What do we need to happen.
I'm picturing this the gooey element for the loot starts invisible.
I want context driven UI when we pick up that briefcase.
It's going to become visible and display an icon.
Now in my game at the moment I only have one piece of loot.
But theoretically we can have more so let's make something scalable.
I'm thinking item this is our friend here.
All right.
Let's get in game and get started.
First thing I do is open my gooey scene so scroll down to see and over this saying I want to put the
onion right here.
And I wanted to match.
So I wanna do is make a new nine patch rectangles child of going.
And call this Loopt container.
All right.
Let's give that it's background so I need to go into graphics in two.
Well I put it interface PRNG scroll down till I find the glass panels.
And I want the glass panel with the top right corner because that's going to match everything else I've
done.
So a glass panel call a top right.
And there it is.
And let's for now just move it manually like that tweak at the moment.
Alright let's recite it so we can see it we're doing and make the nine patch margins work.
So patch margin if memory serves these are all set to 12 pixels.
But I can double check that yeah everything's at 12 pixels and so are you.
Great.
So 12.
Awesome.
I'd like to match the height of suspicion's Let's do that.
I go over to suspicion go to size.
And you are too high or we have height.
But okay that's give you too high.
And got.
Slide her for a second there I think something just think Windows is backing up my hard drive.
The width will be fully there.
I can tweak that a minute.
OK.
We're off to a good start.
Let's get this in the right place.
I'm going to anchor it to the full screen or the full rectangle.
So lay out anchors full wrecked.
Let's put the lay out for now.
At bottom left.
And let's add our margins if memory serves we have 20 picks on margin on each side.
Just going to double check that.
Do do do do.
Yeah.
20.
Awesome.
So let's do 20 from the left.
20 from the bottom like a negative 20 from the bottom.
That's what I meant and.
Negative 122 in my case from the top.
And you're not full rectangle again.
OK.
So going to rank this the full rectangle and look at OK.
So this now matches I know we have a nice grid shape.
Doesn't have to be a grid shape.
You can move this for now.
This'll do.
Let's give it a label.
And I'm going to put the tax label as the list.
At least I would have clicked in the right box and I probably should put the theme in.
So let's go back to look container and load our theme.
Let's put the margins for that as well.
Memory serves.
It was 10 pixels each side.
So take a look.
You dont actually have the mountaineer 23.
So margin.
Twenty twenty three sounds like a weird number and from the left about 20 again.
Finally let's give it an item list so you know I'd like to list and I'm going to place that just here
and stretch it out.
In this particular case I'm not going to worry too much about the fact that I'm placing it manually.
I can tweak these later find it too.
But what we should do is check these sizes so first columns let's say you can have five items of loot
for now all the same column.
And let's shrink the icon again so I can scale zero point five.
I could do exactly what I've done here put a script on this item list which I'm going to rename by the
way so let's call this loot list.
I could get a script on loot list and run everything from there.
But remember I want this whole element to vanish which means I should probably put the script on the
linked container if I put the script on Luke container.
I can use visible true and false and it'll work for all the children.
If I just put on Luke list that's not the effect I want.
So let's make a new script for Luke contain.
And to put this in my scripts folder
and call it look container and it's good to go.
And the very first thing I want is a function for any jobs going to an asset visible to false and just
to check if it's working.
It's it play.
And you can't see it which is great because that's where wanted.
It seems weird creating a gooey element to immediately test that you can't see it but that's what we've
done now.
Let's make a new function call this collect.
And the very first going can happen is visible equals truth.
Because if that doesn't happen nothing else will matter.
Now if I had multiple forms of loot what I would do is pass an argument here with what they were.
But for now I've got a game that only uses briefcases.
I'm going to do that.
And when this runs what I'm going to do is bring up the item list.
Sorry Hoodless will have called it go go along you use ads icon item.
I don't want any text but if I did I could see she's an icon.
That ad I can lightsome before we go any further let's actually add the briefcase to the global script
on my global script and remember if you don't see it just head on down to Scripsit your file system.
And I want to make a brand new reference to a variable and put it right here though sprite's call it
variable briefcase sprite's.
And here's a trick that I learnt from kids can code on YouTube who just fantastic tutorials and got
a you should absolutely check his stuff but I don't know you could do this and it's awesome.
If we go down to our graphics folder and go to loot and drag the suitcase look at that.
It's copied the path over which is awesome.
That saves a lot of time.
So I'm going to save that back it's a container.
We need to add this.
Let's check what an item icon needs.
Some individual control a click on it.
You need the icon and if it's selectable or just added the icon so global dot briefcase Sprite and is
it's like double no.
All right we're almost good to go.
The one thing we need to do is make sure we actually call this function which is my charge fee.
I'd like you to make the loot gooey actually appear so call the Collect loot function when the player
picks up a briefcase just like the last few challenges.
There are multiple ways you could solve this.
So pause the video will come up with the one that you're happiest with and when you come back I'll show
you my solution.
And we'll come back.
I want to use a group so I'm up a container in two it's ungroup of fact I'm going use the interface
group which were already using double check that spelt that right.
But players do do do well using interface.
Yes I'm using interface gret So you're part of the interface group.
The next thing to do is call it as part of the Collect briefcase.
So right at the top here.
I'm going to actually know what this does after the node comes in let's get tree call group.
It's not auto complete because I'm not in the right scene.
That's fine and we want to call interface and we want to call collect briefcase.
I should probably rename that to collect loot.
It should actually collect Loopt not collect briefcase.
Let's change that back to collect loot.
And if I had multiple forms of loot that I wanted to collect I would put the argument in here called
briefcase but I don't so I'm not going to know that should be everything we need.
Now you'll notice by the way that I'm using interface's group again an interface is being used here
for night vision.
What's going to happen if I call a method to a group and it doesn't have it.
So for example the briefcase doesn't have night vision mode.
It doesn't have dark vision mode.
The gooey or rather the vision mode.
No one ever hear this.
What do you call this.
I've got the name of it.
It's a canvas module that's what I say canvas modulate.
There it is doesn't have access to this method.
What's going to happen.
And the answer is nothing.
It'll call a method to the group.
And if an individual member of the group doesn't have that method it'll just ignore it.
The great thing is now we can have groups that do different things and just listen for certain call
the bad news is if you miss spell the group name God I won't tell you.
So you don't know if I've misspelled the name or if my function isn't working.
So double check before we test it and I move my briefcase over to where I can actually get to it so
let's get the briefcase good movement mode and put it here.
I don't really want to run all the way across the map just to test this is working.
Let's find out if it fits.
Here I am again and I crashed.
Why I crash.
Because once again I've forgotten that this is a strength not an object and I should have loaded this
in.
I don't know why.
But this is a mistake I make all the time.
Let's try this one more time.
Do you do perfect.
I have a loot that needs to be a little bit smaller but that's fine I can do that and head over here.
You have a briefcase.
Fantastic.
All right.
Let's tweak the size of that so back to the gooey scene.
Back to my loot list.
Head down to Icon you're not zero point five user point two flightless you have that looks.
We could also use a fixed icon size if we want.
That looks good.
And you have a briefcase.
Phenomenal.
And that brings us to the end of this video.
In this video we're pretty much good to go.
Our game is almost feature complete the next few things we're doing to me by adding polish and expanding
the game to make a more scalable.
But right now you have enough to make a compelling level.
So that's what I'd like you to do.
Share your level put in as many doors as you want.
Vary the size of combinations put it lots of fun camera positions.
Make this a challenge for the player and I'd love to see what you come up with.
Meanwhile excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.