Welcome back.
Wonderful God the people who are wonderful in this video that take things a step further.
We've got a simple left and right moving Sprite.
Let's change that for an animated sprite in this video.
We're going to make money not just move but run.
So do we need to do it.
Well the first thing to do is we have this Sprite here and I don't want it.
Two things we could do we could right click on it and you change type and then pick an animated Sprite.
However it's not going to rename it.
And we have to go in and rename it so instead of that just delete this note entirely.
And we're going to create a new child node animated sprite.
I want to put it right here.
Cook got an error and the error is there are no Sprite frames.
So we have an animated Sprite and we can't do is just drag our.
Where Well you go.
Money ready.
There we go.
We can't just drag it here so we make new Sprite frames and click on the Sprite frames and now we have
our Sprite frame animation.
First thing I do is I want change the word default to Idol when I'm not going to use capitals like that
and just do all lowercase as a good habit hit it too.
And I'm just going to move my money stand over here and let's take a look.
And the collisions should still fit because the same frame are used earlier but I'm also do is put money
ready right here.
A quick Idol press playing hard look we have an animated Sprite.
Fantastic.
I am noticing that the collision is going into the floor a little bit.
There shouldn't be too bad.
We go back into our Sprite player and we can slow things down.
So let's say I want this are two frames a second.
Maybe 10 flavours that are.
I'm quite liking three frames a second.
That feels good to me.
There's also a loop on and off so it just it wants then stop.
It will keep going while I'm at it.
I'm just stuck at running for now so I can see what I'm doing.
Let's add in a few more animations when we want to make a run.
So back into the Sprite frames and let's make a new animation.
And this was a record run.
Let's see.
I want one you walk one and Bunny walk two.
It's going to loop and it's going to loop at.
Well I'll do the last one at three.
And let's see that running.
Whoops wrong thing.
Instead of play run and I want it to run oh maybe it's a little slow.
I think I might actually want a little faster.
So see you at five every second.
Let's see you at 10 frames a second.
As you come tempting you know what I'll put it there.
Although it's seven they're not 100.
Not a hundred are seven much more.
Okay.
So here we have a very simple animated Sprite.
I'm going to put in a few more just to get them in.
Let's do a couple more on it because we will at some point get a jump we may as well do it now.
And jump is it could be a very simple jump.
One frame doesn't let me do this and let's do hurt.
Or animations.
Now we need to do is switch between them.
So back to the script.
OK.
So how do we actually get the animated Sprite player to work animated sprites.
There it is.
Don't play.
And what's it going to play.
It's going to play animations.
So in this case it's going to play run.
I think we called it and we can just duplicate that and move it down here and down here with a playing
animator Sprite clay.
And does this work have that made a sprite move.
So does Bonnie look at that.
Are we here let's take a quick look at the animated Sprite note sup.
We have the actual frames that's playing with the find our own which animation we're playing right now
would sticking with Idol is it playing.
Sure.
Which frame are we on.
Easy.
Is it sent it nice and simple.
Do you want the Sprite to generate at the zero point of the player or do you want to do it from the
corner offset.
Do you want it off to the side or above a blow flip horizontal and vertical horizontal just flips it
on the x axis and flip vertical on the vertical axis which in fact brings me to the challenge because
you'll notice that when Bunny runs loops as you press play you'll notice that when Bunny runs running
right is fine but running left.
But he's moonwalking Bunny isn't facing the right direction.
I'd like you to make bunny face the right way switch which way Bunny is facing the pending the direction.
Now we've actually look to something so he might look at Flip H.
Pause the video when you come back I'll show you my solution.
So how do I make that work.
Well we can animated sprites just before.
Flip on a Scott H.
And remember if you're not sure what that is.
You can just go to the Sprite node and mouse over the property you need and its property.
Flip H all lowercase.
OK so when you moving right we don't want you to reverse.
I wanted that to be false.
Do NOT flip let's duplicate that and move that down here.
And when you're running left I want it to be true.
Let's see if that works.
Phenomenal.
Now you will notice that the flower is moving left and right.
So what I can do is just when you're not moving and made a sprite dart's faculties doing flips underscore
H equals false.
Now that flower is always moving in the right side.
And there we have it.
Bunny can run left and right or stand still and catch its breath.
Perfect.
We then set up animations so he can jump and be hurt later.
So that is looking really good.
We're already there.
So look in this video.
Nice is short.
We've learned how to set up an animated Sprite how to call those animations in script and how to use
flip H and indeed flip the.
Which is great because it means you don't have to make art assets for every single direction you just
have to make it for half of them.
Great work.
Now there is one thing that I'm not too happy about which going to fix later on just to give you a heads
up.
Right now the play script is doing everything the player can do it's handling movement and animation.
Later on we're going to move the animation out of the script and put it into animated playlists have
the animation deal with animation and the player just deals player movement.
That's a little later.
But just a heads up.
We don't want this getting too crowded.
In fact we're going to do a lot of refactoring the next few years.
If you use different art assets and you've got them animating differently or you just decided to tweak
the sprites and do something else I'd love to see them share them the forums and the discord and any
other community site you like maybe the Facebook group.
And either way I see on the next video.