Hello again like for God to be born in this video we're gonna make a character and a play a scene.
Now what we have to do is we have a simple character scene from which the player characters and non
player characters will inherit.
Now this was going be quite simple and we're not going to worry about the non player character just
yet.
Over the course of this section these scripts and scenes for characters play characters non play characters
are going over Volve quite dramatically but with a start off very simply.
So let's start off very simply here we are back in god.
There's a lovely scene with that brown floor and our Brown table and everything's Brown.
I'm actually regretting making the ambient light brown So let's change that why look at it let's go
to different environment and switch this back to a nice blue or at least be a little bit of contrast
to save that.
That's not what I meant to be doing that what I meant to be doing is making a new scene.
Here's a new scene.
And I don't have a bass note of a kinematic body I would call this character before I go any further
let's say that in our scenes and the characters just in here that's character doctor.
Yes this is one that everything would inherit from now this won't have its own mesh.
But I'm reporting for now so I can get a sense of scale.
So let's do that let's put in a measured sense and make it nice and easy.
Let's make a new cube.
This cube is going to be roughly people shapes so say zero point five meters on the x 2 meters on a
Y and zero point five on lizzette.
And I just realized I typed zero point six because I can maths.
Great.
So here is something that is roughly the size of a person.
Now I'm doing this primarily because the models we've got for the male and female are very different
scales we're going to need to get the right scale.
It's a bit of a spoiler this motion sense won't stay but it gives us a good working environment so let's
move the character up.
Where should I remove the character his origin or their origin is in the right place but I really want
the origin the middle the person that can like it where the feet is.
So let's get a motion sense and just move that up so transform and we need to translate it up by one
metre on the Z.
And now the origin would be at the feet.
That seems to make more sense to me if you'd rather have the origin the middle the person you can.
We're going to be putting gravity into the game so it will sort itself out.
But I like it there or at more important and that is really the collision shape which one really glad
that we have a meshed work with.
And I can see it as like a collision issue.
And this collision shape is going to be a capsule is that as you might remember from keep talking about
is traditional when you're dealing with any kind of collision that isn't very very precise.
It doesn't matter if you know it's an arm or a leg or a head that gets hit.
Just the character katsulas great shape.
Okay so this galician Shape is clearly wrong because that's where it's going to collide.
So let's change that one and rotate on the X by 90 degrees and I'm going to move it up on the Z by 1
meter.
Alright it's in roughly the right place when that's in exactly the right place but it's clearly the
wrong size.
So in to the kassell shape and my radius is going to be zero point five.
And that is pretty close to perfect.
Now we can tweak it when we get some actual measures in there but let's say that that is unu characters.
We have a character see.
Now if you look in models under players you'll see that I've given you the original Collider files the
human and woman.
I'm not entirely convinced that naming one human and the other woman is the best naming convention in
the world.
But I suspect that when catalysis made these he made them a little bit far apart.
They don't follow the same conventions which is why we're not going to be using them.
I show you what I mean if we open human There's new inherited one he's a giant.
But more importantly his skeleton is called human immature immature as what blender calls the skeleton
great so we'll open it woman.
Yay.
Animated woman nodding you inherited.
And how much is a different name.
That means that every single animation that these characters come with will need to manually renamed
right because this note here the head animation points to human armature head at and the woman it points
to armature ahead.
That means that you would have to go through every single track of every single animation and change
them.
You don't want to do that.
I've done it for you.
It took a while but we won't be using these files.
These are here just in case anything goes wrong.
Instead head over to scenes.
And over in characters you'll see other players there's a good armatures.
And here I've saved the armature from M and F.
Male and Female again.
And these have been renamed.
So this one is mash.
This one is mash.
These are identical so we can drop them in to the same scene and they'll share the same frames and the
animations have all been renamed to the spine to bone 3 I don't know why the Swan has bones said but
that's fine.
One more thing I want to point how are they talking about skeletons amateur as a skeleton note.
It's just been named by Blender's that's fine.
How do we know how to move the MASH.
And the reason we know is one this is how these skulls and was up in blender but two under mash you'll
see right here a skeleton and it's pointing at its parent.
So those bodies you can assign it to its own immature.
If for some reason you need to move meche and skeleton around that's how you'd set that you'd put that
in here.
However we don't need to mess with this.
You'll also notice that these come with a bunch of different animations.
I've removed all the animations we're not using So I've put a death animation.
In fact this war came with a death animation.
Oh it's so dramatic.
An idle animation.
Yeah he looks pretty idle punching animation.
Yeah.
Pretty mad are running animation and that's what's called working that's me for picking up.
I've given the same names to animation for the female mash for press that but you'll notice the animations
are completely different.
I'm okay with that because when you have different characters and different shapes you want them to
moving a little differently.
So for instance this pick up animation is the same as working.
It looks very different right.
The running animation is pretty similar.
Now she didn't come with the death animation so I've put death in here and I will admit I might have
messed up slightly because she's floating sideways.
On the other hand that's a pretty dramatic death.
I mean you have to give me that.
All right let's close these.
And I'm not going to say that.
And instead what I do is I'm an inherit from character and make a new scene.
I can make a single play a character for now.
We're not going to make a male and a female till later.
And what I'm going to do is we're going to make a single play for now and then later on the section
will make that a template remove the mesh and the armature from entirely and loaded in through script
so we can use the same character or just load in the mash the skeleton and the animation that we need
are not talking let's actually do some work.
Get a new inherited scene.
Remember we are inheriting from the character.
So here's our new scene.
I notice New think is unsafe.
I'm gonna call this player to a plethora and loading in a mesh instance and excellent shape.
I'm going to close the animation.
Good.
And let's save this.
And I say this in the player folder and I say this as player.
A coin.
Let's start with the male character because that's the one that I happened to look at.
Alright first thing to do is I'm a load in this cilice.
Add a child note under scenes under characters and the players armatures almagor.
First thing you notice are boys kind of big isny and he looks as she looks like that statue in Brazil
on the mountain.
What's it called.
You know the one.
But I know one.
So let's shrink and Ellen's got to omniture and on a scale and down to what looks good.
Zip.
Let's try the z axis instead so if I get the height right the rest the skull should follow.
Zero point five.
Oh you'll see your actual scale is on the Z.
Oh that's right he's rotated so let's try that again.
Zero point five.
Nope.
Zero point two five.
Closer was zero point two two small zero point two five is the best yet they are putting five is good.
So if I now scaled down my quarter in all axes he's the right height.
Now when I hide the mesh instance he should fit pretty perfectly.
Look at that in that capsule.
Now if you were using assets that you'd made yourself or your working with a team in the middle of your
game the scales all match up.
But because we are using creative commons zero assets which we're made to work with any engine we might
have to tweak them.
So here we've scaled down the armature.
I don't mind scaling this down because if we look at our image has seen schene not seen you notice there
is no collision and here we are not scaling any collisions so the scaling all works just fine.
It should also work with the animation.
Let's check.
I'm going to right click on this and who editable children and any information player.
Let's just play deaf.
Yeah dramatic death.
Perfect.
OK.
There's an automatic death for me.
So then save this as player.
And what you don't know is that there was an edited cut there because I've got a delicious cup of coffee
next to me.
And I saw it and I had some coffee but that's enough about my life.
What we do is really give the character the player a script.
Now again later I'm going to rename this he's not a big player it's just me player I'm going to remove
the armature from entirely but for now this will get us working.
So let's make a script for player.
Later we'll make more a character as well.
Let's just make something very simple let's make a script for play.
We'll put that in our scripts folder.
Do do do.
Because we committed to this structure.
Been course let's do it.
There is no script sold.
Why.
Because Windows doesn't like zipping an empty folder into as it file so let's make one make a scripts
script celebrities.
And within that player I'm going to call this player DGT or play as we saying script and create great.
I'm going to be using Moven slide again because I want to be able to slide off things and I bump into
them I don't just stop.
I want to keep that machine going if possible.
So I know a couple of variables I need I need a motion variableness going to elect a three.
I need some sort of speed for now so let's make a variable.
In fact this is probably a constant isn't it.
I'm loving my Constance above my very wants because reasons let's call this I don't know 50 random number
50 pixels per frame.
So we don't need to be calling this brain function at all.
We'll do everything within function process.
I'm just not uncommon at that and I don't really want to put everything in here.
So I'm going to call a new function called move and move.
I don't think we need to pass Delta.
I'm going to leave it as it is and I certainly don't need puskas that doesn't do anything.
And we also need to make sure we have a function called Move to call them right pass in there for now
because we now need to put our keys in so that's going to project settings.
When he's a mappin our input into input map and I want for now three actions let's move forward.
Back left and right.
Okay.
And I'm going to map these in.
I'm going do them as keys for now.
I'm going to put in my controller yet do that later.
So the key for Ford is w a key for back is s key for left us amoc is a key for right is d w us a day.
Ha ha.
All right.
So we have a movie function what do we need to do.
Well we need to go if then put dot is action pressed.
We want forward and not.
Input is action press.
I did mean to put capital there but God will fix it for me.
Let's see.
So for going forward and not back.
This should all be very familiar right.
But come on there what he wants to do.
Well now motion dot.
I'm pretty sure this one is going to be the z axis.
I think I'm going to fix it.
Then motion Z equals one.
So I'm going to duplicate these two lines and reverse back and forth.
So if you go back and you not go forward.
This is negative one.
This is all very simple lace.
As we go through the section we're going to make this do things like mouse slow can move relative to
where the camera is pointing not where the person is.
But for now elisha's is something basic.
OK.
So we have both of those as you duplicate these two lines.
And here we go left and not right.
And that will be X will be negative one and right and not left
and here X will be positive right.
Let's save that.
And one I do my level template I want to put the player in.
It is the same in front of the camera Soulas instance in the player in a child of love the template.
And back up to scenes players.
Play em.
Great.
And look how much more he is in this desk.
I think we may have messed up the size a bit.
Hamwi How big is this desk.
Alf I don't limit the double check.
Scale is one that should be good.
All right fine.
Be like that.
Let's see what happens for Pressplay.
There's a desk waiting in the character and I can't move.
Why.
Because I've defined these inputs but I haven't told God what to do with them so very simple challenge
just to see how familiar and comfortable you are at this stage.
I'd like you to use Moven slide to move the player character and a quick tip.
You don't need shelter food and slide.
You do move and collide move and slide has Delta built in.
So if you were to multiply your move slide by Delta you would actually be doing it by Delta squared.
You I get acceleration not motion.
So pause the video use moving side to move the character.
And if you get stuck refer to the documentation and Either way when you're ready come back and I'll
show you my solution.
Welcome back.
Okay so there's nothing particularly complicated here except I need move and slide in a motion.
Time's speed.
Why speed.
Because otherwise we're just moving one pixel every fragment that's very slow.
And the other thing I mentioned it is an up fact right.
So if I put a little more room here succeed in doing.
Did you do.
There's my up factor.
Now I can define up as a constant here.
So let's do that constant up is at Vector 3 and it's zero on the X Y and the wiser on us.
So let's put that in there.
And now when I press play I should be able to do that.
Way too fast.
Okay.
That's ridiculous.
And my speed is much too high.
Let's put the speed to 10.
Like a C and knocking over a giant desk.
There's a couple of other things I'm not doing.
I'm not stopping to put the stop here.
Or we could just do motion.
He calls vector 3 0 0 0 0.
So every frame is going to set this to zero unless we tell it otherwise.
This is not the solution we have at the end because we do want to couple it jump separately but that's
going to take a little work.
Let's take a look at that.
Okay I can move now.
I'm moving in reverse because what I'm pressing backwards I'm heading towards the camera left and right
moving fine.
So let's just reverse these.
So Ford is going to be negative Z and back is going he said.
You'll also notice I am not facing the direction of turning.
I'm also not animated but worry about that later.
So let's do that let's have a face interactions like a variable facing direction and will set that to
zero.
Every frame we're going to rotate to the right direction to make a new function called Face.
Or face forward I guess that a name faces a little on script of a face forward or at a function.
Face forward.
OK so what do what we'll do is rotate the actual armature of the model of the player.
Right.
We want to take the whole thing we just want to rotate the armature.
So let's do that let's grab the armature.
Which is a child of play which is where the script is running so that's fine.
And here I want to rotate but I only want to rotate on the y axis.
And how much shorter a tape by facing direction.
So now I need to set the space and direction now rotate Y if I look at this you'll see it's in radiance.
So you like me and you went to school.
Stop doing maths and when you're 16 you're now in your early forties and you never learned about radiance
at the time.
Here's what you need to radians is an entire rotation right to pi radians rather.
So here's what we do rather than convert the degrees we're just going to use that so facing direction.
Equals 0 0 radians don't rotate.
However if I want to turn backwards that's half a circle.
Well if two pi is a full circle then all it need is facing direction equals PI right.
Okay so what about right.
Well that's half Pi so facing direction equals pi times zero point five or divided by two.
OK.
And with a duplicate VAT's move it down and facing direction is one point five pi.
Let's find out now on PI where I try and I have horribly miscalculated.
Why.
Because this is the wrong function.
I don't mean rotate underscore why I mean rotation because I'm not setting a function.
I'm setting a value right.
Rotation dot y equals fixing direction.
That should be art better.
OK.
Now there's a reason why this is looking a little weird right is because right now the animation isn't
working when put the animations on the carit or facing the right direction but we are facing a direction
that will take 90 degrees.
I promise you it will work.
A desk is too big or our place is too small but we have basic motion.
One more thing we could do we could put the camera as a child or a player but we're off to a decent
start.
So quite a lot in this video.
We've looked at skeleton's meshes and animation players.
We've looked at how you can make sure that your skeleton and your measure are talking to each other
and we've looked at how you use radians in rotation.
We've got basic movement.
Next up we're going to put in animation.
It's a great work and I'll see you next week.