Hello wonderful gotto people in this video we're going to make Bunny jump a bunny that can jump as a
sad bunny.
Let's have a happy bunny a bunny that can jump.
OK so what do we need to make happen.
First thing.
Let's make a scene for Bunny to jump in and make a basic level it's going to be very temporary but it
can be basic level and we'll bring Bunny into the level rather than have a level as part of the bunny
when we start looking at the scene structures I'll explain why but it'll make sense.
Let's have something to jump on some sort of platform.
We need to define gravity.
If we're jumping in there's no gravity what we're really doing is flying into the air and we need to
define a jump speed.
How high do we jump.
How high are we jumping.
OK.
So let's go into that first thing to do.
I want to hide the collision shape and I need to see it.
Let's just save that.
OK.
Before we start making you sing Let's talk about what a scene is.
Because here I've got a scene called player.
Normally when I talk about scenes I'm thinking of locations right and maybe that's my theater background
but I'm thinking like there's trees there's grass over here I mean there's a nice lake off into the
distance river more than the lake.
Whatever the point is I'm thinking of a location right the woods scene in my head is intrinsically linked
to the idea of a space but that's not what a scene is here.
A scene can be a space.
So we're going to make a scene a movie called Level One but it's also the player the play a character
bunny.
It's also it could be a sound effect it could be anything any self-contained collection of assets including
scripts sprites whatever else we might need.
That can be brought together and scenes can contain scenes can contain scenes.
So later we're going to have a camera scene that is part of play a scene and then the play scene is
going to be instance into a level.
So the camera be part of player.
It's all gonna to very inception.
OK.
So let's make a brand new scene.
I'll show what I mean.
So here's another scene I'm gonna use the standard no 2D or create 2D scene.
And now in the instance in the player.
So that's my play a character.
Now it's important to note that this is an instance scene.
I can see that from the Seattle Film clicker icon here.
It's important because I might have several levels I say I don't know we're making all 120 levels for
our game.
They're all going to use the same player as an instance.
What that means is I don't have to go through levels one through 120 and change the player in each that
say I need to change the graphic on its changed behavior.
Instead I can go into the player scene and let's say I've decided that the player shouldn't be the purple
pink bunny it should be the brown money.
So let's change that and save it the bunny is different in this scene.
That's really important it means that I don't have to keep changing the assets.
It's just gonna bring in an instance from elsewhere.
I actually don't want that so I want to move the people money back.
But if you do you should ok let's also save the scenes and I'll save you in your own folder as create
a folder and I call this levels level 1 Doc TSM save
OK minimize that and we get to go within this.
I'm also gonna put some sort of floor I think Bunny should you know have something to land on so we
can see what's happening let's make a static body static body 2D there it is set equality is currently
up here let's add in a sprite just a temporary sprite we can use.
There it is.
And I'm gonna use the got gotto icons let's use this little icon here OK.
I want this to be a bit bigger.
Somebody had to transform on the scale let's make it ten times wider and ten times higher as pretty
big isn't it.
OK I still need the collision shape so let's add a collision collision shape 2D and let's make it a
rectangle quick note if I try and change the size the rectangle if I go to click on the rectangle and
do excellence if I do ten times bigger it's not the same why because this is a measurements in pixels
whereas what I did in sprite was a multiplication.
The original is 32 by 32 pixels I've scaled up by 10 10 times 32 is 320.
So let's change the excess of 320 in each direction and that fits perfectly let's also make sure that
we're moving all children.
So we're going to select the parent and remove the floor down to here and let's move Bunny up
very important by the way I didn't draw a lot of attention this last video.
So let's go back to placing the reason why we want to make sure that we're moving the parent not just
the children is let's say I've not got selected and I want to move money right someone move money over
here now where is Bunny Bunny is where the kid somatic body is but the kid somatic body doesn't have
much visual representation I'm going to look at this and think bunnies with a Sprite is and that's going
to cause all kinds of problems that say I reached the end of the level the sprite isn't at the right
place Gordo is calculated from here so I need the children to always be where the parent is I need to
know where bunny is OK some would say that his bunny.
I need to change what scene happens when we press run.
So let's go to project Project settings and I'm going to go to run OK.
Main scene.
Player player TSM.
So it's like a folder you up upon and into levels and select level one tier ASEAN.
And now when I press play new default saying Okay here's a bunny for a further.
Let's rename the floor and hide the collision shape because it's distracting me.
And yeah that pretty good.
Let's actually make Bunny fold so to do that and to go into the player script.
Now I'm not open the script here but it's opening the player dot G.D. script which is the one for the
player scene so clicking here you're going to open that script.
I'm not changing this individual instance of the player I'm changing the script for all instances of
money all instances of player use the same script.
All right.
So I said I'm going to gravity I'm going to make constant gravity.
Why am I making constant knock on changes at runtime.
There is one gravity in my game.
Okay.
So what should this be it's probably a high number right because I mean multiply by Delta.
If it wasn't multiply by Delta for using moving collide rather move and slide.
If I typed five this mean five pixels per frame but five pixels multiplied by Delta per frame is quite
small so let's say 500 okay 500 well speaking of per frame let's actually make that happen.
So every frame we're gonna move down that's gonna be motion dot y right.
That's the Y position in this vector to motion dot y and we're going to what do we want.
We want add equals gravity add equals means take whatever it is right now and add the following to it.
Now some of you are thinking why we're late if you add to why aren't you going up.
And the answer is not here.
Let me show you why.
Here is a feature of gotto that has tripped me up more times than I care to admit.
Let's say I'm doing a standard piece of geometry right so his x.
Here's why this is zero.
This is bigger than zero whatever that is.
I can't be bothered to think of a number.
The point is positive goes in this direction right.
However that's not how Gordo calculates gotto is actually calculating from the top left.
So our axes look like this.
And y goes this way.
So this is positive y.
This is negative y.
That means down adds to the y value.
The easy way to remember this on occasions y don't forget is that we're actually drawing from the top
left of the screen to the bottom right of the screen.
Right.
Like I would read a book admittedly if you don't read in the language that reads from top left to bottom
right.
That's not very helpful but if you do that can be helpful.
I say I've made this mistake several times.
I actually made it while doing the prototype for this video even after I explained how not to do it
in my rehearsal.
So you know it's really a mistake to make but the short answer is if you want a jump we'll go negative
y and if not to fall we'll get positive y.
I guess another way I can think of this is that my name starts with the Y and I'm very grounded but
that's a terrible pun.
So we're not gonna do that.
Okay so every frame we should fall by gravity.
Let's take a look at how that works.
There's Bunny bunnies on the floor.
Bunny has fallen really fast.
That was much faster than 500 times delta.
What's happening.
What's happening is that we're adding to this value every frame and there's no cap so the velocity we
are heading down which is what this motion is right is increasing with every frame.
So if I immediately upon learning the game go that way I fall at 1 speed but if I wait a while and then
go off for much faster.
So I need to apply this only if I'm not on the ground.
Fortunately moving slide has something we can use.
So if I'm going to hold control and click on move and slide move and slide which is a calling kinetic
body 2D The first argument takes is linear velocity right.
Which way a moving.
A vector too.
But the second one is an optional one.
It's a floor normal.
What is that.
The up direction used to determine what is a wall and what is a floor or ceiling.
Why do we need to do that.
Well we need to do that because although we're doing a 2D game God doesn't know if we're looking from
the side in a standard platform game or top down Bunny Bunny isn't recognizable to God.
So we're gonna need some way of telling it.
I need you to know that this is up this is down so I'm going to define up in my script.
If this is another constant so let's put it near gravity constant up and I'm going to capitalize on
my constants of the nice and easy to spot my script.
And this is a vector too and I just need to define what up is right.
So it's 0 on the X and what is it.
Negative 1.
This is it's gonna be negative because negative y is up.
So now let's make a new function called called apply gravity
and I'm going to say if not is on the floor.
Now let's just move this motion dot way down.
So I'm going to hold out and use the down cursor and I need to indent that properly so if you want the
floor set motion dot y to be positive of gravity.
Else motion dot y equals zero.
When they do need to do is make sure they were actually calling this.
So let's say apply gravity so we apply gravity every frame so every frame is going to look at the gravity
because a.
Are we not on the floor if we're not on the floor apply gravity elsewhere.
This way we could by the way also just right is on floor motion dot y equals zero else.
Motion don't y plus equals gravity.
Okay this is functionally the same it doesn't really military do it.
I guess it is on floor is slightly easier to process and if not is on floor but that's personal preference.
Okay.
In all of this work we need to make sure it's actually using is on floor right now this will never trigger
because it doesn't know which way the floor is.
To do that we need to put up in here.
That's just this vector too in here.
So now I press play Bunny start in the ground.
But then when I move this way much better falling right.
And to make that really clear.
Let's change this.
5 as this nice slices slowly fall.
And now on a stay on the ground for a while.
And that shouldn't change in the middle of this way.
It'll fall at the same rate.
If that wasn't the case.
If I take this up out
full weight a little bit and then fall much faster.
Okay so we're gonna put that up in there.
Great.
Now we also need a jump speed because we to start jumping how high do we jump.
This will be fighting gravity constant jump speed and we should find what that is.
Let's put gravity back.
It's got to be higher much faster than gravity isn't so let's say you think the same.
Yeah let's go with the same as the speed for now 1000.
Okay so let's go if it puts dot is action pressed now let's define a jump cycle project settings input
map and let's type and jump.
All right we need to decide what a jump key is going to be.
It could be w on a quiet keyboard.
If it's an as a T keyboard it'll be something else.
It could be space I'm asking but it's both an add a key for W and a key for space and now either has
pressed it'll counters jump.
So now if action pressed his jump motion Dot.
Why is this going to be minus equals jump speed.
I could also do plus equals and this is negative 1000 but that feels weird.
Let's see how that looks.
And let's make a bigger screen.
It works pretty well.
I tap space is great but look.
Please stop at different heights.
In fact if I hold space go for quite some time.
The reason is bunnies jumping even if bunnies in the air as long as I'm holding the button down Bunny
will jump.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I'd like you to make sure we only jump when we're on the floor.
So pulls the video give it a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution
and welcome back.
Okay.
Easiest thing we could do is use is on floor now.
What I'm going to do is if input is action press jump and is on floor
then jump speed.
So this will only happen if on the floor and a press jump and now it's very clear I need a smaller gravity
or higher jump speed right.
So let's do that let's change jump speed for 3000
now I'm bouncing a bit.
So what I might do is change is action pressed for is action just pressed.
So now holding it won't do it.
Right.
You have to tap it for each time and let's turn down gravity slightly that feels a little high that
feels pretty good doesn't it.
Okay.
Now this is stunt to get a little bit messy.
I've got to play gravity is our function.
I actually will jump as I would function.
So let's put jump here and make a new function for jump and just move this down so I can grab this
and call that jump.
And we could also do move and this time I'm going to cut this
and paste it right there to make sure my indentation is correct.
And now when I press play it shouldn't play any differently but our functions are a lot neater right.
Every frame applied to gravity jump move move and slide each function is doing a single thing and that's
really key.
And look at that we now have a jumping falling moving money which brings us the end video in this video
we've looked at instances scenes how to change your default scene so what scene plays when you press
play how x and y coordinates work and go and how to use the IS is on flow function in moving slide.
This is really great progress our game is starting to come together since a look like a real game.
Did you come up with a different solution to the only jump on the flow problem is your code something
different.
Share your progress.
I'm really curious to see how you guys are doing.
Meanwhile great stuff and I'll see you on the next video.