Welcome back lovely God.
People in this video will get a look at physics body in 3-d.
Our game is going to rely on physics every time a player moves the ball.
The ball is going to be using godey's 3D physics engine.
So we should get this right.
And right now we're not off to the right stuff.
We show you why.
When getting game and you know what we need to make a default scene.
So what do we put a special note as the root cause spatial as the default 3D node.
And I want to call this game and just save this as my default scenes are in scenes I now have again
seen.
And in this an instance in the pitch.
So let's do that let's.
Instance in the pitch.
And the scenes there's my pitch looking good.
Alice is this in the ball as a child of game.
If we look at this the pitch is a mesh instance and the ball is a mesh instance.
When I press play when I want to alban's the ball should fall to the ground but it worked to demonstrate
that I knew the camera.
So let's go back into the game and create a camera.
So we need a camera note not a camera 2D is in 3D now.
And I'm going to move this over here.
You can see by the way I've got my gritz Snapping I think me a double check that off again.
And I can use this preview and see what the camera can see not the angle on a stick with the game.
The sword affinia.
Let's run this song now.
You'll notice in the last video I accidentally set pitched my default scene isn't set right now.
Just your mind you have do that forget to project settings.
I got to run main scene is now blank.
Right.
So I blacked it by going here and just using the reset I can play this scene and use my game scene as
the default.
The ball doesn't know why doesn't the ball move.
After all we have a mesh here and a mesh here.
I would expect objects and space to behave like they should behave and that's because the mesh is not
a physical object.
So why can't we use a mesh instance in a physics game.
Well a mesh instance is a type of geometry instance where it will look at the documentation it'll show
us there what that means is the measure.
This tells me what the object looks like.
Not help behaves meshes on not a type of physics body.
And we want to use collision of physics.
So we need to be using a physics body not a mesh.
We do want a mesh because we want to see the object but we want the object to be able to behave.
So what we need to do is I need to open up my pitch scheme and change this from a visible piece of geometry
that doesn't actually behave like an object.
It has no collision.
It has no physics.
I need to change the root node to a physics node and I need to move ammash to be a child.
Okay well we know how to change a root note right we can just go change type and I can type N.
Static body or just pick that width.
Now the problem is all the information that's in that mesh is going to vanish.
It's now gone.
So I'm now going to quickly undo everything I just it's a change type meche instance and this is going
to get done very quickly.
Right.
And I have a 20 by 15 I believe size and the material you'll be using is the pitch material there it
is.
And I think that was about right.
I'm safer now.
If I want to keep redoing this right now this isn't too bad but if I have like a more complicated ammash
or forgot what the parameters are this is going to get irritating.
Well the next thing we could try is duplicating right we could duplicate this have another picture as
a child and then just change the route of a pitcher's root notes.
If I go to duplicate it I can't.
You can't have multiple root notes.
So have I just messed up and do we have to start again.
No.
There is something we can do.
First let's create a new mesh instance as a child of the pitch.
We have a back up to the Petsch and I'm going to use this screwdriver and spanner or screwdriver and
wrench depending on poverello you're in and I'm going to go.
Copy programs and a copy all of the parameters.
Then I'm going about this meche instance.
I press the icon again and paste all the parameters everything that was in pitch is now a mess meshes
that's now go back to the pitch and I change this to change it to a spatial for now.
It's now a spatial node that has a mesh inserts as a child.
Before we go any further let's double check what kind of node we actually wants to be.
I don't want it to actually be a special node I wanted to be physics body so let's remind ourselves
of the three types of physics bodying in God.
And we're now using physics body not physics body to deep because we're not into hoodie anymore.
First we have a static body a static body is a fixed object that isn't expected to move or wall a floor
a ceiling something that I could call lined with it has solidity.
It exists in the physical object in the physical space but I dont need it tomorrow.
Then we have a rigid body in a rigid body is an object that reacts to physics something that is moved
a door for example or a chair.
I don't expect it to move at itself.
Now I've put reacts in italics because that's the key word here.
It's something that physics is applied to rigid bodies have built in physics parameters right.
They have mass they have weight they have gravity.
They are they have gravity applied to them.
They have things like how bouncy they are.
But the point is they're not expected to move themselves right.
I shouldn't be using I shouldn't be using things like Translation.
X plus equals one on a rigid body.
It's supposed to cut its own movement.
Then we have a kinematic body.
This is an object that does move itself.
So a player would be a kinematic body an NPC that can move like the player does is a kinematic body
an NPC that is moved by something else is a rigid body.
By the way I'm saying there are three types of physics body lying.
There are four.
There's also a vehicle body which is a specialized rigid body that simulates car physics has things
like suspension.
It has things like dampening has all these really cool things but we're not looking at this.
So for now three types of physics body looking at the three types of and leave the fit the vehicle body
on screen.
For now look at the three types.
I know that the pitch should be a static body because it shouldn't be moving.
It is something that things move on or against.
Yeah.
It is static.
So that's one it doesn't change the pitch change type.
To static body and rammer I don't want static body to D.
You seem to confuse everything.
It'll immediately tell me you don't have a collision shape.
You have to have a collision shape.
Let's have a collision shape.
So one of the do is create a collision shape around this.
Now I don't have to do it this way I can actually auto generate them I can click on mashy instance and
right here this mesh button.
I can create a sibling exacerbate a sibling of this the college must be a child of the physics body
not of the mash so I could create a child's sibling.
However I reckon not doing this.
If you don't have to these are pretty simple shapes right.
A plane doesn't need an automatically generated shape but just to show you can create a tri mesh shape
and it's created a tri mash static body.
As a child of the misha's I don't want that from a leap that I want as simple a collision shape as possible
because the more complicated it is the more resources God has to spend trying to figure out when it's
being used.
So let's make a collision.
No collision shape.
Not galician shank to leap is back in shape.
And what's the shape it's going to be a box.
I could make a plane but I'm not making a box and I'm going to use the stance.
To make it the right kind of size.
In fact I could just go into the accent and type in the size.
So the X looks like it's 10.
The While looks like zero point wonder looks good for now and the Z I'm guessing will be 5 No.
6.
KEEP GOING.
Seven point five.
Dead on.
What do you want to make sure of is if I look down here I want to make sure the clear shape is slightly
higher than something with it up.
A touch is at too far that is too far.
So it was moved back down back to transform and other translation.
That's how far you move on the various axes.
I'm just going to give you to zero.
And that should be pretty good.
I get it.
So we now have a static body.
And if I go back up to the pitch you'll notice has friction and Bout's anything there that moves against
the pitch is a factor.
If you want to make your game crazy bouncy you can you could change this tomorrow.
Right now we've got no way of looking at that.
But that's okay.
I must save my pitch.
Now look at the pitch.
The pitch is now a static body.
The ball is still a mesh instance which brings me to the challenge.
I'd like you to convert the ball to a physics body.
Pick the right kind of physics body for the ball.
Now your choices are a static body a rigid body and a kinematic body.
You really don't want to be making this a vehicle because you're not driving the ball.
So figure out which one you want and convert the route scene of the ball from the meche instance to
that type of physics body.
Pause the video when you're hanging with the solution.
Come back and Shane my solution.
And welcome back sir.
I'm going go into the diebel scene which is right here.
And I want to first before I do anything else copy my parameters.
Now I'm going to create a child that has a mesh to do.
There is a paste.
There's pragmatism.
And as it's going back up the ball and here's a moment of truth what I want this to be.
Well let's go look at the slides again.
We know it's not going to be a static body because I want this to move.
Now theoretically yes I can move a static body through code but I really shouldn't be doing that too
much.
It's not going to be a kinematic body because balls don't move themselves it's going to be a rigid body.
OK.
So let's make this a rigid body.
It's a change type.
And rigid body.
Awesome.
I'm sure save that.
Now before we go any further I need to put a collision shape on this elisha's in this collision shape.
OK.
We need new leadership.
What do we want to generate a mesh for this one.
Not really.
Because this is a simple sphere.
Sphere is a type of collision shape.
So there we go it's a sphere.
Now all I need is to give it the same excellence as the measures.
Let's go to the missions and see where they are.
And click on the mash.
Got a radius of zero point two five at the height of point five.
Becky the collision shape quick on a sphere shape radius zero point five Nope zero point two five point
five is the circumference always confuses you.
Press save I shall see if this works.
Boom.
See ramp if anything touches the ball.
It will move.
Let's just make sure that's right.
Winner take the pitch until that angle slightly and as the Gloc.
See that ball pick up speed and off it goes.
Fantastic.
I don't want my picture that angle pickersgill be really unfair to those on this side of the pitch.
So let's move you back and undo that.
All right before we go any further I just want to make sure that my collision layer's meeting is set
up some collision.
And the project settings and I'm going to go down to 3D physics and here my layers as they lay I want
it's pitch layer two can be ball and layer three will probably play.
And now mimic the pitch.
Take the collision.
Now put it.
Michael agila it is a pitch and it's going to interact with balls and plays great.
Say that and it's a ball.
When do the same thing but with slightly different collision because you know obviously.
So let's go into the layers.
You are not a pitch you are a ball and you interact with the pitch and the players before we sign off.
Let's just look at some rules of thumb of how to use a rigid body rigid body nodes should not move themselves
so don't use translation or transformation or whatever.
Plus equals 1.
God will let you do this but this is inefficient right.
They have their own physics.
Instead of you need to move a rigid body directly.
You're going to apply and imposs this is a function with the inner rigid body that tells you okay you
are being move from this direction.
With this much force right rigid bodies don't act they react they are moved by things they don't actually
move themselves.
And that brings us to the end of this video.
In this video I had a refresher on these three four types of physics body.
We've looked at how you can pick the right type of physics body for the task.
We've looked at changing the root node of a scene without losing important parameters.
Right so if you got very excited and brought your first mission and then realized oh I can't use this
yet how can we copy and paste the parameters to a child node without losing all the detail.
Are off to a great start.
We're almost ready stuttering players.
So excellent work and see in the next video.