Halloween, you momma's got people in this video way to create a character scene and a play a scene.
So got something to move around all world and get this game started.
Now, why am I talking about characters and players as if they're different things?
Because in our game, we're going to use character inheritance.
We're gonna have a base current class from which pieces and end pieces are going to derive basic functions.
Now, we don't have to worry about that too much right now.
So we're just going to be focusing on the play a character.
But I do want to set up a system whereby the players inherit from the character.
OK.
To do that, we're going to get into got oh, here's a lovely desk.
Here's a lovely camera.
Everything's looking at Brown.
We can fix that later.
That desk might be a bit big.
We can fix that later, too.
First binary Hussein custom node.
Kinematic body.
Make sure you've got this red one, the 3D.
We don't want kinematic body tutee or it's going to go weird.
OK.
So this is gonna be my character class.
I'm going to use a mesh instance and just make a basic cube, which is right here.
And you keep Meche just to see what we're looking at.
Now I'm going to click on the cube and change the size.
It's gonna be two meters on the Y axis, roughly two meters tall, which is exactly two inches tall,
which is roughly six feet.
And let's say point five on the two axes.
That's gonna be our basic character.
Nothing in the game is gonna look like that.
That's just so we can work in the editor.
You also notice that the origin is here.
I kind of want the arch by the floor, but I don't want the mesh instance going through the floor.
So what we do is I'm head down to transform with mission since selected and I'm just gonna move it up
by Mehta's on the Y axis.
Move it up by one meter and that's perfectly on the floor.
Let's rename this I call this character.
And where to put it now in the previous version, this course, I put all scenes in scenes and all scripts
in the folder called scripts.
I've included the scenes here because we've got some fixes to our raw assets that I've put in here for
now.
Let's just go into the character scene and I'm just gonna save it in characters to save us.
And I realize we're not done with the scene.
Safe scene, right?
Going have two scenes.
We need two characters and I'm going to put it right here.
Why not put it in place?
Because employees will also use this script.
Currently, it's a big white box glowing in the light and kind of like that.
And we need a collision shape.
So back up to character, new node.
And I want collision and.
But now we could use a cube, a matchup perfectly, but I won't be using move slide, which means I
want things to slide off and push away.
And if we have right angles, it's much harder to do.
So instead of is what a lot of games use.
We're going to use a capsule, the capsule, DP rotates and stuff.
This allows us to get good collision and interesting behavior.
If we don't need the collision to match everybody pop perfectly if we're playing a very, very precise
shooter.
This wouldn't work, but we're not.
So it will be OK.
We need to rotate this on the red line, which is the x axis by 90 degrees.
And we need to move it up by a meter.
So that's the y axis by meter.
It's also too big.
So let's head over to the shape press capsule and let's set a radius of half a meter.
Look at that.
That is perfect.
We could say that.
OK.
That is our character.
Now, let's go make an armature scene.
Now, we already have some models we can use.
If we got a models, good players, we have human and woman again, not entirely sure splitting our
characters into human.
A woman is the best idea.
The thing is, I want to be able to drop these in to a character.
I just have them work, and for that to happen, I need everything to be named consistently.
Let's see what we have here.
We have human armature with human mesh underneath, which is animation player.
Animation player has a bunch of animations.
OK, now let's look at animated woman.
We have armature woman.
I don't know how much a tooth for.
And we have animations with different names and different named buttons to make this consistent.
We'd have to do this.
We'd have to rename both of these two mesh.
Don't actually do this.
I'm going to explain what's going to have to happen.
We'd have to move the animation player to be a child of the armature.
So that way we could just export the armature, would have to rename the armature as well.
So let's put that there for now.
Just there.
That's consistent.
But now we have a problem right now.
These no longer work because I've moved the mesh.
It's in a different place from the armature.
So someone is going to have to go through all of these and change every single one of these manually
for every animation.
And that is a lot of work.
And the good news is you don't have to do it.
I've done it for you before we look at where these are.
Why is this happened?
This is happened because katanas has very kindly made free and open source assets for everyone to use.
But he makes one a month and he doesn't make them consistently.
Well, when I say consistency consistently, he makes one a month, but he uses a different paradigm
for each one, different naming conventions, different scales, all kinds of stuff.
So to make them work consistently, I've had to go through and edit them in almost no circumstance when
you're making your own endgames.
Will this happen because you're either gonna be creating or assets or working with someone who's making
them for you or buying a pack.
So let's head over into the scenes, characters, players.
And you see here we have an ominous folder with him, which is much f an image.
M don't worry too much about much F being missing.
If he has the animation and play any animation.
You'll see this that I have made sure they have identical animation names.
So if I call.
We don't have a jump, no jump as he's running since upo got lost there.
Forgot term of jump running mate.
We need to rename that so that now.
But they haven't both have a running animation.
Like, so.
OK, so let's say we want to update the running animation.
Call it run.
Click on animation.
You can rename.
I gonna call it run.
Great.
Have I missed any others?
We have punch working.
Jump Idol.
Death with the male.
We have death.
Idol.
Punch run.
Working.
Great.
OK.
So now we have consistent ones.
And if we look at the actual trees armature mesh animation plan, which means if we instance in either
the male or the female armatures, the script is can have the same exact path to the animation player.
We are going to call the same animation name.
And it's just gonna work seamlessly.
If we hadn't done that, we will have to write a completely separate script for each of these characters.
Furthermore, we have other problems, by which I mean if we take a look at the translation, this really
came like that.
Leave it to us.
However, if we look at the female one.
This is facing the wrong way, right?
So the male is facing the blue line, females facing the right.
So let's just go to the white and zeroed out.
So there's lots of little tweaks of change.
The biggest pains for you.
So they're not there.
I always said pains in the in the rear, but I'm not going to.
Everything else should be working.
So we have our two lovely armchairs ready to go.
OK.
With all that said, let's start using one.
So I'm a dude from a character new inherited scene.
I'm an inherit from character and I'm going to rename this player.
Now, I'm not going to save this player.
I'm gonna say this either as player or player F.
And the reason is later we're going to create code.
Going to allow the player to pick that.
Play a character.
Right.
Putting customization in all this is built with customization mind.
However, I want them both the call player.
That way, if I'm calling, for example, the animation player, x just player, animation player and
so on.
So it all works just fine.
Okay, so we have our player.
I need to save this on the players as player.
And now I'm arbitrarily choosing the male character because that's just what I happen to pick.
You can pick a different one in here.
I'm an instance in.
My armature m.
And already we can see a bit of a problem here.
Right.
The scale is off.
This character is two meters, four meters, six meters, eight meters tall.
OK.
We want two meters tall.
So let's select the armature.
That's got to transform.
And let's just do point to five in all three axes.
Now I'm changing the armature, which if we look at the scene, doesn't have any collision.
I'm not scaling collision.
You really don't want to scale collision.
And if I now hide this mission instance, look at that.
That's pretty good.
We could probably shrink this collision shape a little further.
But I'm.
Yeah, you know what?
I will shrink a little further.
So let's go to the actual capsule and change it to point to five.
Doing that has made this a little bit too short.
So I'm going to drive the extent to the floor.
Beautifully done.
Here is our brand new player character.
Now, both players are going to be using the same scripts and make a script.
I'm not going to call it player male.
I'm going to call it player Dr. G.D. and let's make it empty, haha.
OK, now I mentioned earlier.
Let's just close this animation window and, you know, gives us lots of room to play with.
I mentioned earlier that we can be using moving slide.
Right.
I want things to hit and roll away rather than hit and stop.
So if I'm using the slide, I know I'm going to need a motion variable, which is gonna be a vector
three.
And I'm not running this every frame.
And I won't be doing this on physics, celestial physics process, Delta.
So on every frame we need to move.
OK, let's see what move means.
Like a brand new move function.
I don't need to post Delta through and not using it.
All right.
So what we've be doing here is every time, every frame we need to be checking, if any, the controls
are being pressed and move from there.
So let's set up controls.
Only had project project settings, input map.
We've done this a few times.
Right.
And let's say forwards.
Back.
Left.
And right, OK.
I'm just going to set these up with the keys for now, these WSI deep because I'm using a British quater
keyboard.
Obviously, if you using, for example, a French keyboard, set it to AZT, that's fine.
If you need a controller, use a controller.
I might program my controller at another point for Mountain Dew to be OCD.
Get this working.
And we've done this before, too, right.
I want to use the input, get extra strength trick so that if I do this controller, it'll work just
fine.
So let's make a variable called X and this is gonna be input stopped, gets action strength.
And this is going to be forward and that's a B minus inputs dot get actual strength.
And that's going to be back.
So Ford is is going to be won back is gonna be negative one.
Oh, good.
OK.
So variable Z because we're using 3D here.
Why is up and down.
We're not touching up and down right now.
Input stopped.
Get actual strength.
And I want.
Right.
Minus inputs.
Don't get actual strength.
Left, right.
So now I'm going to set motion to be effective three.
X, zero, Z.
Now we're gonna be changing the mood.
Now, later, we are gonna be changing how movement works.
These are what mouse look and we're gonna have to make sure that the direction keys are actually not
in line with the world and alone and land with a camera which is moving with the mouse.
So it's gonna be some changes.
But for now, that's looking good.
Now, we also need a few other things.
We need a constant
speed.
And let's just start with a speed of 10.
We can tweak these values in a bit.
Okay, so we have our speed of 10.
But you'll notice if I run this.
Nothing will happen to demonstrate that and go to my level template.
I'm going to instance in.
Player M..
And run the game.
Here's my character and pressing the keys.
Nothing is happening.
Why is nothing happening?
Because we need to actually call, move and slide.
So my challenge for you is to use move and slide to move the player character.
This is really a very simple test to see how comfortable you are with moving slide at the moment.
Now, before we go any further, you'll notice this tip here.
Don't multiply by Delta in moving slide, move and slide automatically multiplies by Delta.
Moving collide.
Does not.
If you multiply it by Delta and move and slide, you're actually multiplying by Delta squared, which
would be acceleration I guess.
So pulls the video.
Give that a shot.
I don't know why my knuckle just cracked.
And when you come back, I'll show you my solution.
And welcome back.
OK.
So back into the game again.
And this is going to be move and slide, not moving collide.
What am I doing?
Move and slide.
Got too excited there.
And what we need is motion.
However, we also need to put the floor normal.
We're dealing in 3D.
We can't leave this blank.
Couple things we could do.
We can make it brand new cost up here.
Call it up.
We could be a vector three of zero one zero.
Right.
Zero on the X, Y on the Y.
Zero on the Z.
Or we could type that vector three in here.
I'm going make the constant.
And just drop it in.
And that should work as Pressplay.
In big on the screen, and it does.
Now we're moving very slowly.
And we're actually moving globally, so the camera should be over here.
So I'm going to move the camera.
Do Louie, Louie, Louie, Louie, Louie, look over?
Like so you and I need to rotate us off or rotate and rotate by negative 90 degrees.
Look what that looks like.
Yeah.
What postpunk is better.
Now, why is the character going so slow?
Well, because I'm moving by motion.
Motion is one less de motion type speed.
I forgot to put speeded up.
OK.
So now we should be moving much more easily.
Look at that.
And we can hit the desk and the desk goes flying.
The test is too big.
It gets locked around our heads.
But that works great.
But we are not changing direction.
Let's change direction.
OK, so we want to be facing the direction we're travelling now.
If we had done.
If you're pressing forward and you're not pressing back, move X.
If you're pressing back, end up moving forward, X is minus one.
If we'd done every single step of that, this would be a lot simpler.
But because of streamline this, we going to be a little bit clever with our mathematics.
So first thing we do is we need to change the direction we're moving.
If we're actually moving, if we're not, I don't want to snap back to looking forward.
So let's put it an if statement, if motion, rather, if not motion is what I mean is equal to vector
three zero zero zero.
In other words, if you're not still all right, that's the cleanest way I can think of phrasing that.
Then we want to face forwards and we're gonna pass through X and Z.
OK, so now let's make a function called face forward, and we need X and Z.
Now we're gonna be using radians, so if I look at rotation, careful, because rotation is not the
same as rotation degrees, rotation degrees uses degrees.
There are 360 degrees in a circle.
Rotation uses radians.
I didn't study radians at school.
They were never talk to me.
I stopped doing mathematics.
They just 16 and didn't do it again until I did my master's degree in education, at which point we
didn't cover it.
But a radion is a way of measuring an angle and two times pi radians is a full circle.
So with that said, the rotation is going to have to equal something in that value range.
And to do this, we need some trigonometry.
We can use the octane.
And we need two values.
And we use X and Z.
And we want to do this just on the Y axis.
Right.
We don't rotate all three axes.
I'll be honest, I don't know my trigonometry well enough to fully explain a 10.
I just know if I want to take two directional inputs and turn them into a rotation.
I need a ten and I'm using two inputs, so I need a ten, too.
Now, when I press play.
We'll find that pressing back makes us look right.
Passing laugh makes us look back, pressing forward makes us look left and pressing right makes us look
forward.
The marshes off by 90 degrees, knows two things we could do here.
We could either do some mathematics here.
And to do that, what I would do is I would subtract half times pi.
So I subtract half Pi or Pi over two if you prefer.
And that will work so I can go into that.
And pressing back left and character now works.
Right.
The other thing we could do.
I'm actually on leave it as minus pi.
Whatever to.
The other thing we could do is we go into the plant and we could take this mesh and we could rotate
it.
I would suggest not doing that.
And here's why it is by 90.
First off, I'm on the wrong axis.
So let's find the right axis or take this by 19 nuke or take this by 90.
Okay, so Verity's by 90.
Are the animations still gonna work.
And the answer is not really.
I mean they kind of do.
It's a bit messy.
You can do it.
I would recommend instead using all radians.
So if two pi is a full circle.
That was my script.
Here's my script to Pisar full circle.
Then one PI is half a circle and half pi is a court circle.
We want to turn by quarter and we'll turn on the anticlockwise.
So we'll be turning by negative half pint.
And now for Pressplay, we have a little character who can zoom around.
Now we don't have the animations yet.
That's coming pretty soon.
But we do have something pretty simple.
We can move around.
We can interact with giant physics objects by my desk, push off the edge.
And it's looking pretty good to me.
So I think this is a pretty good place to start.
All right.
He's making me laugh.
I think it's a pretty good place to stop.
We've done quite a lot of work, and I think this is a great piece of progress.
So excellent stuff.
And I'll see you in the next video.