Hi folks welcome back.
Today we're going to look at how we could take that text that were printing out into the output where
only we're going to see it and show it to the player.
To do that we can explore the rich text label by the end of this video.
You can have this lovely background texture.
And it's nice chalk style felt font and be able to display your story to the player.
So what are we doing in this video to make that happen.
Well to display the story in the game we need to learn how to import assets into godda.
If you look at the resources for this video you'll notice there's a zip file you can download X that's
for graphics.
I included a basic blackboard or chalkboard graphic font and a button.
Today we're just going to be using the font on the blackboard and I show you how to create a background
texture.
This isn't a UI focussed video it's just to get you started and show you how to use it.
But later in the course I am going to show you all kinds of fun things you can do with you I think godda
we're going to look at how you can recycle the games displaying really create a rich text label and
going to update that rich text label in egd Script rich text label is the name of a node that allows
us to display text on the player.
So let's get started.
Okay.
Here we are back in lonely lips.
So far all we have is a node called lomie Lips.
Specifically this is a Node 2 D.
You can see that an inspector right here and it has a script.
When I run play dumb dumb dumb.
It's going to display everything we've done in the output.
However the players can't see the output what the players going to see is this and this is a boring
grey square kind of grey kind of beige.
Actually not sure what colour this is.
Let me know in the comments.
So what do we need to do to make this better.
Well the first thing we do is get a background texture so minimize gotta have already downloaded the
looney lips G affects dots up on ogan that and it's a folder that says defects which stands for graphics
select this right click on it and hit copy great back and it got out.
Let's get it on the output.
And over here in the file system I'm on the right click and do show in file manager.
This is going to open the folder that we created when we created this project.
Now I'm just going to paste and there is my g eFax folder inside you can find blackboard JP.
Two buttons and a font.
Great.
So I've put the folder in right place.
Now I gotta find a folder.
Well get back to God.
And it does it for me.
I don't have to do anything.
There's our folder.
Fantastic.
Anything that's in that folder.
If God can read it it will read unless you specifically tell it otherwise.
So let's open the defects folder.
So here I have a texture a blackboard texture chalkboard if you're from the U.S. maybe Canada not sure
blackboard if you're from the UK which I am.
So how do we get it here.
I need a new node.
So over here in the seed tree unhit plus and what no do we need.
Well I need a texture rectangle.
And there it is texture wrecked.
Look there's the description draws a sprightly texture inside a user interface can tile or not.
We don't need it to tile but we do need to be a thing.
So as a child of luny lips you can see the node texture rectangle.
This child parent thing is important.
Every scene has a single parent.
Typically we call this the root node.
Technically it's not the root.
There is actually a secret root node just up here which we can access in code but we can't see.
So instead of talking about root Let's talk about the parent Luni lips is the parent and it has a child
of texture act and we could put a bunch more child and grandchild and so on.
I know that child's isn't the plural of child.
Going around with it is now child's great renamed texture rectangle to be a little less weird.
Let's call it black board.
There it is.
Remember you can follow the convention that all nodes are going to have a capital first letter.
OK so we have our texture acting on Node called Blackboard.
I need it to have a texture first thing.
I can go over here to the inspector where it says no and load it in and that will work fine.
However it's kind of dull so it's clear that much easier way of doing that.
I can take my texture and just drag it over there.
Now there's this blue rectangle that is what the players going to see.
So we have all this texture not being used.
Let's make sure we have the right viewport size.
If I go to project settings and down here and display window I can change the width in the height.
I got mine at 10 8. 720 but we could do.
I don't know 10 days by 650 or whatever.
There's only one 720 but that's how you can change your default size.
I've also as resizable the player is all out to realize this window.
When I hit play.
You'll notice that we only see part of the texture in this particular case that's not what we want.
I mean here expand which is going to allow the texture to be rescale.
And let's do scale.
Angela's shrink it down to about the size of the screen.
If you want to snap to view that's this thing you snap.
And we can even view our grid and I can bring this note right to the right place.
If you want to change the size of the grid that's got to be here under configure snap.
Right now it's 10 pixels by 10 pixels.
If you want that say l.a. 64 by 64 loops 64 that's 64.
I can maths that's how you do that disable the snapped a grid which is the grid with a little magnet
on it.
And let's hide the grid because we don't actually know right now.
Great.
We now have a background I now need one more note type.
I mean that a child of blackboards when blackboard.
I'm going to add one note and here I'm going to have a rich text label.
Rich Text allows me to do things like bold underline change colour.
And it's the best text label for what we have to do.
For now let's just make this nice and white.
In fact a re-enable the grid.
And set my grid to where did it go come back.
Let's go further 40 by 40 just like us.
And she going by 10 by 10.
Let's keep it as it was.
So I don't confuse myself which I'm quite good at doing and all that was quite close was there and found
out there.
OK.
We can now display text within this rectangle later in the course we'll look at things like how to set
margins how to get this to rescale itself all the rest.
For now this is great.
And let's get rid of these grids switch off snapping.
Fantastic.
Okay Rich Text label.
Well that would work.
But for now I'm going to call this story text so I now have a local story Tex.
And he only inspect under text.
I can write some place holder text.
Oh it's tiny in an ugly font.
So now let's get a fonteyn.
How can we get a font.
OK.
Inside the inspector I'm going to scroll down.
La la la la la.
Custom fonts under custom fonts.
I need a new normal font and it's going to be a dynamic font.
Then click on the word dynamic font and that'll bring you into this specific font.
You'll notice other settings sizes 0.
That's no good.
I was about to 35 that's pretty good.
And now I need a font again.
You can use this and loaded it.
Or you could just drag felt pen in.
There's felt pen the size of 35.
Does it work.
Let's find a
place old ATEX.
Look at that.
OK.
I need to set this text.
Something to go back in to my script and instead of print I need a way of actually setting the story.
So what can I use what I need to do is call the node story text from within the looney lips script and
tell it to change what's written under text.
Here's how to do that.
First I'm going to use get underscored no.
And it's going to give you a dropdown.
Actually I'm not going to do that because a lot of typing instead of get on the scale no.
I mean the dollar sign and here I can just type in that and there it is.
Dollar sign is a shortcut.
Forget underscore node brackets quotation.
You don't have to use dollar if you'd rather use get on a school node brackets quotation quotation brackets.
Go ahead.
I'm going to this.
So I have told it I'm doing something with this child that press dot and now that's having a bunch of
things I can do.
Well what do I need to do if I click on story Tex.
You'll see that mousing over this text file will say property.
Text the thing next to property or it says text.
That's what I'm going to type.
Because that's the thing I want to change.
So if I typed text equals.
OK.
So what's it going to be.
Well we've already done that right storing percentage prompt.
So I press play now.
Once upon a time a yarn ate a pizza and felt very full.
It was a sad day for augered cabbages.
And look we've got it here in the output and here too.
I don't even need it here any uploading more let's just delete like six completely.
You'll notice that under here I'm using text and there's a different thing saying beeby code Beebee
code is what allows you to use things like bold underline or the rest of it.
Right now we're not doing that.
I can't put that in.
What if I wanted to use beeby code instead.
If I enable it how can I set it with BBB code.
Well that's my challenge for you.
I'd like you to use what we've just done instead of setting rich text label text.
See if you can figure out how to set the beeby code text in the script using the exact same story plus
percentage prompt.
So pause the video give that a go and then when you come back I'll show you my solution.
OK so the first thing I need to do is I need to figure out what beeby code is called.
It's called beeby code underscore text.
So instead of text I want bbk code underscore text all lowercase that's important I get to make sure
that we're not cheating.
I'm going to comment this line out and then I'm going to do a dollar in it.
Give me a list of things I can use.
I'm gonna call this story text.
Note dot B E code underscore text equals story as a percentage prompt.
Simple as that.
See.
Nice and easy.
Which brings us to the end of this video.
We've covered some really good stuff in this video.
We've looked at how to create a background texture and indeed how to import assets into God which is
really useful.
We looked at how to resize our games display which are going to be using a lot in your future projects.
We've looked at how to use the rich text label note and how to change the properties of a child node
from within the script.
So a really good foundation we've now got something to show the players and in future videos we're going
to start adding the game logic where the player can type in stuff and change the story.
So great work and I'll see in the next video.