Hello again you lovely God.
People in this video will continue your tutorial.
We're going to add objective markers.
We're going to give the player a visual marker that's going to move to the next position when it's needed
to.
OK.
So let's go into God.
And on the do go to scenes levels and I open the tutorial when levels which are up there it is.
And you'll notice I've removed those lights I put in I wasn't really feeling those lights.
In fact I've made a new light.
So I'm like a light hoodie and I've uploaded a brand new PFG I made it just a simple thing I made in
GIMP.
It's this radio pangia right here.
I'm going to copy that and I've put this as a download.
You can download it as part of this leches resources or you can make your own.
It's pretty easy.
Where there is more to go show and farm manager got paste in there and got a will import imported.
Great.
So now I'm just going to drop that.
As the texture.
And there it is as the tax year as enable shadows and move the whole light 2D issues and then move on
here to the right place and look at that.
We have a beautiful light.
Now it's up to you whether or not you are disable shadows.
I won't leave shadows on if he do disable shadows.
It's going to go through the walls and a really want.
Another thing you could do is you can make this particular player not cast a shadow.
Which to do that you would right click on a player go to Edit of all children.
And under light occluding to be sure to move him to a different coalition mask.
There is another player won't cast shadows but the background Well OK.
So that's one option we can do.
I'm not going to do that.
I do want to as shadows as such a major part of our game play.
The play should really get used to it and I make this none.
Ed wants to make this nice and tidy.
Nothing we could do I'm going to add a brand new like note in certain of the like tourie.
We could use this torch.
In fact I've put this real wrong place have I seen a move that too light maps that's where there should
be.
And let's go to all that much.
Very much better.
I could just drag in this torch map.
So like to see texture torture map.
Yeah.
Did you do transform.
Scale zero point two five zero point five.
Smalls point five point five.
And this gives some shadows.
And with this one point this at the door.
And just do a little bit rotation before I rotate this.
Actually remember we are casting from the centre not from the edge I should use the offset so my offset
is going to be 320 is that right.
Yes.
And move that.
Now the shadow will cast here where the light is logically emanating from and that makes a lot more
sense to me.
And we've highlighted the door.
So now the player will be able to see the door.
So if I just play the scene.
Much better to have a nice dramatic light here.
And here now an argument could be made for removing the light completely because this is a weird effect.
So it is up to you if you want to remove the shadow.
That's how you do it.
But looking good.
All right.
Let's get into making some objectives.
The first thing to do is I'm going to make a lot of use of position to day.
I have a brand new node to make a node.
You know on a stick to no two weeks I've been doing it for this entire section and I'm gonna call this
objective marker.
Objective markers that we call objective markers.
The first chart of this is going to be a position to date.
And I'm going to move the position to Dee right here.
I want the player to get into this room and that's going be their first objective.
Let's switch off vision for now the players are going to get into here as their first objective.
So this is well going to point to well what's going to be pointing.
Good questions.
Back to tutorial and work at a sprite.
And now let's head to graphics and into interface.
We've got some we haven't been using on AP engy.
Scroll down to all these nice mouse icons.
Now I'm going to use this cross-hair.
You could use a hand.
You could use ways arrows.
Use whatever you feel fits best for your game.
So I'm gonna make my cross-hair bulloo outline.
So I got my sprite here and I went and changed the vision mode Denyer has been reset the script anyway
so I'm going to go back to vision mode and click on this reset.
This is a reset it back to its default so that's fine.
OK.
This Sprite and some blue bar.
It's got to be hard to see in the dark rooms so let's give it its own lights source so what's going
on light too deep.
And we use this trick again I'm going to give it its own light as a sort of fact.
Maybe that's why one would think that the light was too bright.
Let's give it this blue one.
Great.
There it is.
And it's going to loops back there.
That's sure it move the parents or the child.
It's going to now show against the background.
If you don't have it showing make sure that you are not accidentally moving the child and not the parent
which I did earlier.
So I'm just going to lock that in and just pull it off screen for now.
OK.
So now I have the Sprite which I call objective.
Pointer it is.
And in a moment when I move the script get the script to move from place to place to place.
Let's put our positions at this position to day.
That's going to be for the room objective.
Some call that remained active.
Move objective is what it is.
The player has learned to move objective again and duplicate that and call this next door objective.
And the next one Lute object to night vision objective.
Yeah.
And maybe spot on vision correctly.
Do do do do it again.
And would you brigate And this one is going to be looped objective.
And finally exit objective.
Didn't rename that wanted I exist objectively.
Yeah.
Now admittedly the only reason for me to name these right now is so that me as the editor I as the editor
can see where they are.
But that's a pretty good reason.
I'm a dork objectives and be on the door.
My night vision objective is going to be through this tunnel.
My left object was going the other loot and my exit objective is going to be right here.
What I'm doing is I'm setting these up so that later in a script we can move through these.
Remove the top one and then move the pointer to that top one.
I gave these pointers on their own needs objectives on their own aren't going to do anything.
We need some area today so let's put in some areas.
It is for this one.
I'm going to.
Make another note to Dee.
Just get these nice and neat and let's put that as an actual child childish tutorial just what I meant
to do and I would call this objective areas and let's move you downhill skis nice and close.
Which are alright.
First child area today.
And you need a collision.
So let's put on a collision shape to see.
And that's going to be a rectangle.
Okay let's move.
This shape which is going to live right here.
And when they entered this area that's going to trigger the next objective going to expand this using
the extents again.
So there's going to enter this area.
I don't mind if I go through the walls because they only the plekanec to this to make sure that's true.
Let's go back to Eric today and actually set our collisions correctly so you are.
Let's say you're torain.
That's fine.
In fact you don't need to be on any leady but you do need to interact with the players.
The players are going to walk into here and that should trigger.
OK.
Let's give this a name.
You are objective.
Move.
Great.
And I'm going to do this again for the doorman of wondering if the door slips.
Let's make a brand new objective area so area today.
And you are going to be called objective door and you also syndicalism shape.
No I didn't duplicate this because if I did resizing one collision April races all the duplicate collision
shapes unless I clear out the ship and make a new one.
And frankly at that point I may as well make a new area so that's my new area.
And new college actually.
And you live where I do do your new rectangle shape and using the extents you might be wondering either
why they put scale ones on here if we have to use the expanse.
They're removing that three point one sir.
That's why I guess the play would kick on a door.
Which point they can get through here.
And once again I'm going to make sure on the right collision so take it off the player.
But it can interact with a player.
All right the next one is going to the night vision so that's going to be right here right where the
objective is.
So I'm just going to do the same thing.
Brand new erry today and going to call this objective night vision and give that a collision.
I could fast for this but frankly it's probably worth going through it step by step.
Any mistakes I'm making.
Move that to up here and move that to over here or else.
Make sure I've got the actual objective.
Doesn't matter too much but it's nice to move the whole object and extend the.
And go back and check my collisions.
Now the loot I can put another area tutees but I'm thinking it might be easy just to use the actual
briefcase signal and give it a second on body entered and send that to as well so I'm not going to make
the push for that for the exit.
The exit already works as an exit so we now have all these correctly.
Now let's Y them up so we need a script before you that the spec script is due tomorrow which I'm going
to put in these scripts folder go up a couple of levels to scripts and call it a trilogy and were just
going to go back into to TV mode.
And why in these various objectives.
So minimize those that were objective mode on body and touched and your connecting to tutorial and Sainting
for dawn on body entered connect to tutorial.
I'm not renaming anything these names are absolutely fine on body entered and as cases you troll.
We now have all these lovely objectives in here.
Now let's put the briefcase in so on body entered you are already going to the player but you're also
going to connect the same signals going to connect to that tutorial so that's fine on eggs.
I don't need to because when you exit you're just leaving level that's fine.
Great.
So now let's make this work.
When we're using this what I'm actually going to do is move the objective pointer to the area 2D.
Every time we need to see the moment we're ready we can move to it.
So very first thing I do when I make something the ready function.
What are we going to do.
We're going to move or update the objective point.
So let's come up with a name for this let's call it move pointer.
Think update pointer position is probably a better name
because that way when.
When I or someone else looks at the script in a year's time it's going to make sense immediately I don't
know what this is so.
Function update pointer position.
And that's going to happen on ready so let's make the function for it right now function updates.
Waiter position.
So let's get a variable for the point pointers a quainter equals objective point.
And I'm to do the same thing for this objective markers.
Falser marker equals objective markers.
Do do do.
But I don't want the folder I want the first child because I put these in an order so dont get child
brackets zira.
This is working the same way that it would work in an array.
Now in an array if that child was action right would use the square brackets but were using these subtle
brackets.
When I say its the same way I remember the one array the first variable the first value within that
array is object 0.
We're counting from zero not from 1.
Really what we're doing is we're counting the offset from the beginning.
So zero is no offset.
One is one offset but counting from zero is an easy way of thinking about.
So one doing here is I'm setting the marker to be the first child.
So let's get this working very simply by saying pointer position equals marker dot position.
This will only work once but let's see if the pointer gets to the right place that's run this thing.
There it is right there.
No it started down here and it's now moved up here and such to show that again in 2D mode is actually
here but it's spawning here.
OK so let's actually have this updating itself so after we get the position let's remove its objective
markers J.
For some reason I find it hard to write the word objective today.
Objective markers dot remove.
Child.
And what am I removing removing marker which you've already defined as child's error.
Okay now if I've done this correctly if I copy.
Update point a function like so and put it into each of these signals where passes.
We should see that the pointer update that shown us find out that were in position 1 and we have here.
Great many of them don't go through position to
position 3 awesome going again.
Okay so that's all working.
However I don't really want this to go.
When nothing else I want to mull things I a sound effect and I want a fancy animation.
Sound Effect is easy.
Let's start with some facts about options to tauriel when I add an audio stream player.
And if we go right up to the top and the sound effects message Stop day.
So this is my message and put this in here and let you hear it and make sure that this isn't looping
doo doo doo doo.
It is not looping.
If yours is looping unselect it and hit reimport because if that loops that's going to get annoying.
And let's put an update pointer position on the bottom yo all yo string player got play.
So now play the scene.
Every time this moves we should hear.
Great.
So this animation now up to now we've been using animation player animation player is really amazing
and godda right there's a lot of things we can do with it.
Any property can be animated You can even use the animation player to animate the animation player which
is some inception level weirdness right there.
However I want to animate position from here to here and then from here to here from here to here.
I don't really want to load in several animations I'd rather do this once.
So instead I'm going to do something called tween now Tweenies a node that allows you to interpolate
properties or indeed methods between two values in a variety of different ways.
Put simply tween is an animation technique.
We haven't been using it because it's actually more complicated to set up an animation player.
However this is the kind of instance where tween make sense over animation player with a lot of different
variables that we want to move between but we want the movement between them to be smooth.
So let's set up our tween so under a set up of the tween node.
What I did originally want to use a variable but the autocomplete wasn't working with variable so never
might not to interpolate the property.
Great.
So let's start from the beginning.
What property went uploading like a look at documentation in the first instance was the object like
the thing itself.
What's moving what's moving is the point.
So let's try again.
Pointer defined that.
Great.
What's the property as a string.
I will type position and how I know because I can go into the scene treat just like a real time click
on a pointer scroll down to transform and mouse over position.
There is little Tell me if the tooltip comes up there it is property position call.
So back into script view area.
OK so we are moving the position.
Great.
What's our initial starting value.
Well that's pointer dot position.
We ask.
We are starting from where we are.
Where are we going to.
Well where we're going to is market position marker position and at this point in money and space I
hit return and two taps the two tabs is a convention with and God.
Oh just to let you know this is part of the line above.
I float duration.
How do you feel about zero point five.
That's half a second.
What kind of tween effect we have all these different kinds of tweets.
I mean the link you to a short description of what these look like but really just experiment with them.
I haven't used all of these.
I want to start with a sign that something a fun animation what kind of transition type Do we want.
Do easy and an easy out and float delay is optional.
I don't need to put that in.
One more thing we need to do.
We've defined a tween we have an actually starts this lets go tween dot start he goes without that we've
just done maths for no reason.
Okay.
Move you all the way back here and see how that works.
Run the thing.
Look at that.
And now the objective markers moving.
One thing I have forgotten to do by the way I put a camera in.
I should do that put a camera on the player player.
You are going to get a camera camera today and this is current now.
Look at that.
Now right now this is just moving for no reason.
In the next video we can actually put in some text on this but we have movable objective markets.
Which brings me to the challenge.
I'd like you to explore the Twains find the perfect tween for your high spikes to play with the different
kinds of transition types play with the easing.
Don't be afraid to blow the timing.
Make this really fit your game.
Do you want a different sound a different mark.
Maybe you want a big pointy hand we're going to scale it up maybe.
I don't know you want a floaty ball of light or a particle effect.
Pause the video and find the perfect tween for your game.
When you come back are close the video.
And welcome back.
So in this video we have covered some pretty interesting stuff we've looked at tween notes and I'll
be honest tween nodes always make me need to go back to documentation that's always something I do wrong.
It's a lot of moving parts.
So don't be afraid if when you doing it it doesn't come across the first time.
Stick with it.
You'll get the effect you want.
If you are getting the first time fantastic you are better at tweens than I am.
We've also looked at using position to D to Mark positions our map and we've used apparent node in a
race rather than create an array within the script we're using Object orientation in creating an actual
array so fantastic work and I'll see you in the next video.