Hello you fantastic gotto people in this video.
We're going to make sure that the sprite is animated not just the character.
In other words we're gonna make Bunny look more alive.
We're gonna look at the animated sprite note.
Okay so let's get straight into gotto and I'm going to open the player since my default scene here.
I'm going to click on the little film like I can to open the play a scene itself so it just brings me
straight in here.
And you know what.
Let's delete the sprite note.
We don't need it to hit delete.
And there it goes.
There is no sprite.
Very scary.
Well let's add a new note.
There it is.
And let's type an animated sprite slice and blue we know it's two dimensional.
It's a child of no 2D a sprite note that can use multiple textures for animation.
Perfect little warning just comes up.
Okay let's hover over the warning.
It needs a sprite frames resource.
Was that mean.
Well look over here in the inspector animated sprite has a single frames is empty.
Not a problem.
New sprite frames.
That's what we want.
Now when I click on it to bring this down and see under resource open Ed.
This is the bit we want in here.
We can have multiple animations all right.
I've got one called default.
Rename it.
I'll just double click on it.
That's an idle I have a new animation called Idle except I don't yet.
Let's bring some stuff into it so let's open the graphics folder and players and I'm just sticking my
purple Bunny.
But you could do the the brown one and I think stand and ready until he wants.
We're going to slide both of those and drag them in.
There we go.
Okay.
Now you might be think at this point.
Yeah and you told me this is animated.
That's not animated.
Well let's switch back to animated sprite playing.
And there we go.
Bunny is now animated.
I could speed this up or slow this down.
I've got my speed here.
It's going to do five frames every second.
So if I wanted to do one frame per second.
Very slow Bunny painfully slow.
I could do 10 frames a second hyperactive bunny but I keep it five for now.
I can always change it later.
All right let's stop playing Let's Make a new animation.
This little document with a plus on it.
I want another animation called Let's Have jump and for this one I'm going to drag the single Bunny
to jump.
And what else we want.
We won't walk.
OK.
A new animation walk and the drag those two.
Now if I want to play these other animations they don't show up here to get the show up.
I need to refresh the note.
I'm going to click on a different note comeback and they're all in there.
So let's take a walk and bodies walking one Bunny walking faster but he's walking faster.
Ten frames a second seems pretty good.
But again I can tweak it and jump is just a single animation so let's take a look at that.
To do that I need to stop playing walk and play jump.
It's just one frame.
Okay.
Now this is great.
But how I use it.
Well what you do is you call this in script so let's go into script and we're gonna make a new function
called animate and we'll put it right on the move.
So every frame can apply gravity with a jump.
We're gonna move gonna animate.
Let's go down to the bottom of the script and distraction free mode.
There we go.
And I give myself a little bit more space so you can see I'm doing a function animate.
I mean use the shortcut forget node and call animated sprite.
So the whole control and click on animated sprite here it's properties and here its methods is playing
which is a boolean.
Yes it is.
No it doesn't play an animation by string or stop.
Awesome.
That is everything we need.
So if I just start with animated sprites dot play and then I type in the strange we called Idle.
Now if I press play but he's going to play this animation but as I play this animation no matter what.
So we probably want some sort of condition in here.
What I'm gonna do you see here we've put vote motion right to the top of script.
This is now available in every function in the script.
So I'm going to use that if motion dot X which we start with that's not the jump motion that Y is okay.
If you're going up up is less than zero
then I'm going to play the animation jump.
Let's see if I got that right.
Yes.
Okay.
Else if motion dot X is not equal to zero
animated sprite don't play.
Okay so motion or X is gonna be zero.
If we're not moving left and right so let's play and that's going to be walk.
That's what we call that.
So let's see how that works.
Great.
And it's working right.
Okay.
But we're not stopping the animation.
Let's clear it with an idle animation so we can put else animated sprites dot play idle.
I'm sure a double check that's what I called it.
I called it idle.
Jump and walk.
Okay.
Let's take a look how it works.
Jump jump works great walk works great.
Look when I walk left but still face the same way.
Okay.
Quick challenge for you.
Now before I go to the challenge we've got all these properties we can look at.
I'd like to see if you can figure out how to get us to work.
I'd like you to make sure that bunny always faces the way that bunny is walking.
So switch the way bunny is facing depending the direction.
A quick hint you might want to look at the flip each property in the inspector pulls a video give that
a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution
and welcome back.
OK.
So flip h this mouse over it.
If true the texture is flipped horizontally.
So let's take a look at the walking animation and I flip it.
Ah.
Now there is a continuity error right.
This flower is going to magically flip over but I'm okay with that for now.
Okay so how going to use that let's open the script back into the French into diffraction free.
Yes don't refract anything distraction free.
I want extra conditions here.
I don't want this to be not equal to zero.
I need is greater than zero.
So if you're going right then play the walk and animated sprite dot H flip H is what they called me
sprite dot flip.
H equals false right.
This is a boolean is it.
Is it true or false.
If it's ticked it's true there's not ticked it's false.
The next line is the exact the same Elif motion dot X is less than zero.
So if you're heading left to play the same animation
shouldn't it be a capital area.
And I want to flip the animation
because true okay.
And you know what.
Just to make this a little bit easier.
Before I run this go back to level 1.
Let's get out of structural free mode and let's add a camera.
I'm going to add a camera now.
So camera camera 2D.
Perfect.
And my camera needs to be placed about here I think OK.
In order for God to know that I'm using this camera I need to set this as current.
And right now it's the same zoom.
OK so let's zoom out a bit.
Let's say twice as big.
So two X two y press play nice.
OK now I'm going to have a floor in the duplicated the press control.
These brand new floor.
I'm going to move that down here and then control D another one.
Let's try that
OK.
Now I've got one slight issue I'm hitting space as a jumping is part of the time and that's because
I'm using is just pressed.
So if I'm on the floor and nothing else is happening it's great but if anything else is happening it's
going to be consistent.
So I'm actually going to put this back to is action pressed.
Now when I press play ha a bouncy quite fast Bunny I might up the movement left and right speed.
Yeah let's move the left and right speed.
Speed is not give me a thousand thousands maybe fifteen hundred.
Let's see bunny.
Let's put them full screen.
Bunny can move it.
Look at this bunny go.
That's starts to feel good.
You know what with this zoom out I feel like the jumper should be higher.
OK.
Jump speed maybe jump speeds go I like gravity where it is let's put jump speed at 5000 it's go crazy
oh go Bunny.
All right.
That is feeling awesome that's quite a lot character there isn't that.
And with that I think we should stop the video here actually before we do one more thing I should make
really clear.
We looked at Flip H.
We got to leave you didn't look a flip V if we needed it flip v just tons on the vertical.
And that is a good place to stop the video.
And this time I mean it in this video we've looked at how to set up an animated sprite node.
We've looked at how to call animated sprite animations and script and how these flip H and flip V.
Excellent work.
I think we start to get a really fun little game going.
How's yours looking did you.
Do you have complete different settings.
Can your bunny jump very high but gravity is very low.
He's running much slower by much faster.
Are you not using bunnies at all.
Show your progress.
I'm really curious to see what's going on.
Meanwhile great work.
And I'll see you on the next video.