Hello again, you amazing got people.
Let's create the cube do let's put a player into our game.
So we go right into it because last video was very talky.
And let's start by taking a look at the acid against my models of a cube dude and open cube.
You got the eight.
Now, we have three choices here right now because Cube do Doda is an imported file.
It's not gonna let us modify it.
The reason for this is gonna.
Doesn't actually save D.A. files.
It can open them.
It doesn't save them.
So any changes I make here won't be saved.
Now I can make a new inherited scene.
If I do that, it'll take this scene route.
And it's basically imported all the information as a brand new CNN, which has the armature, the skeleton,
the mesh and the animation player.
The other way I could do this is just say we'll open it anyway and don't worry about it.
Right.
In either case, we now have this player here.
And if I make any changes to him.
So I want to rename it.
I can't save it.
So when I close it.
And come back.
It hasn't changed.
So we need a way around that.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to take Cube DDA open him and I must say open anyway.
Let's take a look at our scene.
We've got the seam route we've imported from Blender.
And by default, that's what it's gonna do.
Right.
It's gonna have the special nut.
Then we've got the player itself, which is called Armature, because the way the plate that blender
makes Rick skeleton's and that's a spatial node.
Then we have the skeleton.
The skeleton has a number of bones in it.
So let's zoom right in here and say Bone five is called hips and it's the hip bone.
Right.
And then it's got the mesh in because it was created as a rigged animation in Blender specifically for
using in games.
It's set up to work.
It knows the skeleton is its parents set up, ready to go.
So what I can do is I can save Branch as seen Halo folks.
Yeah.
From the future here from about three videos time.
So later on in this cause I realize I've made a silly mistake here.
When I told you ignore this coalition shake that's coming on a future video.
When I told you that we can.
Right.
Click on the armature and do safe branches scene.
I was absolutely correct.
We can do that.
But I forgot about the animation player.
And the animation player is a child of the scene root here renamed as play a template.
Again, this is all from a late point, of course.
So instead of right.
Clicking here and saying Save Branch seen, what I would do is the following models.
I'm going to go to Cube, dude.
I'm not going to keep the DEA, ODAC and open anyway.
I'm at 16 route and I'm going to go save scene as and then put that in my plans folder.
If you do that, we can then continue where we're going.
But instead of making the armature the kinematic body, which is coming a little bit, we'll make the
singer to cinematic bodies, which is right.
Click on it.
And he change time and there's a kinematic body and everything from there will work fine if you don't
do that.
There's going to be a lot of bug fixing training at the animation to work.
So just a bit of future proofing safe branch has seen is not the correct Kahir because I forgot about
the animation plan.
Make sure you save scene as a TSA n in your players folder and let's make a brand new folder.
And I'm going to call this place and I'm gonna call this play a template.
Dot, TSC.
Great.
So I'm now going to open that scene and close cube dude.
OK.
So his play a template.
Let's rename this too.
Play a template.
OK.
So right now it's like to play a template.
But I can't use it.
Right.
Click on it.
Change type allowed a kinematic body.
Why kinematic body.
The players can have direct control over it and it's going to generate force rather than being moved
by having force supply to it.
OK, so here we go.
We have a play with kinematic body.
We have an issue though, don't we?
We have a node configuration warning.
There's no collision shape.
You can't use it of anybody who doesn't have collision.
That's finally gonna get a collision.
Collision shape is in 3D.
It's in red.
Perfect traditional shape we can use.
Now, we have a couple options here.
If we're making a very, very high precision game, we would want collision that perfectly follows all
of these joints.
But I don't want that.
So I wanna make a new capsule.
We're going to transform.
I want to rotate it all.
I think the x axis by 90 degrees.
Great.
And let's just fit that, so come down here and the radius is point five, I guess.
Look at that.
And it needs to be a little bit higher, doesn't it?
I was going to drag it up on the Y.
And what I want is for the floor to be right here.
Okay.
Now, why am I using capsule shape?
It's often used for simplicity.
Right.
It's very easy for golf to render this collision shape.
It's not that much taller, Trina, but more importantly, it's going to make the game a lot more fun
because the ball is going to have a much more erratic journey when it's being kicked.
If this was a box, for example, coming from the front would mean we could always predict the angle.
But I want that chaos in this game.
I want the players to be running after the ball and trying and getting in there.
It's going to make it feel a lot more skillful when you score a goal.
So that is my collision shape.
They will look at.
We don't actually have a material coming here.
Right?
We're supposed to, but we don't.
Let's take a look at the mission since I click on the mesh.
The surface one, we have this blank material cube dude material.
Now we also have these two other materials that are made for now, Malicki.
This is blank, but we could do is we could just drag in Q2, for example.
We can we can click on it, that albedo, and then drag it in as it happens.
I want the template to not have this so that if I see this, I know that we're dealing with the template
that is looking pretty good.
Okay.
With that done, let's actually use this template to make a ones.
So I make a new inherited scene and it's going to herit from play a template.
I want to call this player Green.
Oh, she'll give them numbers.
Let's get another play out, one much better save you in players.
Fantastic.
And player one is just like that, except it hasn't new material.
So here's why I will be careful of if I change this material.
Right.
So let's say I wake you read and I got to play a template that's changed to.
Why?
Because I have changed this material.
Everything that uses this material is going to change, too.
So instead I'm easy material overwrite.
I we're back to the top and click on this material.
Not a shot of the mesh.
And let's make a brand new special material in here.
Click on that good albedo and bring in my cue.
Did I say and go back to the play template.
The play template does not have this material override.
Right.
I'm doing it this way because if I try and change this base material, even if I use make unique, it
sometimes doesn't work.
Right.
It can be a little fiddly.
So using material override is great when you're going over templates.
So as I play one, it'll will save us like a brand new player.
So.
And you inherit it.
Scene inheriting four plant template.
Same thing.
So play a two.
And I plan to.
Is going to go here.
And it's got a material override, which is you dude blue.
The newspaper material, excellent luck and I'll see you in the next video.