Hello you glorious go to people.
I think this is a really good time to start learning some really good practices.
So in this video we look at reformatting an elegance in coding before we go any further.
Elegance can sound like quite a nebulous concept right.
How could you possibly quantify that coding surely is about logic.
It's not an artistic form to which I would answer.
Actually coding is both just like many artistic forms are also quite logical.
Coding has a lot of room for creativity.
You've already seen that there's multiple ways of doing the same thing.
What we want is what is the cleanest possible way to write our code.
What is the simplest way to get something done in a way that can be understood by the machine doesn't
go through a whole bunch of unnecessary steps and it's easy to read by humans.
So here are some solid tips that we can do.
And I'm gonna look at how to apply them some tips for elegant code.
First the code should be easy to read by human.
Now I've brought this up several times but essentially I should also look at this in six months six
years.
60 is assuming I'm still around when I'm 102 and read it out right I should understand what it does.
This is important because actually Gordo doesn't care if this is easily by human I could give all of
my variables really bad names right.
Instead of calling things like jump speed gravity I could do variable a variable a one variable A1 one
variable a one one one go to is fine with that.
Got it doesn't care if we do spaghetti code spaghetti code is where all the functions and variables
intermingle and everything goes around the place it's really hard to keep track of what's going on it's
like untangling spaghetti but Gordo isn't the only thing that has to work with the code we have to work
with the code and if you start working with a team this is really important.
One script should be in charge of one thing here I'm talking about something called the Single Responsibility
Principle which is a key concept in object oriented programming which is what God does.
A script should be in charge of one thing this has two sides right.
Don't have multiple scripts working on the same thing one thing one script the other side do not have
one script doing multiple things.
As an example we could easily put our entire game into one script.
However the NPC movements the way the music is played the way the sound effects are handled have no
business in the play script because when I'm looking at this I should know this is the play a note.
It has a play a script it handles player things I should not expect to find the NPR season that encapsulate
now this is a core concept in or object oriented programming and I'm not go into a lot of depth with
that but what I'm looking for here is if a nodal function is missing the game should run fine in other
words we need to write this in such a way that we could remove an entire section of code and it won't
cripple the game it won't crash and that's what we're going to be doing here.
So let's give it a go and I'm going to open the play a scene.
The easiest way to do that is just to get to my plan ode and touch a little film icon.
So here I am in the placing we've got this animated Sprite and I think animated sprite should be handling
the animation.
That's what an animated sprite does right.
So I'm going to rename this player animation which is going to break the script right because right
now the script is calling down here a node called animated sprite no longer exists.
Important point but that's going to be okay because I'm gonna change this.
Now a really good way of doing this already good practice to get into is if you're encapsulating your
code encapsulate your scenery yarn What do you mean by that.
You said encapsulate too many times.
Here's what I mean.
Every scene should have its own script.
If a node within that scene has its own script it's actually an inherited scene so player.
Animation should be a new scene.
So let's save player animation as a new scene.
So I'm going to right click on it and to save branch a scene and save it in player because it's part
of the placing player animation that's ESPN and look it's a brand new scene that I can open and all
it is is the animation player.
Great so now I've got this animation player.
How do I get it working.
Well there's a few ways.
If I open the script one thing we could do is just change animated sprite to player animation and this
will work right.
So if I just replace all of these with a copy and go paste paste
and paste when I press play now the game should work exactly the same way and it does.
But what happens if I remove this note if I remove this node I am now calling a function that is looking
for a node that will no longer be in the tree.
So what can we do to make sure that the player is just transmitting information and doesn't care if
it's something they want to hear it.
In other words if for some reason this node gets removed if I delete it from the scene tree for whatever
reason it should still work.
I'm going to use a signal now I a player and I go to node you know just there is no transmit my movement
right.
So I'm going to have to make a new signal.
So how do I do that.
Well up here I'm declaring my instance variables that is the variable that's available throughout this
instance throughout this entire script.
Underneath them I mean right signal new keyword.
And what's the signal called.
It's gonna be called animates okay.
So I now have a signal called animate and what I'm going to do is under animate.
I'm going to comment out all of this code for now and instead let's put it up top here.
I'm going to emit signal animates and the tip is telling me you can put more stuff if you want what
I want to put in.
I would put in motion
let's take a look at emit signal summoner just like a real time press controller click on it emits the
given signal signal Varg and Varadero.
Remember it's not all cash variable arguments how many arguments we like to put in.
I just want one.
OK so now I have a signal.
Let's save the script.
How can I use it.
Well get out of distraction free mode gets my notes and click on player and look there's a brand new
one could animate now I can now connect it.
But in order for it to be connected to player animation has to have a script.
Look what happens if I try and connect it.
There's no script connect target method not found.
Okay great.
I just need put a script on that.
Let's go to play our animation as a scene and give it a new script called animated called Play animation
G.D. and it's living in the play a thing is just fine.
Great.
I don't want to read.
Function to save that.
Get back into my play a scene and not only connect the signal so with the no tab on the on the right
here assuming you got the default view click on animate player animation is going to create a brand
new method could on player animate.
Boom.
Now when I'm passing this information through I'm in a pass in an argument which we're calling motion
I'm sure I'll put motion in here.
So now what's going to happen is every frame it's going to emit a signal called animate with the argument
motion.
We've now connected it in the inspector to this animated place that this animated sprites note at which
point it's going to trigger here.
So let's get rid of these little gaps.
Yeah.
Okay.
So when I miss a signal which can trigger this function on player the plan node animate with the argument
motion.
So that's going to come through it's all nicely connected.
Great.
So this is going to happen every frame and it's going to pass through a value called motion.
Let's take a look what motion is.
Motion is a vector to right which is right here.
Vector two.
Okay.
So now I've got a challenge for you.
I'd like you to complete player animation all cheat.
Complete the function on player animate.
It should have jump walk left walk right.
An idle quick tip.
We've actually done most of this.
So pause the video give that a shot and when you're ready come back and I'll show you how I do it.
Welcome back.
OK.
How would I do it well if I said we've already kind of done this.
And if I scroll down the player all this information is almost right.
So if I cut this using control X on windows and I go to player animation at G.D. and I paste it here
and I uncommon it almost right but now it's trying to call a child node called player animation.
It doesn't need to do that it just has to do its self.
Now admittedly I could do self docs play don't do that right self-taught play is exactly the same as
play don't put redoubling code in.
Not elegant.
So what you do is remove all of these get nodes get no gun get gun No no no more your gun does good
song you can use I feel like okay so now I play this it should behave exactly the same way.
Right so it looks identical from a player point of view but look what happens if I'm in the player scene
and I delete this
press play now admittedly I'm not.
See the bunny but the game doesn't crash.
Now as far as the game since and the bunny still here we just can't see it so I could put a new Sprite
in let's put a sprite for the moment just to test this out and give its your graphics on G graphics
players.
This one
it works just fine.
So now we've built in some redundancy if for some reason something is wrong our code only got back into
this tree and undo those changes that we got.
If for some reason the node is missing it's still going to work.
You're going gonna check my signal so connected and there it is.
So what we're really doing here is just making sure we have some basic good practices right best practices.
And if we just look over our script more time I've removed all of the functionality for animation for
control and animated sprite from the player.
It's just now transmitting the signal and not caring who who hears about it.
If we wanted to we'd have multiple things deal with the motion.
If I don't know you have an onscreen display that shows you which way you're moving for some reason
or you're using a mobile game or whatever it is we can now use that signal and the player script doesn't
care who's dealing with that signal.
We've connected it here in the inspector the only player animation ever hears it because the player
as a kinetic body doesn't care about the animated sprite.
Anything within the same scene trees the player if it can hear the signal will work and the only thing
that can hit the signal is the player animation mode which is this animated Sprite and it only hears
that because we have connected the signal.
Now we could also connect the signal and script but there's no real reason to do that.
So what we've done here is we've made our code a lot more robust and at the same time more elegant it's
easier to read.
And that brings us to the end of the video in this video we've had a quick introduction to elegant coding.
We've looked at the single responsibility principle.
We've learned how to save a branch as a scene how to take a node and making a separate scene and creating
an emitting a custom signal.
And our game is looking a little bit cleaner as a result.
So excellent work and I'll see you in the next video.