Hello you fantastic gotto people in this video let's make a better looking level we're not gonna use
these template gotto blocks we've got going let's make something that looks good that fits the aesthetic
of our game.
Let's do that.
We're going to use a tile map.
Tom map is an awesome node.
I'm really looking forward to this.
So let's get right into it.
What I want to do is create brand new seemed to create my tile map.
And it's gonna be a 2D scene.
I'm gonna click on that.
It's just a basic node 2D.
I mean rename this to be platform tiles.
Now if we're using this there's a specific hierarchy we want.
Okay.
So we want a Sprite
that has a static body
and that static body has to have collision of some kind.
Okay.
So each tile has to look like this.
And what we going to do is make multiple tiles in one scene
that all have static body 2D and collisions.
Convert them into a single object is gonna be called a tile map
and then use that in our game.
So first let's bring in some sprites.
So I'm going to go over to graphics and we have environment and we have all of these tiles.
You know I'm going to drag them all in and say What are these.
These are sprites and it's got an added all of them in which is lovely.
That's exactly what I want.
It actually matter where they are right now.
I'm going to put them in.
I'm doing it this way because they've been named correctly.
Right.
I don't have to bring in a sprite to rename it grout cake ground cake small.
They have the right name.
Cool.
So we now have a bunch of large and small platforms each themed around a thing.
I'm going to organize them in a way that makes sense to me visually.
Again it doesn't actually matter where they are each one of these has to have OK.
So first thing I said each one needs a static body so it's at a static body 2D and that needs some sort
of collision.
Now right now I'm working on this large cake piece and let's give a static body to a collision piece
and I'm not going to use collision shape collision shape is for making regular shapes.
This is an irregular shape which is a polygon
great.
Now if I wanted to I could be incredibly precise here.
I could press this add point button create.
Point this little green plus and I could get as close as I can to the individual pixels right.
So if I'm making something really precise something like Super Meat Boy I would want to get in as far
as I can but actually I'm not making something like that.
I don't mind if it's a little bit cheeky.
So to do that own work with a grid let's got a view and do show grid and we can configure upgrade with
these three dots here.
I'm going to go figure snap.
Right now it's 10 by 10.
I'm okay with that and I can pick my ground cake and make sure it's actually on the grid.
Well how do I make sure it's on the grid.
I think to snap to the grid that's this magnet with the three dots on it.
Okay.
So now it's snapping to the grid
I want to make sure there's much of my cake is possible is on a grid which is a little bit tricky because
not the right size I might actually have to configure the snap.
Yeah let's configure the snap so get configure snap and s I feel like Kenny likes multiples of eight
some to try a grid of eight.
See how that looks.
Leave that alone.
I'm just making sure that as many pieces as possible are actually on grid points.
That looks pretty good.
Okay.
And I'm gonna add some points.
Great point and I'm just going up to a slightly rough and ready because I can fix this in the moment.
Polygon
you should have finished.
There we go.
Great.
And what I can do is I can move these points with this little blue arrow symbol here I can drag these
points if I don't want that one to delete the one entirely that we got.
Okay so I could drag these out so I can come off the snap right now and just get these as close as I
can.
And that's looking a lot more precise isn't it.
Let's hide the collision.
We could just see the outline of the polygon that's looking pretty good.
Drag you out if a drag on the line is going to create a new point which is handy.
Okay.
That's pretty solid but I don't just want one I want multiples and really I would like them to be identical.
Small platforms will get their ankles in shape but the large ones should be identical.
What we'll do is I'm actually going to create a duplicate of the static body and my press control D
and I can drag that down to the grass.
Be careful I can't just use it as is and the reason why if I enable this robot I'm looking at this grass
piece which is this one and the collision shape is down here.
Why is it down there.
This is the position it was at when I created it and if I look at the transform select a static body
to to look at the transform look the X is minus thirty point eight and the Y is minus 300.
Let's just reset that the position is now 0 0.
All positions are inherited from their parent.
What is telling me is it's 0 from its parent on the x 0 from part of the Y.
So I'm going to duplicate that again and do the same thing with the sand and the same thing with the
snow.
I'm going to go to my static body to D3 to transform reset the position there it is and the static body
2D 3 again it should be for you and for just.
Feel better about myself and to transform and reset it.
So now the collision will be the sprite is.
Otherwise the collision would be a whole bunch pixels that way a whole bunch of pixels this way.
OK I can now minimize those and I'm going to very quickly make a another static bot enclosure shape
for the start of the small group the small cross piece.
For this small cake piece so cake small and you need a static body be and you need a collision polygon
that's control a collision polygon do P2P do and let's get back on my grid and make some points.
OK.
Now if you don't have a solid read shape it means that your collision shape is twisty and on itself
a little bit.
You might want to fix that.
It's got to move and just come off grid so I can see what I'm doing.
And get these as close as I can to something nice.
You can got here you can go up here and that's looking a little bit better.
You live down there.
Okay.
Like I say a little rough and ready but I'm happy with that.
And now I'm going to do this duplicate trick again some of the duplicate three things.
One two three.
You live on grass small you live on sand small home days dragging them down.
So you live on snow small and now let's make sure that you're all in the right place.
So reset the transform for you.
Reset the transform for this one
and reset the transform for this one.
Okay.
We now have a bunch of tiles.
How do I make a tile map.
Well I need to do is get a scene convert to tile set or about mesh library that's for 3D tile maps called
grid maps which are amazing but we'll be doing this for a while as do tiles.
Let's put this in levels and let's call this tile set.
Now if I just press safe now say you need an extension.
I need to pick one of these.
On the pic dot two areas should a resource file and that is good to go to say the scene.
I'm going to save it in levels with the actual levels and go to Level 1.
And how do we use this.
Well let's delete our flaws.
By flaws.
Okay now Bonnie is just going to fall.
We need to put on a tile map.
Let's add a new node called Thailand tile map Node node for 2D 2D tile base maps.
And now I just need to bring my tile set in here.
I'm going to go load levels.
Tiles.
I could just write it in and look.
Here are all our tiles.
Now some things you should know.
1 the tile map has a position that position is 0 0.
It's going to create a single object with these tiles.
All right.
So I press this this this and this and then I move the whole tile map which I to do I got to transform
position 10 on the X.
It moves everything.
This is all one object.
Now when I press play
they all have collision.
All right.
I want to zoom out and just make a very basic looking level.
So that's my tile map and this makes more cake.
Boop boop boop boop.
Don't need this one right click on a position and it's good delete it.
Look at this.
I can paint the level but small platform here.
I shouldn't want it here.
It gets small platform here.
This mix is a little challenging and some grass beneath it.
Now when I press play the camera doesn't move right so I have a platform game with a bunny immediately
goes off screen.
No use to me.
Let's get a little time on the camera Judy.
First let's delete this one.
We go into my play a scene and I'll make a new camera 2D here.
Great thing.
Make it current.
Camera won't work.
Is not current.
That's going to get old Zoom.
I actually wish you zoom out further.
You think 3 3 might be a bit crazy let's find out press 3.
Oh that's quite a lot isn't it.
Maybe it's too much.
Also you'll notice I can move left and right a little bit before anything happens.
Maybe I don't want that if I want that I can go to drag margin right so I can disable drag margin entirely.
And now if I move slightly the camera move maybe I do want it but I want it more or less get a drag
margin and change the amount here.
I've also got something called smoothing if I enable smoothing the camera doesn't move instantly the
camera will follow me.
See how it's coming along now.
So we were really like this.
Some people don't like it disable it.
It's fine.
I'm on leave mine off now because I want to be able to see where bunny is right away and what's around.
There's a few more things you can do.
Limit.
Maybe I don't want a camera to go any farther left.
Maybe 0 0 the Global Zero is as far left you can go so let's go zero on the left.
You are now limited.
You cannot go farther left than that.
And now the camera won't go left but it will go right.
Maybe it will put smoothing on.
Oh dear.
I'm already bad in my own game as well smoothing back on see there's an easier
little bit.
Oh boy I'm bad at my game.
I might even zoom out a little bit more.
However now I can make a little bit of a level so let's stop here and do some stuff.
I'm going to go.
You know what I mean some snow down here and I feel it should be quite a long level so I'm going to
continue my cakes for a bit and it is a bit challenging think I can jump that high.
Pretty sure I can jump that high just in case.
I'll put you here and a few more bits and pieces and I can extend this level it's very easy to use rack
right click on any tile and it vanishes.
Remember though the position of the tile is where the grid position it.
So if I want get in this one I can't right click here I have to right click that and you see the little
squiggles blue.
Right that means it's a tile that you'll note.
You can only have one tile in each position.
Right.
So if I put this one here and I want to put a small one here I can't
put you back.
One more thing ought to do before go any further I want to make sure that the game knows which bits
which to do this I'm going to use something called Collision if a local player and I got a physics buddy
Judy he got these weird things he got layers and masks.
The basic principle is this I am on this layer I can interact with this mask.
Now later we're gonna be using these quite a lot.
So what I need to do is set these up.
I a project Project settings and scroll down to layer names on 2D physics and I'm gonna name these play
ones in player layer 1 not plan 1 let who's gonna be terrain.
OK so select a player a fact that's gonna play a scene here we go.
So let the player go to collision player is on layer 1 and this is a bit wise layer right.
So he can be on multiple layers like Well now one this one of this one that's fine but this is the player
and I can interact with terrain let's go back into level one go to tile map and make sure my collision
is selected and I'm sure take it off the player outcome mouse over and see what it is and also the terrain
layer and it can interact with the player cannot interact with terrain this is gonna become important
for us play and let's take a look at eye level yeah that's it's coming on quite nicely so this leads
me to the challenge I would like you to use your tile map to make an awesome level and I would challenge
you to share the level you made with the community I've made a very rough and ready one I'm actually
gonna be tweaking this as we go but I challenge you to stop playing the tarmac make something creative
so pulls the video make a tile map and when you come back we can wrap this up
welcome back before we finish a quick reminder on how these layers and masks work collision is gonna
be really important.
Collision Les is the layer I exist on and I can exist on multiple layers so I can use this as a sort
of tagging system so maybe I'm a hazard and I'm part of the terrain and I'm an NPC I don't know why
NPC because of the terrain but maybe you can maybe I'm a player but I'm also something else right.
Collision masks are the layers that I can interact with so I'm a player I can interact with anything
that calls itself on the following layers so the bunny can interact with anything that is terrain but
it can't interact with anything that's a player if I had multiple players and I've seen the bunnies
would go through each other they wouldn't interact at all.
Which brings us to the end of the video in this video how to work with a grid how to create a tile map
how to use collision layers and collision asks we've looked at similar properties of camera 2D we also
looked at how nodes inherit properties from the parents member who made that collision polygon and it's
and the transform was in the wrong place we put to zero zero zero zero means zero from your parent not
0 from global so great work I hope you had fun making your levels I look forward to seeing what they
look like and I will see you in the next video.