Hallelujah.
Glory is God's people in this video we look at a function called is on ceiling which is a function of
kinetic body 2D and is really useful.
It's really useful because we have a little bug in our game.
What happens if you jump and hits the ceiling.
Do you keep going.
Well Bunny does.
Let me show you why I put a new tile in this plan and put tile right here so it's easy to get to press
play.
I would expect that I could hit a ceiling and bounce off.
But that's not actually what happens right.
My motion continues until the jump wears off.
Well that's not ideal.
So let's fix it.
And to do that we should just take a quick look at our script.
I'm at the apply gravity function here which you can get to by clicking the shortcuts all the shortcuts
and methods you've made.
And let's take a look at how gravity is working.
If we're on the floor sets the vertical motion motion don't y to be zero.
In other words don't go up don't go down.
Otherwise apply gravity.
Okay.
So if we're not on the ground we're applying gravity.
Cool.
However when we jump we're modifying vertical movement by jump speed which is right here.
I've said it to fifteen hundred.
So my motion why it immediate set to negative fifteen hundred.
And then every frame is lowered by gravity times delta y times delta.
Moving slide uses Delta.
So in other words I have to wait for my jump speed to wear off.
That's no good to me I need a way of resetting it.
So what I'm going to do is use is on ceiling which is just like is on floor let's remind itself how
that works.
Take a look at the documentation is on floor returns true if the bodies on the floor only updates when
we're calling move and slide.
Moving on is on ceiling does the exact thing same thing for the ceiling and everything else can be done
with is on a wall.
Remember however that God only knows about floors and ceilings.
If we tell it God is going to assume this is a top down game unless we tell you otherwise which we've
done.
If we look at move and slide the first argument linear velocity How far are you moving and in what direction.
Second argument floor normal.
So we have a floor.
The perpendicular from the floor is this direction.
That is up with defined that right.
So if we look at our move in slide function first argument is motion.
Second argument is a constant called up which is right here vector to zero comma minus one minus one
is up in two dimensions and remember negative one and the Y is up.
Okay so now I need to do is figure out use is on ceiling.
So what we do is put an elusive Elif is on a ceiling and what do we want.
Well that's actually my challenge for you.
I'd like you to complete is on ceiling so that Bonnie doesn't hover.
Suppose a video give it a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution
Welcome back.
All right.
So clearly on asset set something with motion Dot.
Why.
Now I'm not going to go.
Plus equals or minus equals.
I'm going to set it to something not modified to something whatever it was before.
It's something else I want to hit the ceiling and bounce off.
I don't want it to be zero because that's going to let me hover again.
I want it to be one positive one is down just move down by a pixel.
Because if you move down by pixel you'll no longer on the ceiling.
Well let's see if that works.
Boing boing boing boing boing.
Yes that's what I expect to see.
Right.
I expect to see Bunny bouncing off ceilings.
That's much more like it.
And in fact it's kind of fun when bling bling bling much more like it.
Bye Bunny.
Before we go any further let's do a quick quality of life change.
What if I open the game again.
You know I just want to get past here.
Bunnies get me in the set and scream but I want to see further to the right.
That's actually not that helpful for me.
So let's move the camera mean over the placing like so and I'm going to quickly remind you about how
properties work.
So camera 2D here's my transform under the no 2D properties 0 0 0 the x 0 the Y.
In other words you are in the center in the center of what of your parent all these properties inherit
from the parent.
This is not a global position.
Right this is the position from the parent.
So what I want is to move along the x with zoomed out quite fast.
I want to move by a thousand and to make this really work I'm gonna switch off my drag margins and make
sure that I've got smoothing switched on here and here.
So now in a press play and I get away from the edge the camera center is here.
Bunny is a thousand behind and look at that much more like it now moving backwards is more of an issue.
I could maybe put a script in there but I don't really want to.
I quite like it like this.
So quite short and sweet but I think it's enough for this video in this video we've looked at how to
use it on ceiling.
We've stopped bunny from floating and we've just checked that we're bouncing off things rather than
hovering on them.
It's a great work and I'll see you on the next video.