Hello again you delightful God people.
Let's shine some light on the matter in this video.
We're going to add a flashlight or a torch.
I mostly could be saying torch because I am from Britain and that's what we say.
But if you want to see flash like you say flashlight.
This really is really about light too deep and occlusion before we get down to it.
Couple of things first.
In the final version of our game the player is not going to have a torch.
Cameras and guards will but to get it working and to put it on the player.
As a scene and then we can drop that scene as an instance of the worries and pieces.
Second like 2D has a peculiarities.
So the first thing I need to know is that light to download needs a light map texture you need to create
it texture.
To tell it how the light behaves.
Very simply we need is an image of the beam of light and where it is bright the light will be bright
and when it is black there will be no light.
I provided you with a little cone of light that starts bright and trails off.
It's very simple to make.
Took me a few seconds in GIMP.
Secondly you need to know is that like map is calculated from the origin of the node not from the texture.
So one of the bugs you can get is you think your flashlight is working properly but when you actually
activate it or the occlusions and replaces what seclusion occlusion is shadow it's it's a mask you can
put on just like a collision layer that says if the light hits here stop the light you don't stop all
the light only the light that is on the right layer light on inclusion.
Use layers just like collisions.
Don't worry about memorizing all that stuff to have in the back of your mind percolating what would
work.
But let's get to it.
What I would do is create a new scene and I'm going to use and liked to do you know what.
I'm going to call this torch.
And the warning it's telling me if I just mouse over it is that you need to have a texture.
OK so here's my texture.
Let's get to my light Matt falder this torture map.
And there it is.
You'll notice you can't see it.
So let's save this for now.
Not what's going on.
So this is scenes and let's open our play a scene and an instance of player will put in a torch.
Okay so here's my torch.
When we save the play a scene and updates the main scene you'll see there's a thing going wrong here.
Now this is because the texture is on the centre of the torch.
And for look at the plan a..
The torch is right in the centre of the plate.
And then a move it just a little bit to about here.
Save that hook.
That didn't change anything.
Do not keep moving this texture.
If we look at the torch as a..
I don't want to drag it all the way there because the shadows calculate from where this crosses.
If I drag it to here the shadows will calculate from there.
I need to move the texture NOT the notes.
I'm going to use texture offset.
I happen to know that this texture is about three hundred and twenty.
Yeah.
So the Tetris offer 640 wide so 320 is half of that.
So now the light 2D is positioned where the axes but the texture is where the boxes.
If I say that we now have a working torch.
Let's take a look at it.
All right so right now this isn't behaving like a torch right.
This is behaving like a we are trying.
We need a few things.
One we need the place to be darker.
This flashlight only works if there's a dark room too.
We need shadows.
Well the first problem is very easy to do as a child of Level 1.
I don't make a new node and I use canvas modulate modulate allows you to change the colour of something
canvas modulate allows it to change the colour of the canvas the entire viewport.
So if I minimized this and I pick a nice dark blue very cinematic trick all night is blue.
I actually make this darker in the final game.
But for now it's play.
And already that's looking better at shadows.
Any object can have an explosion.
Right so I'm going to use a node called occlusion which families an object.
So if I want to make a play or an NPC I can give it occlusion just that collision.
If I want to do an auto tile then uh press walls tile set an auto tile click on auto tiles and here's
the occlusion tab.
And this works exactly like the collision perhaps or I have to do is select a tile make sure that my
step is correct only 64 by 64 for each grids point and I'm just going to go click click click click
click so I select the tile select polygon and create my religion.
Obviously I'm going to speed this up as we go because this is a little bit fiddly but I promise you
it will be worth it.
Okay and that should be all of them just going to double check that everything that has collision has
occlusion and a bit map.
Okay time consuming a little irritating but worth it.
So first mendis must save it and I don't think this will work out the box and I'll show you why.
So first let's save my time and press play.
I haven't switched shadows on just like cameras need to have a current camera set and railcars have
to have enable set lights have to have shadows.
So I go back to torturing and find shadow in the inspector and enable it save that.
And now you press play.
Oh yeah.
That we have shadower if you're not getting shadow by the way something you should be checking just
make sure that the occlude are offset isn't set to any value.
So by that I mean go into walls going to order tile and you'll see occlude offset.
What this is doing is it's taking the size of the tile map and halving that.
That means that my shadows are actually 864 by 640 pixels off where I want them to be.
So my shadows are down here to my right I can't see them.
Let's set that to 0 0 and you'll see it's doing the exact same thing with navigation offset.
We're not using navigation but I'm a set to 0 0 anyway because reasons.
Now when you press play.
You should have shadowers to show what it will look like without.
If you're getting this bug.
No shadows.
So just make sure that your shadows aren't being cast off screen.
Right.
I'm now going to do one more thing I want to put shadows on players or one of those on an incense in
just as a test.
The character sing character and then move him somewhere where he could be seen.
OK.
If I press play we ever play the character the character has no movement to it it can't do anything
and it doesn't cast in the shadows has occlusion but doesn't cache others.
Let's give Shadow to the character and that's gonna inherit down to the player and any guards we put
in later.
So let's open the character scene.
Zoom in and add new note and it's going to be like occlude a hoodie.
So clude a light occlude attorney.
Okay I need a new occlude a polygon and now I need to draw a polygon.
This is create.
This is at subtlest you create a zoom in nice and tight.
No I can't use shapes like religion unfortunately so I'm just going to go click with that grid view
on.
I don't want grid as move that point.
In fact you know what let's start that again on the little down arrow clear.
Make sure my grid is off.
I don't want add on.
This can be a little rough and ready.
I was going to click click.
By x.
I can edit some of these if I mouse over it because he wanted to do so.
I want to remove a points or right mouse button at this point.
And I want to move this one down here.
This one down here.
Just get something that's roughly right.
So let's make this a little bit bigger.
So looks roughly right.
Yes.
Add one in.
So that's what is that that is control and left mouse.
If mouse.
Just move that point over here.
There's a good that looks pretty good.
So it's a little rough and ready you can tweak your heart's content.
What I'm going to do now is well let's test that it works to level one.
How it does work.
With one caveat I now can't see the person because the occlusion mask is stopping light from entering
the sprite at all to fix that.
Back to my character click on includer and change the call mode to either clockwise or counterclockwise
just a clockwise.
And then we have seen a play that's the wrong thing.
We can now see the character and the character is casting a shadow.
The player will also cast a shadow.
So we now have working light and shadow in our games.
Now you can add static lights if you want to.
If you wanted to put in little lamps just make a little white map for it and place them around the place
of them.
The player walks into them.
They'll be visible but this is really good.
So now I've got a challenge for you and this challenge isn't one that's going to be directly used in
games but it can be the foundation.
So they would do a little later setting the torch so that the player can switch it on and off with a
keypress.
OK so what we want is we want to be able to activate or deactivate the torch by pressing a key.
Some quick reminders if we go into project settings input map you can either use for example you select
which is space we can define your own keys.
So suppose the media give them a shot and when you come back I'll show you my solution.
Welcome Mac.
OK.
So this is really a script.
I'm a in play for now so we could put a function here called Tomball torch.
Right.
And then call that every frame.
That's bad practice to slow things down.
So instead let's make some big circuits in them doing instead let's go a function toggle torch.
And what I'm going to do is call that when the player pressed the button.
So let's go in put event as a function function input event and if input dot is action just frescoes
as a toggle we don't have to hold down new space which I know is you guys select.
And then I'm going to go toggle torch.
So what do we need to happen and hold torch.
Well I need to get the torch.
So if torch helps us on the zero area and now I need to use a property of torch.
So let's look at the properties of torture quick.
And you can see it has enabled so just by mousing over it like I don't toggle torched dot enabled.
And this is a booleans that's a truffaut's.
So if the torch is enabled then I want to disable it right so torch dot enabled because false else.
Torch dot enabled.
He calls group.
And now when we press space which would switch the torch on and off.
Not bad.
We now have lights that we can switch on and off.
Now this will be linked to a change in vision mode so this is a little dark right now but there will
be a game play version for it later.
But look at that.
We have some real functionality and already the beginnings of a good looking game with some little lighting
tricks and a few other things you could really make something special here.
And that brings us to the end of the video.
In this video we've looked at how to use a light to dinard.
We have made we've looked at how to make sure your lighting and light matter are aligned and have a
set of a light occlude to do you know as well as how to set up a kloof in an altered tiling.
Some of this is a little fiddly but really helpful stuff because now we can make levels that cut shadows
and have collision very quickly and we can make multiple levels.
So really great work.
Go on the next video.