Welcome back.
You are amazing although people in this video going to start work on play detection.
Now you might have noticed the slide says Play detection one field of view that implies it's going to
be a play detection too.
You're quite right.
In this video we're going to figure out are you within the view angle in the next video.
We're going to figure out if there's anything blocking that line of sight.
So let's talk a little bit about what's going to have to happen if I wanted to play detection.
I need to set up that field of view.
We need a way of telling God oh this is what the the NPC can see anything outside of that you can.
Now we're going to use the light being to indicate the player where the field of view is.
Do bear in mind.
That's pretty arbitrary.
I'm just doing it because it's a good gameplay mechanic that the player can see where they can be seen.
And I need that field of view to rotate with the NPC.
Otherwise it's completely pointless.
I also need to check if the players in that field of view and give the player some sort of feedback.
I'm going to change the color of the torch.
Okay.
So what are the NPC needs to know what direction and my facing.
That's pretty key right.
What direction is the player in.
So if I'm facing east and my field of view is a certain degree is the player within that degree.
Are those two things within tolerance.
All right.
So at this point I would normally jump straight into gotto but we do need to figure out a couple more
theory things first so let's take a look.
Now I'm not gonna read this out to you.
I'm just gonna paraphrase it.
All of our sprites face to the right.
So forward is a vector two of one comma zero one on the x zero on the Y and then we can use the function
rotated and we can tell it what that's going to rotate by then we can use global rotation so whatever
your global rotation is changed that as your default directions your forward direction.
Now let's figure out the direction between me and the player.
The player is right here and the guard is right here and arbitrarily that's when the player is at 2
come a 1 globally.
And the guard is at 1 comet 2.
What I care about is this direction.
And it turns out this direction is a vector of one common one.
That's one on the Y and one on the X..
And we can figure this out mathematically.
The direction to the player is.
Player Position minus my position.
So it's a quite easy formula and all we need to do is remember if I want the direction to something
that's it minus me we are going to have to normalize that and that means we care about the direction
of the vector but not the magnitude of the vector a little bit of background a vector measures both
magnitude and direction we only care about the direction.
Okay.
Finally we have field of view.
It's gonna be roughly 40 degrees I believe.
But what we need to know is that there's a facing direction and a positive and a negative as we add
angles to it go this way.
So we need to do is cut this in half and tell it check both of these directions.
So our field of view tolerance is only 20.
That was a lot of theory.
Don't worry if you did memorize all that it should hopefully become clear before we actually get started.
Let's make the template level our default scene.
So when I run the game it'll run from here.
So project settings.
Run.
And our main scene.
I'm gonna click on here and go up 1 and let's go to levels and for now will you template level.
Great.
So now in a press play we should be on the right level.
Yes we are awesome.
OK let's now start editing these pieces.
I'm going to start with camera so let's open the camera scene and I would put my Sprite here on camera
body.
Now our script is going to be the same for all n pieces and they're going to inherit from.
This is the simplest NPC type.
OK.
So when we start having gods that can over on the level they're going to inherit this and our play detection
script is going to inherit from the character template.
So it has to be a cinematic body.
OK.
So let's add that and first thing to do is name it.
They can live in peace.
That's a good name but good location not a name.
We're gonna call it player detection dot G.D..
And I put dot.
It doesn't know what kind of thing it is inherits.
Click on the little folder go back up and it's going to inherit template character.
So now any any NPC will be able to make use of this script and let's start by defining some constants.
I need an F ova tolerance tolerance or great typing.
There we go.
I'm gonna call that 24 now 20 degrees F of tolerance the beam of light is roughly 40 degrees half of
that is 20 and let's define some colors as well so color red equals and we use the color keyword with
the American spelling and in here I can use a few different formats but I want this one red.
Let's say one comma zero point two five comma zero point two five red green blue.
I'm having a little bit of green a little bit of blue and I want a bright vivid red but that's what
I want.
Let's have a white which I'm going to use as color.
1 1 1.
All right one more thing I need I need a variable called Claire which we're going to define I'm going
to find it in the ready functions so function ready to do.
Nope never found you.
Okay let's slow down a bit player equals.
Now I don't want to use an absolute path of the player.
Right so my camera isn't here.
I don't want to say go up one go up one go down to the note player.
What happens if I start shuffling things around.
What happens if I have subdivisions within subdivisions instead.
We only have one node with the name player.
Let's find it to do that.
I need to go to the root of the scene root is a hidden node at the top of your scene.
So let's go slash root.
OK.
So that will get the root node and from here it's gonna go to white screen mode.
We can go find node find nodes.
Let's take a look at the documentation finds a descendant to this node whose name matches the string.
It's case sensitive yada yada yada yada.
If it's owned only find nodes whose owner is this note that's important.
So how do we use that.
Well we only have one node with this name.
This is recursive looking all child nodes.
And it is not owned by this node and that's going to set the player to be the only node with the name
player.
Now this only works because we have a single node called player.
If we had another node call play this would start getting really complicated and we have to figure out
a different solution.
For now I'm kind of happy with that.
Okay.
So we've defined that in a way came out of that mode.
Now let's do something in process function a process
and put a little bit of room there.
Right.
So what do we need to do.
Well I need to check if the player is in the field of view.
If the player in F Ovi I think that's good.
Let's make a function
so function player in F Ovi.
Okay.
So if this so at the end of this we're gonna return true or false so every frame is gonna check.
Are you true or false.
Now let's define that.
First we need to do is define NPC facing direction.
Well we've talked about that but I was going a little bit far so let's do this nice and slow.
This is going to be a direction it's a vector too and it's to the right and not up on down.
So it's one of the x zero on the Y and we need that rotated by global rotation.
So now the script knows that the NPC US is facing to the right by rotated by whichever direction is
actually facing so it knows which way forward is correct.
Now we need to get that direction to the player so direction to the player.
You'll notice I've put a capital P in play here.
That's because I'm referring to a specific node so I'm going to use the node capitalization so when
I read the script I can see that's a capital P player that's a specific object as a node in the same
tree.
Okay.
So remember by watching at the direction to the player it minus me.
So player DOT's position minus global underscore position
now I've put this in brackets because I also need to normalize this.
What does that mean.
It means change the numerical values to be 1 0 0 0 minus 1 minus 0.
Because I don't care how far the player is I need which direction it is.
That's the key information.
Okay so now we need an if condition if I need to get if the player is in the actual field of view but
if I go back to this slide and make it nice and big you'll notice here's the direction I'm facing and
I got a negative and a positive value.
If for example the player is 13 degrees positive from the facing and I say if the player is less than
what is at 20 what it's going to do is say Here's 20.
And all of this is less than.
So if the player is over here is only saying that's no good for me what I need is a way of saying that
20 and negative 20 of the same thing.
In other words remove the positive and negative information.
To do that I'm going to use absolute return the absolute number.
I don't care if it's positive 13 or negative 13 just tell me 13 and what am I returning direction to
player and I need the angle.
Right so let's do angle 2 which is a great function.
Don't have to mess around with dot products nobody else NPC facing direction.
Okay so if this absolute is less than f the tolerance.
Be careful if we run this right now almost everything will work because angle too works in radians and
we are working in degrees so I need to translate that let's translate that degree to radians.
Okay so going to change f of tolerance to radians.
So if that's happen return True else return false.
Now we just need something to happen.
If the player is in the field view.
So if plays the field of you do that.
Else do that.
And here's my challenge for you.
And before we get started I'm gonna give you a few hints.
First thing I want to do is I want to change the color of the torch.
The torch will always have to be a direct child of the end of the node that is running the script.
OK so torch and in here there's going to be a property we can use.
So I want you to figure out the property we can use how to access that code and how to change it with
the constants we have.
So have the NPC torch change color if the players in the field of view and do remember to change it
back afterwards so pause the video give it a shot when you're ready come on back and I'll show you my
solution.
And welcome back.
OK.
So what I need to do is find out how to access this color information in code.
Great as mouse over it.
And it's gonna tell me color all lowercase i guess a torch dot color and I need to change its color
right.
So if Enfield who will have defined it up here.
Red.
Else torched off color equals white.
Now before this happens I just did a quick test and I've done a typo.
I typed in normalize I meant normalized so do check that on the variable direction the player.
That's player dot position minus global underscore position dot normalized not normalized.
OK.
Let's see if that works and I will switch off the player torch.
Check this out now currently we have nothing blocking line of sight which we'll do in the next video
are we actually we're a little bit outside the thing but not by much.
And we have no maximum range.
If I'm over here you can still see me.
But that's a really strong start.
And you'll notice the player torch doesn't work like that.
I'm actually gonna remove the player torsion but I'm really happy with that.
I think it's a great start.
So excellent work in this video.
We've looked at how to use angle 2 to determine if something is in the field of view.
And we've also let them play a note if they've been spotted.
I think that's a really good start.
So excellent work and I will see you in the next video.