Hallelujah you got.
People in this video.
We got talk about parallax backgrounds see right now we have this plain gray looking background.
It's actually a default color that means this is transparent.
Okay we can do that but let's try and create an environment that feels more real more immersive and
gives the illusion of speed.
And to do that we're going to use parallax before we go any further let's talk about what parallax is.
So when I was a kid here's me as a kid I used to go to school by train.
Here's me in my school time which I hated.
And I had no glasses at the time and I had very messy hair.
So here I am on the train.
And here's Ben who is probably standing on a seat.
He wasn't this small but whatever.
He also had messy hair.
OK.
So he sits on the train on the way to school no way back.
And what would happen is the greenery the trees the shrubs the pieces across by the track would become
a blur in the background things like houses fences and let's say power lines
would move at a decent speed.
And in the background the sun would seem not to move at all.
Now I'm aware that these things are not moving I'm moving.
I mean obviously we're moving through the cosmos but that's irrelevant in a local scale.
They are still I am moving fast.
But what's interesting is that the greenery here is a blur because it is moving way faster.
From my perspective and the stuff in the middle distance which is moving way faster than the sun which
appears not to be moving at all.
What's happening is my viewing angle changes the apparent properties of things I'm looking at or maybe
we could do a test tube.
So here is a test tube I'm going to a chemistry class and I need to get a reading for the liquid right
and I will read the liquid here.
But then when I look again the same amount of liquid is here.
Well why did it move it move because I'm at a different angle right.
This is known as parallax error parallax than it is a phenomena where objects seem to be in different
position based on my viewing angle and the faster we're going the more obvious it is.
Now we can use that.
What we gonna do is follow the following guidelines.
One the closer Ella is the faster it should move.
This is going to give us the illusion of speed and of space background layers will go slowly foreground
layers will go faster you'll players will probably not even realize that they noticed this but they
will.
The faster a layer moves the performance of the player will think they're going right.
So we can make money look even faster by using this technique.
Now in Godot we're going to control speed of parallax through scale.
I'll explain that in a moment but essentially what we're doing is we're saying make this layer smaller
which means it'll repeat more often which means it'll look faster.
OK.
A lot to take in.
So instead of explaining it further let's do some practical work.
Now I'm gonna put my parallax layer on the camera to do that.
I'm going to open the placing because that's where I put my camera.
Somebody uses a little film icon hit over the placing and here's my camera as a child of camera.
So I'm an add a child node.
Let's create a parallax background you notice this two things here.
You'll also notice there's a canvas layer a canvas layer is an item that is drawn on the game that has
no position information.
It doesn't care where the thing is it's a piece of artwork that doesn't move with the rest of the game
a parallax background is a type of canvas layer.
Right it inherits from camps.
So we want that first.
If we look on the scroll there's a bunch of options.
Now we don't need to change any of these right the offset the base offset the base scale don't really
care about that.
We do care is ignore camera zoom and I'll show you why in a moment okay.
So we have a parallax background.
Now we need some layers right.
Each layer is going to move at a different speed so let's make the layers cool add a new node.
And as you might imagine we want parallax layer.
Now that's parallax layer needs a graphic.
I mean he's a texture rect.
I don't wanna use a sprite sprite as an object that has position information.
It shouldn't have position information.
It's just a piece of artwork.
Right.
So let's use texture rect okay.
And over here you see I've already selected it onto my g effects background on his background layer
1.
I'm going to drag it into the texture like so cool.
Now if I press play Now this won't work right.
You can see here it just stops.
What I've done is I've created a texture and that doesn't look right at all.
I need it to repeat.
Let's go back to this parallax layer and under motion.
What we want is mirroring.
How often do I repeat.
Now I need to know the size of the image.
I happen to know the size image but anyway to find out more right click on it show file manager and
then because I'm a Windows machine I can right click on it and do properties on Maximilian.
You'll find very similar ways of doing this.
Got the details.
And you can see right here with 2048 height 2048.
Perfect.
That's the information I need.
So a mirroring on a do 2048 2048.
So every 2048 pixels on the X and on the Y mirror this image.
Repeat this image.
So now when I press play
well it looks better but it suddenly snaps.
Why is it snapping.
Because we need to ignore camera zoom.
Ignore camera zoom.
Run the game again.
Remember we zoomed the camera out so it's repeating 2008 for pixels but then the camera pulls back and
sees the edge.
Now when I move we have a single blue thing that seems to go forever.
The player doesn't need to know the order repeating the image.
It's just the background.
We don't need to think about it.
This kind of smoke and mirrors is what great game experience is all about right.
The player shouldn't even be aware that it's there.
Okay let's duplicate parallax last.
I'm going to control deep and there's parallax led to has exactly the same properties.
So I select the texture rect here and use background led to okay.
But we need to do some tweaks and his wife a press play here.
Clouds all the way down here.
Why they're down there.
Because this is quite a large image right.
If I zoom out you can see how large this images clouds star all the way down.
We want to offset it.
Okay.
Well that's easy enough.
Got a parallax led to got a motion and an offset.
We need to move this up by a certain amount I think are up by 750 is good.
But remember up on the y axis in 2D is negative.
Sony's Move up by 750 and now for his play The clouds are much more visible right there all the way
up here.
That's much better.
Bit of a problem look logjams when I full the clouds flicker past what I need to do here is turn off
the mirroring on the y axis some you set y to zero on parallax led to it's still the same apparel X
layer one but not on two.
Now what will happen is we get a line of cloud and then we'll stop.
That's gonna be okay because our final air is the same color as the sky.
So we're gonna have this nice smoke and mirrors effect again.
One more thing I do need to do is I need to make sure that this background land moves quite slowly so
I want to change the scale I needed to change the scale on the x.
So let's change it to zero point five okay.
So it's going to move half the speed that I would expect.
Now let's duplicate parallax led to because most of the properties we need are the same.
Well I do what to do is change the scale here to let's say zero point five.
You'll notice I'm just going up by point to find each because I have two more Esko and I need to change
the background layer three So let's open the texture rect for parallax layer 3.
Put that there and look we have new clouds white clouds subtle effect.
Right duplicate parallax therefore do the exact same thing.
When I put in the fourth layer of texture let's change the scales in motion and that can be a scale
of one.
Now when I press play I run into a problem my problem is I'm not good enough my own game to test this
well.
Right.
It's very hard for me to do this so I'm trying to tweak the gravity.
I'm going to say gravity to 150 is the 300 now jump speed is going to be way too high.
Right.
Because the way we've got it working the press jump look at that.
That's on manageable.
So I'm gonna set this to what you think 3000.
Yeah sounds good let's give that a shot
maybe a little higher than 3000.
That feels good.
And you'll notice that the clouds are moving at different speed and it's quite subtle.
If I want to see this I can that's my level get to 2D and you know what just zoom out and make a floor.
So just really quickly here's a lovely big floor and put it on this line and I want to right click this
one and get rid of that's okay.
So now
the layers are moving at different speed now.
I can change these scales to make them even better right.
I can change this to zero point seventy five on the X this one to zero point five and this once is zero
point two five so they'll repeat even faster.
Press play here.
We've got this really subtle effect that looks like we're in a real environment.
Okay.
Get rid of all these and I might wanna tweak my level soon but I'm actually in a wait.
It's like all things to place and pieces coins are solid.
So for now let's just add a few more doo hickeys we jump on.
Nice.
Okay so we have this lovely little parallax effect that works well.
It also cuts me I might want to move these backgrounds up a bit so I'm going to get at a full screen
mode.
Now I've put them all at minus 750 with the ultimate minus 750 what I do this properly.
So it's got to pallets the effort to reset my offset with his default button saying on three same awful
let's go back to Patrick's background and use base offset minus 1000 as press play much more like it.
Now the ground starts with the players ground starts.
Now we could tweak these values with the rest of it but that gives us a really good starting point.
And that is how to create a parallax background.
And that brings us to the end of the video in this video.
We've looked at how to create a parallax background node and how these parallax layers.
We've also looked into how to tweak these values so find some settings that work well for your game
and excellent work.
Don't forget to show your progress in any problems you might be having.
And I will see you in the next video.