Hello you fantastic go to people in this video.
We're going to create story objects.
Now you've noticed on the slide it's a story book.
Option one we show a couple of different ways you could do this.
But what I want to do is separate my data from my script.
My script is the things that run the functions right that tells Gordo how to behave.
The data is the things I'm going to plug into that and I don't need them in the same place if I take
a look at my script you'll see from line five to line 38.
All of this is just data right.
We could put this somewhere else in the optionally to use a day is going to make story objects to make
new nodes they each hold information.
So here's what I need to do.
First make looney lips less cluttered and to do that I'm going to create a new node and call it storybook.
I want to make each story a separate child of storybooks so I can look at the scenery and see how many
stories I have.
And the script should be able to scale automatically so if I add one I'll take one away.
It won't break the script.
I also would like each story to use the same script.
I don't really want a new script to hold data for every single story.
Let's take a look what we mean.
First thing I do go into looney lips and create a new node going to press control a double click on
node.
This is the most basic kind of note in God.
The only things it can do control pause and hold a script.
Right that's it.
That's all the functionality has by default.
Anything else will have to extend.
Let's rename this two story book.
Hello storybook.
And let's give you a child node which can be another node mythical stories 0.
Cool stories.
You need a script.
Let's give you a script.
So new script and I'm going to call it story.
Why.
Because I don't want a new script for every single story.
I want them all to use the same script first they have to get rid of the function and give it a variable
call prompts which is a an array right and a variable called story which I don't need to initialize
but I can.
It's a string.
Okay.
Similarly I could do going to looney lips.
Take this prompts and just copy this array in some copy it and paste it
and that what fine right.
And then I could do the same with the story
copy it
and pasted OK that will work.
But what happens if I want to make a new story.
Want to save this on a duplicate story zero.
I could right click on it and go to duplicate or express control Dee and it'll make the next series.
In this I called this one story zero because then it won't be story one but they're using the same script.
Any change I make a story one a happy name is going to show up in story zero.
It's the same script.
I can see that by going to the properties and seeing what script it's using.
So I need a way of using the same script for all eight of my stories.
But having different values in them.
So what I do is I'm gonna clear this array and keep the array initialized and clear the string to keep
the string initialize you'll see 1 a second and then we can you keyword just for variable import export
and what this does is it expose the variable to the inspector.
Now this is important and say that this is important because it means I can change the values for that
node in the inspector but it won't actually change the script.
Let me show what that looks like.
To give you good story 1 and write this is story 1 2 3 1 story 1 great and it has here this little circle
button that means set it back to the default.
But if I clicked on story 0 it doesn't have that right.
This is story 0.
You would use export variables for tweaking values in a script without having to change the actual script
but it also works great for our purposes so we can put our stories in here and it'll work great.
One thing that isn't ideal is easy array size zero.
We can change the size the array let's say I'm gonna give it 1 value.
You see here says no it doesn't have a value.
And the reason is an array can hold any type of variable.
It doesn't know what kind of variable to put in here.
I can left it on this pencil icon and pick it right.
So this is going to be a string and I can type a string.
Okay now let's add another one and that one's known as well for every single one.
I'm going to have to go on those drop down menu and that frankly isn't very fun right.
Is going get boring very quickly.
So what I need to do is figure out how to tell gotto.
This is an array of strings.
Now I can't just do this.
Why.
Because that tells me that the first two are strings but what I want to add another one it's not right.
All I've done has moved the problem along and I need this to be scalable.
We need the precise amount of arrays in there for the story.
I need a way of telling it.
This is a specific type of array that can only take the kinetic strings.
So I'm going to use typed G.D. script.
Let's talk about typed and dynamic G.D. script really quickly.
So here is our default variable box that we keep talking about right.
And it can hold anything now in dynamic languages like Python and default dynamic G.D. script.
It's called dynamic because the variables can change right.
You can put anything in here.
This can be an integer a one moment a string of the next moment and array at the next a flow to the
next.
And we can keep changing and changing changing if it's typed.
It can only hold a single type of variable.
This variable is for example a string.
It can only hold strings if you try and put an integer in here.
It will just stop.
It won't work.
It'll break most of the time.
I'm gonna be using dynamic G.D. script right because it's very flexible.
It's very easy great for small projects type G.D. script is usually used for very big projects because
it's very easy to lose track of what variables must be what and this just keeps it all controlled right.
It doesn't allow things to go to wrong.
It's also slightly faster in large projects.
What's happening is gotto is trying to figure out what type of variable this is at runtime every time
you use it and when he gets really really big that will slow it down.
We're not gonna notice it.
The projects we're making but in theory type is a little faster.
So that's great.
But now we have two problems.
One I need to tell you what type of array can only take strings and 2 how to set type G.D. script.
Well the setup G.D. script.
I'm going to go colon and after the colon I'm gonna tell it the type of variable this is and the type
of array that can only take strings is pooled string array like whole control and click on it a pull
string array is an array specifically designed to hold string.
So this is a kind of an edge case thing right but it's going to work great for our purposes.
I actually now don't need to initialize it because I've told it it's a it's a pull string or I can only
help pull strings and now when I try and add a new value it's always going to be a string right.
It can never be an integer.
In fact if I try and type a number in it's giving off a value this 25 is actually a string is not an
integer right.
So that's going to work fantastically for our purposes.
I could also initially story initially 8 that I could initialize story as a string as well that will
work fine.
And now when I go to story 1 story to that different.
Right.
And it worked great.
So for now what I'm going to do is I'm going to comment out this entire template variable all of it.
I'm not selected all press control case all commented out and I'm just gonna start moving them across.
Now the reason I'm commenting now is another video was shown on the solution to this I'm going to keep
it here.
But once you've moved them you could just delete this template.
Let's move a couple across just to show how this works.
So that's my story.
Lives in there.
And how many do we need.
One two three four one two three four.
We have a name.
A noun.
An adverb and an adjective.
Now you can already see that one potential problem here is I can't read the whole story.
Right this isn't easy to resize I this window but even that isn't ideal right.
That's a little annoying.
So copy pasting does make sense here when we look at the Jasons solution.
That's another way we could do this can make this a little easier to read.
However I'm going to do.
I do 404 so you can do the same process.
I'll show you this one and I'll fast forward.
So this story is there once was a something called something called something and that's gonna live
in a story string and I need for again.
One two three four.
And you are a noun a name an adjective
and another What are you.
Another name
awesome Simon.
Do those for two more.
Fast forward and you'll able see them.
Great I've got four of my eight stories here from book we're counting from zero.
I've got all of these things plugged in.
How do we actually get it to work.
Because look identify template is not declared in the current scopes let's click on that.
See the error set current story no longer exists.
So I need to change set current story in a comment this out can you variable.
It's only going exist in this function because it's the only place it needs to be and it can be called
stories.
It's gonna be all of them.
And what I want is I want to get the storybook note and I want to find how many children it's got right.
I need to count them and to do that I only get get child count.
Literally it's going to say how many children do you have that is going to count them zero one two three.
Right.
Which is four.
It's got one two three four children going to count them.
Okay so now let's select a story so selected story.
And what's this.
This is a random story that's a child of storybook how I could do that one of these random integer and
modulated by the amount of stories we have.
Right.
So it's just going to pick a number between 0 and how many children storybook have.
And now I need to select current stories and current story and all to go to storybook and I want to
get a child of it and it's gonna ask for a number.
Which number is it.
It's selected story.
OK.
Before going further let's just take a quick look what's happening here.
I'm assuming control and backslash to get rid of this handy script list whatever it's called.
So I'm going to say that the prompts in current stories are sorry as a dictionary I'm telling it there's
now a key called prompts.
OK so Adichie prompts and the value of prompts is a child of storybook and it's child number.
What have a selected story is we've just found that and now any to find the prompts Qi and I can look
in here prompts is a pull string array and it knows what the values are because we've put them in the
inspector.
Right.
And look here it's going to say these are my prompts it's just gonna add them as a pull string array
which is gonna behave like an array and I will do the same thing.
Current story dot story equals and I'm gonna go storybook dot get child so get child number what number
is it.
Selected story Dalton's story.
Let's just double check that that's what it was called.
It is what was called.
OK so now this should work.
Let's find out.
May I have it now please.
The coffee cup.
May I have a name.
Priscilla.
There we go.
May I have an adjective.
Confident.
Another name.
Sam.
Hi Sam.
There once was a coffee company Priscilla who searched far and wide for the mythical confident town
of Sam that she'd actually be another one hence shouldn't it now be different must fix that story real
quick that there and
you should be another name and you should be another noun.
But look it worked just fine.
Now this can feel like a lot of fiddling around right and we're doing some slightly clever things with
code.
So I'm going to show us what those are in a moment but let's just talk about the advantages of doing
it this way.
I've now separated all the data and storybook and I can look at it here.
I can even minimize this and it just keeps the story separately.
Now I can go into my script and I can delete all of these stories.
I'm actually going to cut them which makes this much more readable rights a lot simpler to see what's
going on I'm going to pace these back for an alcohol and in the next video.
The disadvantage to this is filling these out is a little bit annoying.
And reading this story's a little hard right.
I would probably write it insulin like notepad or something like that and then paste it in but everything
is nice and clean.
If I delete story to it gets rid of the number.
But this works just fine.
Right.
Nothing is going to crash.
I have separated everything out but the game is going to look great.
I kind of want that back now don't I.
So can I do that.
Boop.
Yep there it is cool.
So this is option 1.
The disadvantage of this is it means that the player can't add their own stories.
If I wanted to do that I would go with Jason which is going to be my next video.
Right.
The second option the other advantages I can look at this as a human and see how many stories we have
right with separate everything out ok.
And that is the end of the video in this video we've looked at exporting variables we've used get child
count and get child to figure out how many children does a node have.
And I want to go get this specific node by number.
We've also had a quick look at pull string arrays and a brief introduction to type G.D. script.
Now don't worry if this feels a little bit overwhelming with practice this will all become second nature.
You're not expected to remember every single function every single variable every program I know looks
things up but we have made a really solid starts the game it's actually feature complete at this point
what we gonna do next is look at a different solution.
So excellent luck and I'll see you in the next video.