AWS AppSync is a service that was built to simplify and speed
up the application development process.
It enables us to quickly create flexible APIs,
which we can use to securely access, edit,
and combine data from multiple data sources.
For example, we can get data from NoSQL data stores,
which is the most common way of storing data in AppSync.
We can also use relational databases, get data from HTTP APIs, and
other common data stores using lambda functions,
allowing for great flexibility when it comes to storing data.
The AppSync service uses GraphQL so we can quickly get the data
that we need and only the fields that we want.
Now let's look at some of the benefits of using AppSync for application
development. We can get up and running very quickly.
It takes just a couple of minutes to get up and running
with our first API using AppSync.
We can use the application management console to quickly
create our back end with a couple of clicks,
or we can use the Amplify CLI to automatically generate
our APIs and the client‑side code.
Another important benefit is service integration.
AWS AppSync integrates with Amazon DynamoDB, Amazon Aurora,
Elasticsearch, AWS Lambda, and other AWS services,
enabling us to create sophisticated applications with
virtually unlimited throughput and storage that can scale
according to our business needs.
AppSync also supports real‑time subscriptions. One of the best
features of AppSync is real‑time subscriptions.
It enables our client applications to subscribe to data changes.
So whenever a data change is made, the client application can show the latest
data to the user. It also has support for offline access.
Whenever the client application loses internet access,
users can still edit data on the application. And when internet access
becomes available, the data is synced for us automatically.
It also provides us with customizable conflict detection and resolution so
we can customize our logic when merge conflicts occur.
And last but not least, it's a unified data access layer. Using GraphQL,
it enables us to query data across multiple data
sources with a single network call.
It makes it easy for us to secure the data using multiple
concurrent authentication modes, as well as allowing us to
define fine‑grained access control at the data definition level
directly from our GraphQL schema.
Now let's see these features in action. We'll start creating our first API in the next clip.