AWS AppSync uses resolvers to get or mutate data.
Each mutation query or field has resolvers attached to them to
perform the specific action of handing the data.
For complex cases, when we went to perform multiple operations,
we can use pipeline resolvers.
A pipeline resolver is just like a resolver that has a
BEFORE and AFTER mapping template, and in between,
has a list of functions that it executes.
The list of functions in a pipeline resolver will run in SQL.
Each function output is available to the next function as ctx.prev.result.
Our Task Manager create description uses HTML, and the content in
the description is rendered as HTML as well,
which could open us to cross‑site scripting attacks.
For our createGlobomanticsTasks mutation,
we are going to create a pipeline resolver.
Then, inside this pipeline resolver,
we are going to use a Lambda function that will
sanitize our HTML and make it safe.
From the Lambda Functions portal,
let's create a new function using the Create function button.
Let's name it appsync‑html‑sanitizer and create our function.
Once our function is created,
we are going to upload its content from our exercise files.
From the Actions, we need to navigate to Upload a .zip file.
And then, click the Upload button.
You should find in the exercise files a file htmlSanitizer.zip.
This function has the logic for sanitizing our HTML and making it safe.
Let's upload this file and click Save.
And the logic for our function will be found under htmlSanitizer.js file.
This function uses the sanitize‑html library and then outputs a
clean description from event.input.description,
which is the data that we pass into our function.
One last thing that we need to change is specify the handler.
On the Basic settings page, we need to change the handler.
Here,
we need to change it from index.handler to
src/handlers/htmlSanitizer.handler and then save the changes.
Now that we have set up our function, let's navigate back to our AppSync API.
First, we need to navigate to Data Sources and add our function as a data source.
Here, we need to create a new data source using the Create data source button.
And then specify a name.
Let's name our data source htmlsanitizer.
Next, we need to specify the Data source type.
In our case, it's going to be AWS Lambda.
Up next, we need to specify the region.
In my case, it is US‑EAST‑1.
You need to make sure that you select the correct region; otherwise,
your function list will not show up.
And finally, we need to select our function.
The function name was appsync‑html‑sanitizer.
For the role, I'm going to choose to create a new role,
as this will set up all the permissions for me.
And now, let's create our data source.
Now that we have our data source, we need to navigate to Functions.
Here, let's create a new function using the Create function button.
For the data source,
we need to specify the newly created data source htmlsanitizer.
And then let's name it HtmlSanitizerFunction.
We are going to leave the mapping templates as default.
But if you wanted to change,
we can change the payload here and set it as something else.
Right now, I'm setting to all the arguments that are passed into our API.
Now, let's save our function using the Create function button.
Now that we have our function, we need to navigate to our resolver.
We can find the resolvers in the Schema definition.
Here, we need to find the createGlobomanticsTasks resolver.
On the createGlobomanticsTasks, let's open up the resolver.
To create a pipeline resolver, we use the Convert to pipeline resolver.
This will automatically convert our existing resolver into
a function and then create a pipeline.
As we can see,
it says that it will create a new function using our
existing data source and mapping templates and update this
resolver to a pipeline resolver, which is what we want.
Now, let's convert our resolver into a pipeline resolver.
As we can see,
our pipeline resolver has a Before mapping template and After mapping template,
which outputs the results to JSON.
And then, in between, we have the functions.
AppSync already converted our resolver,
which was a createGlobomanticsTasks resolver,
into a function.
So in our case now, the pipeline resolver has only one function to execute.
We can add new functions using the Add function button.
Here, we are going to use an existing function,
which is the HtmlSanitizerFunction.
Now, we need to change the order.
The HtmlSanitizerFunction needs to be executed before the
createGlobomanticsTasks_Function; otherwise,
the data will be already stored in our DB.
Let's select the HtmlSanitizerFunction and use the Move up button to move it up.
And finally, let's save our resolver.
Now that the resolver has been saved,
we need to update the createGlobomanticsTasks_Function.
We need to get the description, not from the input from the client,
but from the clean description output from the HtmlSanitizerFunction.
We can quickly edit using the Edit button.
Here, we need to change where we get the description from.
Instead of getting it from ctx.args.input.description,
we need to get it from the html‑sanitizer output.
The html‑sanitizer output can be found under ctx.prev.result,
and we are going to use the cleanDescription field.
If you look at our html‑sanitizer‑Lambda function,
it outputs an object with the field, cleanDescription.
Now let's go ahead and save our changes.
Now that we have set up our function,
let's navigate back to our client application and test this out.
Here, let's start by creating a new task.
Let's name this task scripting attack.
Now, in the Description, we can actually insert JavaScript code if we wanted to.
Here, for example, we can set it so it alerts a message,
but we can do much more.
Now, if we move from the code view to the normal view,
we will see that this script will be executed.
And indeed, the script gets executed.
Because the editor is rendering the HTML content,
it's rendering the script as well.
Now, let's say OK and create our task.
And now, if we open our new task, we should not get an alert message,
as it should have been removed by the html‑sanitizer.
And indeed, we do not get it.
And if we look into the code view,
we see that there is no JavaScript there, and our
function execution was successful.
Pipeline resolvers are a great tool when we are building large custom APIs.
We can execute multiple functions in sequence,
and those same functions can be used in other pipeline resolvers, which offers great flexibility and lets us build usable functions.