In this clip, we are going to take a look at resolvers.
We are going to edit the existing resolvers so we can set a
date property for our task automatically,
and the UI will not need to pass a date.
This way we make sure that the creation date of the task is always accurate.
Resolvers are what GraphQL uses to gather the data that it delivers.
It takes in a GraphQL query and outputs the data that the client has requested.
In AppSync we can find the resolvers in the schema definition.
On the right side, we have the resolvers for the mutations and the queries.
Here we have three resolvers for creating,
updating, and deleting tasks and two resolvers for getting and listing queries.
We are going to update the resolver on the createGlobomanticsTasks.
We can open the resolver by clicking on its name.
The resolver has two mapping templates,
one for mapping requests and one for mapping responses.
The response mapping attribute is very straightforward.
Here its just converting to JSON the output returned from the
database which can be found on the context.result.
AppSync has a couple of helping variables that can
be used in the mapping templates.
By clicking on the Info button, we can get a quick reference.
We have context.arguments, or we can use context.args for short,
which contains the data passed during the request from the client application.
Next, we have the identity object that has info on the currently logged‑in user,
which we can use if we want to insert user‑related
information into our database.
Context.result contains the output returned from our data source.
In this case, it would be from our DynamoDB table.
Then we have some helpers which are found on the util object for
converting object to JSON or generating automatic IDs.
If you want to look at the full reference,
you can do that by clicking on the link here.
Here you can find all the existing variables that can
be used in the mapping template.
We don't have time to go through all of them,
but we'll be using a couple of them during this clip.
Now let's take a look at our request mapping template.
The operation for this action is PutItem, which is used to define that we
are adding or updating an item from our DynamoDB table.
Next,
we define the key for a record. Here we are using the auto id function from
our util helper and converting it to a DynamoDB JSON.
Next we define the attributeValues. AttributeValues specify
the data that goes into our database.
The values can be found in the input property of the arguments, so we do
context.arguments.input, or for short, ctx.args.input, and we are using
the toMapValuesJson from our DynamoDB utility.
This will map all the properties specified in our request to a DynamoDB table.
Here we are going to change it so we specify the values individually so we can
set the date property. Instead of mapping the entire output, we are going to
specify each property individually.
We are going to map the title and the description from the values that
were specified on the request. And then for the date property, we are
going to ignore the date that was specified in the request and set the
current date. We are going to use the time utility and then use a
nowFormatted function. Here we need to specify a valid date that is
supported by the DynamoDB table.
The year‑month‑date format works for this case. And then we convert this value
to a DynamoDB JSON This way every time a new task is created,
we are making sure that the date is the current date and the user
cannot set an older date or a date in the future.
Now let's save the resolver and navigate back to our client
application. In our client application,
where we create a task, let's remove the date field and leave it empty.
And now let's navigate back to our UI to try and create a new task.
Let's name our task Date Test And when we create our
task, it should have the current date.
And indeed, as soon as the task is created,
we can now see that this has the current date.
So our resolver is setting the date for us,
and we don't have to specify the date.
Even if the client application specifies the date,
it will be ignored. This way,
we make sure that the creation date for our task is always the current date.
Resolvers enable us to customize the data going in and out of our database,
which enables us to quickly customize them to support different scenarios for our APIs.