I want to get into talking about plugins but before we get to that let's go over Temple attacks again
in the past two sections.
We've been using template tags to display content.
They're pretty straightforward.
You simply call a function and data gets output.
The purpose of a template tag is to make your code cleaner rather than querying the database and processing
the data.
You can just call a simple function.
This is ideal because it allows you to put logic into its own file.
You even have the ability to create your own template tags just create a regular pitch function and
then call it in your templates you can use the function's dot P. HP file to define your custom template
tags since that file gets loaded before your template does.
Let's break down template tags even further.
In most cases you'll find that template tags come in one of two versions.
There's the get version and the non get version.
This doesn't apply to every tag but it is common.
The non get version will echo out the value immediately the get version will return the value in the
past we've used both versions for various reasons.
Usually you want to use the non get version unless you need to process the data further.
Another thing you should be aware of is that most template tags have parameters to modify the value.
And this example I'm using the title function if we wanted to apply some div tag to the title then there
are two ways to go about it.
We can surround the function with the H CML or we can pass it into the function as parameters.
These two solutions will result in the same thing.
The main difference is whether you'll allow WordPress to handle it.
There is one advantage to passing in the HCM although WordPress has a feature called filter hooks which
allow you to modify values template tags contain hooks which can then be used by developers like you
and me by being provided the HCM.
We can make changes to it if we wish for the most part though most developers tend not to pass in the
parameters and heart Kobe H email instead.
When we start working on plugins you'll understand how you can use these parameters and extend them
on your own for this section.
We're going to need a template that we can experimental create a new template called experimental dot
p p.
You can name this whatever you want since this will be a custom template.
This template will be pretty straightforward.
Open the full dash with Dash page template and copy the code from that template into our new one.
We're going to be making big changes to this template.
First we're going to remove the loop completely then up in the page title remove the subtitle and change
the main title to experimental code.
Lastly let's update the template.
Name two experimental once you've made those changes.
I want you to navigate to the WordPress dashboard and create a brand new page you can name this page
whatever you want.
It doesn't matter what does matter is that you select the experimental template in the dropdown and
save your changes
now that we're finished with that we can begin exploring template tags.