We're going to load in some styles for our block.
I'm going to go over two approaches for this.
The first approach is the simplest one.
All you have to do is open the blocks in queue file and then in cue the styles file it would just be
a regular CSX file.
You don't have to use any special tools or libraries to create the CSX file.
With that being said I prefer another solution.
I tend to tackle a lot of large projects so I usually have a setup that's a bit more complex than a
simple CSX file.
I like to use something called SAS or SPSS.
SAS is a CSX pretty processor.
What does a pretty processor.
Basically you write SAS code that will then be converted into CSX code.
SAS is not supported by browsers so the code needs to be processed beforehand.
SAS code is written just like CSX.
You input a selector and then modify its properties.
SAS adds features like variables conditional statements loops vendor prefixes etc. CSX files can grow
to be thousands of lines of code with SAS managing your CSF becomes easier.
You can split your code in two separate files.
Let's say you had a variable that contained the color blue.
If you had multiple files that use that variable and you wanted to update the color then you only need
to modify the variables value and everything else will update accordingly.
If you look around you'll find that some people refer to it as SPSS SPSS is the newer version and the
one will be using the SAS version is the older one but it's still used.
So you may come across this version as well.
These terms can be interchangeable but know the difference for our purposes it's a bit excessive.
However if you're working on an ambitious or large project then it would be beneficial to use it.
I won't be able to go every feature of SAS but that's perfectly fine.
SAS is written just like CSX.
If you know CSX then you'll be able to pick up on it quickly if you already know SAS.
Then you'll learn how to add it to your workflow.
Let's begin.
First we need to install and configure a couple of modules all provide links in the resource section
of this lecture.
Be sure to check them out.
The first module we'll need is the wall loader module.
As you may know the import statement allows us to import modules.
However we're limited to importing just JavaScript files.
Let's say I wanted to import a CSX file like so this would give us an error by adding this module we'll
be able to load in any file.
This includes text HCM L and even C Ss files.
Once this module is loaded a line like this will work just fine.
The next module we'll need is the node SAS module.
SAS is written with the programming language C however we want to be able to use it with JavaScript.
This module will take care of allowing us to do so afterwards we'll need these SAS loader module Westpac
pack and SAS are two different things the SAS loader module will take care of.
Bridging these two together so that Webb pack can process the Files up next we'll need the mini C CSX
extract plug in module when we load CSX.
It will be a part of the javascript code base.
However we don't want that.
We want to put the CSX into its own file.
This module allows you to extract text from your files.
For example if your file had the text hello then you could extract that and put it into its own file.
The way we'll use it is to extract CSX and placed the CSX into its own file.
Lastly we have these CSX loader module.
This module will take care of properly loading CSX files just in case the raw loader module can't.
Quite a few modules but they aren't hard to configure.
Once you've configured them then you can forget about them and work on your project to get started.
We'll need to install these modules switch to your command line and C D into the blocks directory
run the following command NPM ie raw dash loader no dash SAS SAS dash loader C Ss dash loader mini dash
C S extract dash plugin dash dash save dash Dev
you're more than free to install multiple modules you just chain them one after the other.
This may take a while for some of you so be patient
after the modules have been installed.
Check the package file it should contain the dependencies and their versions.
The next step is to configure these modules open the web page config file we created earlier right at
the top load the mini CSX extract plug in module
next we need to create new instances of a plugin I'm going to add a comment below that says extract
CSX for Gutenberg Ed
create a constant named Ed CSX plugin.
This will be set to a new instance of B.C. assess extract module
the plugin requires that we pass in a path to a file that will contain the final result.
This will be relative to the path specified inside the output property.
First passing an object inside this object defined a property called file name set to the value of blocks
Dash.
Name dot CSX
next.
We need to tell the plug in to use the loaders loaders are responsible for connecting third party modules
to web pack.
We have to.
Which are these CSX loader and SAS loader modules just to save some time.
I'm going to paste in the code the code I added was an object to the rules array.
Basically I'm saying that if a file ends with the extension SPSS then it should be processed by SAS
and put into its own file the use property is set to an array.
This is how you specify multiple loaders for one rule.
I'm telling it to process SAS code through the SAS loader followed by the CSX loader.
And lastly the mini CSX extract loader.
It's important that the CSX extract loader is last because we only want to extract the CSX after it's
been processed.
This will simply tell Webb pack how to use the plugin.
We next need to tell Webb pack to use the plugin itself.
Right under the module property.
Add another property called plugins that will be set to an array
pass him the editor CSX plugin instance.
All right.
That should cover things.
Run the command NPM run Dev
hopefully you won't receive any errors.
If you did everything right.
If you look inside the dist folder then you may or may not see the CFS files.
This is because there's no CSF being loaded.
Let's add some C Ss to our blocks.
Open the recipe block directory.
Create a C Ss file called Ed dot SPSS
just as a side note web pack won't give you any errors if you don't create these files so don't feel
pressured to do so.
Let's focus on the Ed file just to save some time.
I'm going to paste in this C Ss for this pause the video if you need to have what I have.
I've provided two methods here for the blocks to assess these to do the exact same thing but they're
written differently.
The first approach is plain C Ss The second approach is SAS.
It's written similarly to plain CSX.
However there's one huge difference here.
Rather than constantly typing out WP block you Timmy recipe.
We only write it once and then next.
Any related styles this SAS code will be converted into the code above.
The second approach is much more organized and less redundant.
You could nest as far as you want to.
Let's test to see if this works.
Open the index file for our block right at the top.
Import these SAS file we're not going to store the values we just want to import it.
So that web pack will pick up on the file to process and extract it.
If you save the file then Web patch you'd begin scanning these files go to your distribution folder
and look for any C Ss files.
There should be one C Ss file open.
You should see something similar to what I see.
If we were to compare the plane CSX and SPSS code then you'll notice that they are completely identical
SPSS took the time to correctly create the selections for our code even though it was nested.
It's a bit redundant to have both versions in our code so I'm going to comment out the plain C Ss version
after making those changes.
If you look at the C Ss file again then you'll see that the code was removed from the file completely.
That's fantastic.
The last step to all of this is to just include the files were going to be using a different hook to
include the files Gutenberg introduces two new hooks 2 and Q files were already using one of them inside
the main plugin and file or using the Q block editor assets hook this hook is triggered when the user
reviews the editor on the admin side.
The second hook is called a cube block assets.
I'll add this in
the name of the function will be are in queue block assets.
This hook is triggered when the editor is loaded or page on the front it is viewed.
We essentially want our style to be loaded in both scenarios.
This is the perfect hook to use for loading style sheets inside the NQ file from the blocks directory.
I'll define the function here
next call the WP register style function pass in a name and a path to the file.
Next call the WP in Q style function and pass in the name.
That's it.
It's as simple as that save your changes and refresh the editor.
The file should load without a problem the block no longer has the dots next to each list item and the
spacing is more condensed.
This is now closer to the front end version that pretty much does it for now.
This example is a bit excessive for our needs but if you're working on larger projects than SAS can
be a lifesaver in terms of management.
This is how I tackle projects and how I recommend you go about this.
We've barely scratched the surface of SAS this course really isn't about SAS but I highly recommend
you check out the SAS courses on you to me it's super simple to learn but very powerful and effective
for any project.
I've got a challenge for you.
The font that's used for the editor is different than the one used on the theme.
The font that's being used is called Leto.
I want you to try and load this font for Gutenberg then update the CSF to use this font.
It shouldn't be too hard.
I'll provide a link to the font in the resource section of this lecture once you tackled the challenge.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Good luck.