We'll be using a plug in called Jake Query rate it.
I provide a link to this plug in in the resources section of this lecture.
It'll create a simple rating UI that we can use in our plugin.
I already included this plugin for you when you downloaded the assets for our project.
All we have to do now is include you already know how to do this so why don't you pause this video and
give it a try.
This plugin can be found inside the assets folder.
All you need to do is include the J query dot rate it dot men dot J.S. and write it top C Ss files
if you haven't figured it out yet.
Then let me show you.
I'm going to use the WP and Qs scripts action hook and I'm going to call the function r and Q scripts.
The next step is to create the file that will NQ R files create a file named NQ dot p p that will contain
our function and include it from within the plugin file.
Keep in mind that I created a folder named front and put the file in here.
One last thing I want to do is set the priority to a high number such as 100.
This here is a personal preference.
Whenever I'm in queuing file from within a plugin file I like to load my assets last.
This is because I believe theme should have a higher priority when it comes to loading JavaScript in
C Ss files.
I've had many problems in the past where my assets had conflicting issues with the theme because the
theme files were being loaded too late.
I've saved myself many headaches by having my plugins asset files loaded last.
Now let's take a look at this function.
I'm simply going to register and in queue my files.
One thing I forgot to mention is that I'm also including a script named Main Doc J.S. This file can
be found inside the assets slash J.S. folder.
Open this file.
It's just basic J query code which we will be editing soon.
Back to the NQ function.
I'm doing one last thing which is making sure that J.
Query is being loaded before our files are loaded.
This should set everything up and we can now begin using the plug it in the resource section I provide
a link to the Ajax in plugins Codex page.
This page goes over how to use ajax and plugins using Ajax on the front end requires a little work.
The first thing we need to do is prepare the data open the recipe template file as you can see the rating
is placed right after the rating text.
We created this div with the class ratings.
I also gave it an idea called recipe underscore rating.
We'll need this as a reference.
I also added this attribute called Data dash rate it Dash reset of all and set its value to false.
This plugin will generate a button that will allow the user to reset the rating.
We don't want this by setting it to false.
This will prevent the user from resetting the rating.
All this information can be found on the documentation page of the plugin the last attribute I created
is called data dash or I.D..
This will contain the idea of the current post taking a close look.
You'll notice I made this into a place holder inside the filter function.
Let's add another modification.
All you need to do is search for this place holder and replace it with the idea of this post
let's test this really quick.
You should see 5 stars and be able to write this recipe.
This works almost perfect as you can see you're able to change your rating.
We don't want this.
We want the rating to be set after the user has done so.
We'll do this inside the javascript main file.
I'm going to select the div by its I.D. and then I'm going to bind an event called rated.
This has been just called when the user writes a recipe inside the function.
We can use the this object to reference the div.
I'm going to select the div again and call the rate at method this method allows us to change the properties.
I'm going to change the read only property to True.
This will prevent the user from changing their rating after reading a recipe.
The next step is to create an object called form.
We're going to send this object when we make an ajax request.
There's only one property we must define which is the action property.
WordPress will use this to determine what function to execute when it receives an ajax request.
You'll see exactly how this works in just a moment.
I'm going to set this to r rate.
Recipe next.
I'm going to create a r ideas property and set its value to the R ideas attribute
the last property you want to define is the rating itself to grab the rating.
We can use the rate it method and pass in value.
This will return the rating
I want to test this out now refresh the page and try rating the recipe.
You should not be able to rate this recipe after rating at once.
The next step is to send an ajax request with all our info so the rating can be saved.
The WordPress admin provides a variable for the Ajax you are out on the front end.
We're not so lucky.
We have to generate the euro ourselves.
It's pretty easy though inside the NQ function.
We're going to use a function called WP localize scripts.
This function is used for providing translated strings to your javascript files.
Despite this WordPress recommends you use this function for also providing a you URL to its Ajax page
handler.
The first parameter is which file will be receiving the translations slash you or else set this to our
main.
Since this is the file that we're using to send Ajax requests.
Next up is the name of the object we can use for referencing the values.
I'm going to set this to recipe LBJ.
The last parameter is an array of values.
We only need to create one value and that is the Ajax you are out you can name this whatever you want.
By the way the value of this key will be the euro returned by the ad menu URL function
this function has one optional parameter which is the path relative to the WordPress admin you are.
I'm going to pass an admin dash Ajax stop BHP.
This is the path that should always handle your Ajax requests.
If we take a look at our folder structure you can find this file inside the WP dash admin folder.
Now we can send in Ajax request using J queries post method we'll send an ajax request to the URL we
generated.
Remember the recipe Obi J is the name we used in the second parameter of the localize function.
This object will contain all our res value the property we want to access is the Ajax you are all property.
Next we want to send the form object and then we'll create the function that will handle the response.
The data argument is a variable that will contain the response body.
The last thing we need to do is to tell WordPress about this Ajax request so we can handle it properly
from the plugin file.
We're going to use an action hook called WP Ajax
let's take a look at this hook by viewing its Codex page.
I provide a link to this in the resource section of this lecture.
This book starts with WP Ajax followed by the name of the action.
This was set in the form object the action hook should be called WP underscore Ajax underscore our underscore
rate underscore recipe the name of the function we want to execute is our rate.
Recipe you can name this whatever you want.
You don't have to name it after the action.
I just do it like this because it makes things easier to manage.
All right.
Now create a file inside the process folder called rape dash recipe dot P. HB and define the function
here.
Make sure to include it from the plugin file.
Inside the function I'm going to output the post data let's try using our rating system now.
There's one problem which is how do we know if our data is being sent and how do we check the data.
This can be done by using Chrome developer tools press F 12 on your keyboard and you should see this
pop up in previous lectures.
We briefly went over how the elements and console taps work.
Now we'll be discussing how the network tab works the network tab tracks of what files are loaded and
how long it takes to load those files.
It also provides information about the request and responses for the most part.
I don't usually concern myself with all this information.
The best part about this section of the developer tools is that you can filter those requests since
a web page can make dozens of requests.
I'm going to filter it by x H R which stands for X amount H GDP requests.
This is where Ajax requests are being displayed.
With this being displayed I'm going to rate the recipe after reading the recipe you should see a new
request being sent to add Min dash Ajax dot P HP.
Click on this request and you will see some data being output it to the right.
It's categorized into five sections the headers tab tells us about the header information inside this
tab.
It's split into more sections.
The general section provides information about the request in general the response headers provides
information about the server itself.
When it replied to our request the request headers provides information about our own request the form
data is what we want to see specifically.
You'll notice our data being sent so we can now confirm that our request is indeed being sent.
With the data we provided next.
I want to check if the server is receiving this data properly under the preview or response tab.
We'll be able to check out the server's response.
We see our data being output it with p p.
Not only have we confirmed that our data is being sent but the correct function is being executed when
our data is received before I move on.
There's one thing I want to highlight the difference between the preview and response tab is that the
preview tab will display the response as if the response was rendered by a browser.
So any stylings applied to the responses page will be applied to this little preview.
The response tab will show the response completely raw and or plain text.
There is one last thing I want to do before we move on to processing the rating back inside the main
plugin file.
I'm going to copy the Ajax hook again and paste it below.
I'm going to change WP Ajax to WP Ajax.
No prev the difference between these two is that they know print version will also process Ajax requests
from users who are not logged in.
No crib stands for no privileges.
We want our guests to be able to read our recipes as well.
This step is optional and is up to you whether you believe guests should be able to make Ajax requests.
You don't have to worry about both of these being triggered as WordPress is smart enough to tell which
one to use depending on the user and the next lecture will begin processing the data and save it.