Let's keep adding onto the recipe plug in the next thing we want to do is create one of these Dashboard
widgets on the WordPress admin page.
A lot of plugins add dashboard which is to provide more info about the plugin itself or the data it
provides.
It's perfect for adding a little news widget feed so users can be kept up to date with your plugin.
Let's create one ourselves.
The widget we'll create will provide the latest five ratings inside the main plugin file at an action
hook called WP dashboard setup the function to call is our ad Dashboard Widgets
create a file in the admin folder named dashboard dash widgets dot P. HP and define the function here
as always.
Make sure to include this file from the main plugin file
creating a dashboard widget is really easy.
You only have to call one function which is the WP ad Dashboard widget function.
There are three parameters we need to set.
First is the slug which can be thought of as a unique idea.
Set this to our latest recipe rating which it the second parameter is the title of our widget.
Set this to latest recipe ratings the last parameter is the function to call which will display the
contents of the widget.
Set this to our latest recipe rating display in the same file.
Let's define the display function.
We want the widget to display the five latest ratings to do this.
We'll need the WP DB global object.
Create a variable called latest ratings that will be set to the value returned by the Get Results method
of the WP PDB object
the query will be using will simply select all the data in the recipe ratings recipe
to get the latest entries.
We have to set the order by for the I.D. column in descending order.
Lastly limit the amount of results returned by 5
next.
Echo out some UL tags and in-between these tags will run a for each loop that will loop through the
latest ratings array
the Get Results method will return an array of results each item in the array will be an object.
Now I'm going to create two variables for the title and perma link to get these values we can use the
functions get the title and get the perma link which will return the values we need about a particular
post notice that we're using these functions inside a plugin and outside of the loop to use these functions
properly.
We have to pass in the post I.D. we can get the I.D. by accessing the recipe ideas property from the
rating object.
This is where we stored the post I.D..
Lastly I'm just going to paste in some HCM El nothing special going on in here.
I'm just echoing out the values and displaying a message that informs the user about which recipe received
a rating and the rating itself.
Save your changes and let's view the admin dashboard again.
We will now see our latest recipe widget along with the latest ratings.
If you don't see any ratings then try reading a recipe and come back to this page.