And this lecture we're going to continue working with the WordPress customized API.
There are five fields we'll be creating that we'll do the following.
The first two fields is for these two button icons on the menu.
We'll let the user decide if they want these buttons to be available.
The next option is the text for this copyright message on the footer.
The last two options will allow users to select the pages for the Terms of Service and Privacy Policy
links.
Before we get started with the customize our I'm going to make the search form in the header functional.
I'm going to open the header and search form templates look for the search form inside the header template.
You'll notice right away these forms are completely different in appearance and markup so I won't be
using the function for grabbing this template.
Instead I'm just going to copy and paste some of the PDP parts into this template.
There are only three things we really need to make dynamic that would be the action for the form the
value for the input.
And lastly make this text translatable.
All right let's get started with the customized.
I'm going to make a file inside the customized folder and name it in my SC dot PDP which is short for
miscellaneous to find a function named J U m my SC customize your section.
This function will accept the WP customize object from the functions file.
I'm going to include this file
the very last step is to call this function from the main customize your function.
I know that was a lot to do but trust me you should always do this as it'll help you keep things organized.
I've been in that situation where I would stuff my code in the least amount of files possible and it
was always a pain to maintain.
Just like last time we'll be using the three step process to create these new settings.
The first step is to create the database values using the add setting method.
The idea for the first setting will be j you header show search and the default value will be yes.
I'm going to copy and paste this for more times and update the names for each of these.
Feel free to pause the video so that you can have what I have.
I have the j you headers show cartoon setting where the default value is also yes the j u footer copyright
text will have its default value to the original copyright text the j u footer TRW page and J You put
her privacy page will both be set to zero.
These will be assigned to pages later on.
That right there is step one.
We have all our database settings ready.
The next step is to create a section or hold all our controllers call the ad section method and give
it the I.D. of J U M ISC section
the title will be Udemy M ie SC settings with a priority of 30
the last step is to create the controllers for each study.
The first controller will be a standard HMO input field so we'll be using the WP customize control class
to help us out as usual.
I'm going to pass in the normal stuff.
There are a couple of things I should highlight.
The I.D. will be Jay you headers show search input.
I will make sure this is assigned to the miscellaneous section and make its settings correspond to the
correct settings value we created earlier instead of a text input field.
I want to create a checkbox.
I will set the type to checkbox the values we use for the checkbox can be set by adding the key choices.
This keys value will be an array of possible values available.
We only have one value and that is yes the name of the key is the actual value that will be compared
to check if the setting matches the checkbox.
The value of the item is human readable text next to the checkbox so the user knows what the checkbox
is for.
Let's refresh the Customize are and we should now see our section and the checkbox being displayed.
As you can see the checkbox is already checked because the default value for this setting is yes.
I want you to do the same for the card button while you're at it try creating the copyright text controller.
It's just a text field nothing complex.
Positive video and try it out.
If you didn't get it that's fine.
It's really simple.
I'm going to copy and paste the previous controller twice and change a few things.
I want you to update the I.D.
then I want you to change the label and these settings key for the card button.
For the copyright text I'm going to remove the choices and type he's by default.
The type will always be text like last time.
You'll only need to change the IP label and these settings key
that should do it for the two buttons and copyright text.
The only fields we have to create are the fields for the pages.
I'm going to paste this one more time and remove the choices key and update the I.D. label and settings
keys appropriately
this time I'm going to change the type to dropdown dash pages.
This is a special type.
We can set WordPress or generate a drop down menu and set the options to all the pages that are published.
The value of each option will be the page idea which we can use later.
This is exactly what we want since the terms of service and privacy policy will be separate pages.
If you don't have a page in mind then you should set these settings value to zero.
So WordPress won't set a page by accident.
This controller is for the terms of service.
I'm going to copy this and set the I.T. settings and label for the privacy policy now
just like that we should have five controllers in the miscellaneous section refresh the customized.
And you should see something similar to what I have because this is a testing environment.
I'm going to set a two page dropdown controller to some random pages.
I'm also going to update the copyright text to something simple.
Make sure to save the changes.
The last thing we need to do is make these changes reflect on the theme.
Open the header template and look for these search and cart buttons.
I'm going to surround these in conditional statements like So
the condition will check if the values for both these models are set to Yes.
Make sure to update the values in both these functions so the appropriate setting test the Customize
your really quick and see if everything works correctly.
The buttons should appear and disappear depending on if the box is checked or not.
I'm going to close the header template and open the footer template.
Let's get to work for the copyright text.
I'm just going to echo out the setting
next.
I'm going to wrap the links in conditional statements and check off the settings have a value.
Keep in mind by default these settings values are zero.
This is also equivalent to false.
So we don't need to perform any checks besides what's returned
replace the links and use the perma link.
Function
template tags can we use outside the loop.
However there is one condition You must pass in the idea of the post or page you like to retrieve information
from most template tags.
Have this as their first parameter.
Let's do that now call the get name mod and get the appropriate setting for each link if you don't pass
in an I.D. and you're using this function outside of the loop then you'll receive an error.
Let's check out the site now.
Save any changes you made an exit out of a customized to make sure the links in the footer work.
After confirming so then you're all done.
Let's take a moment to explore our theme.
When we first started we had a bunch of links and styles and the content was broken.
Now we have a fully functioning theme.