I'm back inside the admin side of WordPress and I'm on the recipe page right now.
There's no way for me to know how many ratings each recipe has or what the rating for each one is.
Wouldn't it be nice if I could see all the data here in this table.
At this point you can already guess how we would do this if you were thinking action hoax then you were
correct along with showing the rating count and the actual rating.
We're also going to remove the tags column as it's kind of useless information for this post to get
started.
We're going to look into when the WordPress admin dashboard is initialized inside the main plugin file
at an action hook called admin in it's the name of the function will be recipe admin in it.
This function doesn't exist so let's create it inside the includes folder create a folder named admin.
This is where we'll store files related to the admin side exclusively.
Then inside this folder create a file named in it.
Dot P. HP defined the function and include it from the main plugin file
inside this function.
I'm going to add a new filter hook called manage post type posts.
Columns
this hook doesn't have to be used inside the admin init hook.
The reason we're adding it here is to keep things organized.
I couldn't very well put this hook inside the main plugin file but I don't want that file to be too
cluttered with hooks.
There's also the advantage of having all the admin hooks in one file rather than mixing them together
with other hooks.
I provide a link to this in the resource section to more about this hook.
Let's take a look at the Codex page the post type in the name can actually be replaced with the name
of the post type where the column will be updated.
So let's go back to the filter hook and replace this word with recipe since that is the name of our
post type.
This filter hook will give us an array of columns already set by WordPress.
We have the option of returning a modified version of this array or a brand new array of columns.
Let's set this filter hooks function to r add new recipe columns.
I'm going to create a file called columns stop BHP with the admin folder and define the function here.
Make sure to include it from the admin in it.
Function
this function.
We passed a columns array.
We're not going to use this though.
Instead I'm going to create an array called new columns the key of these arrays will be used to identify
each column and the values would be the names of each column.
This will be output ID into the header and footer of our table.
If we take a look at the Codex page WordPress provides a list of default columns we can set.
I'm going to use all of these except the tags and comments column.
You should have something similar to what I have.
You'll also notice that I'm making each column name translatable right after the categories column and
two more columns called Count and rating when it comes to custom columns.
You can name these whatever you want.
I'm going to keep it simple.
These column names will also be translatable.
The last step is return the new columns.
Since these are custom columns it is our responsibility to output the data for each column back inside
the admin init function.
We will now add an action hook called manage post type.
Post custom column
I provide a link in the resources section for this action hook this hook will allow us to output info
for each column The Post type keyword should be replaced with a custom post type this hook will effect
in our case it would be recipe the function we want to call is our manage recipe columns
this hook will pass our function to arguments that will need I'm going to set a priority to 10 and the
accepted arguments 2 2 I'm going to define this function inside the columns dot page we file the two
variables that will be passed in our column and post d d column variable is equal to the key in the
columns array and the idea is the idea of the current post I'm going to use a switch statement here
I'm going to check the column and see if its value is equal to either count or rating
otherwise I'm just going to break this statement don't worry about the other columns since they are
WordPress columns WordPress will handle setting those values it's our custom columns we need to worry
about for both of these columns I'm going to ground the recipe metadata and simply echo the corresponding
values for each column
something I want to highlight is that I'm checking if the key in the array is set for each of the respective
columns.
This is just in case the metadata isn't available.
Refresh your table and you should now see our columns appear.
We only have one recipe but we can already see the amount of ratings it's received and the average rating.