The loop is ready and all we have to do now is make each part of the post dynamic in the resource section
of this lecture.
I provide a link to a page in the handbook called template tags template tags RPG functions that display
information onto the page.
There are hundreds of them and each are simple to use.
The purpose of a template tag is to make your code readable and simpler.
Usually you would have to query the database and grab this information manually.
Template tags save you time by doing all the work behind the scenes.
All you have to do is call the function associated with the data you'd like to grab on this page is
a long list of functions that return information about the blog.
A majority of these function can be used anywhere in your template.
You are not required to use them inside the loop.
However there are benefits to running some of these functions inside a loop.
You'll see how that works in just a moment.
Let's scroll down to the post tagged section of this page you'll see we have quite a few functions that
we can use inside the loop.
Let's use one of these template tags.
Now the first one we'll be using is the post thumbnail function.
Open the content excerpt template and look for the image tag that contains the featured image.
Let's remove this and instead call this function.
Keep in mind that this template is being loaded inside the loop.
The function will generate the HDL for our image and output.
The benefit of using a template tag inside the loop is that template tag functions will automatically
detect that it's inside a loop.
This function and any other function we use inside the loop will automatically know which post to grab
the information from.
This function has a couple of parameters we can set the first parameter is the size of the image you
can pass in a number if you believe you know a good size or you can take advantage of WordPress as post
thumbnail size feature and the resource section I provide a link to the post thumbnail page WordPress
describes in detail about post thumbnails but we won't concern ourselves with the whole thing.
Scroll down to where it talks about the sizes available from what WordPress says.
There are 4 size aliases we can use thumbnail medium large and full full can be thought of as the original
size.
Let's pass in full to the function.
The second parameter is an array of attributes that WordPress will add to the HP email generated.
You can set any attribute you'd like.
There are no restrictions.
The only attribute I want to override is the class attribute one class I'd like to use is the image
underscore fade class which will give the image a nice effect.
Let's use the key called Class and set its value to image underscore fate that's all we need to do.
Refresh the page and check out the post thumbnail.
This is exactly what we wanted.
You should see something similar to what I see.
You may have different images as fake or press generated most of these posts and grabs random images
from the Internet.
Some posts will not have images and that's perfectly fine.
We need to do one more thing before we move onto the other parts of the template.
Not every post that is displayed will automatically have an image associated with it.
We can't assume every post will have a post image.
So what we're going to do is wrap the div tag with the class entry dash image with a conditional statement
inside this conditional statement.
We'll use the has post thumbnail function as the name suggests this will simply check to see if the
current post in the loop has a thumbnail.
If it's true then it will display the image.
What I love about these functions is that they can automatically detect that we're in a loop and we'll
check each post individually before we continue on.
I want to briefly talk about thumbnail sizes.
If you were to go to the admin dashboard and navigate to settings media you'll find settings to change
the sizes of certain thumbnails feel free to adjust these as you like.
We also have the power to abdominal sizes.
This is something we'll explore in a future lecture.
Let's finish up the loop here by making the rest of the post dynamic.
Most of the functions I'm going to introduce here can be found on the template tags handbook page.
We're going to start from the top and work our way down.
First up is the title Inside the div tag with the class entry title.
You'll find the title.
We're going to replace this static text by calling the function the title you'll notice that there's
also a function called get the title.
This is a common naming convention for template tags.
The main difference between these two types of functions is that the get version will return the value
while the non get version will echo out the value the value itself is always the same.
Some template tags also come with the option of passing an H2 UML to form out the content.
This function has two parameters which is the HDMI all that will be placed before and after the title.
For example I can pass an opening and closing H2 tags like so as a result.
There are two ways to go about this.
You can just output the h t mail attach yourself or pass it into the function.
The benefit of passing in your h GM is that you give developers the opportunity to modify the h t amount.
This right here depends on the design of your theme.
I'm going to remove these because I prefer not to have developers form out this title.
Not all template tags have these options but it's definitely something you should consider if the option
is available.
All right let's move on.
Next up is the perma link function.
I'm going to replace the link for the title with this function this function will simply echo out the
you are well to the post itself.
Keep in mind that I'm getting all these from the template tags Codex page all these functions are available
to us and you can use them freely.
We will actually have to use this function multiple times as there are multiple locations a link is
being used.
Make sure you update all links as I have.
Next up is the date we'll be using the function get the date and we'll be echoing out the value.
There is a the date function but this function actually comes with a problem.
If there are posts with the same date then this function will end up acting funny and displayed the
same date even after the date between posts has changed in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the date function.
Here is what WordPress sets.
Special note when there are multiple posts on a page published under the same day that date only displays
the date for the first post to repeat the date for posts published under the same day.
You should use the template tag the time or get the date WordPress itself recommends that you use the
get the date function rather than the date function.
The format for the date is determined by the administrator in the admin dashboard navigate to settings
general here we can modify the output of the date.
We can also modify the format through the function itself.
This function can optionally accept one parameter which is a format and the resource section of this
lecture I provide a link to formatting the date and time in WordPress.
You can pass in any of the following and WordPress will change the output.
I'm not going to change the format as I like to let my users determine their own preferred format.
If you don't specify a format then WordPress will use the format in the settings.
Let's keep going.
Use the author function to output the name of the author.
So far so good.
Up next is setting up the URL to the author.
This one's going to be a bit tricky as we have to use two functions to obtain this value will be echoing
out the value returned by the function.
Get author posts you are about this function or return the U.R.L. to the author's profile.
However unlike the other functions this function isn't aware of being in a loop all the other functions
will automatically use the I.D. in the loop.
This function requires that we pass in the idea of the author so to do this we have to use the function
get the author meta which will retrieve information about the author this function is aware that it's
inside the loop.
This function can return a number of values but we're interested in the idea of the author.
So I'll just pass an I.D. in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the author meta function the page displays all the possible values you can retrieve
using this function.
This bit of code here will grab the perma link to the author's posts.
The very last thing we want to do is call the category function which will return an unordered list
of links of categories for each post.
However we do not want that.
We want the categories to be separated by spaces.
Luckily we can pass in a string that will act as a separator.
So I will pass in a string of an empty space.
Next up is the comments.
No function.
Replace this static text with the function this function will output the number of comments opposed
hence there are three parameters which are all optional.
The first parameter is the text to display.
If there are no comments I'm going to pass in the string zero.
If I were to admit this value then WordPress will automatically display no comments.
If there are zero comments in the post by passing in the string 0 WordPress will just output the string
itself.
The second parameter is the text to display.
If there is one comment and the third parameter is the text to display if there was more than one comment
I won't be sending these since I like the default values anyway.
The last thing we have to do is update the excerpt.
I'm going to replace the paragraph tags and call the function.
The excerpt which is a shortened version of the original post.
It's a really great way to give readers a preview of what's in the post itself.
As you can already tell we're just calling a bunch of functions that WordPress will take care of replacing
WordPress takes care of everything from page nation to querying the database to looping through everything.
All we have to do is instruct it where we want to place the data.
Let's refresh the page and see our dynamic posts as expected.
Everything works
before I end this lecture.
I want to talk a little more about template tags.
Let's go back to the page with the list of template texts.
People often get confused what a template tag is template tags is just a fancy phrase for a plain regular
P HP function.
The point of a template tag is to remove a lot of the logic from your template your template should
mostly be H.G. email with some p p code outputting the data template tags or functions that handle all
the logic for retrieving or processing data.
If we take a look at this list of functions you'll see that the first few items are the get header get
footer and get sidebar functions.
You should be familiar with these functions so far even though these functions don't query the database.
They do take care of loading certain templates and performing checks.
There are so many template tags here that it's a bit difficult to explore them all.
The best way to learn about a template tag is through practical use and understanding how to use them.
Throughout this course we'll be exploring how to use a lot of these template texts.
Anyway that wraps it up for now.
I'll see you in the next lecture.