The rewrite API is probably the most dangerous API where press has to offer.
And that's because even during the development phase of your plug in or theme it can destroy your site.
So to kind of keep things from getting too hectic this lecture will only be a light introduction to
this API.
The rewrite API allows you to modify the you real structure of WordPress the FCO friendly you or else
you see being generated are all thanks to the H T access file and WordPress free write rules.
The ability to add more rules or customize existing ones are all possible with the rewrite API in the
resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to this API.
Here's what WordPress has to say about it.
WordPress allows theme and plugin developers to programmatically specify new custom rewrite rules.
The following functions which are mostly aliases for WP rewrite methods can be used to achieve this.
Let's explore how you URLs are stored and what makes the rewrite Api work the way it does.
First let's open the H2 access file.
You can find this file in the root installation of your WordPress site.
Open this file and let's check out what's so important about it.
This file allows you to control how a site works by directly editing some of the server settings.
It's important to understand that Apache not PJ P reads this file.
If you have an error in this file then you'll end up destroying your whole site.
So editing This file should be taken with extra care the commands you'll find inside this file aren't
really newbie friendly but let's go through it one by one.
First you'll find these hash tags with some text after it.
These are considered comments so you're free to type whatever you want after these tags without breaking
the site.
Next up is this conditional statement.
It's written in an odd fashion but keep in mind that this isn't BHP what this line does is check if
a module called mod rewrite is enabled.
If it is then the rest of this code will execute the mod rewrite module makes it possible for you or
else to have user friendly you or else rather than having a lot of question marks Ampersand signs etc
inside this statement is code that will intercept all Euro requests and make the index stop page for
you file control the requests first we're instructing Apache to turn on the rewrite engine.
This will allow us to begin controlling how you are real should be displayed.
Then we're specifying a rewrite base the rewrite base is the list of folders relative to the root domain.
I'm currently inside my Udemy folder so that's what we'll be in put it here next.
All requests made to our site and any directories will be handled by the index dot P HP file.
There are some flags in place before this though.
These flags will make sure to display files that exist like image files.
If the files or directories don't exist then everything will be passed onto the index not page v file.
The way the image displays and WordPress doesn't have to use any CPE or bandwidth to handle the request.
This bit of code is what makes WordPress have a clean U.R.L. structure.
Keep in mind that this is only part of it but a very important part nonetheless.
As an extra precaution WordPress provides this page which stores the original contents of the HTC access
file.
I'll provide a link in the resource section of this lecture.
If you ever break the h t axis file then just copy and paste this into the file and you should be good
to go open Heidi.
Yes you will interview the options table.
Look for an option named rewrite underscore rules if you were to open this options value you'll find
that the word press corps plugins and themes all take the time to modify this option.
It's pretty extensive.
This is where all the rewrite rules are stored.
We are more than allowed to use the options API to modify this option but that's too risky.
All right enough talk.
Let's use this API.
Like I said before this will be a light introduction to this API.
Right now I have the activation function to opened up for our plugin.
I run into a problem where when I create a custom post type it won't work because the you or else aren't
flushed.
This varies from site to site but the problem is all the same.
To fix this you can go into the settings perma links page and just click update for the rules to be
rewritten.
However this is a pain and we always just want our plugin to work out of the box.
We can flush the rules ourselves with code.
There are only two steps we need to do.
The first step is to first register the custom post type.
Despite this being done in the init function WordPress won't run the init function when the plug in
is activated.
We have to call this function manually.
We previously named this recipe in it which contains the registration app for our post type.
We have to register it as it contains the url rewrite.
We can now flush the rules by calling the function called Flush rewrite rules this function will update
the rewrite rules since we registered our post type WordPress.
We'll be able to find out that there is a new you or real structure to account for it will update the
rewrite rules appropriately trying deactivating and reactivating your plugin.
You should receive no errors.
Just like that you were able to flush the rewrite rules and have our plugin compatible with most WordPress
sites.
This step is super important.
If you plan on creating custom post types let me go over what's going on in detail.
When a user makes a request to our site WordPress will check the rewrite rules option inside the database
and determine what page to load.
Based on the rules WordPress will grab the URL and then go through each rule.
It will try and match the URL to each rule once it finds a match.
WordPress will then make the correct queries and load the template for that page if it doesn't find
a rule that matches then WordPress war return a for all for error.
The rewrite rules are highly sensitive WordPress does not check for changes on every page request.
When we created our post type we created a brand new york URL structure.
However WordPress does not save the changes so in our activation function we told WordPress about the
new U.R.L. structure.
Then we told WordPress to add this new rule by calling the flush we write rules function.
The reason we do not call this function inside the init function is because it's not recommended by
WordPress.
If you think about it constantly telling WordPress to update its rules on every page load is inefficient.
It can also open yourself up to security vulnerabilities.