Creating a plugin is very similar to creating a theme.
All plugins can be found inside the WP dash content slash plugins folder by default.
WordPress will provide us with two plugins which are the hello dolly and a kismet plugins.
We also see the plugins we installed earlier.
Let's create our own plugin.
Unlike themes plugins can be created directly inside the plugins folder or in a sub folder.
However it's best practice to just create a sub folder with any plugin the plugin I want to create is
going to be called recipe.
I'm going to create a new folder named recipe inside this folder.
I'm going to create a new file named index top HP just like themes you need to provide a file header
to tell WordPress that this plugin exists unlike themes though WordPress doesn't require a certain naming
structure for plugins.
Actually if we take a look at the fake your press plugin then you'll see that all code is in the faker
Prescott page for your file and not the indexed P2P file.
You can name the main plugin file whatever you want.
Some developers named after their plugins others just use index top P HP.
Either one is fine.
I just want you to be aware of the two common possibilities.
Its all preference for this course.
We're going to just keep everything inside the next page for your file.
There's only one requirement to make this an official WordPress plugin.
We must create a file header and define one property.
So let's create a block comment and inside this blog comments add the following plugin name.
Colon recipe.
That's it.
Go to your plugins page and you should now see your plugin appear.
It doesn't have the rest of the information like the other plugins but it works.
This is the absolute minimum requirement for wordpress to recognize your plugin.
Nothing else in the resources section.
I provide a link to the file header Codex page.
WordPress provides a full list of optional headers we can define.
We're going to use a few of these.
Let's get started.
The second header we want to define is the description.
I'm going to put a simple WordPress plugin that allows users to create recipes and rate those recipes.
Up next is the version.
We'll keep it simple by sending it to 1.0
next is the name of the author.
Put your name down or the name of your organization.
I'm going to put down you to me the author you awry is a link to your personal site or organization
site.
I'm going to drop a link to the Udemy site.
Lastly we want to define the text domain.
I know we haven't gone over translations yet but this should always be set to the name of your plugin
folder.
So set this to recipe let's refresh the plugin page and see if everything works.
You should see something similar to what I see.
Feel free to look at the other headers and define whatever suits your needs.