Cron jobs can be a confusing concept to begin and developers out there but it's quite simple.
A cron job is a task or script that is performed at a certain time.
This can be performed once daily monthly or even every hour.
It's up to you.
Basically it's an automated task.
A lot of servers come with cron jobs built in.
All you have to do is tell the server what script to execute and when to execute it.
WordPress has a cron job task manager builds him.
We want to set up a cron job that will run once a day.
This cron job will pick a random recipe and use it as the recipe of the day.
We're going to schedule our cron job in the activation file open that file and at the bottom of the
function call WP schedule event function I'll provide a link in the resource section of this lecture
for this function.
This function has three parameters.
The first parameter is the first time this event will occur.
We want to run this right away so we'll pass in the current time.
The second parameter is the recurrence.
When will this function run again.
We are given 3 recurrence options hourly twice daily and daily we want daily.
You can set up your own custom recurrence but we won't be covering that in this lecture.
The last parameter is the hook that will be triggered.
Notice that I say hook and not function.
WordPress will create a custom action hook for you that you can then hook into yourself.
Other plugins can also who can do this event as well.
I'm going to call this hook our daily recipe hook WordPress will schedule this cron job upon activating
the plugin.
However I do not want you to deactivate and reactivate the plugin just yet.
We can now use this hook like any other action hook inside the plugin file.
Add our new custom hook and the function will call is our generate daily recipe
this hook is triggered once daily WordPress will take care of checking the time and calling this hook
for you next.
Let's create a file inside the includes folder and call it cron dot P. HP.
Define the function here include this file from the main plugin file
this function will run once a day at the beginning of the day.
WordPress cron jobs aren't perfect unlike regular cron jobs.
WordPress cron jobs won't run exactly at the same time everyday.
WordPress depends on a user visiting the site to check for schedule events.
For example our cron job will run once a day at the beginning of the day.
Let's say we don't get any traffic at the beginning of the day.
If the first visit is 4 hours after the beginning of the day then our cron job will run at that time.
This is very important to know WordPress cron jobs are not actual Unix cron jobs.
We're almost done cron jobs are managed by you the developer so it's important to know how to manage
all your cron jobs.
Too many cron jobs can lead to slow performance.
If we were to uninstall or deactivate the plugin our cron job would still be active.
WordPress does not deactivate cron jobs even if your plugin is inactive.
We have two unscheduled this cron job upon deactivation.
There's a special hook called registered the activation hook.
It works just like its opposite activation hook.
We have to pass in the main plugin file followed by the name of the function to call upon deactivation.
The function will be called r deactivate plugin let's create a file called deactivate dot P. HB inside
the includes folder.
This will contain the deactivation plugin.
Include this file from the main plugin file.
Two unscheduled an event we need to use the WP clear scheduled hook function this function has one parameter
which is the name of the hook.
In our case this would be our daily recipe hook
that's it.
We can now safely deactivate and reactivate our plug in knowing that will only have one cron job running
at a time.
We can now begin generating a random recipe of the day.
To accomplish this task we'll begin by using the transience API.
The transience API is an API that allows us to store data for a certain amount of time.
You can think of this as a cookie or session except that data is meant for the server and not the client.
It's exactly like the options API but with an expiration date by default the transience API will saw
the data in the database to be specific it'll store the data inside the WP options table.
The purpose of the transience API is to have your data readily available.
This can increase performance.
However here's the problem since the data is stored in the database then the response times will be
similar if you didn't use the transience API.
The great thing about the transience API is that a lot of its functionality can be overwritten.
We won't be exploring how to do that because that kind of stuff is handled by other plugins.
Ninety nine percent of the time you'll be working on a site that has a cache plugin installed or you'll
end up installing one anyway.
Most cache plugins or at least the better ones will overwrite its functionality rather than saving your
data in the database.
It'll save the data in memory data stored in memory can be retrieved faster therefore increase performance.
The problem with storing data in memory is that the data is not persistent.
That means that if the server was too unexpectedly shut down then any data would be lost.
You shouldn't store any important or sensitive data in memory for our case storing the recipe of the
day will work just fine.
Even if the data gets lost the cron job will end up storing another recipe of the day.
This is why we're using the transience API currently that data will get saved in the database.
We won't be able to see the benefits of using the transience API but on a production server we will
assuming you also install a third party cache plugin inside the cron function.
We're going to query the database for a random recipe we'll be using this query in multiple locations
so it would be ideal to place this code into its own function that we can call later on INSIDE THE includes
folder create a file named utility DSP HP we'll be placing any custom reusable functions here.
Sometimes you'll have stuff like that so it's always good practice to place those functions in a file
like this.
Include this file from the main plugin file
inside the utility file.
We're going to define a function called R get random recipe inside this we're going to need the global
w PDB object then we're going to make a query for a recipe i.e. let me break down this query.
We only want the post ideas from the post stable the W PDB object provides a post property that contains
the name of the posts table name.
Next we want to make sure we only grab published posts and posts with the post type of recipe.
Lastly we want to order the results randomly using the random my sequel function and limit the result
to 1.
This query actually performs slow.
There are a lot of examples out there that will generate a random row faster.
However this query only runs once a day so it won't release dress the server because of that.
This query will work just fine for our purposes.
We are returning the results of this query.
The last step is to set the transient switch back to the cron function.
We will use a function called set transient in the resource section of this lecture.
You'll find a link to the transience API Codex page.
This function has three parameters.
The first is the name of our transient I'm going to call this are daily recipe.
The second parameter is the value.
This can be anything we want.
You don't have to worry about sanitizing this value as WordPress will sign it.
Is it for us.
I'm going to call the R get random recipe.
Function.
Lastly we have to set an expiration time.
The recipe should only last for a day but time must be in seconds.
We could do the math and figure out how many seconds are in a day but WordPress provides a constant
for this on the transience API documentation page you'll find this section called using time constants
here you'll find a couple of constants that WordPress creates for you that contain how many seconds
are in an hour day week month etc. The constant day in seconds contains how many seconds are in a day
pass this constant in as the third parameter to the set transition function.
That's it.
We now have a random recipe of the day.
We'll get the same recipe every day since we only have published one recipe.
You'll have to reactivate the plugin again for this to take effect
we can now display the recipe of the day inside the widget back inside the widget method.
We are past two variables named arguments an instance let's use the extract function to convert these
two variables from arrays to single variables.
This isn't required but it makes it easier to read our code when using widgets one of the variables
extracted is called Tidal.
We will want to filter the title by using the apply filters function this function will trigger a filter
hook the hook we want to trigger is called widget title.
The second parameter for this function is the data we want to pass onto this hook.
Keep in mind that filters will return a filtered value.
Therefore we'll want to store the value any plugin that wants to filter the title of our widgets can
now do so including us.
We're going to echo out some variables provided by the arguments array the before widget is the T email
before every widget the before title is The CML email before the title you'll notice that the names
used here correspond to the Keys for registers sidebar function.
I'm going to open the widgets file inside the theme we created earlier these four keys are the actual
values for the variables we just used.
Every theme will have different HCM L but since we're using our own custom theme we'll know the values
of these variables.
Continuing on will want to append the title and then echo out the after title.
We don't have to worry about the HCM l styling is up to the theme.
Next we echo out the after widget to close up everything before the after widget we want to echo out
the recipe of the day along with a link to it.
Let's grab the transient that contains the I.D. we can grab the transient we created earlier by using
the get transient function we pass in the name of the transient we want to grab.
This would be our daily recipe
sometimes the transient may not work.
This could be due to a field cron job or failed query.
If that happens we'll want to create a backup.
I'm going to create a conditional statement checking if the recipe I.D. is empty if it is I'm going
to create a new recipe I.D. using the Oregon get random recipe function.
I'll also update the transient using the set.
Transient function with the new value.
The next step is to render the HDL.
I'm going to grab the team L from the static template and paste it in here.
Now all we have to do is take the time to convert it into a dynamic template.
This is nothing you haven't done before.
I'm going to replace the links with the Get pummelling function and pass in the recipe.
Then I'm going to echo out the title.
Lastly I'm going to use the post thumbnail
that's about it.
Let's check if everything works.
Go to the home page of our site and refresh it seems like everything is working perfectly.
We can click on this recipe and view the recipe of the day after you've confirmed everything works.
You can finally move on to the next lecture.
That was a lot to do but it was well worth the effort.
Hopefully you understand how to create widgets transience and cron jobs.