We're going to start things off with Buddy press development.
What I want you to do is install buddy press by the buddy press community.
This is a pretty large plug in so it may take longer than most plugins to install once installed click
activate
currently buddy presses on Version 4.
We'll be going over the latest concepts for Buddy press before we write a single line of code.
Let's modify some of the settings the bunny press settings can be found by going to settings buddy press.
I'm going to turn everything on so that we don't miss a thing.
When we installed buddy press it created a couple of pages for us.
Let's check those out.
It will generate the following pages activity members groups you can view any of these pages and you'll
see that Buddy press will generate the content for each page.
I'm going to view the members page.
I'm going to click on the admin profile and here you'll see a profile generated for us with different
sections separated with tabs.
We didn't have to do a thing buddy press is an extremely powerful plug them that will generate this
UI and functionality for you.
I'm going to go back to the page manager.
I'm going to try and view the edit page you'll notice that nothing here is out of the ordinary.
There are no special settings.
It's just a regular page.
So how does buddy press know that these pages are associated with it.
Well if you were to navigate to settings buddy press pages you'll find the settings where you can tell
Buddy press which pages it should display its content on.
There are a lot more features to Buddy press but we'll see how those work as the course progresses.
I'm going to go back to the admin profile you'll notice that there's this gray trip above the profile
and it has a sidebar.
It's really nice the buddy press took the time to try and match the design of the site as much as possible
but we could improve upon it.
What I want to do is make this page for with an update some of the sea assess to match our own site.
So where do we even begin.
Well keep in mind that Buddy press uses the same system we use something that Buddy press does is leverage
the templating hierarchy system in the resource section of this lecture I provide a link to the buddy
press template hierarchy page.
This page shows you how buddy press loads a certain page that it generates just like WordPress it'll
look for a certain file names and your theme and then goes down a list until it finds a file.
If it doesn't find anything then it'll just use the index top page template.
The rest of this documentation details all the various pages and their templates you can set we'll go
over how to generate these templates in a bit.
For now I want to generate the base template the base template is the template that encompasses all
other template buddy press is a plug in and it doesn't want to generate a whole lot of templates.
It would rather depend on one template and generate sections for that template the base template can
be named any of these names right here on the page.
I'm going to create the buddy press stop HP template inside the themes folder then I'm going to open
the full width page template and copy everything from here into the new template.
We are going to strip this template down to the bare minimum.
I'm going to get rid of the title header we see at the top of every page
then I'm going to remove everything inside the loop except for the post function
next I'm going to call the function the content.
Lastly I'm just going to remove some space and format this neatly
as you can see our template is extremely basic.
The reason for this is because Buddy press will take care of generating the contents of the page and
its format.
Don't worry we can override them later.
This is just to get us started.
Let's see if everything is working.
I want you to reload the member profile page.
You'll now notice a lot of what we saw previously is gone except for the content up buddy press generated.
This is exactly what we wanted.
There are some CSF changes we'd like to make and of course update some of the HD email here and there.
Which is totally doable.
What I really want to change is how the user profile looks.
I really like how the rest of these pages are formatted.
It's centered and their space which mean the menu and the content for the profile.
I want to make this cover image stretch all the way from left to right.
I also want to remove the space between the menu and content.
Let's read the buddy press template hierarchy page for a minute.
If you scroll down a little bit you'll find a section called Single Member pages.
Here is what Buddy press says.
If you are on a single member page buddy press will use the following template hierarchy.
Then it proceeds us to tell us more about what files will be loaded.
Unlike the WordPress hierarchy template system you'll notice that Buddy press will look for the files
within a certain folder structure.
This is very important to highlight as Buddy press requires dozens and dozens of templates and template
parts.
So the team decided it would be wise to use a folder structure so that the root theme folder doesn't
become cluttered with various files.
We will be using number 5 from this list.
I want you to create the folders buddy press slash members slash single inside your themes folder
then I want you to create a file named index stop BHP.
This is the file that Buddy press will look for when creating the single member profile page.
Next I'm going to copy the contents of the buddy press based template into this new template.
Since I don't want spacing and I want the cover image to be stretched I'm going to remove all these
tanks.
I'm going to take the time to format this a bit so that it looks cleaner
what you should have is the header a basic loop and the footer.
It should all be page code.
I know this looks very basic but I want you to bear with me on this.
The tags we removed are what causes the content to be centered and spaced.
Even though I want that spacing to be applying to the rest of the content it's kind of necessary to
remove it since the cover image was inside those tanks.
We could do some C Ss hacks to make it appear stretched but I think a better solution would be to apply
the centering and spacing to the tags inside rather than outside.
Let's test this out really quick refresh the single member page and you'll notice right away that the
spacing is removed and all the content is stretched.
This is almost what we wanted.
The only thing to do now is central the content itself.
We'll get to that in a moment.
I want to make sure the rest of the pages weren't affected.
I want you to view any other buddy press generated page like the activity page.
This page should still be centered and spaced.
After confirming that only the single member page is updated let's move on to the next task in the next
lecture will tackle cleaning up this template.