The next set of tanks we'll talk about our link tanks.
These are tanks that return or output links to different pages of your site.
You can use these functions to generate links to a specific post or the home page.
Here's a list of functions that take care of generating those you or else a lot of these are pretty
straightforward.
So I won't be talking about most of them.
I just want to focus our attention on the Get search link and these search query functions.
Right now I'm inside my editor and I have the search template open up I'm going to scroll down to the
search box section and add my code here.
So one of the more interesting functions is the get search link function as its name suggests this will
return a you URL to the search page.
I'm going to echo this function out this function has an optional parameter which will add a search
term to the URL.
I'm going to pass in the text Hello immediately right after this.
I'm going to echo a brake tag and call the function the search query that should do it.
Let's switch to the browser and try searching for something.
After a quick search the search template will load in our results.
Let's shift our focus to the text output it above the search box.
Two things are output it.
First is the euro generated by the get search link function.
You'll notice that the euro generated is different than the euro up in the address bar.
There are two ways to load the search template.
You can add the s query to the U.R.L. or you can access the slash search page followed by the phrase
like here.
I'm going to copy this your URL and paste it into the address bar.
We shouldn't see the search template load again.
You'll also notice the value from these search query function also changes the value in the euro is
the value output from this function.
I'm going to comment out the code we added in the template.
That's basically it when it comes to link tags.
They output your Ls and they're mostly straightforward.
I only showed the search functions because I wanted to demonstrate the various ways to access the search
template.
I also wanted you to understand why WordPress generated that you URL.