We're almost done with Buddy press.
The last thing we want to do is learn how to make some custom CSF changes.
It's simpler than you may think.
Inside the buddy press default nouveau template you'll find a folder called CSX buddy press will look
for a folder named CSX.
Inside your themes folder if it's available then it will look for a file named Buddy Prescott CSX and
automatically load it for you.
I'm going to copy the entire CSX folder and paste it into our things folder like so
to verify that this is working.
I'm going to open the buddy press men dot CSX file.
I'm going to select the buddy press I.D. and apply a random background color change
refresh the page.
After doing so you should see the changes applied.
This shows that Buddy Press is now loading the style sheets from our theme rather than its default stylings.
I'm going to remove the code we just added now that we verified the CSF file is being loaded.
We can now make some changes.
You're free to modify this C assess file any way you like.
It is as simple as that.
The only unfortunate part is that you need to name these files a certain way and they must be placed
inside a folder called CSX.
Other than that everything else is customizable so that does it for the buddy press development part
of this course.
There isn't much to it honestly.
You'll end up doing one of three things you may want to modify the templates HDMI all you now know how
to do that you just study the HCM L or read the template hierarchy and add that file to your theme in
their respective directory.
Afterwards you can make the changes you'd like to see.
You may want to hook into certain parts of Buddy press.
It's as simple as looking for the do action function inside the templates and using that hook to output
some HCM out.
In case you don't want to modify the template directly.
The last thing you may want to do is make some CSF changes and that's as simple as creating the buddy
Prescott CSX SS file before I wrap up this lecture and move on to the next thing.
You may be concerned about drastic changes to Buddy press.
Luckily buddy press will always inform you about template changes if your theme supports buddy press.
It's always best to keep up with the latest updates and to read about them when they do release notes.
However if for some reason you miss an email you can always go to the buddy press theme development
documentation page on the sidebar.
You'll find a list called template updates followed by the version number.
I'm going to click on two point seven.
You'll be shown a list of changes made to their templates.
If you made a change to any of these templates then you just have to read through this and apply the
changes manually.
This is the benefit of only copying the templates you use into your theme.
If you were to copy the entire directory into your theme then you would end up having to apply every
single change documented here.
This is why I highly recommend you only override the template to actually want to make changes too.
Also as you can see here there is a lot of code and changes you'd have to make.
It's almost an entire nights worth of code here.
All right that does it for Buddy press in the next couple of lectures.
We're going to begin working on new commerce development.