IF YOU'VE ACTIVATED THE RECIPE plugin then that's fine but you'll need to deactivate it for an app.
And this lecture will be doing some plugin activation settings and add some plugin security as developers
we have to do everything in our power to secure our plugins.
Of course we can't account for every hack there is throughout this course.
I'll be sure to advise you what you can do to secure your plugin.
One course of action we can take to secure this plugin is preventing users from calling this plugin
directly.
It's common for hackers to try to visit the file directly instead of letting WordPress load it.
So how do we prevent this.
Well it's actually quite simple.
Open up the recipe plugin file at the very top.
Add a conditional statement this conditional statement we'll check to see if a function exists.
WordPress loads its own files and constants before loading plugins so that they're available to us.
The function we want to check exists is called add action if this function doesn't exist then we know
for sure that WordPress isn't loaded and therefore we don't want to run the rest of this scripts inside
this conditional statement.
We're simply going to echo out a message.
Hi there.
I'm just a plugin.
Not much I can do when called directly and then exit out of here.
This way of doing it is common amongst plugins.
Actually I took this from the plugin a kismet.
This is a plugin prepackaged with most WordPress installations.
Let's take a look.
If we open the Kismet folder and view the Kismet dot Peach Tree file you'll find that this is implemented
in the same style and fashion as the recipe plugin.
This isn't completely foolproof but this should stop some of the most basic attacks out there.
Let's begin working on the plugin activation now inside the main plugin file.
Let's add some sections first.
Here are the four sections that will make setup includes hooks and short codes
under the hooks section.
We're going to call a function called register activation hook this function is a special kind of hook
made specifically for plugins.
This function will be called when our plugin is activated.
This function has two parameters.
The first parameter is the path to our plugin.
We could use some built in functions to get the path but there's actually a simpler way of doing this.
The HP provides a constant named file.
This constant will always point to the file it's used in the second parameter is the name of the function
that will execute.
We'll call this r activate plugin just like last time.
I'll be pre fixing the variables functions and anything else with R underscore to prevent collisions
with other plugins and themes.
Let's define this function now.
Create a folder called includes and within this folder create a file called Activate up HP
within this file determine the function and make sure to include it from the main plugin file
before we execute any code.
I want to check if the current version of WordPress is compatible with this plugin.
You can set this to any version you'd like but I'm going to keep things simple and say that the minimum
version required is 5.0 inside the activation function.
We're going to use a conditional statement inside this conditional statement.
Let's call the version compare function.
This is a P2P function that will help you with comparing versions.
The reason we use this function rather than a traditional comparison operator is because versions will
usually have multiple decimals.
For example WordPress currently released version 5 point 0 point 1.
This is a number that can't be compared traditionally.
So this function will help you with that no matter the schematic versioning you use for the first parameter.
I'm going to use the get blog info function and pass in the value version.
This will return the current wordpress installation version.
The second parameter is 5.0 which will be the minimum version required.
Lastly we'll use the less than operator.
This will basically check if the current version is less than the minimum required version.
For example if the current version is five point eight then it will be processed as five point eight.
Less than five point zero.
This will return false.
Which is great because that means our plugin is compatible with the wordpress installation.
However if this returns true then that means the WordPress version is really low.
If it is then we don't want to activate this plugin so we'll use the WP die function and output the
following message.
You must update WordPress to use this plugin
make this string translatable the text domain.
This time will be recipe.
All right so activate your plugin and you should be able to do so without any errors.
Now we can start developing the plugin we'll be revising this function later to create some settings
but for now we'll leave it as is.