We've explored how to load modules in the previous lectures but now it's time to learn how to use an
actual module.
Throughout this course we'll be using something called Web pack in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the Web site Web PAC describes itself as a module bungler.
That's not very descriptive so allow me to explain further Gutenberg requires a lot of files in order
for it to function correctly.
As you progressed through this course.
You'll find that we'll have dozens of files created just for the front end loading all these files is
bad practice as it can use up resources and hurt the performance of our site.
When Pax solves most of this by combining all your files together let's say you had dozens of J.S. files
for your plugin web pack will grab all those scripts and try to combine them into one or two files.
It'll also take care of minute filing and optimizing your code for you when PAC can do so much more.
By also combining your styles and compressing your images it can also create a web server for testing
your site on the site.
You'll see that web pack provides a simple diagram on how it works on the left you'll see various files
needed for your code to work.
This includes files from third party frameworks and libraries.
These files will be processed through web pack and as a result you'll have fewer files that are ready
to be used in production.
You'll notice that it also processes different file types so it's not just JavaScript see assessing
each GM out.
Westpac takes a little bit of work to set up initially but I promise you that it's very easy once you
understand what's going on.
I want to highlight that we won't be using all of web packs features we don't need it server because
we already have one.
We don't need to compress images or process the SS files we will solely focus on the javascript that
web pack can help us with this is perfectly fine.
You don't have to use web pack to its full extent.
A lot of the additional features are for developers who want to use web pack with known as the back
end.
Since we're using P HP and WordPress we don't need those extra features.
We just want help with the javascript code using web pact is completely optional.
However as you may have noticed I like to keep my code clean and organized web PAC will really help
us with organizing and scanning our code.
I also want to use the latest javascript features which aren't available in modern browsers.
This is something we'll explore more as the course progresses.
Let's look at some examples.
You don't have to follow along just watch.
Right now I'm on a site called strand bird guitars.
I'm going to open my developer tools and select the network tab.
We've talked about the network tab before it allows you to view the files loaded and how long it takes
for those files to load.
I'm going to filter the results to only display javascript.
Then I'm going to completely refresh the page and see what we get as you can see there are dozens of
files being loaded and the site takes some time to load.
Let's take a look at another example.
I'm on the Udemy site now.
I'm going to do the same thing as before open the developer tools and refresh the page right away.
You'll notice one huge difference.
There are weightless files being loaded and the site is loading faster.
You may or may not have noticed but Udemy is a single page app since it's a single page app.
You don't have hundreds and hundreds of files that should be loaded.
However the Udemy development team is very smart.
If the developers use Web pack to combine all their files together which reduces the amount of time
to load their site I can actually prove this further.
If I click on one of these scripts you'll see the preview appear on the right.
You'll notice the code has the key word web pack when PAC will load its own code to help you organize
your code.
If you take a closer look you'll notice that this file contains libraries such as angular and angular
carousel.
Usually you would expect these to be in separate files but with Westpac we now have one individual file.
This is the power of Westpac.
All right.
Let's get started with using Westpac.
Right now I'm inside a folder called Web pack dash example.
I want you to create a folder and name it whatever you want.
I also want you to open your terminal and navigate to this directory.
I'm using Visual Studio code so my terminal will automatically point to this directory.
I'm going to run the commands and PM in it.
This is a sub command that will help us generate a basic package file.
You'll see what this looks like in a moment.
After running this command go we take him through a walkthrough to help you customize your package file
the first field is the name property node will usually recommend some default settings.
If you decide to leave these fields empty.
I'm fine with the name so I'm just going to press enter it'll then ask for a version.
I'm also fine with the default.
Then you'll be asked to enter a description.
Even though there is no default this value is also optional.
So I'm just going to keep moving forward.
It'll then ask for the name of the entry point to file by default.
This is set to index dot J Yes.
Keep in mind that you can name your entry point or file whatever you want.
You can set this to apt on JSA or even server dodgy.
I'm going to keep it simple and just leave it at the default which is index dot J.S. the next property
is the test commands.
Tests do exactly what they sound like they will test your code for any bugs or errors.
However we won't be doing that so we'll leave this empty get repository will also be empty.
Since we won't be using get keywords author and license will also be empty.
You'll be asked if the settings you set are fine.
I'm going to say yes and then press enter node will then generate a file called package Di Jason.
Open this file and view the contents as you can see all our settings are now St.
For the most part a lot of these properties are unimportant to us as we won't be using Node heavily.
We'll only be using it to help process and combine files.
You'll notice we have this property called scripts where we can define our own commands.
We'll take a look at this later but you should be aware that it contains the test command we were asked
to input earlier since we input nothing.
It'll just have this default text saying there was no test command give it.
That's fine we won't be using this anyway so the default value is just fine as it's you are allowed
to create this file manually but I always prefer using the command as it makes sure if there are no
errors.
The reason we need this package file is because we'll be installing and using various modules.
The package file will save the modules we use and even keep track of the versions used.
You won't be able to see the benefits in this lecture but I assure you that it will help us in the future.
For now.
Just make sure you have it all right.
Now we can install Webb pack to install Webb pack.
You'll need to run the commands npm install Webb pack dash dash save dash Dev let's stop right here
for the most part.
This isn't anything we haven't done so far to install Webb pack.
We have to use the NPM install Webb pack commands.
However we also have this dash dash save dash Dev text right after it.
And this example we're using the save Dev flag.
This flag tells no that it should save this module inside the package.
Jason File as it's a required module.
You'll see what this looks like in just a moment.
All right let's execute this command node will do its usual thing and install Westpac for us.
Once Webb Park is installed you'll see the node underscore modules up here along with all the modules
required to make Webb pack work.
I want you to open up the package dock Jason File and you'll notice that there has been one change to
the file by using the save Dev flag.
Node will update the contents of this file by setting this property called Dev dependencies.
This property contains a list of all modules we have installed.
The benefit of this is that we no longer have to worry about remembering the name of the module.
I want to show you something.
I'm going to delete the node underscore modules folder let's imagine that I'm moving my files from one
system to another transferring modules can take a bit of time to save some time.
You may want to ignore those files.
Luckily you don't have to memorize all the names for each package.
Instead if you have the package Doc Jason File then you can reinstall all the modules by just running
NPM install.
If you don't specify a module to install then node will assume you want to install the dependencies
specified inside the package dot Jason File.
I'm going to run this command just like that.
I'll have web pack installed again.
All right.
There's one last thing I want to show you before we move onto configuring web pack.
There are two kinds of dependencies production dependencies and developer dependency.
Right now we're using a developer dependency developer dependencies are modules that are only meant
for development.
Developer dependency should not be used on a life site production dependencies.
On the other hand are meant to be used for live sites or projects.
I'm going to delete my node underscore modules folder and remove the property Dev dependencies this
time I'm going to run the command NPM install Web pack dash dash save.
There are two flags for saving dependencies.
I'm going to run this command and then go over the differences once again all have web pack installed.
Let's view the package.
Dot Jason File again this time a new property called dependencies is created.
This property will contain modules for production.
Only the dev dependencies will contain modules for development.
Only you can specify what modules should be for production or development by using either the save or
save dash Dev flags respectively.
For the most part it actually doesn't matter in our project because we won't be using note at all for
the production part of the site.
We're only using Node for development purposes so I just use the save Dev flag.
I'm going to delete the node underscore modules folder again and remove the dependencies property then
I'm going to run the NPM install web pack dash dash save dash Dev command again.
All right.
That was a long introduction and I knew it was a lot to go through but that's the basics of getting
started with web pack and the next lecture.
We're going to begin configuring web PAC.