Right now the recipe posts type we have is pretty standard just like any other post I can create content
add tags and even add a featured image.
I want to give the user the ability to rate a recipe on a scale of 1 to 5.
To do this we'll have to use something called the meta data api.
Usually you would try to create a database table and have it store the data.
However WordPress allows us to use something called the metadata API.
What is metadata.
Well metadata is basically just pieces of information related to a post page or user on its own.
It's not very useful.
Metadata has to be connected to something.
We'll use metadata to add and store all the additional information we'll need for recipes by using the
metadata API.
We free ourselves of having to create a table and managing it in the database.
In the resource section I provide a link to the metadata API Codex page as you can see there are only
four functions that you can use but they're very powerful.
We won't be using these functions.
And here's why.
Click on the ad metadata function.
WordPress provides a note that says this is a generic low level function and should not be used directly
by plugins or themes.
Instead use the corresponding meta functions for the object type.
You're working with as WordPress recommends we shouldn't use these functions.
Instead we're going to use meta functions specifically made for custom post types.
Now that we have an overview of things let's get started.
I'm going to go to my wordpress admin dashboard and create a new recipe.
I'm going to fill in some of these fields really quick.
Feel free to follow along and fill in these fields with whatever values you like.
We're not really worried about the values right now.
I'm going to make a recipe for a cake for the content area.
I'm going to use something called Lorem Ipsa lawn Epsom is a really handy tool that will help you generate
content.
I'm going to set this to two paragraphs and generate some content.
Copy and paste this into the text editor this tool is really great because you won't have to type in
gibberish or write actual content it'll generate dummy content for you.
I'll provide a link to it in the resource section of this lecture.
Next I'm going to add some tags and categories.
These can be completely random as well.
Don't submit this post just yet.
The next step is to save the metadata.
Along with this post once we have that code written out we'll submit those posts inside the index file.
Let's add the action hook save post
this hook is triggered when a post is saved.
Of course we only want to use this hook if the post is a recipe post and the resource section of this
lecture I provide a link to the Save post hook.
WordPress talks more about this hook but we want to concern ourselves with this custom post type example.
WordPress provides an example for how we should go about making sure we only save data for a specific
post type rather than a generic post or random post type.
However if you scroll down even further you'll find this note that says as of WP three point seven an
alternative action has been introduced which is called for specific post types save underscore post
underscore post type looking to this action.
You wouldn't have to check on the post type in the sample above to make sure we only process recipe
posts will add underscore recipe to the hook name.
This is what's called a dynamic cook.
Some hooks can be triggered for specific post types WordPress handles this for you.
All you have to do is call the hook and then replace the dynamic part with your post type.
Be sure to check the documentation to determine whether or not a hook is dynamic.
Just like that this hook will only be triggered for recipe posts.
The function we want to call is are save post admin for this part of the lecture.
We're going to use the two extra parameters that are optional for the add action function.
The third parameter is priority.
There is a possibility that other plugins might use this hook and the order of execution is determined
by this third parameter.
If this is set to 1 then this function will fire first before all others if set to a high number.
Then our function will fire last.
The default priority is 10.
We're going to leave this at 10.
The fourth parameter is what we really want to set this parameter allows us to define how many arguments
are set to the function.
What does this actually mean.
Well action hooks can provide our functions with extra information about the action currently happening.
Not every action provides this but the save post hook does by default.
This value is always 1.
However the safe post provides 3 arguments.
So set this to 3.
The only way to find out if an action hook provides extra arguments is by checking the WordPress documentation.
At this point I want you to create a folder called process.
I like to create a folder for functions and classes that process data.
This folder will contain all files related to updating deleting and creating data.
Once again this is not required by WordPress.
This is just the way I prefer to keep things organized.
Create a file called Save dash post dot p p and define the function here make sure to include it from
the index file
this function will be provided three arguments.
The first is the post I.D..
The second is the post which contains info about the post itself.
The third is update this variable is a boolean value.
It will let you know whether this is a new post or an old one being updated inside the function.
I'm going to create an array called recipe data.
This will be set to the function.
Get postmaster when it comes to metadata you will perform four types of operations.
You can either add get update or delete data.
The reason we're grabbing data is because this function will be called whether a new post is being created
or a current one is being updated.
In this case we're trying to grab metadata for a new post.
However since the post doesn't exist then there shouldn't be any metadata for it.
That's perfectly fine.
If no metadata is found then this function will return an empty value.
We'll use that to determine whether we should create it or updated.
This function has three parameters.
The first parameter is the idea for the post.
I'm going to pass in the post ideas variable then we have to set the key.
As you can imagine a post can have multiple pieces of metadata attached to it from various plugins because
this is the case.
WordPress allows you to give your metadata a unique key or name to identify it easily.
You can name your key whatever you want but you usually want to keep it relative.
We'll be calling our metadata recipe underscored data.
Lastly we have to determine if we want an array returned or a single value.
This third parameter can be true or false.
If you set this to true then WordPress will return a single value by default.
Metadata is stored in an array because multiple pieces of metadata can be attached to a post if you
just want the value without the array.
Then you should pass in an array.
However keep in mind that you're not limited to just storing single values.
If you don't want to create multiple metadata for a post then you can store the data in an array.
If you set this to true WordPress will return that array.
If you set this to false then WordPress will return an array within an array.
It can be confusing I know but just go with me on this one.
Ninety nine percent of the time you'll want this value to be true.
Just like that we now have the metadata.
I'm going to make one simple check by reassigning this variable using a ternary operator.
I'm going to check if the variable is empty if it is then we know that this is a new post.
If that's the case I'm going to set this variable to be an empty array.
Otherwise I'll just let it be all right.
The recipe data variable is ready.
After this I'm going to start setting some keys.
The goal is to store data related to rating the recipe.
There are two things we'll need to store.
We'll need the rating and how many times a recipe has been rated.
I'm going to create a key called rating and set its value to a ternary operator.
The condition will be checking if the rating key is already set if it is then I'm going to set it to
itself while wrapping the function with the ABS into function.
Otherwise the default will be zero I'm introducing the function abs and which is used for sanitizing
the value in the resource section I provide a link to the WordPress data sanitation and escaping user
data page.
This is a very important page.
You should read up on this page goes over the various functions for sanitizing user input a lot of great
examples and explanations are detailed here.
We will be using these functions throughout the course to stand as high as user input.
For now we're only going to use the ABS in function.
There's something I want to show you go back to your editor and navigate to the directory slash WP dash
includes slash formatting Guppy HP
this file contains a list of the sensitization functions for wordpress I highly recommend you look into
this file to understand how most of these functions work.
You can even borrow some of these functions for your own non WordPress projects.
If you ever had trouble with sanitizing data let's go back to the Save post function.
I'm going to create another key called rating count.
This will have the same values as the rating key like so
you should have something similar to what I have at this point.
The last and final step is to attach the data to the post.
WordPress provides a function called update post meta.
There is another function called add post meta but we're not going to use it.
The update version will actually check if this data already exists.
If it doesn't then it'll create it for us.
It's a kill two birds with one stone kind of scenario.
I'll provide a link to this function in the resource section of this lecture.
We're going to pass him three things.
First is the post I.D. even though this is a new post WordPress we'll be smart enough to provide us
with the post I.D. that will be use.
So let's pass him the post I.D. variable.
Next is the name for the metadata.
There can be multiple metadata is for one post.
It's important that we pass in a unique key.
I'm going to name it.
Recipe data.
Lastly we pass in the value for our metadata it's that simple.
Let's resubmit the data and the Post will now be sage the post should save successfully without any
error.
However how do we know if the metadata was St. will have to check the database to make sure open Heidi
and connect to your database metadata is stored in a few tables for our particular case.
This would be WP underscore Postmedia before we verify the data.
I want you to notice that this pattern is repeated for a lot of tables.
The actual content for the post is stored inside the WP posts table to find the metadata.
You need to add the word admitted to the table name.
This is true for the comments and comments Metta terms and terms meta.
And lastly the users and users medal tables metadata can be applied to almost anything including your
own custom tables.
If you ever do decide to go that far then I recommend you follow WordPress his database design.
Anyway let's move forward inside the posts table.
I'm going to look for my newly created post.
It should be the very last row in the database.
The reason I'm looking for the post first is because we need the I.D. Now that we have the I.D..
Let's look for the metadata in the posts met a table the post I.D. column will determine which metadata
is connected to which post searching through this you should eventually find the metadata related to
our newly created post.
WordPress takes the time to add in its own metadata and that's perfectly fine.
If you look long enough you'll eventually find the metadata with our key the key name is under the metal
key column.
The men of value column contains the actual key itself.
The value here is a bit strange.
WordPress does something called serialization for our values serialization is the process of converting
a PDP object or array into a string that can be stored in a database.
Objects and arrays can't be stored in a database.
They have to be turned into strings.
That's what's going on here.
If you look around you'll see that some values aren't serialized and others are.
If you're storing single values then they won't be serialized only objects and arrays are.
We don't have to worry about this process as WordPress handles it for us.
If you're using the meta functions then you should be fine.
However if you make raw sequel queries then you will need to take care of this process yourself.
All right.
That should wrap things up.
We have confirmed that the metadata has been saved and we can finally move on to displaying the rating.