In the previous lecture we got started with commerce development.
Right now we have this dilemma where we have two pages that aren't padded and have the sidebar messing
up the structure of the page.
The two pages are what we do commerce calls product pages in the resource section of this lecture.
I provide a link to the Template structure documentation page.
This page goes over how you'd go about overwriting the templates from commerce.
It's very similar to how you would go about overwriting templates in Buddy press.
It says that templates can be found inside the world commerce slash templates directory right below
you can find a link to the latest template changes the latest changes were made in three point five.
It should be noted that not every world commerce update comes with a template change.
If you can't find a version that's not here it's because there were no template changes made during
that time.
Click on one of these links you'll be taken to get hub where the repository is hosted this repo is the
same file and folder structure we have downloaded in our WordPress site.
If you take a look around you'll notice we have a plethora of templates made available to us.
Two things I want to highlight is that we have these folders called emails and Global's if I open the
emails folder you'll find all the email templates that will commerce will use whenever it needs to email
a user about anything specific like resetting a password or placing a new order.
We'll be taking a more in-depth look at these in the future lecture the other folder locals are templates
that are used globally throughout world commerce.
This is what we'll want to override in just a moment.
Let's tackle one thing at a time.
The very first thing I want to do is remove the sidebar from these two pages since we commerce thinks
it's necessary to take a full width page.
We should just force Woo commerce to take the same amount of space as any other post.
But I like this full width style.
Just like last time we have to search through all these templates to find the correct file to modify.
I did this already and it's easier than you may think the two files will want to modify are the archive
dash products dot HP and single dash product dot P. HP Temple of files
if I were to open these two files you'll see that world commerce provides helpful block comments stating
that these two templates are used for displaying products.
This is one way to save yourself time instead of studying H2 UML and comparing code you can just read
these comments where Wu commerce will describe what these templates do in more detail.
Now that we've determined which two templates to modify let's open them up inside the editor.
Initially the next step you may want to take is to copy this file paste it into our themes folder and
modify it from there.
But this would actually be the wrong action to take at this point.
The reason for this is because the world commerce does things slightly different than what most plugins
do.
This approach is very flexible and easier to work with once you understand how it works.
So what am I talking about.
Well let's examine the code from the single product template for a moment.
After looking around you'll eventually find a spot in the code where it begins to load the side bar
using the Wu commerce sidebar hook.
This might look a little weird at first.
Commerce uses a hook to load the sidebar but how.
Well let's take it one step at a time.
Well Commerce is calling a function called do action and running the hook Woo commerce sidebar.
We already know what this does.
Any code that hooks into this hook will be executed.
That includes us as well right above this code.
You'll see a block comment which is very important.
It might seem like random information but it's very useful to us.
The at hooked symbol is telling us that we'll commerce hooks into this hook within itself.
That may seem strange but it's completely valid to do something like that reading further you'll see
the name of the function and the priority.
Let's double check this to make sure this comment is in line.
Feel free to follow along just watch what I do.
If you can't I'm going to copy the hook.
Woo.
Commerce sidebar.
Then I'm going to right click on the Wu commerce plugin folder and select finding folder.
We only want to search through the code inside this plugin almost immediately.
Visual Studio code will show me all the locations where I can find this text within the web commerce
plug and folder will be returned with five results two of which are comments which we can ignore.
Another two results will be inside.
Do action function right above each of these is the name of the files where the searched texts can be
found.
The two files where this is used are the archive product and single product files.
Just what that information alone we can determine that this hook is specifically for product pages only.
What we care most about is this first result which uses the add action function.
Let's click that and preview the code you'll see that Woo Commerce wants to call a function called Woo
commerce get sidebar with a priority of 10.
This is the same information that was given to us in the comment block previously.
Let's check out what this function does.
I'm going to do what I did last time.
I'm going to copy the name of this function and then search for it from within the Wu commerce plugin
folder.
We don't care about most of these results.
We only care about where the function is defined.
I'm going to double click on the result where the function is defined.
Visual Studio code will open that file and take you to where that function is defined.
All this function does is call the function W C get template which will load a template file the template
that will be loaded is the global slash side bar dot P HP file just like Buddy press will.
Commerce has a function that loads Woo commerce specific templates.
This function will search for the template into locations the first location is inside our theme folder.
Even though we don't have any world commerce templates it will look for a folder named Wu commerce and
then find the template relative to the path passed in if it doesn't find it there then it'll look for
the template inside the Wu commerce slash templates plugin folder.
Let's open this template from the Wu commerce plugin folder
there's quite a bit of code going on here but it's mostly just comments.
We're going to focus on this line here to load a sidebar.
All the symbol it does is call the function get sidebar and pass in the string shop.
If you don't remember.
Let me give you a brief overview of what this function does.
This function will look for example at named sidebar dot P. HP inside the themes folder.
However if you pass in a string it'll then look for a file named sidebar dash followed by the name of
the string and then end it with DOT P HP.
In this example it will look for a template named sidebar dash shop dot P HP.
This file doesn't exist in our theme so WordPress will default to the sidebar.
Dot P HP file which is what's happening here.
This is why the sidebar is being loaded inside this shot page even though it doesn't really work with
a full with page.
Now do we understand what's happening.
We just have to remove it.
There are a couple of solutions here.
We can copy the archive products and single product templates to our theme and remove this line of code
or we can just grab the sidebar dot P HP far from the Global's folder and just remove it.
Both approaches are wrong.
The correct solution is to just remove the action.
We have done this before but you're completely allowed to do so and it's easy to do.
I'll explain why this is the best solution in a moment but first let's try it out.
I want you to open the things functions file and call the function remove action.
This does the opposite of what the add action function does which is remove an action function from
money.
The first parameter is the name of the action hook which will be.
Commerce sidebar.
The second parameter is the name of the function that we want to remove which is the Wu.
Get sidebar function.
The last parameter is the priority which was 10 all this information can be grabbed from the comment
blog that contains this information.
You don't have to search through the files like I did.
Well Commerce does a good job of commenting everything as you can see throughout this template.
With this one line of code we have removed the sidebar.
Let's refresh the page and see if everything worked.
As you can see the sidebar is now gone.
All right.
Let's talk about the benefits of doing it like this instead of copying the templates and just modifying
them.
We save ourselves the time by doing something like this.
Another benefit is that this code is so much easier to maintain.
I would rather maintain one line of code as opposed to maintaining a whole template.
Lastly we actually open ourselves up to more flexibility even though we removed this function from the
hook.
Other functions will still be allowed to run even us.
Let's test this out really quick.
I'm going to create an action hook for the world commerce sidebar.
I'm going to run an anonymous function just for example sake.
I'm going to simply echo out the word test refresh the page and you'll now see the message being output
it.
If we were to remove the do action function call from the template then we limit ourselves and other
plugins from needing to use this hook.
This would be considered bad practice and would give more problems down the road.
It is so much easier and simpler to just remove the function from the hook.
I'm going to remove our anonymous function as we don't want to use it in production.
The next step is to just add some padding which is easier and doesn't require as much research inside
the Global's folder.
You'll find HCM L that applies to almost all pages in commerce.
There are two templates called Wrapper START AND wrapper ends.
These two templates generate code that wraps around all woo commerce content specifically templates
that require their own templates rather than a short code open.
Either of these files if you take a look you'll see that world commerce grabs the current name of the
theme activated it checks if any of the official wordpress themes are activated and while output different
types of HCM l depending on the theme.
However if the current theme isn't an official wordpress theme then it'll just load these default div
tags.
Here's what we're going to do in order to override existing templates we have to create a folder named
Wu.
Commerce inside the theme folder.
Let's do that now
then we can just copy the templates respectively into this folder.
I'm going to copy and paste the Global's footer into the Wu commerce folder in our theme.
Then I'm going to delete everything inside this folder except for the wrapper start and wrapper end
files
open both files.
I'm going to remove the conditional statement since we already know that this isn't an official wordpress
theme.
I'm just going to leave the last set of opening and closing div tags in both files
then I'm going to apply some classes to the first opening div tag I want to empty content dash wrap
class
then I'm going to apply the class container to the second main element.
These are the same classes we use in our other templates.
I'm going to refresh the page you should now see our content being paid correctly for the most part.
I don't mind modifying these templates since they don't have any significant code that would cause problems
with other plugins or our theme before I wrap up this lecture.
I want to talk about keeping up with updates.
If you look at the documentation page I linked earlier you'll find a link to fixing outdated with commerce
templates.
This page goes over what the title suggests.
It's very simple to do.
If you were to go to the admin dashboard and navigate to woo commerce system status you'll find information
about how well commerce is operating and if everything is working smoothly.
If you scroll to the very bottom you'll come across the templates box.
This box tells you what templates are being overridden.
In our case it would be the wrapper template files.
Whenever an update occurs you will always want to check this box.
It'll give you a warning to let you know if the current template you have overridden is outdated.
If it is then you just simply need to paste in the new version and redo the changes you made.
It's kind of a pain but it's what you have to do.
So how does Wu commerce know when a template is outdated.
Well if you were to open up one of the overridden templates you'll find a block comment inside this
block comment.
You'll find this one piece of data that says version followed by the version of the template will commerce
will check this value to see if it's outdated.
It's extremely important that you always leave the block comments intact when overwriting them.
It's how you keep yourself up to date with the latest changes.