In this lecture we'll explore how to create templates for attachments that template hierarchy goes through
quite a bit of templates to display attachments.
You can actually get really specific here by creating templates for certain MIME types.
First let's understand what a MIME type is.
A MIME type is a way for a program or browser to identify what kind of file is being loaded.
It's similar to a file extension except the mind types or stored internally into the file itself.
This makes it a bit harder to change as opposed to file extensions checking a MIME type is safer than
checking for an extension but it isn't foolproof.
Now that we understand mind types let's explore the template order WordPress will use.
First it will check for the MIME type of the file and then search for a template with the same name.
If it doesn't find one then it'll fall back to the attachment template.
This is followed by the single attachment that uses the slug.
Lastly the single singular and indexed templates are used in that order.
Anyway let's get started with creating attachment templates.
Go to your Adam and dashboard and look for the menu item media.
WordPress will allow you to manage all your uploads through here all file uploads are what WordPress
considers attachments.
If you use faker press then you should see quite a few attachments being displayed here.
Fake your press generated these for us which is nice.
I'm going to click on one of the images and you will see this modal pop up providing more details about
the attachment.
There are two ways to view this image.
You can either use this you are all here or you can click on this link that says view attachment page
Let's view the attachment page as you can see we have the image appearing here and we have the rest
of the page being displayed by default.
WordPress will use the single or index templates if an attachment template isn't present.
While I do like that my theme is being displayed there is way too much information here just for the
image.
So let's create the attachment template now or this template.
I'm going to copy all the code from the single template into this new template.
Then I'm going to remove the metadata featured image patch nation links next and previous links tags
related posts and author box
what you'll end up having is the title content and the comments.
Not really spectacular but this is just an attachment template so the details don't matter as much.
Let's refresh the page and see what we get.
The image will disappear and nothing really displays.
But why is this.
What's happening is that WordPress now assumes you want to display attachments your own way by creating
the attachments template you're also given control over how an attachment should be displayed.
WordPress will not do it for you.
So how do we get the attachment info.
Well there's a special variable that's created that contains all this info back inside the template.
I'm going to print R the post variable.
I'm also going to surround this with pre-tax
by calling the function the post this variable is automatically created for you and you can use it anywhere
in your loop in future lectures.
We'll go over how to use this variable to our advantage but for now we'll just look at what's inside.
Go back to the page and refresh.
You should see the data about the post being printed out.
There's a lot of information being output here but we only care about three properties.
The first property you'll notice is the post type.
It's set to attachment which WordPress uses to determine if the attachment template should be used.
There's also the mind type being set will actually use these later to create more specific templates.
I'll talk more about that later.
The last property that's important is the g Whitey's property.
This will contain the direct link to the attachment itself.
Now that we know where to find this information let's use it.
I'm going to remove the print statement and then write above the content.
I'm going to create an anchor link the text will be direct download and the link will be dynamic using
HP.
I'm going to access the G white property from the post object like so if everything worked then we should
be able to refresh the page and see the direct download link appearing something I want to highlight
is that if you don't see a title then chances are the attachment itself doesn't have a title.
If you go back to the media manager you should see this field where you can set a title set one so that
you don't see a lot of empty space all right.
This is great.
I want to take this a step further but I want to do is display that image right below the download link
but there's one problem we face.
This attachment template will be loaded for any attachment.
This includes videos applications PDA files and any other files that aren't images.
Luckily we can get around this by creating a template for a specific mind type in the resource section
of this lecture.
I provide a link to the function get allowed mime types.
We aren't going to use this function but what I want you to look at is this list of mind types on the
left.
You have the extension and on the right you have the mind type itself.
You'll see that mime types or formatted in a certain way.
There's the category and then the type of file itself.
For example there's the image video text audio and other categories.
If we look at the image category you'll see all the various types of files that fall under this category
which are JPEG gif PMG.
So on and so forth.
Let's create a template for this.
All you have to do is name your template.
After the MIME type in this case we should name the file image dot the HP now.
Any attachments with this MIME type will be loaded using this template.
I'm going to copy over the code from the attachment template into this template.
The only change I'm going to make is add an I am G tag right below the direct download link since we
know that the URL to the image itself is saved inside the G United property.
I'm just going to pass that in here.
I'm also going to give this image a class of image dash responsive so that the image doesn't wander
off the page refresh the page and you should now see the image appearing.
This is great because we now have two attachment templates one template is for images that will display
that image to the user.
And another is for any generic attachment.
You can obviously take this even further by adding a video player for videos or a PDA viewer.
The solutions are limitless.