Ezio is a beast of its own as a developer.
You should take every step to make sure your theme is SC already and is compatible with most SEO plugins.
There are dozens of them out there throughout this course.
We've prepared the theme to be SC already but we can definitely take it a step further.
Right now I'm on a site called scheme dot org.
I'll provide a link in the resource section of this lecture schema is a way to tell bots and crawlers
more about the content on your site.
Currently if a crawler like Google's crawler were to read through our HD PML it would have to guess
what kind of content is being read.
Google's algorithm is smart enough to be able to sort through all the H2 UML and make good guesses.
However we can help.
This is where micro data comes into play.
You can add attributes to certain tags to let the crawlers and bots know what they're looking at and
decide how important the content is.
Most SEO plugins will assist you by adding some micro data for you but there are just some sections
that can't reach.
So it's our job to cover those missing spots.
This site will provide you everything you need to know about micro data.
If you go through the documentation you'll find a link for getting started.
We won't be going over every little thing.
I'll just cover the main points.
It isn't that hard.
Micro data is just a fancy word for a few set of specific HDMI attributes that specify what kind of
content a bot or crawler is viewing.
The first attribute you use is called the item scope.
Just by including this attribute you're specifying that the HCM element contains information about something
the next property is the item type where the value of this attribute is a you are well to where more
information about this element can be found.
The U.R.L. must point to schema dot org and to the appropriate page.
We'll talk more about these your roles and how you would go about setting them the last property is
item prop which is an attribute you set to specify how the element is related to the item type.
It gives you the ability to fully describe the content these three attributes are the attributes you'll
use the most.
When adding micro data to your templates it may seem kind of confusing at first but you'll get the hang
of it once you start adding them.
Let's start using them on the schema site.
I want you to click on the schemas link.
You'll be taken to a page where you can view certain types or view the full list.
I'm going to view the full list on this page you'll see the full hierarchy of types.
You can select when you get started with micro data.
The very first thing you want to do is think about what type you want to set.
In general your Web site is a type of data that sounds weird but just go with me on this.
If you look around you'll find a type called Web page.
Click on this.
Here is what schema has to say about this type.
Every Web page is implicitly assumed to be declared to be of type.
Web page.
So the various properties about that web page such as breadcrumb may be used.
We recommend explicit declaration if these properties are specified but if they are found outside of
an item scope they will be assumed to be about the page.
We really don't have to set this type but I believe it's a good example when it comes to getting started
with micro data.
I want you to open the header file from our theme search for the opening body tag and applying the item
scope attribute.
This is the first step by applying this attribute.
You're telling the crawler that this element contains information the crawler should be aware of the
next attribute you need to set is the item type attribute the value of this attribute is the you are
well to that type.
This is an important step.
As I stated previously it must be a you or rail to where more information can be found about that time
that you are well is the full you are rail H GDP colon slash slash schema dot org followed by the type.
You can also just copy and paste the euro RL you find here it's important to understand that only you
are real to the schema dawg site are allowed all other sites will just be ignored.
The bot will see this and then look at the euro well for reference by looking at this page it'll understand
what kind of properties you can set and what you can expect to look for when it's scanning all the children
elements.
That's the basics of it.
There is one more attribute but I want to use that in another example.
It's perfectly fine to specify a type and no properties.
I'll expand more on this later but let's move on to the next example open the single template and search
for the author box this element contains information about the author.
It would be ideal to apply some micro data to it just like the last element.
We need to decide on the type.
If you look through the list you'll eventually find an item called person.
Let's use this inside the template and the item scope and item type attributes.
Copy and paste the euro as the value for the type.
This time I want to specify more information.
If you look through this documentation you'll find all the properties we can set for this type.
One of these is name.
Every person has a name and our author box displays the author's name to apply a property you have to
use the item prop attribute apply this attribute to the span tag which encompasses the name then set
its value to name.
We're only going to apply this property you are more than free to apply more properties.
You'll also notice that we have a type on the body tag and it type for this element which is inside
the body tag.
This is perfectly allowed.
Types can have types inside them to reiterate what's going on when search engines scan this page they
will eventually come upon this element Upon scanning it.
It will find the attribute item scope telling it that the developer is specifying what kind of information
is inside this element.
It will then look for a type which in this case is person.
It will then search through the properties for this type.
This is how you would go about using micro data.
So far we've used only the web page and person types but there are dozens of them on this page.
Some are even children of certain ones.
For example the type thing is the parent of all these types including web page and person.
If we look at the Web page type you can see we can get even more specific with the type by seeing the
page is an about page or contact page type.
The more specific you are the better I'm going to give some closing thoughts.
Adding micro data is absolutely not required.
You'll find that a lot of sites don't use micro data.
It's more or less a way to help search engines better understand a page.
If you forget to add micro data to a comment or to an article then that's fine.
Search engines will still scan the elements and try to understand the content on its own.
These attributes are just a way to help it better understand your content without having to guess.
If you're having trouble using micro data I highly recommend you work with an NCO specialist and work
together to maximize the CEO of your theme.
To test your snippets you can go to the structured data testing tool from Google.
I'll provide a link to this in the resource section of this lecture.
You just paste in a you are real or just paste in a small snippet of code and Google will tell you how
it reads that data.
Since we're on a local server we really can't test it.
That basically sums up micro data and how to use them.
I highly encourage that you read the documentation to learn more about what you can do with micro data.