In the last three lectures we took a look at how to register and authenticate users manually.
We took care of submitting and processing the request.
We also took care of error handling and redirecting the user if the authentication was a success.
In this lecture we're going to take a look at an alternative method for authenticating the user.
Previously we only use the functions WordPress provides to handle the logging.
However WordPress provides a couple of files for handling the logic for us.
This process is a bit more limited and harder but we get the advantage of letting WordPress handle the
logic for us.
The original WordPress logon page can be used to authenticate the users.
We can hook into this system and use it to our advantage.
So let's get started.
The very first thing we need to do is create the short code inside the main plugin file under the short
code section.
Add a new short code and call it recipe off all to form the function to call will be our recipe off
alt form short code
after defining the short code.
Let's define the function that will contain our short code logic inside the includes slash short codes
folder create a file names off dash form dash all dot P HP.
Define the function here and include it from the main plugin file
let's add this short code to the My Account page.
We previously named it recipe off art form so input that into the short code block and update your changes.
Once that's been input ID log out and then navigate to the My Account page.
I'm going to place the short code right below the forum so we can do some comparisons.
Back inside my editor I'm going to copy the code from the original authentication short code into the
new one
then I'm going to get rid of most of this code except the conditional statement at top and the return
statement.
WordPress provides a function for generating a log in form it integrates really well with Wordpress
as log in system.
However it is not formatted so we'll have to take care of that quickly.
I'm going to set the form HCM email variable to div class equals call one third no bottom margin
then I'm going to close the div tag right before the return statement.
We'll be placing most of our code between these two tags.
The function that WordPress provides for generating a log in form is WP log in form.
I'm going to append this function onto the form H2 email variable
in the resource section of this lecture I provide a link to this function.
This function only has one parameter and that's an array of settings we can pass in to change the output
of the form.
One thing I do want to highlight is that while there are quite a few parameters here the log in form
is not that flexible.
WordPress doesn't really provide a way to add classes or change the HCM l will just work with what we
have back inside the editor.
I'm going to pass in an array.
There are only two keys I want to set the first key is the echo key.
Since this is a short code we have to return the HDMI out the WP log in form function will output the
form by default in order to make it return the GMO.
We have to set this key to false the next key I want to set is the redirect key by default.
WordPress will automatically redirect the user to the page where the form was submitted.
It doesn't really make much sense to redirect the user back to the log page.
If they've successfully logged in I'm going to set this to the home your URL function and I'll simply
pass in a forward slash to indicate I want the user to land on the root you URL with all that said let's
refresh the page and see what we get.
WordPress generates this form for us which doesn't really look appealing.
Like I said before the function we are using doesn't allow us to customize the HCM.
And class is being used.
The reason we use it is because it'll generate all the input fields required for this form to work with
the WordPress log and flow.
Alternatively you could just copy and paste the h t email into your short code and just modify it from
there.
For this course I'm just going to apply some styles to the HCM l generated inside these slash assets
slash C Ss folder.
You'll find a file called off dot c SS I want you to register and in Q this style sheet from the front
and Q function.
I'm going to do this really quickly all right.
I just registered and in queue.
This file.
All I'm really doing is stretching the width so that it doesn't look so out of place.
Refresh the page and you should see form look more formatted and improved.
You can leave it like this as we don't really need to do anything else.
WordPress will now handle authenticating the user and providing errors.
There is one problem I have with this form no besides the styling.
I'm going to empty out these fields and then submit the form after submitting the form.
You should see an error message.
However I'm not redirected to the My Account page.
Instead we end up on the default WordPress log in page.
The point of having a front end form is so that the user doesn't have to see this.
We'll have to slightly modified the way of the authentication behaves in order to make the submission
redirect back to the My Account page.
If it was a failure just to save some time I'm going to paste the code inside the main plugin file I'm
inside the main plugin file and I added in end to hooks here which are both the same.
These hooks are actual hooks WordPress registers.
The reason I'm adding them here is just for example purposes.
So the name of the hook is authenticate you use this hook to check the user data.
WordPress will register two different functions here.
What's most important here is the priority.
What we want to do is change the way the authentication behaves while still letting WordPress do the
heavy lifting.
I want my function to run after WordPress has finished processing everything and is about to redirect
the user.
I want my priority to be a higher number than these two.
So my function gets executed last.
I'm pacing in these two hooks to show you their priority.
After these two hooks WordPress will have already executed everything and we can then take over.
I'm going to comment these two out since WordPress already registers these two hooks doing it ourselves
would be redundant below this.
I'm going to add a filter hook using these same authenticate hook as above the function I want to call
it will be called are all to authenticate
then we must set the priority by default.
This will be 10 but I want this to be higher than the ones WordPress registers.
Therefore I'm going to set this to 100.
You will also be provided with 3 values to use in the function.
I'm going to set the fourth parameter to 3 so we can accept all three values in our function just to
save some time.
I'm going to define this function inside the short code file at the bottom like so the three parameters
that are accepted are the user username and password.
Inside this function I'm going to create a conditional statement that will check if the request method
of the server variable is not set to post.
If this condition passes I'm just going to return the user.
I don't want to redirect the user if the method is not post.
Post is usually the method that's used when processing log in data.
Next I'm going to create another conditional statement to check if the user object has errors by passing
it into the function is WP error
if this returns false.
I'm going to once again return the user object.
If this ends up happening then that usually means the user was successfully authenticated and so there's
no need to redirect them back to the logon page.
If the function has made it this far then that means the log in submission has failed.
I'm going to create a variable named error codes and set its value to the function.
Get error codes from the user object.
This function will return an array of error codes.
I want to pass the error codes back to my form so that we can display the errors to the user.
However we can't really pass an array back to the user so we'll need to convert this to a string.
I'm going to wrap this with a function called join which will convert an array to a string.
The first parameter to this function is the separator which will just be a comma.
The second parameter is the array itself.
Now that we have the error codes in string form we'll have to append it to the your bill itself that
we want to redirect the user to.
I'm going to create a variable named log in you are well and set its value to the home your URL function
and passing the string.
My dash account.
We are manually setting the page here.
Usually you want this to be dynamic but we'll keep things simple here for now.
This is just an alternative example to the original authentication method we did anyway.
I'm then going to reassign this variable to the function add query arg.
This is a function provided by WordPress that basically accepts a U RL and will add a query to the URL
for you.
It will take care of making sure the euro is safe and ready to be used.
There's three parameters for this function.
The first parameter is the name of the query which will be log in.
You can name this whatever you want but log in tends to be a common naming convention.
The second parameter is the value for this query which will be the error codes.
Lastly you just pass in the URL which would be logged in you are.
Now we have a full you URL with the error codes you'll see what the error codes look like in just a
moment.
The last step is to call the WP redirect function and pass in the U or L this function will redirect
the user to the My Account page just as an extra measure.
I'm going to kill the script with the exit statement that should finish up our function.
Let's refresh the page and try submitting the form with no input whatsoever.
You should be redirected back to the page like I have.
If you look at the URL bar you'll see the error codes appearing each error code is separated with a
comma which is great.
Back inside the shortcut function we can grab the error codes by creating a variable named errors and
set it to the get variable
by default.
The error codes will not appear so we'll use a ternary operator here.
I'm going to check if the get variable is set.
If it is I'm going to set it to this variable.
If not I'm going to set it to an array.
Of course the get variable is a string so we'll need to convert it into an array.
I'm going to use the function explode to convert it from a string to an array.
The first parameter is the separator which is a comma and the second parameter is the string itself.
Just like that we now have our error codes.
I'm going to paste in some code here which I'll go over.
All right so all I have here is a loop going through each error in the array.
There are four possible error codes which are empty user name.
Empty password invalid user name and incorrect password.
I'm adding some messages to the form element and displaying a user friendly message to the user.
Nothing too crazy here.
All right let's refresh the page and you should see the 2 errors appearing here.
I'm going to submit the form again but this time with correct credentials
you should be logged in and redirected to the home page if it was successful.
This is exactly what we wanted.
So that concludes how you would authenticate a user.
I've shown you two ways on how to do this and either one is a valid solution.
Some developers tend to think that they have to extend everything but that's simply not true.
You can take advantage of WordPress as core behavior and just tweak some things internally using hooks
at the end of the day.
It's all preference.
I'm going to comment out the second solution.
I usually don't recommend it because at any point WordPress could change this behavior.
There's also a lot of plugins that alter the way wordpress logs users in it tends to be a pain to deal
with.
Now you may be wondering but what about user registration.
Unfortunately WordPress doesn't provide any functions for creating a register form.
This means you'll have to create it manually and hook it into the regular WordPress registration system.
We won't be doing that in this course as it tends to be a long and hard process making it not worth
it.
However you're free to check it out yourself.
All log in and registration is handled inside the WP dash log in copy HP file.
Anyway I'll see you in the next lecture.