I want to display my custom taxonomy on the front end before I do that.
I want to add some settings from my taxonomy.
If you were to go to the origin edit page you'll find a list of origins and a forum for creating a new
one.
This form is pretty basic but I'd like to add onto it.
I want to add a U or L for more information about an origin to pull this off.
We'll have to do a couple of things.
The first step is to add the form fields inside the main plugin file.
Add the action hook called add form fields.
This is a dynamic hook right before the hook name.
You have to append the name of the taxonomy which has origin.
This is how WordPress knows which taxonomy this hook should run under the function I want to call it
will be named R origin ad form fields next.
Create a file inside the includes slash admin folder named origin dash fields not P HP.
Define the function inside this file and make sure to include it from the main plugin file.
I'm going to paste in some H2 email into this function let's break this down the H2 e-mail here is the
same HDMI l you'll find if you were to inspect the element on the form.
Nothing really special here except for two things.
The first thing is the name of the input field.
It should be unique.
I set this to are more info you are out.
The next thing is the paragraph tag which contains a short description about the input field.
This is completely optional to add but it's useful to give your users more information about this field.
That's all there is to creating the input fields.
You don't have to worry about adding form tags as this will already be wrapped in one.
The next step is to save the value back inside the main plugin file.
Add a new action hook called Create underscore
this action hook is also dynamic it is followed by the name of the taxonomy which is origin the function
I want to call it will be named R save.
Origin Metta.
I'm going to create a new file inside the process folder called Save dash origin dot P. HP with the
function defined inside.
This function will be passed in the term I.D..
Lastly make sure to include it from the main plugin file
inside this function.
I'm going to check if the field is set.
If it isn't then I'm just going to return the function
just like posts.
Terms can have metadata to clarify the origin is a taxonomy but each individual origin is called a term.
This goes for any taxonomy the individual categories or tags for a post is called a term so you can
have term metadata the metadata API can be used for this.
WordPress provides a set of functions to save.
Term metadata which work the exact same way as the Post metadata functions.
The name of the functions are just different.
I want you to call the update term meta function.
The first parameter is the idea of the term.
The second is the name which will be more info you are real and the last parameter is the U.R.L.
I'm going to wrap the value with the function escape you are raw which will make sure this is a safe
you are El.
This will take care of creating the term.
It's important to note that taxonomy is will have two different forms of form for creating the taxonomy
and another for editing a taxonomy to save some time.
I'm going to go back to the main plugin file and copy this action and replace the second one from create
underscore origin too.
Edited underscore origin the edited version will be used when a user updates that you are out the function
will be the same.
We're almost done.
The last thing I want to do is create the form field for the edit form page.
The HCM l will be different but the idea is the same.
I'm going to add a new action hook called edit form fields where the beginning of the hook is the name
of the taxonomy which will be origin.
The function I want to call it will be named R origin.
Edit foreign fields.
I'm going to define this function inside the origin dash fields file
a couple of things will be different from the new form.
This function will be passed in an object called term that will contain information about the current
term to grab the metadata.
I'm going to create a variable named U.R.L. and its value will be the value returned by the function.
Get term meta the term object has a property named term ideas that will pass in as the first parameter
the next parameter is the name which has more info you are L and the last parameter will be set to true
now.
But I have my you are L I can display the form with it.
I'm going to paste in some HCM L which is a tad different than the function above.
I know it seems weird but the HCM CML tends to be different for both fields.
The edit form field uses tables to format the form.
What's most important is the input field for the value.
I'm echoing out the you are out.
This will take care of the form and saving the data.
I'm going to test this.
Refresh the page and you should see the field appearing.
I want you to create a new origin.
You can paste in any you or l you want.
I'm just going to paste in a U or L to the France Wikipedia page.
You'll now see the term appear to the right.
Click on it and check to see if the edit form is working as well.
You don't have to change any values but if you press update then you should still see everything intact.
The next step is to make the origin appear on the front end along with the more info you are out open
the filter content file.
This is the file that contains the function to modify the output onto the front end.
I'm also going to open the template for this.
I'm going to make one modification to the template I want you to add another list item that has three
place holders for the name.
The actual value itself and many placeholder for the more info you are El inside the filter function.
We will replace the tex holder with origin for the actual value itself.
We're only interested in the first origin itself.
I'm going to create a variable named origin which will contain the value returned by the function.
WP get post terms
this function will get all the terms associated with this post.
The first parameter is the idea of the post.
The second parameter is the taxonomy which is origin
this function will return an array of terms.
I'm going to create another variable named.
More info you are l I'm going to use the ternary operator to assign the value for this variable.
I'm going to check if the first item in the origin array is set.
So we know we have at least one item in The Origin array if there is a value.
I'm going to get the more info you are well metadata using the Get term meta function.
Otherwise I'm going to set this as an empty string
now that we have our values prepared let's display them for the origin itself.
I'm going to use the ternary operator again if the first item in the array is set.
I'm going to output the name of that term each item in the array is an object in the resource section
of this lecture.
I provide a link to the function WP get post terms.
If you scroll down to the return value section you'll find the properties for each object in the array.
One of these is the name which is what we're using here.
However if the first term is indeed empty we're going to use the phrase none
the very last step to all of this is to display the more info you are out.
I'm going to use a conditional statement to check if the more info you real variable is empty.
If it isn't I'm going to replace the place holder with a clickable link.
Otherwise I'm just going to replace it with an empty string let's test this out.
Now I want you to view a recipe without making any changes to it.
You should see the origin list item with none next to it and know you are well appearing after you've
confirmed that you can now edit this recipe.
I want you to assign the origin we created earlier save your changes and view the recipe again.
You should now see the origin appear along with the more info you are.
That wraps it up for this lecture.
We've learned how to make taxonomy and settings for our taxonomy is.