IOS 6 comes with a lot of features we'd like to use.
I'm only going to show you what you'll need right at the start.
There are more features than the ones I'm about to introduce but also use those as the course progresses.
And this lecture we're going to start talking about the changes to variables.
I'm going to be working inside the index file.
Make sure any code inside this file is commented out as you may know variables are created using the
VAR keyword.
I'm going to create a variable named foo and assign it to the string hello then I'm going to log this
variable.
This is pretty basic but it's very difficult to control.
This is a problem with JavaScript.
It's a very relaxed language and it's not strict at all.
You could just turn on strict mode but that only does so much.
Right after we define this variable we can change the value of it to something like the number 5 in
this example.
That's fine and all but it becomes a problem when you're working with larger applications throughout
this course we'll be loaning hundreds of JavaScript variables and you'll find yourself needing more
control than usual.
I'm going to run the command node app slash index you'll see that the number 5 is being outputting.
This is the expected behavior so far.
Even though there are different ways to define variables it's not like those methods are completely
replacing the VAR keyword.
Using the VAR keyword is still completely valid.
Javascript code and it will continue to be supported for many years.
I just wanted you to be aware of that.
All right let's start things off by learning about the concept keyword.
The keyword concept is short for constant constants in JavaScript work the same exact way constants
work in P P.
I assume for the most part you understand what constants are constants allow you to create variables
that never change they can never be changed after being defined.
If you try to change the value of a constant then you'll be given an error and the value would still
stay the same.
Using a constant is fairly easy.
All you have to do is change the keyword from a var to contest that's all you have to do everything
else is still the same.
You can set the constant to any kind of value you want.
It can be a string number array and even an object.
Let's test this out by running node app slash index after running this will get an error.
The error is telling us that you can't change the value of a constant which is what we're doing in our
code.
I'm going to comment out this code and then run the command again
after running it will see no errors.
And the concept is working as expected throughout this course you'll see me using constants a lot actually
if you were to view any tutorials or look at other people's code then you'll notice that constants are
widely adopted.
You'll definitely get a lot of practice using constants and you'll be fairly confident using them by
using constants we assure ourselves that we have more control over how our variables are set.
So far we've only tested this with note using constants on browsers is a different story.
I'm going to run my code through web pack.
You should see a success message.
Let's check out the page.
If you look at the console and you'll see the number of being output add on to the console.
Here's the thing.
Constants on e 6 feature Westpac and Babel help make sure your code is compatible with all browsers
including older ones.
Most modern browsers already support iOS 6 but older browsers don't.
Unfortunately web pack doesn't have a way to force or simulate this behaviour for you so it has no choice
but to convert the console keyword to var so you may be thinking What is the point of using iOS 6 if
it's going to be converted for backwards compatibility.
Well there are two reasons.
The first reason is to be able to write code for the future.
That may seem weird but eventually iOS 6 will be compatible with all browsers 100 percent.
You'll want to prepare for this.
So when the time comes you'll have to make very little changes to your code base.
If you were to continue writing code with early versions of JavaScript you'll find yourself behind the
pack and spent a lot of time updating your code base.
You don't want that.
The second reason is that iOS 6 provides a lot of security and control over your code.
A lot of the tools and libraries you'll be using are written in iOS 6 whether you like it or not.
This kind of forces you to write your code to be iOS 6 ready.
Since you're loading so much code you should take extra precautions.
You only want to allow code that should be able to modify your data if you keep using var.
You'll eventually find yourself in this situation where your code may not behave the way you expect
it to.
There's a lot to be said but I'll leave it at that.
Let's move on to the next way of creating variables along with constants.
You can also create block scope level variables.
That's a big phrase.
Let me break down what that means.
Yes 6 introduces the key words let's let is another way of creating variables.
I'm going to create a variable name to bar and assign its value to 10 using let is as simple as changing
the keyword var to let just like last time.
You can create any kind of variable you want.
You can use left for strings numbers arrays objects etc..
I'm going to Long Beach Bar a variable and then I'm going to run this script through node as expected
will see the number 10 outputting.
I'm going to create a conditional statement this conditional statement will always be true inside this
conditional statement.
I'm going to reassign the bar variable to 5 run the command again.
We should get no errors and as expected we'll see the number 5 instead of 10.
What exactly does Lett do.
Here's where it can come in handy.
I'm going to move my bar variable definition inside my conditional statement like so let's try running
the command one more time and see what we get.
You'll receive an error stating that bar is undefined.
This can seem strange at first but it's not.
Once you understand what's going on let makes it so only code that is on the same level as where it's
defined can change it.
And this example we defined the bar variable inside this block statement only code inside this block
statement can access and change the variable bar once this block statement is finished running then
the bar variable is destroyed.
This means we can't access it outside the block statement like we do in this log function.
Previously everything was working fine when the variable was defined outside the block statement.
That's because the variable was available globally.
This is the power of let variables you can control how far a variable can be controlled in a way.
It adds an extra layer of security.
I'm going to move the bar variable back to the global scope and get rid of this conditional statement.
Lastly I'm going to run it through Westpac.
Let's view the code on the browser again as you can see both variables where output it with no errors.
That's basically it for variables.
This is just the basics of these two keywords.
You'll find that both keywords are used in a lot of design patterns for their benefits.
This course is not really a javascript course.
I know that may seem weird because for the past few lectures we've done nothing but use javascript.
However I'm only introducing you to the fundamentals and basics of JavaScript javascript definitely
has a lot to offer and I encourage you to learn more about it after you finish this course in the next
few lectures will finish things up with Arrow functions and modules.