The last step to completing our block is to render it right now I'm looking at the block we just created.
I filled in all the fields and updated the post.
If I were to view the post on the front end then you'll see it displays just fine something you'll notice
is that the styles are completely different from the styles used in the editor.
In most cases you want this to be consistent.
I'll show you how to load styles for Gutenberg but for now you can ignore this right now.
The problem we face is Gutenberg is unable to render the block again after a page refresh.
What does that mean.
First we'll have to understand how Gutenberg handles our content.
The Gutenberg lifestyle is straightforward but there's a lot that goes into it.
This diagram is grossly oversimplified.
Whenever you're writing content on the Gutenberg editor the edit function is constantly called to update
everything the edit function will always return processed HCM which will then be rendered onto the editor.
Things change when the user clicks on publish or update the save function is called which does something
similar to the edit function it will run any code inside.
In return the process states seem out this time the process H team L is sent to the database I currently
have Heidi opens all posts are saved.
Any WP posts table if you scroll down to the bottom you should find the recipe posts you created just
in case you can't find it.
You can go back to the browser and look at the You of all the post I.D. is set under the post query
here once you have the post I.D. you can switch back to Heidi and look for it under the post content
column.
You will find the content saved as you can see there is no JavaScript or JSA ex.
This is pure HCM.
Right now we only have one block.
These comments prove that fact WordPress will take the time to surround your blocks with comments that
contain the name.
These comments serve a purpose.
I'll explain in just a moment.
But let's look at the front end again.
If you were to view the H team L for the post you'll see the comments no longer appear before content
is displayed.
The Gutenberg comments are removed as they're not necessary.
All right so what is the purpose of these comments later down the road.
You may want to edit a post when you do so.
Gutenberg will load the content from the database.
However here's the problem.
The content is pure HCM l Gutenberg has to take the time to break down your content into blocks again
the comments assist with that by telling Gutenberg which pieces of each team l belong to which block
and this example Gutenberg will be able to understand that this H.G. email here belongs to the recipe
block.
Simple enough so far.
Here's where the complication begins.
Gutenberg doesn't know which piece of text belongs to which attribute.
It's obvious to us that this piece of text is for ingredients and this other piece of text is for cooking
time.
However Gutenberg doesn't know that
for the most part Gutenberg doesn't care what the HDL looks like.
It's looking for the attribute data.
To recap it loads the H2 CML from the database it will then convert the h t amount in two blocks it
will then look for the attributes once a Grams the attributes.
It will then use those values in store for the block.
The edit function will then be triggered so that it can render the H2 UML on the Ed itself.
If it's unable to find certain attributes then it'll assume the content was changed outside of its scope.
The question now is how do we get Gutenberg to identify which piece of text belongs to which attribute
before I answer that I want to note that I commented out the update ingredients function and place the
function back inside the text component.
All right let's move on.
I'm going to minimize the edit function so that it doesn't get in our way.
Then I'm going to scroll up to the attributes object each attribute can have a type.
Add this property to the ingredients attribute that type determines the data type of the content if
the attribute stores a number.
Then you can set this to integer a string is used for text and you can even use array for multiple pieces
of content.
We'll be using string.
The question is what's the difference between type and source.
The type is for setting the data type the source is used to instruct Gutenberg.
What exactly it should extract from the GM mail that comes from the database.
More on this in just a moment.
The next property will need to set is the selector property.
This will instruct Gutenberg where the data can be found inside the GM L..
I'm going to set this to dot ingredients dash p h here's how Gutenberg will interpret this.
We're channeling Gutenberg.
Hey I have an attribute called ingredients.
If you're loading the data from the H GM L. then you will be able to find the data inside a tag with
the class ingredients stash P H I want you to extract the text inside and store the value as a string.
It will do this for each attribute once all the attributes have been accounted for it will then run
the edit function and render the content onto the editor itself.
Something I want to know is that the type property is optional here.
It's only required if you're working with metadata but we're not using metadata so it doesn't really
matter here.
I like to set it just in case.
I recommend you set it to another thing I want to note is that the value we passed in for the selector
doesn't exist.
We'll be adding it soon enough.
For now I want you should do this for the rest of the attributes
all of them will have a type of string the selector will be their names followed by Dash P H P H being
short for placeholder WordPress now knows where to look for the data however it can't look for the attributes
since we're not rendering the CML as we're specifying here.
We'll need to update both the edit and save functions for this.
We'll start with the edit function.
All you need to do is surround the attributes with some span tags with their respective class names
like so
to save some time.
You can just copy this and paste it into the save function.
Be sure to remove the class name attribute from the root element as WordPress takes care of adding it
for you.
That should do it open your command line and C D into the blocks directory then run the command NPM
run Dev.
You shouldn't receive any errors thus far.
Go back to the Gutenberg editor remove the block we have and save it.
We have to do this since we want to remove the copy stored in the database then refresh the page so
that we can load it in the latest code for our block.
Lastly add the block in again and add some settings.
Once you have that set save your post
if we did everything right then we should be able to view the post without a problem.
You should see what I see.
If I were to inspect the element then you'll see it has all the correct classes and formatting just
to double check open Heidi and view the contents of the post.
It should be the exact same HCM L with the comments added in.
Lastly go ahead and refresh the editor itself.
The block should be displaying just fine with the data saved.
Congratulations you just created your first blog.
It took a long time to get to this point but it was well worth it.
Here is our trusty process chart.
We've prepared the environment include the files registered the block created the settings and render
the block.
You will want to make sure that the block renders perfectly on both the front and back end.
I've added an extra step here which is optimize and enhance in the next few lectures we'll take a look
at how we can improve the user experience by styling the block and adding additional settings when you're
ready.
I'll see you in the next lecture.