To create an elastic container registry,
you'll need to run the aws ecr create command and provide a repository name.
Next,
run aws ecr get-login with the region of the ECR
repository you want to log into, and the --no-include-email flag.
The output of this command will be a Docker login command that
you can then run to log into the repository.
When you create your ECR repository, make note of the repository URI.
You're going to need this when you build and push the Docker images.
Next, run aws ecr get-login with the region and the --no-include-email flag.
This will output a Docker login command that you can then copy and run.
You should see a Login Succeeded message.
Note also that you can manage your Docker credentials
however you need to on your system.
In order to push an image to the Amazon Elastic Container Registry,
it must follow a certain format.
RegistryId is the id of the registry you created
where you want to manage the image.
The host will include the region where the repository is located.
Dkr.ecr and amazonaws.com are constant.
Image-name and tag are whatever you want them to be for your image.
For example, docker build -t, image id, .dkr .ecr.
region, .amazonaws .com /demo: 1.0 space dot,
indicating that the Docker file to build is in the current directory.
You can also use the docker tag command on an existing
image following the same format.
Once you've logged into the repository, you can simply push the image.
For example, docker push, then the full image name.
I'm in the directory with the demo app files and the Docker file.
Let's go ahead and build an image for the 1.0 version of the demo app.
Once it's built, we can see the Docker image.
Next,
run a docker push to push the 1.0 version up to the ECR
repository that we created earlier.
To create a cluster,
you'll run the eksctl create cluster command with two or three parameters.
--Name is the name of the cluster,
--region is which region you want the cluster to be created in.
You may need to specify a list of availability zones with the
--zones flag if you get an unsupported availability zone
exception creating your cluster, otherwise it is optional.
When you put it all together, it will look something like this,
eksctl create cluster --name, cluster name,
--region, cluster region, --zones,
and a common delimited list of availability zones.
Let's run the eksctl create cluster command.
This may take a few minutes, but in the end,
you should see the message that your cluster is ready.
At this point we just have a Kubernetes cluster; we
don't have any apps deployed to it yet.
We'll use kubectl to create a deployment named demo app
using the image we pushed earlier, identified by the full name that we pushed.
For example, kubectl create deployment, deployment name,
--image=, then the image that was pushed to the repository.
Once the app is running,
we'll need a load balancer service to map the ports and
allow us to hit the app externally.
This is also accomplished with kubectl.
Kubectl expose deployment, deployment name,
--type=LoadBalancer --port 5000 --target-port 5000.
In this case, the app is running on port 5000 so we just kept that mapping.
We'll run kubectl get nodes to verify that we're connected to our cluster.
Notice that we haven't deployed any application pods yet.
Run kubectl create deployment to deploy the 1.0 version of our demo app,
and the pod is up and running.
Let's expose the deployment so we can hit it and see what it looks like.
Run kubectl get service to get the external IP.
Note that AWS uses an elb URL for the external IP.
If we hit in a browser, we can see the message from our demo app that it is working as expected.