When you're trying to decide which cloud provider to use for Managed Kubernetes,
a good place to start is,
are you already using a cloud provider for something else?
It may make sense to leverage and expand your existing
skills for a particular cloud provider.
Next,
is there some unique requirement that a particular cloud
provider can fulfill better than others?
For example, geographic locations of clusters,
high availability configuration options,
specialized node types and storage options.
In some cases,
you may have performance requirements that will work
better on one cloud provider than another.
The nice thing is that you can easily set up a cluster with your
application on multiple cloud providers to evaluate your
requirements and determine the best fit.
Another important item to evaluate is ease of use.
For a given cloud provider,
how easy is it for you to perform common tasks such as create a cluster,
configure kubectl, manage node pools, push and update images,
monitor your resources, and delete a cluster.
Ideally you should be scripting these actions so they are repeatable for
different environments of your application such as dev,
test, and production.
The command line interface or CLI of each cloud provider can simply your scripts
so be sure to consider the features available in each CLI.
In this course we'll mainly be using the CLI of each cloud provider
in our demos so you can get a feel for each one.
For each cloud provider, we're going to walk through a similar workflow sequence.
First, we'll create an account, set up the CLI,
create a Kubernetes cluster, and configure kubectl.
Next, we'll push an image to a cloud registry,
create a deployment from the registry image,
scale pods and nodes, and update the application with a new image.
Finally,
we'll take a look at the web console and how you can
access the container registry, cluster, and node pools,
monitoring metrics, and billing details.
At the end of each module,
you'll also see how to delete the cluster and clean up any
additional resources that were allocated.
We've covered what running in the cloud looks like,
as well as what questions you can ask to evaluate different cloud options.
Now you're ready to see it in action.
Join me in the next modules to see an end-to-end demo of
Microsoft Azure Kubernetes Service, AKS; Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service,
EKS; and Google Kubernetes Engine, GKE.
Even if you have a preference already,
I encourage you to check out all three so that you have a
better idea of what it's like to set up, deploy, update, and delete a cluster in each cloud provider.