When you're ready to scale the number of pods in your deployment,
you'll use the kubectl scale deployment command.
For example, kubectl scale deployment, deployment name,
--replicas=, then the desired number of replicas; in this case 3.
To scale the number of nodes you'll use the az aks scale command,
passing in the name of the resource group,
the name of the cluster, and the desired number of nodes,
in this case, 5.
Your node pool will then scale up or down to match
the requested number of nodes.
Right now there's only one pod.
Let's scale that up to three pods.
We can check the status with kubectl get pods and
eventually see all three pods running.
The original one that's been up for a few minutes and the new
ones that have been up for a few seconds.
If I hit the app in a loop,
notice that two of the responses have started over at 1,
this would be the new pods; then the existing pod picked it up at 6.
Again, in our simple app,
the counter is unique to each pod and starts over
at 1 when the app is restarted.
Let's take a look at our nodes.
We have three nodes.
Let's say I wanted to scale it down to one node.
We'll run the az aks scale command, then when it's finished,
we should see the succeeded message.
If we run get nodes again, we can see that only one node is in the ready state.
If we look at the pods, we can see that one has been running for a while,
probably the one that was on this node to begin with,
then two other pods have been started on this single
node to maintain our replica set of 3.
We can hit the app again to see that two of the pods are indeed new pods,
while a third has already been running for a while,
because the counter started at 8.
Let's scale it back up to three nodes.
Again, these commands may take a while when you run them,
but here we'll just cut to the success.
Now we can see that all three nodes are ready,
but the pods appear to be the same.
If we hit the pods, we could see that none of the counters restarted.
We can look into this a little bit further and see that all
three pods are still on a single node.
Depending on the implementation of your cloud
provider and what the defaults are,
it may not automatically rebalance pods across all of your nodes.
To update the application you'll need to build and tag a new Docker image,
then push it to the repository.
In this example, we create a new image for demo with a 2.0 tag, then push it.
Once the image is in the repository,
you can use kubectl to set the demo image for the existing
demo app deployment to the new 2.0 image.
Kubernetes will then automatically spin up new pods with the new image.
Let's update the application to say Goodbye instead of Hello.
On this workstation, we still just have the 1.0 version of this image.
We could go ahead and run docker build on our workstation and tag a 2.0 version,
then push it to the registry,
but there's also an option to initiate a remote build on a cloud agent so I'm
going to show you that for the 2.0 version of this app.
If your machine has an OS that does not currently support Docker,
this feature could be an alternative to spinning up a
VM just to build Docker images.
The command is az acr build, then the namespace,
image name, and tag for the image you'd like to build,
the registry where the image needs to be pushed upon successful build,
the name of the Docker file,
then the directory that contains all the source code and
other information needed to build the image.
First it will pack all of the source files into a tar,
then upload them to the cloud.
Once a cloud agent becomes available,
it will download that source code and execute the Docker build.
We can see all the output like we would have if we
had built it on our own machine.
Now we can see the push of the new image to our cloud repository.
Once that's complete, we get a message that it was successful.
Again, all of this happened on cloud machines.
I don't have the 2.0 version on this workstation,
but it is in our cloud repository.
Let's run kubectl set image for the 2.0 version of the application.
Once the deployment is updated,
we can check the progress of the pods to see the 2.0 versions getting
created and the 1.0 versions getting terminated.
After about a minute, we have all three pods running with the 2.0 version.
Notice how the three pods are distributed across
only two nodes in the node pool.
If you have specific affinity or distribution requirements,
it's important to understand the default behavior of each cloud provider and
where you might need to be more specific with your deployment.
Let's hit our cluster again and now we can see the Goodbye message and that all three pods are indeed new and have started over at 1.