Welcome to this course.
It's amazing to have you on board as a student now in this course.
You will learn all about the merge stack.
You will learn how to build amazing full stack web applications with longer TB express reactions yes
and no chance and you will learn all of that not just in theory but actually applied in practice to
a real course project which we will build from scratch a project that shows you how these pieces work
together and which will all include important topics like file upload and user authentication so that
by the end of the course you will be able to build your own full stack.
Web applications with these technologies.
Now that's the course.
But who am I.
My name is Max and I will be one of your instructors in this course.
I will be responsible for the parts about react note expressing how we combine all these things including
authentication.
But in this course I'm joined by manual among Would you be expert who will be your instructor and guide
in the database related sections.
Hi EMMANUEL I'm a data scientist and Mongo TB expert.
Now you know what this course is all about.
But what are your course requirements.
What do you have to bring to the table to succeed in this course.
In this course you will learn how to connect node express Hmong would you be and react and the connection
is the core focus of this course.
Therefore this course does not dive deeply into each of these technologies.
The course comes with refreshers on react.
Hmong would be a note but the refreshers are well refreshers.
If you really want to dive deep in her make sure to check out dedicated courses on these topics but
for discourse basic react Chase.
Knowledge is highly recommended and also basic knowledge of no chase helps a lot to succeed here.
These are the core requirements of this course.
And with that it's now time to dive into the course.