Welcome to this optional module in this module we will refresh our knowledge on mongo TB and Mongoose.
So if you have some prior experience on these technologies you might want to skip this module.
But in case you're totally new to Hmong would you be in Mongoose or if you want to refresh your knowledge.
This module contains all the required information.
The monkey is a database and we can connect Mongo TB to our backend.
In our case the node expressed back and and stored information in this database mongoose will help us
to easily manage the connection between the backend and the database will dive into that of course for
all.
Module.
Now what's in this module now.
Well in this module we learned what Mongo DB is.
We'll set up a so-called with TB cluster the Hmong would be server in the end and we'll set up a simple
node and express AB and see how we can then interact between our backend and this Hmong would you be
database.
But then if I look at Mongoose and will understand what Mongoose models are these models help us to
define a structure for information stored in the Hmong TB database.
This is what we will dive into here.
And finally we will see how we can create and access documents stored in our database with mongoose.
That's what's inside this module.
So let's get started.