So we got a basic idea of how the Mertens stack works and how did different pieces work together.
As I mentioned throughout this course you will not only get refreshers about the individual building
blocks but most importantly will build an entire application where you can see all these pieces build
out individually and then come together when we connect all the different blocks with each other.
Now this project which we're going to build is a project we of course have to plan before we dive into
it.
So in this module I want to plan a reactive work specifically the entire merged project with you because
this hopefully also helps you approach your next project and get an idea of what you might want to keep
in mind what you have to think about before you get started and how you can create a plan for the thing
you're trying to build.
Now for that there are a couple of general planning steps for which will walk in this module so that
by the end of the module we have a clear plan of what we want to build and how we want to build it.
The first step for that of course is that you need an idea you want to solve some problem that off nor
typically will not be a step you have to think about and specifically dive into.
Because more often than not you will have an idea and then you want to start planning an app that solves
the problem or that works on that idea.
So this is only a rough first step which typically can already be checked off the list by the time we
were getting started.
So the next step the real first step after you have an idea you want to solve a problem is that you
create a sign you sketch out the application you want to build at least this is what I like to do.
If I'm building a front end and that by the way is really important the steps I'm giving you here are
not the objectively correct steps you have to go through whatever you're trying to build.
These are the steps that work for me for you.
Do you order might be different.
Maybe you have some other step maybe you don't need a specific step.
I'm just sharing my personal approach here with you.
So I got an idea and now I want to create a design I want to sketch out the application.
Now when I talk about creating the design year you could really work with the signed tools like frame
or X or a Sketch app or Photoshop and build your design there.
Now I'm not a designer and this is not a design course.
So we're not going to do that here often.
This is all a task you will probably outsource because chances are you want to focus on writing the
code and you also are not a designer.
Hence here in this module we'll just draw the general skeleton will sketch out the application will
not really set up a specific design for this application here.
Of course we want to make sure it looks nice but that's something we'll do when we implemented I already
prepared some nice styles and colors for you there.
So once we get the general skeleton we sketched out the general front end of this application.
We of course also have to think about the data we work with both in the front end but also more importantly
on the back end of our application.
So we want to plan our data models the data we or our app will work with which entities do we need and
which data do we need to send across the wire from front to back end and then all the from node expressed
to the database does of course is a crucial part because that is a part that will affect all building
blocks of your merged application.
Now once the data model is clear and we got our front and sketched out we of course have to plan our
back and end points and the page yes you could put that into quotes because we don't really have more
than one page but the different components you could say you want to have on the front and in your single
page application These are the steps I want to go through together with you we'll do it here in this
module.
And this is my rough planning process I go through whenever I approach a new project.
Now obviously you can do way more work on all these steps.
You can always come up with a complete to sign on your own.
But as I mentioned since this course is not primarily about the signing and so on I want to keep this
module short and just give you a general idea of how this works.