Creating the code for the users is pretty straightforward actually because as for the places we again
need a schema.
So what we build right here in our place chairs file there.
We predefined a structure of a document so of data a new user sign up has to contain.
Then we will export the schema and use it here in our users controllers.
So that's actually what we want to do right here.
So with that let's get started with the schema first and to do this we again go to our models folder.
Now create a new file.
This time a user j s file.
And now we can again follow the logic long before we first have to import Mongoose here.
So we require Mongoose and what else we have to import while we need our schema constant here with Mongoose
dot schema to be able to create the schema.
As I said Now we want to create a user schema therefore naming our a constant user schema makes sense
I guess.
We again will instantiate the new javascript object here and this object now contains all the properties
our new user needs.
So what properties are these.
Well the first property obviously is the user name.
As for the places before we will again use an object here and the name should be of type String and
it should also be required so required should be set to true.
We can actually copy this because our second property D email will kind of have the same information
but I want to add one additional property here because our EMA will be an information which we carry
a lot for example then we do to use a log in while we need to query the user email in our database.
Now although the database in this project in discourse will not be very big if you have a really big
database which is typically the case if you store user data then you want to make sure that your email
is curated as fast as possible and for that you can simply add you need right here.
If you said you need to true this would just create an index for the email which in simple words simply
speeds up the querying process if you request the email.
Therefore we add this property at this point.
Another property we need is our password of course for the user.
So the user has to add a password.
The password should also be a string here and it should be required and we could add one additional
property the main length property.
This simply validates the minimum length so the minimum amount of characters our password should have
in our case will stick to six characters here.
That's optional though but I guess it makes sense here to at least make sure the user adds a minimum
length for the password.
He uses the next property is our image.
We had this before in our places.
This is again a string and required set to true.
Again we're talking about a year earlier.
So that's basically the same logic we had before for the places we don't store any files in our database.
The last property we have to add for our user schema is the place property your places plural because
one user can have multiple places but one place can only be allocated to one single user.
You remember what we talked about in the last lecture.
And places will be dynamic later so we will store the ideas of the places allocated to a user right
here for the moment.
I'll just use a string And set required to true.
This means we will add the place manually but that's just step one.
Later in this module when we add the relation between places and users.
This will of course be a more dynamic approach but we collect the idea from the corresponding place
a user created.
With that we are almost done with our schema and we could already create and export our model.
But there is one thing missing here because unique appear.
As I said only creates an internal index in the database to make it easier and faster to query our emails.
What is missing though at the moment is an internal validation.
Whether the email that we want to create right here exists already.
This is not done by unique.
For that we have to use a third party package.
The Mongoose unique validator and to use it we first have to install it with npm install dash dash save
Mongoose unique validator
with that it's installed and now we can use it by creating a new constant name Unique validator.
And now we require the Mongoose unique validator right here with that we can use this for a party package
to make sure we have a unique email here and to add it to our schema.
We simply added to the schema via a plug in method here.
So we add unique validator like this.
With that we made sure that we can query our email as fast as possible in our database with unique.
And we made sure that we can only create a new user if the EMA doesn't exist already with our unique
validator package here.
Now we can create and export our model.
We know the syntax already it's module exports and this should be Mongoose start model method.
And here we have to give our model a name as a set for the place already.
This should be in a singular form and with an upper capital starting character.
So in our case the naming the model user makes a lot of sense as remember this would also define the
name of oral collection.
So the collection will be called users without the capital you and we want to export our user schema
here safe does now.
And with that we finished the creation of the schema and the model very important though we still don't
have any connection between users and places.
I want to repeat that because this will come later but if we look at both topics separately we have
not a place a schema and the user schema therefore let us not use our user model.