Now last but not least I want to make sure that when we delete a place which I'll not to hear about
in a second that we also clean up the file that belongs to the place.
And at the moment we're not doing this.
If we have a look at our places controller in the lead place we of course get rid of the place.
We of course get rid of the connection to our user but we're not getting rid of the image that belongs
to the place.
Now we don't necessarily have to.
We could also write a script which cleans up every month or we do a manual cleanup or we want to keep
all the images because we're using them for us machine learning algorithms or anything like that anyways.
But if you do want to clean up it's not too hard to do.
Before we get rid of our place here I'll get the image path here.
Out of the place in the place document we can simply access this image key right.
Because that is where we do store our image path.
So we get access to this image path.
Then I delete everything in a database which is the important thing because if deleting the image should
fail for whatever reason it's not that bad it's ok we can do a manual cleanup.
So after all this database cleanup I want to delete the place.
Now for that I will again import the file system package no dress offers because this gives us this
unlink method.
And with this imported at the end here at the end of delete place we can call FS unlink and use our
image path here which I extracted from the document up there.
So now this is what I wanted to lead on link takes a second argument a callback function which might
hold an error if things go wrong here I will just log it to the console.
You could do more with it.
I certainly don't want to wait for this to complete.
Though we could send the response in here to wait for this to complete.
But I don't care.
This deletion process is started and as I said if it should fail for whatever reason or something like
that it's not the end of the world.
So if this added If we now save this and we go here to the front end and I click delete and confirm
this it deletes it here does looks good.
We got no error here.
And now if we go back to the back and we see only one image and that's our user image the place image
indeed is gone.
If we quickly have a look at Atlas we should also see that there to places collection is empty and if
we have a look at our users we got the user but the place Key was deleted from its places array.
So this is now the cleanup finished and this ensures that when we delete something when we delete the
place we also delete the image that belongs to the place.