Let's now use our model and ask for the places where we started with creating a new place so we've creating
a document.
We have to follow the same approach right here.
So first we just have to look at the create process creating a new document meaning we should have a
look at the user sign up here.
So to create a new user for that we go through users controller and now first import our newly created
user model right here.
So we use a new constant named user which is equal to our path.
So this is dot dot slash models slash user.
Now we can use the user model and we'll work on get users later.
But here our sign up constant this is where we have to change some code now.
The first code block.
So this part right here is OK we'll come back to that later though because we have to adjust a little
thing but this is not important at the moment.
But here our has user content that created user and how we add to the user.
These are the areas we have to change now.
Let's start with this.
Has user constant here.
Here we have some kind of dummy validation all ready to check whether a user email exists already.
We have our newly created user model.
This whole logic does not apply anymore.
So let's change it here.
But one important note as I said before we have a validation already in here with our unique validator
package.
The little issue about this package is that we get a default validation.
This means we get an error message in case the e-mail exists already but it might be a very technical
error message.
So to make sure we have a nice user experience we should add a manual validation logic right here.
This means we will get rid of this code right here and now let's say this is our existing user and this
should be equal to user so I'll use a model dot.
Now how can we check whether an email exists already.
Well we've defined one method here.
Find one simply finds one document matching the criteria in the argument of our method and what would
be the criteria in our case.
Well it would be the user email.
So with that we can easily check if the e-mail of the user exists already.
So as we've save or find as we had it before this right here is again what.
Well an asynchronous task and therefore we of course should wrap this in our tri catch code block like
this.
And this also means we cannot use a constant right here due to block scoping.
So we add let existing user right here and get rid of the constant additionally we have to add async
appear and a wait ahead of our user.
So this was step one.
Now we check whether an e-mail exists already.
If checking this doesn't work.
So not if we find that e-mail.
But just if this find one method does not work as intended then we want to catch any potential errors
and store it in a constant
new HDP error.
We did this a lot of time already.
As I said we could refactor the code a bit but for demonstration purposes I rewrite this code again
and we could say that signing up failed.
Please try again later.
Of an error code of 500.
And we also have to return next error.
So let's not say we find a user or already so the user exists.
Well then if existing users if this is true in the end then I want to create another error HP error
here and I want to return user exists already please log in instead.
And the error code he will be for 2 2 and we want to return next error to stop the code execution one
side note here.
You can argue whether you want to expose the information right here so that the user exists already.
You can also be more cryptic here and say log in failed I think for a better user experience at this
point.
We should give the user information that the user is existing already.
Let us now finally say we don't have an existing user.
So creating a new user is possible.
Well then we are at this code block and again as we did it for our places just to remind you.
Down here in the places we now have to make sure that we add all the properties we created in our user
j s file so name email password image and places.
Let's do this by maybe getting rid even of these and creating it again from scratch.
So let's not say that our created user should be a new instance of this class of our user model in the
end.
And this should be the name which the user enters the email the user enters and an image.
Again the image should not be a file but the you are L to a file.
I got a link to a file from the web here.
Again for demonstration purposes it's exactly the same process that we followed when we used our place
this model.
So we have this dummy image.
Then the user password right here this is a user input.
Another very important side note here we will save the plane user password at this stage of the course
but very important.
This is not the way to go here at this point.
We don't care but later in the off indication module of this course will of course encrypt the passwords
here because storing did not encrypted password is of course a serious security issue.
So don't do it this way.
This is just the right approach at this stage of the project.
And finally we add our places as I said places will be a dummy value for the moment such as what the
user adds as the place idea once the relation was set up.
This will be a lot more dynamic.
With that we can create the new user actually.
What is missing though is how can we now save the user for data.
Again delete the dummy user's code here and well for saving the data.
What do we use well we use again the safe method.
If we go to the places controller than here that's actually exactly the code we need right here.
And this time I will actually copy paste the code to speed things up a bit at this stage like this.
So we await not decreed.
Please but created user at this stage and we catch an error.
And if this fails we will simply say not creating plays but maybe signing up failed.
Please try again later error code five hundred.
So that's the same logic that before and here of our response will again also use a well known approach.
So we will convert our Mongoose object created user to a default javascript object and will also set
getters to true.
What's the reason for that.
Well it removes the idea so the underscore in front of the property to make it easier to access the
later idea.
Very important here.
What you get back as a response also includes the password.
As I said this is all done with what you would typically do.
It's just here for demonstration purposes.
At this stage of the project and here you can actually make small you the capital you so let us know
restart our development server and go back to postman create a new post request here again HDP locals
5000 slash API slash users this time not places and now slash signed up to create a new user here.
Now we need a body of Jason data once again.
And here we have to add all the properties we added in our model.
So first we need a name which could be menu my name here.
An email test at test dot com.
We don't need an image we provided that in the code.
So we need to add password here.
Maybe test should be a string and we add the places asset before with dummy input here.
We'll change it later when we create the relation.
So if I know its end and as we can see we have a problem but we actually have two problems.
First our request doesn't work.
And second we don't have an error message.
So let's first check the problem of the error message here Yeah I got it.
Yep that's the problem we are using fro here but we are now in an asynchronous task so this doesn't
work.
We have to use return next year to avoid this error.
So let's put this in here.
Now this should at least work and we should also correct this for all our other cases where we have
for all as part of an asynchronous task for example here in our place as controller I think we got the
same problem down here for update place here.
We should also use return next to ops like this.
So with that we also corrected this problem here.
Don't think we have any other fro errors so if you know go back to postmen and send the request we at
least get an error message that we passed invalid inputs.
And the reason for that message now is well our password you remember here in our user model and we
said that the password should have a minimum length of six well and our current password doesn't fulfill
these requirements as we only have four characters in our password.
So if we add two or three characters let's say should be testers and it sent once again then we are
again in another loop.
So that's the first problem we have.
But what's this problem.
Well as we're using our dummy property for the places here.
So this one in our schema and also here in our model we of course also have two added right here to
our a constant.
So if we add places right here safeties go back to postmen and hit send.
You can see we've finally created our new user.
We have the idea with our guidance logic.
We got the name the EMA and all our results.
Again we get back the password here.
That's not the final implementation we will have.
But if we have a look at Mongo TB we should see that we have our places database and in the user's collection
we can find our newly created user so that we can now create a new user.
So to sign up is done.
Now it's time to log in our user.