So let's ensure that only authorized users can delete a place.
Now here we again extract our place and we populate the creator.
That's important.
Creator is now not just an idea here as it is here in update place where I just find the place and I
don't populate creator instead with populate creator the creator field holds the full User object that's
important to keep in mind here though still here we find a place and if we don't find a place we throw
an error but if we did find a place I want to check if the place was really created by the user who
sent the request.
So here we can check if place start create or dot I.D. And again keep in mind that creator here is the
full User object which is why I access idols like this here.
If that is not equal to request user data dot user I.D. so a similar check as we have it up here in
the update place route no important here you don't need to call to string the cost Costas I.D. gather
here already gives us the I.D. as a string and effort a check should be good like this.
If we have a problem here we can basically use the same error we used up there.
So Copy that down and return this error where we say you are not allowed to delete this place in this
case here.
So now if we save this let's give it a quick try.
Let's try to delete a place by here switching patch to delete and postman the U R L is right and the
headers are right now if I sent this I get you are not allowed to delete this place on the other hand
on the front end with the right user year if I click delete and I confirm this it should succeed and
it does so this year is now working we got authorization added now as a last step as a little bonus
actually I'll fix some status codes thus far I always used 401.
And to be honest in the end it's up to you what you use here it's not that strict but if you want to
be very correct here then four hundred and one means an authorized which means your you might be authenticated
but you're still not allowed to do this operation to perform this operation we have four hundred and
free which means this is forbidden in general which you could translate with your not authenticated.
So here I want to search for my 401 cases and check if they are all correct.
So this is my user a d comparison and this is.
So here they are correct in the user's controller on the other hand if I have 401.
Then here we have invalid credentials so 403 makes more sense there and then check off it's the same
if we fail because we have no valid token I would say it's rather a 403 error but ultimately it's up
to you and it's not the end of the world if you use four hundred and one instead of four hundred and
free or wise whereas.
The important thing is that we have this logic added here.