To serve everything from one server we need to work on our node application.
We need to deploy this onto a host which is capable of executing our notorious code.
For example Morocco.
But that's the new thing.
We now don't just need to render our rude stare but in a dish.
Now we also need routes that serve our ReACT files so these single page application we get there in
the end.
And that is new.
It isn't too difficult though.
What we need to do in the end is we need to grab our built applications so we still run NPM run build
here on the react side.
We can do that right now to apply our latest style changes.
So we still need to run NPM run build here but then we will grab our build folder and copied over into
the back and folder though before we do that let's double think about our production environment variables
in react the back and you are L now will be a different one.
Or to be precise it will be the one where our node application will be served on later.
Now in my case this is correct here.
This is the you are L under which I will still serve my node application later.
But if you know one is served as on a new he Roku project or on a different node hosting provider then
you need to ensure that you find out which you are L you will have after you deployed your node app
and enter dis here.
So in my case it should be fine though so let's now grab the build folder and go back to the back and
folder and there may be at a public folder and copy everything that's in the build folder so we'll actually
grab the content of the build folder into this public folder here.
The name is up to you but public is the more common name you would choose for that.
Now we want to ensure that everything in the public folder is statically served and we did something
similar already in app trials with our images so in the end we can copy this line here.
And added after and that's not really important added after our roots here.
It also means that dissimilar where here where we handle unknown requests is no longer needed because
now I want to say any request going to any you are l will be served statically so you're I remove that
filter at the beginning and I want to serve my public folder here just like this.
So what I'm saying here is any request which reaches my back end which was not handled by these routes
and I need to do this first so that my API still works but any requested was not handled by these routes
will now be handled by this route and this road will simply return to content in the public folder.
So for example the index H Timo file.
Now if we rethink this solution however it doesn't look that great anymore.
Indeed we would serve everything in that folder statically and that generally is something we want to
do because we want to ensure that for example any javascript file and any see us as file that is requested
from our ReACT app can be served but that's now the problem.
This alone is not enough.
We can move this back up there actually to our other static serving solution here so that we simply
registered as as another static path or we basically say if you're requesting something which does not
start with uploads images we'll see if we find a file here and we will serve it what does unfortunately
you won't do is it will support our front end routes if we are on our running react app and we go to
slash off there.
So in the front and now then the request which gets sent to express is actually that we're looking for
a off folder and by default for index H html file in there.
And of course we have no of folder here in the public folder.
So this works for the initial index H demo file and it works for all the JavaScript files and all the
C is as follows so for all the assets we need here.
But this does not work for our different routes to make dad work.
I will now go to that place after my other routes and use a new one where I want to catch all on handled
requests because here I now want to set up a middleware function with request response and the next
of course where I will always return the index H terminal file.
So in here the idea is simply is that I call rest send file and that's a method provided by express
where I sent back a response that is basically made up of one file in there I always for any unknown
wrote one sent back the index H Tim l file so that the front and routing the react router can take over
and resolve the unknown you are L so here I want to send that file and we can build a path for that
with path resolve where the first argument is dir name.
So that constant which is available in node and expressed it gives us the current folder of this app
guess file and then we want to go into the public folder of course and in data serve de index H table
file.
That's my idea here.
This file should be served with Dad we should have a setup where we can request any route and even if
it's a back and route and these rules kick in or it's a static file like a javascript file then these
routing or these handlers help us or it is anything else and in this case we always sent back our single
page and we can also test as here we can start up our local server and for that just make sure that
in packaged our Jason you also add a script like this.
Def script which I edit here that allows us to still run this with Node 1.
So add such a script because starting this with node would not work because that wouldn't take d environment
variables into account and for local development I want to use them so let's use death which uses Node
1 and then run NPM run def to start this node server locally and let's see where that works and locally
we are using port five thousand.
We can ignore the fact that this image is missing we'll take care about this later.
But what we can tell is that this works and if I reload on the off page this also is getting served
and if I try setting a request here.
So our API should be hit does all the works and we can see in the network tab that indeed we send the
request there.
We got back our places here for example so we are interacting with the API so this is working but in
addition to that serving you react reactive through that very same node express app that hosts our back
and API is also working now.
Also remember what I said early on in the slide when you were serving both from the same host.
You can also omit these cores headers so I will comment out this middleware.
You can leave it here.
It's not a problem but you can also get rid of it.
We don't need it anymore.
If I commented out and I reload here you will see this still works if I tried to log in again.
This still works without any errors besides the image which it doesn't find to which I will come back
later.
So this works and this is now the app prepared for hosting with combined apps where we have no ID Express
and react in the same project.
So with that we should also be able to deploy this node JSA application so whenever we have a new version
of the react that we just build it and then we copy the content of the build folder into the public
folder and replace everything in it with it.
And once we got that replaced we deploy our reactor up here.
So how does this work.
Well we use get ad again where we can say added new react app front end whereas in whatever you want
to name it
and then we use get push you Roku monster again to push this updated node application to Hiroko and
this is basically the same application as before but it now includes our ReACT application and the logic
to serve it.
So let's wait for this process to finish now.
Enter after let's visit this you are El again and if we entered like this we should see our application.
Now you will notice that the image of the user is missing though and it was there a second ago.
Now we'll come back to why Data's missing in a second but let's first of all try authentication and
so on if dad works.
This seems to work.
Let's all try creating a new place.
Like we did many times before let's look at place here and this really all seems to work.
So why are we not seeing the user's image here.
Because in general the deployment seems to be all right and that's the important thing I'll come back
to that image thing here in the next lecture.
But first of all let me make it really clear that this is now our app.
Both the reactive and the note API served on one machine on one server on one service provider.
He Roko in my case here.
So we got everything on one server and this therefore is the other option of deploying this you can
use to hosting providers like firebase or any other static host for react and then no chance hosting
provider for the back end for the node rest api or you use one combined setup.
It's up to you which one you prefer splitting it onto two servers can give you a certain performance
advantages because requests are split up and not all requests hit the same server but depending on the
size of your app that also might not really matter.
And then you might find it easier to just host everything on one host.
Ultimately it's up to you.
I just wanted to show you both alternatives and now let's find out why this image is missing.