WE'RE DONE WITH THE PLACES WITH THE RIGHT orange roots here.
We haven't even touched the user roots so time to change that and as always it's all the great practice
for a you register all these user routes make sure that you can get there from inside your root app
J.S. file and simply add some dummy logic sent back some dummy response in all these routes and they're
mapped respective middleware.
Now of course after a short pause but you have to pass the video to try it on your own will then do
it together.
So where are you successful.
Let's go to users roots chess and let's make sure we set up a routing there for that we can actually
copy the code from places routes and move it in there so that we import and set up the router.
But of course here we will need the user's controller which we require from the users dash controllers
file and the controllers folder and we'll have different routes.
We will have a get route to slash nothing.
And that's all what we plan on the slide earlier.
And there we will probably have some middleware function which we haven't created yet.
So we'll leave it as empty for the moment will not have a second get root but we'll have two more post
routes one post route which should be slash sign up which will later be triggered when a user sends
his sign up data and one is post log in when a user does not sign up.
Which means create a new user but instead tries to log in on an existing user.
These are our roots.
Now we need to middleware is for that the middleware functions for dead.
So here in the user's controller I'll add a new middleware function here which I'll name get users and
that's a normal function request responds next and looks like this.
Then I have to sign up a function request response next and I have to log in.
Function request response next.
Like this.
Now all three functions need to be exported to solve use stat multiple things.
Export I showed you earlier with exports dropped.
Get users exports stopped.
Sign up pointing at the sign up function and exports dot log in pointing at the log in function.
Now all these things are exported from the controller and back into users routes.
We can now reference these export functions.
So here users controller get users here.
Users controller dot sign up.
And here users controller dot log in pointing at these functions now back in the user's controller we
can now add some dummy logic and for the moment that means I'll also add some dummy users here simply
again an array.
Here it can be a constant because we'll never replace it with a new array and then we could add a user
let's say a user has an I.D. a user has a name Max Schwartz.
In my case here not my full name but good enough a user has a email test at tests dot com and a user
has a password which will later byte away hash to make it non plain text but for the moment I'll go
with a plain text password in our dummy data here.
That's it for the moment now and get users.
I want to return that array of users.
So here we can send back a response status code 200 which we therefore actually don't need to set.
We can do it won't be a problem but we don't have to.
We can just send back our response where we have our users and there.
I simply sent back all my dummy users simple step.
So it's a very simple middleware function of course but it does what it needs to do for a sign of a
want to create a new user.
So I will extract data from the incoming request body and the data I get there is the the user name
the email and the password.
Lets me just go with name here.
But you can expect any field you want of course.
And then here I'll create my new user created user so new object I.D. can be generated with Dad you
you I.D. package we installed earlier.
Let's just make sure we import it here if we want to use it in that file.
So const you requires you use flash before and then we can execute you you idea as a function to generate
a unique idea and then name email and password are all stored in equally named properties.
Which is why we can always use this shortcut which then behind the scenes is expanded to this which
you could also write.
Alternatively of course then I want to add that user to my dummy users heater with push.
We can do that and then sent back a response where the status code is actually 201 because we created
new data and where I then stored that created user in a user property of the object which is added to
the response.
Now for a log in I want to extract data from the body as well.
It's a post request so it will have a body.
I expect to get the email and password there and here I simply want to search if we have a user with
that email in our array and if we do.
If that password is equal to the password we get here.
This is not our final authentication logic will refine and harden that in the authentication module
but for the moment it's good enough dummy code so here I will have my identified user.
You can of course named constant however you want by going to my dummy users and finding a user where
the email property holds a value equal to the email I'm getting in my request body and if I do find
that user so if identified user is truth I can continue or put in other words if it's false see I want
to return an error so I will import my own age to the error class by requiring it from the models folder
like this and then we can create an error here and throw it so fro New Age.
The error could not identify user credentials seem to be wrong and the status code here is four hundred
and one which means that all indication failed if we make it past as a check we know we found a user
but we haven't validated D password yet.
So let's check if identified user password is equal to password which we extract from the body or actually
grab scrapped as and combine it with this check.
If we don't find an identified user or if we do find one but the password is not equal to the password
we got in the body then we want to return this error.
Ivor why is if you make it past this check we know we do have a valid user and then I want to return
a response where for the moment I will just have a message phrase say locked in.
Of course later we'll send back more data than just this text but for the moment this will do and I'd
say that's good enough.
Dummy code for all user routes let's give them a try to try them.
We have to make sure we can actually reach the routes we set up in the users routes file though and
at the moment this would not be the case because you must never forget that initially you start your
server by executing the app J.S. file and only what's set up there will work in the running server and
there I do for example register my places routes as middleware.
I don't do it for the users routes at least not yet.
So that's what we have to change.
We should add a new import here and import the users the routes by requiring them from the routes folder
users routes and then register them as a middleware.
So here right below or right above the places routes doesn't matter I'll filter for API slash users
and forward any requests where the path starts with debt to my users routes and now we can actually
reached these routes at least that was the hope we have an error cannot find controller users controllers.
Yeah I need to add a s here at the end of my file that was missing.
Now it restarts and it works and now with that let's go back to postman.
Let's first of all send a get request to get all users.
So here I'll send the request to local host 5000 slash API slash users if I do that I get my users array
here with the one user I got.
So that's looking good.
Let's now try to sign up for Dad all at post request and I'll send the request to local hosted five
thousand slash API slash users.
Now here we need to attach a body.
So let's go to Body raw Jason and attach some Jason data now to sign up a new user.
We need to add a name email and a password because data is what we're extracting from the incoming request.
So here I'll add a name menu email test to at test dot com and also a password testing if we had sent
here let's see it works.
Could not find this route Yeah because it should be slash sign up of course.
Not just slash users.
Yeah this looks better.
Manual was created.
Let's now try logging in.
By sending a request to local host five 5000 slash API slash users slash log in here we all need to
edit a body Jason body of course and there we just need to provide an email and the password.
So first of all all provide a valid combination testers.
This is the combination for this user.
Email is test at test dot com password is testers Data's what I am providing here should be a post request
though not a get request and then click send and I get locked in.
Now let's try invalid combination for example an email address which doesn't exist or the e-mail address
test 2 which I just created but where the password is wrong because here I create it testing as a password
not testers and this also fails if I enter testing though here it should succeed and address.
So now it works.
There's just one tweak which we could add we want to make sure we're not able to create a user which
we already have.
So an email address shouldn't be registered more than once.
So here in the sign up middleware function I'll actually check if we can find a user with that email
address.
So has user can be found by using dummy users and then there I'll find a user where user email is equal
to the email that was attached to the request.
And if that is true the which it only is if we found a user then I know we already have such a user.
In that case I want to throw a new H to the p error where I say could not create user email already
exists and I'll add a status code of 422 which we typically use for invalid user input so if we now
try this and I try to create a user by sending a requested a sign about which already exists.
So for example test at test dot com is hardcoded.
It exists even after a server restart.
I get this error if I try a test to it test dot com.
And remember that the server restarted because of that change.
So our previous changes are lost.
It therefore works if I now try it again though often worked one time.
I of course fails because now it is user exists.
So this is looking great.
We got the dummy user routing and logic in place and with that we implemented every route every API
endpoint that's listed here on that slide where we planned our API.
Now therefore we're almost done but there is one thing which I really don't like at the moment and that
is that we don't validate incoming data.
For example when we create a new place we don't check whether we do have a tile whether that's not empty
ends on that something which should change.