To show the position of a place on a map I will add two new components.
One is a modal a modal is an overlay which you see on many Web sites.
It's basically like a pop up but built into the page not in a new browser window.
It has a background where we can use this backdrop which we already use for the site draw on mobile
and then we have that model as an overlay in that modal we can display anything.
And indeed I will build a reusable modal here which we can use to host any kind of content confirmation
dialogues whatever we need.
In this case a map.
And that's then the second thing we need.
We'll build a special wears off that modal which uses that model but then hosts a map inside of it.
So let's start with the generic model itself for this in UI elements here next to card and so on.
We can grid and you file the modal jazz file and all the modal C is as follows because we will certainly
need some styling in modal J.S..
As always we import react from react and then we have our modal component here which receives props
and which exports this model then in the end we also need to import our C as as file here.
So import dot slash modal CSA s now actually in here.
I want to have a second component.
No one is forcing you to only have one component per file.
Typically that is what you have.
But if you have two components that work closely together then you can also absolutely have more than
one component in a file.
Please note that I will only export the modal here though.
The second component which I will build here is only for internal use.
So the modal component will use that second component.
I will also build and that will be the actual modal overlay so the thing we will actually see on the
screen this is another component I add here which is not export it but will be use by modal.
Now let's start with structuring the content of the modal overlay.
I will use the react Dom create portal method there.
So let's import react Dom from react Dom.
And then here I will return.
React.
Dom create portal and output some content here in a special place.
Variable use document get element by D modal dash hook which is a place we should add in the public
index H TO MAIL file maybe here between backdrop hook and draw hook.
That's our mode Look that's the place where the modal will then be mounted to into real dog so in the
modal component we now need to specify the content which should actually be rendered there.
Now the content here is a diff with a class name of modal.
Now actually it's more than that I want to be flexible here.
So I render a template literal here so that I can add my modal class but I can also inject some other
class name and that's props start class name so that in the end when we use the modal we could also
add our own classes to the modal and we're not restricted to the classes set up here just a little extra
flexibility.
I will also add a style prop and set this to prop start style so we could also directly add inline styles
to this modal if we wanted to then I want to have a header in there.
So basically a header title is shown at the top of the modal does header will also receive a class name.
And here again I want to be really flexible so we'll add modal underscore underscore header but then
also add prop stored header class so that we can add our own header classes if we want to Indi header.
The idea is to have a h to tag where we output some text that is received on a props header property
that lets the header below the header but still inside the div I will add a forum will not always need
debt but if we had some modal content that should be part of a forum wrapping everything with a form
here can be an advantage.
Now you could also certainly built this in other ways.
But here I want to have a really flexible modal so want to give the developer who will then use the
modal which of course is us the possibility to add content that is automatically wrapped in a forum
not a must do but something I want to do here.
Here I will add ons up my handler and check if props on submit is set.
And if it is set I will call props on submit.
So will bind on submit to these on submit I get fruit props and otherwise I will pass a inline function
here where we get the event and where a call event prevent default.
Why.
Because I want to make sure that if we render any buttons inside of that form we don't accidentally
reload the page by triggering our forum submission here if we do provide our own submit function then
it's the duty of that submit function to prevent the default.
Now inside of that form I'll add another death class name here again is a dynamic binding to be really
flexible and there I will bind us to modal underscore underscore content and then prop start content
class so similar to the header.
The idea simply is that if we use the model in some place of our app we can dynamically provide our
custom header class to adjust the default look our custom extra class for the content and I'll do the
same then later for the footer of the model which will also add inside of this content output props
children.
So whatever we add between the opening and closing tag off the model.
And then last but not least I'll add a footer still inside of the form.
And here in that footer or on that footer just as before dynamic classes are added and here I will have
modal underscore underscore footer as a class.
But then for extra flexibility at prop start foot or a class to allow external customization.
Now that's by the way all that the reason why I have that form here in that footer.
The user should be able to inject footer content for example buttons that allow the user to confirm
a choice or something like that.
And dad would be hard to do if we only injected everything into content here.
Now by the way that split into a content div and the footer is the reason for this default form here.
If the user wants to render a modal that holds a form of course you could inject the form here as a
content with props children.
But if you want of a nice styling where to submit buttons are visually separated from the content which
is the styling that will be applied by default with the default clauses I add here.
Then this would not be possible to be all in one form because the forum would live here and the buttons
would live here and there would not be inside of the forum.
That's why I have to is wrapping general form here which wraps both the content div as well as the footer
where the user can then inject for example the inputs of a forum and then the submit buttons and if
you are not using a forum and you're not providing on submit it's ignored anyways so that's the general
structure of the modal overlay.
Now why do I have a separate component down there because a modal is more than just the overlay a modal
also needs backdrop and I also want to play a little animation when we open and close to modal so therefore
we need to import two more things we need to import the backdrop from dot slash backdrop here and import
see us as transition from a react Transition Group.
That animation library we already used earlier with that in our modal a component not in modal overlay
but in modal I want to return a react fragment because I'll have some sibling top level elements and
I want to check if we have a show prop which is true ish in which case I will render the backdrop and
on the backdrop we can click and I will not trigger on cancel method or function which I receive on
the on cancel prop here.
If that is the case so that outside of the modal in the place and the component where we use it we can
handle the cancellation and close it or do whatever we want to do.
Now both sides are entering the backdrop.
I also want to render it a CSX transition here and D in prop here is bound to prop start show which
is our trigger for the backdrop as well.
I set mount on enter and on mount on exit at a time out of 200 milliseconds and then class names not
class name but class names and set this to modal now the appropriate class names which does CSX transition
component then we'll use will be added in modal C as s.
And speaking of that attached you find a modal us as file and you can simply put the content you find
in there into your modal see us as follows.
I'll make sure you are importing modal CSX and you're almost done.
I'm saying almost because the key part is missing the modal overlay.
We're not using that in our motel down there of course that is what I want to render between my CSX
transition components though.
So here we can add modal overlay and close it and now do one thing.
We forward all the props we get from outside to modal overlay.
This index might look strange but what it does is it takes the props we pass two modal which is the
component we export and forwards them to modal overlay which is the internal component which we don't
export.
This allows us to set for example footer for a class content clause header ends on on the export of
modal component where we of course don't need it.
We don't use it here but we then forward it to modal overlay so it allows us to set props on this internal
component from outside so to say and distant X might look strange but this is D spread operator which
takes all the key value pairs of the props object and spreads them as attributes so to say onto modal
overlay with Dad.
We created a general modal now that General modal is nice but of course you want a modal with a map
now we'll work on the map soon but for now let's show the normal modal route African go to the place
item where we have this view on map button.
And now we need to manage some state which we change when that button is pressed to show the modal and
then all the in the backdrop of the modal is pressed to hide the modal.
So I will import use state from react here and add a new state in place.
Item show map and set show map which initially is false because initially I don't want to show the modal
and then I will add functions here.
The open map handler there.
I'd simply call set show map and set this to true and disclose.
Map handler and you can guess what I'll do there.
I'll set this to false.
Now we all need to import the modal we just built.
So import modal from our shared components UI elements the modal file their and now you start.
Now how do we use it.
I want to render it next to my list item.
And keep in mind it won't really be rendered dear instead because I use a portal both on the backdrop
as well as the modal overlay.
It will be injected in a different place of our index H to mail file and that's the nice thing about
portals which I already touched on earlier.
They allow us to use a component in a certain place in this case and a place item and yet render the
content of that component in a different place which semantically might be better than attaching the
modal markup next to the list item we might be able to achieve the same look but for screen readers
and so on and for semantics in general that would not be ideal.
So that's where a portal can help us now we have multiple sibling rude items.
We need to react fragment so we can wrap the list item with that.
And then with react fragment as a new top level element in this component we can render our model here
next to the list item now.
On this modal I want to set the show prop and set this equal to show map.
So to this state we just added I also have on cancel handler here which just to make this clear again
isn't the end a function that will be triggered when we click the backdrop.
That's when I Indian forward that click event to on cancel and triggered a function that's passed through
on cancel.
So on cancel therefore point at the close map handler function so that this function is executed when
we click the backdrop I will provide text for the header and there I simply want to use to address the
human readable address of the place
and add extra content clause which should be placed dash item underscore underscore modal dash content.
Let me reformat that to make it easier to read and also add a fuller class to that modal
which I'll set to play stash item underscore underscore modal dash actions
the last but not least I'll set the footer prop itself to a dynamic value which will be some J is X
because there I want to have a button which allows me to close the modal and therefore I'll add the
on click listener to the button and set does equal to the close map handler just as on cancel this button
component here through the footer prop will be rendered in our model overlay in this place yet that's
where I use the footer prop and since I've forward all props I pass to modal to modal overlay if I pass
anything in a footer prop does this verbiage will end up so with that I prepared the model but the main
content is missing between the opening and closing tag off the modal we have to specify what should
be rendered in the place of props children because remember props children instead special prop react
nose which renders whatever is between the opening and closing tag of your reacting off your chest x
element.
So here in the middle there I want to render my map for now I will render a div here with a class name
of map container and I will actually add this class in place.
Item C as s maybe here above the media query map container can be a simple class where you set a height
of let's say 20 REM and a width of 100 percent.
So make sure to add this class to place item C as s and to distill here and insert of this div will
soon add the map.
For now I'll just have h to tag raise say the map which is of course not our final result and with dapper
almost stare the missing piece.
Now it's that we connect the buttons down there.
Now we can add on click listener as I already did it here in the footer because the custom button component
in the end forwards the default on click event to well the function that is received on a on click prop.
So we have to provide such a on click prop to react to a click and hence here on the view on map button
I'll add on click and bind this to open map handler.
So to that function which sets show map to true we save all files it should recompile and if I now click
on View and map you'll see that modal slide in and of course all the slide out if I close it.
However it reloads the page if I close so let's quickly go to the modal reason for that is that we have
to us form which gets submitted and yet there on prevent default.
Of course I should execute this as a function not just point at it.
So at the parentheses after prevent default and now with Dad if we go back I can click close and it
doesn't reload instead of just removes the model and this all should look good on mobile.
Yeah bit Big there maybe.
So maybe we should shrink our map container a little bit.
Let's say 15 REMS should do the trick.
And with that it looks good.
But of course now the map itself is missing we could of course all the by the way find you in the position
where the model is shown that it's shown further on top.
That could be done in the modal C as as file there change top 20 30 we age maybe to twenty two VH B
ages as C as this unit that is basically the viewport height and this means 22 percent from the top
of your viewport height.
So now if you do that yeah I think that looks pretty decent.
Yeah.
So now let's focus on outputting a nice little map rendered for Google Maps.
Here in this modal.