So back in or cold.
Let's now go down to our delete place constant and see what you have to change here to make sure we
can delete the place successfully the first part here.
Our try catch block to check whether we have any general error is fine.
There is only one thing we have to add right here because what we want to do in the end is we want to
find the place idea of a place we're looking for to delete this place.
But at the same time we also want to search for our users collection and see which user has this place.
And then we want to make sure that if we did a place that this I.D. is also deleted from this user document
this means we need access to a user document and we need to overwrite or change an existing while information
in this document.
And to do so we can use these so-called populate method here populate allows us to exactly do dead so
to refer to a document stored in another collection and to work with data in that existing document
of that other collection to do so.
We need a relation between these two documents and these relations were established in our user j s
file here with ref place and in our place J S file here before the user.
Only if this connection is existing then we are allowed to use populate.
Otherwise this populate method would not work and depopulate method needs one additional information
it needs information about the document where we want to change something and move in this document
we need to refer to a specific property in our case this is the creator property because you create
a property contains the user IDM Mongoose then takes this idea but searches for the entire user data.
So the idea allows us to search for the user and then to get back all the data stored in a user document.
With that we have to theoretically option to change something in our user and of course to also find
a place by I.D. in our replace document we can keep the rest of this code here like this does is fine
now before we work on this try catch block though I see we missed something before because what we should
do here actually is before we continue we should check whether a place is actually existing because
this is our general error catching part but we never check whether a place idea actually exists let's
quickly implement that if plays like this so if we don't find a place for the provided DB Well then
we want to return an error stating that we could not find place for this I.D. error code for or for
and of course return next error like this.
So this is what you forgot before and now this is a better error handling syntax I would say so let's
not focus onto this.
Try catch Pardo because actually this is exactly the same approach that we followed when creating the
place of course.
Now we don't want to save and push but we'll remove and Paul little hint here.
But generally the handling of this code is exactly the same.
So we can need a session to start our transaction.
And only if we can delete the place and if we can delete the place the from the corresponding user then
this transaction should be executed.
Otherwise we will have an error here.
So this one.
Something went wrong.
Could not delete place.
So now is your chance to post the video at this stage and to implement this code on your own.
After that we'll do it together
so let's see.
We already have some code here.
I would like to start from scratch though.
For that we first need to create our new constant for our current session.
Here we have to add a weight as it's an asynchronous task and now we need to use start session here.
We'll start session.
We can now use the start transaction method here and with that we can get started with the actual logic
we need to make sure we can delete the place first we need to remove the place from our places collection.
We checked before whether the place exists.
Therefore we can simply refer to place remove here and we need to add deception property here to make
sure we refer to the current session so here.
So this the session that we just created.
And removing all as an asynchronous task so we remove the place.
Now we have to access our place stored in the create or Saudi place I.D..
For that we prefer to place start creator and in the creator we want to access places our places Ellroy
and hero.
We now don't want to push but to pull.
Well what our place.
As explained before for push pull will also automatically remove the I.D. so we don't have to explicitly
tell Mongoose to remove on a deep.
This is done internally by default.
This should hopefully remove the place from the user.
What we need to do now is we need to save our newly created user.
This is again an asynchronous task and we referred to police dot creator and now to the safe method.
They're important though as we did it for remove with our places.
Here we again have to refer to our current session.
You can name is of course as you prefer.
This is the name of the constant here.
We can use places pull and save on create the like that because creator.
Well thanks depopulate gave us the full User object linked to that place.
And if all this was successful then we can finally commit our turn transaction.
So this is it actually.
With that we can also hopefully remove a place the response right here is fine so we can keep this.
So let's save this and let's go to mongo TB and let's say we want to delete the Empire State Building
now.
For that we need our object out here.
So this one.
So let's copy paste this.
Now let's go to postman.
Create a new request this time.
This is a delete request.
This goes to slash places here and now slash.
Well our I.D. that we just copied if we had sent.
Now we can hopefully delete the place and we should also see that the place is no longer part of the
array in our user.
So let's send
and this looks good.
We get the message deleted place here.
Let's just have a look at this in our database.
If we rule out that we can see places as empty so this worked fine and also for our user here we still
left the error.
But as you can see we don't have any more places here in our area.
Therefore deleting the place from the user also worked fine.
With that we are almost done with this module.
There is actually one optional thing I would like to show you because here we use this populate method
and there is another part in our project where we could use this populate method.
This is optional though I just want to show you how this method works in a bit more detail and the place
where we can use this as an alternative is here.
When we get our places by the user I.D..
So in this constant here this is the last part of this module Indian.
So let me show you how we can use an alternative syntax here.
Have depopulate method.