To convert an address to coordinates Google has a nice API.
You can search for a Google geo coding API and below the ads.
You should find this API here.
That's a documentation of the API and you can of course check that out to learn all about that API.
In the end what we want to do is we want to do a geo coding request here on the right.
We want to search for an address and get back coordinates now to be able to send the request there.
We need an API key.
That's not something we need on our API we build but a lot of API which are exposed to the public which
is not the idea of our API.
A lot of API which are exposed to the public require api keys so that they can kind of keep track of
the users working with their API.
Now to create such a API key we first of all need a Google account.
So let's sign and by the way in case you can't create a Google account or you can set a building with
a credit card which you will also need unfortunately to work with the Google API as you can just write
some dummy code that simply translates every address into the same pair of coordinates so that you can
follow along and of course just fine.
I will show this in the next minutes as well.
So now I did log in with my account and I can now click on get started here at the top and you'll be
forwarded to a page where you can pick the products you want to work with.
Now there we only need places but it all doesn't hurt to choose maps.
If you decide to also use Google Maps on your front end with one of their SDK is like a Javascript SDK
they are exposing but places is the thing we absolutely need right now so you can't continue.
Then select a project or simply create a new project which is what all do here.
Course project you can of course pick a more meaningful name click next and now wait for it to finish.
Now you might be prompted to set up a billing account and add a credit card.
What we do here is free though you can search for Google Maps pricing to find detailed information about
their pricing and you will see that you have a two hundred dollar free you search every month for their
API is and that will get you very far.
You'll find examples down there where you see what this costs and so on.
So what we do with the frequency and volume we use in the course will be free.
But of course checked is in case you are working with Google Maps or any Google API in real application
so here I will confirm that I want to use this account for billing.
And again if you can't set up billing you can continue here but I will show you some dummy fallback
code in just a second.
Here it will just confirm that it will enable all API eyes and then this will load a bit more and I
get my api key by the way.
No need in copying mine.
By the time you're watching this I will already have invalidated my key of course.
Now this key is something you should copy or just leave his window open for now because we will need
it now.
I will add a new folder to the node application which I'll name you till for utility you can of course
named a folder how you want and then they are all at a location J as fall in data.
I'll add a API key constant all caps to make it clear that this is like at the local constant I will
use in this file and this is the API key I got here by Google.
Now with that we can write a function here in that file which takes an address reaches out to Google's
API and converts does address to coordinates.
Now if you can set up billing and you therefore don't have an API key.
Here is a dummy function you can use get coords for address and by the way of course it does not matter
if you create a function like this in the declaration form or if you do get coords for address and use
an arrow function for example you can use either notation here to mix things up.
All use this declaration form and I expect to get my address here as the argument.
Now if you have no API key if you consider building you have no credit card you can simply return coordinates
here coordinates where we have a latitude and there I will use the dummy latitude I have in the places
controller.
So essentially I will use this object here to be precise.
I will return this object here they are now that's my dummy however actually in the real function which
will write in a second will make age the BP request which will be a asynchronous task in which they
offer will work with promises.
So we'll turn this function to a async function by using the async keyword in front of it async await
is a functionality built into modern javascript.
It in the end make sure that this function or the return value of that function gets wrapped into a
promise and it makes sure that when you're working with promises in there you can use a wait in front
of the promise to wait for its response instead of promise then.
And if this all doesn't tell you anything attached you find more resources on promises and async await
since as Javascript.
I assume that this knowledge is there here or that you're picking it up side by side with this course
and therefore for now what we have here that's the main takeaway is a function which will return to
coordinates but wrapped in a promise so not immediately not synchronicity but asynchronously through
that promise.
But returning this year is the fallback anyways so only required if you have no credit card otherwise
now will write to code which will send the request to Google's API and get us the coordinates for a
given address now to send the request from insert a node app.
We have some built in core modules that help us with that but it's a bit cumbersome to use them to be
honest.
So I will use a third party package here which I installed with npm install dash dash safe and that's
the access package.
Now if you have some javascript and especially some front end javascript experience you might already
know this package.
It's a very popular package for sending H to p requests from front end applications to back ends now
not known by everyone.
Is that this package can also be used on a node server to send the request from there.
And that's exactly what I'll do here.
Full install access and it will allow me to send a request from my notes server to yet another server.
So together no backing.
So let's run this here with NPM start and then here I will import access by requiring access like this.
Now here I can send a get request to a U R L and now the question is which you are l Well we get that
from the Google Docs.
Again search for a Google geo coding API to get back to their docs and there was this geo coding request.
Here you can simply copy this you are L here and go back to your code.
Now I will use back tricks here to create a template real literal and no default javascript feature
which allows me to create a string where I can easily inject dynamic segments because here this address
does dummy address should be replaced.
So Mark all that address so everything after that equal sign in front of that ampersand symbol and then
add a dollar sign an opening closing curly brace.
That's the syntax for injecting I dynamic value into a string or into a template literal.
Now that is the address we're getting as an argument but we need to convert that to get rid of special
character or whitespace.
With the help of a global function away lable in JavaScript in note J.S. and that's the ENCODE you are
I component.
Function simply pass your string to it.
So the address string and it will give you back a string which and codes everything into where you are
L friendly format.
Now we all need to inject our API key here and that's of course the global API key constant we created.
Now this sends a gat request to this you are L and should return us the coordinates for that given address.
So here I get my response by a weighting that is available because I added async here for the response.
It's the same as if I would have called then here and then added My response handling function here.
It's just a bit easier to read which is why I use it.
And then there we can get the data out of the response axis gives us a data field on the response object
that holds our data.
And I have first of all want a check of data is not set or and that's special for a Google API.
You can read all about that here in their docs if there is a status field whips data dot status which
is equal or which holds a value of zero results written like this.
Google will give us this field with this text a if no coordinates were found for a specified address
and this will handle the scenario that the user entered a valid address when it comes to our validation
so that it was a non empty field but an address which simply can't be found.
Well in that case we'll get back this response by Google.
If we do get back that response I'll create a new error.
A new age to the p error and therefore I will import my own age.
The P error class here from the models folder a new P error where the messages could not find location
for the specified address.
I mean 422 could be a status code we set here because it would probably happened because of an invalid
user input but you could also go for 404.
It's up to you and I don't want to throw that error here.
Now if you throw an error here in the async function the promise that is automatically created and wraps
everything in the function will basically also throw that error if we make it past this.
If check we know we have no error so then I want to extract my coordinates and I get that from data
dot results and you can read more about the structure of the response you get from Google here in their
docs.
So the coordinates can be found in data results.
They're the first element because this turns out to be an array but the first element is the one that
best matches to give an address their geometry and then location and this will be an object which looks
like this year.
So does the location object.
So it has this lat and LNG key with no values in it which we need and here I will then return the coordinates.
So that will then all the return of coordinates object just as we did it before with the dummy code
in case you don't have an API key.
And with that we just have to make sure we export this function so we can use it so we can use module
exports and set this equal to get coords for address.
Of course not executing it just pointing at it so that we can execute it from inside our files specifically
the place controller there.
I want to use this now.
So here I'll have get coords from address which all will require from the you till folder and there
to location file.
And now we need to call this when we create a place to translate our address to coordinates.
For that I will convert my create place func here to a async function as well by adding the async keyword
in front of the argument list simply so that we can use to await keyword in here and work with promises
in a more elegant way.
Now since I did this however we should also not throw errors anymore but call next year instead because
when working with async code throw will not work correctly in Express so you always need to next your
error.
Now with that I still do my validation first and once I extracted the address it's time to convert the
address to coordinates.
So here we can call get coords for address and pass in the address.
This returns a promise so we can await it and get our coordinates here.
Now this might fail it might throw an error right.
I'm throwing an error in there and if you want to handle an error when using async await we have to
wrap this into a try catch block that's all.
But Mila.
Javascript so we'll actually create a coordinates variable here and assign a value to it instead of
try catch so that coordinates is not just scoped to the dry block and then here we might catch an error.
If that fails if we do catch an error I simply want to next it.
I want to forward it.
I also want to return so that no other code they're off to runs since we catch the error.
We don't quit the function execution automatically.
So we have to quit it by calling return Album wise if we don't make it into Catch.
So if we do get coordinates coordinates will be populated with our coordinates.
That also means that I no longer expect them here on my incoming request.
Instead I get them here when we convert the address to coordinates.
Therefore we will still have coordinates down there if we make it thus far and everything in general
down there can stay the way it is.
Let's now give this a try save everything and let's see whether it works.
So here I'll try to create a new place.
I no longer need to provide my coordinates here.
I will create my title here.
New York Stock Exchange so that this is all valid and hit send and I got an unexpected token error here
because of that extra trading karma which I forgot to delete.
Make sure you do and then send it again.
And this is looking good.
We got a location here.
And since I'm not passing coordinates here these have to be the coordinates inferred by Google.
Let's also try a different place here.
By entering a different address for example the Marine plots in mention Munich.
You could enter anything here.
Google will translate and look it up.
That's really good.
So here we have the Marine plots a place you probably have to visit when you were in Munich and let's
look Dad up.
Keep the old coordinates in mind.
We should get different ones now and we do.
So this is really looking great.
We got that up and running we also got no errors here on the server side and therefore now we're even
sending a request from our back end to another back end to another API which already gives us an idea
of how we could communicate with our own API later.
And we're doing this to convert an address to coordinates and with that I'd say with a pretty nice dummy
Rest Api already a node express application which gives us exactly the API we planned and the biggest
thing that is missing right now of course is the database access which will add an extra module.
Now one thing I just noticed here of course we should return now because I'm no longer throwing an error
so function execution would not stop otherwise hence we have to return now to make sure we don't execute
any other code thereafter.
We didn't need to do that before when we threw an error because when we throw function execution automatically
stops.
If we just next it it does not stop item automatically.
So we have to return it.