No one ever or I just sport that indie application we built is that I forgot to change something and
NAV links here where I load my places I always pointed you one and as a result when being logged in
if I click my places I always get this error here.
Now therefore we should change this of course this year should be bound dynamically to a string where
we say something that Nemec and then slash places and the dynamic thing here is coming from the off
contexts and should be our user I.D. so that we use the real user I.D. here and not that dummy user
I.D..
So with that if we are logging in here and I go to my places I might not find any places for this specific
user if he hasn't created any.
But if we have a place like here a dummy place I created behind the scenes then we do succeed.
So that is an adjustment I should make fixed that Annapolis to ensure that your navigation app works
correctly.