So let's make sure we feed the information about the input value and the validity back to the place
where we use the input.
So in our case to the new place component so any input component here.
When the end want to call some function which we expect to get from from outside.
So in this case from new place through some prop when ever our input state changes basically or to be
precise when ever the value or the validity of the input changes.
So for that here in the input component I will use a new or a no reactive which we already used before
and that's use of fact use a fact as you learn allows us to run some logic when some dependencies change
we can use it to run something after the first render as we did it in the case of Google Maps but we
can also use it to runs on logic in our case here whenever the input value or validity changes because
that are the two conditions and typically they change together of course under which we want to emit
a new value back to the place back to the component where we use the input component so maybe here we
can use use of fact like this.
Then here we have the function that should be executed.
And here we have our array of dependencies.
So array of things that should trigger this function.
Now what do we want to do in this function.
I want to call props on input for example because that is stand the prop we can set in new place to
be basically informed about changes.
So where we then pass a function to input.
So when I call props on input here as a function because I expect to get a function on this prop and
then maybe pass our I.D. off that input back to the component where we use the input component pass
input stage stored value and pass input state that is valid.
Now we need to specify our dependencies here and we could say our dependencies are props and input state.
Right because we use data from props and we use data from input state in there.
Dad would make sure that this function runs whenever anything in our props changes or whenever anything
in our input state changes.
This can actually create infinite loops because we call a function and the parent component.
And if that then leads to the parent component giving us new props we call that function again.
And even if it does not lead to infinite loops it might execute too often.
It would also execute if our touch state changes even though that's not a state that yields any new
value or validity information.
So therefore I will not feed in these dependencies but pull out the relevant pieces with object D structuring
from the props I want to get the I.D. and the on input prop like this so that here I can use I.D. and
just call on input and from the input state I want I get the value and is valid from input state like
this and that means here I just forward value and is valid.
And here I have I.D. value is valid and actually also on input as dependencies because the on input
thing here is also something we get from outside.
So whenever one of these things changes over the function it should be called the I.D. or most importantly
value or is valid we will call on input so the value we get on the on input prop that takes us to the
new place the new place component there of course we now have to provide a function that should be called
so here in New Place J.S. we can add a function and named add tidal change or tidal Input handler.
It's a function which will receive the I.D. you might say that's kind of redundant because we know it
will be the title that changed.
This will become important later.
So for now let's just get it it will get the idea of the input that changed the value and the answer
whether Dad input is now valid or not.
Because these are the three pieces of information we pass here in our input component idea value and
is valid.
So we get these free pieces of information here.
Of course you could pick different names here for the parameters though it's a brand new function in
a different component after all.
So now here we can bind
on input to the title Input handler so that this is the function that does get executed.
Now we should be careful though.
We will have one problem or we could have one problem whenever an input.
We call on input and be forward disinformation.
We trigger this function here right.
And if in this function we now do anything that changes to state of the new place component and re renders
it what will happen technically is that a new title Input handler function gets created because we create
this function instead of the function.
So whenever a component function runs this function is recreated even if it has the same logic as before.
It's a new function object.
That's how javascript works.
So that means that the function will technically change the function is fed into the input component
and there on input is a dependency of this function.
So then does affect function would run again would trigger this function again and would effectively
lead to an infinite loop to avoid this.
We import another hook from react and that's the use callback hook we can use use callback to wrap a
function.
So in this case this function here and to find the pendency is off this function under which it should
read render and here for the moment I specify no dependencies which now means if the component renders
if the component functionary executes this function here will be stored away by react and will be reused
so that no new function object is created whatever the function the component function renders but that
instead this function is reused and doesn't change and that then does not lead to use of fact to run
again.
That's really important here to avoid an infinite loop and with that of course the question is what
do we want to do in title input handler.
Well we want in the end managed the overall validity and values of the entire form because we will have
multiple inputs there we can already create a second one for example we can create a second input and
Dad let's say is actually a text area maybe hence we don't need to type the label then could be description.
We also should provide an I.D. by the way here.
Ideas should be title and here idea would be description let's say.
And I also want to provide my validators here.
I want to require this but I also want to make sure that we have a min length of 5 and therefore we
don't actually need require because if we have a minimum length of 5 Well it must not be empty anyways.
Here we can enter please enter a valid description at least 5 characters as extra hint maybe
and we could also specify a row is here but I'm happy with the default of 3 which we coded into our
input component so now we have a second input and now we want to find out in our input handlers whether
the overall form is valid.
And of course we want to store all the values of the individual inputs.
So actually we'll need a second handler here a description input handler and we'll bind this description
input handler to this second input here to the on input prop there.
So now we've got two input handlers.
Now we need to manage the overall form validity.