In the input component we need to be able to work with initial values and validity.
So Indian component here.
Value is not always an empty string.
It also can be a value provided from outside.
So here props.
Value could be something we set as the initial value or an empty string.
If the value prop is not provided and for is valid it's the same we set this to props.
Valid or false if that's not provided.
So this is one important adjustment here to work with initial values and support does as well.
Let's see if that works.
If we save this and we click on edit here we're taking to this forum and this form looks horrible because
the form styling is missing all fixed as soon.
But if I now have a look at this the button is disabled and that makes sense because an update place
we currently always disable it.
But let's see if I get an error if I now remove that initial value by the way.
The fact that we see this initial value here already shows us that our input seems to work.
And yeah if I remove it we get an error.
If I add a valid input back we get nowhere.
So that is looking good.
That seems to work now.
Of course the overall forum is not looking that great there.
I actually want to use the same styling as a new place and therefore I will named as place forum CSX
here and the new place J.S. import plays form CSX and import the same here in update place so that I
can reuse this styling does of course means that an update plays to the form we should add this class
name of placed dash form so that the styling applies there too.
And with that that looks a lot nicer.
So that's good.
So our input component seems to work and the form is looking good.
But now what about the forum state itself.
What about this forum reducer and all the logic we wrote in new place.
A lot of that logic is required here as well but not all the logic.
For example the initial state is a different one.
Here we have title and description and we should also have address and an update place.
We only need title and description and we don't need address.
So how can we kind of reuse that and still make it configurable from inside each component.
For that we can create a custom hook.
Something we haven't done yet but which you will do now.