So now with routing setup let's start working on the actual components and there.
I want to start with the users component the users component is not where we sign up but where even
we're not locked in.
We can see a list of users and how many places they shared.
It's this list of users page here at the very top of our plan.
We created so data for here in the users component.
The goal is to output a list of users you could say so we'll create a new component here already because
splitting is always good.
And in that new component in the user folder in the components folder I want to output my list of users.
So we'll named a component users list J S is the file name.
We will also need some styling so add users list dot c as s here as well.
And I also want to have a separate component for every item in that list.
So I'll have a user item j as fall as well as a user item C is as follows.
Now as always how you exactly split and structure your code is always up to you.
There isn't a single best way there isn't a single right way.
But having a granular structure where every component is relatively small and focused is rarely a bad
idea in this day for what I will do here.
So in users list J.S. I'll set up a default component by importing react from react so that we can use
J as X then we have users list here and we will get some props here because we will get the list of
users from outside later so from the parent component and then it will export this and it will copy
this into user item and just rename users list here to user item both here and then the export numbers
than dead.
It's the same.
I will also import the C is as follows.
So here I import user item not see us s and in the User List in the users list.
J is fall I will import users list dot c as s so that we have the style false imported as well.
Now in the users list component here My idea is to output either a message of no users found if we have
no users in the app yet if we just launched or most of the time when we do have at least one user a
list of our users.
So there are two possible branches of J.S. ex code I want to return and dead in the end will depend
on some data which I expect to get from outside via props so which I expect to get from the parent component.
So here we can add if check and say if props items I expect to get items property the name is up to
you.
You just and later have to use it on your users list component when you use it in J as X as well.
So here I'll go with items as a name for this prop if the length of that because I expect items to be
an array and hence it should have a length property if length is equal to zero which means we have no
users yet I want to return a div with a class name of center which is a class name I defined here in
index CSA s it just centers to contain and in there I want to output a h to tag where I say no users
found so that's my first possibility.
Alternatively if we don't make it in here and that's not dead J is X code we return in this component
therefore.
So if we do have at least one user we will return something else will return an unordered list and then
that unordered list.
I want a map my items which is an array of objects not an array of J is X but an array of vanilla javascript
objects into an array of J as X elements.
So here we can use the curly braces to output a javascript expression or to be precise the result of
that expression in J is X code.
And here I want to go through my items which I get on my props and map every item into a J as X element
so that this can be rendered SJ as X here so every item here will be a user of course you can named
as whoever you want but it will be a user so that name makes sense I guess and I will return a single
user item for every user so we'll import that other component.
Import user item from dot slash user item.
So from that I'll profile here and return user item as a self closing JSA X element by the way here
we can also shorten it is get rid of the curly brace in off the return statement and take advantage
of the shorter arrow function syntax which looks like this.
Now every user item needs to get to that special key property which we don't need to handle inside of
the user item but which react needs to manage lists efficiently and there.
I expect every user to have an I.D. I can expect all of that because we are the one writing this application
code.
So it's our duty to provide the right data later.
I also want to forward the idea of a user on a separate prop to the user item though and I also will
pass on an image which we can output user dot image let's say has that image data and the name of the
user which I expect to get on user dot name
I also want to output to count the number of places does user has created and hence I will pass a place
count property to user item and forward user dot places.
I expect places to be a property on the user object that holds the number of places not the other place
data just a number of places.
This user created so that's a lot of I want to right now nothing of that will happen because all we
have at the moment is a simple user item that receives a bunch of data and doesn't do anything with
that.
And even worse all our logic is based on the assumption that we get items prop in the users list and
that's also not the case.
So before we work on the user item and the styling let's make sure we do pass and the items prop to
the users list and that will be passing as a value is an array of users where every user has the data.
We're trying to extract down their now the question is Where should this be passed in.
Well in our users page that is where I want to use that users list in the end.
So here I will import users list from And now let's go up one level to be back in the user folder and
then into components and then here its users list which I want to import.
And then here I will return users list in the end.
So my page is very simple because I outsource the rendering of the list into a separate component and
that's a default approach in react to keep your components lean.
Only do very few things in every component on its own.
Instead then delegate tasks to other components.
In this case delegated to rendering of the list of users to the user list component.
So now users list requires and items prompt because that's what we try to extract in there.
Right here props items and props items and that should be an array what we pass in as a value should
be an array.
So here in my component I will create a user's constant and that is written in all caps because it's
kind of a dummy constant later in the course we will fetch our users from our back and from our node
express application.
But at the moment we have no such back and so I will work with dummy data for the moment.
So here users is an array an array of objects in our every object will represent a user.
And since we try to extract some data from every user we should make sure that this data is all provided
specifically every user needs to have an I.D. and image a name in places later of course a user will
also have an email and password.
But on this component we're not interested in that.
So here we will never extract that data from a user.
So here it's OK if a user has an I.D..
Let's say you one has a name up to you.
Let's say Mark Schwartz has an image property.
And here I just picked a random image you URL from the web because right now we have no image upload
in our application so we'll have to pick some you or l of some person somewhere in the web and last
but not least every person also needs a place as property and here I'll set this to free any arbitrary
number of your choice.
Now instead users a ray which I'll pass two items and then I will reformat this with a shortcut.
And this is what we get.
So I got one user a year with free places and have forward data Ray off that one user to users list.
Now in users list we then output our user items and in user item nothing happens so time to let something
happen there in the next lecture.