So let's continue with our efforts to build a image upload component.
We see that this console log fired when we picked a file.
Now my idea is to manage the file here instead of the image upload component to create a preview which
we have in there.
But to then all of course pass it to these surrounding forum which in needs to file to then eventually
upload it to a back end.
So whenever we need to manage something which also should update the Dom it's of course time for a use
state.
So here is an image upload we definitely need to use state because we will have a file which you want
to manage with file and set file which initially is undefined but which we will of course set at some
point.
I will also generate the numbers state the preview you are L and set per review you are El which the
end well is d you are ELA off this image preview which we want to generate so that we can show a preview
to the user and last but not least of all the ad is valid and set is valid here and use this and initially
let's say it's not valid here by initializing this state to false.
So free states which are managing here and now with that in the picked handler it's important to know
that in the event target which are locked which is does input element you will have a files property
that holds the files to user selected.
This is default javascript you get dead files property on the event target if that event target is a
native file picker which this one here is.
So we will have the files here and therefore we can check if this exists if it's not undefined.
So to ensure that this does not somehow get fired without the user picking a file.
And I also want to ensure that files length
is not equal to zero.
And of course this should be an end a load logical end.
So now we're ensuring that we have files and that if we have files we have more than one file actually
we could all check that it's exactly one file.
There shouldn't really be a wave to pick more than one year in the Zep but if you would manage to do
so I certainly don't want to handle it because we only supports the upload of one file at a time here.
So we check whether we do have files and if it's exactly one and if that is the case we can continue
here because if that is the case I want to extract that picked file from event target files and get
the first and only one and then call set file and set it to my well picked file to the extract that
file.
I will also set is valid to true thereafter because we have a file and then we can return to not execute
any other code otherwise if we don't make it into this if statement we know we picked something wrong.
Well in this case I want to set is valid to false here and actually we can remove the return statement
here and instead do this in a Alice block because then after t of statement no matter into which branch
we made it we can call props on input here.
So I expect to get an on input prop here on the image upload component which should point at a function
in to which we forward the idea of this input which we all received through prompts and this picked
file if it exists.
Now it does not always exist of course.
So actually let's set picked file here to be a variable and just assign a new value if we do have a
file and otherwise it will be still undefined which is also fine here.
And of course all the forward is valid.
Now here it's just important to understand that when we call set as valid it does not immediately update
this state value.
Instead it schedules this state update.
So when I call on input here and how forward is valid at this point it will still be the old is valid
value so not the new one.
After this update.
So actually here I will add a new variable file is valid which has set equal to the current state of
is valid.
And then here a set is valid.
But again this does not update the state immediately.
So in the meantime I will set file as valid to true here manually and set it to false.
Here and then just for word file is valid here at this point so we always basically call the function
we receive on on input and we always pass our picked file but that file might sometimes be undefined
if we didn't pick of a valid file and we will forward the validity information.
That's my idea here.
Now this doesn't help us with the preview though.
Now I want to generate a preview whenever we got a new file so whenever we basically updated our file
state.
Now doing something up on state change that screams for a use of fact.
So here we can add use effect and register a new use fact.
Function this function here should trigger or should execute whenever the file changes so we'll pass
file as a dependency whenever we picked a new file.
I want to run my logic here because in this logic in this function here I want to generate a preview.
So first of all I'll check if file is not on the flight because maybe file changed because it now is
not a file anymore but now undefined.
In this scenario I will return because if we don't have a file here there is no need to continue.
We can't generate a preview USL image preview anyways.
Otherwise if we make it past does a check we know we have a file and now we can generate an image preview
you are El with API.
That's built into the browser.
The file reader so I'll create a new file reader here and store it in a file reader constant.
And again this is baked into the browser and they offer it into browser side JavaScript the file reader
as the name suggests helps us read files helps us parse files and we can use the file reader to convert
a file which is like a binary data into a readable or output able image.
You are l You could say now the file reader has a bit of a clunky API and to work with it we have to
call file reader read as data you are L.
Now that's not too clunky I guess.
This is the anti command to create you are L we can output but the problem is this does not work with
a callback.
This does not give us a promise.
Instead before we call read as data you are L on the file reader.
We have to register G on load function like this and execute this function does anonymous function whenever
the file reader loads a new file or is done parsing of file we could say so dysfunctional executed.
Once this reading of the file here is done and then in here I want to call set preview you are L but
then here we also don't get the past file as an argument.
Instead we have to extract it from file reader daughter assault.
Yeah that's just how does API works with that.
However we are setting a preview you are L and with that we can use this preview you are L so down here
and J is X on the image I now want to output the preview you are L here.
However only if we have one.
So let's check if we have a preview you are L and only output the image if that's the case if that's
not the case if we don't have a preview you are L I will output a paragraph where I say please pick
an image and in addition I also want to output an error or a text which can be provided from outside.
So from the component that uses the image upload component in case we picked something invalid which
should be pretty hard but still in this case.
So if this is not valid is valid is false.
I want to output prop stored error text here with this.
If we now safe that and we switch to sign up here I do have my image picker and now I can pick this
image and here's my preview it all the crash though props on input is not a function and that makes
a lot of sense because remember dead ends picked handler.
I do call props on input so I referred to the on input prop and I expect to have a function in there
which I can call but at the moment when we use image upload and you off component here I'm not setting
this on input prop so we need to do this and they are we now need to point at a function and you might
think that we now need to create a new function but thankfully that's not the case.
If we have a look at the on input arguments were passing here we see it's the I.D. then the file that
was picked and then the validity of this file.
Now that is pretty similar to what we have in the input in our input component for regular text input.
We also in the end call on input at some point and we forward the idea the value and whether that value
is valid.
No that's exactly the same as we have here.
Here I have to I.D. the value because the picture file is just the value of this control if you will
and then the validity.
So therefore in off we can just bind this to input handler.
So on input takes the input handler function.
And in case you don't remember the input handler function is coming from our custom form.
Look here it is.
So we can manage our file our picked image with our form hook as well because the form look our custom
form look does really not care about the data we're managing with it.
It doesn't have to be text data.
It can be a file as well.
We should just make sure that whenever we switch modes if we switch from sign up to log in we add a
image key and set this to undefined because when we switch from log into sign up we need to add a image
key and set this to an object where the value let's say is null initially not an empty string because
we're not working with strings here.
Later we'll store a file there after all and is valid is set to false.
And now this should be part of our general form validation and of our form data.
Now to confirm this in the off submit handler I will console log form state DOT inputs so that we can
see where our picked file is part of that or not.
And with this if we save all of that switch to site up again and enter a valid name valid email address
and a valid password we see the sign up button still is not enabled.
If I switch back log in it is but in sign up it is not because the image hasn't been picked yet.
Now if I open that picker and close it that's still not enough but if I now pick an image here like
this one you'll see this gets enabled and if a click here of course we get an error because we already
have a user with that email address.
At least I here in my set up already have such an error.
But from our log here in line 70 we see that we have the image and the value is indeed just such a file
and we can submit this file to the back and this will be something we have to work on this will be possible
though.
So picking the image works now before we ensure that we also can pick a image when we create a new place.
Why don't we work on the back end and make sure that there we accept such a file.