So back in our code again I got two windows one for the back end and one for the front then you can
see it on the top left corner.
And I want to start on the back and there I want to start by ensuring that we are generating such a
token.
But I actually want to start one step earlier when a new user signs up when we create a new user.
Right now we always stored a password as plaintext in the database and thus far this was OK because
we had no real authentication anyways.
But now I want to change that because we never ever should store passwords as plain text in the database.
Why.
Well if our database gets compromised by an intruder or by an employee who isn't happy.
So if someone gets access to our database and is able to extract data from there if the password is
stored in plain text this attacker has everything all the information it needs.
If the password instead is encrypt it.
So if it's a string which can't be decomposed to the original password then the attacker might still
have to email and the name which is bad enough but at least the attacker doesn't have the valid password.
So the data which can be extracted is less useful therefore we don't want to stored a password like
this but instead encrypted hash it before we store it.
And for that we can install a third party library with NPM installed dash dash safe in the name of that
library is be tripped.
J.S. This is a notorious library that helps us create secure passwords or not create passwords but hash
passwords which means encrypt them convert them to a unreadable string or to a string which can't be
reverse engineered to be precise.
So with that installed we can rerun NPM start and now in the user's controller.
I want to import does library.
So there I will import be tripped by requiring be tripped J.S. like this.
This library now helps us with hashing passwords.
So in the create user function and the sign up function here therefore we first of all still check if
we have a user.
That's fine.
But if we come to the conclusion that we can create a new user I don't want to create this password
but instead as I said such a hashed password now to generate this we can call B crypt and then there
we have a hash method to the hash method we pass in the password we want to hash and that is the password
we're extracting from the incoming request.
So the plain text password a little side note by the way of course data between the front end and the
server should be exchanged why are H2 G.P.S..
But data is something which you don't control here in this controller or on the front end but in the
end with the service you use for hosting your application.
So I assume that this is the case in production by the time we receive the password on the server side.
We of course automatically unpack it back to plain text but ideally it was transmitted while HBP yes.
So once we got the password here we pass it to hash and then hash all that takes a second argument which
is the so-called salt or the number of salting rounds.
Now here 12th is a good value.
And this simply influences the strength of the hash and how easy or hard it is to reverse engineer it
and with twelve salting rounds we should have a hash which can't be reverse engineered and which still
doesn't take hours to generate now hash then returns a promise.
So since we're already in a async function year thanks to async in front of our function parameters
we can of course await this generation and the result will be the hashed password here.
Now of course as always this could fail.
It shouldn't but it could.
So let's wrap it with try catch and catch any potential errors here.
And if we got an error here.
Well then I will create a new HP error and say could not create user.
Please try again and send back a 500 status code because this that is some kind of technical server
side error.
And then we can return this error with next year as we did it before so normally we should make it past
this try catch block though.
And then we have a hashed password.
Now when we create a new user we set the password key the password property of that user object to that
hashed password now and we don't store a plain text password Dale for.
But the hash password now was that we stored his hash password.
But of course the next question is how do we identify the user by the password then.
Because comparing passwords like this won't work anymore.
After all in the database we won't have to plaintext password so we can't compare it to password entered
by the user.
And if we did this if we're assured that we have the right password how do we generate this token.
These are the next questions we have to take care of.