To set up a basic node express application in the app J.S. file I will first of all import Express.
With that note J.S. specific import syntax where we require a package and and stored the imported content
the imported object in the end in this Express constant and I'll do the same here for the body password
because we'll also need that to past the body of incoming requests.
And with that imported we can create our app object by executing express as a function.
That is what you'll learn and you refresh your module and on that app object we can then bridge Mr.
middleware either generic middleware which triggers on all requests with the use function here with
the use method or middleware for specific h to be methods with get and post and patch and so on and
there we don't have to specify a filter path and they're offered a middleware function.
Once we're done with all the middleware and of course right now I haven't added any but once we have
added it we can call listen on the app object to listen on a certain port.
And here I will use port five thousand too darn well start my dial up and server on that port.
So on local host five thousand.
And with that it's now time to register middleware now which middleware do we need.
Obviously we want to use middleware body parser that ensures that we parse the request bodies of incoming
requests.
In addition however I also want to handle requests to different parts.
So I want to set up my routing so to say routing simply means that I want to listen for a certain age
to the p method path combinations and then run different code for every combination.
That is what I mean with the term routing.
I want to route certain requests to certain functions that should be executed upon those requests.
Now we can set up such a routing with APP get to handler get request to slash nothing for example but
it is a good practice to not do the routing here in this main aptly as file which would get Robert big
if you have a lot of routes but to outsource it into separate files and therefore here I will add a
new routes folder next to app J.S. and in there I will add two files.
The first file which I'll add is places routes start J.S. you can name the file however you want I just
name it Dash routes so that it's clear that this will contain some routing logic.
Of course you could argue that since this file isn't a rule it's folder that's already clear and we
could just name it places but since I'll have our files named places and other places of the app as
well I'll go for places routes here and also users routes.
J.S. now my idea is that in these files I set up the middleware or I register the middleware that is
responsible for handling routes regard it related to places and routes related to users.
To do that let's get started with a simple places route and fought it all now again.
Use Express here in this file so all again imported here and that's important by the way.
If you need express in more than one file you have to import it in every file where you use something
from the Express package.
So just because I import express here an app Chase already does not mean that it's automatically unlocked
in all our files.
No.
If we need something from Express and displaces Robert's file and we will need something from it here
then we have to import it here.
Now the question is what do I need from this express package.
I need a special feature a special tool and that's the router which we can access with Express dot router
which we execute like a function.
And that's important here.
I don't execute express itself as a function as I did it in the app J ust file but instead does a router
method with a capital R which exists on the imported express object.
This gives us a special object on which we can also register middleware which is filtered by HBP method
and path but the interesting thing is that we then can export our configured router by the end of this
file and imported an app J.S. and registered as entire configured router as one single middleware in
app class.
Now it becomes clear if we simply do that.
So here in router I will start by registering a route and let's say it's I get Rod for Slash nothing
for the moment we don't actually need this specific route and we can find two this later but for the
moment let's just register this.
We simply call get on the router.
It basically has the same like the app object when it comes to middleware we can use use to register
something on every request or post get patch and so on to register something on specific HP methods.
Then if we do pick a specific method we have to add a filter string here.
So simply the path by which we want to filter and then the function which should execute when a request
reaches this route.
So when we get a get request to slash nothing then we have our standard middleware function as we know
it with the free arguments request response and next and in there we can now run the logic we want to
run upon such a request.
And here I will just say get request in places like this sort of we can see a log in the console and
that's sent back a response.
And here the special thing is I'll not send back a response with send but instead here I want to send
back a response that contains Jason data.
You might remember that earlier in the course in the theory module I explained dad with a rest api we
would exchange data in the Jason format.
That means Dad we don't send back H to him Al or anything like that but instead does machine a human
readable data format.
EXPRESS J ust makes that easy.
We have a Jason method there on the response object.
The Jason method takes any data which can be converted to valid.
Jason So for example an object an array just a number just a boolean or just a string.
But here I'll go with an object and there simply add a message.
It works.
It's totally up to you which object you pass here with any properties of your choice here.
I just have one property the message Prop. 8 works.
So that's basically the data which will be encoded to this Jason format which will be attached to the
response which is then automatically sent back when we call Jason here.
So this sends back a response with some Jason data.
Now with that we registered this route.
Now that's in the roots file here.
However we need to kind of link this to the app J.S. file because ultimately when we run NPM start later
we will execute this app j ust file.
So we need to establish a connection between this file and d express app we're setting up here and the
routes we registered here and to do that we need to export our configured router from the places routes
JavaScript file and the export certain tax in no chars looks like this module dot exports equals router.
This simply means the thing which we export in this file is this router constant so days configured
router object and yet this is what we export in this places routes J ust file and now since we export
it here and only because we export it here we can go back to app US and import from our places Robert's
file.
We can not just import from default no chess modules or from third party libraries we could also import
from our own files and it is a good practice to have the third party libraries and Node core modules
at the top and then leave an empty line here and then add your own imports.
It's not technically required but considered a good coding practice.
So here I will get my places roots or however you want to call it by calling required and now not just
a name of your file but the relative path to the file.
So here from app J.S. we have to go into the roots folder and then target the places Robert's file so
it's not slash which means start at the current folder then roots which means go into the roots folder
and then places roots and you can omit the file extension it will automatically add that for you.
Now we have to configure a router which we export here in places roots in this places rule it's constant
in the app chars file and this now conveniently is simply a middleware we can use the router here as
a middleware.
That's a nice feature expressed today as offers so we can call app use and register places routes like
this and now it just means that our routes which we configured here are added as middleware in app J.S.
and this allows us to move the logic out of app s and keep that file lean and setup our plays related
routes here in the places Robert's file with that we have an app that should work.
So if we now run NPM start our node server starts up.
And if we now visit local host five thousand we see our Jason data here.
Now it gets printed as text here.
But if we open the browser developer tools and we go to network and reload this page here's our request.
And what you see is that you get a status code of 200 automatically.
That's the default status code express gives you on responses it sends back and you see in the response
header that the content type is set to application Jason express J ust does this because we use the
Jason method here.
It converts the data to Jason and sets the right headers.
And if we go through the response tap here you see that is the response that you've got back.
And this here is actually how Jason looks like properties are enclosed in double quotes and string values
are enclosed between double quotes as well.
So this works we're able to send back this simple data the simple response but of course we're not done.
This isn't even a road which we need instead we need other routes.
If we have a look at our planning slide here and in addition we also need users routes and we want to
make sure that we can reach both routes in both these files.
Of course we haven't set up and use those routes yet but we'll do so soon from our app jazz file.
We're also not passing any incoming requests bodies.
So that's all something we'll have to do.
So plenty of work left.
Let's continue with that in the next lectures.