So no sequel versus sequel.
What already differences.
And when should you use.
Which one.
So we got no sequel.
We got sequel and examples for no sequel databases would be of course Mongolia B which is what we are
using in this chorus or couch TV and for sequel we could name my sequel or Microsoft sequel.
Just to give you some examples here now no sequel databases do not enforce a strict data schema.
We talked about collections and documents already.
Tables and records in a sequel database and collections can contain documents with different schemas.
So you could have a basic schema for your documents you have but then for newer documents you could
change the schema and add an additional property to it for example.
This is possible with no sequel databases.
And this also makes it very flexible for sequel databases.
We enforce a strict data schema so if you define the tables and the corresponding records well you normally
don't deviate from that structure or deviating from the structure later would be a bit more difficult.
Therefore you should create your data schema and this is what you stick to it in a sequel database for
no sequel databases.
We also have less focus on relations a relation would be something that if you have a document with
the users in the document with the places then the users document could contain the police idea to refer
to displace or to establish a connection.
Now we can also do this in no sequel and we will do it throughout this course.
But generally the core focus of no sequel is again less strict and less focused on two such relations.
Again to make this whole story and clearing data structure a bit more flexible you could say for a sequel.
Well relations are a core feature.
You typically have one table with the users and one table of the corresponding products and then you
need a relation to kind of know which user bought which products.
And to summarize these points so far we can actually say that no sequel works with independent documents
or the documents are not necessarily related to each other for sequel databases.
Well the records are related.
That's again one of the core concepts behind the sequel database.
Actually these are some differences but when should you use which database now.
Well no SQL databases are great for locks orders or some chats or messages.
So generally whenever you have a high frequency of incoming information it should be stored or requested
because nautical databases are really fast and you can create your own queries quite easily.
Therefore these are typical application areas for no SQL databases SQL databases are either used for
shopping cards contracts or generally bigger social networks.
So these kind of applications not talking about these differences and these recommendations.
This is not a hard restriction here.
These are some general guidelines you can follow but you can always deviate from that depending on the
application that you want to build.
It can also happen that you have both types of databases inside your application.
So one specific area of your application in terms of analytical database the other one with a secret
database that's not too unusual actually in this course.
We use Mongo to be as the moon stick is a well quite cool combination of different technologies and
it's a lot of fun working with mom would be a mongoose later.
It allows us to quickly query data and to really interact in a nice and efficient way with the database.
But as I said this is no hard differentiation here but this is a mainstay course.
Therefore we will use Mongo to be here.
So that's the differentiation which we know sequel and sequel.
And before we then set up Hmong you know there was one last thing you have to cover because actually
if you have a front end we could actually directly connect this front and to our database.
Well that would be a really bad idea.
Let me tell you why.