Now to play around with note Trey has a little bit.
I prepared a brand new project here.
It's basically an empty folder which I opened with my I.T. visuals.
Did you code in there we're going to write some notorious code executed and understand how it works
now important for dad of course in case you haven't done so yet.
You need to install No.
Simply download and install the latest worm from notorious dot org.
It should automate as you pick the right operating system for you if not click on our downloads to choose
one manually.
Simply download the latest version.
Walk through the installer it just gives you and you can leave all the defaults there and hence by the
end of the installer.
Once he went through the entire process you will have no choice and a number tool NPM which stands for
node package manager installed on your system.
Now let's ignore that NPM tool for now and let's write some no chance code for that here.
I'll add a new file app J.S. you can name it however you want and in there we can write normal javascript
code we can for example create a constant user name and then console log that if we want to now important
this year users next gen javascript syntax I'm using constant let instead of wah.
And in general for all this course I will use modern javascript syntax.
Arrow functions D structuring spread operator and much more so in case you're not really familiar with
this modern javascript syntax you should definitely look into some dedicated resources which teach you
this modern syntax.
For example my accelerated iOS 6 javascript course or of course my javascript complete guide course
which teaches you everything about JavaScript including a little introduction to know.
Yes actually.
So we have this basic script here.
And if we now safeties filed we can execute this with node.
For that let's open the terminal here in this idea eats the normal terminal just integrated into the
idea.
And it's already navigated into this folder which is the convenient thing about it.
And there you can run node app J.S. the node command is available because you installed no trace on
your system and then would just type the file name including the extension of the file of the javascript
file we want to execute through node J.S. if you hit enter.
I see Max here and you should see whichever name you entered here is a user name because that is what
we do in this script.
Now it is noteworthy that if we tried to enter alert here and we execute this we would actually get
an error here.
We get an error that alert is not defined.
This is the thing I mentioned regarding some API is not being available.
The alert function which does exist in the browser environment does not exist and no chance.
This kind of makes sense because the alert function opens an alert in the browser.
Here we have no browser no checks has no built in functionality to open some window on your system.
That's not how it works.
So that's one of the API but you can't use anymore.
No worries there will be new APIs.
For example we can write to a file for this.
We need to import this file system functionality.
If you only works with browser side JavaScript and you haven't work with modern project setups there
which use bundling to combine multiple files.
You might not really know the concept of imports and exports in JavaScript.
You might simply worked with multiple script imports in your HDL files to import multiple scripts.
Well in no charge yes and also by the way later in react chess where we will have a build workflow which
supports bundling and splitting our code across multiple files.
We are able to import functionalities from file B into file a and we're able to export functionalities
so that we can use them in our files.
And this is important to understand.
Dead with the exception of some very few global functions.
Everything which you want to use in a file has to be imported before you can use it.
So for example here I want to write something to a file for that conveniently no trace has a couple
of built in core API I's just as the browser has a couple of built in core API is like the dorm API
for working with the file system.
No chars has the file system API.
We imported with the require function and that's important.
The required function is a function globally available in no chance one of the very few globally available
functions now required takes a string and that either is a relative path to one of your files where
you're exporting something or in case of the filesystem or other core baked in modules.
The name of that module in this case f s for file system.
This is a module which is available with the default installation of no chance.
You don't need to install it separately or anything like that.
Now require is a function which tells no chance that you want to import something from that file or
in this case this module you're pointing it now that something that object all functionalities then
is returned by the required function.
So we should store it in this case in a constant which will also name f S. though this name here is
up to you.
You could named it however you want.
Now we can use it as File System object to use a couple of methods which are built into this filesystem
module.
Note Charles offers to us specifically there is a right file method the right file method takes a path
to to file we want to write and then the data we want to write to that follow the path in its simplest
form can just be the file name and it will always be written into a location relative to the script
you're executing.
So here for example you could have user data Dot T X T to create a text file and it would create that
user data text file next to the app chars file.
Second argument is our data and there I will enter name plus user name so I'll just write a string as
data to that file.
Now with that there is a third argument we have to provide to write file and that's a callback a function
which will be called for you once this operation is done because right file like many functionality
is built into no chance is a asynchronous task which means it can take a bit longer especially if you're
writing or reading a lot of data and therefore no chance does not block the execution of the average
javascript code.
Instead it will outsource does longer taking task to the node j s environment which is able to use multi
threading ends on which javascript the language itself is not.
And it will call a function once it's done.
This function will get an error object which is null if no error occurred or which is not null.
If an error did occur so if error is trophy we know we have an error.
So in this case I just want to lock the error and otherwise I'll just log wrote file.
I'll return here so that we don't locked is in case you do have an error.
Now with that we have some valid javascript code which will run in the node environment and if we now
call node app chase again you'll see road fall here and you'll see the user data dot text file appear
here.
And if we look into that file we see name colon.
And then well the value we stored in user name.
So this is all the no notorious code using one of the API is which is only available in the note J S
environment and not in the browser environment.
Other than that our D special API is its regular javascript code and therefore everything you know about
JavaScript also applies to no trace code because it is JavaScript.
The only exception really is which API eyes you're able he was all the browser specific API is like
the dorm and so on are not available here.
Instead you have new API as.