We added our first simple route in a extra file failure to keep our aptly us file lean.
Now as I mentioned though this isn't even a road which we need.
We need to get roots in the places area but we need roots for a specific user I.D. or a specific place
I.D. we also need our roads like post patch in the lead.
So let's work on that now.
Let's also make sure that we only reach our places routes if the request starts with Slash API slash
places as indicated on that slide and not with Slash.
Nothing as it's currently the case because we all want to be able to use slash API slash users to later
reach our users routes.
So for that back in our application to make sure that we only make it to these places routes if the
request starts with Slash API slash places we have to add a filter here on this middleware in the app
J.S. file.
Now when using the U.S. method you don't have to add a path filter but you can then this filter will
also not be treated as.
This has to be the exact path filter but as a the path has to start with the specified path filter.
That means that here is a first argument we can add slash API slash places and express chars will now
only for award requests to our places routes middleware.
So to the routes configured here if their path starts with Slash API slash places it can be longer than
that so it can be slash API slash places slash something.
It will still be forwarded but for example just slash API slash.
Nothing would not be forwarded to places routes.
So with that if we change this we make sure that if we reload here this does not work anymore because
now our route here slash nothing actually has to be prepared with Slash API slash places and that's
all important.
The root filter you set up here is automatically added to the filter you have here.
So if you want to have requests which start with Slash API slash places you must not repeat that here.
Instead here you only add the path after that initial filter you have an app has already.
So here that simply means just API slash places slash.
Nothing should trigger dysfunction so here if we now enter API slash places we get our message again.
This works but of course whilst it's nice that this works this isn't really the logic we need here.
Instead if we have a look at our plan again we need to get root which has slashed users slash some user
I.D. in it or which just searches for a specific place I.D. and to practice dead.
Let's actually add constants here in places routes dummy places which will later in the course be replaced
by our database access in the end but here.
Let's just store some dummy places for the moment and every place could have an I.D. p one could have
a title for example Empire State Building could have a description one of the most famous sky scrapers
in the world.
Location which actually should be a nested object with a latitude and longitude.
And here I simply use Google Maps to search for that so I'll paste in the values you can simply use
Google maps and search for the Empire State Building to then find the latitude and longitude here in
the you or l the thing after D at is the latitude.
The thing after the Commodore after before the next comma is the longer etude.
So that's what I simply pasted in here then the address which I'll also simply paste from Google Maps
and a create or field which points at a fictional user I.D. because we have no real users at the moment.
You one which I would say is the user who created that place later of course we will have real users
and linked up models will have users connect the two places.
For now we'll just work with the dummy data.
So now we have a place which we could try to get by its I.D..
So I actually here I wont of a get request where the I.D. is part of the U R L.
So the idea is that we send the request to API slash places slash p 1 for example and this gives us
the data for the place with the IDP one so the I.D. should be encoded in the U R L.
That's a typical pattern you see in such API is in reality to tell expressed that we have a dynamic
segment which we don't know in advance because of course I can't say I want to load something for p
1 because later we'll have more places with different ideas.
So to tell expressed that we have a dynamic segment where we don't know the exact value in advance but
to where we want to be able to later use it in this middleware function and find a place by the concrete
value which was entered.
We add a colon here in our filter and then any identifier of our choice for example place I.D. or just
paid for place Heidi.
Now express Chase accepts this route here if I save this and I reload this you are L with places slash
p. 1.
We see we make it into this middleware function and that's great.
But now I also want to return that place with that I.D. which could mean nearly half here because I
added it as a dummy place for Dad we need to extract the concrete value that was entered for this concrete
request which reaches this function and express J as has got us covered with that too.
We can get the place idea by using the request object and there you will have a parent's property.
This is added by express J.S. the parents property Indian holds an object where your dynamic segments
here will exist as keys and the value will be the concrete value the user who sent the request entered.
So here we can access request parents thought pit and get the concrete I.D. that is encoded in the U
R L well and now we can search for a place with that I.D. and the dummy places array and add that to
the response we're sending back.
So here we can get our place by reaching out to dummy places and using the Find method which is a default
javascript array method.
It helps us find a specific element in an array find takes a function which we pass to it which will
be executed on every element India rate and the element that's currently looking at will be fed in to
the function as an argument.
So the place in this case which I'll just name P here and the argument to not clash with this constant
name then here in this fine function we have to return true if we're looking at the place which we want
to find.
So here I will return p dot I.D..
Equal place I.D. So I'm comparing the idea of the place I'm currently looking at and keep in mind dysfunction
year executes on all elements and does it right of course here we only have one but if we had more than
one it would execute on all of them and it will then return true if the idea of the place it's currently
looking at is equal to the idea that was part of our U.R.L. and then here instead of returning some
message I can return the place here in my response.
This syntax here by the way can always be shortened to this that is default JavaScript in the end means
that JavaScript automatically expands this to this if the name of the property is equal to the name
of the variable that holds the value you want to store in the property.
You can shorten it and with that if we now safeties and we reload this page you'll see indeed.
Here I get back.
That place data I get back that plays data because I entered a valid I.D..
If I for example would try to find the place with the IDP to which I don't have here in my dummy places
you would see I get back an empty object because there is no place which I found.
So there is no place added to this object of course in such a case where we didn't find a place we might
want to handle this error differently and return of 4 0 for error for example.
But we'll have a look at error handling a little later.
For now let's leave it as it is and instead work on a novel route.
Let's implement that get slash users slash colon you idea route here and that is actually a great practice
for a you will implement to gather in the next lecture.
But here it's your job to instead write a new route that is able to accept this dynamic you I.D. segment
extract that in the middle where function then and find a place where the creator has dead user I.D.
you learned everything you need for that in the last lectures.
So definitely try it on your own first before we then do it together in the next lecture.