So where do we create this document.
Well if you think about the operations that you're going to achieve here create read update and delete.
Then the first logical step to use the model is C Create.
Because if you can create the document then we can also have a look at reading it updating it or deleting
it.
So we want to create a new place and this can of course be done here in our places controller.
Here we have the dummy places we won't use these at the end of this module of course.
And if we go down a bit we have our trade place constant.
This is what we should focus on now as we want to use our newly created place model though we first
have to import it for that appear in the import place again with a capital P as this would be a constructor
function.
And this requires our models places file with that we can use the place model.
And if we go down a bit here here it is our creative place constant the previous code is fine.
So here we have some validation.
And here we have the coordinates that we get with our chief coding logic.
So we don't have to change this but here our created place logic.
This has to be updated.
So let's get rid of this code here and let's first instantiate our place constructor here with new place.
And now we have a new javascript object.
And here we can all add data to our model what our model needs still it's already predefined by our
schema.
So we have title description image and so on.
Because of that we can get started with the title once again I'll again use this shorter syntax here.
So title title is what I wrote right here.
We need the description the address we need to location with corresponding coordinates and we need an
image.
And as I said before the image should be a U R L so no real file later in this course in the file upload
module.
We learn how we can store images on our server not on the Mongo DP servers and under the database but
on our back and server then that's your elbow point towards of Hull stored on our server.
Here I'll just take dummy your l from a file in the Internet.
Make sure to store this As String.
Don't forget the comma.
And with that we only need our Creator here as I said we will use a dummy idea.
Don't forget to add to see me colon.
And with that we created our model already.
As I said very important make sure that the properties here in our model are the same that we have here
in our schema.
Otherwise well this will throw an error not talking about errors.
This brings us to this push logic here.
This is not valid anymore because we have a different method we can use here found and create the place
constant now with the model logic with our place model.
The logic here is created place dot safe dot safe is a method available in Mongoose and safe will handle
all these Mongo D.B. code you need to store a new document in your database in your collection and additionally
safe will also create that unique places ideas.
I talked about previously safe is also promise.
This means we have an asynchronous task again as we saw with the connect method before saving files
to our database can take a few moments.
Therefore asynchronous task right here.
And as we already have async appear now I will create place constant.
We can now add a weight here and to make sure we catch any errors.
Let's also add try catch to make sure we are covered in case anything goes wrong which hopefully won't
be the case so we will catch our error here and create a new error constant with our new HP error.
We used already and the error message could be something like creating place failed.
Please try again and an error code of 500 here.
With that we're almost done.
There is one thing missing though and this is return next error.
We have to at this year or we should add this year to stop our code execution in case we have an error.
If we don't add return next year the code execution would continue.
Even if we throw an error definite enough we want better.
Therefore important to add this too.
With that we are actually done.
So if we now start our sorrow once again and go to postmen create a new request.
This should be a post request targeting HDP local host 5000 slash API slash places as we want to create
a new place.
Then we go to Body raw and Jason and now we have to add all the properties that would you find in our
model.
So this was first the title which is the Empire State Building may be a description a very famous building
in New York.
We need to address which we can and get via google maps here.
We don't do location.
It's automatically retrieved by our geo coding logic.
Same thing is true for the image we hardcoded that when we instantiate the place.
This means we only need to add our Creator and this could be you to maybe.
So let's see if we now could sent here yeah.
This looks good.
So we create that place apparently.
Here you can see the unique I.D. that was created automatically.
We have an underscore in front of the idea.
We'll tackle that later but generally this looks fine.
Let's also see what happens if we go to our database now here.
If you click onto collections that looks good by the way here we have two places.
The first place is the database name.
The second is the name of the collection.
So places.
Here is what we specified in AB.
Yes.
Right here in you collect connect method places and the collection name is here in place J is right
here.
Our place in the model method without the capital P and a plural.
So that's basically the name of this collection here.
And more importantly inside this collection we can now find one document.
And if you look at the ending of T I d.
It's B6 and that's exactly the document we created right here.
With that we achieved a lot already.
We were able to create the schema to create the model and to create our document in our database.
So C Create from our CRUD operations is completed.
Let us not continue with the R read so we'll have a look at our get requests.
Now.