Now we have an idea of how our application should roughly look like which data are we going to work
with.
Well there are two main entities we heard over and over again in the last lectures.
We have users in his application and of course we have places.
Now it's up to you which exact data you want to have on your user model and which exact data you want
to have stored in your places.
For me in this demo application I came up with I want to have users who have four key fields or attributes
every user should have a name and email address a password and also an image now name and image are
optional we'll definitely need email and password in order to implement authentication which of course
requires that email password combination.
Now for the places it's all up to you but dear I want to have a title and a description for every place
a human readable address.
So basically street name city name location which is a pair of coordinates latitude and longitude and
also at image.
Now besides these two standalone entities it's important to understand that of course they are related
every user can create multiple places and therefore owns multiple places.
And on the other hand every place belongs to exactly one user.
So implementing this relation and updating it correctly will all be a part of the application we're
going to build.
So we know about our data and how to front end should look like before we plan the different routes.
We want to have on the front end and which pages we need there.
Let's have a look at the back end which API endpoints will we probably need their well since we have
two main data models here.
User and place I got two main end point areas.
Let's say we want to accept requests which reach our back end domain dot com slash API slash users.
And then there are a couple of specific routes which all start with API users specifically slash nothing.
If a get request reaches our back end domain slash API slash users slash nothing else then I want to
return a list of all users we'll need that for the page where we display all users and the number of
places they created.
If we send a post request to slash API slash user slash sign up then I expect to have data attached
which allows us to create a new user.
And then after this creation succeeded all the automatically locked the user in and you will learn what
logging users in means in the context of a Marine app in the authentication module.
When we send a post request to slash log in we'll just log the user in.
So I expect to have a password and email attached to that request and then we'll skip the creation part
because we assume this user already was created.
We just try to lock the user in.
So these are our a user related routes but of course we also have places.
So let's say for requests which reach our domain slash API slash places slash user slash you I.D. if
that's a get request then I want to retrieve a list of all places for that given user I.D..
So the idea here simply is that we are able to get all the specific places a user created.
If we get a get request to just API slash places slash some place I.D. then I want to get that specific
place by that idea.
And important both you I.D. and P I.D. which have this colon in front of them are dynamic segments.
So what exactly is part of the you or L here is up to the front end.
This will be interpreted as a user I.D. or a place I.D. though now if we send a post request to just
API slash places slash nothing then I want to create a new place and I expect that the data which is
needed to create a new place is attached to that request.
If we send a patch request to slash API slash places slash some place ideas then we want to update that
place by its ideas.
This request will carry data in its request body as well.
It needs to carry the data which we need for updating the place namely the new title and the new description.
And of course updating is nice but sometimes we also want to delete a place and deal for our walls and
want to have a delete route where we accept a DELETE request targeted at API slash places slash some
place ideas which will well delete that place by its ideas.
These are the end points we need.
We have all the crud operations in there we have off indication in there and we will build them out
step by step for this course.
Now let's have a look at the front end.
We already sketched it out but now let's plan the specific page components we need their.