The disk storage is important for storing of files correctly but of course we also want to validate
that we don't get a invalid file.
Of course we also have some validation on the front end already.
Because in my image upload component I already have to accept attributes set on the input but you learned
that on the front and everything can be hacked or simply changed by the user with the developer tools
for example.
So we can't rely on front end validation.
We don't do that for our other fields and we shouldn't do it for our files.
So on the back end I will add a file filter here.
This is a function which receives a request object to file and then also a callback which of course
is the same pattern you already saw there.
Now here we have to call this callback.
Even with an error if validation failed as a first argument or with null as a first argument if it succeeded.
So Dan for first of all I will add a constant is valid and then check in my mind type map if I can find
the file MIME type here.
So this year will retrieve PMG j peg or j pick if I have one of these MIME types.
If I have another MIME type it won't find an entry year and day Fred will return on the find.
So now if the double bang operator in front of this we convert undefined or now to false and we convert
one of these findings here to true.
So now we have either true or false.
However not here but here of course.
So now we have either true or false stored and is valid
now next.
We can create our error here and there.
I will basically check if is valid is true and if that's the case I will set this to now because then
we have no error but if is valid is false so if we have some invalid upload then I will set this to
a new error where I say invalid MIME type like this
and then we can forward our error.
And the second argument is a boolean debt basically informs Malta if we accept the file or not and here
I can forward is valid because if that's true we form our true.
We accept the file.
Otherwise we don't.
Though if you pass an error and that is a real error you already deny the file.
So adding a Wrong file should now not be possible.
This is the finished configuration of Malta and with Dad we should be prepared to accept and store files
with this.
We can save it is we are applying this middleware to our sign up route.
Now we need to head back to the front end and of course all the restart our back in server but then
head back to the front end to make sure that we send the right type of data to that back and to that
sign up route and include a file in our HDP request.