So we saw no Jesus and that it can be a bit cumbersome to work with no Che is only what is expressed
chase then express jazz is a framework for no jazz.
So that means we use no jazz.
We write JavaScript code in the node environment but express makes certain things easier just as react
which by definition is a library and not a framework.
But it's pretty close to each other just like react makes things easier in the browser where angular
or view or other libraries or frameworks in the browser.
The idea behind a framework always is to give you a lot of utility functions and methods and things
that allow you to focus on your core business logic and not so much on reinventing the wheel and building
all these core primitives or doing all these primitive tasks like passing data again.
So it makes building Web apps server side code in decades of no charge is much easier.
And one thing that is specific about express or specific Q express is that it's middleware focused which
won't tell you much right now but by the end of this module it will.
So let's add Express.
Asked to our simple application here and see how that simplifies things.