Express is a library for no chase and thus far we have a note project where we're only able to use node
core modules to add third party library.
We need to convert this to.
You could say manage project for this let me quit D server here and now let's use NPM a tool which was
all installed to gather with node J.S. NPM stands for node.
Package manager and indeed it is a tool for managing packages for node applications.
So for adding third party libraries you could say actually you will later see in the course that we
don't just use it in node apps.
We can all use it in front of the apps and the reactive but for the moment let's focus on Node now to
use NPM to install packages here.
We first of all need to convert this year to a managed project and we do so by running NPM in it.
Now we're ask a couple of questions with that and you can simply hit Enter everywhere to just confirm
this and once you're done with all these questions you get a package done.
Jason File does hold some general configuration which is all fine but more importantly dismal store
all dependencies.
We will install and to install a dependency in this project folder we run npm install then the name
of the dependency in our case Express is the name just expressed like this and then also here dash dash
save.
This will tell NPM which kind of dependency does this dash dash save for core app dependency which we
use in our application code or dash dash save Dash.
Def if it's a development only dependency so some tool which helps us during development but which we
don't need thereafter.
So here it stashed Ash safe because Express will make up a core part of our application.
And here I actually get an error that I can't install a package under a package which is already named
Express and indeed here the name was express let's renamed as to node express in the package.
Jason File and repeat does npm install command.
And now it will go ahead and add this Express dependency to this project to be precise it will do two
things.
It added this dependencies enter here and packaged up Jason and added the node modules folder in that
folder you'll find the Express package under E but you'll also find a lot of other packages.
These are dependencies of Express and dependencies of dependencies.
Notice folder can get quite big so whenever you share your project with someone else it's quite common
to actually delete the node modules folder so that only your code falls out there.
And now to recreate it because you have these entries and package stored Jason you can just run npm
install and it will go ahead and install all the dependencies with the words that are mentioned here
into your folder.
It will recreate the node modules folder data for here at this.
So now we get express installed.
How can we utilize Express.
Well we can utilize express to simplify it.
This is listening to incoming requests and doing different things for different types of requests because
besides parsing that data which is cumbersome it's also cumbersome that we have to check the method
like this.
If we have more and more methods and even more and more different you are L's which we want to check
we have to add more and more if statements to the single request listener which we have not ideal.
So let's actually get rid of all that so that we have an empty ashtray as polygon.
And let's use Express for that here I require Express just as before I just specified a name here.
This is not a core module but the installed module I required by the name of the module in this case
Express.
And now this thing which we get here and express constant turns out to be a function.
You'll learn things like Dad and the official docs of packages in this case and the official box of
Express.
This function will give give us app object so we'll call express as a function and store the result
which is a reg object full of functionalities and features in this app.
Constant one feature which you have here is again a listen method.
So here I will again specify a port five thousand.
What we don't have to do here is call create server.
Express will do that under the hood and basically expose that server object enriched with a lot of other
functionalities on this app which I'm storing here.
So now with that we could execute the file again and have a running server but of course one which doesn't
do much now to handle our get root when I just enter low close 5000 like this which currently is not
supported because I have no roots or no supported requests at all here to handle that we have to register
as so-called middleware here and express chase because Express has one core philosophy which is basically
that every incoming request is funneled through a bunch of middleware functions normal functions in
the end which are able to get data out of the request or manipulate the request even and also manipulate
the response and eventually send it back.
That's the idea behind express you have a bunch of functions which can be called on incoming requests
and every function can do something with this incoming requests or with this response which is about
to be sent.
You can only send one response per request though.
Now Middleware is registered by calling the use method on app use is a method provided by the Express
library on this apt object.
In its simplest form this takes a function of function.
Here I'm using a general function which takes free parameters a request object which is the incoming
request.
Basically I object similar to what we got with vanilla notorious but it is an object enriched with some
extra data.
A response object although similar to what we had in the plain vanilla note app but again enriched with
extra functionalities.
And the third parameter is a new one.
This is a next function which you call if you don't want to send the response it is middleware but instead
you want to forward the request to the next middleware in line.
If you're not calling next then any middleware after dissimilar where if we had more than one will not
be reached by this request.
So you should always call next unless you are in the middle where where you want to send back a response
since you may only send one response anyways.
There is no need to execute any other Middleware is there after so here we could create a middleware
which sends back a response and here we have a send method actually where we can have our body where
I now again want to render that forum.
So on that forum where that method of post and then in there where the input of type text with a name
of user name and we had a button opening and closing tags where we had create user and that button was
of type.
Submit that's the setup we had before.
Now we have it again with that if we now save this and we execute this file again and I go to locals
5000 again we see that firm which is great.
Now that forum is of course nice to have but it would also be nice if we now could do something useful
with the post request for that.
Let's add another middleware a middleware which is also reached and I will copy that middleware function
and for the moment I'll just console log middleware here and then call next.
So that this middleware does not send back a response but does something in this case just log something
and then forwards the request to the next middleware in line.
Let's restart the server by quitting it and restarting.
And if we now centers request again you will see middleware here by the way.
You could also see this twice here if the browser is by default also requesting fav icon which my browser
is not here at this point.
Then this fav I can request would also go for the middle where you can just ignore it otherwise you
will just see one middleware log here.
So now we have that extra middleware but this doesn't do anything.
Well what could we do in here.
We could parse our request body for that.
We could bring back what we had before our on listener where we get our chunks of data.
Then here we have the body which is an empty string initially.
Then we basically append our chunks of data there and we also have the end listener here which executes
when we are done passing the incoming requests body and in later I can get my user name by calling bodies
split on the equals sign and extracting the second element.
And now I want to add a request body field and I'll do this just with the dot notation on the request
object all dynamically add a body property and set this to an object where I set the name key to my
extract that the user name and the year after I call next.
Please note that I call next instead of the end handler.
So did we only commence to the next middleware if we're done passing to incoming requests data and not
earlier.
So now we go on to the next middleware in line and in that next middleware the request bodies should
be available.
So in that second middleware let's check if request body is a thing if that is set and if it is set
I will return response send returns so that the code thereafter doesn't execute because I either one
or sent this response or sent that.
Alternatively we could wrap this into a else block but we don't need to do that if we simply return
here and here I want to have my age one tag then output request body dot name dot name is the property
where I'm storing the user name and then Carlos De age 1 tech if we do this let's restart the server
go to this page again hit enter and get undefined so that does not work why does it not work.
Because I'm always setting request body even if we're handling a normal get request which has no attached
data this end event listener will fire so request body will always be set and this case just to an object
where name holds undefined as a value so I will tweak this and check if user name is a thing if this
is true for you and only said request body if it is a thing now let's restart again hit enter again
and we see the form let's enter menu create a user and we see that here.
So now we're doing the same as before but with express some things maybe got a bit easier but overall
we didn't gain much mostly because we still manually have to pass the data here right and we still need
to check to see which kind of response we want to send.
So these are two things we want to improve and actually there is a third thing.
Always having to restart that server that's annoying.
Let's get rid of that to.