And with that we're almost done with the theory.
No there's just one more thing left and that is related to how we host our different parts.
You know from the big picture that we have three big blocks that react app the node express app and
the Hmong would be database and the server that database runs on.
Now the question is Where are the different pieces surfed from.
Now we got two main options here.
We can have one server one computer which hosts both our node API and the react single page application
under the same domain.
So my page dot com slash nothing might return our single page application and then under my page dot
com slash API we might have to end points for that single page application to talk to.
The alternative is that we have to separate ad servers.
One very simple server which simply serves our a single react J.S. application H HTML page and all the
JavaScript files.
That application needs and one server which hosts our API so if we take a closer look for the left case
that we have one single server we have a note express API which handles incoming requests on that server
for example under a slash API.
Any requests targeting these pops might reach our API and requests which are not targeting our API routes
would return to react single page application in the end.
So these requests would get us a single H2 mail file and the associated JavaScript files that are required
to run the react app between the reactive and a note API.
Even though they're running on the same server we have that separation learned about so don't know much
about each other.
Other than that they run on the same server.
Data is still exchanged with these Ajax background requests in Jason format.
We have to separate its servers.
Then we really have two different machines one which has our node API on it.
Our node express API and one which is served from that very simple so-called static host is static because
it will be a server which doesn't need to execute any service site code because it is a server that
doesn't run any node or any other programming language application on it.
Instead it's just a server which returns our H2 mail file and JavaScript files and to see us as follows
and so on.
So therefore we got our two ends served on different servers and data is exchanged and Jason format
when we sent these background HDP requests.
So that's always the same.
In one case they're just surf from the same machine in the other case from two machines.
In both cases we got these logically separated apps.
Now regarding the Hmong would you be database that always has its own database server but just like
the node server and the react app this server could be installed on the same physical machine as our
node and maybe all the react that runs on or on a separate machine and often you want to use different
machines here to make sure that just because you're getting a lot of requests you're not slowing down
on your database requests or database queries and the other way around.
So therefore separating the node express app and the database server onto two different machines is
a good idea.
Technically you could run everything on the same machine.
You'll always have the same logical separation though.
No actually there also is a third way which I really don't want to talk too much about though.
You could have your node express server and not build arrest or graphical API there but instead render
H HTML pages on the fly on that server with templating engines like E.J. s or POC.
If you took my no chance to complete guide course you'll learn about this approach as well.
Now you damn for really rendered different age to male pages for different requests on the server and
that rendered H2 Mal code is returned now to get react into the equation.
You could have some parts of D pre rendered H.M. pages which are controlled by react in a widget like
way so react only controls parts of page instead of the entire page.
This is possible but it takes away from the great highly reactive user experience.
We can build with single page applications since we create and return H to model pages from the server
for everything the user does.
We constantly reload pages we add a slight delay and we don't have that highly reactive mobile app like
feeling we can achieve with single page applications.
Therefore it is not the approach we will use here.
Technically of course though you could build an application with the same technologies Hmong wouldn't
be expressed react and note so merged with this approach but you would not get the same great user experience
and differ typically when we talk about learn we talk about the logically separated ends no matter if
they're served by the same physical machine or not.
We don't talk about this approach well and with that all out of the way let's have a look at the very
simple first moon application so that you can see the big picture.
Also in code before we den dive into the different course modules where we will get a refresher on react
node express among would you be and then more importantly build the different building blocks of our
course project which is such a moron app and then also connect these building blocks.