So we're sending a sign up request and that's great.
And we got many of our requests to send.
But before we do so let's actually improve our setup here a little bit at the moment we're sending this
request but there are two things which I'm not liking for one we're not letting the user know that something
is happening.
Now of course our application here is super super fast because it's all running locally on our machine.
So the moment we press log in or sign up here the request gets sent and it only takes milliseconds to
complete.
This will probably take a bit longer.
Once you really deployed this to a real server and the distance between the user and your code is a
bit further.
So it would be nice to show some loading spinner some indicator to the user that something is happening
in addition to that.
What if an error occurs.
For example if I switched to sign up here and I hacked myself into a wrong form submission by inspecting
my content and then manually removing the disabled attribute.
Now the button is enabled and any user can do that.
Of course this is not a security issue.
You're only hacking yourself but if you do that nonetheless you are able to for example enter invalid
data here.
So if I re enabled this I can press sign up here and of course we do get back in error.
We can see it here and to lock our back and validation works and this is the reason why we do half back
and validation by the way because front and validation can be disabled by the user.
But still it's not a great user experience that it still continues and we show no error message the
same by the way if we would try to sign up with a user who already exists in that scenario we also don't
really handle an error.
So on the back end we got some security mechanisms in place for signing up or validating input and in
the sign up controller when we create a user we all do check whether that user already exists.
But at the moment we're not really taking advantage of this on the front and we're not giving the user
a great feedback.
Never for a loading state nor for an error state.
So let's change both now and to change both in my off page on the front and I in the end want a handle
well two different states the loading and the error state.
So here we already import use state.
And with that we can set up new states here in our off function or off component we have let's say is
loading and set is loading here.
And initially we're not loading so I start in a false state and I also have an error and let's say a
set error or state and function here.
And initially we have no error.
So does this on the find.
Now we can use these two states to kind of update our UI.
So here when we start sending the request before we send it I of course want a set is loading to true
for example because now I am loading and I want do you I to read render HERE SINCE THIS HERE IS A async
function and they offer all wrapped in a promise.
React will all the go ahead and immediately update the UI and not batch multiple state updates for example
state updates that come later together.
Instead it will do this right away because it detects that this is a synchronous and there will be some
time between this State Update and potential future state updates.
So here I set is loading to true.
Now we can all of course set our error to null here and make sure it is reset but we don't really need
to do that.
We should handle that differently.
So let's just set this loading to true.
Now once we got our response I of course want to set is loading two faults again and no matter if we
got a response or an error or loading is definitely done.
So at this point here I want to set is loading two faults.
Now if we do have an error however I want to call set error and set this to let's say error message
it's up to you what you want here if you want to set this to a more complex object or if your error
should really just be a message which you expect to get here we can also provide a fallback in case
a message property does not exist where we just say something went wrong please try again.
We shouldn't we need that though because on the back end we already have error handling in place which
always in the end gives us a fallback error message nonetheless this thousand hurt so we now get this
set up here and we're ever setting our error a state or we're setting the loading state.
Now this log anything.
I only want to call off the log in if we didn't have an error.
So only here in the tri block and therefore I actually want to set as loading two falls here and here
separately.
Otherwise I would set it to false.
After we already changed the context and probably redirect it.
So make sure to first clear your local state on this page before you trigger something that might change
the component that's loaded.
Otherwise we might be updating a state on a component which is not on the screen anymore.
So now we have a loading state and we have some error state.
Now of course we want to take advantage of these new states and for that attached you find two new components
in the components zip file which you can drag and drop into your components UI elements folder.
That's the loading spinner and the error modal the loading spinner also has its own C as s fault the
error model doesn't.
Now these are components which do just what the names imply.
They render a loading spinner or they utilize our existing modal.
So make sure this import path fits your structure and it points of your modal component file.
So they render a modal which shows an error message or a loading spinner.
Now with these add it back in off page and the off component here let's import those components.
So I will import the air or modal here from shared components UI elements air or modal.
And of course do the same for the loading spinner which I import from shared components UI elements
loading spinner these two new components help us use our new states were managing the is loading and
the error state let's maybe start with the is loading state here inside of this cart I will add a dynamic
element where I check is loading and if this is true I want to render the loading spinner and later
important add the as overlay prop just like this you could set it to true but this is not required it's
true by default if you added like this and this in the end will just impact how exactly does loading
spinner is loaded you can check out the loading spinner logic and see as s styles to understand what
exactly this does and with that if we save this let's give it a try.
Let's go back here switch to sign up and Andrew of some credentials here click on sign up and now we
see a loading spinner and we are redirected.
Please also note however that I actually got an error here so I don't want to be redirected.
I got an error and still I was redirected.
Now that's something we'll have to handle in the next lecture.
We're not showing our error modal but even worse than that we were redirected as I just said and this
is definitely not what we want.