So back to the front and they are we pick a file and then the off page.
It's part of our foreign data as we confirmed.
Now we need to attach to the outgoing request and now we need to do something interesting here.
We need to send different type of data thus far.
We always send Jason data now sending Jason data still is correct if we're logging in because then we
only submit text data email and password and important when I say text data I mean all data which in
the end could write like this in javascript code so including arrays and objects.
Anything we can read as a human.
Now for images that's different images are binary data.
We can't write an image like this year.
Right.
So therefore we can't use Jason as a format.
Instead we wanted was a better data format and that would be form data a format which is already built
into the browser and into javascript.
Thankfully we can create new form data like this.
It's a browser API.
So it's a way lable just like this we don't need to install any third party package for this and we
can store it as form data in a constant.
Now to does form data object we can append new data and the cool thing is on form data.
You can add both normal text data so things like to email the name or the password but you can also
add binary data so files.
So here I will append email you first as a first argument need to specify an identifier then as a second
argument the value for this identifier.
So in this case of course form state inputs email values what we have and Jason down there as well.
Now we can replicate this two times to do the same for the name and of course refer to foreign state
inputs named order value and then hear the password and refer to formatted inputs password dot value.
This is the data we submitted before as well.
So for this we wouldn't need foreign data but now we can add or append to be precise our image and this
should have a key of image because on the back end if you remember I'm looking for this image key here
with this line I'm looking for a request body Key Named image which includes my image and we set up
this request body key with this line in the end because we'll append form data as our request body in
just a second.
So this has to be image here but other than dads of course form this data inputs image not value because
we are managing this image file in our regular form state so now we can find you at our request instead
of sending Jason stringing fi data.
So instead of sending Chase and data here we just add our form data and the cool thing about form data
is that the fetch API which we use under the hood and send request automatically adds the right headers
so we don't need to set headers manually anymore.
Instead it should just work like this and this should send the request with form data which includes
all our old data but now also our image
now back on the back end.
Our controller our users controller and they are create user might not fully work yet.
We'll see if this extra action here still works.
Now that we're not sending Jason data anymore we're also not using the file here by the way we're storing
it on disk.
But then here we're not storing a pointer added in the database or anything like that.
So I'll come back to this as well.
But for the moment let's just save this and see if does upload process in general works safe to front
end as well and then go back to the react app switch to sign up and let's try creating a new user pick
an image and of course also pick you are L.
For now it does can all be a used one and click sign up.
Now we get user exists already but if we go to the back end we also see that an uploads images we should
have a new file and this is the image which just was uploaded so the upload works.
You'll also see of course that this means that despite our validation failing the file was saved.
And the reason for that is that when the validation fails that of course means that we in the end throw
an error here in the user's controller here.
Here we're checking whether we have validation errors now by the time we reached this code.
Of course all our Middleware is executed.
So to file indeed was stored.
So if you want to undo that storage we'll have to roll it back manually.
And in general in a controller we're not doing anything with the file that will be the next step.
But what we can see here already is that the general upload and using foreign data works.
Now let's just make sure that we also do something with the file here in sign up.