Time to update our places now in the great thing now is that we actually learned all the core concepts
we need to do so therefore this should be an easy task now.
Let's do it together though.
So update places as before our first caught here with our error check can be kept.
This is fine.
The same thing is true for the properties here that we want to get from our request body.
Parents can also be kept.
But this part here with dummy places this has to be replaced.
Now as we have real data in our database now the update logic right here.
Well we'll have a look at that in a few seconds.
And what I can see right here is this dummy place should of course also be delete it now.
So how do we start.
Well Indiana updating a place simply means that we want to get the place by the police idea and then
update the title and the description.
Now as I'm talking about finding the place Spidey place idea we can again use our fine by I.D. method
we had up here for to get police I.D. constant.
This also means that we will use the same try catch block again.
Therefore we can from the start use the same logic in the enviornment here.
So we will implement it try catch block from the beginning now though.
So let's go down and let's not say that we again have our place variable here let this time not a concert
as we start with our try catch block inside try.
We have our place once again which we use right here which we just defined and place should be equal
to place dot find by I.D..
That's the same logic we just saw.
And what did it that you want to find.
Well that's of course our place I.D. here.
This one updating places once again is an asynchronous task.
Therefore don't forget to add a sync up here and a weight down there.
With that we have to catch any error.
Case here.
If we have an error let's again stored in a constant here should be equal to the new HDB error.
And there should state something went wrong.
Could not update police error code would again be five hundred and we should not forget to add return
next.
Error here.
So this looks final already.
With that we have to change.
Updated place to place down here as we refer to place up here.
Therefore we can also use place when it comes to updating the title and the description and what is
missing now.
Well storing the updated place of course at the moment you're just sending back a response which you
also have to adjust.
But we also have to make sure that the updated information is stored again in our database for that
we can again use the safe method which you also used before when we created the place.
And as we know safe is an asynchronous task therefore we will again use try catch and now await our
place safe method to safe this updated place.
And in case we have an error we'll again catch it you'll see it's kind of the same process we have here
for all these tasks.
And here we can say something went wrong
could not update place and again a 500 error code and also don't forget to return next arrow down here
to make sure the code execution is interrupted.
What's missing here.
Well we should again convert our Mongoose object to a normal javascript object and we should get rid
of our underscore ideas of the underscore of the eddy property to be more precise right here.
For that we will refer to place dot to object.
Here we can use this method directly as we are not having an error here as we had it before when we
were getting the place by the user I.D..
And now we can set getters to rue that save this.
And let's not see what happens if we want to update the please for that I'll create a new request right
here.
This time it will be a petty request to age to DP local host
not user places slash the idea of our place so let's take the idea down here
and it's pasted.
Now we need to go to body.
Raul and Jason once again.
Now we have to add the title and the description that we want to change.
For that let's say the title should be the Empire State Building.
Before we had Empire State Building.
And that is Rob junior should be.
Well what do we have at the moment.
Here we have a very famous building.
Let's say
a great building like this.
So we have the two properties so if we sent the pets requests now we can see that it was successful
and we have the title.
The Empire State Building and the description was also changed to a great building.
So this also works fine now.
Let's not also have a look at our database and as you can see we also have the Empire State Building
and a great building.
So our database was also updated successfully.
With that we have create read update.
What's missing now is deleting documents in our database.