So let's finally get to the point where we can see the real advantage of Express.
Before we do that let's make sure we don't always have to manually quit the server and restart it for
that quick add one last time.
And now let's install a new library with npm install and that is Node 1 installed with dash dash save
dash death because this will be a development only library will not use it in our code but to simplify
our development flow our development process because node one is a tool powered by node chess which
actually will execute JavaScript files with node J.S. but it will not just execute them but also watch
them watch all files in the project folder and whenever any file changes it will restart the server
automatically.
So whenever we save a file with changes in it it will restart the server for that we need to use Node
1 to run our capture has fallen for Dad in turn we can go to package Doug Jason and use a so-called
script scripts are simply Walt's short utility scripts we can execute and here we can add a start script
and the names should be start and then for example execute node app J.S. with that if I run NPM start
I execute this script by the way start is a special name if the script would be named differently for
example def you would have to run NPM run death only for a start and test you can omit the run keyword
and directly run test or in our case start now if we do that then this code here will execute.
So in this case node aptly s which is the same as before.
Now that's not what I want here instead here.
Let's quit that server and use node Mun node monsters package we just installed.
And this is available as an executable inside of this project.
It's not available globally on your machine executing Node 1 there most likely will fail unless you
install it globally before but inside of these scripts.
Any dependency here which is executable script or executable tool will be available.
So now if we save this package does Jason File with that change made if we execute NPM start again this
will use node man we see a more colorful output there and in the end this executes aptly s which is
great but now you will see that if I change something for example year on this response I add user a
colon as extra text and I had say if you see this restarts and hence here we see that change in action
without some manually quitting and restarting the server which of course is great.
So that's a little convenience added leave that process running.
You can always quitted with control C once are done for today and with that let's actually focus on
our logic here because now I want to make sure that I actually am able to parse the incoming requests
in a more comfortable way that we don't have to manually parse it for it is I'll install a new package
and here I will quit the server just to install the new package which will not do all the time and this
package is named body dash parser installed with dash dash save because this will now be a package which
we use actively in our code and thereafter on NPM start again to start node 1 again.
Now this is a package which I import here under a body parser you can name the content however you want
from body parts that are into app J.S. body parser gives us ready to use middleware is which we can
use and express apps to parse incoming request bodies it allows us to get rid of all that killed in
our first middleware and instead of writing our own function here we can write body parser dot J said
or dot you are L encoded dot Jason will become important later this will allow us to automatically pass
all incoming requests for Jason data here I will get a regular form data which the browser generates
for me when I click this happen been button and since here I will use you are L encoded to that you
need to pass an object to configure it and said extend it to false here in this case.
Now this will parse all incoming requests and try to extract any data which is in your body if it's
of type you are L encoded data which will be the case for such a submitted form it will also call next
for us so it will also automatically move on to middle whereas after this.
Now in addition I now want to handle a post request in a specific middleware and for dad instead of
using use which allows us to register a middleware that runs on all incoming requests I will use post
which allows me to register a middleware which only triggers on incoming post requests so where the
age the P word is post then here I want to have my middleware function with request response and next
and in there I want to return this response.
Now I also don't need to return it anymore because there is no code there all author which I would want
to skip.
We can now get rid of that if statement request body will exist by the way because the body parts are
automatically creates and populates such a field on the request object.
However the user name will be available under the name we picked here on the input.
So there I picked user name.
So I have to use user name here as well now that our middleware here also shouldn't trigger on all requests.
But let's say on get requests.
So here I can use get instead of use.
And now we're filtering for requests which use a get method if we now safety's everything will restart
automatically and if I now hit enter on my you are elegant I get an error.
Now I do get this error because get and post actually need at least two arguments.
The first argument is not the middleware function itself but a string which identifies the path.
So the thing in the U are L after our domain which should trigger this middleware.
So we're not just filtering by h to be method but all by path.
And here I want to filter for a slash which means for request targeting slash this function will run.
So for now safety's at enter again.
We see the form if I enter a slash users here we don't see it.
So it is really just slash you can also add such a filter on app use.
But there it's not mandatory.
And although it will work as a starting filter so slash would work for all requests that start with
a slash.
Often the domain.
Which means really all request slash users would handle all requests that start with Slash users often
the domain even if it's slash user slash new here forget it's different.
It has to be exact match and the path is not optional.
It has to be provided instead.
Same for post.
We can all take this as a chance and for example use slash user here as a year L and tweak the forum
to provide the action attribute to tell the browser where to send the request to.
So did it sends it to slash user so the domain slash user we now save does again and I hit enter here.
We get the form if I enter menu you see the you are l changed to slash user and indeed we see the user
being output here and that's really important.
The user name here we didn't have to pass it on our own.
Instead this built in middleware did it for us and that's the power of Express.
We have to use middleware based approach which allows us to create our own middleware which is very
useful to funnel our request through multiple steps and the response as well but we can all the plug
in existing third party library Middleware is to get functionality like this body passing out of the
box without having to write the logic on our own.
Which of course really simplifies things for us and allows us to focus on our core business logic.