When it comes to deploying more naps I see two main options on how you could do that.
The first option probably the better one or the more common one is that you deploy two separate apps.
And with that I mean that you use two different servers.
I will come back to that.
The other option is that you deploy one combined app so all on one server.
Now let's have a look at option number one first.
So two separated apps they air your react app and your node REST API would simply be deployed to different
service or different services which offer hosting in the combined app case.
We change our node REST API a little bit to not just be a pure REST API anymore but to also have a route
which in the end returns the react app so that we have both the backend routes the API routes and here's
do you react abroad hosted from the same or served food in the same node REST API because the react
app simply needs a static host.
Which is why we can deploy it on a separate server at separate machine.
We just need some server which serves our ReACT assets which is the index HMO file the scripts and to
see us as follows statically no service IDE code needs to execute there.
We don't need to execute any note J.S. code or any of our server side code to serve our ReACT assets.
Therefore we could use a pure static host like a W.S. free firebase hosting and many other providers
for static hosting as well.
You can simply google for a static hosting provider and you will find many examples.
The node REST API of course does execute code on the server and therefore we need a hosting service
a hosting provider that is capable of executing node J.S. on the server and data from AWB as we could
use our own easy to instance which is our own virtual server which we can configure to our needs in
great detail or Elastic Beanstalk which is a service that takes a lot of configuration out of our hands
and makes that easier.
Or we use other providers like Heroku and again if you search for node she has hosting provider you'll
find many many examples.
Now in the right case where we have one combined app we just need a provider which is capable of executing
notorious code because while we have an app that needs to execute no trace code and then in our no chase
code we need to ensure that for certain requests we just return our index h him and file our ReACT scripts
and our CSO as files so we will need to tweak our notorious code for that and then just push it as one
app onto some server.
Now I will show you examples for both.
One important difference we all will have to adjust in our code is dead when we deploy two separate
separated apps.
We essentially have to set up we had during development right.
We had local host three thousand four to react app and local those five thousand for the node app.
So there are no changes are required.
And for example we need to set these course headers you learned about now if you have one combined app.
We need to change something because that's not the setup we used during this course.
And then for example we could get rid of the course headers because we would be serving everything from
the same domain and therefore the browser wouldn't need these headers to know that access is allowed
to the API.
Because the API would sit on the exact same machine and domain as the front end does now let's have
a look at both options and let's start with deploying two separate apps.