To output our own goals.
I'll add a new component in the components folder and to keep it manageable.
I'll actually create a new sub folder for every component.
This is not a must do but I personally like doing this because then I can quickly find all my components.
Of course you now need to adjust your import here in app shares.
My idea you did it automatically in case that did not happen.
Make sure you adjust your goal list import to reflect that new folder.
Well I added and then it will add a new gold component here in the components folder as well in there.
Add a new gold jazz file and a new goal.
See us as fall.
If you want to apply some styling now in the New Gold J.S. file we first of all need to import react
from react.
You always need to do that.
Otherwise you can't use J as X in that file because keep in mind J as X is translated to react create
element and then here I have my new goal component here.
We could accept proper spot as long as we don't need them.
We don't have to.
And then I export new goal now in app class.
I want to render new goal so I will import new goal.
Again the name here is up to you but it should start with a capital starting character and I import
is from components new goal new goal and then here we can rendered is above our goal list let's say
like that.
Now it wouldn't work because new goal is not yet valid react component because it's a function right
now but it's not a function that works as a react component because it's not doing one crucial thing.
It's not returning to is X so let's return some J is X here and there to keep things simple all at form
and in that form I'll add a input field type text self closing element in regular H2 email.
This doesn't have to be self closing in J is X it does have to be self closing and then a button which
is of type.
Submit where I say at goal a very simple form and if we now save that you should see it here.
Now let's add some styling to make this look a bit prettier.
For that I'll add a class to the form new dash goal and I'll import the new goal C as as file into the
new goal JavaScript file.
And then here on the New Gold Class which is added on the form I'll add a margin of 2 REM in all directions
and text align
center so that this looks a bit nicer.
And now we could also style the input on the button but I don't want to spend too much time on that.
So I will leave it the way it is now right now when you click the button by the way.
This page will reload because right now the default browser functionality will kick in which is that
when a button types submit is clicked in a forum a request is sent to the server that's served this
page.
Note it's not the behavior we want here though because here I don't want to send a request to any server
because we're not doing anything on the server side.
Instead I want a handle that click with JavaScript and that is the first thing I'll do here.
Let's see how we can handle events because thus far we haven't done that.
I want to handle the submit event of this forum here and react makes that simple.
We can add event listeners to any element not just to the forum but to any element by adding on lowercase
on and then the name of the event.
Now not every event is supported on every element but here you've got the default age two male elements
available.
So for example on a forum element you have to submit event on submit on a button you also have on click.
But since it's a button in a forum it's better to handled is on the form itself now what do you pass
as a value to on submit though as a value.
You have to pass a function that should be triggered when this event happens.
So a pointer to a function.
You could do this year with curly braces and then an anonymous inline function.
But I don't like that too much.
Instead I will create a new function here and in JavaScript you can create functions and functions.
So instead of the new goal function which it still is in the end I can create a new function.
I will create my ADD goal handler.
Note the naming is up to you.
But I liked his naming of having handler at the end of my function name.
If it is a function that is triggered upon some event.
So this is a function.
In this case I'll again use an arrow function which is not a must do but I will use only arrow functions
here and on submit.
Now can point at ad goal handler.
Don't execute it here so don't add parentheses.
Instead you just want to point at the function so that the browser and react in a common effort can
execute this function for you when the submit event occurs.
Note This function will get an event object and event parameter passed and automatically by react and
there for example we can call prevent default which prevents the browser default of sending a request
to some backend which it shouldn't do here because we're not handling this on the server side here.
Our server only serves that single index HCM I'll file it does not have any logic to handle any submissions.
Instead I want to handle it here in javascript on the front end in my react application and for the
moment I'll ignore what the user entered here and I will simply instead create a dummy goal and I want
to pass that dummy goal to app J.S. and add it to my core Scholes here so that it then is rendered here.
Now step by step we can create a new dummy goal of course in that article handler by adding a new goal.
Constant here which is a childhood object.
The idea here could be a random number with math random.
This of course is not really a unique idea but it's good enough and I'll convert it to a string.
It's good enough for our demo application here I mean and then the text here later will be the text
user entered here for now just some dummy text.
Mind you go.
So now we have the new goal here and of course we can console lock that to see that everything up to
this point works.
So if we save that we see our form here.
And if I click on Add go the page will not reload but instead we see this dummy goal here and I could
create of course multiple goals but at the moment they're not added to this list to add them to the
list.
We now need to get that goal out of the new goal component to the app component.
Now before we learn we can pass data around the props but that was from app to goal list.
So to a lower level component a component which is included in app.
Now it's the other direction we want to pass data from new goal to the parent component so to the component
which includes the new goal component.
How does this work.