When you're creating your word macro solutions,
you're obviously going to get stuck from time to time.
In this video,
we'll discuss some of the strategies that you could use to find help on Microsoft Word.
The topics.
There are five main tools that you have at your disposal when you're getting help.
Onward Lee B.
A.
First of all,
we have the Internet,
so Web searches.
I'm not going to say very much about this.
It's such a part of our lives nowadays that if you're stuck on something,
you go to the Web and you type in precisely what you're stuck on.
The more precise,
the better,
and you get some help.
So if you're writing a macro from scratch and you're not quite sure how to start,
you could basically do a search on exactly what you're trying to achieve with the back row
,
and you'll find people who have had similar requirements and look at some of the solutions
that they found again.
If you're stuck on a particular problem,
an error message perhaps keeps cropping up.
Every time you try and run a macro,
you type in the exact error message that you'll get in do a Web search on that and look at
solutions that have been suggested for people who had the same problem.
Then,
of course,
we've got the built in help reference.
Next,
we have a facility called the Object Browser.
This is access from the visual basic editor and gives you a structured presentation off all
of the elements,
which constitute word Vehbi,
eh?
Next we have the macro recorder,
and this provides an excellent method off Generating Co.
Just to get you started so that you can actually see what things are called.
One of the problems of using the help reference or using the object browser as we'll see in
a moment,
is basically that it's quite difficult sometimes.
Didn't know what the lanes of the elements that you're trying to manipulate.
What's it actually called?
I can't look it up because I didn't want it school.
So this is where the back Rory Cup record it becomes by useful.
And then finally,
we have a nice feature called intelli Sense.
This is something that's built into the visual basic editor,
which anticipates what you're about to do and displays in context help,
which you can then use instead of having to type everything himself,
Rely purely on your memory,
so Web searches.
I'm not going to say anything more about.
As I said,
It's basically something that is inherent to everything we to in this world now.
Ah,
so let's move on to the help reference.
And of course,
we're not talking about the general word help which we've got here.
Um,
so I was closed that down.
We specifically want word vb a help.
So we need to go into developer visual basic or,
of course,
press old F 11 the keyboard shortcut on from here.
We either choose help.
Microsoft Visual Basic for applications help.
Well,
we click here or,
of course,
repressed F one by default.
The help will appear online.
If you spent a lot of time off line when your code in you might find it convenient to
download the word 2013 db a reference and then we click on download on activate theme
specific VB,
a reference that we want to download,
assuming you're happy to use the online reference.
As I said,
the main problem that people find is where do I start?
What are we're actually looking for First of all,
obviously start with word 2013 development reference,
and he's got three sections.
Concepts.
How do I and reference the concepts contained topics on that useful things that people
often do at the sort of introductory and intermediate level.
Let's say,
for example,
you want some help or format in text.
You might start off by reading this section on the pliant format into text so as you go
through,
it will give you a brief description of each technique and then give you some sample code,
which economically copy and uses a starting point for your own code.
Let's just go back to the development reference.
Then we got How do I?
This is a similar Siris of topics,
but they are more advanced says You can see they are referred to things like content
controls,
building blocks and connected to databases.
And then thirdly,
we have the reference itself,
and because it is comprehensive,
obviously it has on awful lot of things that you will never actually need or use in your
coded.
At stake is an example.
The front object.
Let's say you're working with character formatted,
so here you will see you have three ways of proceeding,
you can look at every piece of syntax,
which is fond members.
Here,
you've got links to everything that could be done with the foreign objects or,
if you want to focus either on properties which are essentially attributes that you can set
.
And if we go back to the word interface in the home tab.
Obviously,
the found object equates to the front group on the ribbon.
All of the character formatting attributes that we might said,
such as the font color,
the forms name the phone size.
All of those are essentially properties.
So when we click here,
everything that we see is equivalent to one of those options.
If we now just go back to the forms,
object,
by contrast,
the methods,
our actions that you can perform on the front.
And,
as you can see,
that's not a huge amount of them grow and shrink,
probably the two most frequently used in this list and,
of course,
their equivalent to click in on these two elements.
So a method,
basically is an action that you can perform on the object.
So if you think about it,
if we compare,
grow and shrink to size.
Size is a specific attributes.
Grow is an action.
It's a similar thing to the contrast of saying that the child is four feet six inches tall
.
That would be basically a property of the child,
as opposed to saying the child has grown by three inches since I last saw her.
Okay,
so that's Ah,
quick overview of using the reference from cold,
if you like.
In other words,
you just jump in and you navigate through.
This method tends to be the hardest.
Because,
obviously,
as we've said,
the main problem is,
where do I start?
What are things called?
What am I looking for?
So let's just close that.
Let's now have a look at the object browser.
So again,
developer visual basic and it's under the view menu.
It's structured in exactly the same way as the help reference that we just saw,
so we would start by choosing word as the library.
Then we have the same west that we saw so we could go down to funds as we did the help
reference,
and here we can see all of the members off fund.
So here's the grow method.
You can see that methods have this green icon,
whereas property have this old index card icon with the hand holding the index card so we
can see here.
If you want to make something bold,
it's gonna be the front object on the bold property off the front object.
So what the Object browser shows you?
Basically,
it's simply structure.
It shows you where a property is or where a method is in the context of what's called the
word object model.
In other words,
every piece of syntax,
which it's legitimate.
Inward.
Vehbi,
eh?
What are the V B A equivalents to each of the elements within word.
So as you work in the word interface,
using all the options on the different ribbons,
the Object browser basically tells you what the equivalent vb A's to each of these commands
that we have in the word ribbon.
But what it doesn't give you a course is much help.
So having isolated whereabouts within the structure of V B.
A A particular elements lives.
If you want,
we'll help on it.
You're then press F one or click on this help.
It has to be this help button,
as opposed to this one.
If you click on this one,
even if you have something highlighted in the Object browser,
you're always going to end up on the starting screen that we saw earlier.
So if you want to get contextual help on the currently selected elements,
you either press at one or you click on this icon sighs you can see with now on a
description of the font,
not bald property on DWI can see here basically that we need to put any expression that
refers to a formed object,
and then we can set it to true false or W d undefined.
I say we can set it because here the help reference confirms that it's a read write
property.
In other words,
that property which weaken both check to see what it currently is and modify.
Then further down.
We've got a quick example off using the fund stop bold property.
Okay,
so that's the Object browser.
And as I said with both of those,
both the help reference in the Object browser.
The key issue is if you're starting to write Vehbi,
eh?
What am I looking for?
What are things called?
So this is where the macro recorder becomes so useful.
Whatever you're trying to do with your VB a code inward,
you can actually record yourself performing that step most of the time.
This won't actually write the back row for you,
but what it will give you is code that you can use as a starting point.
So let's take a couple of examples or using the macro recorder.
Let's say that we want to find out how to,
as part of our macro,
how to delete the third qallab of the currently selected table.
So let's just insert a quick table,
give it a few rows and columns.
Say this many.
Let's just put some text in so you know which call him is which.
So I'm just gonna put one,
234 So now we simply go to the developer tab and we record a back room.
We click on record macron.
We won't bother giving in the name,
which is using it as a help feature,
and we won't save it in the normal template for the same reason we'll just save it in this
current document.
So now we can't do any clicking while you're recording the macro you can click on a cell,
for example.
So what we need to do is to make sure that we're in column three.
And the logical way to do that is to use the keyboard shortcut.
We're going to the first column.
A man just used the tap key twice to go to the third column.
And,
of course,
if you then use the delete column,
come on,
you must then delete the third column.
So the keyboard shortcut for going to the first column in a table,
its old home.
It doesn't really matter which row of the table I happened to be on.
I now know that I am in the first column,
so now I just press the tab key twice.
This means I now must be in the third column on any road.
I dont goto layout all the options in the ribbon or find while you're recording America.
It's just the click in within the document that's not permitted,
and I go to delete two's daily columns back interest of the third row.
That's all I wanted to check,
so I go to developer and stop recording.
I could go to visual basic and retrieve the macro when you record a macro model is created
,
it's usually called new back rose.
We double click to open it,
and there's our code.
So here is where I pressed Walt home.
Then I press the tab once and twice,
and finally I chose to delete the current collar so I can now copy these lines.
Typically,
I'd sort of take them out.
Andi,
slot them into the macro that I'm actually created.
Let's look at another example of how you can use the macro recorded to check syntax.
Let's I want to do some work on format in and page set up,
and I really want to get ah,
handle on some of the since accidental need to use to prepare a report and make sure that
it's formatted in the right way.
Let's again go into developer and recorder macro in the current document.
Now let's go back to the home tab,
and rather than chosen individual components,
the most trick you can use is wherever there's a dialogue available,
you simply record yourself open in the dialogue and clicking.
OK,
so if we want to know everything about fonts,
you just click on the launch button here,
which brings up the front dialogue.
Don't need to change anything.
We just click.
OK,
let's do the same for paragraph.
Click on The Lordship Barton up comes the paragraph.
Dialogue.
We click.
OK,
then we wanted to do some work on page layout.
So we go across the that again.
We've got the laundry Barton,
which brings up the paid set up dialogue we click okay with without making any changes.
Then we stopped recorded.
Now,
when we go back to visual basic,
you'll see we've now got macro.
To added,
it was the first on the recorded in his back road to and look what it's done,
so we didn't actually choose anything.
But simply by open in the dialogue and clicking,
OK,
all the want properties are now available,
so whatever it is we're trying to do,
we can find it in this list on try and get a handle on how it works.
Similarly,
we scroll further down.
We've got all of the paragraph formats in and the down still everything to do with page set
up.
So that technique is very useful just to sort of get a whole bunch of code that you can
then analyze,
as well as simply looking at the code.
You've now got a context,
but you can use as a starting point when you use in the help reference and when you use in
the object browser.
So let's look at how you can go from code to help reference or from code to object browser
in context.
First of all,
let's say you want to just verify how vb a handles for names.
Is this a special piece of text or can I put anything I like?
How do I know what to put?
So basically,
you highlight these in tactical elements question in this case,
by doing that,
I'm I light in dot form stopped name because this structure,
as we'll see later,
basically saves me type in selection,
not fond at the start of each line.
So it's equivalent to have in selection dot for dot name selection dot for dot size
etcetera.
So when I select dot name,
I'm effectively selected form stop made.
If I want the help reference at this point,
I can simply press F one.
I can't think of anything I can do in the men used to get to the right place as we've seen
,
these will take me to the start in page rather than the context that I'm after.
So I press F one on the keyboard and up comes to help specifically on the full name
property.
It tells me here it's read,
write,
which means I can check it and also modify it.
But it's a strange so that this means it can be anything.
So,
having verified that,
I could say Go along to the home tab,
choose a particular forms and simply copy the name of the font as a string.
Then I can go back to the visual basic editor pace that inside the quotation marks because
I now know that this is simply a strain.
I know that that's gonna work,
that that line of code will change the current selection to back,
formed that Mike and do exactly the same thing with the object browser.
Let's I just wanted to get an idea of the structure of where the font dot name actually
fits into the general scheme of things.
Again.
I select dot for dot name and instead of President one.
What you do is to right click in twos definition,
and this is also a good way of checking whether something exists.
If you type something and you're not sure whether it's legit,
right,
click it and choose definition.
And if you get an error,
you know that it's not the JIT.
So when I choose that up comes the object browser in context,
the font object is selected.
All the members of displayed and the name property is highlighted.
Okay,
so as you can see,
the macro recorder is a really useful way or actually just getting yourself started and
getting to know what things are called.
What the various components within Microsoft Word or called when you're automating those
particular elements.
And then the final thing I wanted to say as a help feature Waas intelli sense.
This kicks in basically when you're right in your own back roads.
So let's say we want to create a back row between these two.
For example,
Mrs Cool it test and let's say that we want to use selection,
not forms,
as we did in the macro that we've just recorded.
So if I start typing myself with selection thoughts,
can you see that as soon as I type the dot.
All of the members of selection are displayed,
so I know that whatever it is,
I type has to be something in that list.
And as soon as I start typing it so f o is all I need to type to get font to be highlighted
as soon as it is highlighted by then press the tab key.
This boat saves me time.
And,
of course,
with longer syntax,
it's going to save me typos.
Then let's say we want to do exactly what we did in very recording.
We want to change the fault name.
So again I typed dot and what I'm seeing now is everything to do with funds.
All of the members of the fault object.
Just as I saw a moment ago,
all of the members of this election object.
So we said it was dot name again.
I've just typed and a and then press tab equals.
Then we know it goes in quotes,
and I think it's still on the clipboard.
I have a copy anything since not space that in close quotes,
let's have a look at another example of intelli sense.
So let's I want to change the color of the phone.
So I type in dark color and I can see from the list that it's gonna be color index.
So I press the tab key.
Just lock that in and watch what happens when nights I've equals.
You'll notice that I get a list of options,
and these basically are called in Yuma rations,
which is equivalent to making a choice,
usually in one of the dialogue boxes.
All of these integrations start with W.
D.
So let's I want Dark Blue.
It was gonna be W d dark blue And again,
I can look these up so occasionally when you take the equal sign,
nothing comes up.
So you have to do it from memory.
But to check that you've got it right,
you can just highlight it.
I'm going to definition if it exists,
the object explorers displayed,
and you can check all of the different options again to find them in the list when you're
in the word library.
As I said,
they will start with W.
D.
And then it's just a case of guessing what they're called.
So these ones are called WD color index,
and you'll find there are a lot of these in the word interface in terms of what they quit,
too.
If we go back into the home tab,
look at paragraph,
for example,
and take alignment.
So here I've got centered right and justified.
Wherever you've got choices like this in the word interface,
it never uses simply strings that's too much room for error.
It uses thes W.
D in Yuma rations.
Onda entirely sense provides a great way of checking the So if I go back in,
for example,
let's say we want to send to the text mail.
We'll just do another with blood,
which is a technique very favored by the macro recorder.
Let's leave it blank line as well.
So this will be with selection got paragraph formats.
And as you can see,
I've just type p a r than I press tab.
And with then if I move back up inside dots,
a l alignment of it comes and I press tab.
And then again,
when I suppress equals here these items they all start with W.
D.
And as soon as I start typing center happens to be the 1st 1 So I just pressed tab to pop
it in,
so you'll find that using intelli sense is a great way as your type in your code of getting
interactive in context.
Help,
uh,
would saves you keystrokes and saves you typos.
And as we go through the course,
I also mentioned ways in which you can maximize the occasions on which this intelligence
will actually kick in.
Just save you having to rely on the old memory all the time.
Okay,
so that's about it for this tutorial.
That's an overview off the five different techniques that your use as you're trying to get
help to speed up the process off,
creating your back rows and automated Microsoft Word.
The macro recorder is an excellent tool for identifying the names of word elements,
which you want to manipulate with your BB a code to get help on a particular object,
property or method from the code window.
I like the appropriate syntax element and press F one to navigate to a particular object,
property or method or to a word W d in,
um oration.
Highlight the appropriate syntax element in the code window and then press have one to get
help on a particular object,
property or method from the object explorer.
Navigate to the appropriate method or property that President one