in this video,
we'll look at how you can modify the way in which the visual basic editor works by
customizing the settings in the Tools Options Dialog Box in the Exercises folder and in the
Section two sub folder,
Let's Open 05 VB Options a Man.
Let's go into the visual basic editor,
and here you'll find we've got some code in a module just named Body or one,
which is really taken from some of the exercises that we've completed in previous tutorials
and will use this code as we discussed the way in which you could customise the operation
of the visual basic editor.
Given that the visual basic editor uses the old school Microsoft interface found in Office
2003 and earlier,
you won't be surprised to learn that in order to customize the way in which the program
functions,
you're going to tools choose options.
Because,
of course,
this is the way in which Microsoft Office programs traditionally worked the options.
Dialog contains Four Tabs editor,
and it's a format General and daqian.
The options in the editor tab mainly relate to the help that you receive as your type in
your code in the visual basic editor.
The very first option is auto syntax.
Check on this,
I think,
is really something of an overkill option,
which alerts you every time you make an era.
I'll give you an example of why I call it overkill.
Let's say that we're about to types and code at the end of this subroutine.
Let's eight an if statement,
Um,
I don't think we have discussed if statements yet,
but that's beside the point.
Eso I start my statement with the key word if and then I think of something else that I
need to track,
something I may have missed out.
So I want to leave the if statement incomplete and just go and deal with that other
situation.
So I move up the page,
and as soon as I leave the line up comes this rather going pop up to tell me I've made an
error and of course I know made an error because I haven't finished the line.
So I click OK,
and then,
from then on,
I'm fine.
So my preferred set in is to simply deactivate waters in tax track.
Let's just look at the difference,
so I start my F statement decided to do something else.
And when I leave the line,
I don't get the annoying pop up message.
However,
you'll notice that the incomplete and therefore incorrect line does go red so I can tell
that I made an era even without it,
sort of yelling at me.
So it's sort of subtly reminds me that I've made an error rather than shouting at me,
so I'd advise you to leave that switched off.
Then we've got require variable declarations.
Variables are a very important part of V B A.
And in fact,
the next section is devoted entirely to working with variables.
And the very first video deals or includes a description off this feature require variable
declaration so you'll learn all about that in the next section.
The next three options determine the intel ascents,
or auto completion options within individual basic editor.
And these are a big time saver as your edit in your code.
So let me just show you how these work festival alternate members.
So if you remember the keyword members when we would discuss in the Object browser as we
click on each class or objects on the left here on the right,
we see the members off that object.
In other words,
all of the methods properties on,
in some cases,
events which are associated with that particular object.
And this is what this option relates to.
So if you enter a key word,
which is descriptive off a particular object,
when you follow that with adults,
all of the members of that objects are displayed on.
In other words,
the list that's displayed tells you all of the legal syntax that you were allowed to put at
that point in your code.
So it's a very useful feature.
Let's take an example.
Let's say that at the end of this sub,
so if you remember,
this is just a dummy sub,
which simply displays a message in each of the subroutines that have called from the main
sovereignty.
So let's say at the end of the final message,
or perhaps at the end of each message,
we want to add the user's name on the syntax for picking up the user name from the Excel
interface is application dot user name,
and you're probably familiar with the concept of concatenation where you string text
elements together and you could do this when building string formulas in Excel.
So what we do here,
let's say we're doing it on all of them.
Put a space or perhaps commerce space.
And then,
after closing the quotes,
who then put ampersand application dots.
And,
of course,
because the option to display members is activated up come all the members and no prizes
for guessing that user name is what I then put perhaps like an unfinished that off with
ampersand exclamation mark.
So I could then copy that on Place it on each of these,
say,
when I run.
My three messages now have my user name at the end of them.
So if I were to switch off the option waterless members,
it simply means that when I start type in application dot you'll see nothing happens.
So I can't think of any reason why a someone learning visual basic you would want to
deactivate that option.
Let's just don't do my lost changes.
Believe that,
as is so that will remain switched on.
And then we have auto quick info,
and this is very useful when you're typing methods and functions.
So,
for example,
we recorded this code But if we were typing it,
let's Brie time that line,
for example,
not execute.
So that's the auto list members kicking in.
So I simply press tab when executed,
highlighted to insert it.
Then when I put a space,
the auto quick info kicks in,
and this basically tells me all of the parameters required by this particular method.
As in the case of Excel functions,
any parameter,
which is enclosed in square brackets,
is optional.
So again a useful feature.
It helps you to confirm the name of your parameters.
And,
of course,
it's useful,
as we'll see later to always name your parameters.
Justus.
The macro recorder did when we recorded this.
So let's just undo those changes.
The auto data sips feature is used in debug in your code when you're working in something
called Break mode and we'll discuss this in Section eight,
which is all about error handling and debugging,
I'll just briefly mention what it is just to give you a taste of what's to come.
We're trying to track down an error within this subroutine.
We can put a break points on any line to do that you fling in this column here.
And this means that whenever I run the macro,
it will automatically going to break mode at this point,
enabling me to execute the macro line by line and monitor how things are going at each
point safe.
I now run,
you'll see it stops on this line.
This line hasn't yet been executed,
and then I can step into,
which means basically execute each line one at a time.
And as I do this,
if I hover over various lines of code,
the data tip pops up and actually tells me what that element contains.
So you can see here.
It's telling me Replacement,
not text currently contains full stop space.
And the reason for that is that the line that's currently highlighted is the line which
will be executed when I next step into,
rather than which has already been executed.
In other words,
this replacement dot text is the last one that was executed.
When I step into again,
then if I hover over replacement,
not tax deals,
yet now contains the close parenthesis space.
So that's just a quick taster of what's to come.
We'll discuss this in detail.
Let's just come out of break boat and removed the break point.
We'll discuss this in detail in Section eight on error handling on deep Again.
So let's just get back to tools options.
Then we have,
ah,
Windows settings.
Dragon Drop texted it in very useful.
It allows you to move lines or any code around simply by dragon.
And,
uh,
it's It can also be used for copying.
So,
for example,
if I wanted to change the order in which some of these were executed,
let's say I want to do the question mark last.
I can just select all of these lines of code and just drank them down,
like so to copy.
As you probably know from other environments,
you hold down the control key,
so if I select these,
I've got control held down.
As I drag,
I now get a copy of those lines,
and you do this very often.
We've got similar lines of code just to get yourself started,
and the trick is to hold his.
Remember when you use that technique to modify the copy you've created,
and of course,
everyone always forgets to modify one bit.
But such is human nature,
and then we've got a couple of very simple,
that useful options defaulted Full module view.
Basically,
I've got several subroutines in here.
On full model of you is the default,
which basically shows all of them simultaneously at the bottom.
Here,
I can go to procedure view Andi.
At this point,
I'm only seeing one subroutine at a time in the top here.
I've got the procedure drop down menu,
and I can choose a particular procedure to go to it.
So if you find that as your macron's get longer,
you prefer to stay in this procedure view where you're just looking at one procedure at a
time,
then obviously you can just go in here and switch off.
Defaulted for Marty.
Old view.
If we credit new module,
you'll see it's now defaulted to procedure view automatically.
Let's just remove that model,
and then we've got a very simple one here.
The procedure separator.
That's this line,
which separates all the sub procedures,
and it's usually a good idea.
It makes that much easier to make sense off.
If we switch it off,
they simply disappear.
In the editor formats.
We can change the colors.
Probably another good idea mess.
You tend to use one machine exclusively all the time because every time you go to a new
machine,
you'll be faced with the default colors.
So if you want to,
you can click and specify what text looks like when it selected.
So that's it's normal appearance.
Do you want era text to be a color other than red and the break point text that we saw when
we would discuss in there This option bought her data tips.
Do you want the yellow highlight or do you want another highlight?
So,
as a general rule,
you'll want to leave all of these using the default colors again,
We have comment text as green so you can easily distinguish comments from ordinary code.
He would text things like End with end sub,
which are basically components of E B A,
rather than names that you have created for your own variables or literal text and so forth
on these going to dark blue.
Okay.
The other thing,
of course,
you conduce is to simply change the forms and size.
So courier issues because it's a mono spaced fund,
which makes it easier to get things toe line up.
Um,
and obviously if 10 if size,
tennis and comfortable you may like to increase that size.
Teoh.
Make it easy to work with,
then in the general Tab,
we have two main types of options.
We've got options relating to use of forms and working with those.
And then we have options relating to the handling of errors.
User forms.
Air used for customized interface is very straightforward there,
covered in detail in Section seven,
that just to show you quickly,
we can insert eight years of form and you'll notice that we have a grid on the user form.
So as we create in various controls,
such a strike zone pool your name.
This is a label control,
and then next to it,
we might put a textbooks control to the user to enter their name.
And as we work in with these controls,
the grid makes it easy.
It's a line them up so we can customize the grid space in,
and we can just specify how tight we want agreed to be.
So,
for example,
we might have 10 by 10 and you'll see we've now got a looser great let's just put that back
to the default so again.
I won't mention all of these options.
I won't discuss these options at this point when we come to the section on debugging and
error handling will have a look at them there.
These last two options here quite straightforward.
Show tool tips on collapse Project hides windows.
Uh,
when you hover over each of these,
you'll see it displays a tool tip.
And why would you not want that?
So if we switched that off General show tool tips And this time,
when we hover over the each of the tools,
no tool tip appears.
So I would imagine most of the time you'd want to leave.
This switched on.
Let's just reinstate show tool tips.
And finally we have here collapse project hides,
windows,
and all this means is when I click to collapse a particular project.
All of the windows related to that project disappeared,
so I had a couple of windows open.
As soon as I expand back,
they come,
and if I go to the window menu,
I can see them here,
and this is quite useful,
especially where you've got several projects open several workbooks open,
and obviously each workbook contains a project So you end up with lots of windows open as
you close or collapse.
Each of the project the windows related to that project will disappear.
A commitment easy to find your way around.
The final tab is simply docking.
And this relates to the way in which you can position the various floating windows,
which are available under the view menu so you can see by default.
They're all DACA ble once,
for example,
bring up the project sort of the properties window and it stopped on the side here.
So for some reason,
I wanted to dock it somewhere else.
I could just pick up,
knew that now it's docked at the bottom.
Now,
if you wanted above the project,
I could docket here and then made.
It suits normal position below the project so that behaviour is normally fairly useful.
You might want it to be switched off.
Perhaps if you're working on dual monitors and you want to sort of keep different windows
on different monitors.
But as a general rule have in the dock in features by useful in makes it easier to keep
your screen nice and tight and tidy.
Okay,
so those are the various options that you can set.
As I said,
there are a couple of them,
but we haven't discussed.
Just remind you require Variable Declaration will discuss in Section three,
which is coming up the next section.
Very first video.
We'll talk about that,
then Auto data tips on the options here all relate to error handling and debug in which the
topics discussed in Section eight on them.
I don't think we'll say any more about the form groups settings.
That's fairly straightforward.
So it relates to use of forms basically what you discussed in Section seven.
The settings in the Tools Options Editor tab allow you to dictate which auto completion and
help messages displayed.
Apart from the annoying auto syntax check,
it's best to leave all these options activated settings in the Tools Options Editor four
Back to control the font size and color used for the different types of VD.
A syntax.
The Tools Options General Tab contains two types of settings.
Options related to the editing of use of forms,
which will be discussed in Section seven events,
dialogues and user forms and options related to the wing,
which VB a handles errors these will be discussed in Section eight.
Debugging and error handling the settings in the Tools Options Doc in Tap Control,
which floating windows could be docked to the sides of the visual basic editor.