in this video.
Well,
look at Project properties.
These settings allow you to customize the way in which products are displayed in the Object
browser and also to lock project from viewing so that users could only see your code once
they supplied the appropriate password in the Exercises folder.
Let's go back into zero to and then 05 vb e options.
And this is the file that we worked with in the last video.
And here is everything.
As I left it,
I save my changes.
There are two ways of specifying project properties.
You can either right click on a project to his project properties from the right click menu
.
Or you can highlight the project.
Go to tools.
It's his product properties from there.
The option that you see displayed in the menu depends on the name of the project,
which is one of the things that the project properties allow you to change.
So here the name of the normal project is actually normal.
Hence,
when I right click,
I see the choice normal properties,
and similarly,
in the tools menu,
it reads local properties.
Whichever method you choose,
the product properties dialog is displayed and it has two taps General and protection in
the general town.
You can enter a unique name for the project,
and this is quite useful.
If you typically work with several projects at a time,
they may have a couple of Adan's a couple of templates,
all at the same time.
Having a unique name for each one becomes school useful.
So what will be a descriptive name for this project?
Well,
we were using it to practice Lee B E Options.
So let's use that is the name.
No space is allowed so I could put it under school or nothing at all.
They will call it VB Options,
and then we can give it the description.
Let's just put practice on set in be options.
These options of the bottom relate into the help file,
and conditional compilation arguments are fairly advanced.
And unfortunately,
we won't have time to delve into them.
In this course,
let me click OK,
you'll see instead of the word project.
We don't have V B E options and you'll notice in the properties window.
We have yet another way of trading today as well as this.
We go into the object browser in the library's drop down menu,
you'll notice that Alavi be a options is displayed.
It would have been displayed even if we'd left the default name Project in placed.
But clearly giving it a descriptive name of our road makes it easy to recognize when we
choose it,
You'll notice that the description that we wrote is displayed in the description tab at the
bottom of the object browser.
So when I click on Module one,
you'll see all of the subroutines that we've got are displayed.
So when you've created a complete VB,
a solution,
this facility is point useful because it gives you a way off this monitoring exactly what
you've developed and of navigating to specific parts of your solution.
Let's just go back into tools you'll notice instead of project properties.
We don't have VB options properties and let's look at the protection time and here we have
the facility off lock in the project for view it.
So if we switched that on and I'll just pop in a simple password,
let's just take it 12345 In order to see this work in,
I'll just need to closed the document cancels his clothes word for a moment,
then just go back into the document.
And this time you'll notice that the project is collapsed.
Normally it opens in the state in which you left it.
But obviously once it's been locked,
it's always collapsed.
So when I try to expand it,
it asks me to supply the password.
12345 And only then will it allow me to expand.
Explore the project.
Okay,
so those are the two tabs that you have available for set in project properties.
And as you can see,
both camps a fairly straightforward and they are quite useful as you start developing more
projects and put it more more code inside the the general tab of the Project Properties
Dialog allows you to name the project and provide a description,
both of which it displayed when the project issued in the Object browser.
The protection tab allows you to lock the project so that it can only be viewed after
supplying the passport that you specify.