in this video,
we'll take a closer look at working with strict variables.
Well,
look at declaring fixed length as well as variable than strings,
and we'll also look at a couple of VB a string functions.
Let's go back into the Exercises folder that let's open up our word.
VB a train in template,
right click and open,
and then let's go into the developer tab on visual Basic.
If you're Section three,
model is not still open.
Just double click to open it up.
That's scroll to the bottom and create a new macro.
So we're now in 03 03 mackerel A.
Let's call it strings.
Let's now switch across to procedure view.
Just a the bottom here.
If you click on the procedure view icon in procedure view,
you only see one macro at a time to access other micro's.
Just go to the top right to the procedure.
Drop down menu and you can switch back to any of the other micro's.
Let's start by declaring a couple of variables.
We've already seen how you can declare a variable,
which will hold a string of an indeterminate length.
You can also limit the length of a string When you declare it,
let's take an example of both.
Let's first have a variable into which weaken store the users first name so dim.
Str first name as string So here there's no upper limit on the length of the string.
Now let's say we want to ask the user to choose a user name and that it's gonna have a
limit off 10 characters with no spaces so dim.
Str user name has string and to limit the length,
we simply use an asterisk followed by the number of characters.
So asterisk 10.
Let's now use the input box function to populate these two variables.
So we're dealing here with data variables so the key word would be let equals input box and
then in brackets will put the prompt Please enter your first lane and then let again full
str use the name.
Please choose a user name that's now insert a break point on the end sub line so all our
code will execute and just before the end sub will go into break mode so we can have a look
at the variables.
So we run well.
Enter grants,
click OK and then as a user name.
Let's enter Red Hippo and let's go over the limit.
So hippopotamus.
So what?
We click OK if we look at str first name.
No problem.
It's what was entered when we look at str user name,
it's chopped off what was entered and we've only got effectively the 1st 10 characters.
Let's exit break mode by clicking on the reset button and let's remove the break point B B
A has a number of functions designed to be used with strings.
Let's just take a look at a couple of them and I'm sure we'll encounter several war during
the training course.
Let's say that we actually need tohave str user name completely not the case and with no
spaces.
So the statement we have so far gives us whatever value is entered by the user to remove
spaces from whatever they answer,
we can use the replace function,
so we start our statement with replace because it's a function within a parentheses on the
tool tip tells us that we need three obligatory parameters and then we've got a Siri's off
optional parameters.
The first parameter is exactly what we already have.
That's to say the string inside of which will be searching so we can put a comma and move
on to the next parameter find,
which is the string that were searching for.
And this is a space,
obviously,
because it's a string,
it goes in quotes.
The third parameter is what we're replacing it with and because we're replacing it with
nothing but still with a string,
we simply put quotation marks open and close,
but with nothing between them and that ends our function.
So so far we have a statement,
which gives us whatever the user enters minus any spaces that they put it.
We could now wrap a second function around what we've got so far to give us an uppercase
version of this string.
Again,
the function goes at the start,
and it's you case.
And then we put the statement that we have so far in parentheses.
After the name of the function,
let's test the macron,
so I'm going to reinstate our break point and run.
Now let's see what we've got.
So the space science it is removed.
Everything goes to upper case,
and we've got do hip hop will be working with strings throughout the course,
so you will get plenty of practice on doing all the best.
Ah,
so let's leave it there for the moment and we'll move on to look at working with number
variables,
So I'm gonna click resets to come out of brake mode,
remove my break point and then save out changes to declare string variable of indeterminate
length.
Use this in tax dim str variable as string to declare string variable whose length is fixed
.
Use this in tax dim STL variable as string star ex,
where X is the number of characters allowed.
B B A.
Contains a number of functions for manipulating the contents of strings.