In this video,
I will briefly discuss what is involved in learning Microsoft Word.
VB A programming.
What skills do you need to have in place before you can comfortably write your own macros
from scratch?
There are basically four elements that you need to have in place.
The first of these is not going to be provided by this course.
It's assumed that you already have this knowledge.
You need to know Microsoft Word very well.
In order to be able to automated,
you need to have an intermediate or advanced knowledge of Microsoft Word.
You need to be familiar with beaches such as sections,
headers,
footers,
the distinction between paragraph format in character formatting,
how tables are created and modified.
It's also useful if you're familiar with advanced features such as content controls.
Without this knowledge,
it's going to be difficult for you to understand the significance of some of the code that
you're writing as well as this.
You may find yourself right in Macron's to perform steps in Microsoft Word,
which can be done perfectly well without the assistance of macros.
The second skill you'll need is a knowledge of programming.
If you already have experience of programming.
This is a distinct advantage because this is one thing you won't have to learn.
However,
this course does not assume that you have any programming experience whatsoever.
So when we introduced new features,
new programming features,
we will discuss them in depth to make everything clear for you.
Next,
you'll need the knowledge,
specifically visual basic for applications.
This is the program in language,
which Microsoft used to automate all of the Microsoft Office suite.
And again,
if you have knowledge of visual basic and have used it in other contexts,
this is a distinct advantage,
because again,
this is one thing you won't have to learn.
The final part of the puzzle is that you need to become familiar with the word object model
,
and this is the programmatic representation of all of the various features within Microsoft
Word.
Now,
Microsoft Word has been around for a long time,
and it has over the years become extremely powerful,
and it has a vast array of features.
So the bulk of what you'll need to learn in order to program word is the syntax which
represents this vast array of beaches.
So the object model is as huge as word itself.
The good news is you don't have to learn every single aspect,
just as no user uses every single featuring word.
When you write programs,
you'll be doing a limited and specific series of tasks.
They tend to involve objects such as documents,
ranges of text,
paragraphs,
characters.
So you'll find that you can achieve an awful lot in the wearable automation simply by using
a few features.
But do bear in mind that the object model is a very huge beast,
and it does take a while to become familiar with the syntax involved in its use.
Learning word.
VB a.
Programming it Bowles gaining mastery of four elements.
Microsoft Word itself,
programming in general,
Visual basic for applications for the D A and the word object model.
Learning the word object model is the largest,
most challenging and most important part of this endeavor.