in this video pulled its and more work on number variables will look at a couple of useful
number functions.
I've also looked at how VB A handles the distinction between raw numbers as used in
calculations and formatted numbers,
which have characters added to them,
such as commerce,
in order to enhance readability.
Let's go into the word BB,
a train in template,
and we want the Section three model variables and Constants and let's add a couple of
Micro's.
The 1st 1 will do is a simple macro,
which will convert a Farron night value to Centigrade and to give us a chance to practice
on useful techniques.
What will do is to display the result in a formatted fashion.
So instead of simply displaying the raw number that the calculation returns will format it
to make it more user friendly.
And we'll put the degree symbol,
Um,
at the end of the the number.
No,
we compare V B A with Excel,
so let me just go across to excel enter a random number,
and I'm sure you're aware that in excel you conform at numbers to look exactly as you want
them to,
so I can choose currency and here I've got thousands separators and I brought two decimal
places with,
in my case,
the pound sign.
But the raw number that I entered is still stored by Excel.
So Excel takes care of both the wrong number and the formatted number for you,
Aaron v.
B A.
You have to take care of both parts.
Both numbers yourself.
So what we'll do for our temperature conversion example will have to number variables.
They can use this single data type,
but then we'll have to string variables which were equivalent to the but which will contain
formatted versions off those two numbers.
So let's create our macron s 030 full macron a and we'll call it tempt conversion.
And then I'm going to switch across to my preferred procedure view.
If you prefer for model of you,
feel free to stay in that Do.
Let's begin by declaring our variables so dim sng far,
which will be the paranoid value as single.
Then sng sent a single and then let's do the string equivalents.
So then str far a string and then str sent a strength.
Now let's populate the Fahrenheit variable by using the import box function.
I'm gonna keep using the optional keyword.
Let again just to draw your attention to the fact that these are data variables.
They're not object variables,
but sng,
huh?
He cool in four books.
Isn't ah number in Charing Points?
Then we've got to convert that to center.
Great.
So let's sng sent equals on the conversion as soon as I remember is you take off 32 so sng
for minus study,
sir.
Then you multiply by five divided by nine.
So now we've got the numerical value sorted out.
We want to display the result,
but use formatted number values.
So this is where our string variables come in.
So let str far a cool and to actually generate a formatted number,
we can use the format function.
This is a string function which can take a numerical input value and return a formatted
version off that number which includes non numeric characters.
So for meant,
the expression will be sng far and then the format goes in quotes and it's done in the same
way as excel custom formats.
So let's put hash coma Hush hush 0.0 So these placeholders means that if there is a number
in that position,
it will be entered in the result.
Otherwise,
no zero will be inserted where zero means if there is a significant number at that point,
it will go in.
But if there's not,
zero will be inserted in its place and similarly will have two decimal places and it will
round 22 If there are more than two decimals in the results on,
we can do the same thing for SDR sent.
So we're gonna copy this line on the way I normally did is just move the cursor to the left
click ones to select the whole line and control See followed by control V twice.
Because the line is highlighted.
The first control of the which is,
of course,
paste pastes over the selection so effectively nothing happens.
So you then just repeat control V to get the second line.
So this now becomes str sent and snd sent.
So now that we have our formatted numerical values,
we can output the But why don't we just add in the degree symbol since you've got words
very convenient insert symbol at our disposal.
I'm just gonna nip across to that insert symbol and more symbols.
And then let's scroll up,
Scroll down again and there's our degree.
Sign me.
Insert that now I'm gonna use cut.
We don't really need to leave it here,
So just cut it into the clipboard return and then we could paste it in here on in here.
So now we can output these two variables in a message.
Let's just put that on that blank line.
Chemistry box.
Presti off ampersand Karen Heights It cools and percent str sent 10% centigrade.
What's test our code,
But before doing that,
it's always a good idea to save and then run.
So let's see what 85.52 Fahrenheit is equivalent to 35.52 degrees Fahrenheit equals 29.73
Sent a great So see him in.
We've got the right formula that looks fine Before we leave this example.
There's a very useful function that you can use whenever you ask the user toe.
Enter a numeric value and this is the valve function.
Well,
to show you why it's useful if we run the macro again on the user says I'm interested in 79
degrees as my input.
When we click OK,
we get a type mismatch error because of the presence of those textual characters That's
just like on end.
Now,
as we go through the course,
we'll learn more facilities for test in values that you're about to place in variables.
But Vow is a very simple way of ignoring those textual characters.
So if we wrap the malfunction around our input box like so,
then when the user enters degrees,
the valve function simply stops reading characters when it encounters something that's not
numeric,
so very often that will just make the input box function bit more robust.
Okay,
I'm going to switch back now.
It's a full model of you on the reason I do this is so that I can be sure that the next
macro we create goes exactly where I wanted to.
So let's write our second macro,
and what we're gonna do this time is to work with inter jizz.
We're going to ask the user to enter their age,
and then whatever age they enter,
we will take off 20% and then display a message which says,
Really,
you don't look a day over whatever.
So if they enter 50 as the age we take off 20% leaving us 40.
So we display a message that says,
Really,
you don't look a day over 40.
So let's call this one greet user,
and then I'll just get across to procedure view.
So we'll dinner variable to the user's name.
Str name.
Just string Ben for their age.
Brianti age as integer,
and then we'll have a separate variable to store the age that we want to display.
So let's call that dimmer pence like that age as anti Gia.
And then let's populate the 1st 2 variables.
So let str name equal input books.
Please answer your main.
Then let's I n t age equal and then we'll use the valve function input box.
By the way,
empath and STL name 10%.
How old are you?
And then we closed both the input books from the vowel functions.
So now we calculate in flatter age.
So let's say in AIDS multiplied by no 0.8,
and we display our message.
So really,
you don't look a day over I m percent flat age,
So let's save and test.
So who's running our macro.
Let's say Barack Obama,
By the way,
Barack Obama,
How old are you?
Really?
You don't look a day over 42.
So 42 is probably a bit too precise.
It would probably be nicer if we could round the age to the nearest five.
So 42 were drowned down to 40.
43 would round up to 45 so forth.
Although we working with an integer we can still use the round function to do this.
So what we do is we put the round function around the calculation that we've got so far.
Then we divide by the number that we want to Round two,
which is five.
And then we multiply the whole thing by that same number high by five.
And as if by magic,
we end up with the original number rounded to the nearest five.
So let's try it again.
Onda 56.
So that then rounds 2 45 And again,
let's save our changes.
The format function could be used to create a formatted string version of a numeric value.
When asking the user to enter a numeric value,
the valve function can be used to remove any trailing textual characters.
The round function,
as well as round in floating point numbers,
could be used around to the nearest multiple of any whole number.