in this video,
we'll look at the use of constant in B.
B.
A.
We've seen how you can use variables to store values,
which potentially contain several times during the execution of your macron.
However,
you very often need to keep track of values,
which will always be the same as your code executes.
These are the kinds of values which is storing Constance rather than in variables.
So once again we're working in the Section three model off the word VB a train in the
template and we go to create a macro,
which illustrates the use off Constance.
And we're taking the example off a message that's displayed in the error handling sections
overall.
Macro,
which gives the technical support email address that should be contacted when the user has
problems.
Since this email address is going to be used several times,
it's useful to define it as a constant so that if it needs to be changed,
we only have to make the trained ones that will update wherever it's been referred to
within our code.
So let's create our macron and let's simply call it using constants.
Look,
I'll just switch across now to procedure view to declare a constant used.
The key word constant as opposed to didn't.
And it's also useful to make it easy for constants to be distinguished from variables.
One technique is to use upper case letters for the name of the constant.
We can still use the prefix,
so str support the veil because everything is up.
A case we need to have.
A separator between words and the permitted separator is the underscore character.
We then specify the type,
just as we do,
or we declare a variable.
But what's different is that because this is a constant whose value will not change,
we now have to say what that value is.
So let's say support at some company.
Don't come another example of where you would use a constant might be if you had a rate
such as V A T value added tax that we use in Europe,
which occasionally a subject to change.
So if you're going to refer to it several times during your code again,
you define it once is a constant rather than hard code in the actual rate in your lines of
code.
So let's take bettors are second example,
Combs s N dri.
That rate a single equals Notley,
too,
and we might also want to store a formatted version of this,
which would be a string STL.
That rate has strength equals 20%.
Then let's say we're in the middle of our air handling section and we want to use an MSG
box that includes a reference to these constants.
Let's just split the line,
So ampersand str support,
you know,
And then we'll put a couple of blank lines in spending line one small then we might say in
parentheses.
Hourly rates.
From now we could say hourly rates of £50.
But what would be better would be to have another concert.
So Const.
Sng away,
right?
A single.
It cools 50.
We could can Katyn eight hour only rate subject to They see that after sound you Let's
split the line again snz our rates on your the full stop.
So let's save and test our code.
So our common messages and the values held in our constants are inserted.
Let's just go back to full nodule view for a moment and refer back to the macro that we did
in the last video This variable de 80 Target is a prime candidate,
for definition is a constant because it doesn't actually change.
It's not designed to change throughout code execution.
So here,
rather than having dim,
we should really have constant.
And then let's change the capitalizations and match.
And then,
of course,
we have to define it so we can move equals,
followed by the date.
And then let's just delink this.
Another candidate would be here with hard coded that figure of 14.
It would be far better to define a constant,
let's say was called int critical date or int critical days and set back to 14 and use the
constant in our code rather than the literal valued.
So let's do that as well.
Send in critical the able ass as Inter jure equals 14 and then we can use that name instead
of 14.
Let's just make sure that we haven't broken the code by doing this.
Everything still seems fine,
but we've added a bit of clarity to the code that we had.
So let's just say about changes.
Constant should be used to store values which required by your macro,
but which will not changed your in code execution.
It is also useful to define literal values as Constance rather than embedding the literal
is in your code.