in this video,
we'll take a closer look at the use of variables that story in references to word objects.
We'll be talking about using variables to store references to the document.
Object,
the range object,
the table object and the row objects.
However,
as you'll see throughout the course,
variables could be used to store references toe any word object.
Let's scroll down to the bottom of the Section three module,
and we'll we'll do in this tutorial is to create a macro that creates a new document,
then creates a new table in that document and adds headings to the first row of the table.
And let's just call it object variables.
Well,
switch across to procedure view,
and we'll begin by declaring the variables.
So it's logical to start from the top of the hierarchy.
So the first object that we be creating is the container for everything else,
Which is the document so dim D.
O.
C.
New,
since it's a new document that will be created as documents next,
we'll drill down inside our new document and access the range object.
The range object can refer to 100 pages to a paragraph to a word to any range you specify
Inside a blank document that has just been created,
the range object refers to the insertion point to the blinking cursor instead of them.
Our energy,
new as range inside the range,
will place a table object.
So did Tvl,
new as table,
and in order to put some text inside,
it will refer to the first row of that table.
So let's dim row headings as road.
So those there are four objects and it's obviously logical that will start at the top of
the hierarchy with the object that contains all the others.
So we start with the document object to populate an object variable.
We use the keyword set as opposed to let which is optionally used for data variables so set
folk knew equal to,
and we then put any statement which refers to a document.
In this case,
we want the statement that creates one.
So it's documents your God,
that gives us our new document.
We now want to populate our range object to point to the contents of this new document so
we can say set Florentine you equal to dock new don't range because the document is blank.
Are Engy new equates to the current insertion points within the documents about that
insertion point.
I mean,
I want to create a table.
So now it's said TV l knew equal to on what we can say is doc new dot tables don't add.
And then in brackets,
we specify three parameters.
First of all,
the range within that document where was like the new table to appear?
And of course,
this is where we put in our in Genoud.
Secondly,
the number of Rosie like,
let's say to and thirdly,
the number of columns so that will create our table.
Andi by default it won't have any borders,
so the table itself won't be visible.
Let's say we prefer to be visible.
A nice,
simple way of doing this is to say,
tbl new got borders,
enable equals true.
And now let's add headings to the first row of the table.
First of all,
we'll set our variable row headings equal to tbl.
New don't rose brackets one.
We can now target the text in each of the cells in that robe object.
So road head ins Nope.
Cells one no range,
no text vehicles on Let's say name and we can then copy this line.
So just move the cursor to the left edge of the line.
One click to select the line control,
see for copy control the four times 23 4 and then we change these two to three and four.
So we have name,
let's say date,
amount,
details,
and that's it.
So obviously,
this is a fairly small sample off working with these objects,
but in a typical macro,
you would be doing the more manipulation with each of these objects.
So having them in a variable is a very efficient way off,
being able to manipulate them simply by using the name for this variable.
Let's just test that this works so well.
Save and run.
Let's check out new documents so everything seems fine.
We've got our table with four Collins and two runs just one final point before we leave
this topic.
And that's the technique for removing objects from memory.
It's obviously not very important in this specific example,
because it's a brief,
but if you want to do some memory management and just free up memory by reset in variables
that you no longer will be using.
Here's the syntax for doing that.
So let's say we've now finished without table.
We want to remove it for a memory we would use Set tbl view.
He cools nothing.
So there nothing Keyword is reserved for use with objects.
Variables.
Let's just running again and obviously we get the same result.
But from memory management point of view,
that variable is no longer taking up any memory.
Let's just save,
and we'll finish this section by looking at the use of the with and with structure.
Those of you who have done some B B A will probably be asking yourselves,
Why didn't we actually use with an end with in this context?
And that's the topic of our next video.
Using variables to store references to word objects helps to make your code faster and more
efficient.
When a signing objects to a variable,
remember to use the keyword set to remove an object from memory,
use the syntax set my object equal to nothing