Hello and welcome to Section four Word BB.
A programming in this section will discuss ways of making your code more modular and
efficient by separating different sections of code into different sub presages and
functions.
In this first radio,
we'll revisit a technique that we discussed briefly in Section two,
whereby you can have one main sub procedure that calls a Siris of subordinate subroutines.
In this example,
we want to record a macro,
but to save messing up our template,
we'll use a blank document.
Although the steps that will be performing in the macro will be performed in this blank
document,
we still want our code toe end up in our template.
So the first thing we'll do is to attach the template to this new document.
We go to developer,
document template and attach,
and then we go across to our exercises folder,
which is on my desktop.
And here's our template.
When we go across the visual basic you'll see here.
I've still got my Section three module open.
I'll just closed that down on going to Section four,
which,
of course,
is completely blank,
apart from our option,
explicit just to remind you why that comes up.
Tool's options require variable declaration because that switched on every new model will
have option explicit inserted.
Let me also remind you of a second way of a tat in a template to a document,
especially if it's a blank document.
We find the template,
and we simply double quick it instead of the usual right click and open.
So here we've ended up the document one.
But because it's based on the template when we go into visual basic again,
we have access to our word VB,
a training template.
Let's close that for the moment and let's go ahead and record a macro.
So what we're going to do is to take the example of a document that we need to create,
which tracks the creation of a series of reports.
Each report,
Let's say,
has ah,
an author who is responsible for its creation,
and the document that were created will give details of each report.
Who is its author?
When is it due by and what percentage of the document is currently complete?
So,
of course,
we begin by starting the macro recorder and let's use our usual name in convention.
So we're in Section 04 This is video 01 Necro A and we'll call it Main.
We don't want to save it in the normal template.
We want to saving in our word VB a training template which we can access by choosing this
option.
And let's begin by put in the head in that we want a top of the document.
Let's call it report creation summary.
And then let's make that line ahead in one.
Then let's insert a blank line or two and insert a table,
so I'm going to have life Collins and two rows.
Next,
let's form at the table.
And finally,
let's add some headings.
That's our macro completed.
So we go across the developer.
Stop recording.
Now let's go into visual basic to see what we've ended up with.
When used the recorder,
it creates a module called Numac Rose,
and obviously we specified that we wanted it to go into our template.
And here's our new macro.
So we'll begin by copy and all of this into our Section four model,
and we can then lose Numac Rose.
So what will now do is to divide this code into separate sections and Obviously,
in reality,
you would be working with longer sections of code,
but the principle would be the same.
So this section relates to the creation of the document itself.
So let's cut this section and paste it into a separate subroutine because they're
subroutine will not be a macro in its own right.
We used the key word private So 0401 B and we'll call it create documents.
Then we can paste in our code and let's just modify it slightly.
So at the moment,
all of this will happen in the active document.
Let's say we want it to happen in a new document.
So the start of this subroutine,
we can just add in the statement that creates a new document documents Not bad.
So obviously,
when you create a new document,
it becomes the active document,
and all of this will then happen within that document.
Now,
one thing we're not going to do in this example is to work with variables will put
variables on a back burner for a couple of videos.
The reason is when you're working with multiple modules,
you have to address a separate issue,
which is the question of variable scope in other words,
the places from within each module from which each variable can actually be accessed.
So we weren't work with variables for a couple of videos,
and then we'll will address the topic later.
Okay,
let's go back to our code and look at the next section that we want to create.
So here the table is being created on here.
It's being formatted.
So let's put both of those into one subroutine.
Several cut all of these lines and create a second private son.
So this is create table and paste.
And then finally,
we have this section where we actually enter the headings.
Let's call that create headings and then we just need to cool.
Each of these sub presages.
You can get rid of all these comments.
So here we just need to use the optional keyword call,
and it's always useful to use it so it stands out,
so you can immediately see where each subroutine or function is being called.
Control the control,
say,
of course,
And there we have it.
So this is a classic set up whereby you have a main subroutine,
and it then calls several subordinate some procedures.
So the macro is the one whose name is simply preceded by sub,
that everything that's preceded by private sub is only available within this model.
Two other sub procedures in this case to the main.
Some procedure you can,
of course,
test each of these independently.
Whether or not it works will depend on what that particular section of code does.
For example,
one private sub may require certain things to be in place before that code actually makes
any sense.
So normally,
it's only the the main.
Some procedure in this set up that you actually test and run.
So let's go ahead and run.
And let's look at the document that's been created for us.
So there we have documents to now we've got ahead in one,
and we have our table so that since we work in time,
we can say,
Don't save on this occasion,
we've lived dangerously.
In other words,
we haven't been saving our code.
Um,
on the normal circumstances,
I would always advice,
of course that you save everything you do.
But on this occasion that's abandoned Document one.
So,
do you want to save your changes to document one.
No,
we don't.
But then it's gonna ask us if you want to save our changes to the word VB,
a training template,
and this time we click on Save a Simple Way of Model a rise in your code,
Mr Creator Macro,
which then calls a Siris of subordinate subroutines when defining a subroutine designed to
be called by other subroutines,
precede its name with the keywords private sub to call.
The subroutine used the optional keyword call,
followed by the name of the Subroutine.