In the last video,
I mentioned that if you call a function or subroutine,
which has arguments defined,
you need to supply a value for each of those arguments.
As is often the case in program in,
this is only partially true.
In fact,
you can make arguments optional,
which means that when you call the functional subroutine,
you can either supply a value.
Or you can simply admit it in this video.
We'll look at how this process works.
We'll stay with the same example of creating a document inserting a table and put in
headings in the first row.
But let's say we want to make the insertion of headings more flexible.
We want to cater for a maximum of six headings,
but we want the flexibility of being able to enter fewer than six headings.
Optional arguments provides a mechanism for making this happen again.
We'll call this main,
and we can then call the function and subroutine that were used in the last video.
And let's say this time we only want to end three columns of information.
Let's now refer back to the macro that we wrote in the first video.
So here we had this third subroutine called create headings.
So let's now copy.
This is so this will be 0404 b.
And instead of having these fixed headings,
we now want the flexibility.
First of all,
they're being able to supply our strings as parameter values and secondly,
off being able to vary the number of parameters that are actually in use.
So to do this,
we define our arguments or parameters.
But with each one,
we specify that it's optional.
There are three things to remember when creating optional arguments.
The first is that optional arguments always follow obligatory arguments.
So if your subroutine or function requires both,
you put the regular arguments first and then you put any optional arguments.
The second thing is that you use the keyword optional before the name of the parameter,
and the third thing to remember is that you need to supply a default value for the optional
argument,
which will be used if no value is supplied when the function or subroutine is called.
So in this example,
we don't have any obligatory parameters.
We want to create simply a Siris of optional parameters said.
We used the key word optional and these air strength.
So let's call the str h one etcetera as strange and then we supply a default value.
In this case,
a good choice will be the blank or empty string.
That way,
when we moved to the cell,
an end to the text will be entering nothing.
So we won't be modifying the table.
So that's our first parameter.
Let's just go onto another line and then we content across and just copy what we had before
.
So we want to enter a maximum of six of these so we can just pace you turn.
I meant just modifying the names.
And here,
obviously this is the last one.
So no comma and no under school.
The next thing we need to change is that these values will be used in the function.
Cool.
And these parameter names will be actually used within the subroutine.
So we're gonna have just three.
Let's say we want the report name,
the date do and the percent complete.
So let's just move these into the function.
Cool.
So we want to call this and then we want to supply as parameters report name.
So cut this.
Just paste it in Let's use the same style by split in each value onto a separate line.
Then we want due date.
So this time let's drag and I just tapped out across split the line and finally we wanted
percent complete on clothes.
So these will be the only three arguments that we supply and obviously they will go into
str h one,
h two and H three respectively.
The last three arguments will simply stay as their default value.
So the final thing we have to do is to use str h one as the text of this one on eight to
and so forth.
So we just need one more.
These two lines copy paste,
paste and change that to six.
So after we've created a table,
we end up in the first cell.
We ends of the first head in move down one end to the second and so forth.
So there is a fair bit of redundancy in this process.
And those of you who have programming experience will be thinking of condition,
ALS and loops to make the code a bit more efficient.
But with what we've covered,
it still works.
It's a bit long winded but basically these last three entries are blank strings,
so they don't have any effect on the content of our table.
So let's distract that our code works so we'll save and run.
Now let's look at the table that we end up with.
So we've got ourselves a three column table on the headings have gone in and the last three
parameters,
which we didn't supply value for.
Don't do any harm.
It'll when defining a functional subroutine.
Obligatory arguments must always proceed.
Any optional arguments to define an optional argument used the key word optional and supply
a default value.
Optional argument is data type equals default value.
If no value is supplied for an optional argument,
the default value will be used instead.