when you divide your code into separate sub procedure is the question of variable scope
becomes important.
Some of the variables you declare will only be pertinent to one particular sub procedure.
Others you'll want to access in several different sub procedures within model.
On a larger project.
You may divide your code into separate modules,
and there may be variable,
which you need to access from sub procedures in different modules.
Since the code that we've been using in this section was generated by the macro recorder,
it obviously doesn't news variables.
But as we've seen as your macro is growing complexity,
the use of variables becomes more and more essential.
So let's look at modifying our code so that it actually uses variables,
the basic code that we have created a new document and places a table inside it.
The three main objects involved therefore going to be the document second lead the range,
which refers to positions within that document and thirdly,
the table that we create.
And in the first row of which we insert headings.
If we examine the code generated by the macro recorder,
you'll see it makes continuous use of the selection object and the problem with this is
it's ambiguity.
At one point in the code,
it's gonna be referring to a range.
At another point,
it would refer to paragraph another point.
It refers to a table,
the table cell and social.
By using variables,
we can remove this ambiguity and make our code much clearer.
So let's begin by copying the 1st 3 sub procedures that we wrote there will just modify the
names on.
We'll look at making them a bit more efficient by using variables instead of relying on the
selection object,
as the macro recorder always does.
So that paste that in and let's modify the three names so that becomes a five.
And to this illustration,
we will really need create headed.
So let's just delete that line on the first variable.
That it's logical to create is the document variable.
So him Doc knew as document,
and then here,
where we create the new document,
replace a reference to it inside DOT knew so that sets talk new equal to,
and then we can do the same thing to the table.
So we created table variable.
And then when we create the table,
he plays a reference to it.
You know,
variable that.
Having modified that simple statement by placing another statement in front of it,
we now need to make sure that these parameters are enclosed in parentheses.
When we delve deeper into VB,
a syntax will discuss when you do and don't need to place parentheses after the names of
functions and methods.
Now we leave things as they stand.
Both of these variables will have a scope,
which is local to this sub procedure in which they're declared.
So this means that when I create my new table in order to get it inside doc New,
which is where it belongs,
I'm having to use active document,
which means that at that point in time dot knew one I've just created has to be the active
document.
If I change the scope of this declaration,
however,
so that it's module level instead of procedure level,
I will be able to refer to dot knew in any some procedure within this module.
So let's do that.
It's very simple to do.
We simply need to declare the variable at the top of the model above all the subjects ages
so we can simply cut it from this position.
Let's lose the blank line and then we just paste it after the option explicit above all the
sudden procedures,
the simple fact of declaring it in this position makes it module level,
and we can use the keyword dim.
However,
it's much better practice to use the keyword private,
because this explicitly specifies that this is a private module,
which is the key word that specifies model level scope.
Another useful practice is to have a name in convention,
which makes it easy to distinguish between model level and procedure level variables.
One common convention is simply to place the letter M at the start of the name,
so the M specifies the scope has been model level,
and in this case,
the D.
O.
C specifies that it's a document variable,
and the convention is where you have a local variable.
You simply don't use any prefix.
You typically have a prefix to specify the data type,
but you don't then put a sort of P to represent procedure.
You simply haven't prefix to specify the data time,
so at the bottom here will now need to update our name so that they'll be comes in em.
And in this position we can now explicitly state that we want our table to go inside.
Don't new and don't continued rather than relying on the fact that it's probably going to
be the active document.
I've just noticed,
by the way,
that there are three lines in here which completely unnecessary.
This is one of the things about using the macro recorder,
which is how we generated this code.
It records every single thing.
You,
too,
so I must have timeto Why,
after type in summary,
an extra Y and then deleted it.
And the macro recorder said,
Ah,
you want an extra way and then you want to delete it,
so I'll put the code in for you so you can just delete those.
You almost certainly haven't gotten these three lines in your coat.
I hope their presence hasn't confused you,
so we can now test our code.
Let's just save,
and it's the main back row here that we need to run.
Let's look at the document that's been created,
and there it is.
So that's the difference between a procedure level Onda module level variable.
There's 1/3 scope that you can give to a variable,
which is to make it global.
So let's just have a quick example of doing one of those.
You declare global variables in the same position as module level variables,
but instead of using the keyword private you use public,
so let's just do a quick test and the convention is we use G as the first letter of the
name.
So let's call it G str test straight And in fact,
what we can do to save time is we can make it a constant.
So if we put Const at this point,
we can land.
Just populate it in one line so we could go into any of these modules.
Andi,
refer to this variable and it's going Teoh,
actually give us this value of test that we've assigned to it.
So I'm just gonna go into conditional is loops in the rays,
which is what we're coming onto next.
At this point inside,
it's blank.
And let's just put a test macron in there and use MSG Box on paste.
Just copied the name and run and up comes out test.
We probably won't be encounter in this very often if it all in this course,
But as you start right in larger projects,
you will find that you need to refer to variables and other modules on the way to do that
is to give them a scope,
which is public.
So for the moment,
let's just lose our public constant and save our changes.
Variables declared within a functional subroutine have a local scope and can only be
accessed from within the procedure in which they declared variables declared at the top of
a module a bubble.
Some procedures using the keyword private have a model level scope.
Variables declared at the top of a module using the keyword public have a global or project
level scope.