in this section,
we look at the VB a statements which are used to control the flow of execution within your
Mac rose.
Their two main types of statement.
Conditional statements allow you to control with Siris of steps have performed depending on
the result of conditional tests.
The second type of statement is a loop which allows you to efficiently carry out a series
of steps several times,
and we'll begin by looking at if statements.
So let's go into the Section five model and let's create our first macro.
I will call it simply if statement let's begin by looking at the structure of an if
statement.
The basic structure is as follows.
If we used the key word,
it's followed by a logical test in other words,
a test which can only result in either true or false,
followed by the keyword Then.
Then we put the statements which will only execute.
If the test is true,
then we have the option of put in the keyword else.
Then we can put a series of statements which will only execute if the test is false and we
then closed the of statement with the keywords and if Let's take a simple example.
Let's say that we want to have an application which will only run if the user is used in
Microsoft Word 2007 or later,
the statement that allows you to test the version of world that's being used his
application dot version.
So if I go into the immediate window imply question mark application version because I'm
using word 2013.
When I press enter,
I get 15 20 warts.
Now this result looks like the single day to try it,
doesn't it?
Because it's gonna decimal,
so it can't be an integer or along.
However.
In fact,
it's a strength.
So if I look in the object browser moved down to application,
don't version.
You'll see it's a property,
which returns a string.
So when using this statement,
if I want to do a comparison such as Greater Band,
I first need to read this value into a numeric variable.
Let's look at how that would work.
So let's dim introversion as in Georgia and weaken venues the valve function to generate a
numeric value based on the string that we've just seen.
So this is a data variable,
so it uses the keyword Let which is we knows option also be admitted.
Introversion equals application version,
and we then just wrapped the valve function around that.
So I've been converted that into an insurgent.
We can then test whether it's greater than or equal to 12 because the number 12 denotes
were 2007.
14 denotes word 2010.
So we simply say,
If introversion greater than or equal to 12 then so that's our test,
and we'll just put one statement.
If truth MST box,
Welcome to the application else.
A mystery box.
This application is designed word 2007 or later,
so we'll see if we running on this machine.
We should get this message.
This version of in if statement caters for only two possibilities.
If the test is true,
we carry out one set of statements.
If the testes false,
we carry out another.
However,
there's a second variation,
which allows you to cater for as many eventualities as you want to do this.
You use the keyword else.
If,
as an example,
let's create a macro which will calculate a grade based on a school entered by the user.
Let's just switch across to procedure view and let's dim in school,
as in Geagea and SD ah grade.
As strength,
we can then populate in school by the user using an input box and again we can use vow.
So now we can use an if statement to evaluate in school and to populate.
Str grade accordingly,
so we'll start with the highest values.
If in school is greater than or equal to 80 then str grade equals a next we want to test
for Be on.
Let's say that B is between 70 and 80.
To do the second test.
We use Elsie so it's greater than or equal to 70 and and we can't simply say and less than
We have to repeat in school less than 80 and we also have to repeat the keyword then and we
can then just copy this line B A c okay,
and a So you see,
we would be looking at greater than or equal to 60 Lesson seven c and then that day created
honoree was 50 less than 60 and the final test will be full e,
which would be greater than or equal to 40 and less than 50 and anything less than 40 will
then be in F So we don't need a test for this.
It becomes the else and we end the statement with and it having populated str grade we can
now output it.
So let's simply say message box a school Volver I understand in school Abbas ends gives us
a grade happy sand str grade and the sand full stop and that's tested.
It's a little saved and run Man Center score of 75 Store 75 gives us a great be when using
an if statement to handle two possible outcomes,
use this Intacs if test then statements.
If test is true,
Pells statements it testes false.
And if when using an if statement a handle more than two possible outcomes.
Use this in tax if test one then statements if test one is true else.
If tests to then statements if test to its true etcetera else statements.
If all above tests of false and this