in this video will look at the Select case statement,
which provides an alternative to use in if and else it when testing for several different
possibilities.
In this example,
let's say that we want to create a new document,
insert a title and then below the title inside the creation date.
However,
after the day components off the date,
we'd like to insert the correct ward inal such as S,
T,
N de R D or TH will create a function which will calculate the orginal based on the current
date.
So that's first created,
Macron said.
The macro will create a document,
so let's just switch across to procedure view and then here we could dim stock you as
documents.
I'm also create str orginal as string.
So first we create a new documents and then we want to calculate the orginal so we'll
create a separate function which does this so it's gonna be str orginal equals and then we
do a function called So a function is gonna be s 050 to be on.
Let's say it's called calculates.
Orginal will need to pass the function an argument which could be today's date which is
generated by using the function now.
Once we calculated the orginal,
we can then write our head in and today's date in the new document.
So that will be broken.
You not content.
Since it's implying document equals on our headed.
Let's just call it status report,
and we'll follow that with a return.
Three b.
C.
R now has to split the line,
and now we want the formatted date,
including the orginal.
So we'll put the day component first.
And for that we can use thief format function that we saw before.
So we four met in today states and the day component.
Let's say we want four days,
which gives us the name of the day and then a number with no lead in zero representing the
day of the week.
So that's the day component.
Close that then we insert str orginal and then we finish off with the month and year again
.
We format in today's state.
We put a space,
let's say four m.
So we get the full name of the month on a space followed by a four digit year.
So now all we need to do is to write this function.
Let's just go back to full model view so we can ensure that our function goes in right
place.
So it's private function and paste controlled me.
So this now becomes the name of the parameter that we want to use.
Which,
of course,
will be a date parameter.
So d 80 inputs as date.
Then after the closing parenthesis,
we specify the type of data that are function returns,
and this will return a string such as nd or SD,
representing the orginal.
Now let's return to procedure view.
So now comes our select case statement.
And let's just look at the overall syntax four selected case.
So it's select case.
Then you have the test expression to be evaluated.
So we have case test expression and then,
for each possible value,
we use case and we can either put a single value for a list of values.
So let's say value list one that we put the statements if valueless one contains the match
,
and we can then repeat that as many times as necessary.
In our case,
there are four orginal so we've got S t that we have nd rd and th in fact,
having tested for S,
T,
N,
d and R D.
If it's none of those three,
it must be th So Instead of having another case test,
we can use the statement case else.
So if none of the above the truth,
then these statements will execute.
And to close a select case,
you simply use and select.
So that's the skeleton of a select case.
Let's now flesh it out.
So our test expression is gonna be the day component of D 80 input.
And to extract this,
we can use the day function,
which is simply day and then in parentheses.
We put in this case the variable,
which is D 80 input.
So that's what's being evaluated in the select case.
The first list of values were interested in considering will be one 21 and 31 if the day of
the month is any of those three.
We want our function to return S t.
To specify the value returned by the function,
we use the name of the function,
so I'll just copy it.
Since it's a bit low.
Then we simply say equal and the value in question because we've specified that the
function returns a string We have to put the value in quotation marks.
So s to how we can then just copy this and paste it in.
So here will have nd Yeah,
I'll be yeah,
th on the days of the month when we require n d will be too and 22 and will require RD in
the day of the month is three or 23.
It's none of these values in our case else will kick in and our function will return th So
let's return to full model of you and we could now test down macro that save and let's run
Let's see the document that's been generated So we've got a title status report and we've
got our orginal inserted S t because it's the 21st old Bartsch.
So that's a quick rundown of how select cases used.
As you can see,
there is a certain amount of crossover between if and else if and select case.
But the key difference is you select case where you're evaluated just a single expression,
whereas with the if and else if structure,
you can have a completely different test with each else.
If that you actually use the Select case statement is used in preference to if else,
if when testing an expression all variable which may contain one of several possibilities.
The selected case statement uses the following syntax Select case test expression,
usually a variable case value list.
One statements,
if any,
of valueless one matches Test expression case Valueless to statement if any of valueless
two matches test expression,
etcetera.
Case else statements if none of the above matches test expression and select.