so most of the time where you want to loop through an object collection,
this is the best way to do it.
However,
you can still use the for next loop on.
One of the benefits of doing that is that you have the counter at your disposal,
which you can use to find Tune how the Lupin is actually executed.
Let's go back to full module view and let's call this final macro for next objects.
So let's take an example of looping through the items within an object collection.
The collection in question.
I'll just quickly show you in the word interface.
It's file info and on the right here we have properties and advanced properties,
and these are the properties that will be looping through.
So they're divided here into different categories and in V B A.
Been owners built in document properties and they are in turn a property off the document
object.
So let's declare some variables,
starting with I as Integra,
which will be on counter.
Then we'll need to know how many items there are in the collection,
so we will cool that so we'll call that one and BDP as in built in document properties on
this will be Integra.
Then let's create a new document so we'll have a You will have a document variable.
Then we'll read the name of each property into a string variable.
So str name have string and the value associated with that property also into a string
variable.
So these are our variables,
So the first thing we'll do is to create a new document.
Them will add a table to it.
Then we'll enter some headings and then we'll loop through be built end document properties
collection.
Then inside,
the Luke will capture the name of each property,
capture the value of each property,
and then we'll writes the name inside the table in column one,
and then we'll write the value in column two.
Okay,
so to create the new document,
as we've seen a few times,
it sets both new equal to documents not add on to create.
The table will simply go back to our previous section and let's just grab the code that we
recorded using the macro recorder,
and we can then use Doc New instead of simply active document on this occasion will need
instead of two.
We'll need to use in to be deep pain.
So this is simply the number of items within the collection that we live in through.
And since we also want tohave headings will need to put plus one here then for the number
of columns will need to now,
of course,
we haven't yet calculated what this is.
So that's something I neglected to do.
Let's just put that in.
Find number off items been collection?
No.
And to do that,
it's going to be let rather than set.
And as we know,
we're mitt let into bdp equals and in vb A When you want to find out how many items there
are in a collection,
you normally use the count property.
So we start with dot knew got built in document properties.
Got count.
Okay,
so now we can go into end to the headings and again if we go back to the previous sections
,
Montiel and look at our create headings we did We basically need thes three lines or a
variation of these three lines.
So we write the first head in,
we move to the next cell and rewrite the second heading.
So this is property name and then here property values.
So let's just say what we've got so far and test it.
So there's our two column table and it's got the number of rows and hopefully that number
corresponds to the number of items within the collection that we live in through.
So now we can live through the collection.
So this is our four next loop.
So it's full counter equals start value to end value Step X and then we'll close it.
Youth in next counter.
So the counter is I that both of these become I.
The start value is one either first item in the collection on the end value is our variable
,
which we called into DDP.
Our step value is one,
and since that's the default weaken,
simply delete the step parameter.
So now we want to capture the name into our variable cold STL name.
So it's let which we admit STL name equal,
and we then need this syntax which refers to the entire collection.
And we specify which item we want to process by place in an index in parentheses.
After that statement and the index that you very often used within a loop is the name of
the counter.
So because this value is constantly changing,
this is equivalent to saying each because each time you go through the loop it will have a
different value which will correspond to the next fighter inside the collection.
Having identified the item,
we then drill down and extract its name property,
so the value capturing the value will follow the same pattern sdo valued.
And then at the end,
it's going to be don't value.
Having captured those two elements,
we now want to out put them to the table and we can simply use these two lines.
So we moved to the next cell and then here we obviously want to write the name.
So that's str name and we do the same here.
And this time we want to write the value.
So str value I'll just tabal of these lines in for make them a bit more readable.
Now,
when we test this code,
we're gonna have a slight problem because the value of one of these properties can only be
extracted if it's been set.
And in the case of a brand new document,
there are a number of these properties which haven't yet been set.
So when you're trying to read the value,
you end up with an era.
So it's definitely a good idea to save before we test,
which you should always do anyway.
So we get an error message,
and if we click on debug,
this will tell us which line we've actually got to.
So basically it's reading the value which hasn't been set,
and that's what's generating the error.
Now.
We haven't discussed our handling is yet,
but we have discussed,
if statements.
So I've made a note of which properties are actually problematic in that they haven't been
set and they are properties number 10 12 25 26 27 28.
So for the moment,
what we'll do is to use an if statement to make sure that these values are red.
They just skipped over,
and perhaps we can enter a default value of not applicable or not available.
Perhaps we can enter a default values instead of attempting to actually read the Value
property.
So let's just have a look at the document that's being generated.
So it got this far with no problem,
but then when it trying to read the next value.
It failed.
Several close about saving on this is the culprit.
This is what's causing the problem.
So we need to make sure that that is contained in an if statement,
so it doesn't attempt to do that line unless the conditions are correct.
So we basically need to say if I is not equal to that's the symbol that means not equal to
10 ums.
I is not equal to 12 and well,
we want to say eyes not equal to 25 26 27 for 28 and a quick way of doing that would be to
say not and then in brackets I greater than or equal to 25 and I less than or equal to 28
and then close brackets,
then we need the key word.
Then we can tabal of their sent to make it more readable and then close that with and lif
and it might be useful to put in else in there as well.
So so str value equals and let's just say not available and again we can save and we
contest.
So by using the if statement,
we've managed to avoid the problem parameters,
and we're only attempting to read the value on those elements where the value is available
before next.
Lube uses a counter to control the repeated execution of a series of statements within the
loop.
The counter itself could be used to further refine code execution before each next loop.
He's used to live through the items within a collection of word objects,
such as documents.
The for next loop uses the syntax for counter equals start value toe end value,
Step X,
where X is any integer statements.
Next counter the four each.
Next loop uses the syntax for each object variable in object collection statements.
Next object variable.