in the last two videos.
We've looked at four next and do Nuk statements in this video.
Well,
look at the third type of Lupin structure offered in V B A.
While Wen statements,
Let's create a new macro unless simply cool it while when.
What does Mitt across the procedure view?
And let's look at the basic structure of a while.
Wend loop.
We have the key word while and we have a conditional test.
As long as they're test proves to be true.
We carry out a series of statements,
and the structure closes with wend a made up word which obviously is a contraction of while
and end.
You use this structure basically where you don't have a numerical component to control the
looping.
For example,
you don't know how many items you want to process.
You just want to keep processing them until you run out of them.
In this example,
what will do is to create a table in a new document and complete one column by making an
entry,
moving down the line and then checking to see whether we're still in the table.
As soon as we no longer in the table,
we stopped making entries when we stopped moving down.
So in other words,
we fall out of the loop.
So let's begin by declaring a document variable and creating a new document inside it.
Then that's at a table.
We can use some of the code that were recorded in the last section.
So let's go back to Section four.
I will just copy this line and let's say we want to create 40 rows and two columns.
Next,
let's just scribble down to where we entered the headings and copy a couple of lines from
here as well.
So the head in that we want in that first cell will be total time taken.
And this time,
instead of moving right,
we want to move down and the unit will be a line rather than the cell.
So so far we have a table with 40 rows.
We've entered total time taken in column one row one and we have moved down to road to
column one on,
Let's say from here What we want to do is to enter the time in mili seconds that it takes
to actually complete the table.
Now you may use this technique if you're testing the efficiency of code that you've written
and you want to know.
Basically,
for example,
which of two approaches is going to give you the best performance on Dak?
You make your macro run most quickly.
One of the simplest ways of time in an event is to use the timer function.
The time of function gives you the number of milliseconds that have elapsed since the last
occurrence of midnight.
To use it,
you start by taking a snapshot of the timer,
and then you constantly refer back to it to find out how many milliseconds have elapsed
since your snapshot.
So let's declare a couple of new variables for this purpose.
The time of function returns a single value.
Several cool our variable SNG timer,
a single and then the entry that we actually put into the table will be a string civil dim
str time as strength.
So before we lived,
we need to capture the timer in SNG timer because it's a single will use the prefix let
which we simply admit snd timer equals timer.
So now we can do our loot and the thing that we want to test to control the loop is whether
or not we're still in the table.
We can do this by looking at the information property off the selection object so it's
selection don't information and then in brackets,
we use one of these constants W d within table.
As long as that statement is true,
we know that we're still in the table and we can continue looping.
So now we want to calculate the time elapsed and place it inside str time So str time
equals Tell him which will be the current time elapsed minus our snapshots SNG timer.
This will give us a single value with an indeterminate number of decimals after it.
To make it more consistent,
we can write the full matte function around it.
So that's format and then time a minus SNG timer is the value that were format in comma,
and the format that we want has to go in double quotes.
So we want one significant number before the decimal.
If applicable,
dots on,
let's say for accuracy.
We want four decimal places.
Now we want to insert that value into the table and then move down one line so we'll just
copy these two lines and tab them in to select them both and press tab.
So here we want our str time and I said the word milli seconds.
So let's see what we get when we run.
This will save and run.
Let's look at the results in table.
So we've got a total of nor 0.9609 milli seconds African just close.
This one of the things I'll be stressing throughout this course is that using the selection
object in this way is very inefficient.
And as your code becomes more complex and as the number of operations that you're
performing increases,
you'll find that this inefficiency leads to very slow code and perhaps the macros which
take,
um,
announcer portable amount of time to run.
So we will discuss these techniques in detail as we go through the course that,
um for the moment,
let's look at how we can actually make this slightly more efficient.
What we'll do is to copy this code.
I'm going back to full model of you so I can make sure I paste it at the end here on.
We obviously need to rename this,
so we'll call it while wend No selection because the main thing that will be doing is to
remove the need to use the selection object so instead of used in this election,
object will effectively use a counter so dim I won't call it I since it's not gonna be the
inherent counter that we used with the for next loop.
So let's call it into counter,
as in Georgia.
So the cell within the table that we're targeting will now be controlled by the counter.
So we can start here by set in this counter to a value to which is the first road that we
want to target.
So encounter equals two before the lib starts,
and then here,
the equivalent of moving down will now be to increase that counter.
And we do that by saying encounter equals encounter plus one.
The next thing we need to do is to change the way that the loop is actually controlled.
So now it's going to be controlled by the value of the counter.
So we simply say,
while encounter is less than or equal to now,
we could say 40 because we know that's the number of rows.
But what's perhaps better is to say,
doc new dot tables on in brackets one because it's the first and only table in dot knew dot
rose dot count.
So that way,
if we were to change this number,
L Loop would still function correctly on.
The final thing we need to do is to target the table cell where we want the milliseconds to
be entered.
So we're doing it this time not by selecting it,
but simply by put in a reference to it.
And this is much more efficient.
It takes much less time because the interface isn't forced to actually make a selection and
scroll to the current row of the table.
So we use the syntax companew dot tables brackets,
one don't sell.
And then in brackets,
we say we drove.
And,
of course,
the rose being controlled by encounter,
and the column is always going to be calling one.
Then we won't stop range.
No text equals.
So within this statement,
there's no selection.
There's no activation of the object there,
simply a reference to it.
And using techniques like this,
you can create macros,
which run much more quickly than those macros,
which constantly select elements within the word interface as you do when you use the
recorder sterilise,
Test it,
save on,
run on,
Let's look at the result in time.
So we've got 0.54 milliseconds,
as opposed to I think 0.9 in the last example,
Let's just close and unsafe.
Another thing you can do to make Macron's run faster is to use the syntax application.
Don't screen Updating equals false.
Let's use that on both of these macros.
So,
in fact,
we can put it here.
Application dogs green update in equals false.
I'm just gonna copy that and paste it in the other version as well.
Sir,
Just in here,
OK?
And let's now increase the number of rose to 400 so we could get an idea off.
How these to perform as they're doing more work so we'll run this one first.
Let's save a fair few seconds,
and it's a 10.4 10.4 milliseconds.
It's very 10.4 seconds.
As you can see,
I've just realised.
Actually,
I've been calling this milliseconds,
but in fact the figure we're looking at is seconds rather than milli seconds.
So I'm gonna just update that no need to save.
So let's just get rid of the Milly here and here.
Okay,
so we've got 10.4 seconds to beat and you'll see we've done it here in 0.3 point three
seconds.
That's quite a dramatic,
as you can see,
quite a dramatic difference in terms of performance,
so hardly scientific.
But just to point out,
basically that whilst you can use techniques like this where you're using the selection
object for everything,
it's far more efficient,
as we will see as we go through this course to use references to parts of the word
interface rather than to rely on on selecting those elements in order to manipulate them.
The wild Wen statement performs a series of steps as long as a given condition remains true
.
The syntax of the while went statement is as follows.
While test condition statements wend