In the last video,
we learned that each object within the word object model as members,
which consists of the methods and properties off that object methods are essentially
functions.
They're the actions which can be performed on that particular object.
In this video,
we'll look at it more closely at the syntax involved When working with object methods.
Let's go into the Section six model.
Let's just create a macro,
which will enable us to discuss some of the syntax features involved.
When you're working with object methods,
let's just call it object methods.
So in the macro will create.
A new document will display a message telling the user that this macro may take a long time
.
Well,
then,
ask the user whether they want to save the document that al mackerel will create as a PdF
file.
If they aren't,
say yes will then display a message confirming that the macro will be saved as a PdF so
will begin by declaring its and variables.
This variable will hold a reference to the document will create.
And then we need to declare a variable,
which will hold an answer to the question.
Would you like to create a Pdf file.
We've already looked at using the input box function to get the user toe arms for a
question.
However,
if the question is simply a yes,
no,
you can actually use the MSG box function to ask the question.
However,
the answer that's generated is actually stored as a long integer rather than as a piece of
text.
So for that reason,
will dim l N g answer as long I long integer So we've seen how you can create a new
documents.
We've also discussed briefly the usefulness have put in a reference of the new document
that you create into a variable.
This then provides you with a mechanism for manipulating the document further with your
code.
So we used the keyword set variable name equal to,
and then we simply put a reference to any object off the appropriate site.
So the statement documents Stop Ad is obviously used in the ad method,
and the reason that we're able to use this method to assign a reference to a document into
our document variable is because the ad method returns a value.
In other words,
it returns a document object,
namely,
the document that has just been created by the ad method.
We can verify this by looking in the Object Browser view Object browser.
George Cut F two and then because the documents object is obviously part of the Microsoft
Word object model,
which is word from the libraries drop down menu.
Then let's just scroll down to find documents and the ad method.
So when we look at this in tax,
we can see after the various optional parameters that the ad method returns a document so
that,
as statements after the closing parenthesis tells us that there is a value being returned
on its off the document type.
So now we want to tell the user this macro may take a while,
and we do that with M s tree box,
which we've seen several times and what we've been doing so far.
It's simply place in the first parameter,
which is the only one that's obligatory senses.
You can see all of the others here are enclosed in square brackets that tells us that
they're all optional.
So we've been simply put in a value for that first parameter,
which,
of course,
is a string,
and that's the type of data required by the prompt.
Although this works fine,
the best practice when supplying parameter values for a method is to actually put the name
of each parameter.
The benefit of this is greater clarity.
Anyone look into the code could immediately see the value that each parameter relates to,
and it also means that you can place the parameters in any order.
If you simply supplying values without name in the parameters,
then you must put them in the order stipulated by the function or method.
And if you admit any,
you still need to put the comma to separate the values so it becomes a bit more cryptic,
especially where the method has a lot of parameters.
So for the rest of this course will be main in allowed parameters on some occasions and
slightly overkill because there's very little room for errors to creep in,
and there's very little room for ambiguity.
However,
it is definitely best practice,
and very few people in programming will ever accuse you of trying to be too clear.
So instead of going straight into this string,
we put the keyword prompts,
as in the name of the promise,
sir,
and then we put Coulombe equals immediately followed by the value you want to assigns about
parameter.
So let's say this macro may take a while to complete and let's use the title parameter,
so I'll put the continuation sign space underscore.
I just have across a little bit title and let's just say use Ah in the Let's have 1/3
parameter.
So now I'm gonna use buttons and you'll see that I don't have to think about the order.
I just do them in the order That's convenient for me as I'm type in them.
The entry that you choose here will determine the style of dialogue that you end up with on
the buttons that it contains,
so we want really information.
So here we use in the MSG box function purely to send information to the user,
But it could also be used to capture information.
Let's just have a look at this in tax.
So this time we need to go to the V B,
a library and the MSG Books,
and you'll find them as G Boc's in the interaction objects on the reason we've never
actually used interaction in our code.
It's because it's also in the global's,
so any element that in the global's doesn't need to be qualified.
You don't have to say parent DOT member,
you simply go straight to the member in question so the MSG box function doesn't need to
have any prefix.
Okay,
so what we're looking at is the fact that it returns the value on the thing that tells us
that is the as keyword following the close in parenthesis.
So when we looked at documents don't add,
that method was returned in a document object.
Other methods might return a string or an integer or a long integer etcetera.
The MSG box function returns a constant,
and you could recognize these constants by the 1st 2 letters.
So in the case of a visual,
basic method will function.
The constant will be prefixed with VB.
In the case of Microsoft Word,
the constant will be prefixed with W.
D.
In the case of Microsoft Excel,
it will be prefixed by the letters X l and so forth.
You'll also notice that the Barton's parameter also takes a constant.
If we want to look at either of these,
we can just click on these links,
so these are the various parameters which are permissible for the VB msde Reebok style
constant.
Let's just hit the back button and then for the results,
we have basically all of the various possible buttons that the use that may click on and
which one is available will depend on the buttons parameter specified when we actually use
the function.
So we've used VB.
Yes.
No.
So no prizes for guessing that d be no and baby yes will be the two parameters which our
function will return When you click on them at the bottom Here,
you'll see that baby Yes,
actually equates to a six baby no equates to a seven.
So which one would you are there trying to remember?
It's definitely gonna be the constant name,
isn't it?
So we tight baby?
Yes,
depending on which one we want to test.
So this time we're going to use this pattern set my variable equals M s tree box.
And of course,
the variable in question is LNG answer,
which requires let rather than set on a course,
Let is optional.
Ellen Jones equals MSG books.
This time we need parentheses and I'll explain in a moment when you do need parentheses and
when you don't will move on to that shortly.
So again we'll put our named parameters Prompt.
Colon equals create PdF file.
I will split out parameters onto several lines.
So this time we need Phoebe.
Yes,
no,
and we close out parentheses.
Okay,
so let's address the question of when you do need parentheses after a method on when you
don't.
The basic answer is you never need parentheses after the name of a function.
So most programming languages every functional method will require parentheses after the
name of the method in B B.
A.
You don't.
However,
that's only true if the method is the only thing on that line.
The only piece of code on that line is the method with its parameters.
As soon as you introduce another statement on the same line,
you do need to have parentheses around the arguments off the method.
So here,
because we using message box on its own,
there's nothing else on that line.
We don't need parentheses to enclose the three arguments,
but in this example,
we've introduced another statement,
the assignment statement,
which assigns the result of the message box function to LNG answer and by introducing that
extra statement is now obligatory that we have parentheses around the three arguments.
And that's the simple rule in B B A.
As to when you need parentheses after a method name and when you don't Okay,
so now,
Long variable,
we now have an answer,
which we can test so we can say if LNG owns equals.
And although it's a long integer,
we don't have to look up the actual number and use that in our test.
We can use the constant name that we saw,
which,
if you,
Landau was simply baby.
Yes,
if you are type in the names of these constants or E numbs in Yuma rations is there also
called.
It's always useful to type them in lower case,
because when you leave the line,
if they're correct,
then the case will change automatically.
So if you see the case remains lower,
you know you've got it slightly wrong.
So if VB yes equals baby yes,
Van a mystery box and I'm just in a copy of this one,
and let's say pdf will be saved insane.
Bolder,
as as we're document title can be pdf buttons,
TV information.
That's fine.
And if and then let's test.
So we'll save comes our first message books.
Let's say yes,
create PdF oil and up comes out second.
Okay,
so there's some of the main things to bear in mind when working with methods and obviously
from this point onwards,
But in the course you'll see lots of examples off working with different methods.
So hopefully you will have plenty of opportunities to actually revisit these topics.
As we continue to work with methods throughout the course when specifying values for the
arguments of a method,
it is best to name each argument using this syntax method.
Argument.
One.
Colon equals value.
One coma argument to colon equals value to etcetera in V b.
A.
The arguments of a method are not placed inside parentheses unless the method is not the
only statements on that line.
If a method has a return value,
it can be captured using the same tax set.
Variable name equals method