I haven't had a look at working with events and properties in this video.
Well,
look at the Centre Axe for home in in on individual objects.
The basic syntax involves referring to the object,
either by its name or by its position within the collection.
However,
as we'll see,
there are one or two other sent tactical variations,
which it's worth discussing.
Let's open up the Section six folder and then inside that let's open up 0601 tables.
Then we can go across the developer document template and attach.
Then let's work our way into the Exercises folder and attach our word VB a training
template.
When we then go into visual basic,
we have access to all the modules in the template.
Let's just scroll down to the bottom here,
and I sat in a macron on Let's simply cool it reference in objects and then let's switch
across to procedure view.
The normal method of referring to a document is to use its name as an index.
The reason for this is that it's quite difficult to know what position the document will
occupy within the documents collection.
The documents collection,
of course,
is all the documents that are currently open inward,
and it's the order in which documents are open or created that determines their position
within the collection.
So you'll normally only identify documents numerically when you're looking through all of
them,
perhaps making modifications to each one or examining each one in some way.
So let's say we want to create a reference to the document we've just opened.
We could declare a variable doc tables as documents,
and then to identify it.
We would use its name so set Doc tables,
equals documents and then in brackets and double quotes,
we would put its name.
That's just co p it.
And then we contest our code by saying a mystery box and I won't bother put in the
perimeter name because I'm going to take this out in a moment.
Stock tables dot tables don't count.
Family should get 12 tables when working with objects within the document,
such as tables,
paragraphs,
words,
etcetera again,
there is always a possibility that you'll need to look through them,
but the norm is usually that you use a numeric method of index in them.
So in the case of the tables,
the number of each table is set up by its position within its container.
As you probably remember,
each table is headed by a month,
and so obviously the January table will be the first,
and the December table will be the last.
Let's put that to the test.
So we say Doc tables the tables and then brackets 12 dots select when we run in our code.
If we move back to the document,
you'll see it selected the 12th and last table.
Let's just de select it if we weren't sure what the last table waas and we still wanted to
target it and we could use the Count property of the Tables collection.
Since the first item is one,
then,
however many tables there are,
which is what Count tells us must also be the index of the last one.
So here we could say,
Doc tables,
no cables,
not count.
If we were going to use this number for something else,
we would put it into a variable and then used the variable thereafter.
Okay,
so let's delete this select statement and let's just finish off.
Our macro will say that we want to insert some text in the tables correspondent of the last
month in each quarter,
and we want to complete all four columns.
So we've got our head ins and we want to actually write some text in each of these cells.
So you want to put in a report name,
Author due dates,
percent complete.
Zero and departments.
Let's say I t.
So the first thing is we'll need a counter to control the Lupin.
And because we don't want to process every single item,
a numeric counter will be best.
So then I as integer and then we can create a for loop fel.
I equals three by either third month to 12 and we then need to go up in drums of three.
So Step three Next I then let's create a range variable for ourselves.
So let's dim RMG data as range and we can now inside the loop set our energy data equal to
God.
Tables don't tables.
I So we're living through a war the rather than tables.
Then we want the second road not rose to.
And let's target the first cell don't sells one and finally don't range.
What we're interested in here is the text inside the range and then the text inside the
range next to that and so forth.
So to target the text inside that cell,
we can now say orangey data text equals on.
Let's say it's going to be quarter 1/4 to etcetera.
So we have quarter m percent.
I mean,
I want 123 and four,
as opposed to a 369 and 12.
We can get that by divided.
I buy three and let's finish off with the word report that takes care of the text inside
the first cell in the second cell.
We want the author and let's use application.
Don't use the name for that.
So we've got our NGDATA set to the first cell,
and we now want to right into the second cell.
Fortunately,
the range object has a special method which enables us to do that.
It's the next method,
so we can simply say orangey data don't next.
And then we've got two parameters,
both optional.
But the charity will use both of them,
so the unit will be W.
D.
So and the count.
Well,
of course,
for the 1st 1 B one,
and I put a space.
But I've now realized that we haven't finished the statement.
So we will need to have brackets around these parameters so that we can now say not text
equals application,
Don't use the name.
And then we've got three more cells to do.
We have date,
do percent complete and department.
So we'll just copy this and increased account.
So here we want the day to do.
And let's say it's gonna be 30 days from the current date so we can generate it by saying
format now plus 30.
So now will give us the current date.
And then we had 30 days to it,
and then the format can simply be de de slash m m slash y y next.
We want percentage complete at this point in time,
it 0%.
And finally we have department,
which we said we were going to make I t.
So let's test our code.
You save and then run.
So there's November,
September gin and March.
Just one last thing to mention before we close this topic.
And that's a couple of special objects that you can use which refer to document objects.
First of all,
we have the active document,
which is self explanatory.
It's the document at the forefront in the Microsoft word interface.
And then we have this document,
which is a special object,
refer into the document that contains the macro that's currently running.
So let's write a quick macro,
which will test to see whether the macro is running in the active document.
Well,
not so I'm just gonna go back to full model view and then some 060 full be That's cool it
active documents and we can simply say it's active.
Document is this is a special key word that you use when you're comparing two objects you
can't be used.
For example,
on regular data variables,
that would be an equal sign.
It's purely for either document variables or document object references as me using here.
So if active document is this document,
then MSD box.
You're going current macro run in and active documents else chemistry box your name current
micro run in and another document and if so,
at the moment,
the active documents is tables.
And of course,
our macro is running in GCS word VB a training.
So when we run it,
we should get the second the elf that this document object is very useful because it means
that you can use that code in a different document and it will still run to reference.
An object within the collection by name used the syntax name of collection and in
parentheses.
Name of object.
To reference an object within a collection like position,
use the same text name of collection and in parentheses.
X,
where X is the position of the item within a document.
Position of an object within a collection corresponds to its position within its parents.
Object.
When an object is added to a collection,
it takes up position one in the collection and all other objects move up one place to
reference the last item in the collection.
Use the syntax name of collection and in parentheses.
Name of collection Don't count.