so far we've been created.
Code designed to be executed as and when required in this section will shift our attention
to a different style of coded where the code executes automatically based on events that
take place in the world environment.
This is called event programming,
and in this first video,
well,
just get an overview of how event programming works.
Let's go into the Exercises folder and then into the Section seven folder,
and here you'll find a file called Overview.
Let's go inside this.
It's simply a blank macro enable document.
So let's go to the visual basic editor on what we've been doing up till now is creating a
module or using a module that was already there.
And then inside the module,
we place outside procedure,
which automatically is treated as a macro.
We then run the macro as and when we need it.
Events up procedures.
A slightly different the first way have created them is to go inside the this document
object,
which you'll find inside every project.
For every document that you open in Microsoft Word.
You can either double click on that this document object Well,
you can right click and shoes view code to create some procedures,
you can either type them yourself or you could have them automatically generated for you at
least the shell,
obviously the code,
and you'll have to do yourself to do this.
You go to the object.
Drop down menu in the top left of the code window in twos.
Document the default document event handler Document New is then generated for you
automatically to create some procedures for other events.
Go to the procedure menu in the top,
right.
The other events relating to documents well open and clothes.
And obviously there's nothing to stop you creating these sub procedures completely manually
.
But these names have a special significance,
and these are the names that you have to use in your procedures in order to get your code
automatically to run when that particular event occurs.
Any code that you place in this some procedure will execute automatically when you close
this document.
If this document were a template when you close any documents based on that template,
the code will also run the document.
New sub procedure.
Apply specifically to templates.
Any code that you place inside this of procedure will run automatically when you create a
new document based on this template.
So let's test this functionality.
Currently,
we're working on a document rather than a template.
So this saad procedure won't apply.
And all we want to do for the moment is to have a line of code which should be executes.
So I'm just gonna say MSG Books goodbye and hello.
Although we can execute these sub procedures within the visual basic editor just to test
them from the user point of view,
it's really a case off these actions taken place document being closed,
the document being open or the document being closed.
So let's test that will close and up comes out Good bunny.
We click.
OK,
save our changes.
When we go back in,
up comes out.
Hello message.
Let's now save the document is a template,
so they will choose template.
And of course,
it has to be macro enabled.
We'll go back to the Section seven folder and save visual basic.
We can now reinstate our new sub procedure and to test it,
we could close and save.
So it's open a template weaken right click into his open to create a new document Based on
the template,
we can either choose new well,
we can just double click on it.
Up comes at a message.
If we now save the file,
you'll notice it's an ordinary document.
It doesn't need to be macro enabled.
And when we close it,
there's a goodbye message when we open it,
that's how.
Hello message.
Let's go back into our macro enable document.
So that's a quick look at how you can add code,
which executes automatically inside the this document object.
Let's just close the code window and let's look at the other way of implemented event
programming.
This is via user forms.
As with models,
you can right click on a project and then choose insert user form.
Or,
of course,
you can go to the insert menu and she's using form.
From there on the standard toolbar,
there's 1/3 method you can just from the insert button.
Here you can choose years of full up comes a default user form,
and also the toolbox window pops up for you if you close it at any time,
like all the other floating windows,
you make it visible black owns of the View menu and he ages.
Toolbox.
The use of form is basically a sophisticated dialogue box in which you can create
functionality similar to that found in dialogue boxes that you use in the Microsoft word
environment.
You can add any of these controls to the user form,
and you're then able to add CO two Your user Fall,
which enables you to create interactivity so that as the user interacts with the various
control,
your code responds and makes changes to the use of form itself two variables to the
document and indeed to the Microsoft word environment.
So let's create a really simple user for and obviously we'll get more sophisticated as we
go through the different tutorials in this section.
Going hand in hand with the toolbox on the user for itself is the properties window on any
control that you click on.
You'll see the properties appear relations of that control.
So the moment we have no control,
you've just got the user form itself,
and we can start my name in the use of form.
We'll use a three letter prefix of fr m for the full unless is cool.
It frm basic.
From here,
we can change the caption.
This is the text is displayed at the top of the form,
so we'll say a basic user form.
And then we had our controls.
So I'm just going to add a label tag by clicking on the label tool on the toolbox and then
just by either clicking or dragon on the form itself that I can change the caption.
Either here or I could go back into the properties window,
make my changes there.
Whatever is convenient.
So let's just put please and your name and I'll just make that a bit wider and that a text
box,
which is the next control along insolence,
the user can enter that name.
And finally,
I'll add a button.
Come on,
button.
Can I just click in and changing the caption to continue?
Let's just put that a bit closer to its label Ventoux.
Handsome functionality.
I can start by name in each of the controls,
using a prefix so unused lbl full label l VL name txt for text box Txt name and C M D for
command button.
Next someone to put some code on this button so that when they click it,
the code will execute.
To do that,
I double click on the control itself and that opens the user full code window and gives me
the default event handler for a command button.
And since the click event is the default,
that's the one I want.
If it weren't,
I go to the procedure.
Drop down menu and choose a different procedure on the object drop down menu.
I have access to each of the objects on the user form,
including the use of form itself.
When I choose any of these,
the default event handler is automatically created and the other events available for that
control a displayed on the procedure Drop down menu.
So I don't actually need this.
I'll just get rid of it when the user clicks to continue button.
All I want to say is Hello,
followed by the name that they've entered.
So MSG box,
hello ampersand to refer to controls on their properties.
I can use a special keyword inside the use of form,
which is me,
and this refers to the user form itself.
I could also say FRM basic,
but if I then take the code and place it somewhere else inside a different form of the
different name.
The code won't work.
I'll need to change the name to master new form by using the keyword me wherever I use this
code inside of form,
it always refers to that form.
The form that contains it tends me.
So I'm looking inside of textbooks.
I know that text boxes always start with txt because that's my name in convention,
so assumes eyesight.
Txt There it is.
Tab in goes the name.
And then I put a dot as per usual to drill down inside the control on the property that I
want,
the one that contains the text that the user has typed inside the control is the value
property and that's it.
The final thing is,
how do I actually make the user form itself visible?
Because this code will only execute when they click the button.
If they haven't seen the form,
they're not gonna click the button.
So in this example,
let's go back into this document and ice modify the document open.
So instead of giving a message,
it displays the use of form.
To do that,
we use the name of the four fr and basic,
not show okay,
lets test everything.
So I'm gonna close and save and then go back into the document.
Up comes the use of form,
and when I click continue,
I get my message and I can man just dismiss the full.
Okay,
so that's just a quick overview of event programming,
how you can create procedures which will execute automatically when a given event occurs in
the upcoming videos.
We're looking more detail at this process and look at ways in which event program it can be
used to.
Our benefit event program in refers to the creation of special sub procedures called event
handlers,
which,
triggered by actions taken place in the Microsoft Word environment code placed in the this
document object and inside user form objects executes automatically when the event
specified in the name of the men procedure occurs