before we take a closer look at use of forms,
Let's look at words built in dialogues.
Very often.
The functionality that you're looking for already exists in Microsoft Word,
so you can simply avail yourself of these built in dialogues from than having to reinvent
the wheel,
create your own user form.
Let's go back to the word VB,
a train in template and for our first example,
we're going to use the insert date time dialogue to allow the user to optionally insert the
date and time in their chosen format is part of our macron.
So let's open up the Section seven module and create our first macro.
So we're in tutorial three Macro A.
That's cool.
It built in dialogues.
So in this simple macro will create a document,
asked the user for a title but also display the insert date time dialogue.
So if they want to,
they can insert the date using their preferred format.
So we'll digressive variables and finally,
ah,
dialogue Tlg dates as dialogue.
Then let's create a new documents,
and then we can set our Engy new to the range of that document.
Let's then ask the user for a title and let's insert the title into the document,
followed by a carriage return.
And finally,
let's deploy the head in one style.
So now we want to give the use of the option of insert in the date,
and obviously we wanted to go after the head in.
So this time we do need to use the selection object to position the cursor at the end of
the document.
To do that,
we can use the programmatic equivalent of control end,
which is selection,
not end key on.
Then the unit would be W D story.
And finally,
let's set the style to normal.
Now we're ready to display the dialogue.
It's a property of the application object,
and when you type the oven in brackets,
water completion displays all of the constant names for you.
The Dialogues collection is also member of Global's.
This means that application dot is optional,
so you'll probably find its most often admitted.
Having placed the customer in the correct position.
Well,
we then have to do is to display the dialogue and make it available to the user.
To do this,
we simply say the LG dates not show,
and from there the dialogue is displayed and behaves normally.
If they use a cancels,
nothing happens.
If they click OK,
then whatever date style they've chosen will be inserted.
So let's save and let's test it.
Let's choose that goes out of style and let's look at the results.
Stairs are headed and there's our chosen date.
V B.
A also offers an alternative method of displaying a dialogue whereby when the user clicks
okay,
the options they've chosen aren't actually executed.
However,
those options are available to you,
the programmer,
so you can actually read them and make use of them as you see fit.
So let's write a second macro and look at this type of functionality.
The example we're going to take is the user name.
Let's say that our macro will check the word user name and then insist that the user has to
enter their first name and last name as the user name.
So if it looks as though it's got the wrong format,
will automatically display the options for them to actually enter the correctly formatted
using name.
So basically,
we want this dialogue to appear for them to actually make the necessary choices.
Let's call this one dialogue without executes.
So let's dim our dialogue.
Tlg in vote,
Let's say as dialogue.
So the first thing we need to do let's just switch to procedure view here.
The first thing we need to do is to test whether the user name has the correct format.
And to do that,
we'll write a separate function to do the testing.
So let's say,
if our function on let's call our function validate named,
this function will return a Boolean value so we can say if validate name and then in
brackets,
as the argument for our function will pass Application.
Don't use the name if this equals false,
then will display a message box.
Here's in the prompt,
please,
and first and last names as word your name.
And let's use the buttons for an ITER with BB information.
Let's also change application.
Don't use the name as a sort of secondary prompt,
so application don't use the name equals so as a prompt.
When we display the dialogue,
we'll just have it saying first name,
space,
last name,
and each time we display the dialogue that prompt will stay there to tell the user what we
waiting for?
So now we're ready to actually display the dialogue.
So he said,
the LG Info Equal Teoh dialogues.
And the trick is,
of course,
remember in these or finding them.
I'll show you in a moment where you could look into help coming along.
So in tools options User in for and what we do This time,
instead of saying theology info dot show,
as we did last time,
we will now say D LG info dot display.
And the difference is that the display method will not cause any execution of the options
within the dialogue.
When the user clicks okay,
nothing will actually happen in the word interface,
however,
whatever options they've chosen are actually available for us to use,
said STI L g in for don't display.
So let's say what we've gone so far,
and at this point,
I'll just show you how you can actually check all of this rather cryptic syntax.
So when you go into the BB a help,
you need the word develop a reference and then concepts,
and then here just to get the sentence you can use built in dialogue box argument lists and
here you've got two columns.
So these Airil the constant names each constant,
represents one of words built in dialogues.
And then the argument lists relate to the options,
the names off the options within the document.
So if we scroll down to the one that we've just been working with,
so here it is,
you'll see that we have name,
initials address.
And,
of course,
the one that we're after is going to be named.
Okay,
so we now want to persistently display the dialogue until the user enters a valid user name
.
We could do this by put in this line inside a loop.
I do and just tap the line in and then close it with loop.
We then need a while or on until test.
Let's use until,
for argument's sake and the test is going to be controlled by our validate name function,
the function which will write in just a moment.
So until validates name on the parameter that we evaluated is gonna be d.
L g info dot name just to remind you why we're inside this dialogue.
And there are three parameters which the user can change.
And of course,
the name parameter will represent the user name.
So until the validate function returns true,
we'll keep Loop ID after the loot.
Completes with their need to use the execute,
function off the dialogue object.
And this is because we've used display to display it rather than show.
So when we use display,
basically there's no execute functionality.
So here we now need to say D LG info don't execute.
So now all we need to do is to write the function.
So I'm going to switch back to full body,
all of you and a scroll to the bottom half.
So this is gonna be private function validates name,
which requires a single string parameter.
Let's call it str name and which returns a Boolean value to do the validation.
I'm going to use the split function,
which takes a string and converts it to an array using the D limiter you specify.
So our deal emitter will be a space because we're looking for two words separated by a
space.
Let's declare the array that we're going to use.
Let's call it a str names and then open and close parentheses to indicate it's an array.
This will be a dynamic array because We're not sure how many elements were going to end up
with and that will be string.
Then we populated.
Str names equal split.
The thing was split in is str name.
That's the parameter that's been populated when the function is called and the D limiter is
a space.
We can then use the you bound function to test whether we've got the two items that were
actually looking for.
So we could say if you bound str names equals one.
Because,
of course,
if it does,
that means it's got two items Item zero on item one because the default lower index for an
array is zero because we ourselves haven't overridden that that default behavior will kick
it as well as the array having the right number of items.
We also need to test that we haven't got this string past is the parameter because that
would indicate that the user has simply got confused and left the prompt first name last
name in the user name books.
So let's copy that and just use a compound statement.
So and STL name are parameter is not equal to control V to paste bed.
So if those two things are true,
it looks good.
But before we go back and return a true value,
we just need to test the length so we can do a one line if statement to that.
If Len a.
Str names brackets zero that's the first item.
Closed brackets for lend is greater than one,
and Len str names one.
The second item also have has a length greater than one.
Then it's safe to return true and to return a value,
you simply put the name of the function badly.
They name equal to the value in question,
which will be true else.
Validate name equals falls and if so,
we're now ready to test our macro,
let's just save our changes.
Let's make sure we've got an invalid name in there to start with,
so I'll just copy my initials.
So you know,
I got an invalid user name in there.
Cause out macro to enter the prompt and go into the loop for us.
I'm comes our MSG box,
and when we click OK,
in goes out prompt.
So let's put an invalid name in there and back comes the dialogue until eventually were
forced to put in a valid name.
And when we click OK,
the execute then kicks in.
So if I checked the user name again,
you'll see it has actually been changed.
The application dot Dialogues collection contains Microsoft words built in dialogues,
each identified by a W D Word dialogue Constant index,
for example,
Dialogues WD dialogue Insert date time.
If the dialogue dot show method is used to display a dialogue,
it behaves normally and executes the relevant commands when the user clicks.
Okay.
If the dialogue dot display method is used,
no commands are executed when the user clicks.
Okay,
however,
values entered in the dialogue can be retrieved,
using the constant names from the argument list to verify the constant names in the
argument list.
For each of words dialogues,
see the help topic Word 2013.
Developer Reference Concepts built in dialogue box argument lists