in this video,
we'll take a closer look.
It created a use of form and at in various different types of control to the user form
we've already encountered.
Labels and text boxes in this video will work with combo boxes,
option buttons,
check boxes and spin buttons.
Let's go into the Exercises folder.
Let's return to a word VB,
a training template and in the visual basic editor.
We simply right click on the project and insert a user form.
Now we can start by set in the properties of the form itself.
Let's give it a name.
There were in Section seven,
Tutorial four a.
Let's call it F R M Book because the theme that will be using is the creation of a book.
The user will be able to enter the title in the author of the book,
Choose the Size,
set the properties for the title and all the text on,
and then click OK to create the book.
Next we can enter a caption.
It's always better than having it's say Use a form one.
So let's say create book.
If you know you want to use a particular forms as the default,
then you can just click here into something different from the built in default off to
Homer,
we'll leave it as is similarly,
If you wanted a different text color,
then you could choose it from this drop down.
If you want a specific height and with you consigned them in where you can just use the
resize handles to resize is you go.
So let's go for 300 by 300.
And that is,
of course,
pixels.
So that's our form set up.
Now we can think about our controls.
So the top I'm gonna have a large text box into which they contrite the title of the book
and then above the text box,
they'll be able to choose the font,
the size and whether they weren't bold italic.
So let's put a label in here that will be titled.
Then let's have a text box below that all the way across,
and let's limit the font size to 24 to 36 in increments of North 0.5.
So if 36 is the maximum,
let's say we want to have two lines of text.
You normally need something like 1.5 times the font size in pixels to accommodate that
particular size.
So we've got 36 as the max 1.5 times 36 is 36 plus 18 which is 54.
So let's say we want to lines of text.
That's gonna be 100 night.
So we set the height off the books 2108 So now above the box,
we want to have the formed attributes.
So I'm just gonna hold down the control key and just drag Sure you come across this in
other contexts,
control drag to copy.
And then this will be front and we won't next to it.
That dropped down for them to choose the front.
So here's the combo box that will give us a drop down,
and I'll just click to create it on reposition it and make it a bit wider.
Next,
we'll have the phones,
and what we'll do here is we'll have a text box first of all like so,
and this could be very swollen just wide enough to display two significant numbers and a
decimal,
and next to that will have this very useful control called a spin button.
This is the control just here.
Let me show you how it works.
So we just drag out to draw.
To control the same height is the textbooks.
We could just not that up against the textbooks like so So the idea is the user is now
gonna be able to click on these tiny arrows to increase in,
decrease the font size,
and we'll lock the text box so they can actually type in the number.
And then finally,
here.
Let's have Boulder,
right,
Alec,
as check boxes.
So we click on the track box tool and create a check box,
which only needs the letter.
B for Bold doesn't need to be anywhere near its.
Why does that?
So we could just move that next to the boned size while it's highlighted.
I'm just going to go into the phones and make that bold.
Then,
having got the size correct,
I'm going to control drag to get a copy.
You'll probably find if you try control shift.
Can you see how the plus sign disappears?
So it's logical to assume that control shift will give you a copy aligned horizontally but
the original aligned vertically with the original.
But in fact,
it doesn't work,
so you can just use the grid to align,
and then it's just controlling its own to copy.
So here we want Italic I,
and I'll just switch off bold on her metallic or a bleak.
Instead,
let's select all of those.
You'll notice that when you drag select,
you don't need to enclose the objects you want to select.
You simply need to define a rectangle which touches them,
and then that select all of them and use full.
That's the line bottoms.
So now we can copy all of these and modify it for the author.
So just drag select,
hold down the control key A and distract down to copy.
This now becomes author.
Or perhaps authors like so.
And let's say that the limits this time in terms of font size are going to be 14 to 24.
So 24 to the max 1.5 times 24 is 36.
And let's say we only need one line so we can set the height 2 36 and finally,
in this area at the bottom,
we can put our different book sizes,
so I'm just gonna control drag to get a copy of my label.
Let's just put in book size,
and this time we use in option buttons or radio buttons,
as they called in every other environment.
So let's just click to create the 1st 1 Ah,
let's change this to five.
My eight.
We can decrease the height slightly,
then control drag to get a copy.
Ah,
let's make the 2nd 1 5.75 by 8.25 We'll do four in total.
So let's copy these to control track to the right.
This one can then become 5.5 by 8.5.
And then finally,
this could be six by nine.
So those are full size is.
And finally,
let's put in ah,
couple of command buttons.
So this will be the okay button.
Let's make it creates.
Then we can take the size down control drag up and on the co P.
We could change the caption to cancel.
Let's just a line.
The bottom edges off these three Eisen's so I'm just gonna drag,
select and in the format menu.
I haven't actually gone over these options,
but they're very self explanatory,
and here we need a line bottom edges.
I think we have got a better result if the create button had moved up to align with these
rather than vice versa.
So let's don't do on the order of selection is what determines it.
So if I drag from left to right,
this is the last item to be selected.
And then when I do for Matalin Bottoms,
it moves up to align with these.
So that's our form.
Now we can think about renaming all the controls I say renaming because no control that you
had to use a form it's ever without a name.
The program simply assigns their name to the controls as you create them.
So textbooks one textbooks to label one label to etcetera.
So what we'll do is to name everything,
give everything a meaningful name.
So when we're working with code,
we can identify each item very quickly based on recognising the naming conventions that
we've used.
So even though we're not gonna actually do anything to,
the labels will still give them a name and we'll use the prefix lbl so lbl title,
lbl font,
or to be going precise lbl title funds.
I'll be a law tha LBO author Front and finally lbl size.
Then we've got our textbooks is T X t will be the prefix txt title and txt also.
Then we've got out two text boxes here said Txt.
Title size and txt author size.
Next,
let's to our combo boxes.
So CBO is a common prefix.
CBO title funds CBO author funds next less to our spin buttons.
So he's basically going to be the same idea as our text boxes because they obviously marry
up.
And we just use Spn as the prefix So spn,
or the size when our check boxes chk as a prefix.
So title be and Skytel.
By then we have author B and author I.
Next we can do our option buttons.
So I hoped five by eight up to five by 85 0 55 my 85 off six by nine on Finally,
we've got our command buttons CMD cancel on and creates