when working with user forms.
One of the things you have to bear in mind is that the user won't always enter data in the
format with a range or when the attributes that you want them to.
In this video,
we'll look at ways of validating user input.
Here's the form that we created and worked on in the last two videos,
and although we haven't directly addressed the question of validation,
the form does include some validation already.
For example,
here we've made it impossible for the user to enter non numeric values all values outside a
given range.
And we've done all this a design time purely by lock in the tax boxes.
So we've set the locked property to true.
And then here on the spin buttons,
which control the value in the textbooks.
We've actually got a max and the men,
so it's impossible for the user to go outside the specified range.
Another example of this type of design time validation can be found on combo boxes.
Let's run the combo box,
and the name combo box implies that it's a combination.
It's a combination of a drop down list and the text box which means that weaken type,
a non existent fund,
which is clearly undesirable.
So let's look at how we can stop that from happening.
If we highlight both of these combo boxes using click on the Control click in the
Properties window,
we have the style attributes,
and you'll see we can either have drop down combo or drop down list.
And if we true's drop down list,
then all we can do is to choose one of the options we can't actually type on option One
undesirable consequence of what after stun is that I've managed to wipe the two values that
we had in place,
so I'll just reinstate those.
This one was impact.
This one was times New Roman and let's test it.
So now when I type as soon as I saw happen,
end it drums down to the first font,
beginning with N.
It doesn't let me actually type of value,
so a lot of validation can be performed simply by the way you designed the form and what
you end up with our maybe just a few text fields that need validation.
So you've got a test that certain fields have numbers in them certain fields have dates in
them,
that sort of thing.
So for our example,
let's say we just want to test that the title and author aren't left blank and don't exceed
a limit of,
let's,
say,
50 characters.
There is actually a max length property,
so we could use that in exactly the same way as we have been designed time.
But let's say that since we do,
invalidation will do all the validation in code rather than it designed time.
So let's go back to our create button code and at the top of this event handler,
let's put some code which will call a validate function,
and we can have the validate function return in a 1,000,000,000 value or another technique
,
which is the one I'm going to show you is tohave it,
return a string.
If the string is blank,
that means there are no errors,
and if the string isn't blank,
it will actually contain the error messages,
which we then display.
So to hold the error messages will create a variable called STR Errors has strength,
and then we'll call our function,
which were right in a moment.
Str errors equals Let's call it validate form.
This is the function well right in the moment and that we could test the result.
If STL errors is not blank,
then the display.
An error message.
MSG box str errors which may contain one or more error messages,
perhaps each on a separate line.
And then we can exit the sub so nothing else happens.
And if so now,
I'm just gonna go down to the bottom of the code window and add in our function private
validate form,
and it won't need to accept any parameters because it's going directly to the form,
but it will need to return a string value.
So after the closing parentheses as string,
I want to switch across to procedure view.
Now we need to have a string variable in which we can build our error messages so I'll use
the same name,
which,
of course,
is not a problem,
because we're now in a separate procedure.
Them str errors as strange,
and then we just test out two text boxes.
So let's start with the title,
and we could just use the Len property to test how many characters there are.
So if len me dot txt title don't value.
So let's say we've got a minimum for the title of five characters.
So if it's less than five and we can just copy this,
don't really think we need to go into a separate line.
So lives Thea continuation character and just paste it in there.
So the other limit we said waas 50 So or it's greater than 50 then str errors the calls
please and a title between five and 50 characters and if and then we just do the same for
the author copy paste paste,
txt,
Orthodox value So now we want to return.
Str errors on what I will do as well is just to explicitly specify that str Errors at the
start equals the null string and to return str errors We simply is the name of the function
Validate form equals str errors One error I've made is that here I've potentially wiped the
first error So if this is an error,
I set str errors on this line.
But if this is also an error,
I simply overwrite str errors on this line so very simple This should be str eras equals
str Errors lie the existent value and percent.
The new value and what we can also do is just to spread these out on two separate lines.
I put in ampersand B B C off at the end,
maybe twice to leave a blank line.
So that's a simple example off how you can set up validation so it starts when they click,
we call the function,
and the return value goes into our local str errors,
the warm local to this some procedure.
If it's not the null string,
we display it and we exit the sub.
In other words,
we do none of this,
so let's just save our changes and test form.
So I'm gonna leave in both blank click on create and you'll see we've got out,
too.
Error message lines coming in there.
If I complete one,
then I left with just one.
It is possible to implement validation of user form controls that design time by making it
impossible for users to enter undesirable data in the first place.
An efficient way of validating all of the fields in the use of form,
which may contain erroneous values,
is to create a function which returns either a Boolean value or a string containing error
messages if there is a found or the null string.
If no errors have found