before you share your macro solutions with colleagues or clients,
it's always a good idea to think about shielding them from any unpleasant surprises on one
of the standard unpleasant surprises possible with Macros is that your users will encounter
sister mirrors when they try to run Your Mac.
Rose in this video will discuss ways in which you can implement error handling techniques
to prevent users from encountering such errors.
We'll also discuss debugging techniques that you can use to track down these errors in the
first place.
Let's go into the Section eight folder,
and here you will find that we already have a macro to work with.
Before we discuss this macro,
let's just talk a bit about what error handling attempts to achieve.
And the first thing to point out is that error handling really is designed to deal with run
time errors kind of Aris that people who run your Mac Rose may experience syntax and
compilers should be cleared up long before you get to the stage of actually thinking about
era Hedley.
So let me just remind you what syntax and compile hours are.
Let's just create a temporary sub.
Let's create a variable called STR and instead of type in strength,
let's make a deliberate typo put strength.
Then let's do another type SRT instead of str equals input box.
Please enter your name on.
Let's deliberately forget to close the parentheses now as soon as I leave this line,
of course,
the syntax era is indicated and that line will stay red until it's corrected.
So that's very straightforward.
The two compilers will be picked up as soon as I test.
The macron is the first usually find type not found.
There is no such thing as strong,
so that's reset and correct that one.
And then we run again.
Variable not defined just to remind you the thing that's flag in,
that is the option explicit.
So this means that I have to define or variables.
And of course,
I didn't define this.
I defined this so there We have examples of very straightforward syntax and compile errors
,
and these you'll clear up long before you think about actually releasing your solutions and
sharing them with your colleagues or your clients.
You may need to use some of the debunking techniques,
which will be discussed later in this section in order to track down some of the compile
hours,
but most of them common sense will actually enable you to solve them.
So let's delete that nights now turn our attention to run time errors.
These the more serious errors on the kind of errors that you want to shield your audience
from.
So in this macro,
what's happening is that we are first of all opening up the document,
and the document in question is accessed from the folder that contains this document.
In other words,
our word.
VB.
A training template.
Let's have a look at that document.
It's in the section eight older and it's called Students Schools,
and it contains a table with number one exams taken and total school.
Al Macro,
first of all,
opens this document,
and it does so based on its location and the name of the file,
and then loops through the table,
starting on road to,
And it calculates the school the sort of average school by dividing the contents off column
three by the Convents off column,
too,
and then calculates a grade based on the school that it's the average called.
It's calculated.
It then works out the great to the personal and finally rights that grade into column four
off the table so it's taken.
Column three.
United it by call them,
too.
Calculating the Great based on that average pop in the grade into column four.
So let's see it working when everything's in place.
So where we run it populates The Falls column with the appropriate grade.
Now it's close without saving.
And let's think about situations where if someone else was running this macro,
they could get an error.
And,
of course,
the most obvious one is it.
The file in question is not in place or if someone has put it in the right folder,
but given it their own name,
let's just simulate that situation.
Let's remove the S so the file no longer exists.
And,
of course,
when we run,
we get a run.
Fine ERA number 5174 And this time we have a fairly user friendly Arab message,
it explains.
We come and find your file.
Maybe it was moved,
renamed or dilated,
and then it gives the path to the file that it's trying to open.
In spite of it being fairly friendly this time,
we don't really want the user to be exposed to this title era,
and it's this kind of situation.
That era Hamlin is designed to prevent.
What happens when in error occurs was determined by a statement called On era Go to and the
default statements which kicks in.
If you make no provision for error,
handling is on error.
Go to zero.
So,
in other words,
go to a non existent line.
Heads,
let V b A.
Let's just put a comment in here that vb a handle errors.
And if you do nothing,
then on error,
go to zero is the statement,
which is in effect.
So the only time you ever need to use on their ago 20 is if you yourself have taken over
error handling and you then want to reinstate the default behavior.
Let V b A have letters from that all so clearly,
with or without this statement,
if we run it,
we know we're gonna get V B.
A displayed an era.
So let's just take that out of the picture.
Just make it into a comment line and let's look now at how we can take over error handling
shield the user from the visual basic editor.
I'm just display a user friendly era message.
So handlers ourselves,
we use the statements on era.
Go to label.
Onda label basically is a name which you could give to any points within a sub procedure.
Haven't created a label.
You can at any point say,
go to that label to use this technique in normal programming.
This very bad practice and the only time you should use it is in this type of error
handling that we're discussing.
So first of all,
we come up with a name for the label on one just called era.
Happily,
the usual restrictions for names apply no spaces letters on Underscore character,
only the position where you place your labels should be just above the end sub.
So I just put in the name that I've said.
I'm gonna use error handling and to tell baby it's a label you simply put a kulak.
So whenever you say go to Sara Hamlyn,
it's going to go to that label and execute the lines that follow that label.
And let's just display an error message.
Let's have VB critical as the buttons style.
I'll go to simply takes us to our handling.
So if this is always put,
the next thing that's gonna happen is the end of the celebrity.
So we test our code again,
we get our message cannot continue,
and that's an end of it.
One thing to bear in mind is that there's nothing special about this line.
It's still part off the sub procedure.
So in the normal circumstances,
the compiler will actually get to this line.
If there isn't an error and it will display this under normal circumstances,
let's just prove that well,
I'm just going in here and reinstate in the S so that the name is now correct.
So this time our error handling won't kick in drugs because it's part of the subroutine.
This line is still going to execute.
Let's just test that so it opens the file.
As you can see,
it's popped all the grades incorrectly.
But because this line is part of the subroutine,
it's still displays the era so clearly what we've got to do is to stop that from happening
.
Let's just close the students schools without saving and to stop it from happening,
we simply need to make sure that we always exit sub prior to the era handling label.
Let's just put a comment in there and then let's test again.
So this time it opens the file pockets the great in but doesn't display the Arab message.
Okay,
so that's a very basic technique that you can use to implement error handling in the next
couple of videos.
Well,
look at a few permutations on this basic theme.
Let's just do one last thing before we finish this video that's going to tools options.
And then in the general time you'll see here,
we've got this protracted section and by default,
break on.
Um,
handled errors is switched on.
So this means,
basically that any time you override the default on our go to zero v B,
A R handling won't kick in.
If your code includes those statements,
all reviews the statements on Eric Co 20 Then,
of course,
V be able handle errors if you have ever handling in place.
But for debugging purposes,
you want to deliberately look at every single error.
Then you can override your own our handling by switching on this option,
break on all errors.
This,
of course,
means that any time you have got error handling,
it simply ignored VB a handles or errors.
And of course,
it's then very important that you remember that you have got this option switched on.
And when you've finished your debugging session,
you'll then go back to break off level errors.
Another typical situation is where you get a client or colleague who's reported that they
constantly get in errors,
which take them into the visual basic editor.
Even though you know you have our handling in place annual solution and it's worth checking
with them by talking them through,
just ask them to look in tools.
General see which Aaron trapping option is currently set on the machine that they use in
and obviously,
if necessary,
Anson to put it back to the default break on handled errors.
The statements on air ago 20 is used to reinstate Phoebe a default error handling,
whereby a system error messages displayed in the visual basic editor.
The statements on air ago to label is used to transfer code execution to the label.
All labels should be placed at the end of the sub procedure and the statement exit.
Some should be placed above each label to prevent the code that follows them from executing
.
When no errors are encountered