in this video,
we'll turn our attention to the business of debugging tracking down errors When you can't
get your coat to work properly,
we'll begin by looking at two techniques for are put in important messages,
which you can use to monitor key aspects of your code.
MSG box and debug dot print In the Exercises folder and in the 08 debugging and air
handling sub folder,
go find a file called Debug in practice,
and you'll probably recognize this from the previous exercise.
We go into the visual basic editor and into the Models folder.
You'll find that Model one contains a simple macro,
which attempts to delete all the tables,
and it does so by starting a table one and working its way up to table 12.
And as you probably remember,
I pointed out that if you attempt to do this because you'll remove in objects halfway
through,
you'll get an error because having deleted six tables if you attempt to delay Table seven,
it no longer exists.
So we're treating slightly here because we actually know the solution to the problem.
But let's look at how we can monitor how we can create output which allows us to monitor
what's going on as our program runs so that we can see exactly when and why the program
actually breaks.
So what we'll do is to take all of this code and just copy it.
And let's just rename the copy.
Yeah,
let's call it MSG box output.
So inside Al Loop,
we want to introduce some debug in statements,
and the first thing that we want to do is to make sure that our debug in statements don't
produce any errors.
So we're going to disable error handling within the context of our debugging,
and you'll remember from our previous videos in this section.
To do that,
we can say on error resume next.
Then,
after our debugging statements,
we reinstate normal baby air handling by saying on error,
go to zero.
So let's now place Ah debug in statements between those two lines and are we going to do?
To start with here is to create an MSG box which outputs key information on the two key
bits of information in this context that we want to monitor how many tables remain and
which table are we currently attempting to delete?
What I'm also going to do because we want to actually see within the document what's about
to be deleted.
We'll also select the table.
So let's just copy this statement.
This document all tables I don't select and then up comes out message box.
So let's say tables remaining Empress end paste.
And this will of course,
be this document dot tables don't count.
Then it's going to a new line on,
then table to be deleted.
This time we only really need I.
So there's our monitoring statement.
Let's save because,
of course,
when we run,
we're gonna mess up our documents.
They will want to revert to the saved version so important to save before tested.
So first table,
January 12 remaining table one about to be deleted because Jonah has been dilated,
March now becomes table to which is the next to be deleted.
Now may become stable.
Three July becomes full,
September becomes five,
and this is the last table that we can successfully delete.
We've got all the way up to November because we're constantly delete in tables so November
will be debated.
But of course,
now we're in trouble.
We've got six tables remaining and we're attempting to delete Table seven.
So the statement this document on tables I don't select will have failed,
but because we've got on Air a resume next.
That's the only reason we haven't had an error as yet.
But of course,
as soon as I click OK v b A era Hamlin has been reinstated,
so I get the normal era.
Okay,
so that's an example of how you can use be humble Msde Reebok statement to just monitor
what's going on as your macro is running,
let's just close without saving and then go straight back in.
And let's compare the MSG box with the other method of output in which is debug dot print.
The problem with that mystery box,
as you can imagine,
is that if there are a lot of MSG box statements,
you're constantly having to click.
OK,
etcetera.
So if you imagine we had a couple of 100 of these to do clearly,
we wouldn't want to have a mystery box popping up 200 times.
So this is where deep Abdullah print becomes useful.
Instead of displaying a dialogue,
it's simply creates a textual report,
which you can then look at after your code has run.
So let's look at how it works.
Let's copy all of this on.
Just change that to be and change this to deep out print.
So because we're no actually looking at the document while the codes run in,
we don't need to select the table that's about to be deleted on.
All we need to do is to replace MSG box with debug dot print and to assist readability.
I'm also gonna put an extra carried return at the end of the statement so that each pair of
lines will be separated by a blank line and that's it again,
I'm going to save before running so we can revert in the same session.
When we run,
we go straight to the error because obviously it's quite a quick process.
We end and to monitor the report that's been generated,
we simply going to view immediate window,
and here we can see the output created by the debug dot print statement.
So als the statements that were coming up in the msde Reeboks we can now monitor and we can
look for a pattern.
And of course,
when we get to this line,
we can see exactly where the problem occurs.
Only six tables remain in and we're attempting to delete table seven.
So typically,
once you've looked at the output created in the immediate window,
you get a bit closer to solving.
The problem I want you,
Then do is to select all and delete.
So control a select all.
Just delete it.
Ready for maybe modifying your debug dot print statements to get closer to solving the
problem.
Just to remind you about solving the problem.
By the way,
I hope you remember the solution to this problem.
You simply reverse these two and then add step minus one.
So you're starting with the highest number working your way down to the lowest.
Hence the item that your targeting always exists because you haven't yet deleted it.
But we are just using this purely to discuss techniques for monitoring code as we're trying
to isolate a problem.
So I'm now gonna close this without saving in case we need to test it again.
The MSG box function is a useful and versatile tool for debugging code,
allowing you to output key monitoring information while a macro is running the debug dot
print function can be used as an alternative to a mystery box when the output messages
would become irritatingly frequent,
for example,
if you're in long inspirations.