As our sample application sits right now,
we're able to customize max attempts and back off,
which is great, but we're still retrying every type of failure.
Think about it.
Every HTTP 400 bad request error will be dutifully retried.
Typically, we want an HTTP 400 to fail immediately.
Can Spring Retry do that?
Absolutely.
Welcome back to Spring Retry: Getting Started, from Pluralsight.
My name is Tyler Griffiths,
and in this module we're going to add custom exception
handling to our Spring Retry implementation.
In the last module,
we saw that RetryTemplate allows us to set a retry
policy using the RetryPolicy interface.
The RetryPolicy interface is implemented by simple RetryPolicy.
We used one of simple RetryPolicy's constructors to specify max attempts.
But simple RetryPolicy has another constructor that allows
us to specify a map of exception classes that extend the
Throwable class as the key, and a Boolean as the value.
The Boolean indicates if the exception is retriable,
i.e., a true means retry this type of exception.
In this module, we will add custom retry exceptions to our RetryTemplate.
We will then look at different types of server errors and how they can be
handled individually with custom retriable exceptions.
By the end of this course module,
we'll have added custom retry exceptions to our SaaS Bass sample
application and completed SaaS Bass's wish list. Hurray!