To add Spring Retry to the Bass Tracker Service's LakeProfileClient,
we first need to add Spring Retry to our Maven dependencies.
Then,
we will create a RetryTemplate bean in our application bean config file
and pass it into the LakeProfileClient's constructor.
And lastly,
we'll wrap the RestTemplate methods in our
LakeProfileClient with the default RetryTemplate.
To follow along with this demo, for the Bass Tracker Service,
check out either the initial branch if you want to code along,
or the final branch if you want to follow along.
For the Lake Profile Service, we're not making any changes in this module,
so check out the branch with the module name.
If you have no idea what I'm talking about,
please refer to the Setup clip in the Getting Started with Spring Retry module,
which will walk you through cloning the repositories
and setting up the demo services.
If you're on the correct branch,
let's open the Bass Tracker Service and get started.
Here in our bass-tracker-service,
the first thing we want to do is navigate to our Maven
pom.xml file and find our dependencies block.
Then, we'll add the Spring Retry dependency.
Next, we'll navigate to the bass-tracker- service application file,
which is where we define our application beans.
Because we added the Spring Retry dependency to our pom.xml file,
we can now create a new RetryTemplate bean and import the RetryTemplate class.
This RetryTemplate bean doesn't have any customizations,
so it effectively inherits all retry defaults that we mentioned before.
Namely,
that it doesn't have a back off period and its max attempts is default to 3.
While we're here,
let's take the opportunity to pass the RetryTemplate
bean to the LakeProfileClient bean.
Now,
let's switch over to the LakeProfileClient class and
add RetryTemplate to its constructor.
Now that we have a RetryTemplate in the LakeProfileClient,
let's wrap the getForObject method in the RestTemplate's execute method.
We'll also add a log when a GET request is attempted
or a POST request is attempted.
Then, we'll do the same on the postForObject method.
That's it.
That's how simple it is to add retry to an existing HTTP client.
Now, let's see it in action.
The simplest way to test if retry is working is to run the Bass Tracker
Service without the Lake Profile Service running.
This effectively simulates the Lake Profile server being down,
so we should see that the Bass Tracker Service makes
three createLakeProfile requests, and then fails,
and three getLakeProfile requests, and then fails.
Let's run it and see what happens.
In the logs, we can count three create attempts with a failure,
and three get attempts with a failure. Very cool.