For our retryable exceptions,
we're going to use a whitelist strategy where we retry
everything unless we specify otherwise.
In this case,
we'll retry all RestClientExceptions except for HTTP 400 and 500 errors.
This is because if we've made a bad request,
no amount of retry will help, and if we encounter a 500 error,
we want to know about it immediately as it usually
indicates a major problem with our server.
On the other hand, if we encounter a 404 or 503 error,
that typically indicates a temporary state that would be good to retry.
To configure custom exceptions in our SaaS Bass sample application,
we first need to build our retryable exceptions map.
Then we can pass that into our existing SimpleRetryPolicy constructor.
Let's get into the code and make it happen.
To follow along with this demo,
for the Bass Tracker Service check out either the
initial branch if you want to code along,
or the final branch if you want to follow along.
For the Lake Profile Service, we're not making any changes in this module,
so check out the branch with the module name.
Here in our bass-tracker-service,
we want to create a new map with the key as something that
extends throwable and the value as a Boolean.
Then, we'll insert RestClientException class and set its value to true,
indicating that we want to retry all rest client exceptions.
Then,
we'll insert HttpClientErrorException.BadRequest .class and set it to false,
indicating that we do not want to retry HTTP 400 errors.
Lastly,
we'll insert HttpServerErrorException.InternalServerError
.class and set its value to false as well,
which should account for not retrying HTTP 500 errors.
Now, as a very basic example,
let's switch over to lake-profile-service and throw a socket
exception on getLakeProfile and run it.
Then, let's switch back to bass-tracker- service and run that.
We can see that our RetryTemplate didn't retry the getLakeProfile request.
This is because throwing a socket exception maps to an HTTP 500 error,
and we told RetryTemplate not to retry 500 errors.
So it's behaving as we would expect.
Custom exceptions are a powerful way to fine tune your retry framework for error handling.