Now that we have our SaaS Bass sample application set up and running,
let's dissect it to see how it's constructed.
First, a little background about SaaS Bass.
SaaS Bass has moved away from a monolithic application,
literally running on a single server, to a distributed microservice architecture.
This has enabled SaaS Bass to scale to handling
millions of transactions per second.
It's also allowed them to organize their application architecture in a
way that can be handed off to domain-specific teams,
which makes adding new features easier, faster,
more reliable, and scalable.
The SaaS Bass sample application represents a portion
of their microservice architecture,
focusing on two services named Bass Tracker Service and Lake Profile Service.
At a high level,
the Bass Tracker Service is able to create and request a lake profile.
It does this using Spring's RestTemplate,
which is an HTTP client implementation.
It then creates a lake profile using an Http POST call to the
lake profile endpoint and requests a lake profile using an
HTTP GET call to the same endpoint.
Let's open the Lake Profile Service and Bass Tracker
Service in IntelliJ and take a look.
The Lake Profile Service consists of a main application class,
an endpoint class, a LakeProfile model class,
a LakeProfileRepository class, and a properties file.
Let's look at each class in turn.
The LakeProfileServiceApplication class is the starting
point for a Spring Boot application, and as you can see,
it simply starts the Spring Boot application running.
The Endpoint class is where the getLakeProfile and
postLakeProfile endpoints live.
Looking at the GET endpoint,
we can see that it requires a profileId PathVariable.
It then queries the lakeProfileRepository for the requested
lakeProfile by its ID and returns a JSON representation of the
lakeProfile with an HTTP 200 return code.
The POST endpoint accepts a JSON representation of a new lakeProfile to create.
The lake-profile repository is an in-memory database for this demo,
so we add a 2 second sleep to simulate real-world database
latency before persisting the new lakeProfile.
Why we do this will become evident later in the demo.
LakeProfileRepository extends CrudRepository,
which is a basic datastore interface that provides us with
CRUD methods such as findById and Save.
There's some underlying magic that happens to provide
those CRUD methods that we can't see here,
but the important thing to note is that the repository entity is a
LakeProfile and the ID type used for LakeProfiles is type Long.
The other thing to note, as previously mentioned,
is that by default, LakeProfileRepository is persisting to an in-memory database,
meaning that if we terminate the application,
the lake profiles we created via the POST endpoint are gone.
The LakeProfile model class is annotated as a JPA entity,
meaning it can be persisted to our in-memory database.
We use a few other JPA annotations to indicate which field is the primary key,
autoincrement its value,
and to specify the column names we want to use on the database table.
We are also using the @JsonInclude annotation so that we can
serialize and deserialize this object from a JSON
representation on our POST and GET endpoints.
The last file is our properties file,
which has a single entry for the server port,
which as you can see is port 8080.
Now, let's switch over to the bass-tracker- service and look at the code for it.
Looking at the structure of the application,
we can see that we have a main application class,
a LakeProfileClient, a LakeProfile model class,
and a properties file.
Looking at the main application class,
we can see that it's more complex than the LakeProfile service.
Aside from starting the Spring Boot application,
we've added a Logger, as well as a LakeProfileClient bean,
and a CommandLineRunner bean.
Let's look at how LakeProfileClient is constructed first,
and then we'll come back to the CommandLineRunner bean,
as it's the main driver for our demo.
The LakeProfileClient bean accepts a URL for the LakeProfile service,
a connectionTimeout, and a readTimeout.
These parameters are specified in the properties file,
which we'll look at in a minute.
We then construct an HttpComponentsClientHttpRequestFactory and pass
that along with the URL to the LakeProfileClient's constructor and
return a constructed LakeProfileClient.
The LakeProfileClient is basically a wrapper around Spring's RestTemplate,
which is a RESTful HTTP client implementation.
LakeProfileClient has two methods,
one for getting a LakeProfile and another for creating a LakeProfile.
The LakeProfile class has the same fields as the
LakeProfile class we saw in LakeProfileService.
We've overridden the toString method so that we can
see the object when it's logged.
Our properties file has the Bass Tracker Service port,
the base URL of the Lake Profile Service,
a readTimeout, and a connectionTimeout.
The connectionTimeout and readTimeouts configure the
LakeProfileClient to wait for up to 1 second for a connection and up
to 3 seconds of inactivity between two data packets.
Going back to BassTrackerServiceApplication,
let's examine the CommandLineRunner bean.
We create a new thread in which to POST a new
LakeProfile to the LakeProfile endpoint.
We do this in its own thread to simulate a real-world
environment in which we could be making requests
simultaneously and need to account for that behavior.
We then sleep for 3 seconds before getting the LakeProfile we created,
and logging it.
We sleep for 3 seconds because that's 1 second more than the 2 second
simulated database latency we added to LakeProfileService.
This ensures that we won't have a resource race condition and
get a 404 error due to the LakeProfile not having had a chance
to be created before we get it.
That concludes the tour of our SaaS Bass sample application.
Next,
we'll tweak this sample application to simulate the pain points SaaS Bass is experiencing.