Now that we've implemented custom policies,
let's examine which of SaaS Bass's pain points are alleviated by retry.
We'll start by simulating socket exceptions.
In SaaS Bass's case, socket exceptions are caused by a temporary server overload.
To follow along with this demo, for the Bass Tracker Service,
check out the adding-custom-retry-policies-socket-exception branch.
For the Lake Profile Service,
also check out the adding-custom-retry-policies-socket-exception branch.
Here in the Lake Profile Service's Endpoint class,
we've simulated a temporary server overload by throwing a socket exception
the first two times each POST and GET request are made.
After the first two attempts,
the GET and POST endpoints can proceed handling their requests.
Let's run the lake-profile-service.
Now, let's switch over to the bass-tracker-service.
We haven't made any modifications for this simulation,
so we should expect that the CommandLineRunner will attempt to
create the Lake Profile in a separate thread,
wait for 3 seconds, and then try to get the newly created profile.
If either request fails, it should retry up to three times.
Let's run it and see what happens.
Sure enough,
we see that each request is attempted three times and we are able
to create and get the lake profile successfully.
The interesting thing to note here is that we saved ourselves about
6000 ms using an exponential back off policy compared to a fixed back
off policy with a 1000 ms back off period.
Six hundred milliseconds may not sound like much, but that's a significant time savings in the context of an API call stack.