In this section,
we're going to test a repository that connects to a
SQL database with hand-written SQL.
Spring Boot provides a lot of functionality out of the box for us
to support our database and JDBC connections.
First, when Spring Boot finds the H2 library in our class path,
it automatically creates an instance of H2 and a data source object
that allows us to persist data to and from H2.
Next, because we define a schema SQL file in our project,
Spring Boot will automatically execute it for us to create our tables.
Then, because our repository requires a JdbcTemplate,
Spring Boot will create a JdbcTemplate for us and wire it into our repository.
Finally, when we create our repository,
we specify that we want both a data source and a JdbcTemplate so they will
both be autowired directly into the repository for us.
The product repository provides the following set of
functionality: It provides two methods to find products,
findAll, which returns all products in the database,
and findById, which returns the product with the specified ID.
It provides a save method that persists new products to the database,
it provides an update method that updates an existing product,
and finally, it defines a delete method that deletes a product from the database.
Let's take a look at the source code for the product
repository and see how it works.
First we're going to look at the project's POM file to see
how we added support for the H2 database,
then we're going to look at the schema SQL file that Spring
Boot will discover in our class path and subsequently create
the schema for us in the H2 database, and finally,
we're going to review the product repository source code.
The first thing we want to look at is our project's Maven POM file.
When I set up the project on start.spring .io,
I chose both JDBC and H2 in the list of dependencies.
So we can see that the Spring Initializr included the
spring-boot-starter-jdbc and the h2 dependencies in the POM file.
By default, the h2 dependency is included with a test scope,
so I changed it to runtime so that we can run the
microservice against the h2 database at runtime.
If you intend to run against a production SQL database,
such as MySQL or Oracle, then you can leave that set to test.
Now let's look at the schema SQL file.
The schema.sql file if located in the src/main/resources folder.
When Spring Boot scans the class path, it'll find this file,
see that we have an H2 database in our class path,
and execute the script against an H2 instance.
In this case, we create a single table, products,
with an id, name, quantity, and version number.
In previous versions of Spring, without Spring Boot,
you would need to explicitly point to this SQL script
when defining your data source, but Spring Boot will handle this for us.
As with most Spring resources,
we build our repository using both an interface and an implementation class.
The ProductRepository interface defines five methods: findById returns an
optional product for the product instance with the specified ID,
or Optional empty if a product cannot be found.
FindAll returns a list containing all products in the database.
Update updates a product in the database and returns true if the
update was successful or false if it was not.
Save saves a new product to the database and returns
the product instance that was saved,
which includes the automatically generated ID.
Finally,
the delete method deletes the product with the specified ID from the database,
and returns true if the delete operation was successful.
The ProductRepositoryImpl class implements the ProductRepository interface
and is annotated with Spring's Repository annotation.
Spring uses this annotation to identify this class as a
Spring-managed bean and adds it to the application context.
The ProductRepositoryImpl defines a constructor that accepts
both a JdbcTemplate and a data source.
The JdbcTemplate is used to execute our queries, our update, and our delete.
The dataSource is used to build a SimpleJdbcInsert object,
which will be used when inserting a new product to the database,
primarily because it can be used to return the automatically generated key.
The constructor saves the JdbcTemplate and the
SimpleJdbcInsert object to member variables.
The findById method executes the JdbcTemplate's queryForObject method,
passing it the sql: SELECT * FROM products WHERE id =?,
binding the ID to its ID argument.
It then provides a lambda implementation of a row mapper that
constructs a new product from the provided result set.
If everything works out correctly,
then it returns an optional product; otherwise,
it returns an Optional.empty.
The findAll method executes the jdbcTemplate's query method,
passing it the sql: SELECT * FROM products,
providing a similar lambda row mapper.
The update method executes the jdbcTemplate's update method,
providing an update SQL and binding its parameters to the provided object.
The jdbcTemplate update method returns the number of rows updated,
so the product repository's update method returns true if
the number of updated rows is equal to 1.
The save method leverages the simpleJdbcInsert's executeAndReturnKey method,
passing it a map of field properties that's built from the provided product.
The executeAndReturnKey method returns the automatically generated primary key,
so we set that as the ID on our product,
and then return the newly created product.
Finally, the delete method executes the jdbcTemplate's update method,
providing delete SQL and binding its ID parameter to the ID argument.
Again, the ID method returns the number of rows affected, so we return true if one row is deleted.