Let's review what we learned in this module.
First,
we have a simple microservice that persists data to and from a
relational database using hand-written SQL.
It's comprised of a controller that handles web requests and responses
and delegates its business functionality to a service.
The business service is mostly a pass through to the underlying repository,
but in your own microservices,
the business service is responsible for any business logic
that your microservice may need to perform.
The important behavior of our service is that it knows what
repository methods to call for what functionality.
Finally,
we have a repository that uses Spring's JdbcTemplate and
simpleJdbcInsert classes to execute hand-written SQL.
The benefit to using the JdbcTemplate is that it implements the template
design pattern to remove all the boilerplate JDBC code,
which allows us to focus on our business functionality,
namely,
specifying the SQL statement to execute and
building objects from the result set.
This microservice uses Spring Boot 5, which simplifies our Spring configuration.
The Spring Boot 5 application automatically scans our
class path and identifies our controller,
service, and repository, and it scans our dependencies,
which includes both the H2 database and Tomcat.
So it creates an H2 database and creates an
executable JAR file that embeds Tomcat.
Next,
we walked through creating unit tests using JUnit 5
for our three Spring components.
We started with the controller,
we leveraged Spring's MockMvc class to execute full
HTTP requests against our controller, and to validate the response.
In this test, we used Spring's MockBean annotation,
which uses Mockito under the hood,
to create a mock implementation of our service and return
the conditions that we wanted to test.
Then we tested the service, which was probably the easiest of our tests.
In this case,
we injected the service into our test class and created a mock
repository to simulate different scenarios.
Finally, we tested the repository using DbUnit and DBUnitExtension.
DbUnit allows us to populate our database with a known set of data,
and then write tests against that set of data.
In order to do this effectively,
we created a test Spring configuration using Spring
profiles that created a test database.
At this point, you should feel comfortable testing controllers using MockMvc,
creating Mockito versions of Spring beans using the MockBean annotation,
testing services, and writing tests against a SQL database using DbUnit.
In the next module, we'll review another microservice,
but this time, one that persists data to a MongoDB NoSQL database using Spring Data.