Hello, I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module Managing Through Effective Communication in
the course Practical Team Management for Software Engineers.
Maybe by this point of the course you're thinking, what did I get myself into?
We have talked about aligning our work to the business,
how to structure and define the roles of our new team,
how to build their skills and how to acquire new talent,
nowhere in there are we doing much technically.
Are you starting to miss the technical stuff?
Or are you excited and motivated to learn and broaden
not only your management skills,
but enhance your future opportunities in leadership and management?
I did make that metamorphosis, that is, my professional transition,
and have never looked back.
Okay, now for your next lesson on being the best manager you can be,
learning that effective communication will greatly help and
enable your ability to be successful as a manager.
What we've got here is a failure to communicate,
from the 1960's movie Cool Hand Luke, and that is exactly what you don't want.
You don't want to fail at communicating.
So far in this course we have discussed many new
soft skills you will need to have.
In this module the skill sets are only going to get softer and soft
skills are the harder ones to learn and get good at.
So first let's recap what we have done so far in this course and how quality communication is required for each.