Managing expectations for me is the single most important aspect to
maintaining a healthy and rewarding relationship with my customers,
my teammates, and my management.
Now let's see why managing customer expectations is so important.
Do you know what your customers expect from you and your team?
Are you meeting your customer's expectations?
You might answer, well I think so.
How do you know?
Well really not a clue, you might answer.
Well that is what this module is all about.
We will talk about how to understand just what a customer expectation is,
how important it is,
and how to help you manage those expectations so you
can successfully lead your new team.
Here are the steps and challenges for you to manage
expectations of your customer.
So first, what, what is it you're going to do?
You're going to manage your customer expectations
and the operative word is manage.
Warning,
it is a moving target and you need to assess and adapt and
we will talk about techniques for this.
Next, just how will you do that?
By following the key principles provided in this module you will be
successful at managing your customer expectations.
And when will you do that?
Every day.
It is how you act, speak, write, interact, lead and manage throughout your day.
Managing expectations is not just a single event you do every other week, it is the way you conduct your business each and every day.