Effective communication is the foundation,
the basis,
of success in order to be successful in the topics we have covered so far.
The first is aligning IT to the business.
You must be able to talk, listen,
document in order for the business to even tell you what
they are doing and what they need.
You can't align your work to something you can't understand or determine.
Managing customer expectations.
You must be able to listen and understand the world
from the customer's point of view,
show empathy and be able to relate with your customers.
Building team structure and capabilities.
Based on what you need to do by aligning your work to the business
and understanding your customer's expectations,
you therefore have to be able to define the right team structure and build the
capabilities you need to perform and support the business.
Acquiring the right talent.
Without the right people your job will be excruciatingly tough.
With the right communication skills you will be able to
find and hire the right talent to, again,
meet your mission of supporting the business.
So what are the consequences of failing to communicate well?
Well your clients and project needs may not be met.
Your customers may not respect or support you.
Your subordinates may be confused about what is expected of them.
You may be unable to hire the right talent.
Your goals and plans may come crashing down all around you.
So welcome to the module that'll help you mitigate those consequences and risks.
As a manager you are required to communicate effectively to the business,
the customer, your team, and potential new hires.
That is a talent, skill, and capability that you must have or improve upon.
Okay, let's do a quick overview of this module.
Here are the module topics.
The course will be divided into two sections,
the first, I'm going to talk about informal forms of communication,
such as stand ups, walk arounds, informal emails,
and daily interactions.
Then on the formal side I'm going to talk about presentations,
meetings, emails, and status reporting.
All these are key tools and methods of communication,
so right out of the box as a manager if you use these tools
and the methods I'm going to propose,
you'll get way ahead of the game in terms of better
communication with your customers, your management,
and your team members.
I'm going to divide the world of communications for you into
two types or categories of communication.
The first, informal, and the second, formal. Now let's discuss and explore each.