Why align IT to the business?
In this section we'll see what alignment means and the effects of bad
alignment and good alignment of IT with the business.
According to Info-Tech Research,
47% of business leaders feel that business goals are unsupported by IT.
If IT fails to support the project or programs that benefit
the organization then IT is perceived as a cost center that
delivers very little real value.
Here's a hint,
you never want your team or group or department to
be perceived as a cost center.
The term cost center or overhead implies no added value.
Now highly effective IT teams will realign IT with the business,
however,
a staggering 92% of IT departments surveyed claim their
IT strategies were less than adequate.
Many IT strategies are just too technical, both in wording and content.
Technical jargon is difficult for the business to understand and
there is very little emphasis on people or processes. So here are your challenges ahead of you.