Understanding alignment.
Now let's see what alignment means and the effects of bad alignment and
good alignment of your IT activities with the business.
Here's a text book definition, a bunch of words, I know, but they are important.
Alignment to the business: It's the art and science of formulating,
integrating, and implementing decisions between the business and IT,
which enables an organization to achieve its objectives.
Yes a bunch of words, but they are important.
Now let's deconstruct this statement to more fully
understand its meaning and implications.
So when someone in a company says we have aligned our IT to the business,
here is what they mean.
It is when a business organization is able to use information
technology effectively to achieve its business objectives.
Also resulting in improved business outcomes,
such as improved financial performance, better products,
services, or marketplace competitiveness.
The bottom line is the ability of IT to produce business value.
Now here's a simple tip: So here's a tip to prove
your team is adding business value.
For everything you do in IT,
can you say the following: What my team is doing now…,
all results in adding business value…, and I can prove it.
That is you can connect the dots between your activities and actual
business requirements meeting the needs of the business.
And if not,
you must inspect what you are doing and adapt so that your team or
organization is in fact focused on always adding business value.
Now it won't be 100% all the time, but I would always strive for 90% plus in your daily activities.