So now we have a structure to our team,
we have defined the roles and the responsibilities and the duties,
we are now ready to build the skills necessary to accomplish our work.
The determination of the skills is based on the gaps,
a gap may be a role that no one can feel because that set of skills
required is simply missing from your team or a gap maybe simply skills to
be enhanced for a person in one or more roles.
Do your team members, and yourself of course,
have all of the capabilities and skills you think
they need to get the work done?
Let's explore those topics in this section.
We as IT people tend to focus on the technical
skills or alphabet soup of skills, such as HTML,
XML, CSS, SQL, et cetera.
To me there are three critical categories of skill areas.
The first one is the obvious one of course, technical.
Sure you will need to acquire new technical skills or
possibly improve some that you already have.
Typically new managers think that's all there is to it.
This is a huge mistake in my book.
Here are the next two areas you should not overlook.
Communication skills, you need to write effectively,
speak effectively,
and interact effectively to lead your team and work with
your customers and your management.
And lastly, is the leadership skills.
Now you have been chosen as the new manager,
I would suggest to you that either you have some leadership skills
already and that is why your managers have selected you,
but I would strongly encourage you to grow your leadership skills.
Also you want to begin growing and grooming your team members to
all be leaders in their own right and context.
So as you can see,
the technical skills to me is only one-third of the picture of what you want.
Resumes tend to focus only on technical and it can be
tough to figure out if the resume you are reading will
represent all the skills you need.
We will talk about that more in another module,
on how we acquire the right talent.
Okay, now let's see some examples of each of these.
Technical skills are the knowledge and abilities
needed to accomplish mathematical, engineering,
scientific or computer related duties,
as well as the specific tasks relating to technology.
Here are some examples, software development,
like JavaScript, C#, Java, Angular, Python or MySQL.
IT ops, like database administration, IT networking,
cloud computing or Microsoft Windows operating systems.
Creative professional like game design, 3D design, Photoshop and web design.
Data professional like Oracle, SQL and business intelligence,
things wrapped around data or big data.
Architecture and construction, like CAD, Rhino, AutoCAD and 3DS Max.
And information and cyber security, like digital forensics and malware analysis.
Those are just some of the examples and some of the categories.
Now let's look at the communication area.
As the technical skills are sometimes known as hard skills,
communication skills are sometimes known as soft skills.
Here are some examples.
First, of course, writing skills.
Employees obviously place a high value on excellent writing skills.
In my experience I have found that IT people tend to have
much to improve on with writing skills.
You're going to be sending emails, writing proposals,
presentations, developing business plans,
all need good writing skills, and I don't just mean grammar,
which is of course important.
What I mean is that you are able to influence,
mentor,
guide and shape the activities you are responsible for through those skill sets.
Quality writing skills are critical for that.
Presentations.
Good presentation skills require a person to be able to
stand up in front of a group of people, your team,
your customers, and present your ideas, plans,
and issues and be successful in doing so.
Meetings.
Meeting skills are harder than they look.
You need to design an agenda, determine who should be invited,
ensure the intended outcome is realized,
track questions and issues, prepare and email notes out to the attendees.
Now those may seem easy or even mechanical,
but you need to lead and manage that team to a successful outcome.
Stand ups.
Stand ups are not just for software engineers anymore,
I use them in almost aspect of what I do.
But it makes a good listener and someone who can make people feel comfortable,
trusted,
and respected so that they in fact talk and share the important and critical
information that the stand up was to expose in the first place.
Walk arounds.
Now walk arounds for me are impromptu,
3 to 5 minute jaunts where you can get up and maybe get a drink of water and on
the way back poke your head into an office or two and say,
hey, hi, what's up?
How are you doing?
How are you coming on that assignment?
Keep it more personal and casual and use it to build
rapport with your team and customers.
This skill is likely to be more for you or someone
who may take your place one day.
Interviews.
We will cover this in more detail in another module,
but good communication skills will be the main vehicle by which you will
determine if the candidate is the right candidate to hire,
in my opinion of course.
And as I've said, more on that later.
This skill is likely to be more for you or someone
who may take your place one day.
Interpersonal skills.
These are life skills we use every day to communicate
and interact with other people, both individually and in groups.
People who have worked on developing strong interpersonal skills
are more successful in their professional lives and if I might
say their personal lives as well.
Everyone needs these.
Here's a hint,
if you have great interpersonal skills you will go far in life professionally.
So you can see I covered a plethora of communication skills and forms that
you as a manager definitely require and must improve on,
but also your team members should as well.
These skills, I would like to suggest to you,
may in fact propel your career farther than the technical skills.
Leadership skills are an essential component in positioning
yourself and team members to make thoughtful decisions about
their team's mission and goals.
Now this area is a bit more fuzzy.
Some people are naturally good at leading others and some aren't.
So I suggest to you the following question, is leadership trainable?
I say it is in the context of this course and in your
new role and manager of your team.
On this slide I will list a set of skills,
or maybe I like to call them behaviors,
that you'll want to have in your skill set.
The first is to be able to embrace and champion change.
Next, earn credibility across the organization.
Desire and have a passion to lead and manage people,
that's real important in your job.
Ability to build trust.
Able to exemplify strong communication skills like we talked
about earlier and demonstrate strategic,
that is long term, planning skills.
Also do you support process and metrics,
in other words understanding the critical role of well
defined processes within your organization.
And have some basic project and team management skills.
And lastly,
marketing skills to kind of market the good things
that your team does to others.
So I would look for training opportunities to learn
more about these leadership skills.
There are many books and articles,
plus check out one of my other classes titled Leadership and
Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
Now let's focus on you for a moment.
You need to build your skills as well.
Since you have just come from a technical role,
you know, based on our scenario,
you will likely either need the following skills or need to improve them.
One of them is going to be delegation.
If you master the art of delegation, that is giving work to others,
handing work off, you will also be building trust,
big time, because they will say to themselves you trust me to do this?
This instills trust back to you and a deeper sense of responsibility
and motivation with the person you are delegating to.
Leadership, of course, we talked about,
but I just want to emphasize it for improving your
management growth opportunities.
Also communication, again we've already talked about communication.
But I want to reemphasize it for improving your management growth opportunities.
Leadership and communication are critical,
you're going to be moving away from the technical side,
so your skill gap, if you will,
will be in the leadership and communication area and a big way to
improve your productivity of your team and to grow yourself would be
also to improve your ability to delegate.
And lastly, succession planning.
Who will take your role when you are out of the office,
sick, on vacation, yeah hopefully you can go on vacation,
or actually get promoted and move on?
I have seen many times in the corporate world that a person's promotion is
held up because they do not have anyone to replace you.
You want to put the processes in place,
you want to do the things we've talked about in this course so
far and the remaining portion of this course,
so you can build a good and solid team that has a lot of good
leadership and communication so at some point,
either for a short time, you're away on vacation,
or you have other opportunities to move on.
These are very good practices you must work on to
promote your own career as well.
Alright now let's see how we build up our list of skill requirements and put together a plan in the next section.