Now let's define the requirements of the person we want to hire,
and let's also keep in mind the last slide as well,
most people tend to think about just replacing someone almost one for one.
But as we discussed, looking for new skills,
new capabilities, and diversity may help leverage your team to new heights.
Let's always ask the question, why are you hiring?
So in order to write a targeted job description,
you need to know exactly why you are hiring and that way you can
write the best requirements for the job opening.
When you want to attract the right candidates,
you have to begin with a well thought through job description as a starting
point in implementing your talent acquisition strategy.
Let's see how we can do this in this section.
To begin writing our job requirements,
we need to identify the roles or roles of the position as
well as the associated responsibilities.
Now this should be easy since in the module building team structure and
capabilities we identified and documented the roles we needed for our team and
for each role we identified the list of responsibilities.
So in a way this is really easy,
just pull out the documentation of the role or roles to be
fulfilled and their corresponding responsibilities or duties as
we defined them in the other module.
Okay, now let's look for any gaps.
Now that we have our roles and responsibilities as a starting point based
on the roles and responsibilities of the person leaving,
more than likely, let's look for any gaps,
that is what might we be missing?
Will the new position replace an existing role or roles?
Okay, that's the easy case, we have material and we are ready.
Will the new position add responsibilities that did not exist before?
Well then in this case we need to identify and document the
new responsibilities for each role effected.
Next, will the new position change any existing responsibilities?
And in this case we need to identify and document the changing
responsibilities for each role effected.
Will the new position add a new role that did not exist before?
Okay,
then we need to identify the role or roles needed and document the
new or changing responsibilities for each role.
You may have noticed that I have stated identify and document.
There is a reason for it, most managers do not like to document.
If you learn anything from this course, you will see we document everything.
That's a best practice and truly will make your life as a new manager much,
much easier.
Now let's revisit our skill requirement areas.
So remember in the module on building team structure and capabilities,
we identified three areas of skills we need to have a solid and healthy team.
The first is the obvious one, technical.
So identify all the technical skills required for the roles and
responsibilities we have identified so far.
Next communication skills,
determine the communication skills you think are required for
the roles and responsibilities identified.
Lastly is leadership skills, again,
based on the roles and responsibilities we have identified,
list the leadership skills you think you and your
team will need in the new hire.
Okay, so as you can see,
this is a very straightforward and prescriptive approach
to creating your new hire requirements.
Now let's see an example.
Now let's itemize the skills needed in each of the
three areas we just discussed.
The first is technical, and in this case,
based on the roles and responsibilities,
we think we need Bootstrap, CSS, Cascading Style Sheets,
and jQuery.
Next would be communication.
We think based on the roles and responsibilities we need
someone that has some good presentation writing skills and in
that case probably PowerPoint as well.
And lastly would be leadership and in this case we think we need
some project management skills because we see some big projects
coming up and because they're big projects we may also need some
developing estimates, how we can make some good estimates for these projects.
So in this case, of course, this is a short list just to illustrate the process.
But in your case,
you will list all the skills you think are needed in each
of the three areas and there may be, you know,
20 technical skills and 4 communication skills and,
you know, 13 leadership skills,
and again we want to have the full list of skills,
as if we're looking for the person that walks on water.
Later we may compromise and hire someone that doesn't have all those
skills because typically people do not walk on water.
Okay, now let's recap.
Now let's go through our requirements checklist and do a quick recap.
You have identified the roles, some may have been existing and some may be new.
You have identified the responsibilities that may be new
for an existing role or for a new role.
You have identified the core technical skills.
You have identified the key communication skills.
You have identified the desired leadership skills.
Now some team input, take the material you have and sit down with your team.
Ask them for their inputs and feedback and be sure you haven't missed anything.
Also, by engaging your team they will feel part of the process,
they will feel appreciated and excited about the new hire,
rather than wondering why the person has just left your team.
And lastly, document all of this.
This won't be the first time you'll have to do this process,
keeping your notes for the next time will save you time in the future.
So now you are ready,
you know what you need and now you have to find the person
that will fulfill your requirements. Now let's take a look at the acquisition process in the next section.