In the previous section we learned about the kinds or types of skills we needed,
technical, communication, and leadership.
Now we want to determine exactly what those skills are so we can
develop a plan to acquire and learn those skills.
As you have likely noticed in this course when we do things we
always try and align what we are doing with the business and
determining skill requirements is no different.
Let's see an example of how we will do this.
Now let's determine role and skill gaps or requirements needed for your team.
We're going to follow these steps.
Step 1,
review all of your projects and activities you identified
in aligning your team with the business.
Step 2, review long term requirements as well.
You are in the technology field and it moves very fast,
so take a peek at the future and see if any technologies may
help you get your job done in the future.
Step 3, review your team member needs, they will now,
maybe better than you in some cases,
what they need to improve on or learn for the first time even.
Step 4, integrate the lists into one long list and prioritize.
Step 5, develop a plan and, well, implement it.
And step 6, regularly inspect and adapt to the world changing around you.
Okay now let's do an example together following the
six easy steps I've outlined here.
Step 1, review projects and activities.
Remember our priority grid?
We have priority 1, 2, and backlog items,
so you want to review these items with your team and determine together
what skills you think you need to get your job done.
Certainly focus on priority 1 and priority 2 and then lastly the backlog.
So we're going to review the priority projects and activities that
are aligned to the business and determine what technical skills will
be needed for those priority projects.
Some examples, bootstrap, CSS,
and jQuery may have been the three skills your team said,
hey we need those to get the job done.
Next we review the priority projects and activities that are
aligned to the business and determine what communication skills
will be needed for those priority projects.
Some examples may be, I need some presentation writing and PowerPoint skills.
Next we review the priority projects and activities that are
aligned to the business and determine what leadership skills will
be needed for those priority projects.
Some examples may be project management skills and developing estimates.
So now we have a list of skills we need that are driven by the business.
Next we're going to review long term requirements.
Step 2, review and assess long term requirements.
As an IT professional you are looking to the future and
keeping an eye on new technologies.
It will generally not be specific hands on training,
but newer technologies are trends that may benefit your company downstream.
Also this training may be geared to business or IT
managers talking about how a new technology may be applied
to improve business performance.
Here are some examples.
Cloud, mobile apps, big data, things like that.
Typically you might be the one to go to this kind of training or maybe a very
key person on your team that has an architectural affinity,
if you will.
You don't want to send a bunch of people since this is long
term and these technical areas may change.
It might not even happen in the future.
Step 3, review team member goals.
You want to review and assess what team members want.
First this may appeal to their own personal goals of learning new things,
as well as maybe you just missed some skill areas and they're
just going to point it out to you like, hey we've got to learn this,
didn't you realize that?
So here are some examples.
Maybe in this case it was SQL Server and database design and modeling.
Maybe you thought they knew everything this area,
but I guess not, they needed some more training. Now let's put these lists together and prioritize.