Step 3, conduct face to face interviews.
Now based on the candidates that passed your phone interview,
you can now schedule them to come into your office.
You might need to coordinate schedules with not
only yourself and the interviewee,
but also one or more of your team members if you want them involved as well,
and I recommend that you do that.
The goal of the in person interview,
do they meet your requirements that you put together to join the team?
If so, they will then move on to the final selection list.
Alright, prepare interview questions.
Have a prepared list of questions based on the
requirements we wrote in the previous section,
you can prepare your list of written questions.
Here is your verbal and interpersonal skills will come in handy.
Your job is to ask questions to get them talking.
For now, I am focusing on the overall process,
my six steps,
but in the section following this section I will dive much
deeper into the questions themselves and help you design
and write those questions.
Write two or three questions per requirement.
If you have a hard time writing questions then maybe
you're not sure about the requirements.
Now this does take time,
but after you do this you will have a repository of questions to use and reuse.
So take a look at the demo file for this section,
I have included a ton of sample questions.
Not all questions need to be asked.
The list is just your superset of questions.
You might find that after asking a question,
a new one just pops into your head, so just ask it.
You might want to take a note of it so you can add it to
your list for the next interviewee.
Provide a written test.
Now for in person interview we provide a written technical
test in addition to the normal interview.
This allows us to have an objective score based on their answers.
We also score on soft skills, such as teamwork,
personality, attitude, motivation, and things like that.
Now those items are certainly subjective.
Document your rating.
Always document their answers and how you rated them.
Check with your manager or HR for any guidelines.
If HR does not require you to document, please, please do it anyway.
These results contain valuable information that you will help you
pick the best candidate in the following steps.
Try not to be too clinical.
In other words, they may not get the exact right answer and that might be fine.
Some I score either correct or partially correct or
just write down close enough.
Remember, not knowing some things is sometimes not that bad.
Instead,
someone who knows how to find the right answers and solutions may be
the more practical and meaningful person to hire.
Prefer one on one first, that is I prefer to do the one on one interview first.
Why waste the team's time if the candidate doesn't work out?
Plus if the person just is not a fit at all,
then again, I don't want to waste everyone's time.
I like to set the stage, make them feel comfortable,
and not just throw them in a room full of people to
start hammering questions away at.
So I prefer to do the one to one first,
make sure everyone's fine and comfortable,
look for any weird signs or whatever that might say,
hey I don't even want to go with this person.
After that short interview, off they go for the team interview.
After the team interview I like them to come back and I'll talk to them
again and get their feedback and see how things have done.
Next, the team interviews.
If the person passes my first what I call quicky interview,
I will pass them to the team.
I usually do not participate in that session and delegate my trust to my team.
The team appreciates that and will have more ownership in the selection process,
which is very important downstream if that person comes on
board and they're going to work with them.
When done with the interviewing I want to review the results with my team.
After the interview,
I get with the team or sub-team that did the
interviewing together for a debriefing.
At this point you are only looking for two things, are they in or out?
No ranking yet please.
Are they a potential new hire candidate or are they just tossed out of the list?
Again, make sure everything is documented,
this enables a better outcome and may prevent lawsuits,
you never know.
Okay so outcome of this step is a list of qualified
candidates that you might hire.
By the way, if you want some guidance on interviewing skills and approaches,
please check out another one of my classes called Leadership and
Communication Skills for Software Engineers. Okay let's go on to the next step.