Now let's map IT goals to the business goals.
We're going to have the business goals on the left
and the IT goals on the right.
And remember from the previous slide,
we had a goal from the business to increase revenue by 25%.
So on further discussions with the customer we decided that
we could also increase student sign-up by 15% and also
increase corporate sign-up by 10%.
So in our discussions we thought 15% for students,
10% for corporate, maybe we'll achieve our revenue goal of 25%.
Notice the key goal was a 1.
0 and I made these underneath that as 1.
1, 1.
2, just so they're like sub-goals.
Then on the right I'm going to come up with what are my IT
goals to achieve those business goals.
So the first one I write is add 100 new courses to the on-line catalog.
That might be a great way to entice more students to sign up.
The next goal will be to enhance the Ecom portal to
support PayPal and multi-tender payments.
You know,
if we make it easier for students to spend their money or
for corporations to spend their money, we might also increase revenue.
And lastly, enable corporate account management from the admin portal.
We to add more features for the admin portal so that the administration can do
more things to increase and encourage corporate sign-ups.
Now this is a simple example,
and then you could take it down different layers or maybe there's
several other activities you'd like to have.
I have a simple numbering system on the right as well.
So 1.
1.
1 and 1.
2 tie into the business goals of 1.
1.
And the other IT goal, 1.
2.
1 ties into the business goal of 1.
So that way I can link everything up,
because remember in order to align everything to the business,
I want all my activities to be transparently connected and
linked to all business goals at all times.
Now let's take it a step further and map our projects
and activities to our IT goals.
Now let's map our IT project, activities, and goals to the IT goals.
Okay,
on the left I'm going to have the IT goals and on the
right IT projects and activities.
Now almost every IT group I've seen has a list of backlog items and projects,
which is great, but what I say - how does it map to the business?
Many times they say they are not sure.
I truly believe that that answer is a major disconnect with
the business and now is a new important responsibility for
you as a manager of your team.
Okay, on the left - add 100 new courses to the on-line catalog,
and on the right I'm going to launch two projects,
A and B, to satisfy that requirement.
Next, enhance the Ecom portal to support PayPal and multi-tender payments.
I'm going to have projects C, D, and E identify it to support that goal.
Next, enable corporate account management from the admin portal.
And on the right, operations task 25.
3 and 25.
4.
Now you've noticed I've mixed the term project and operations.
So before we jump into the next section on allocating resources and priorities,
let's talk about the differences between projects and operations.
Projects versus operations,
I characterize project activities quite differently from operational activities.
This module lends itself to the former where the
business is driving project activities,
but at times some activities may not be full on projects,
but just flow into the routine operational activities process.
So let's talk about the attributes of each.
I'm going to have project attributes on the left and
operation space attributes on the right.
First the projects, they tend to propel the company forward.
They have management's focus,
management's keenly interested in what they're going to accomplish.
Typically they may drive new revenues, they may drive new services,
they may drive new cost containment,
and also drive things to improve customer service.
Now on the right are the operations, the activities that are more day to day,
functions of the business that just happen day to day.
Keeping the lights on, if you will.
Kind of like a utility company.
And typically they're tracked in an issue tracking system.
Okay, so somewhat different.
Projects will have a beginning and an end,
they'll usually have budgets of focus, things to accomplish,
and on the right will be operations,
the day to day activities to keep the business going and keep the lights on.
Typically when we do IT planning and tying all of
our activities to the business,
it will typically tie the projects because that's what
the business is really interested in.
In the meantime,
you still may have a whole collection of operational activities
that you're doing because the business might say,
yep keep that system going, I have nothing new for it,
but in the meantime I have some new work which may drive new projects.
Okay,
now that you have your major projects and operational
activities mapped to the business,
and remember we are doing this to ensure we are doing the right
things for the business and adding value and not just playing
with some new technology or project.
So the question remains, how would you allocate resources?
Well first things first, what are the priorities? And let's find out in the next section.