Motivating your team.
When people are motivated, I think just life's grand.
I want to relate each of the earlier modules and how each module provides a
platform for creating or growing motivated team members.
There are lots of ways to motivate people,
of course,
but I'm going to focus on the three earlier modules and
how they relate to team motivation.
Connect team members with your company's business.
People want to feel that they're part of something bigger than
themselves and one of the best ways for workers to experience
this feeling is to understand and feel personally connected with
their organization's goals.
Like many managers you may not have explicitly articulated
your goals or vision to your team members,
however,
in my experience communicating the company's goals and
mapping your team's work to those goals is indeed a major
factor in keeping workers motivated.
Also,
employees who are committed to the organization's goals are
more likely to stay in their current position.
This means lower turnover rates, higher employee satisfaction,
and ultimately higher productivity.
In an earlier module, aligning IT to the business,
I provided you a step by step approach for aligning your
work with the company's business goals.
This will not only ensure your team is working on the right things,
but also as a side benefit, actually increase your team's motivation.
Next, connect with the customer.
There are two key items to discuss here.
One is if you do align your work to the business in a thoughtful
and organized approach as I have detailed,
your customers will absolutely love and appreciate your efforts,
no doubt in my mind.
Secondly, managing your customer's expectations as we detailed,
will bring you and your team closer,
that is you will be more connected with your customer.
So in an earlier module, managing customer expectations,
I provided you a step by step approach for managing your customer's
expectations and using the customer service grid technique for determining
your customer service shortfalls and correcting them.
Next, connect with team members.
There are many ways to connect and interrelate with your team,
in fact, please check out one of my other courses,
Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers,
where I talk about several topics that will create
a cohesive and motivated team.
But in this course,
the third element so far is providing training and
learning opportunities for your team.
Typically learning new things is a great motivator.
Showing that you have a process that you follow to review the business drivers,
look at the long term trends,
and also look to see what their personal skill interests are for each member.
This shows that you care for your team members and care about the business too.
Very professional indeed.
Team members who are given opportunities for professional growth are more
likely to report a strong commitment to their organization,
at the same time as they gain new skills and knowledge,
they are more likely to use those skills to their own benefit as well.
So in this module I provided you a step by step approach
for determining the skills you require and putting
together the plan to accomplish it. Okay, let's summarize this module.