In the last section we talked about the acquisition process for new talent.
And in that section we talked about, of course,
you're going to ask some questions.
Now it's time to actually talk about how do we
prepare and design your questions.
You want to ask questions that will enable the interviewee to demonstrate
their capabilities and qualities to you and your team.
Alright, let's get started in this section.
Again I just want to emphasize that it's not all about technical skills,
but also about communication and leadership strengths as well.
Sometimes I use the term interpersonal skills to also
represent communication skills.
Interpersonal skills can be an enormous strength to your team,
especially with the customer, especially with requirements gathering,
especially with negotiating and things like that.
So we want a collection of questions that will enable the
interviewee to clearly demonstrate to you and your team,
not only their technical, but also their communication,
leadership, interpersonal skills,
based on your requirements list that we put together in previous sections.
To assess the interviewee's technical capabilities,
I would suggest something like the following.
I would provide a written test.
For example, if you're looking for a database person,
you may have a list of questions about SQL,
database design, database administration,
and features of Microsoft SQL Server, for example.
Now a written test enables the objective scoring and
comparing to other candidates.
This approach makes it pretty easy to see how the person did on the questions,
where they were strong and where they were weak,
and allows you to more easily compare candidates.
A test may also include a programming example or an example of
actually using a tool or platform to get something done or
accomplish a predetermined outcome.
For example, continue with the SQL example,
maybe they have to perform a complex joint operation between multiple tables,
things like that.
So they can really literally demonstrate their skills.
Some people are pretty good at taking tests,
A, B, C,
answering questions and things like that and the real test would be actually
getting them to perform an actual series of operations.
To assess the interviewee's communication capabilities I
would suggest something like the following.
Have you developed presentations for senior management or important customers?
If the answer is no,
then you know they may be a little weak in presentation skills.
Now in our scenario of our requirements, presentation skills was a requirement.
Now if they answer yes, then you need to ask follow up questions,
otherwise you really haven't a clue to how good those skills were,
and here they are.
Who was your audience?
This will give you a feel for the composition,
how senior or important were they.
What was the situation that caused you to give the presentation?
Maybe it was a project status or results of research or something like that.
What was the intended outcome you wanted?
This is an important question.
I strongly believe that every presentation should have a clear intended outcome.
And does the interviewee understand that and were they
successful in doing that during their presentation?
Did you achieve the outcome you wanted?
This may give you some insights into their ability to
convey and communicate successfully.
To assess the interviewee's leadership capabilities I would
suggest something like the following,
one of your team members' deliverables are not what you expected and the
quality was not what you wanted… what was your course of action?
How did they approach this situation?
Let me talk about that.
Did they go for a quick fix or show more leadership qualities?
That's what you're really looking for, leadership qualities.
Did they have a corrective action plan to help the person improve over time?
And things like that.
So you can see in these three different areas in terms of technical,
communication, and leadership, we had some key questions,
and you'll want to follow up with two,
three or four other questions to have in your hip pocket so you can dig deeper.
You know, you don't want yes or no answers,
you want to get them to talk,
you want to get them to expose their interpersonal skills,
their personalities and their capabilities so you can see
them demonstrate those in front of you.
Now let's move on to a couple other attributes that we want to look for that I think are also very important during the interview.