Hi everyone,
my name is Michael Krasowski and welcome to my course
Practical Team Management for Software Engineers.
So there you are, heads down and cranking out code,
life is grand, and you just love being a software engineer.
Then one day your boss says to you,
hey I think you've been doing a nice job and I'd like you to
be a manager and manage a team for me,
maybe about 5 or 8 developers and I will need you to work with the customers,
figure out and document requirements,
determine your software development lifecycle,
figure our your standards, your architecture,
manage your work tasks, hire people, and all that stuff,
and you know come up with all the team management things you think you need,
and oh, by the way, you start tomorrow.
If something like that has happened to you,
then you've come to the right place, this course is for you.
This course is your starter kit and as a new manager or a
manager needing to acquire new skills,
we'll be covering the following major topics and themes.
Aligning IT activities to the business, managing customer expectations,
building team structure and capabilities,
acquiring the right talent, managing through effective communication,
and promoting productivity through team processes.
By the end of this course you will know how to begin your journey as a
new manager or a manager looking to improve your skills with the
confidence and skills necessary for your success.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to improving your skills with my Pluralsight course Practical Team Management for Software Engineers.