Promoting to production, well we're getting close now.
The key users have identified that the last release looks great
and they'd like to move it to production.
Okay, let's see what that entails.
Promoting to production, whereas a release identifies changes to an application,
and a build implements those changes, a promotion delivers the changes.
More specifically,
a promotion is an indication or signal that a given build has been
approved for deployment to a certain environment.
This approval can require a form be filled out in triplicate,
or it can just occur as a result of someone deciding
to just go and deploy a build, every organization is different.
You may have a promotion from test to stage and then from stage to production,
or something else.
So let's explore the options in this section.
I would also like to first introduce you to this term, DevOps.
It is a recently new term and it is used to refer to the
collaboration and communication between software developers and
the information technology professionals.
As part of the collaboration, of course,
is the promotion of a build to production.
Again, the area of DevOps is quite large and will not be covered here,
but I wanted to give you context for where promoting to production fits in,
also Pluralsight has several courses on DevOps,
so you might want to check them out as well.
Okay, let's talk about the promotion process.
So here's the sample promotion process to kind of give
you an idea what I'm talking about.
The first would be approvals and scheduling.
So be sure you get the approvals to move your build into production
and then set the date and time that works for you,
your team, and of course your customers,
they're the most important group.
I like installing on Sundays or Mondays if possible so you
have the week to remediate if need be, otherwise you're working the weekends.
Next,
you must communicate when you're moving anything to production
and you must coordinate it with your customers,
especially your customers.
Also the DevOps teams, if you have one,
and your manager and other business or IT entities as appropriate.
Update any documentation,
we always forget or just hate to update any documentation.
This is not allowed in my shop, so update the release notes,
user docs, help manuals, online portals like SharePoint or file shares,
maybe you send out an email, text messages or use some special social tools,
like Slack.
Provide training.
If training is required, be sure it happens before the rollout to production.
Be sure everyone is ready and prepared.
Remember the build may be perfect, the promotion to production may be perfect,
but if the users are confused, ill-trained,
then the perception from the user or customer base
will be that the build did not work.
Yes, I know, the build works for you from the perspective of a software engineer,
but not from the end user, so train and educate as needed.
Next, move and install the build.
Now please document your process on what is needed,
like DLLs or scripts or files and things like that,
and how to move and install your build into production environment,
like copy files to that folder, run this script,
et cetera.
You may do this or it may be handed over to another team.
In the DevOps model,
you'll always hand it over to the DevOps team to actually
do the installation and configuring,
but you must first write the instructions on what to do.
And lastly, archive the build,
in case you need to go back and review what you provided.
So always keep track of that as well.
Okay so now we are in production and we will likely have
some application maintenance to perform as our customers
and users use our new system. So let's check that out in the next section.