You've all heard of structured programming,
now what I'm proposing to you is structured emailing.
All your emails should follow a set, high level structure,
and well as keeping your emails on the shorter side,
and they should follow a standard structure that will also
help you write quality emails faster.
But first,
let's look at the metadata of an email before we jump into the body of an email.
So in an email, the TO: portion is for the intended audience,
the people who must read it.
Do not put every Tom, Dick, and Harry here,
only the people that must absolutely need to read it.
Think carefully and thoughtfully on who will need
to read and receive this email.
It will typically be those who must know the information or
must take action based on the information.
Now here's the CC:, or for a little historical reference,
carbon copy, if you can believe we still use that,
it is for the optional audience.
And remember, do not expect the people in this list to actually read your email.
Okay, you're really sending it as an FYI or out of courtesy.
So clearly know the difference.
The people in the TO: are people you want to read and take action,
the people in the CC: are those who are more FYI,
oh by the way you may want to read this.
Alright next is the blind carbon copy, BCC.
It is for a very a very limited audience.
I really don't recommend using BCC at all.
You want no one in the TO: or CC: to know that this person or
persons is in the BCC and that also receive the email.
If that is the case, well what are you hiding?
So I believe in open and honest communication,
so I don't use this at all,
but wanted to share it with you so you know where I stand.
Now,
if you think someone needs to kind of understand the email you send out
and it's more of a one on one or maybe might be a BCC,
here's what I do.
I don't use the BCC, I send out my email,
I go into my sent email folder, find it,
and then forward it,
say to my boss or forward it to that person with a sentence or two up
front saying by the way I wanted you to see this,
that gives them some context.
If you just send the BCC and they get it as a blind copy,
they may not know the context.
Why are they getting it?
Why did you send it to them as a blind CC?
So again, I don't like to use BCC, I recommend that you don't,
but if you want to send a one or two off special,
then I would go into the sent folder and do a forward.
Alright, Subject.
Most people haven't a clue what to put here.
Here is what I strongly recommend, I want you to be compelling,
in other words, use few words that are compelling,
which will entice them to read and open your email.
And you want to be clear so it's easy for them to
understand just what the email is all about.
And also be concise, keep it as short as possible,
not too long, not to short, no fuzzy subjects.
For example, don't just say status report.
I have no idea what the context is.
Or meeting notes, again no context.
So it would be meeting notes, you know,
maybe it's the topic or we're talking about the polar project,
and the date,
maybe there's something like that in the meeting notes subject
so people know exactly what it's all about.
Okay, now let's take a deeper look at the body of an email.
Over time you'll develop a body structure that works for you.
But here is a simple structure for the body for your emails to get you started.
Now I always recommend using the template that
you'll see below here in a moment,
but always feel free to mold it to fit your needs.
Okay, first a greeting.
I always believe in a simple greeting.
Hello Lauren, good morning Lauren, something like that.
I do not recommend Joe, Mary,
- just add a little bit in there and it just makes
it more inviting in the greeting.
Easy and simple to do.
Next, I'd like to have what I call a soft opening,
maybe a pleasantry,
a compliment or a nice comment like hey I hope you
had a nice vacation when you out, things like that.
Only one sentence, only short.
It's not a love letter, it's a formal business,
but we're trying to just engage the reader and make it easy,
hey hello Michael, oh I like that, oh yes I did have a nice vacation.
Okay, now we're going to get into the meat,
in other words, what is the reason for your email.
Something like, as you requested, please see the attached status report.
In other words, what is the reason for the email?
Make it very clear and make it maybe a sentence or two.
Do not use large paragraphs, consider it something like a presentation,
not a lot of bullets and a lot of text, keep it clear and concise.
Alright, also there might be a call to action.
Please read and provide me with any feedback, something like that.
Next would be the closing message,
like thank you and I will see you at our next meeting on Friday at 10:00 AM,
something like that.
Again, the closing message is short, it's one line.
And lastly a signature block, I can't stand it when someone just says Joe.
I might not even know who Joe is.
So I like a nice signature block.
It's going to be your name, your title, they may know your email,
but maybe it's in there, a phone, maybe a location of where you're at,
so it's very easy then for someone to read your email and if
they have any questions I know who to reply to,
though it might be in the email of course,
but I know who to reply to in the sense of I could pick
up the phone real quick and call.
I know your first and last name.
I know your title.
I have some context,
especially if you're sending it out to an external customer or client.
You want to be professional.
So I really encourage you to have a good signature block.
Again, this section is on formal communication, formal emails.
Okay, so to recap the body, after you write your email,
quickly glance over it and make sure is it clear,
is it concise, is it courteous, is it consistent with the way you do things,
is it compelling?
And you will improve the impact of your emails immediately.
So I call these Michael's 5 C's, Clear, Concise,
Courteous, Consistent, and Compelling.
So you glance over your email and your subject,
does your email and your subject text meet this criteria?
If it does, great, hit the Send button.
If not, tweak it a little bit and then hit the Send button.
Okay,
remember with emails you are not in the room with them reading
it alongside them and filling in the blanks,
so to speak.
So to communicate effectively and to reduce or eliminate ambiguity,
having the structured template is very, very important.
So to make your life more simple,
come up with one or more templates that you can use.
So maybe you can layout an email for a customer because it may be a certain way,
and then reuse it for your weekly updates,
for example.
The same approach may apply for each project,
for your manager, so you may have different email templates that are formal,
but they could all have a greeting, a soft opening,
a reason, action, closing, and signature,
but slightly tweaked based on the audience you're going to send it to. Okay now let's check out formal status reports.