Valuing customer service.
So what do your customers think about your service?
Pretty good, I hope so.
Can you quantify it?
Can you measure it?
Can issues with customer service affect a customer's expectation?
Absolutely.
For example, I go into a restaurant and order my favorite hamburger.
It meets my expectations once again, but the table service was not very good.
He was just never around when I needed him,
so my overall expectations were not met even though the burger was great.
So just making great burgers, or writing great software, may not be enough.
Remember your project manager did not provide very good
service while running the project, yet the software was perfect.
Guess what?
The customer's expectations were not met.
So let's explore further.
Here's an approach to determining the quality of your customer service.
Okay,
to get a really good handle on your customer service levels
you must go out and talk to your customers.
Okay so who are your customers?
I would talk to management and users or anyone that touches all or
part of the systems that you provide support for.
Also determine your service offerings.
What is it that you do?
Maybe call these your service badges or synonymously service offerings.
For example,
your call center is a service offering or what I'm
going to call a service badge.
And for each one of your key customers,
and make them as senior as you can possibly be,
senior in the org chart, ask your client or customer how good the service is.
And also ask them how important that service is.
And keep your categories or badges really, really simple.
Now I'm going to go through a complete example in the next slide
so you fully understand what I'm getting to,
the result of which will be where you need to focus your
energies and your team to improve customer service.
This will also help you focus on the right work that aligns to the business.
Okay, now let's see a detailed example.
Here's a technique I'm calling customer service quadrants.
So here is an easy way to find out how you are
doing with a customer or customers.
I recommend you do this approach face to face with discussions as well.
And you may learn more about the customer,
your service,
and their expectations simply by going through this very simple process.
Okay, here are the quadrants.
On the left, on the Y axis, I'm going to have from not so good service,
to good service.
And on the bottom, the X axis, I'm going to have not so important,
the kind of work and services that you do to pretty important.
Alright, so that quadrant would be not so important and not so good service.
That quadrant would be not so important, but you're giving them good service.
This is pretty darn important to the customer and you're
doing really well in that quadrant,
and this quadrant over here on the lower right,
pretty important, but not so good service.
Okay, so that's how things would line up,
and in those quadrants we're going to place a service or
what I'm going to call a service badge and that's going to
be placed there by your customer, not you.
Okay, so here are the service badges I'm going to use in this example.
Phone support, you provide phone support,
and here's where they place that service badge,
in the quadrant that says pretty good service,
but not so important.
It's nice to have phone support, but to them not so important.
There may be other things more important to them.
Next, time to repair, that is time to fix something that went wrong,
maybe a bug or maybe the machines went down.
And this one's going to go in the upper right,
that's very important to them and by the way they
rate that as pretty good service, okay, well good.
Both of these service badges or service categories are in the good service area.
Good.
Maybe you didn't know that or maybe you did know it
and it reinforces your thoughts.
Next, database security.
They put in the lower right quadrant, pretty important to them,
service, not so good,
not horrible because it's in the upper part of that quadrant,
but not so good.
So that might be an area that you want to focus on.
Hmm, so you're going to say well why is it that you put that service badge there?
Start the dialog,
better understand what the issues are so you can add
those issues to your activities.
The next examples is buggy software.
Hmm, I wonder if they thing we have buggy software or not.
They actually do.
Having buggy software is pretty important to them,
in other words, they don't want it,
okay so we're in the not so good service on the left side,
but very, very important.
So we know that's a target area of improvement.
That buggy software must be corrected.
Alright, so this is the area that I have outlined here,
the lower right quadrant is where it's really
important to them and not so good service.
So if this quadrant was empty, it did not have any service badges,
great, you're doing pretty darn well.
If anything is in this quadrant,
those are areas that I would say you'd want to attack first.
So you can see that this very simple customer service
quadrant can easily be used with your customer,
very easy to read, very easy to understand,
and it'll help target those areas that need improvement.
So I use this technique all the time, it works well,
encourages dialog with the customer and give it a try,
very simple and a very quick way to figure out where you
need to improve your customer service.
And by improving customer service you'll learn more about what your
customers expect and this process will result in putting you more in
sync with your customer's expectations. Okay, now let's summarize this module.