Well we have come full circle, we determined we had a need for a new hire,
that is, we needed to acquire new talent and now they have been onboarded.
Great job.
Okay, let's recap this module.
First was retention.
Before you start hiring or replacing people,
take a look inward and determine your retention rate.
That is,
how many people stay working for you over a period of time
compared to the total people working for you?
We had a simple example,
that is if you have 5 people for a 12 month period and 1 leaves,
your retention is 4 divided by 5, which is 80%.
Now actually that sounds kind of bad because you have such a small little group.
So it may be appropriate to prorate that using months.
Also you'll want to look at things that improve retention,
such as recognizing and rewarding people,
offering learning and growth opportunities,
and lastly, don't forget, they don't leave the company,
if they leave they leave typically because of you.
Finding the right talent.
We talked about hiring from not only outside your company, but inside.
I suggest always looking inside first,
so you'll want to look how the new hire may add value for
longer range portfolio transitions or new skills you didn't
originally realize maybe of value, or new capabilities,
such a very poised speaker or succession planning,
someone who could potentially replace you,
and lastly diversity,
someone with viewpoints that may bring a whole new emphasis to your team.
Then we needed to define the job requirements.
First, we needed to understand why you were hiring,
this will, of course, help if you define the new requirements.
Sure you need to acquire new technical skills or possibly
improve some that you already have,
but you also need to look for leadership skills and communication skills.
People need to write effectively, speak effectively,
and interact effectively to work with your customers and management.
Next we went through the six step acquisition process.
Step 1 was document and post your new hire skill requirements,
step 2 was the screening of those resumes and doing the phone calling,
so you were narrowing down your large pile of resumes to
those that pass your phone interview,
next in step 3 would be the in person interview which
might include a test potentially,
you may also want one or more of your team members
involved in the interview process.
Step 4 was an optional follow on interview or interviews.
Usually one interview is not enough,
you may need to kind of drill in and go deeper with some of those candidates.
In step 5 we had the selection.
Now you pick one that you want,
but you also need to have a backup just in case that
first person does in fact decline.
And step 6, of course, was just the paperwork and getting everything all set up,
usually with HR.
Then we jumped over to preparing your questions.
It is important to prepare your questions ahead of time so you can
pull out the information you need from that person.
Never do it random.
You may also want to test that person or maybe have them write a program or
use a tool to actually literally test their hands on skills.
Remember other questions are very important for critical thinking,
trying to get them to talk and find out whether they have
the right attitude and the right motivation for the kind
of job that you are offering.
And lastly was onboarding.
So we discussed the checklist of activities for that new person.
First we do introduction, then business alignment,
talk to your customers, we then review the structure,
roles,
and responsibilities that the person will perform and also talk about
the processes themselves that your team follows.
Then we give them their first one or two assignments,
and then we also assign them to a mentor,
which may be yourself, but as I mentioned,
I really prefer you to find a mentor that's one of their coworkers
to start building that relationship between them.
Okay,
in the next module we will learn how important communication
skills are in your new role as a manager. See you there.