Now let's summarize the highlights of this module.
One of the biggest takeaways from this module and possibly even this
course is that every single customer interaction is an opportunity
for you to manage customer expectations.
Don't ever forget that and leverage that and you'll have a much better
and a much healthier relationship with your customer.
Now here are some examples of opportunities I was talking about.
It could just be walking down the hall and stopping for a quick chat with a
customer; email providing further explanations or clarifications; status
reports that succinctly talk to accomplishments; meetings for determining
the body language and verbal communication to ascertain their feelings and
what they're thinking; agendas,
be sure you're talking about the right things that the customer wants to
hear and listen to and cover; and steering committees.
These are usually the guys that really have the influence in the company.
So if you're in front of your steering committee,
be sure you take the time to find out or gage what
they think about your team's service,
maybe make it an agenda item or show the customer service quadrant
results by steering committee member to provide an overlay and
comparison by member; presentations,
they give you control of content and of the messaging,
so use this medium to pull out or extract the attendees viewpoints
regarding your service if and when it makes sense to do so.
You name it,
use these forms and others as an opportunity to
gage the feelings that they have, their interpretations of what you are doing,
answer any questions and calibrate any concerns you have around budgets
or schedules or deliverables and service in general.
If I was walking down the hall and saw my customer
for the ERP system I might say, oh by the way,
Joe was out ill, what a bummer, so we'll still try and make that Friday due date,
but if will be likely it will be on Tuesday,
will that work for you?
Note all these behaviors and actions exemplify that you care.
Remember no one is perfect and you'll have service issues,
that is our professional life at times.
But what is important is that you are taking actions to
correct and improve your service,
your customer will greatly appreciate you and your team for it.
In the beginning of the module I gave you some
examples of customer expectations,
I would like to review each one and see how some of the
techniques and tools we have learned will help better
manage the customer's expectations.
Now managing expectations does not mean that there are no
problems or problems just go away on their own.
Really managing expectations is listening,
communicating, planning ahead, knowing just how to convey bad news,
issues or problems in a such a way that involves them
and you can work as a team to resolve.
Okay, you will deliver a build every 2 weeks.
Well this could be a yes,
but… since based on your resources and the high
amount of effort to make a build,
you provide your customer with options to choose.
Option 1, I need to hire one person for that schedule of every 2 weeks.
Option 2, I can do a build every 3 weeks right now with no new head count.
And Option 3, after we finish project A and B,
I might be able to do every 2 weeks.
You will hold a weekly status meeting.
As I mentioned,
having time with a customer is a golden opportunity to
help manage customer expectations and get a read on where
they are at with your service.
I recommend here that you set up the meetings,
provide the agenda, and send out meeting minutes,
which include agreements, actions and accomplishments.
Next, you will be on call for ecommerce support.
Okay, set up a call list with your team,
publish it to the customer,
sit down with your customer and educate the customer that they can
post issues in your issue tracking system as well.
You will understand my business.
Well there are several items here.
Work with them to ensure your activities are aligned to their business,
have weekly status meetings,
which will enable you and your team to further get to
know the customer and their needs,
possibly a sign of business analysts to that customer with the
job to be the main focal point into your team,
and conduct a customer service quadrant activity each quarter.
So here are several different items to get you to
better understand their business.
You will always deliver on time.
We all strive to do this, of course.
What this may mean when a customer says this is that
if you pick a date for a milestone, you better make it.
So I would suggest for each date, for each milestone,
include potential assumptions about how you are depending
on your customer's inputs or maybe data to be available
in order to meet that date, or maybe you're waiting on an external resource.
And also this may cause you to add a little to your estimates
to ensure that you can make it on time.
Consider using an SLA to tighten things up,
and remember too an SLA helps your team know exactly
what's expected of them as well.
You will never have a bug.
Well you and I both know there will be bugs.
But you will never say that to a customer.
First explain about your process for creating test plans with your customer,
in other words, you're creating the plans with them,
and how your engineers use test cases to ensure that
the software meets the requirements.
Emphasize how you need their help and inputs to test since your customer
and his or her team are the subject matter experts.
You may further explain how your issue tracking system will
log all issues and you can have regular sessions with them on
your progress to remediate them.
So you are providing an approach and building confidence in your customer
and also setting expectations about what you will do.
Now all these are really elements of quality communications,
written communications, being realistic,
knowing your limitations, and learning just how to say no by saying yes,
but… The first topic we covered was why manage customer expectations?
We learned that the secret of customer satisfaction lies
not just in what you necessarily do, but in what the customer expects you to do.
Next we define customer expectations.
We discussed the realm of worth, merit,
and importance of understanding customer expectations and why these can
make you and your team optimize your capabilities.
Next we discussed several strategies for managing customer expectation,
such as quality of communications and verbal and written skills.
Knowing your limitations,
that is know what you and your team are truly capable of and
ensuring your customer understands that.
Also setting clear timelines, remaining practical yet still show optimism,
and learning how to say no by saying yes,
but… or hey maybe you can choose among some options.
Next was Service Level Agreements, SLAs,
where expectations are specific, not fuzzy,
expectations are in writing, and expectations can be measured.
We also deconstructed an SLA by a business attribute and gave several examples.
Lastly,
valuing customer service or measuring customer service by using my simple
customer service quadrant approach to isolate each of your services or products
and allow the customer to rank them in each quadrant.
This gives you valuable information to better focus your team's
efforts and reset the customer's expectations.
Lastly, please embrace, live,
and breathe the fact that every single customer interaction is
an opportunity to manage their expectations.
Okay,
in the next module we will learn how to develop team
processes that promote productivity. I'll see you there.