Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
Now we're going to finally apply the padding to the sequences with the pad token.
So first We'll answer two questions First why do we have to do that.
And second what are we going to do exactly with our questions and our answers.
So the answer to why we have to do this is that all the sentences in a batch whether they are questions
or answers must have the same length.
And now the second question what are we going to do exactly.
Well as you can see I've prepared here two sentences one question and one answer.
And as you can see the question Who are you.
And the answer I am about where I don't have the same length.
And after we apply the padding this question and answer will become this.
Who are you.
Bad bad bad bad.
And I am about as know.
So basically the bad tokens are added so that the length of the question sequence is equal to the length
of the answer sequence.
That's the purpose of betting and that's a must do in deep in LP.
So now what we're going to have to do is for each batch and for each sentence of each batch we will
complete the length of each sentence with enough pad tokens so that each sentence of the batch has the
same length.
So let's do this.
It's going to be quite easy.
We're actually going to make a function that we're going to call apply betting apply padding function
that is going to take two arguments the first one is the batch of sequence sequences in this way batch
of sequences.
I just want to make sure you understand the argument here that a batch of sequences and not single sequences
of sequences first argument and the second argument is going to be a word to any dictionary whether
it is two questions word two in Dictionary or the answers were in the dictionary.
We'll actually use them both.
But the name of the argument I'm giving here is words.
And just keep in mind that it is the dictionary mapping the words to the integers.
All right so there are two arguments.
Now let's define what this apply baning function has to do.
So you get what this has to do and has two complete sentences with bad tokens so that all the sentences
in the batch have the same length.
You can actually practice do a little exercise here and try to make that function.
You take your bet of sequences you take each sequence of the batch and you try to add the tokens in
a way that all the sequences of the batch have the same length.
All right.
And now I'm going to start implementing the solution.
So since all the sequences in a batch must have the same length.
We're going to start from the sequence in the batch that has the maximum length and then what we'll
do is we'll take all the other ones and we will complete them with bad tokens so that all these other
ones have the same length as the largest one as the one with the maximum length.
So let's do this let's get this larger sequence and more specifically what we need exactly is the length
of this larger sequence because we will use this length to complete the other shorter sequences in a
batch.
So I'm going to introduce a new mobile here that I'm going to call next sequence length.
All right the maximum length of all the sequences in a batch Max sequence length.
And how are we going to get it.
Well we'll basically take the list of all the sequences and get the max of the length of the sequences
and there is actually a trick to do this in one line one line of code.
You might guess what it is.
It's the for loop inside the list.
And you know we take the maximum of the length inside this list as we have to put in square brackets
and there goes the for loop inside.
And so now what do we want to get.
Want to get the max of the sequences in the batch.
So we're going to have to loop over all the sequences in the match and to do that with you for sequences.
In Well our argument batch of sequences.
So I'm just copying this in batch of sequences.
And what do we want exactly.
Among all the sequences that we managed to get thanks to this loop Well we want the length of the sequence.
All right.
And thanks to the max you will get the maximum of the sequence length.
All right perfect So now we have the largest sequence length and we'll use that right now to complete
the other sequences which are shorter with tokens.
So I'm going to introduce a new line here and that's where I will complete the other sequences.
So how are you going to complete them.
Well first of all since that's exactly what we want to return you know the batch of sequences completed
by the tokens we are ready first to return what we want and what will come after the return is the batch
of sequences with the added tokens.
So how are we going to add these battlegrounds.
Well first of all we have to return the list of sequences.
So I'm introducing some square brackets here and then we're going to do the same trick before loop inside
this list because of course we have to loop over again all the sequences because for each of these sequences
we are going to add the path tokens to make them have an equal length to the largest one.
All right so for then sequence again in of course again our batch of sequences I copied that before.
And so that's the for loop.
And what we want to do comes before the for loop and what we must do is add the tokens to complete each
of these sequences and how are we going to do that.
Well the trick is to first take our sequence which so far has not long enough length but we are going
to add the tokens to that list the sequence right now is a list of token key identifiers.
And so what we're going to do is a list EDITION we're going to add up to list and the first list will
be the sequence.
And the second list will be a list of tokens of length that will complete the length of this new sequence.
We want to get so that it has an equal length as the largest sequence.
And the trick to do that is to add here plus then since we're adding up to lists I'm introducing some
square brackets here and inside the square brackets we're going to have the right number of tokens so
that our sequence gets the maximum length sequence and to do that's what we're going to do is well first
get our token but we need to actually get the integer ID of the PetroChina because remember our sequences
are encoded in two unique integers and therefore that's where our word to in dictionary comes into play.
We're going to get it to get this unique integer ID and coding the pet token.
So I'm taking my words in a dictionary and then in square brackets.
Well since the key of the dictionary is the token itself.
I just need to enter the token in quotes and so well we can get it here.
That's of course the bad token which I am copying here as the key of my word in dictionary that will
return the unique integer ID of the by token.
All right.
And then that's not over of course to complete the sequence so that it has the maximum length sequence.
We are going to multiply this single element list that contains the token ID by a scalar that is by
an integer which will be wait for it.
The maximum length sequence minus the length of that sequence.
And that will complete this sequence so that it gets the maximum length sequence with the tokens that
complete it.
All right so multiplying this single element list by scholar is like doing a list addition several times
so that it gets several tokens inside this list.
All right so as we just said we have to multiply this by the difference between the max sequence lengths
which we got at the previous line.
So the max sequence length minus the length of that sequence so that we can complete it with the token
IDs.
And so now very easy to get this length of the sequence we're dealing with right now in the loop.
Well we have to get the len function of that sequence and that will complete the sequence that it has
the maximum length sequence that is that it has the same length as a sequence that has the largest length.
All right.
I'm just removing that F here because that was the new variable which doesn't take an S and here.
Everything looks great.
We're ready to execute this to define the Apply padding function.
And there we go.
We now have our function apply betting and we will definitely like it very soon on our batch of sequences
until then.
And you've been on the.