Hello and welcome to this new tutorial and this one we're going to add the last tokens to our two previous
dictionaries that we just created.
And these last tokens are the ones that are useful for the encoder and the decoder in the sector like
model which are you know the star of string that we're going to encode by as so as the end of string
that we're going to encode by the OS the iPad which is very important for our model because the process
turning data and the sequences in the batches should all have the same length and therefore we have
to input this token in an empty position.
And eventually we will create a last token which will call out and that corresponds to all the words
that were filtered out by our two previous dictionaries.
Thanks to these dictionaries we know which words are not the five percent least we can word so later
on in one or two tutorials.
We will use these dictionaries to replace all the words all these five percent less frequent words.
By this token out so that these 5 percent less frequent words are all replaced by one same common token
which will be out.
So that's why it's very important for us right now to create these tokens.
And of course add them to our two dictionaries.
Questions words to end and answers words to it.
So let's do that.
Let's start by creating our list of final tokens so we're going to name that list tokens and remember
ellipses in square brackets.
And inside we just need to input these tokens so the aura is important here.
Otherwise this won't work.
Given the second Dementation that will follow the first one should be the pet inside this pair of symbol.
We input what we want and we will call it that.
All right then the next token should be the end of string which will also need to put in quotes.
And these math symbols.
So the end of string we're going to call it.
Oh that's the classic way to call it.
You will see that in a lot of papers and a lot of documentation the OS end of string.
Then the next one will be the token by which all the words that were filtered out by our previous dictionaries
will be replaced.
And as we said we want to call it out as in filter out.
So out and finally the last token we need is the start of string which remember only intuition lectures
is the first token that should start in the decoding layers.
You know when we decode the output of the encoder which is the context.
Well the first element of this decoding is the start string.
That's very important.
So that's why we need to include it right here.
Same in quotes and in these math symbols.
And we're going to call it the classic way as s star of string.
All right so we have our tokens and now we just need to add them to our previous dictionaries.
So now we can make two for loop one for loop for the questions worth two in dictionary and one of the
for loop for the answers words to any dictionary.
And this will be the same for those who will just do a copy paste.
Once we make the first one so for then.
Well we want to basically loop over all these tokens here so the loop variable is going to be called
token for token in tokens.
Very simply.
Then call in and inside.
We just need to add each one of these tokens to our questions word to any dictionary.
And you know how to do this the trick is just to take our dictionary questions words and some cutting
this and I am pasting that here then in square brackets.
I just need to enter this new key that I'm creating that I'm adding to my dictionary and this new key
is the token.
We are dealing with right now in the loop.
So that's the key because remember the keys identifiers in the questions words to int dictionary are
the words that are the tokens and then the values are of course some integers.
Remember it maps to questions words to a unique integer.
So what integer could we choose here.
Well it must not be one of the integers created here in this previous code section in this follow here.
But very simply we can just take the max.
Plus one of all the integers that we created here.
And since these integers were added from 0 to 1 to 2 to 3 etc..
Well we can simply take the length of the questions words to in dictionary because the length of this
dictionary corresponds to the total number of keys of this dictionary and that is the total number of
values.
And since we counted from 0 to number of keys well we can simply take here the length of this dictionary
plus one.
And with this will be sure that we have a unique integer for our new token.
So I'm going to add here Len.
Then I'm going to paste my dictionaries again and I'm going to add plus one as we just said and that's
it.
This loop is done because when we're done dealing with this token here in the loop we will get to the
next slogan but the length of the questions word in dictionary will have changed because we will have
just added a new token and therefore we are safe here the next token will have a new unique integer
that's perfect that works this way and simply we can move on to our other dictionary for the answers.
Which is answers words to it.
And as I said it's exactly the same the same logic when you just need to copy this page here and just
replace question by Answer There we go and says words to end.
And same here.
Answer these words to it are right and that will do it.
So now we simply need to select these lines and execute.
There we go.
We now have our final tokens the essential tokens for the sectors like.
Added to our two dictionaries.
Perfect.
Now we're going to move on to the next step which will be actually very quick and easy because we just
need to create the inverse dictionary of the answers words too in dictionary.
And why do we need to do that.
That's because we'll use this inverse mapping when building the SEC to sec model.
So we simply need to do that quickly and then we'll move on to the last final steps of data processing
and we'll quickly get support to building the at the SEC SEC model.
So I can't wait to get there.
And until then I depend on the.