Hello and welcome back to the course on the deep natural language processing.
And today we're talking about attention Mechanix.
So let's have a look.
This is where we stopped off previously.
So we've got an encoder which is a recurrent neural network and we've got a decoder.
Another recurrent neural network of the LSD and fashion.
And so here what is happening is we're feeding in our input into our encoder one by one into these layers
of neurons.
And then at the end we have this representation of our whole input here which is of called the vector
of meaning.
So the whole meaning of our sentence is contained to it here and then we use that.
So we use this layer now to decode our our whole neural network over here.
So to basically come up with a response using a decoder to the questions are here was something like
Did you like that last week.
And the responses yes it was great.
So that's what we have so far.
And the kind of like the weak point of this whole architecture is exactly over here.
So it's a great architecture it facilitates memory so we adding more and more information here so it's
all kind of like accumulating.
And then this vector meaning it has a lot of information has pretty much the whole sentence here.
So it's it's great that we facilitates memory.
However as you can imagine they first of all this is a fixed dimensional component of our network and
it is representing a variable variable length component or variable length input so our input could
be like a thousand words could be 10 words could be 100 words in every single case.
It's all stored in this fix them actual representation and that's not ideal.
So basically that's a lot of information to store here and moreover it doesn't really change depending
on what type of sensor you once you have this architecture you might need it a longer sense is a short
sentence and all the time it only has this facility in order to take care of the meaning of that information
and then the other thing is that after that this meaning has to be carried through the whole of the
decoder has to go all the way through the decoder has to carry a long we have it has to be able to maintain
all of the information was here in this in this layer as it goes through the decoder.
And words are pulled out of it's information is pulled out or like generated from it.
So this approach is is OK for kind of short sentences short responses and questions but as they grow
longer it becomes harder and harder for the network to do that.
To be able to provide proper responses and maintain that mean.
So that's what happens with Chad.
But we're also going to quickly discuss what happens even in translation because we will see through
all this tutorial that attention is a concept that is very very powerful in translation as well which
sequences sequence networks can be used for and translation is a good analogy in translation.
So the way it works is so here you've got the question you've got the sentence that should we want to
translate so they say in English and you want to translate into French or some other language.
It would be very simple.
So you have like a very similar type of literate primitive simply and in translation like that analogy
or the metaphor which I liked which I think it was.
Christopher Manning from Stanford which I heard from him on one of his online lectures.
The analogy is very powerful.
What he says is that like if you're a translator and you take all the like you have an input word having
just this one vector of meaning here is like reading the whole sentence that you need to translate and
then closing your eyes at it like OK I got the whole sentence in my head I'm going to translate it all
now.
So translators don't work like even human translators don't recognize you like you've got the sentence.
It might be long or short doesn't matter.
You translate it a bit by bit then you look back then you kind of like OK you like you get to certain
point and then you look at the sentence again and you keep going.
So you have the luxury of looking back at what you have just so that is the Nalgene translation.
And now we're going to start fixing this whole situation up.
All right so we're going to look at a different sentence just makes it up again a sentence.
How is your sister end of sentence.
I didn't put the question mark just have some space but feel free to ask the question about another
element.
And then our network is going to attempt to answer with.
Thank you.
She is fine.
And let's see how this plays out.
So first word and then we feed it back in you then.
Next word feedback thank you.
And this is where we're going to start talking about attention so attention along this way actually
was already here was already here when these words were generated we just didn't talk about it because
like I wanted to get away from the start I wanted to look at components like further down the sequence.
But the same principles apply here here everywhere.
So what does a station do.
Well basically before we have an output come in from here what happens is all of our input layers or
all of the components of the encoder like I've highlighted that we hear and read are taken and then
we're going to now look back at them so they were going to allow this stage or this component of the
D-CT are to look at what was a producer like.
Basically we're saying that the decoder has complete liberty to access any of the information that is
available before not just information that was encoded into this picture meaning that it was passed
on here was posted here and so on.
It does indeed have that but now it also has I like a special VIP access to all the information that
was available before.
And how does this access work.
Well through training the decoder will know which of these elements to pay the most attention.
And the way it looks is like this.
So for example it has learned to give weights of importance to these compounds.
So let's draw these weights.
There's five weights.
The bigger the weight the more significant the more important is that component and the weight gain
or the way that happens is through training.
Become a bit more clear just now as soon as we get this out here.
And so it knows these weights it knows that for this next output it needs to pay most weight on this
component.
And second most weight on this component third most weight on this compound these kookaburras don't
really matter.
And through a step a step which is called the soft back function which you won't get into now.
But what happens is basically these ways we make sure the algorithm make sure that these weights add
up to one.
So this by the looks of that will be like a point of point six point point to point one and point zero
five point zero or five.
So just just for us so that it's easier to operate.
And then what happens is we take these weights and we create a context.
How do we create it.
Well we take this weight and we multiply by this vector we may take this way multiply by this vector
this way.
By this one this way.
So this context vector is a weighted sum of all of these contex actors or all of these layers in our
recurrent neural network.
And so now we have the Quantic sector which is predominantly comprised of this vector a bit less of
this one.
One haaf like quite significantly less of this one and less of this and tiny bit of these two.
And then what we do with it's called the X factor is we it into this new layer of our decoder as an
additional input.
So now you have this input this input and this input range decoder and then we get the output which
is she wants to make this and I think she's fine.
OK so that's the mechanics.
Now let's assess what just happened.
Why.
Why are these ways like the burning question that you have right now.
I can feel it is why are the weights exactly like this.
Well let's think about it.
The decoder got is creating a sentence to tell us that this person that we've been asked about is fine.
And in English it the pronoun will depend on the gender.
Right.
So if it's free it's a female person it's a she.
If it's a male person it's going to be a.
So thank you.
He is fine.
I think she is fine.
The like the the point we have to understand here is that the meaning is the same.
He is fine or she is fine.
So that person is fine.
So the meaning is absolutely identical.
What's the D-CT and that's why.
That's another hint and why it's called the de-code or so it's kind of decoding the meaning of what
we want to.
And so we know like decoding the meaning into words we know what we want to enhance or we're building
what we want to answer.
And now we're slowly decoding it into words so we want to say that that person is fine they're OK everything's
great.
So now we're slowly building it up and we go to a stage where we need to decide what pronoun to use
and based on prior training we get this.
Right now we're Remember the difference between training and application.
Right now we're in application mode.
But before there would have been like millions and millions or hundreds of thousands of iterations for
training of this model and through training the
model would have learned that when you want to decide a pronoun you need to find now or other pronouns
in the question.
So it's a very simplistic explanation of course it's all based on neurons and the model has no clue
what a pronoun or a noun is it doesn't have the sign understanding of language constructs and so on
but it intuitively learns these things through iterations iterations and we can call them pronouns nouns.
The model doesn't care.
It just knows that when there's when there's a decision to say he or she it needs to go back and find
something like this.
And so basically that's where this highway comes from because it needs to make informed decision then
these are ways they don't matter as much.
This is the pre-Roman one.
But like I put them here just for illustration purposes and they can also impact this work right.
So let's have a look.
Why can this word impact this work.
Well because we're trying to say that wherever they're talking about wherever the question is about
that they are fine or that here fine or she is fine or it is fine if it's not that person.
But this word is it's tallying us.
How many of them are there for you.
So yes Sister indeed is singular.
But if we don't look at it like not only sister tells us about the number of people and number of subjects.
Also this word tells us so.
How are your sisters and brothers or how are your sister and brothers so that could have been a sentence.
So in that case there would still be singular but this is this word would tell us that actually there's
many people that were being lost.
So in this case in that case that's why the.
That's why the wait is important in that case if there are you know then this would have been thank
you.
Not she.
But I think they are find something.
So that's why they support it so it can have any impact.
But in this case is just confirming that Sister singular good.
So you didn't get additional information.
Then why does this one have a not a significant weight.
Why is it like it's small but it's still bigger than these two.
Of why with this one.
Well again for a similar reason that for example I'm not sure.
Like I this is not very old like I I just put this here to illustrate purposes like I have a point.
And the way I would interpret this if I saw something I guess I would say OK I meant maybe the network
is sees this POS as important it's because it wants to make sure that there's nothing coming further
so soon as it sees the U.S. It knows that there's no other subjects or other words again it could be.
How are your sister and brothers.
So but because it says the AOA as it knows that there's no one else saw it so therefore it nosiest and
the confirmation that this singular female so they would go.
That's the intention mechanism.
Let's have another step to kind of concrete this stuff in.
So next one is to fit in our response from the previous opponents and again we highlight our inputs.
That's where our attention is going to be based.
And then we look at the way it's to do something like this.
And then we build the context Victor and from the context vector we feed in the input or the output
that we feel in that context worked itself into as an input into this new way of the recurrent neural
network.
And so why is this important and now is going to be she is.
That's what we're looking for.
She is fine.
So why is this important.
Well you can pause the video and try to understand this yourself try to kind of assess this yourself.
If not then one two three.
This is my interpretation I would say well how is your sister.
Because here everyone is.
It's.
Right now we're kind of deciding we want to say that these people are that person or this subject is
fine or fine and we decide singular or plural so because this is singular it's going to be easier for
us to say it's a singular same process here sister.
So if it was how is your sisters.
That would be problematic.
But because it's incorrect.
But that's you know like if this were sisters then this would have been our right.
So they kind of linked in terms of singularity or singular or plural and therefore what you heard in
terms of plural or singular and so here.
Yes so that that does carry some kind of significance and it was similar to yours.
OK.