Hi everyone and welcome to this new update to our deep learning A.P. atheism course in this update we're
going to be focusing on a recently released version of the chapter from his course that was created
by Abraham Sanders.
So with that being said let's take a moment to thank Abraham because it's a great extension with some
awesome changes and features so to become more familiar with the chapter and the code.
When you get a chance you can find the repository here if we visit the following page.
At good hub dot com slash Abraham Sander's slash set to sec dash Chaput we can see the repository along
with the associated files and information.
In addition to the files here the files or the folder and containing the files is set to sec Chamba
will be attached to this lecture.
And you can find other related information useful context including the checkpoints and Waite's file
interactive options for running it and continuing training instructions within the repository.
So when you get the chance scroll through it it is a great way to familiarize yourself with the information.
And for the purpose of these lectures we're going to be examining a few changes in the code along with
some relevant useful information.
And at the end of the lectures we will look at how to visualize the intenser board and we will experiment
with the chap while running it and testing some of the commands.
Overall going through this code and this update is intended to help give you some ideas so that you'll
be able to incorporate some new features to your chat bots or help in the future if you decide to extend
the algorithm.
And you're also going to be able to train and chat with a new model.
But for now let's get everything set up that we need in order to run this version in the model we need
to upgrade our tensor of low by running the following command.
So we can launch the terminal and if you were working with a virtual platform or a container environment
such as the one we created in the course you will have to activate it first.
So if you're on a Mac or Linux you will use the source activate Shambat command.
If you are on Windows you will use the Activate chap on command.
Now I'm just gonna install it in my root directory here.
We will run those first.
If you are working with the Chaput platform so we want to run Pipp install upgrade tents or float and
I already have it installed so it will come back with a requirement already installed.
But we need to upgrade our tender flow for this model and we also need to install Jason Pickel and we'll
be using the same command.
The Pipp install upgrade Jaison pic will run
all right so we have everything set up and now we can get started.
If you get the chance I'd recommend again taking a look around the repository.
Since it has some very useful information for running the japa along with some of the information related
to the arguments and parameters and methods that were passed in and built into this chap but with that
we can wrap this up and I will see you in the next video.