Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning.
Today we're kicking off this section for recurrent neural networks and I'm very excited about this section.
There's going to be quite some interesting tutorials.
This is a one of the most advanced algorithms that exists in the world of supervised learning.
So let's get started.
We have our little breakdown of supervised versus unsupervised learning branches.
And here we've got artificial neural networks which we've already talked about.
We were talking about convolutional neural networks as well.
And today we're talking about recurrent neural networks.
So there's just so that we see where we are in the big picture of things slowly getting to the unsupervised
part of the course.
But nevertheless that's focused on our own ends today.
All right so now that we know where we are on the map in terms of a list let's have a look where we
are on the map in terms of the human brain.
And so why are we doing this why are we looking at the human brain as if it's a map of the world.
Well the reason for that is the whole concept behind deep learning is to try mimic the human brain and
get kind of similar functions as the human brain has and leveraged the things that evolution has already
developed for us.
And I thought it would be pretty cool if we can somehow link the different branches of deep learning
and we've discussed so we've talked about or the outcomes of risks we're talking about.
And then CNN and now we're talking about RNA and if we could link those to certain parts of the human
brain.
And if it don't make sense so let's have a look here.
We've got the brain the human brain has got three parts so get the cerebrum which is all of this colored
part.
Then we get the cerebellum which is underneath there and that's the little brain.
I actually looked it up in Latin and that does mean little brain.
And we've already looked at a dissection of the cerebellum in the Partow took about and ends that orange
that beat that big orange picture where we saw all of those little neurons that we were trying to kind
of gauge how many there are there are these millions of neurons in the brain and then we've got the
brain stem over here which connects the brain to the organs and her arms and legs and so on.
And so that's how the brain.
Those are the main three parts of the brain.
Now the cerebrum has for Lopez and they're colored in here.
So it's got the frontal lobe.
It's got that temporal lobe.
Got the parietal lobe and it's got the occipital lobe.
And now how do we link these.
Right.
So we've got.
And then we've already discussed CNN and Arnon.
And the interesting way the is on probably was to start off with.
And then because what is the main advantage of an ant.
Well the main advantage the main breakthrough in and ends is apart from the back propagation algorithm
which kind of applies to all of them.
And in fact whatever applies to and applies to everything here.
But for me I think the main thing about an ends and it wouldn't even exist without saying this whole
concept of depression when you don't exist are the weights.
The fact that a man's can learn through prior experience or through private airports and prior observations
that's extremely valuable.
And so what do those those weights represent and moreover the weights of course are present across all
neurons in the brain.
But we're going to try to take away the main philosophical underlying notion there and that is that
weights represent long term memory that once you run your own and then you've trained it you can switch
it off you can come back later it's trained up you know the weights and so whatever input you put into
it it will process it the same way as it would yesterday as it will tomorrow as it will the day after.
So the weights are long term memory over neural network and that's why weights or the A-n go into a
temporal lobe.
Again the weights exists across the whole brain but philosophically and ends are a start to deploring
and they represent long term memory so we're going to put them in the temporal lobe because the temporal
lobe lobe is responsible for long term memory hence called the temporal lobe meaning that lost things
lost through time and their brain is very complex and of course other parts also responsible for memory
as well.
But we're going to simplify things and say N-N is like that temporal lobe then CNN is much easier.
It's vision recognition of images and objects and so on and so that's the occipital lobe.
And today we're talking about our own ends.
And as you'll find out our own ends are like short term memory.
They can remember things that just happened in the previous couple of observations and apply that knowledge
in that going forward.
I'm giving away so much already.
You like your pretty much no there as this tutorial but nevertheless.
So that's the frontal lobe that's where we have a lot of the short term memory.
And of course the frontal lobe also like a quick breakdown of the frontal lobe also responds is responsible
for personality behavior or motor cortex working memory.
And like lots of other things but in our purposes the main thing that we're looking out for is the short
term memory.
By the way if you're interested.
Temporal Lobe is the temporal lobe is concerned with for cognition memory.
That's our long term memory parietal lobe is and these are from Wikipedia.
The parietal lobe is responsible for sensation and perception and constructing a spatial coordination
system to represent the world around us and we are yet to create a neural network which would fit into
that category and occipital is vision.
All right so there you go a bit of neuroscience so let's move on to our favorite neural networks.
So here we've got a simple artificial neural network three inputs to outputs one hand larrup.
What does a r n and how do we represent this as how do we represent or turn this into an RNA.
Well we squash it we squash it all together.
So they're still there but we think of it as if we're looking from underneath or from underneath this
neural network.
So we're looking for a new dimension.
Right so we're looking.
It's still there it's just flattened out.
We're looking at a we're adding a new dimension to all of this but remember that those neurons the whole
network is still there.
Nothing change we just question it for our purposes then to simplify things which is going to change
these multiple hours into two.
And we're going to twist this whole thing make it vertical because that's the standard representation
then in terms of neural networks we're going to call them instead of green.
We're going to color the hindlegs and blue.
And there we go and we're going to add this line.
And what does that line do.
Well that line is the temporal loop and this is an old school representation of our own ends and basically
means that this hidden layer not only gives an output but also feeds back into itself.
So again this is an optical representation so the common kind of approach is now to unwind this or unroll
this temporal loop and represent and ends in the following manner like that so you can see that again.
Don't forget that we've got we've had lots of these things happening right so you're looking in a new
dimension that the layers are actually still there are still there but we're just not focusing on them.
We just remember that each one of these circles is not one you are on.
It's a whole layer of neurons.
And so what is happening is you've got inputs coming into the neurons then you've got outputs but also
the neurons connecting to themselves through time.
So that's the whole concept that they have some sort of memory short term memory that they remember
what was in that neuron just previously or.
And then the one before that.
Or before that it used to remember what it was previous and that allows them to pass information onto
themselves in the future and analyze things.
Kind of like when you're you know when you're watching this course right.
So it would be very sad if you could not remember what was happening in the previous tutorial.
I mean even if we break time down discreetly through not by seconds but like continuous seconds by discreetly
through tutorials and we say like every moment in time is you tutorial it would be very sad if you did
not remember what we had in the previous tutorial or in the previous section or in the previous part
of the course.
Right because then this whole recurrent neural networks part wouldn't makes any sense.
You wouldn't have memory of what a neuron is what an activation function is but because you do remember
those things you can understand this and same thing here.
So how why would we deprive a artificial construct which is supposed to be a synthetic human brain or
like a mimicking the human brain.
Why would we deprived of something so powerful as short term memory long term memory is great but short
term memory is so powerful why would we not give it that opportunity and that's where recurrent neural
networks come in.
That's the gap that they feel it.
And so let's have a look at a couple of examples.
A huge shout out to the Karpovsky blog Capozzi don't get how do I owe some of these examples from here.
So one to many relationship this is when you have one input and have multiple outputs.
Example of this is an image where a computer describes the image you have one input the image and that
would go through a CNN and then would be fed into an R and it and then the computer would come up with
words to describe the image.
And this is an actual computer describing image.
How accurate is that black and white dog jumps over bar.
This is the computer looked at this image and it like up.
It's a black and white dot based on what it's previously learned.
You know the long term memory allowed it to come up with weights and come up with certain feature feature
feature recognition system and come up with the filters come up with everything that is required to
CNN and then the Arnon allows it to make sense out of the sentence right so you can see that the sentence
actually flows.
You know there's a there's an and there's a lake over the bar and then there's like a verb there's a
noun and so on.
So basically it allows the Arnon is what allows it to put a sentence together in this case then many
to one would and example would be sentiment analysis.
So when you have a lot of text and from that text you kind of need to gauge is it other people.
Is this like a positive comment or a negative comment what's the chance that it's a positive or positive
or negative is that comment.
And you've got an example here as well.
And again there's lots of other different examples these are just some.
Then we've got many too many for instance.
I wanted to show you this one so here we've got an example of Google translator and I don't know if
a Google translator uses Arnalds or not.
I know that they have very sophisticated deep learning in Google mind and I've heard that they've used
that in their Android systems and so on.
I'm not sure if they use Arnaz here or not but the concept remains.
So if I say here from English to check I say I am a boy who likes to learn.
You cloak carrier out to it.
Right.
And basically in other languages in some other languages it is important.
What's gender you're a person is right.
So here boy is male.
So that's why he's got Teri arat.
And if you see if I change this to girl in English the other words don't change but in check the other
words change you said Holker caetera Aranda said.
It so you can see right away.
Now it's not really a rat.
It's caetera meaning that these words they depend on the gender of this word Holker and Holker is a
girl and therefore this becomes caetera rather and again I don't know for google translate these are
an enemy who are going to comment on that.
But basically the concept is the same that you need short term information about the previous word in
order to translate the next word right.
You can just translate word by word and it's just a simple example and of course it's like it makes
to make a sentence make sense.
You didn't do need information about the.
But like a very visual example we have here is that the at the least you need to know the gender of
this word too in order to translate the following words for the sentence to make sense.
And that's where our own ends have power because they have short term memory and they can do these things.
So there we go that's a many to many.
You put in lots of words and then you get lots of words out that translation.
And of course not every example has to be related to text or images there can be lots and lots of different
implications of ordnance.
For instance many too many you can use are an ends to subtitle movies meaning that you can have running
spells so basically or describe every single frame in a movie and that is something you can simply do
with a CNN or other neural network because if you're watching a movie you need context about what happened
previously to describe what's happening now.
And so you need that short term memory you can't just run around through a million movies and kind of
understand the whole plot that is going to happen you need short term memory of the plot to be able
to comment on every single frame.
And speaking of movies today we don't have additional reading today we have additional watching.
So a movie called some spring in 2016 directed by Oscar Sharpe and it's got you know this actor almost
middle age from TV shows Silicon Valley and this movie was entirely written by Benjamin who is a Arnon
and LACMA to be specific so I'm going to show you this movie now.
Well I'm not going to play it.
I'm just she will find it so she goes.
Ars Technica it's only nine minutes long.
I highly recommend it.
I've seen it twice.
It's so it's so fun like you will find that.
So a couple of things this is a great description here as well so it's worth reading through this action
interview Benjamin and he actually gave himself the name of Benjamin.
That's why they call him Benjamin.
Is this really cool to see these things and what you'll find about movie is the acting is amazing just
amazing.
Like I had shivers down my spine towards and it got in the top 10 in London in the London Sify in the
Sipher London Festival.
And then what you'll find is that Benjamin is able to construct sentences which kind of makes sense
for the most part which is good but what he lacks is kind of the bigger picture.
He cannot come up with like a plot that constantly makes sense even that even though the actors do a
great job about putting it together and it does look amazing in the end.
But you will notice and kind of look out for this separate when you're watching separate the sentences
and you'll see that each sentence on its own more or less 90 percent of the time makes sense.
But overall he cannot properly link sentences together.
And that's that's the next step for our own ends where you know we're this is still quite a new technology
or it's only picking up recently so it will be developed very soon.
And maybe when you're watching this tutorial you're laughing in the future to five years from now you're
laughing to herself and you're saying oh we've already passed that milestone and probably we will very
soon.
But this is where things are now.
And I highly recommend checking this out.
Only nine minutes long.
So there we go.
That's what our Arnold's are.
In a nutshell and in the next tutorial we will continue digging deeper look for the next time.
Until then enjoy learning.