Hello and welcome to part three training the SEC to sec Merrill we just built a brain in the previous
part part to building the success moral and now it's time to train this brain and this part three to
make it smart or at least able to talk able to chat with us.
So for this tutorial everything's going to be fine.
We're going to set some values for the hyper parameters that will be used during the training obviously
and that you will be able to change if you want to experiment more and try to improve the results.
I remind that machinery in deep learning AI and also of course deep in our be a lot of the work is experimentation
tweaking the parameters to try to find the best model that will lead to the best accuracy.
And eventually in our case the best shot but so we're going to choose some values here.
I'm not saying these are the best values at the end of this course.
We will actually try to improve the model by either tweaking the parameters or improving the data processing
or even improving the architecture of the sector sick brain of our chat.
But but these are at least relevant values that are most of the time the values used in the architecture
of the neural networks you can find online.
So let's do this let's set these parameters and we're going to start with the number of epochs.
So I remind in that book is the whole process of getting the batches of input into the networks then
for propagating them inside the uncurse get the states then for propagating the uncurse States with
the target inside the Dakota record renewal that work to get the final output first if I don't output
scores with then the final answer as predicted by the chat but and then back propagating the lust generated
by the outputs and the target back into the neural network and updating the weights towards the direction
of a better ability for the chatbot to speak like a human.
So a netbook is basically one whole iteration of the training and we're going to choose one hundred
epochs.
However if the training takes too long on your computer.
Well I recommend to choose less books like 50 but not too low because we really need a lot of books
to get some correct results.
So airbags equals 100.
Then we'll take care of the batch size and we'll choose a batch size to start with 64.
And again if the training takes too long you can try 128.
This will get basically more questions and get answers in your batches to train the new network to batch
size across 64.
Then we have to choose a value for the Arnon size the size of the Arnon and we'll choose 512 then the
number of layers.
The number of layers which is how many layers you have in the end co-direct renew that work and also
the decoder Recker a new network.
The number of layers and we're going to choose three layers three layers and we'll probably change that
at the end of the implementation when trying to improve the model.
So non-players all three then we have to choose the encoding embedding size which I remind is the number
of columns in your embeddings matrix that is the number of columns you want to have for the Billings
values.
Where in this matrix each line corresponds to each token in the whole corpus of the questions.
So encoding and building size.
And we're going to choose a size of 512 meaning that we're going to have 512 columns in this embeddings
matrix.
Then I'm going to copy this because our next hyper parameter is going to be the not the encoding embedding
size but the decoding and building size for which will also choose 512 decoding embeddings size then
their learning rate.
Very important hyper parameter.
The learning rate is quite tricky We never know exactly what to choose.
It must not be too high it must not be too low.
If it is too high.
Basically your model will learn too fast and will therefore not learn how to speak properly.
And if it's too low.
Well basically it will take ages for the model to learn how to speak properly so learning rate.
That's a tricky one.
We're going to start with 0.01.
I'll do a lot of experimenting so make sure to check out you know the checkpoint lectures which are
actually articles but the checkpoint lectures at the end of each part where I share the code because
basically I give the last version of the code that I always try to improve.
So in these checkpoint lectures you will always have the best version of the code with the best hyper
parameters and the best improvement the best corrections because at the time I'm speaking this is the
first time I implement this.
And therefore you can imagine that by trying to improve it and improve it and improve it again while
the code and therefore the child but will definitely improve over time.
So I'm starting here with a learning rate of 0.1 but don't be surprised if you find another learning
rate in the implementation given in the checkpoint.
So learning raising calls 0.01.
And now we're going to have to choose learning rates.
So that's basically by which present age the learning rate is reduced over the iterations of the training
because you know we want to start with a certain learning rate but then want to play decay over the
iterations of the training to reduce the learning rate so that it can learn in more depth the logic
of human conversations.
In our case or in general the correlations identified in the data set.
So learning read decay very important parameter as well.
And we're going to choose a common value that you will find in most implementations.
We're going to choose a decay of 90 percent 0.9.
If you look at the implementations and get Herb or on any other open source platforms you will either
find a decay of 0.9 or one meaning that there is no decay but we're going to apply a decay here which
will be 90 percent then next type of parameter is a minimum of the learning rates we want to apply because
since we are applying the decay the learning rate will be reduced over the iterations and we have many
iterations so we don't want the learning rate to reach a too low value.
And for this we're going to set a minimum learning rate and this hybrid parameter for that will be men
learning rates which we will set to be called to 0 point 0 or 1.
So that's a very low minimum learning rate but at least the training will end for sure.
And besides we will try to add some early stopping in case there is literally no improvement during
the training.
So no worries with that and early stopping the training will come to an end.
And finally we have one last type hyper parameter to include here which is the key prob. hyper parameter.
And for this I'd like to show you something.
So I'm going to go to Google now and the thing I wanted to show you is this paper by the best of the
best.
Jeffrey Hinton Jeffrey Henzen is the guru of artificial intelligence.
He is the top one reference in deep learning artificial intelligence and all the research around it.
And actually the new very promising capsule networks are invented by Geoffrey Hinton.
So this is a paper by Geoffrey Hinton called drop out a simple way to prevent neural networks from overfishing
and we're going to trust the value recommended for the drop out rate in this paper.
If we scroll down a little bit well first you have some nice explanation on what it is about and especially
here you see you implying dropout that neuron is present with a certain probability p which is of course
our key prob. probability the parameter that controls to drop out rate.
But mostly that is equal to one minus the dropout rate.
And that is for the training time there is we only deactivate the ruins with a probability one man's.
During the training time and then a test time of course all the neurons are always present.
That's why I remember when getting our test predictions we didn't apply drop out.
That's because the neurons are always present.
So basically this keep drub parameter is one minus the dropout rate it's the probability of a neuron
to be present during the training.
And so if we scroll down even more we will find a recommended value for this dropout rate right here.
Page 1133 we see that dropping out 20 percent of the input units and 50 percent of the hidden units
was often found to be optimal.
So this keep up hyper parameter for which we have to choose value is actually for the Hittleman it's
not input units and therefore we're going to trust Jeffrey Henton for the first try of our model.
We're going to choose a dropout rate of 50 percent which therefore is a probability of 50 percent as
well because the probability is 1 minus the drop out rate.
So that means that during the training the neurons of our record a neural networks will be present with
a probability of 50 percent and we'll see how it goes.
But I feel safe using Jeffrey Hinton's research results.
So let's go back to Python and let's include this keep probability high parameters like that keep probability
on purpose you know instead of keep prob because this is the name in the tensor of API and therefore
you must introduce it this way keep probability keep prob won't work.
So keep probability.
And this we will choose as we said 50 percent that is 0 point five and there we go.
We are done with our hyper parameters we could choose some more happy parameters if we want to develop
even more the morals.
These are not the only hyper parameters but that's definitely the most important ones for our model.
And again feel free to tweak them.
I will tweak them even more I will do some research to try to improve the chatbot as much as possible.
But for starters these should be rather than the values and the way we will test them in the end.
In part for testing the second set model.
So now let's select all these and execute.
There we go.
We now have our hyper parameters and so we were ready to move on to the next steps.
So the next steps are going to be quite quick and easy.
We'll just basically prepare the training so that we are ready for it.
That's going to be a big part.
Try to get some good energy for it because we are going to have a quite long journey until then and
already been on the.