Hayes welcome to part for testing the SEC to sec model and congratulations for having reached this far
indeed you built a brain you trained the brain and now you're about to chat with a chat but so congratulations.
You did the most difficult part.
So as you can see right now on my computer the training is still going on.
I just woke up after a good night's sleep.
And as you can see we've reached already the third book and I already got some weight that we can see
here in File Explorer.
So these are the first weights and therefore these are not the weights of some very smart brain.
Or should I say of some brain with high abilities to speak with us.
So we're going to have to wait some more for some better weight.
And on my computer unfortunately this is going to take a couple of days.
But no we will get them.
And besides in the meantime I'll give you an awesome pre-trained chat but which is my favorite.
But in the whole internet so I will show you how to execute this chat and chat with it.
But in the meantime we're going to implement part four now to test the second sic model and basically
implemented code that allows us to speak with the chair.
But in the council but as far as I'm concerned I'm going to do that on another computer because I want
to leave the training do it things peacefully on this computer.
So I'm going to jump now to my other computer.
Welcome guys and welcome again to part for testing the sector to signal.
So as you can see I've transferred everything from the old computer on which the training is going to
this computer which is by the way my laptop.
And so now we're going to implement part four that will allow us to chat with the chat but with the
weights that we've got so far.
After a couple of hours of training I remind that the results will be very poor because the chat but
needs to train a lot more to know how to speak like this would be the case for a child learning how
to speak but you will know how to implement the code to chat with a chat.
But and besides when we have better wait in a couple of days well we will load these ways of course
in a flashlight to have a better chat with the checkbook.
All right so we're going to start by actually loading these weights and running the session.
And so to do that I'm going to introduce the checkpoint variable which is going to contain the path
to these weights.
And so the path is in the working directory for that which is this folder right now.
And in this folder.
Well we need to get the shot but underscore weights that S.K. Peachi and that's it you know.
So only this part in the weights you don't have to include the rest.
So jabat weights that seek it.
All right.
So that's our checkpoint.
And now what we're going to do is open a session so introducing a new voice won't hear session and I'm
getting a sense of flow because the session is actually going to be new object of the interactive session
class which we already used.
It was actually in the training.
So now we have our session and now we're going to do is the same you know we take our session object
and then used a run method from this object to initialize the global variables with tens of flow that
global variables initialiser this one.
And with some parenthesis.
And then after that that's where we will connect these loaded weights to the session and to do this
we'll have to create a new object.
This Savir object which will create by taking tenths of first then the train module and then the saver
class.
All right so this is just an object of the saver class.
And now that's where we connect the session to the checkpoint through the Saveur because we're going
to take our Savior and then use the restore.
It's like a load function.
The restore method from the saver class to connect our session and our checkpoint.
All right.
And there we go.
This way we load the weights.
All right.
And no need to execute anything right now will execute everything in the end.
So I'll see you in the next tutorial for the next step which will be to make a function that will convert
the sequences and string in the question to sequences of there including integers.
We'll need to do that to set up the chat afterwards which will be our last step until then.
And again I'll be.