Hello and welcome to this new tutorial in the previous Statoil we imported the data set.
We now have the lines and the conversations and two separate data sets that we called conversations
and lines.
And now what we have to do is to create a dictionary that maps each line with its ID.
So why do we have to do that.
What is the purpose of doing this.
Well first of all one of the best advice that I can give you for coding is to always understand where
you come from and where you want to go.
So we come from the previous story where we import the data set and now we need to understand where
we want to go and where we want to go.
What we want to think in the end is a data set that contains basically two columns the input and the
output because the inputs will be the inputs that will be fed into the neural network and the outputs
will be the target.
You know because we will compare the target that is the real replied.
Reply by the characters to the answer.
Reply by the chat but and thats how the chat but will learn to speak whether its prediction is close
to the target.
So where we want to go is two words a dataset composed of inputs and outputs and the way to do that.
The easiest way to do this is with the dictionaries because we'll have to keep track of the conversations
to make a correct mapping between the inputs and the output.
And by the way this is a first dictionary that we are creating but you're going to see that you'll create
many others.
And besides knowing this we want to obtain such a structure.
Well keep in mind that you'll have to do a lot of cleaning because in order for the training to go smoothly.
Well the techs have to be as much as possible.
They need to be simple simplified as much as possible and you will see that will have some cleaning
Suppe phases in this data preprocessing phase.
So that's why right now we need to first create a dictionary that will map each line with its ID.
And let's start doing this right now in this tutorial.
So to initiate.
To initialize or introduce a dictionary.
We need to start like this.
We need to first give it a name and we're going to give it the following name.
We want to map each line with its ID.
So the key identifier of the dictionary will be the ID of the line and the value will be the line itself.
So since we map from the ID to the line the following name we're going to give to our dictionary will
be ID to line.
I did to like and to initialize a dictionary only to do it this way by introducing a pair of brackets
just like that.
All right so dictionary initialized and now the common thing that happened afterwards after initializing
is naturally a loop because we are going to iterate through all the lines of our lines dataset and for
each of these lines we are going to split.
First the line because it is separated by the plus plus plus dollar plus plus plus we are going to split
that into the different elements of the row and then we will get the key which is the first element
and then we will get the value that is the line up which is the last element.
You know if I open this again well this is what will split the value here and the first element is this
one the ID that will map to the last element which is this one.
They do not.
OK so let's do this.
Let's start this all up.
So to start followed we start with for of course then we need to give the loop variable which we will
call line because we are iterating through the lines.
So for line in the well in lines because our lines are in our lines dataset then Cullen and then we
enter the loop.
So first Rimando was wanted do we want to open this again we want to split this because we want to get
this and this.
So we want to split this whole value here and we're going to split this by this string here plus plus
plus plus plus plus.
And the way to do this is to first take the line and I'm going to add an underscore here first and that
just means a temporary variable because it will actually not be used later.
It's like a local variable that is only going to be used in the loop.
So on that score line equals.
And this is where I'm going to make the split so I'm going to take my line which is a loop variable
line that split parenthesis and then in the parenthesis when it's input.
What do we want to split by.
And we want to split by the plus plus plus dollar plus plus plus so end quote.
I'm going to add space plus plus plus dollar plus plus plus there is a space because if you look closer
there is actually some spaces between the elements and this string here plus plus plus plus plus plus
all right so be careful with that.
So that makes the split and then we're going to get what we want that is the line ID and the line itself.
That is the text but just for safety purpose we're going to make sure that the line has the correct
length which should be fine.
You know if we can do this again.
Well each line should have 5 elements 1 2 3 4 and 5.
We just need to make sure of that.
Otherwise we will get some shifting issue and that could be bad.
So in order to avoid this shifting issue it's better to only get the IDs and the lines for the lines
they have for sure five elements and it's OK if we lose some lines so that's OK.
And so as we said if the length of the line the temporary local voidable line is equal to five.
Well what do we do.
We're going to get the key and fire which is the line ID and the value which is the line itself the
line set by the character and there is actually a trick to do that in one line.
We simply need to take our dictionary that was introduced as ID to line and then in brackets we can
enter the key here which is line 0 and then to get the value but not only get the value but also to
do the mapping at the same time.
We simply need to add here equal to value itself which is line and which element of the line.
Well look at this again you know the key identifiers does and the value is this.
They do not.
And that's the 0 1 2 3 4 element and counting from 0 because indexes in Python start at zero.
So be careful that the fourth index and the fifth index and therefore here I am entering four.
And that gives my dictionary that creates my dictionary that maps each line ID with its text.
So let's check that.
Let's check if everything's OK and let's have a look at our dictionary.
So press incremental control plus enter to execute.
There we go dictionary.
I did to line create it as you can see it was recognized by both and directly as a dictionary.
And if we double click on it yes if you double click on it.
Well we get our dictionary with in the first column here the key the key identifier as I told you.
And in this column here the value which is the line itself said by the character.
So for example if we take this line here well the line is you know I can talk about that.
That's the value of the dictionary and it has the key identifier L A thousand six.
So there are a lot of lines but there we go.
We got our dictionary that's perfect.
And that will be very useful for us to then get this special structure of the dataset that I spoke of
at the beginning of the story.
Perfect.
So now we're ready to move onto the next step which is to create a list of all the conversations with
the IDs as we got in the conversations they just set.
And we want to do that of course because we need to keep track of the conversations for the training
data.
So we'll see that in more details in the next the Tauriel.
And until then Id been on the.