Hello and welcome to this new tutorial and this one we're going to load the model input that is we're
going to load the inputs of our set to morrow and to do this we have a great tool for this which we
actually made ourself which is the model input function that we made in part to building the SEC moral.
That was the first one.
This one here that returns the inputs to targets the learning rate and the key probability hyper parameter
and we chose a learning rate of 0.1 1 percent and keep probability of 50 percent.
All right so we're going to use this function basically to return all these model inputs that will be
just one line.
Very easy.
Let's do it.
So the first thing returned by this function is the inputs.
That's basically the questions that will feed into our set to SEC Network.
Then we also have the targets which are the target answers the answers to the questions target.
Then the third element returned by this function is the learning rate L R and finally the fourth and
last elements returned by this function is the keep prob parameter keep probability and all of these
these four elements are the four elements returned by our model inputs function.
All right so let's get all these inputs by executive on this line and there we go we have the inputs
to target learn rate and the key probability parameter.
So another quick and easy step.
Right now it's pretty calm but then we're going to have a storm when starting the big main part of the
training but no worries we will survive it.
So now I'll see you in the next tutorials to do some other quick steps and then we'll start this main
part of the training until then.
And Jaideep an Audi.