Hey guys welcome back.
OK.
This is the section you've probably all been waiting for.
This is where we take the processes and the information that we've learned in the past lectures and
sections and we work on isolating out the process we use to create our content.
And then we start automating and so we'll do in this section is we'll start talking about process flows
and workflows that will the next lecture isolating out tasks that you do well and tasks that other people
do well.
Dividing them into assignable chunks then we'll start learning how to use Trello to make what's called
a Conboy onboard then we'll learn how to use later gram and optionally buffer if you want to to learn
how to prescheduled posts and then we'll get into writing requirements finding the right people to do
each individual segment of our workflow and how exactly do we optimize and maintain that process.
All right guys this is the section where I let you in on the behind the scenes how I'm doing a lot of
the content production how I set up the process and hopefully will give you a template for how you can
do it for virtually anything.
All right.
With that being See you next lecture.