Hey guys welcome back.
OK so in this section we're going to talk about competitions.
Now competitions are pretty simple it's when you give away something usually something that doesn't
cost you a lot of money or it's something that cost you a lot of money and in return you get increased
engagement follows tags chairs whatever it is that you want.
You can tailor a competition for that.
So this lecture that's what we're going to do want to talk about the types of competitions out there
like giveaways and sweepstakes and as I said a very large variety of them.
We're talking about the best practice so you don't do them incorrectly and get in trouble and we're
going to try our best to figure out what the monetary value of pulling one of these off is now this
is one of these sections where you can sit back and relax and just watch if you want to watch me screw
around and blow some money and see how it works.
That's perfectly fine with me.
So if you have a budget and it's something that you actually could justify for your business Well I
think this is the section for you.
See you next lecture.