Hey guys, welcome back.
Let's go over quickly what we're
going to cover in this section.
OK, now, if you have experience with Instagram, you have
a profile that you like, and you're, you know, crushing
it with the daily feed of you smashing your face into bread,
well, then I would suggest skipping this section entirely, or
at a minimum being picky about the lectures you watch.
You'll be warned at the outset of each lecture that, you
know, this lecture is the equivalent of a G-rated movie -
also known as extremely boring, because
there's no gunfights or curse words. OK.
You've been warned.
Please don't be this guy. Anyway, what we're going
to start off by doing is talking about your profile,
what goes into it,
what parts are your top tier concerns
and what parts are minor,
we'll talk about picking or creating a profile image
that works specifically on this platform, how to
create a dummy account which we'll, you know, incorporate
into our growth strategies later on, how to get
your very own special pretty links, links that don't
look like crap, and we'll spend some time getting
the absolute beginners used to the basic UI. That's
going to be a lecture, for those of you guys who have
an Instagram account, please skip it.
We'll talk about what to do when the name you want
is inevitably taken by a group of Danish teenagers
(that will make sense later), how to write your own bio,
and how to get started with some basic analytics tracking.
All right. Got it?
Everything to do with the profile is
going to be covered in this section.
Why do we care about the profile?
Well, I don't know, it would be like asking why do
we care about the home page of our website.
Now, for those of you who know the answer, good job,
you're done with this lecture, and those of you who
don't know why a home page is important,
I'll indulge you, but Jesus, we are off to a bad start.
No matter what your goal is embarking on this
journey of Instagram growthage - real word -
whether it's just a ton of followers or more leads for
your business, or more revenue for your business,
whatever, every possible follower, lead, meat sandwich
filled with money, they have to go through your profile.
The entire business of Instagram,
believe it or not, is for the most part
limited to one link in your profile.
Now, that's where you can drive people to your website,
to your lead generation page, or to whatever, even
other Instagram accounts.
Yes, I know, you can make money elsewhere on Instagram,
and we will cover those, but this is the number
one place of concern for you as a business.
Make a bad impression, lose the followers.
Make a good impression, and everything
else will seem like a piece of cake.
So take this section seriously.
It's the foundation of any success
you have with this platform.
Got it?
All right.
See you in the next lecture, where we're going to break down
the profile into digestible chunks that we can target one by one.