Hey guys, welcome back.
OK, so we're going to talk about another crucial
part of your profile, that's the profile photo.
So where does the profile photo
fall in the order of importance?
Well, I'd say it's probably only second to the combination
of your username and your profile name, and, well,
obviously your content is number one to all of that,
but when we're talking about the five or six things we have to optimize in the profile page, I'd probably put it like number two.
It's important because it sets the stage for your account.
A great looking profile primes people to
think that this is a high quality account.
Don't be surprised if people follow you
just for having a great profile shot.
That actually does happen quite a bit.
Great shot, I'll follow you. Sometimes
they don't even look at your actual photos.
But if you're a branded company, then I'd say it really
has less to do with your profile quality, simply
because I don't know what people really expect you
to put besides your company name or just your logo.
So in the case of business profiles, people just subconsciously check off that "Hey, it's not a pixelized photo
of a naked mole rat or a middle finger,
so we're pretty much good." Regardless,
put some thought and effort into this.
So, you know, with that being said,
how exactly do you rock a profile photo
in the profile photo game of Instagram?
Well, first thing you need understand
is how it technically works.
So where exactly are you going
to see the profile photo?
Well, if you've never used Instagram,
I will tell you. One is on the profile page in the top left,
but also you have a tiny, tiny thumbnail
version of it in comments,
and then, again, you might see it at the top left of your
profile, but on web, and on web it's a different size.
So you have your web profile, your mobile profile, and then
you have your comment miniature thumbnail. Mobile
phones and tablets always show the logo the
same size, but web essentially upgrades it.
OK.
So here's the rule: 110 pixels by 110 pixels is what you
see on mobile. Now, 180 by 180 is what you see on web.
So that means we should use a photo that is, you
should probably make your photo 180 by 180.
You really don't want your photo to look pixelated
or rasterized, if you're fancy, on web browsers,
because a significant amount of the
traffic actually is on web browsers.
Now that we've covered the size and gotten that down,
what do we need to say about shape?
Well, as the more astute in the
course have noticed, it's a circle.
Now, do you want to upload a photo that
is a circle then? Well, no. If you do that,
then essentially the Internet explodes and it's kind
of like dividing by zero. It creates a black hole.
You can't do it and it's irresponsible to even try.
So you upload a square photo.
Yes, a square.
Who said rectangle?!
You need a square.
Luckily, any time you upload a photo for your profile picture, Instagram, inside of the app, will actually help you crop it,
so it's really not that big of a deal.
Now, everything else I can give you is in the form of
wisdomly and wizardly advice, really it's just going
to come down to what type of account you have or
you're going for, at least. If you're a company or a
brand, and you're just making a profile for
an extension to that, then it's relatively simple.
You put your logo. I'm really not kidding on this one.
Your main goal is to provide something that's
consistent with your name and account.
If someone expects to see something, well, then you
want to meet that expectation. With regards to logos,
there are a couple of tips though. If you can, use the
symbol of your logo and not the text. The symbol,
if you don't actually know what I'm talking about, is
the graphic that generally accompanies the name
of your company or often is just by itself.
Nike's is a swoosh, Puma's is like
a house cat, and Adidas is...
I honestly don't know what the hell Adidas is. The reason
we preferably use a symbol is that the user can already
see who you are by virtue of your
account name and username,
so it's kind of redundant. If you don't have
a symbol in your logo, it's perfectly fine.
a symbol in your logo, it's perfectly fine
- a lot of people don't -
then you have to use what's called logotype.
Logotype is your name, but it's in a stylized way.
So some companies don't have symbols,
they just have their name, but it's all funky.
An example of this might be like Under Armour's logo.
It's like a U and an A kind of mixed together.
There's also this one, if you look at H&M.
Literally just H&M, that's their logo,
but it's written funky and it's in red.
Now, if you don't even have that, then just try to put
the most simple and uncluttered version of your
logo you can. Sometimes we just don't have non-text
logos, or the text we have is really similar to what
you would just get if you typed it into a Word doc.
That's fine.
What you can do though is just go
for the shortest thing you can.
You really just have to make do with what you have
and keep in mind it's going to be viewed in a circle.
OK, here's an example of a company
that just didn't do anything.
This is Foundr (minus the E at the end),
and they do really well on Instagram,
but I mean, they did a decent job with their logo,
given the circumstances. Not ideal, but they don't have
a symbol logo, and that is technically their logotype.
OK, so your logo, well, that's boring, right?
How exactly can you stand out?
Well, I'd say there's two ways that
I've seen that seem to work.
The first one is to use the background of the page
or the circle outline of your image in your logo.
OK, let's look at WeWork, for example.
WeWork is, they do rentals for co-working
spaces that are hip and cool all over the world.
Here, what they did is they made a concentric circle
inside of the gray line that automatically shows
whenever you put a profile photo,
so it looks like the image edge is
actually part of the logo itself.
Nicely done.
So nice, I almost want to pay $45 a
day to use their co-working spaces.
I say almost, because $45 a day for
cucumber water... kind of stupid.
But with that logo, mmm, I don't know.
All right, now here's another one. Walmart.
And yes, I know, they are the Fortune 500 equivalent of
the death star, but their logo works. White on white
stands to highlight the actual color in the logo.
Here's another one.
The Onion. I don't know if you guys have
ever read The Onion, they're hilarious.
They kind of do the same thing.
They use the white background to blend in the page.
You know what you get extra points for? You get extra points
if you can actually get your logo to work with that red
and magenta circle that shows around your
profile when you have a story posted.
But that is boss mode,
and trust me, we'll get into that and
the whole stories thing later on.
I've only seen a couple accounts ever do it well. Now, if you want to spice it up a little more, try using the inverse of your logo.
OK, some branding experts would disagree that you
should ever do this, but I personally think it spices
things up and people still recognize who you are. Look at Tinder's website, and then look at the profile photo they have, for example.
They inverted their colors. Cool.
OK, what if you're just a person and not a brand then?
OK.
Again, pretty straightforward as to your options.
You - and get this - want to show your face.
Not only do you want to show your face,
you want to show a good photo of your face.
OK, here's the thing with personal accounts, your face conveys your personality way more than your body or your clothes.
We are social animals.
We get a lot more information off of
the face than we do your chesticles.
So, first thing, don't go for a body shot,
show your face as much as you can.
The second thing you should do is make sure
that you have a high resolution image,
that was preferably shot professionally, and that
essentially means it was shot with a good camera, light,
and someone who knows what they're doing. And I don't
generally mean, like, you know, the hostage photos
you took standing next to a wall for your work lanyard.
I mean, like a professional headshot. Like, for instance,
what did you use for your LinkedIn photo?
I'm not saying use LinkedIn's photo, because
sometimes those are really too stuffy,
but you want one that's as high quality as possible.
If your photo was shot from, like,
an iPhone, it's fine, but it's not great.
You're not really doing yourself justice.
Remember, this is like one of the first things people
see. Look, here are photos of me on an iPhone,
and here are photos of me with an actual person who
knows what they are doing with the camera - went from
potato face to glorious magnificence.
If I was making a personal account, I would use
one of those and maybe make it look like this.
Now, a nice camera will shoot at a high
resolution, and that means crisper images.
Now, "Why is that exactly?", you ask, considering that it's,
you know, it's going to be 180x180 pixels no matter what.
Well, a nice camera actually will easily triple the
pixels in the same space, so when you downsize it
or at least they downsize it on their servers,
their servers can pick the best pixels in the photo,
and that's actually why it ends up being sharper.
I know, if you shoot something in a low resolution,
it just doesn't have as much to work with.
You also want to make sure your photo doesn't
have a bunch of noise in the background.
Now, when I say noise, I mean basically things to look
at, visual noise. Seriously, have you seen how small
the thumbnails are on this thing,
especially in the comments?
You won't be able to see any of that and it'll actually
just make your image look like a smudge on the screen.
You could either show them one thing, your face, or
nothing. If you try to show them more than one thing,
they'll see nothing, because nothing is essentially what you
get when you have too much visual noise on the image.
Use a plain background photo,
and if you're really nice, I might show you how to use
Photoshop to remove your background manually.
It's brutal, but you can do it.
OK, and last up, if you are a themed account,
again, this is one of those accounts that just post photos
on a theme, and it only kind of adjacently supports
your business or your industry,
well, you kind of have the same options.
You can use a logo or just use the best photo you have
from what you think will be your content. If you're
a comedy account, well, you can get away with anything
really. You can get away with a lower resolution photo,
like fuckjerry over here, I think it was kind of
a play on, like, that design from the 1990s.
But if you're not a comedy account,
then really the same rules apply.
Keep it simple, and then keep it high resolution.
If you can make it blend well with the container line
or the background, well, extra points.
The only other tip I can give you is, since you have a more
wide open canvas to work with, make something colorful.
Seriously, color should never be underestimated.
Why?
It's because of your comment thumbnail.
You're going to get a lot of viewers that click through
your comments to your page, because that's a
big part of growing your account.
What stands out when you're
scrolling through 100 comments?
Well, something that's crisp and has colors in it.
Personally, I like deep reds, like Airbnb here.
Another example is Thought Bot. Red, for whatever
reason, kind of always stands out, especially against white
and gray, which is what the text and the background is.
Green works as well, but only if you use it as an
overwhelming color, or it's a shade that you don't always
see. Again, dark green actually
kind of blends in a little bit more.
All right guys, that is really it for now.
Remember, we shoot for a square image,
it's a 180 by 180 pixels, and you want either a simple
symbol logo as a brand, or a professional shot of your
face if you're a human person. Themed
accounts can really do whatever they want.
My suggestion though is to go for something that's
colorful and then matches your content. Next lecture, I'll
show you how you can put up your photo, what to
do if you have no editing tools or motivation in life,
and then, finally, if you do want to get professional design or professional photos done, what exactly are your options.
All right, guys. See you then.