Everybody welcome back.
OK.
So in the last couple of lectures we set up our P.S. one lecture we did it with Drene cloud and the
other one we did it with Amazon 80 of us which was the free one.
Now that we have our set up we create an account with Jarvi.
We've downloaded the software.
Now we're going to do is actually spend some time getting used to the user interface for Jarvi what
it looks like and what are the sections that we care about.
So get into your GPS assuming that you did it in the GPS unit just install it on your computer which
is a perfectly viable way of doing it and you should.
When you first open up Jarvi see just your dashboard.
Now I'm going to use the Jarvi instance that I've actually been using for the account just because there's
more to play with.
But your thing will look like it's pretty much empty now on the left hand side.
We have six different sections.
There's a dashboard social profiles tools Gobal tool settings proxy manager and my account.
Now you really are going to be using probably three of these.
There's other ones that you all set the settings for once and that's pretty much it.
So let's just take a tour of what it should look like now.
The dashboard is split up in the summary statistics what's new contact sport and notifications.
The summary is pretty much the only useful part of the dashboard.
This just shows you what's going on.
And I find it very useful to make sure that it's actually running because occasionally I've had a setting
wrong or whatever reason.
It's just not running.
Sometimes like my license might expire then I'll stop.
And so I like to check this to make sure that yes indeed stuff is moving so I can even check the time.
So to 6:37 a.m. to 23 is the time according to the server.
So I know it's actually running as we speak.
That's great.
Statistics is somewhat useful.
This will just tell you more or less like how many actions Jerry's going to be running.
How many follows it's done.
Unfollowed how many post it's made.
It's fine.
I'm perfectly fine using things like iconv Square just looking at the accounts just because it's faster
and you can use a VPN.
It's pretty laggy so I don't really find it super useful.
What's new is really tell you about updates.
They do update this quite a bit.
So if you are really going to get in the zombie strategy it's worth checking out and seeing what exactly
they've been fixing or changing because occasionally you'll have a button and it'll work totally different
one day and you have to go kind of fish the changes out of here and what's new now.
Contact support is right here.
Typically I just contact him with this Bakugan CommSec support.
They're actually pretty fast.
And each time you run into a problem like your accounts getting blocked they can actually look at it
and then tell you which is great.
Now social profiles is where you're going to set up all of your accounts.
And we might as well just add that account that we made before I think advanced technology today.
So in order to do that you go to add profile and then you want to do Instagram profile.
OK.
Now make sure that you give it a name that actually makes sense.
I always give mine just numbers so I know which.
So maybe we're talking about.
You could name it based off the name of the account.
But I found that that got really confusing really fast it's much easier to say number 27 is malfunctioning
or whatever.
I also like for instance to put in the username and password here into the description it just saves
me from having to go and finding it to find it later on especially if I'm sharing this with say like
a virtual assistant that actually helps quite a bit.
Now what you have to do here is click Show proxy settings and then you have to make sure that you enter
in your proxy because you don't enter in your proxy.
The first time this thing runs it's going to connect with the IP address of your virtual private server.
Now remember in the previous lectures we found the IP for our VPN is and it's usually pretty static
it doesn't change that often miners like 69 24 somethings I mean something which is fine for one account
but then if you keep forgetting to do this you'll have every single account first log in with an IP
address and then unscramble soci at that IP address with all of your accounts.
And that's bad.
So what we want to do is do our proxy IP or proxy username proxy password.
Now it depends how you set this up.
If we were doing the authentication through username and password which was one of the settings with
high proxies then we would just do this.
And then also make sure to put in the IP in the port.
But if you don't then you actually can just leave this blank.
OK so let's go grab that IP that we set up before they're going to is this one right here one it's going
to proxy it's in Chicago.
Here's the proxy IP.
Here's the port now.
Just copy and paste this.
Although it depends if I think on your Mac it doesn't actually let you copy paste it.
So a lot of times I just keep flipping back and forth to do it.
Once you get the IP in there the next thing to do is add in the port and the way they have it set up
it's kind of clunky but you just have to put a colon and then put the ports of Mines to 1 3 0 8.
So I put a colon to 1 3 0 8 and that is just the way that they like gathering this information so that
it's not working it's probably that you did the syntax slightly wrong.
So just make sure you check that first.
Now again thing is being authorized by the local IP address remember.
So I don't actually put a new user name and authentication so I can just do this right here.
So let's see now the next thing is entering the username and password for your account and this is the
Instagram account right.
Not your proxy account.
So we were advanced technology today type in your password.
And then what you want to do is hit varify account and it'll check to make sure that not only your proxy
works but also your user name and log in for Instagram ok.
If you got everything right it should stay valid.
Great browse button.
All that does is actually it opens up in a browser where you can log in and view the Instagram account
through this little miniature browser like this.
And this is useful for a lot of different things.
Sometimes you just kind of get disconnected from the system where you don't really know exactly what
you're doing and sometimes you can just log in and do it manually right here.
We'll use this a lot actually later on.
OK so now we have it all set up and go back to social profiles and we can see that Instagram account
there down here is set up now it has a number of post number of followers shows us the followers increases
is an incredibly important number because I want to make sure that's always going up.
As you can see these are all zeroes which actually just kind of a bug sometimes it just I don't know.
Jeremy's not like a perfectly polished product but is something I like to check quite a bit.
And then you can see the total number of fall the wings engagement and et cetera et cetera.
Now the next section is the tool section and this is really the most important thing we have.
OK.
So what it does is it lists all your accounts and then it has columns for all of the different things
that it could be doing.
So it could be auto liking can be auto commenting can be auto falling auto following.
It could be read saying direct messaging.
It could be automatically deleting your posts so or Sarah like for instance liking on comments and also
things like story viewers so we'll talk about each one of these.
So if you want to just get into your new account to double click on it.
OK so you see a section like this.
And now here's where we set all of the settings for different things that we wanted to do.
So we have to follow the follow back and follow the like the comment contact direct MR's manage comments
tweet post comments.
You get the point.
You can do a lot of different things.
Now what you do in these setting pages pretty much is the difference in success and not being successful.
Typically what you would want to do is at first you start with followings and unfollow things.
OK.
And then as you establish some credibility with your account it's not a brand new account anymore.
Then you can start adding on more things like likes some people and comments.
I personally hate it because it's just not good engagement.
If you've seen on innovation station we have a lot of commenters who post something and it makes no
sense.
It's not relevant it's not in context to the post that's generally people using bots for comments because
it always just says something really generic like a hard or a thumbs up so I usually just say just don't
do it.
Contacting is a setting you can give it so that it automatically goes out and finds new accounts and
messages them not necessarily people who follow you.
It just goes and finds new accounts.
Now keep in mind when you contact an account they don't follow you you don't follow them it often ends
up in that secondary folder on Instagram where you know you go to your messages you see your messages
and it says other than a parentheses and says how many messages you have.
That's where those messages usually end up.
So a lot of people even look at those I generally ignore those now direct messages a little bit different
that's for sending direct messages to people that you follow or they follow you in which case it usually
shows up in that direct messages section and not the other section of direct messages.
Now the other settings are kind of optional Noojee things I don't do until much later like deleting
posts.
I don't usually delete posts.
If you have a curation strategy that you really want to make sure you only you are constantly deleting
and then reposting and deleting that something a can be useful deleting comments that's not terribly
useful once you find out that you're getting a lot of like negative comments blocking follower is not
usually useful reposte end users and hashtags however are things that are pretty useful.
Now I use the repo's tool to repost from my main account and that's where I put all my settings.
That's pretty much the heart of this so users and hash tags has a section where you can tell Jarvi to
automatically generate hash tags and then automatically append them to your post.
It is actually pretty cool.
They can add hash tags to your comments and not the caption.
If you want to which is something that we always suggest because adding them to your captains usually
looks bad unless you're only using a couple.
This is something we will explore and then it's coming lectures and then liking comments.
This is just an automatic system for liking the people who comment on your post.
It's pretty straight forward.
Generally speaking this is a good thing because Instagram likes to see accounts that engage with people
who comment.
So something to keep in mind.
Save posts and story viewer.
These are two different settings for if you want to have your account randomly move around and do things
that bots don't usually do like bots don't usually go around and save posts.
They also don't usually go around and watch stories because why would they write it's just a computer
doing this.
But we use these just to make your accounts look more authentic.
So it is something that I toyed around with we don't really know 100 percent whether or not this makes
your life easier.
But I would imagine it makes your account harder to distinguish from accounts that are obviously bots.
So something to consider.
OK now there's a lot to do here and we'll do a entire lecture focusing on that but we'll just want to
move through and view what the rest of the software looks like so good global tools.
Now Google tools is a section where you can just do a lot of manual tasks or set up tools that apply
to every thing there.
For instance like if you have story viewing set up you'll have a section here that shows the stories
in real time that you're watching.
Here's your direct messages.
This can be pretty useful if you want to actually go and look at all the messages that people are sending
you or that you're sending without actually having to log in to every single one.
This could be crazy if you had 300 zombie accounts.
So this action is called creating accounts and this is exactly what it sounds like.
You can actually create accounts for you.
So if you have a system for creating a profile picture and getting a name and having a bio and everything
like that you can actually have them do it for you.
No.
Typically the way you do it is by importing like image files that it can randomly grab for its pictures.
It's not something that I'm really going to sporks this is I would consider way way more advanced than
you guys need to know.
If I were really going crazy with my zombies and I wanted to have thousands of them this would be crucial
but for me it's not OK now managing comments well this is again just a viewer.
I can see all the comments I get for all the different zombies that I have and I could potentially you
know click on some of them view them and even respond to them see like this is a comment on one of my
posts actually from my account but I could respond to it.
You have that kind of fish out the ones that are actual responses.
And it kind of just depends of your zombies doing well.
Now here's engagement groups.
Here's another section that you can explore on your own.
It's not something we cover in the course.
I don't particularly find it super useful.
Why.
Because Jarvi has a section called like exchanges now which acts as an engagement group but I think
it works way better.
Next up the settings.
These aren't early.
I don't really touch anything in here.
This is something that if you get really advanced you can check out some of the things that they have
here.
Honestly you don't really need to dive into this if you don't want to.
You can put some settings for your embedded browser.
Notice that was the browse button that we hit before so we could actually go and use it like a normal
person.
Then they have some other settings that don't actually apply to us like social platforms you do a lot
of settings for Facebook and Twitter and stuff like that.
So if you're doing a cross-platform strategy makes sense to try this.
But for the most part you're not going to touch this now proxy manager right here is a bird's eye view
of all the proxies that you're using now.
This is kind of the page you'll use if something goes wrong in one of your proxies.
You'll figure it out here very quickly.
You can also do things like selecting all of these and then verifying all the proxies that'll do is
just ping all of the settings you have to see which ones are working or might not be working.
You can also use this to manage your proxies so that for instance you could have it so that three or
four or five accounts share one proxy or even have them rotate.
That's something that you thought was useful.
So yeah I mean I only have 30 zombies or so.
So this isn't particularly useful on my account.
Nothing really happens here except for upgrading your plan like friends and I'm in a professional plan.
It's 50 bucks a month.
That's because I have 30 accounts.
So it allows me to go up to 70 for that.
Now if I only want to do 10 accounts I'd be fine doing 20 bucks a month isn't per se works for me.
And then if you have more than 150 which a lot of people do you have to actually contact them and set
something up with them.
OK.
Now this next section is called campaigns and destination lists and the way that this works is that
you can set up what are called independent campaigns and these are particularly useful if you for instance
want to narrow in on someone else's account and repost lots of their postings.
But then you want to do it too.
Not just one zombie but maybe 10 different ones so you could do is you could create a campaign have
that campaign only target one account grab their information and then send it to your accounts.
I don't actually use campaigns just because with the repo's tool and all of the tools tools that we
explored before I pretty much get everything I need I can just do it there.
But if I was re posting specifically from a list of different accounts this is actually where I would
do it and I'd set it up here.
A lot of people do spend a lot of time here in the campaigns and they might set up different ones depending
on whatever.
I mean they might make one every month that focus on different accounts just to mix it up.
Destination list is where you set up your zombie's for accepting campaign.
So let's say I set up a campaign and I have it such that it scrapes all of them from business insider
their account.
OK well then I'd have to set up a destination list for every single zombie.
And then when I'm campaigns automatically be able to check the destinations which are either individual
zombies or groups of them.
And then I can set it up that way.
OK hopefully this isn't too overwhelming.
Honestly the first time you get into Jarvi it is overwhelming.
It's also very slow.
So you do kind of feel like you don't want to click on the next section because you don't even know
if it's going to load or what.
But as as you get more and more familiar with this as you start setting up the settings for some of
your zombies it starts to get a little bit easier.
There's still a lot of features I don't use but that's also because I'm not trying to build hundreds
and hundreds and hundreds of zombies if I were suddenly something that I would want to look into.
OK.
Next lecture will start getting into the individual settings.
When you set up your first zombie.
OK so you then.