Hey guys, welcome back.
OK.
So this lecture we're going to cover
how do you use other people's videos in your own videos.
It's actually pretty useful to understand how you can
get other clips out there to make your own videos.
I know a lot of you are probably going to
be using other people's clips exclusively.
That's perfectly fine.
I mean, that's what we're going to be doing at Innovation
Station, we're not going to be shooting any of our own video.
We're going to be using clips from all over the
internet. So we covered a long time back
how to use free stock images on Instagram.
Same thing kind of applies.
There's a lot of free stock video
platforms, so that's something
also, just go and look at that. The same websites
I showed you, Pixabay, Pexels, Allthefreestock,
they work the exact same way for videos,
you just click a button and you go to Video.
Now, if you want to use the video of someone else on
Instagram, and this is something you will absolutely
have to do at some point, especially if you're going
to be using any of the shout for shout advertising
and marketing strategies that we talk about later,
you will have to figure out how to do this.
So if you're on iOS, the best way that I've found how to do it -
and again, there's a lot of different ways to do this -
is to use an app called IGSaver.
If this is not in the App Store when you
go and look for it, it doesn't really matter.
There's tons of them, there's Instagrab, InstaSave, IGSave,
IGSaver. This is the one that just worked for me.
It's hideous.
It's really annoying, but it works every single time.
That's really all we care about.
So if you want to try this one out, that's perfectly fine.
Otherwise, there's plenty of other ones.
When you open it up, it just takes you to this home
screen, which is essentially photos from the people
you're following in your feed,
plus the ones that you've posted. What you can do is
just go down here to Search, and then you can search
for whatever the account is that you want the video from.
So let's say Gary Vee.
Let's say we are taking a video from him. So click that,
go to his actual account, not his 200 other ones.
Then you figure out which video you wanted
for whatever reason, you click that, okay.
So there's his video.
It makes you look at an ad.
It's super annoying, but it's free.
And then you can watch it to figure out
this is the one that you want.
Do we want this? Do we want this?
Yeah, sure.
And then what you do is just hit Save to gallery. It has other
functions on it, but those other functions, like reposting
and changing captions, and stuff like that,
I would rather use those on other apps that are just better.
This is just perfectly fine for saving to your gallery.
So now that I've done that, I just go
to my photos, and it's right there.
OK.
So now I can use this for whatever purposes, I can throw
it back into any of the video editing apps, I can transfer
it to my computer, or I can just directly
upload this if I wanted to, whatever.
All right.
Now let's look at the Android version. Now, on Android,
God bless the marketplace,
it's the same situation you have everywhere else.
Tons and tons and tons of apps that do it.
They're all much lower quality, it seems like more
often you run into bad ones on the Google Play store,
but I found several that worked. So Save & Repost
works, Inst Download and Instant Save are the ones
that I've used that worked.
They're relatively straightforward.
I mean, you have to do them a little bit different on
Android, but I'll show you for instance with Instant Save.
This is the way that you would do it.
So you go there.
No photos yet.
So the way it works is you go to Instagram,
you go find the video you want, and then you click
on the three dots and click copy link, and then
it'll automatically work. So I'll show you how to do it.
So you can just hit Go to Instagram, now it opens up your
Instagram, puts you in there, and then you can just find
the photo you want. So we can go back to Gary Vee
and we can pick a video.
So how about this one? Cool.
OK.
So then what you want to do is up here, top
three buttons, like I was saying, hit Copy link,
and then just flip back to Instant Save,
and there you go.
So it automatically detects that you've done it, and
you have it right there, and then if you want to
share it, you can hit the Share button,
if you want to trash it, trash it.
In my experience, you have to do this sometimes
a couple of times to make it actually save,
but such is the way with Android.
So when you go to your photos, you have camera and
whatever, and then it's right here, usually has its
own folder, and that's where you can get access to these videos.
OK, so that's how you do it on Android.
Now, let me show you how you would do it
on the computer from say, like, YouTube.
YouTube honestly is a giant goldmine of videos.
I mean, you can find videos on anything out there.
So I think it's incredibly useful.
But you will notice that YouTube video quality just
varies wildly, so sometimes you get high res, beautiful
stuff, and other times you get stuff that was shot on
like a really old camera and it's just low resolution.
So you have to be kind of picky with that.
The tool I use is called Clip Grab and you go to
clipgrab.org, it works for both Mac and PC,
it just depends on which computer
you're on, that's what it'll show you.
So you download it, and once you actually install it,
I'll show you what it looks like.
So it looks like this and it's fairly simple. So there's two
different ways that you can find videos. One, you can search
through their system, and it's the same rough search
as if you search through YouTube, or you can go
directly to Download and just copy
the link of the video that you want.
So let's say we found a YouTube video.
What do we want?
Okay, let's say boomerang tricks, this one. Sure, why not?
OK.
I could take this link up here and go over to Clip
Grab, and there you go, it automatically copied it.
But if it didn't for some reason, I could just copy and paste it.
OK.
And then it pulls up the title of it.
If that's what you want, good.
You can play around with the quality if you want.
Sometimes it will just tell you straight up
you don't have HD available for this, only 480,
but whatever. You can change the format
if for some reason you care about that.
But otherwise, I just hit Grab this clip
and pick where I want to save it.
OK.
I'll let that download and then I'll
show you it in here in a second.
Otherwise, you can just do search.
So if I did the same thing, it would probably just
show up like that, if I said "boomerang trick."
OK.
So then I could click that and then it
automatically populates it for me.
Great.
Now, while this is downloading,
I will tell you that YouTube is kind of a
minefield when it comes to copyright.
Earlier we talked about Creative Commons
with regards to photos, but with YouTube,
that's quite a bit harder to find.
It's harder to tell if they're Creative Commons or what.
So typically, my advice is that you
should find a clip that you want, okay,
and if it's not watermarked, doesn't have
a logo in the corner, you can use it,
and then in your post
generally what I like to see is you say, you know,
"Contact me for copyright" somewhere in your
caption, or "DM for copyright," something like that.
So if the person who made this finds out that you
have it and they actually care, then they can tell you
that and you can take it down, because a lot of
times, people find that you used it and they don't care.
They're perfectly fine, they wanted it to
get shared out there. At the minimum,
sometimes they'll ask just for attribution, so all you have
to do is say at the bottom where you got the clip from,
and that's usually it. Very rarely you have
someone come and say "No, you can't use it."
That usually only happens when you take videos from,
say, like, big companies or companies that spend a
lot of money on their production.
So that's kind of a minefield. Otherwise, I think
it's just impossible to only work with things that
are in Creative Commons, because 90% of the videos
out there are just a big question mark, and I don't
think the content creators think that much about it.
OK, now that it's done, you can just go to Show
in Finder or Open downloaded file - of course, this
is different if you are on a PC or a Mac, but
it's virtually the same, so there we go.
You open it and we have the video.
Now we can do whatever we want with it. Cool.
OK.
So those are ways of getting videos to use in your posts.
It depends if you're on iOS or Android.
There's just 101 apps for saving things.
Those are the ones I showed you that for me at least
are the least obnoxious and work consistently.
And then if you want to grab them off YouTube,
I use Clip Grab and I think that works pretty well.
Other than that, pay attention to copyright.
If you can, try to be careful, give attribution if
you're open to it, and make sure that there's at
least an avenue for them to contact
you if they care about the copyright.
So, with that being said, see you guys in the next lecture.