Hey guys checking in.
We are now at 40000 followers.
So that is a bit of a milestone of sorts because Shoot-In for fifty thousand point I will get my foot
off the gas and stop caring about this.
But so far since we last checked in really not much has happened.
Honestly I've really put this on autopilot.
I'm not really doing anything other than trolling people in the comments just getting them to respond
more then that's really it.
I mean we've started recycling most of our posts.
You can see right here.
I think we have a pretty weak list of innovations we've found.
And for the most part our really just digging out of the post we've had before.
You see over here these are some ones we flagged that were high performing.
I think what I'll do in the future is start flagging not only the high performing ones but the ones
that people repeatedly ask about buying.
So like for instance the foil Yeah it's this thing that it's like a surfboard that holds you up over
the water and people are pretty excited about it.
And I think the price wise it's something that we could probably sell.
So I think when we get to the point where we're going to start monetizing this account this might be
one of the things we explore.
We start focusing more on these low to medium priced items that seem to get a lot of attention.
And we already established that people are interested in them.
So it's really a matter of putting a link like an affiliate link to buy this whenever we post it or
trying to do an image post and have them shop through the image.
I'm not really sure.
It's a little bit hard to do this with the video so I'm honestly kind of just waiting for Instagram
to come out with some way to sell from videos which should be happening any day now.
Seems like they're kind of missing an opportunity with that.
But again they're you know shop on instruments something they've only relatively recently rolled out.
So check out our stats as we're doing right now.
You know for the most part nothing really much has changed.
Pretty steady growth.
If you look at our data days notice that snowballing effect that I mentioned a lot it's really gotten
to a point where it's just hard to have days below 200.
You know I think the last one I had was like two weeks ago and there's a couple right there but they're
just getting more less and less frequent.
It seems that without doing anything we are getting up in the 300.
So what I've noticed is more often when I'm posting they'll notice when it says views.
How many people will view it and there's a huge disparity between the average post.
We do so like this one for instance I can't remember it says eight thousand views because it's not so
bad but this seventy seven thousand and didn't do anything to this post at all I just a lot of people
talking about it.
I posted this probably three or four times now.
But yeah there's just a lot of those that seemed to do really well like these are ok.
Blah.
Ok this one did a lot better.
This one for some reason just got a lot of people talking about it is basically people saying it's their
autonomous cargo ships and it's just people saying like I'm just going to rob them or whatever which
might be a valid point.
But really it's not that original.
Yeah I mean the image posts for the most part are doing as poorly as ever and never really a big part
of the account strategy.
It's just kind of a way to flex with the limited content so that we could have extra things to post.
And also just kind of gives it the stripe which I think is still pretty memorable We might even switch
honestly to just doing videos and are really now doing it.
Like for instance tech with tech junction is one of them.
So there's a cow.
This is kind of the way that if I wanted to go as low as possible I could grow a lot faster and just
do what these people do.
This guy basically has like five of these accounts.
They all point at each other.
They all just share the same exact stuff and it's all just click baiting nonsense.
Most of these are actually not even real.
They are usually things that rely on video special effects to make it look like it's real like he post
a lot of these things that just have been debunked and they're not real like this.
OK.
You know that doesn't work.
They kind of stuck with the really click Baty stuff that is mostly fake or is just designed for the
lowest common denominator.
Yeah I could probably grow a lot faster but I'm trying to keep the brand at least above water.
I think the idea is later on we start doing shout outs or selling shout outs or selling features.
People aren't going to want to be featured on one of these accounts that just posts the absolute garbage
of the garbage that just gets attention.
All those things are worth pointing out.
We have a week or so gotten three or four people asking features I'm still in that phase where it's
the Kenelm's getting large enough that it's getting attention and people want to be featured but it's
to the point where I'm not sure that what I can charge is worth it.
You know I've had one person say yes for $150 and then it was just a matter of trying to still trying
to figure it out.
I have had a couple other companies ask seems to be pretty popular with Kickstarter.
So if you're going to do a technology Kickstarter they always seem to you know hassle me about getting
a post for their kickstarter.
Really just depends on what it was.
You know I think we had one today that was a modular desk.
OK.
I don't know I mean novel ish I don't know if I could really do much with that.
All right.
So anyway I think I've said this over and over again but I'm not going to do much on this account.
It's going to continue to grow.
We'll continue to do.
Shout for shout.
I think we did two or three this week.
They were pretty easy.
They are all from the automated outreach that I've been doing we still have an excel sheet going or
just kind of marking them out as we go down and you know for the most part it ends up working maybe
20 percent of the accounts so a message.
So that's promising but you know again we're at 40000 So a shout for shower isn't as valuable as it's
going to be in or at 200000 or something more significant.
All right guys so with that being said if something new changes I will check in soon.
But otherwise I'll see you guys at 50 K.
All right.
See you then.