Hey everybody welcome back.
So I'm going to check in again now that we're at 45000 followers and give you an update on where we're
at what seems to be making the account grow and then giving you an update on a pretty big change we've
switched from manual posting to probably say like 95 percent automated posting.
OK so here's the account we're at forty five point six thousand looks decently good.
We'll look at our iconic square to look at the day rates.
OK so in a kind of square you can kind of see that for the last week.
Our growth has slowed quite a bit.
We 70 29 88 89 215 and then that those two zeros are just because I Kano's who are constantly keeps
re authenticating and when it riata indicates it forgets what it had before so it will say zero.
Like for instance one day told me that I lost $45000 that obviously that wasn't the case.
But you can see that last week we actually had a pretty good tear are going to 84.
159 1 2 3 1 2 4 2 6 183.
I mean for me anything over 150 I think is a solid growth rate especially considering that I'm not creating
the lowest common denominator account.
I'm not just posting viral videos that are all fake and clearly just designed for people to share without
even watching the video I'm actually trying to do something that's a little better so I'm perfectly
fine accepting a lower growth rate.
But anyway so the shift downward towards the 60s towards these like sub hundred that had to do with
our automation and all explain that here in a bit.
We were really turning to testing things out as are switching from manual to automated.
And so at first it wasn't working out so Karaite.
But for the most part what I've noticed with our growth is that it's really hash tag or explore page
or die.
Right.
So if you look at our posts they are either viewed by 2000 to 4000 people or the hash tag pages which
will bring them to 40000 50000 people and in some cases they'll have the explore page which will bring
them to 100000 people almost pretty much all of our growth comes from those hashtags and explore page
hits whereas the other ones are just kind of duds and that's perfectly fine because I just really started
reposting all of the old stuff that we started at the very beginning and the accounts were cycling through
and already know that something is a kind of duds like they didn't do well the first time I don't know
why they do well the second time but I'm not trying to do just the best hit strategy like I was doing
earlier but a month ago I just it's not really sustainable if you don't have that much content.
Later on I think we'll switch to doing better posts only.
It's just a balance right.
We post everything that we can post for four months without people seeing the same content but if we
switch to like the best only or as say like the top core tile then you know we only last a month so
it just depends on how long people's memories are.
So OK I'll show you kind of examples like let's see ok so like this stretchy battery.
Right.
I think it's interesting but I only got 4000 views so if you look at how many followers came from it
literally zero.
All right only 12 people click through and you can see Instagram's diagram didn't like this post because
I only got 4 percent viewing from people who weren't already following me.
But we look at let's say a different one.
So here I don't know why this one was more popular.
It's like a farm in a box kind of thing as you can see more people were commenting on it.
Most people just love the idea or hate the idea.
I mean that's pretty much the divide in our comments and then for the most part I just kind of stimulate
discussion by trolling people to view insights.
So 419 people came from that and you can see 87 percent weren't following me.
So I got $171 just from that post.
Now if you look at the breakdown now it hit the Explorer page.
So that's where Tony 2000 came it might have been a local explore page where it didn't show to a ton
of people but people who'd already shown an interest in technology or innovation got it shown from other.
That is a hard number to figure out.
It's like a breakdown of how many people share it through direct message.
It's just kind of odd where those come from it's just every everything else.
So what ends up happening is a lot of our views are from people deeming it to other people.
So that is a portion of where that's coming from.
But some of it I still am not entirely sure and I don't think Instagram even knows because they're not
even willing to share where that came from.
So let's see.
Let's look at this.
Bjorn.
Remember this was C. 2000 views.
OK so this is just a dud again toll profile visits no one followed.
Then this whatever this hotel that was completely green and it gives energy back to the grid got us
160.
Right.
And if we look at it again this one had the explore page a little bit more 74000 users from the explore
page.
Cool.
There was one that really just blew up this one for whatever reason it's just this thing that floats
in the water and it uses tidal changes to generate electricity.
I don't know why it's so popular but we got almost $400 from it 150 3000.
So it really just hit the explore page.
You'll notice 21000 from other.
And that's again like people sharing it.
And again I don't even know but it really hit the explore page and just did well from there.
So that's really where we got the distribution on that one.
And if you notice any of them any comments is only 18 comments so a lot of students are messaging me
which is kind of funny that we have students now following the count.
But one of the questions is Why do you have so few comments versus how big your account is.
And honestly I don't know.
I mean it's kind of the way that this works.
It's kind of passive and we haven't really figured out an optimized strategy for getting comments.
Sue we do get comments but it's like a bad post.
We're going to get four or five a good one might get up to 30 or 40 but it just that's not really what's
getting us or distribution.
So that's something we kind of optimize in the future.
But the moment seems like the hash tag pages the Explore pages are doing plenty.
Here's another one that did pretty well.
This again I think it did well because people hated it.
It's a clip you put on your body and it tells you when you're bending over incorrectly and it helps
you prevent injury so virtually all the questions were like I know how to bend over.
That's not a problem.
And whatever.
That's fine if people don't like it they're going to comment and that still pushes it up the algorithm
so I'm perfectly happy to facilitate that rage.
Again this one for whatever reason it's from other which I think in the Q&amp;A section I'll do a little
bit more of a deep dive into what other is but for the most part with the newest Instagram it's kind
of a mystery.
This one for whatever reason it's literally conquered it's just mud.
And for some reason it did really well.
Got a $136 from it.
But then you just noticed it's really just hot or cold or hot or cold.
This one again.
Nothing like 32 you got one follower from that.
OK.
So that's pretty much where we're at.
It's hash tag page or explore page or die and it really it ends up being pretty consistent.
I know that on any given day one of these will hit and that's going to get most of our follows from.
OK now let's switch over to look at the Jarvi setup we have for automation.
Right.
So we will jump into the yes.
All right so the basic idea was that you know before we had someone who was manually posting all war
posts every single day and they're in us time zones.
That's where my audience is and I wanted to get off of that because that was expensive and that was
the goal all along.
So now what we've done is we use Jarvi and we use the campaign section where we've been doing is using
a combination of there scraping tools to just scrape our posts and then also I just had a virtual assistant
load them all up and then we just set them up in the post section.
So let's look at here we go active and then you can look over here and the post lists.
So we have everything listed out here.
You load them up.
Sorry juries really slow you load them up here in the drafts and you'll load the comments along with
it and then essentially it ends up happening is we just click them and send them to the post list and
then change the order.
So the first issue that I was really struggling with was the reason why I didn't automate it any time
sooner was how do I preserve the two videos one image post system because if that breaks down then the
whole aesthetic of using the quotes kind of goes away.
And that was a concern.
So the way we manage it is just by doing it here like we just will set the number.
And you'll notice.
You can just do it manually.
So zeros the first one want the next two is the maximum three.
So it just posts automatically in that order.
Then all we do is when to publish and you just set it up here.
So right now I think it's only for posting a day and we're still kind of tweaking things but we haven't
during the set times and then these were just times that we had noticed that we get a decent amount
of interaction during this needs to be optimized so I don't think 8 a.m. is the ideal point to post
this.
You also get to keep in mind that it's based on the time of year.
So this is 144 which is west coast time.
All right so we just had to set it up that way.
Realistically probably push this one an hour forward but with Icona square I can go there and look at
the reach and look at the gauge and see what are the best times and by doing that I can come back here
and tweak it and ideally see a little bit more reach and engagement.
So here is pretty straightforward.
We'll bump it up to 5 to get back to where we were originally.
But right now we're kind of keeping it low where to publish.
You just set up a destination or just set it up as an evasion station really simple just one wall.
Okay let's look back over at the draft.
No.
The other issue that comes with automation is do you guys remember my posting pattern it was that I'd
post a caption and then the hash tags and then three comments or two comments of a Moji to hide it.
OK well we can do that.
But it's hard to automate the emoji and have them non-generic.
So that was kind of an issue and really the only way we solved it was just by when we added all of these
into the drafts.
We just went and manually put it in and put in him.
From what they were before and the way that you do the comments is by using their spend tax settings.
So this year it says the little brackets and it says comment.
So it's just called a token.
So if you add tokens you can do Khama and the way it treats the information is that anything after this
token will go in the comments.
So you can set it up so they can do multiple comments.
Again it's just you have to spend a lot of time tweaking this.
We also added the locations and that was unfortunately just a manual.
And if you go to Instagram advanced options you can add locations for each one.
Again it's frustrating to put all of this stuff in at once but once it's in there it's pretty much done.
It's just going to run and all you have to do is check in to make sure it post correctly.
So yeah I mean that's pretty much the basic setting we have we have nothing to take care of stories
right now.
So Jervy has a setting that when it publishes a post you can set it so it says also post this as a story
that would be perfect.
But when it does that it kind of comes out funky.
It ends up publishing it all wonky with like bars at the top and bottom.
And it's not ideal.
So we're still trying to figure out the best way to do stories.
The good thing is that stories are incredibly easy to do since Instagram has that share feature for
stories.
So really all I have to do is just take each post at the end of the day and just click share on each
one and it creates that little preview box.
And I put a hash argument to it and I don't even do that again.
The virtual assistant does that and it takes her 10 minutes a day it's really nothing.
So if you look at our history or here we can see what's been posted.
We can very easily set this up so we automatically send new history posts to bomp or over here.
Riadh publish posts into the post list.
What we could do is if we just added every single post we ever had all we'd have to do is just check
that box and then it would automatically cycle so I wouldn't have to check in three months later and
reload them again so I can just hit that and I'll just automatically do it.
Now I'm not going to do that just because ideally I'd like to have a little bit more control over what
gets posted if something sucks than I'd prefer to just remove it and further down the line try to optimize
our post schedule.
So even over here we can see create a report and you know for the most part.
Works pretty straightforward.
All right so that's what we're at.
It's our automation strategy is working.
It did take a hit at first with followers.
Why.
It's been a little inconsistent especially in your getting the settings right.
One thing we are running into is that since Jarvis is doing all of the posting and doesn't really like
that because it acts like a bot.
So when it's Graham thinks it's a bot and keeps walking you out and occasionally unscrambled even grabs
some of the posts we make for some reason it's always the image post and then remove them and screws
up our design and so we kind of had to keep going back and figuring out and figuring out the solution.
For now was actually to go to Jarvi and change or follow bought settings because our follow bot was
bringing in followers and it's a good thing to have that we had it maxed out.
So I had it so that it was falling like 300 people a day or something.
And I think that was just kind of pissing off Instagram.
It just looks very odd to be doing that.
And then also having a bot post everything for you.
So I kind of went here and just tinkered with this such that it would only do about 67 follows per day
and then once we get out of the woods where we're not having a lot of issues with Instagram taking our
post then I'll start cranking this back up.
It might also be a case of it's not really worth getting this back up to 300 again.
How many conversions we get you know out of 67 and only gives me probably 10 followers a day at that
300 is only going to mean maybe 30.
So it's just something that you kind of have to balance.
All right guys that's where we're at.
I'd say right now it's pretty much like 95 percent automation.
It's just me checking in to see what is going on.
I still comment on the post just because I think it's kind of funny but also it really does help with
engagement especially if you see a post doing well.
You can see the and the reviews like so if we posted two hours later it's already at say like six thousand
a reach.
Then I'll start commenting in there and even posting unsolicited comments for me that just kind of helps
it push it along and ideally you know if you get enough people participating you can have the explore
page and that's how you then get those posts to do really well.
All right cool.
So that's where we're at.
I'll check in again probably around 50000 and hopefully at that point the automation system will be
100 percent going.
And this is something that I'm not going to spend really any time on.
Once it's set up the idea is just it's you know it's ready to go.
And I don't have to touch anything.
I'm obviously not doing literally I mean anything besides playing with comments and checking the posts.
But still you know any work is more work than I have to.
So that's what I'm shooting for.
All right guys.
See you in the next checkup.