Hey guys, welcome back.
All right, so in this lecture I'm going to put together
all of the different pieces that we went over
in this section for the follow along account Innovation Station.
So that includes the profile photo, which
I talked to you about how I did that, with
99designs, the name, we already talked about, you know,
I used SquadHelp plus reaching out to people,
the account name, we'll do the bio, the
call to action, and then we'll set up the link.
OK.
So let's do that.
First up, the profile photo.
So let's just get started.
All right, so I logged into my account. What I'm going
to do is I'm going to take the photos that I got from
the competition, and I just uploaded them to Dropbox.
The way you want to get files and videos to your
account, because you can't do a whole lot in the web
version of Instagram, is just to use some type of
cloud service like Google Drive,
Dropbox, One Drive, Amazon Drive.
That's pretty much the only way you can do it.
Like I said before, and we'll run into this later on,
if I wanted to transfer a video, or transfer a photo,
get it into the Instagram app, you've got
to do it through some kind of service,
especially if you're making the images on the
computer. So I am using Dropbox, and I put two of
my logos here, I don't necessarily know which
color scheme I'm going to go with immediately,
I might change them up later.
Let's say we started with this one. On iOS, you just tap it,
and hit Save to Camera Roll, and it exports and it
saves it, on Android it's slightly different.
I think it's just save,
and if it's not save, you hit the three dots
and put export, it's the same thing.
OK.
So then what you would do is you go to your
Instagram account and then click on Edit
Profile, remember, you don't click
on the actual profile image itself,
that takes you to the stories thing. Then what it'll
do is it'll ask you to readjust it by pinching
with your fingers. Alright,
so that's good enough, I'll screw
with that more later to get it perfect.
And hit done, there you go.
Now we have a profile picture.
OK.
Now, moving on to the account name.
This is what I did.
I just used an app for scribbling down notes, it's called
Bear, and I just wrote out a bunch of variations.
So with the account name,
this is a themed account, so what do we care about? We care about immediately explaining what the account does or delivers.
We also want to make sure that we
get some keywords in there.
So these are the options I had.
The best innovations every day,
the most inspiring innovations every day, life-changing
innovations every day, we post the best innovations
every day, daily innovations for inspiration, inspiring
innovations every day, daily innovation inspiration.
OK, the reason why I used these was the keywords
I wanted were innovation and inspiration.
Inspiration is a really big key word.
Innovation is a decently strong keyword.
I might change this later on.
I don't know.
This is what I think will work now.
I also really wanted to emphasize that I post every single
day, so that's why I said every day, every day, every day.
I realize it's two words, but sometimes, you know,
you have a 30 character limit, so sometimes you have
to work with what you got.
I tried to use some adjectives or describers that
were a little bit out there, like life-changing, that
could work, but really I think what I'm going to land
on is this one right here, daily innovation inspiration.
Daily is the most succinct way of
saying we post every single day,
innovation inspiration has that rhyme and that
alliteration that I like, it also just looks cleaner than
this, it seems kind of weird sometimes
putting a sentence in your account name.
OK, so Daily innovation inspiration, will load that up,
so I will put that in. Alright, now you can look and see
how it looks. It looks fine for now.
And now we move on to the bio.
OK.
So the bio is 150 characters. What do we care about? We
need to do a two sentence technique or a list technique.
I decided on the list just because I think it's easier to use,
I think it makes your account look a little more professional,
And also I just don't really know how
to sum this up in two sentences.
So what I did is I wrote out several
sentences that I think I could fit in.
So, curated list of only the best in tech and innovation,
don't fall behind, world changing trends,
monthly tech giveaways, DM for business inquiries,
and then, you've never seen this before.
So what I did is I just thought about what were things
I wanted to convey to people about the account,
I needed to make sure that I justified
why they should follow me.
Ok, so I said curated list of only the best in tech.
There's a lot of accounts that do tech
and gadgets, but they just post anything.
So I wanted to make sure that this was the most curated,
because I am going to be posting things are a little
bit weirder that you wouldn't necessarily find on Instagram.
Then I tried to justify why you might be following this,
so I said, don't fall behind, world changing trends.
That makes sense to me.
Like, I'm trying to go for the business community, so
why would you follow an account that talks about
weird stuff that's being invented?
I'm guessing that it's because you like to follow trends.
It's about being competitive.
Then I put monthly tech giveaways.
That's something I might do.
We'll cover that later in this course, it's actually way at the end, where we get into giveaways, and promotions, and sweepstakes.
I think that's worth doing, at least putting it up there now,
but you could totally put in whatever you want.
Here's another option, DM for business inquiries.
Later on, we'll talk about growing the account, and that
is something that can be extremely useful, getting
people to message you and then figuring out co-
promotional opportunities. Then the last one is like,
you've never seen these before, because
I'm trying to differentiate myself.
So maybe these are things that
are secret, or weird, or different.
What I ended up settling on
was just these three, so 150 characters really only give
you three short sentences, and this might actually
take some fitting in when I actually get to posting it in.
But before we post that in, we need to decide
on our call to action, because that goes in the bio,
like we talked about before. Here's some call to actions
I came up with, so I came up with two options. One was
I could promote my idea generation course, I think
that complements it decently well, and the other
one was I could actually promote one of the companies that
I'm using as a source, they're a database for innovations,
they're kind of expensive, but I think I could promote them
and set up some kind of an affiliate relationship potentially.
So I set up call to actions that work for either one of those.
So, come up with a new business idea in one day, it's easy.
Need a business idea? It's easy. $10 for business coaching? It's real. 97% off award winning course on innovation, 33k students.
Those are just things I think could be interesting to
highlight. Some of these like, need a business idea,
$10 for business coaching, these are rhetorical questions.
So you read it, and if your answer is no, and you keep
on reading, and if your answer is yes, then I got you.
You're the person I want to talk to.
I also want to appeal to the short attention spans
on Instagram by saying you can do it and it's easy.
So if you're someone who is looking at my account
because you're trying to start a business, you're trying
to come up with new ideas,
then I can convince you that it's actually pretty easy,
that piques interest a little bit, like, it shouldn't be easy.
Is it easy?
And this also is another one.
You know, we have to be tangible about what we're
trying to give them, so I was trying to fit in things like
do it in one day, or here's tangible, like, $10 bucks,
that's really cheap, or another tangible, 97% off.
Those are kind of the highlights to get people to click through
and this was just credibility or award winning. Again,
I won some random awards. And then down
here were the ones I was thinking for
the company called Springwise, and these I just
pulled off their website, because they have 8,900
innovations, so I just came up with something
like these. Potentially, I could say it's a database
of 8,900, the world's never seen them, so
appealing to their competitive sense, or
maybe I can get a percentage off, which I doubt,
because I actually know this company, or just focus
on the number of how many they have
in their database, so whatever.
I think what I'm going to probably use is some
type of like, this one, I could try this, but it's really
just going to depend on how it looks visually,
and whether or not I have enough characters.
OK, so what you want to do is you want to go to Notes
on your phone. On Android, the way you would do it
is just use Docs, so get on here,
and then just use Google Docs.
It works the same way as Notes.
And then just make sure that you
obviously have a Google account,
you'll create a new doc, and just do it like that.
OK, great. Back to iOS.
So you open up Notes, now this is the
way that you copy it into Instagram's bio.
For whatever reason, this is just a hack.
This is how you do it.
If you do it this way,
then you can put in breaks in your sentences,
whereas if you just type it in Instagram,
it actually doesn't allow you to do that.
So this is what I picked, curated list of only the best
in tech and innovation, world-changing trends to
watch, weekly tech employees, need a business idea, it's easy.
Now, I had to change some of these from what
you saw on the screen before because of the links.
So I was just running into some issues
with things like, don't fall behind,
or business as opposed to biz idea.
So I just had to simplify these a little bit.
I think I actually have a little bit of extra room now,
but I can use those for whatever I want later on.
Again, this is just a game of optimization,
optimization, optimization.
So we'll see later. Ok, so what you do is you copy it out of
Notes, go to Instagram, your bio, and then you can paste it.
Now, I didn't include my link in the bio, because
the link actually goes up here in the website section.
That's how you get it clickable.
I don't actually have a link right now, so I'm just going
to put mylink.com, we'll set that up later. Hit done,
now you can look at it visually.
OK.
We have our logo.
It's the rocket.
That's cool. Daily innovation inspiration,
cool, whatever, and the rest of it looks decent.
I'm going to clean this up really
quickly by doing a couple things.
I want to have it visually not have this weird
staircase look to it, like that first sentence is way
too long, I don't need that long of a sentence.
And I also think I can clean this up, or at least make it
a little more visually interesting with more emojis.
So I'm just going to do this really fast, so I don't need to
say "only", I think that'll help, and I can put in more robots.
You guys have trouble putting in emojis,
just go back to the Notes app, or go
back to Google Docs, and do it that way.
I'm allowed to do this because I'm using the Google keyboard.
It's called G-board.
I didn't choose a pasty white hand
because I'm also pasty and white,
I picked it because the normal emoji is yellow and I
wanted to contrast it with a bag of money, which is yellow.
I think that looks better.
There's just more to look at.
It's more visually interesting, it's got more color,
and that first sentence has been kind of reined in.
I think ideally I could get that one down to something
simpler, so I can maybe just say innovation instead
of tech and innovation, but for the
most part I think this is pretty good.
OK.
So that pretty much covers it for me
on my end with Innovation Station.
See you guys next lecture.