Hey guys welcome back.
So this lecture what we're going to do is talk about the three different types of ads that are available
to you for Instagram ads.
Now you've heard me say this in The Last Lecture.
Instagram ads are very much like Facebook ads.
Really the only difference is that you have a couple extra formats that aren't available on Facebook.
But as far as advertising goes we kind of follow the same basic standards so if you know how to do Facebook
advertising or you know the basics behind advertising in general those are very easily extended to Instagram.
But in this lecture let's just break down what the three main types of ads are on Instagram.
So the first thing we have our regular post ads are post ads are ads that are going to show up as if
it were a regular post in your news feed.
Obviously it's going to display to anybody that you target regardless of whether or not they've even
heard of you or follow your account.
Now we can see a preview of the different types of ads within that type of.
And we can do photo ads videos and Carousel ads.
Now I see regular post ads appealing to two different types of people.
One you don't have an Instagram account and you want to reach the Instagram audience which I don't blame
you.
Currently it's something like eight hundred million active users and of those eight hundred million
60 percent have displayed some interest in purchasing on the platform.
Facebook can't even say that the second type of person is someone who has an account on instagram but
they want to run an ad that doesn't really jive with their timeline or the regular post-comp position
that they've already established.
Now story ads are the second type of ads and these are vertical ads that are going to run in between
stories that a user would normally watch.
I remember at the very first screen in the homescreen of an screamy see at the top all the stories that
you can view in between those sets of stories that's when ads will run and these ads are typically going
to be 19:20 by 10 80 pixels and they're relatively new.
I mean like a story they're kind of low effort and they're designed to get people who are just kind
of mindlessly going through their stories list with stories you have to keep in mind that these are
new right.
So because they're new they haven't established a lot of traction or a lot of baseline information to
kind of work with with regard to how effective they are.
So keep that in mind because they're new they actually have really good click through metrics right
now.
But if you know anything about advertising it's that as people get more and more used to ads they become
less and less effective.
We call that the law of should click through.
So keep in line with stories you have to focus your content on being very engaging in the first three
seconds because unlike a regular post ad it disappears.
Right.
The person has to be really on the ball and they have to be really engaged in order to have the wherewithal
to click on your name or scroll up to do something with the ad or the post.
They can see it and then scroll back to it later.
They can sit there and stare at it all day long a story only lasts up to 15 seconds if it's a video
or 10 seconds if it's an image.
Now the last type of ad on Instagram will be called boosted ads.
And essentially what that is is when you have a post on your account you can boost it and you do that
inside the app itself.
It's actually pretty straightforward.
But what you do is you essentially pay for extra reviews for people to see your post.
Now the don't have a reason why you might do this one of them might be that you're trying to grow your
account and you notice that one of your posts did really really well.
That's a pretty common when you say OK well maybe I'll spend $5 a day to get this out there to get more
and more attention for my account.
The alternative to that is let's say you're running an ad right.
And as opposed to wanting to blast that ad to your followers over and over again you could boost one
of your promotional posts and use that as a way to essentially get more people looking at it and potentially
get more conversions.
OK so those are the big three.
Keep in mind we can boost our own post though we already posted on her Instagram account that can be
pretty useful if you have a really really good post that's doing really well and you'd like to extend
that or if you want to kind of slip in a promotional post and then advertise it that way.
We also have regular timeline posts which just show up as if it were a regular post.
However they're not going to be associated with your account.
So you don't have to worry about those people than seeing that post associated with your account.
Maybe it's too spammy Maybe it's to sales the Who knows they're great.
Even if you don't have an Instagram account because anybody can run them and use Facebook.
Targeting System to pick whoever they want to hit and then the last one were stories and those are relatively
new to the metrics are pretty enticing right now and for the most part they're cheap.
However we don't know how long these will last or if they'll stand the test of time.
So it's hard to say whether or not here is more valuable than say a dollar and a regular post.
All right so the next set of lectures will drill down into each one of these ads and then you'll watch
me run an ad of each type.
OK.
See you then.