Hey guys, welcome back.
So this section, what we're doing is we're covering
automated or semi-automated outreach strategies
for growing your account.
Now, when we talk about outreach strategies, you
could outreach to people for a lot of different things.
You could outreach people to sell them something,
to try to get them to follow a different account.
In this section, we're going to talk about how to
outreach specifically for collaboration posts.
Now, with Instagram, when we talk about collaboration posts,
kind of the gold standard is what we call the shout for shout.
You know what shoutouts are, we looked at those before,
but shout for shouts are effectively where you trade
shoutouts with accounts that have similar themes,
similar audiences, and ideally, similar follower counts.
We're currently in an Instagram trend where
Instagram, because it's owned by Facebook,
they're kind of reeling from Facebook getting in trouble
with some of the ways that they allow businesses
to spread their information.
*How do you sustain a business model in
which users don't pay for your service?*
*-Senator, we run ads.
-I see.*
There used to be the case that Facebook and Instagram
were very business friendly, as in you're trying
to grow your account,
okay, we'll show your stuff to all sorts of people.
But now Facebook's kind of reeling that back,
Instagram is following the same tact,
they're trying to make it such that now they really
only want to show people information from friends
and family or accounts they already follow.
So as a business owner or someone who's trying to
use this for business means, that actually is quite
a bit more difficult.
If you have been following our follow along sections, you probably noticed that it used to be the case where we posted something,
like 75% of our views were from non-followers,
now it's more like 25%, if you're lucky.
So that means that we're operating in our own little
echo chamber, so when we post something, for the
most part, it really only goes to our followers, and
that getting an introduction or exposure to someone
else's followers becomes that much more important.
That's the only way we can pierce
these little bubbles we're in.
So what type of shout for shouts are there?
Well, really kind of falls down into three different
categories. One, we have traditional post shoutouts,
and that's really what everyone used to do.
You'd say "Hey, want to do a shoutout?"
And then they would say "Yes, let's do it."
Here's a post,
here's a post, you trade posts, and then you coordinate
when to post it, and then you try to obviously even
it out such that maybe, if one account is smaller than
the other, they post twice and the other posts once.
Really it's just a relationship game. But we
have other options available to us as well.
The other one is story shoutouts, which are the same
exact thing, but you're using stories, and that simplifies
things quite a bit, because we don't have to negotiate
how long the post is going to be up anymore.
We also don't have to really coordinate as much
as before, because if we do a post, it would be like,
Okay, you going to post something, I'm going to post
something, you'd wait for the other person to post it,
then you post it, or you try to set up the same exact
time that you're going to post it. With a story,
you know if you post it, it's
automatically going to be 24 hours,
and if they tag you, you automatically know it's there.
So as long as they get it within that same 24 hour
window that you've originally posted, it's pretty
easy to meet that basic rule of reciprocity.
Then of course we do have true collaboration posts,
and that's really where you're not trading posts,
you work with another account to make an in-between post.
You see this a lot with personal accounts. Two
influencers, people with large followings, will make
a photo with both of them in it or they'll do a
conversation with each other and live it or whatever.
That's kind of the trailing end of what's available.
Now, you could certainly do that, and it's a good
idea, especially if you're very strategic about it,
but that's not really something that we're going
to cover, because as far as ROI goes, that takes
a lot of effort, a lot of coordination,
and the return is pretty much, eh,
probably the same as doing a traditional shout for shout.
So over the next set of lectures,
we're going to do two different things.
One, we're going to find a virtual assistant and set up
a process by which they can go and find accounts
and message them, and then what we're going to do
after that is do something that is truly automated,
instead of the first one, usually you do one or the other,
and we're going to use Jarvee, which we introduced
in a previous section, and use some of their tools to
just automatically grab users and send messages
to start this collaboration process.
Now, there are obvious pros and cons to each one.
Pros of hiring someone is it's going to be more
accurate, you're going to have more control over it,
but it's going to cost a little bit of money
and it does take some management time.
Now, the pros of doing a fully automated version is
that you can do it fully automatic, you don't actually
have to do anything. You don't
have to hire anyone, you don't have to pay any money, besides
a subscription fee to Jarvee, and that's pretty much it,
but of course the cons are that, well, it still takes maintenance
time, because you have to go and check it and tweak it,
but you also run the risk of, well, because you're using
an automated software, you could potentially do
it wrong and have it run rogue,
and get your account in trouble.
Now, I don't think it's terribly likely, as long as you're
smart and you follow the advice I give you in this section,
but it is definitely a distinct possibility.
Now, it is worth mentioning, I think that the maintenance for
running an automated strategy versus a semi-automated
strategy are almost kind of the same.
I mean, it's still the tinkering, and twisting,
and the upfront set up costs for both sides.
So I generally consider that a wash.
All right, guys.
Next lecture, what we'll do is we'll start the process of
setting up a person, an individual who is just cheap or can
do it on a fixed rate price, to go and find us some
people, automatically grab their information, and then
start sending out messages.
All right. See you then.