Hey guys welcome back.
So this lecture around to do is we're going to talk about Instagram live now Instagram live is a feature
that got rolled out as I'm recording this.
A year ago something like that and the basic idea is pretty simple.
What you're allowed to do is run a live screen of whatever your camera is looking at.
And anyone who follows you will get a notification and then they can hop in into kind of a live chat
room and then follow along.
It's essentially a copycat of Periscope which when you guys are watching this or you know periscope
you exists anymore.
But the whole idea of periscope was that you can film yourself live doing something and there was a
lot of creativity that came from that.
A lot of people really took advantage of this new medium to engage their followers and to do some pretty
interesting things.
Lindsey Graham live is pretty much just an extension of that.
And for the most part people use it to break up their typical content strategy and to use it as a way
to kind of bring attention immediately to whatever it is that you're doing.
Now it's not immediately obvious if you've never watched one of these how you can use this to grow your
business and I'll be honest when I say this right up front.
It's Instagram live is one of my least favorite features just because it's not immediately obvious at
least for me how I could use this for the follow along that account is an innovation station and it's
also something that I don't I don't do a lot of live content.
So if I were to switch to a strategy that uses a lot I really have to put some thought into how to make
it work and how to pull it off on short notice.
So typically we see this with someone We'll go live and it'll be let's say like an educational Q&amp;A.
They can do live workshops.
I've seen people do live tutorials on how to do something.
Also I've seen businesses use this as a way to tease a product launch to talk about something to show
it off.
Also have seen it be pretty effective with like flash sales.
So if you have something that you need to sell any of your higher inventory on something you can on
a live and show it off and play with it and give a exclusive discount to someone who buys that.
If you're a company.
I've also seen this work pretty well.
If you have news about your company that's a nice little impromptu.
You just jump in and say hey we got acquired or Hey we just launched this new feature something that's
worth while that's something that's not necessarily something you would have made a well-polished press
release about.
Now you have a personal account what I've seen work the best.
Our Q&amp;A is what you do is it's pretty simple.
You can just make a post and say taking questions for a live Q&amp;A and then you can even do it as a story
and in the story there's a sticker now where you can submit questions and you can kind of use that to
gather a bunch of questions and then during your live you can answer those.
You can also just do it as a live impromptu kind of Q&amp;A.
You have people in the chat room ask questions.
My only suggestion to that is just be careful because sometimes the crowd can get unruly depending on
its size and also just the way it's set up it's kind of hard to read all the questions so if you're
answering a question and someone asks another one a lot of times it's hard to go and go back and find
a good question.
It's usually best practice if you're going to do that to have somebody with you who can at least like
be paying attention to the comments while you focus on the content.
Another thing that works pretty well are giveaways.
Now kind of combining this with a different section later on when we talk about what giveaways work
the best.
But if you have something that you want to give away just as a way to reward your followers or get them
to engage then it's pretty easy just to say I'm going have a giveaway to a certain time.
Did you run the live and it's a give away and then you just kind of have to come up with the rules for
people watching.
What do they have to do to actually get this stuff.
It's even better as your account gets larger because as you get larger What you can do is you can give
away someone else's stuff which is really nice because you don't spend any money.
And as long as he makes sure the stuff is giving away it fits within the theme of your account then
it's a pretty win win situation.
So there are three best practices that I think you should be aware of before setting out on an Instagram
wife.
The first one is you need to understand the engagement metrics and what makes a live video work.
Now the whole idea with this is we're not only trying to engage our followers and reward them but also
we're trying to use this as a platform to get more followers.
And the way that we get more followers is by if we get enough engagement and enough viewers it will
slowly start to creep up and start showing on the explore page.
Now how many viewers and comments you have to get to get to that point.
We don't really know.
It kind of just depends.
I indicated and I'm going to tell us that because of it did it make everything way to.
So just keep that in mind it's comments and it's viewers you want to keep your viewers on as long as
possible and you want to get them to comment as much as possible.
OK.
Now there's a lot different ways that you can do that and it's kind of up to you.
I mean it's this is one of these things that I still don't think is solidified.
There is no guaranteed way of increasing your gauge on Instagram live but I've seen some clever things
like for instance when these accounts run to me live sometimes I'll do giveaways.
And the way that they'll do it is look give away let's say a shout out or an item and they'll ask the
person to answer a question they ask them to answer it in the comments one letter at a time and they
have to answer it without having their chain broken.
That is actually kind of a I mean it actually works because people will try to answer it really quickly
and multiple people trying to do it.
Keep breaking each other's chain even though it kind of does lower the quality of the chat room as a
whole so if you're trying to get people to engage by reading the chat room and reading questions or
actual interesting things that can backfire a little bit.
Now the second best practice for you to be lines is always to promote your life beforehand.
OK.
It's really easy to throw up a story post because remember me in the stories section we made a story
post for a give away.
It was really easy to do I did it in like 30 seconds.
Throw that up and keep letting people know when it is set a date.
Make sure you have the time zone and then tell them about it and on the day of perfect.
I personally like to throw up a regular post and a story at the same time saying we're giving away this
or we're going to do a live Q&amp;A at this time and that's a really easy way to get people to jump in.
Now you don't have to make like a brand new post for this because that could actually take a little
bit time.
You can make it in a story post and then save that as a regular post.
That's a pretty easy feature to do.
And then number three try to give them something at the end if you're doing a product promotion try
to give them a coupon at the end.
Tell them that there's a coupon at the end if it's a cue in a tell them that you know the most interesting
question will be at the very end where you are announcing something that's really interesting at the
end.
The idea here is that you want to make sure that your live count like the viewer count stays consistent
you don't want people checking and getting the value and then immediately leaving.
So by telling them that something will be at the end of it.
And typically it helps to tell them this is like a 15 minute thing or a 20 minute thing or whatever
that can incentivize people to stay long enough which will help your metrics and ultimately your goal
with the SCRAM line which is to get more people to your live video.
All right guys that's pretty much it for now.
Make sure that you promote your life beforehand.
Make sure you're specific about it.
Make sure that you give something away and then make sure that whatever you're doing you're designing
it for two things in mind.
Total Viewers and total comments.
That's really what's going to make this important if you're trying to get new viewers in and not just
engage the ones you have.
All right next we're going to do is just go over that you and I will show you how you can set up a live
video and then after that we'll do a live demonstration of a live.
Sorry for being redundant for innovation station.
All right CNN.