Hey guys, welcome back.
Let's talk about image sizing and what to do
so you don't accidentally crash Instagram's servers by
submitting a triangle photo, or even worse, a photo in 4K.
Oh my God.
All right.
First off, in case you forgot, how big should our images be?
Is anyone paying attention?
We already talked about this actually,
and you should probably know.
Believe it or not.
Or maybe we didn't, and I'm just crazy,
which actually could be a legitimate possibility, you kind
of lose track of things when you're making courses.
Now, we want it to be 1080x1080.
That's a square.
It's also what's considered full HD.
An easy way to remember this is, I don't know, whatever
number you associate with HDTV which is 1080p.
If you think it's 720, just slap yourself,
because that's not technically HD anymore.
Now, that's essentially what we're going for,
an HD image. Now, does it display 1080x1080
on the screen? Anybody who's done this on their
computer, you probably noticed immediately.
That's a huge image.
It's not like your phone.
Well, guess what?
No, actually on mobile displays it displays as 600x600,
and even on the web version it seems like something
like 600x600 is the cap as well.
So then why exactly do we do it in almost
double that display resolution?
Now, one of the reasons is that when it's downscaled,
which is a fancy term for shrunk down, it'll come out
as a sharper image.
And the other reason is that Instagram actually stores your
image on their servers in a duplicate copy as 1080x1080,
assuming that it was actually submitted that way.
Now, what exactly does that mean?
Why do we care?
That means that Instagram knows that it's going to eventually show them all in 1080, and so it's going to need
that 1080 version to make everything work
retroactively for all their photos.
You can tell just essentially by the code that
they know they're going to move on to it soon.
So by doing this, you're essentially
future-proofing your work.
You're welcome, future you.
OK, so that's out of the way.
Now, seriously.
Remember that, even burn it on yourself as a tattoo.
Put 1080 inside of a sweet flaming skull, for all I care,
as long as you remember it. Now, does it necessarily
have to be a square?
Actually, no, it's just that squares are reportedly the best to use.
Whether people just like them more or they're just
nostalgic for the old Instagram, I don't really know,
but you can post in two other sizes,
which are called landscape and portrait.
Now, sometimes, and you might have seen this, you'll
be looking at a photo and it'll be this weird rectangle.
It's not super common, but you do see it.
Instagram finally allows that now.
Now, landscapes, you'll want to make it in 1200x673.
Yes, I realize 673 is incredibly random,
but that's just how math-ing works.
Or, if you're a British person, how the maths work.
Once Instagram gets a hold of your 1200x673
image, they'll shrink it down to 600x336.
OK, whatever, they store the big one,
and they're going to show the small one.
The last size worth knowing, or at least paying attention to, is the portrait size, and that's supposed to be done in 1080x1350.
Now, it'll store it at that size, but it
will scale it down to 481x599.484.
Yes.
So not really important.
Just understand that it's different. Portrait is designed
to fit with the new portrait shots that have
been added to iOS and some Android compatible phones.
If you already knew about that, and that happened
like three years ago, I'm sorry, you from the future,
but that's just the problem with making these courses.
So when should we use each type,
and is this something I have to memorize?
Well, first of all, no, you don't have to
memorize it, but 1080x1080 is pretty helpful.
We actually have the numbers attached as
a cheat sheet in the resources of this lecture,
so you can always just keep that.
So check it.
Now, when should you use these though?
Honestly, I don't actually think it really matters.
It's not really as if your engagement is going
to be lower if you don't use all three.
The only time I think it matters is if you have a great shot
and you just can't fit it into a box and get the same effect.
Now, in that case, you've got two other options.
Also, keep in mind, guys, we're going to use tools to
make these images, and most auto resize them for you,
so don't really freak out, it's pretty easy.
All right, guys, that's pretty much everything you
wanted to know about resolutions, and then some.
Moving on.