Hey guys, welcome back. OK, this lecture, we're going to
talk about another habit worth getting into your process,
and that's called curation. Now, typically, curation just means
I pick and choose which things I want, like a curated
experience or a curated interior design, that's kind of what
I'm talking about, but I mean it in a different way. What
I mean is that on Instagram, and
you might have actually noticed this,
you can delete your posts.
You might have asked yourself how is it that these gigantic accounts out there, usually the ones that have 1 million+,
how is it that they post really weird stuff that has
nothing to do with their brand, looks totally different,
it's not a match to their name,
and then when you go to their profile, you only see that one that you saw on the feed, or you don't see anything at all.
Well, it's a very common thing called curation,
and it's something that you need to do.
So the basics of this, without sounding too obvious, when
you post something, it shows up in all of your followers'
feeds and then a little bit extra,
some other people who are not
following you will also see it,
and it'll show up on your profile. OK, after you post it, it
kind of throws it out there on top of someone's list, and
it just depends how much they scroll before they see it.
If you delete it almost immediately afterwards,
well, then it's not going to show up on your profile, but it still
shows up on their feed, it doesn't pull it from their feeds.
So what often happens when someone posts something that
is experimental, doesn't go off with their brand, whatever,
they'll post it and then take it down.
Now, there are three main reasons why you
would choose to curate a post. The first reason
is that what you're posting is a change in brand, or tone, or style, or even a different type of media something that's different.
If you established your account as a motivational quotes account, and then you posted a one-minute long video, and it's like an interview style,
that might be the case that you go back and you start deleting slowly over time some of your older things, so that you can
change the brand of your account over to videos,
assuming that that's what you want to do.
Alternatively, it could be the case that you wanted
to just try out a new style and it didn't work,
so then you delete it. Now, if you follow the other lectures, I say the best way of doing this is using your dummy account, because
in your dummy account, you'll be posting the same things on it automatically by using Buffer, which we covered before,
but on the dummy, you can post and it doesn't really matter.
You don't really have to worry about it.
You don't have to keep checking to see if you should
delete it, you can just post it and leave it there.
Curation doesn't really matter there.
Now, the second reason why you might curate
a post was because it was an advertisement.
OK.
Obviously these's different types of advertisements.
Next section, we're talking about shoutouts, that's a very
common one where you shoutout someone else, so
you take one of their posts,
you post it on your feed, and then you link back
to them. It's a way of kind of sharing an audience,
we'll talk about that later.
That might be a reason why you delete it.
OK, someone else's account doesn't really match
your brand, doesn't look right, and people can
kind of tell when you post something that's benefiting someone else, and not necessarily your audience to the fullest extent,
so you might delete it in that case.
It's could also be the case that you are promoting your
own product, so you posted something, you let
it out there for, let's say, I don't know, an hour,
people see it, interact with it, whatever,
and then you just take it down.
Why?
Because maybe you don't want your feed to look like you
have product pitches over and over and over again.
By doing that, you can post more often.
Why wouldn't you just leave it up for like a week instead
of just posting it repeatedly and taking it down? Every time
you post it, it pops it up to the top of their feed.
So if you leave it up for a week,
eight days later, the odds of people seeing it are much lower.
You also run the risk of them going to your profile and seeing it, and getting that impression that it's a kind of spammy account.
Also, it could possibly be like a product placement. Sometimes real companies will pay you to post, that's something you'll deal
with when you're a larger account and
you have lots of followers, but it's pretty common, especially if you get larger, people will reach out more and more, so maybe
you post yourself drinking something from a company that
wanted you to do that, you might take that down
depending on what the agreement was.
Why you might take something down?
It just had low engagement. Remember, we calculate engagement
by taking the comments, the number comments,
plus number of likes, divided by our total followers.
Typically, we see something a baseline of 2%, 1.8%,
but it depends on the industry.
Usually, you have an industry baseline,
and then you have your baseline.
Maybe the industry baseline is 1.5% and yours is 2.5%
Let's say you post something and it just flops, it's a 1%.
Okay.
In that case, you might actually delete it, because you
don't want someone to then go to the rest of your
posts and see the ones that just didn't perform well.
Nothing wrong with the style, or the tone of
the voice, the media or anything like that,
it just didn't work, for whatever reason.
So those are the three reasons. One, you're experimenting or you're changing over your account to an entirely different style,
or brand, or media type. Two, you're dealing
with shoutouts or advertisements.
And then three, one of your posts had low engagement.
I really like to think of curation as like turning
the hedges, it's something you need to do,
and generally, I like to at least once a week or twice a week
go back to the posts and kind of thin out
the herd, let's say. I might go and look at it,
and for some reason if a shoutout or an advertisement is still up there, I might delete it, I might just look at the posts using
Iconosquare or Instagram's Insights, although
it doesn't give you as much information,
see which ones just aren't doing well,
and then let's say go and trim them out.
It's really up to you.
Sometimes what I do is I try to look for posts that have a
larger deviation from the average, so let's say my average
is 3% and I'm OK with anything from 2% up.
Well, maybe I have something that breaks that
2% rule and it's a 1.8% or something like that,
I might want to trim that down, because at the end of the
day, it doesn't matter if you have a thousand posts that
are medium quality,
what really matters is that all of them are high quality.
People aren't going to scroll past a couple hundred in general. It's also the case that sometimes if you repost old content, and
that's something we will do at a certain point, just because
we've created enough content to last for years,
you might actually go back and delete your old ones.
Someone who might be scrolling through it might notice them.
Curation is generally a tool worth using,
and it even lends itself to some pretty weird
strategies that you can try out if you want to.
For instance, what you can do is if you
know you have two different audiences,
let's say a big audience in the UK, a big audience
in the West Coast of the United States,
the time difference really is 8 or 9 hours,
so if you're trying to post for the optimal
time in the US, you would want to post at
let's say you want to go for the 10:00 PM.
OK, so if you post at 10:00 PM San Francisco,
that's 5:00 or 6:00 AM in London.
That's not useful for the second audience.
So what you might do is post one for San Francisco, leave it up
for a couple of hours, delete it, and then post when it actually
gets to the next best time for your London audience.
Then it's up to you if you want to leave it up or not,
you could take it down or you can just leave it up.
I generally like to leave it up. That way you can be
at the top of the feed for both of your audiences,
and if you want to, you can even tailor the post,
maybe say something location specific.
All right, guys, that's enough about curating posts, you'll probably see me talk about that and do that in the follow along
section, it's pretty important, I'll make
sure that I have at least one video on it.
Alright, see you next lecture.