You guys welcome back this lecture we're going to do is just go over what the Instagram live user interface
looks like.
How do you start from one and what settings you have to control it.
So it's pretty simple.
It runs very similar to stories like it runs just out of your camera.
So just go to your home screen and then you can put the camera on the top left and all you have to do
now at the very bottom is go to live.
That's it.
It's just a camera setting.
Typically once you're on the screen then it's a question of getting set up making sure you have everything
ready to go.
And then actually jumping and it gives you some previews right here so you know you can flip your camera
around right before you go live.
You can also add these facial things very similar to snap chat filters that change your face to make
you look ridiculous.
That's kind of nice of you just doing an impromptu thing.
Now up here in the top left we have settings.
Now what you can do is similar to stories.
You can actually hide your life from certain people and all you kind of have to do is just go to hide
story from.
And it works very much the same way.
So if you had someone who was really obnoxious and and past experiences just lower the quality of whatever
it is that you're doing live you could block them if you wanted to.
Or perhaps you work with other Instr recounts as advertisers so maybe you don't want to see exactly
what you're doing.
Other than that I definitely like to say save the camera roll just so you have a backup of whatever
you do allow message replies it's pretty much up to you and the rest it's pretty simple if you want
to do cross share to Facebook you could do that.
It's all pretty straightforward.
OK.
I mean that's pretty much it.
I'll jump into the dummy account just so you can kind of see what it looks like once you start one.
But you also see how we run one with innovation station and it'll be a bit of a learning experience
too.
This is the first time we'll be doing it for that account.
So now here for it.
Let's see.
So innovative or dummy account.
And we wanted to run a live.
You just go live and then you start video checks your connection.
You're now live.
Right.
OK.
So yep pretty much.
It.
It gives you options for like for instance bringing someone into your chat right here.
So if you have someone in your chat watching it you can actually bring their video in as well so it's
a pretty easy way to turn this into a conversation directly.
Here's a way to send it directly to people to get their attention.
So let's say you wanted to do a joint life together.
You could then hit that share button that Senate directly to them as soon as you go live.
Here's that same button if you want to make your face look ridiculous.
So yeah for the most part that's pretty much it.
You have comments right here.
And if you want to turn them off any point you set turn off commenting and then turn off requests to
go live.
So that's basically when people will request to join in on your video.
Now it's up to you and what your content strategy is if that's something you want to do.
So when you're done you know.
And and it will say in my video you confirm it and then appear on the top right.
You can save it.
And if you want to keep it public for 24 hours you can leave that tract.
And you know I don't know.
I'm not even sure exactly where that will display.
But could it share.
OK so it ends up just adding it to your story.
Right.
So now hold onto my story and click that it'll basically show what happened.
It'll show me staring at my keyboard talking for 24 hours.
So not exactly fascinating but that's pretty much it.
I mean there's nothing really else to this.
It's pretty straightforward.
It's really up to you to design your content and to figure out what exactly are going to do.
You know do a Q&amp;A do unity tutorial interview someone you can totally do that on live just pointed at
both of you or pointed at one of them and take turns alternating back and forth.
Don't make it a Q&amp;A do you want to make it on those ones where you have fans come in and ask you questions.
It's like multiple people talking at once it can kind of look like a chat room really up to you.
OK.
Next you're going to do is I'm going to show you just some quick and easy ways to promote the live event
that you're going to do to a post and a story.
So it really simple.
Then after that we'll do a actual live run with innovation station.
See.