Hey guys welcome back.
OK so just a quick question that I've been getting from students wanted to pop in and kind of clear
this up for you guys.
What is the difference in a VPN and a proxy and how is that relevant to creating Instagram accounts.
Do you guys know what a VPN or a proxy is.
See in the next lecture.
But those who don't well stick around.
OK so there's two different types of IP addresses that you can buy what's called a proxy and one is
called a VPN VPN stands for virtual private network.
And that definition doesn't really help you a ton.
Basically there's only one difference between the two.
Now a proxy is just an IP address that you can use somewhere else.
If I have a proxy I can install that on my system and then route all of my traffic through a different
server that has a different IP address.
And then when I interact with Web sites or even desktop applications those systems will think I'm coming
from that location.
That's pretty much it.
Proxies are usually cheaper than DP ends.
Now VPN on the other hand does the same exact thing but it encrypts your traffic.
Typically you see the paeans being used in for instance countries where they have a lot of censorship
or they block a lot of Web sites that you want to use the part of encrypting your traffic is just so
that you can have an extra layer of safety if you want to hide your information hide the information
you're sending or whatever.
There's a lot of different reasons why you might use a VPN people for instance in medicine use VPN because
they just don't want someone intercepting their traffic through things like data sniffing and then pulling
confidential information a proxy on the other hand is for someone who doesn't really care about hiding
their information.
They just want to appear that they come from different location.
Now I use proxies typically because I don't really have anything that I want to hide.
But in my case I use proxies for things like buying airplane tickets.
Now why is that.
Well for whatever reason if you go to like Kayak.com or Skyscanner or whatever you use if you take an
IP address from some other country that for whatever reason might have a lot of promotions going on
or is just a lower income country a lot of times you can get cheaper flights.
You can also play this game with currencies where I use a proxy in a country that has a currency that's
currently sliding.
And I can pay in that currency and the conversion rates.
Great.
That's what I personally use it for.
It's a weird kind of loophole but there's a lot of different use cases why you might use a proxy.
Now which one should you pick for your Instagram.
Typically I just say use a proxy and the reason why I say this is because proxies are cheaper faster
because they don't have to do a lot of the encryption that might slow down your traffic.
And with the vpn the encryption actually might create problems.
So if you're using Instagram for incense and they see your data it's coming and like the packets you're
sitting their servers are encrypted.
They might actually flag that and it might look weird to them.
So generally I try to avoid the paeans and I try to stick with proxies hide my ass.
Each is a VPN so just keep that in mind.
I'm not saying it won't work but I'm saying it's one more thing that you should keep in mind if you
want to make sure your traffic looks as legitimate as possible.
OK guys.
That being said any questions post in that Q&amp;A or in the slack.
Otherwise I'll see in the next lecture where we're going to jump back in and start creating some accounts.
See the.