All right guys welcome back.
So this lecture are going to do is we're going to start the process of finding someone who can do automatic
outreach for us.
Now in this picture we're going into two different things.
One we're going to create a job post posted on freelancer dot com.
And then the second thing is we're going to set up an automatic Google sheet and set up the framework
for which they can start gathering information.
Now if you have already taken my advice from the previous sections where we talk about scaling your
content and you have someone who could do this for you already then that's fantastic.
But I'd still like to show you how if you're going to hire specifically for this this is how you would
do it.
OK.
So the first thing I want to do is set up the receptacle for where this supposed person is going to
gather information.
So I like to use Google sheets.
You can use Excel.
You can use whatever you want.
Honestly as long as it has basic sharing on it and you can share it with someone and you can revoke
their access to it as well.
Should anything go wrong.
So I'm just going to go to Google sheets and create a new sheet.
All right what I want to do is just call this out for show outreach.
OK.
And then what I need to do is just kind of set up the parameters for how they're going to collect information.
So when we think about who it is that we would potentially do a collaborative post with what do we care
about.
Well we're probably going to care about what their name is what their audience is what the size of their
account is.
We're also going to want to track whether or not we've contacted them and whether or not they've responded
so pretty simply we could just say.
So let's say the account name.
So that's their name on Instagram and then we're probably going to want a guess as to like the category
that they're in.
And then we'll probably want to know how many followers they have followers.
And then pass that it's pretty simple.
So let's just say contacted.
So that'll be a yes or no call on then we'll just say responded.
And that's a yes or no again and then whether or not the promotion was run.
OK.
So here's way to basically work is I just want to gather the name of the account what category there
and just to make sure that we're getting the right people then how many followers they have.
The time that they were gathered then I want to make sure that we track whether or not we've contacted
them whether or not they've responded and then whether or not the promotion was run.
That is really pretty much it.
Now we have collected all the information we find relevant should we go down this process and actually
start running this pretty competitively we might add other things as we figure out oh okay it's also
pretty important that they have a video already or maybe the response time is important.
There's a lot of other factors we can't always think of at the very beginning.
So let's just make this so it's not a blight on the eyes OK.
And that is pretty much it.
All right.
So now in order to find someone this is one of these tasks should be as if you're watching my outsourcing
course as we go away and adapt to this.
But I kind of summarize this very quickly.
The complexity of the task you're asking them to do is going to be the largest factor in how much you
have to pay them.
If it's really really simple that means you can write out very simply what they have to do in order
to do it correctly and then it doesn't really matter who you hire where they're from how well they speak
English etc. etc..
With that being said there are generally speaking two major platforms for hiring freelancers or virtual
assistants.
I know there's a bunch of other ones like people who are our guru and like virtual systems dot com.
But in terms of size you can't really compare them to up work and freelancer.
Now if you remember talking about upwards of works great for finding a variety of different people all
over the world for a variety of different tasks or as freelancers great for finding people who are really
cheap who can do very basic simple tasks.
So that being said that's going to be the platform that we're going to try to use.
So just go to freelancer dot com looks like this works basically the same way as up work.
I mean we just create job posts.
You add in basic payment information and then you post it you can post for free on this one.
And for the most part yeah the community really kind of revolves around simple basic low pay tasks.
Just keep that in mind that's not to say that you can't find great people doing things like building
entire web site but I'm just saying that their community kind of skews in this direction.
So good.
Create an account.
Once you create an account it should take you to a page like this.
It's not hard to set this up.
They don't even require a credit card from you up front or anything like that.
I've used this before so you can kind of see like I've used them for personal assistance and basic data
entry.
That's kind of the sweet spot I've found for freelancer now posting a project I really simple can't
miss it right here is that poster project.
All right.
Now like up Orrick we have choose a name for our project or to tell more about a project and upload
information that we think is relevant now.
In order to do this well I think that we should make sure that we hit the same basic tenants that we
talked about before for job posts.
So I like to do just as it is to open up a word document.
So either Microsoft or Evernote bear test scathed whatever it is you use is it really matter.
And then just kind of scratch our notes in here.
Now this one is not going to be particularly hard because we're just looking for someone who can follow
directions very basically and that's it really.
So we don't need to get too fancy with this and it don't even have to think too hard about the title
we give because it doesn't really matter if we get 200 people applying versus 50.
You only need one person.
So give a basic description of the job up front.
I need someone to compile Instagram accounts that meet this current Syria and then to message them on
through my account.
OK so that's the basics of it.
And then what I like to do is give a little context as to why I'm looking for Instagram accounts that
are similar to the account I'm currently growing.
And I'll give them a link to it because they want to see that
and say I want to reach out to a lot of other counts to see if we can promote each others accounts.
OK.
So that pretty much explains what it is you don't need to go into absolute detail as to why or why you
think it's effective at all while in early care they're just here to complete a task.
OK I don't know what I want to do is probably give a little bit of the how right I've done the what
the why.
Now any idea of the how so how I'll say my account uses new technology and innovations.
I need to find all accounts that appeal to a smaller audience.
Accounts must be in one of these categories and then list out technology
gadgets.
Luxury like tronics and I can even say things like start ups because those are you know decently related.
So then we can even do things like science that's often a common overlap.
Science is like then I can give an example things like hearing Mr. X X are viral videos.
You can then focus on electronics and I think that's a pretty good list.
I can always go back and edit this.
Once they get started especially once they start running out of accounts.
But they should be able to find thousands and thousands accounts with these criteria.
Now then I need to give them more criteria as to what specifically they're looking for.
So all say accounts must be let's see.
So we might say our accounts at 27 thousand.
So I would say over 15000 followers and under because I don't want to waste time to say 75000 followers
just because I think a 75000 person follower might be inclined to work with me reading over that they're
kind of just wasting their time.
Now it's up to you whether or not you want to give them further criteria.
I could say something like only accounts with a certain engagement rate.
Right because it maybe you don't want to promote two accounts that have low engagement rates which would
so leave my audience.
I might also say I only want to count that primarily have an audience from United States.
OK now that's up to you whether or not you want to get that detail but you just have to keep in mind
this becomes a little bit more complicated and you have to have some way of showing them how to figure
this out.
Right.
We use hype auditor but it's not realistic.
If they do this for hundreds of accounts that'll get expensive to figuring out who their audience is
their engagement rate.
You know the free tool they can use and there are some free tools and that might be something we're
showing.
But for me I would rather catch that later on in the process.
I'd rather cast a wider net to say anybody who meets these basic criteria and then once they start messaging
them they'll respond and then it's up to me to start the actual process with them by negotiating how
we're going to share our promotion or what videos I need or when we're going to do it because it's very
easy for me to then look at the person's account and go oh I don't actually like that account and mine's
me motivational relational entrepreneurship.
So that reminds me I'll add a couple more I dare just because those accounts are very used to doing
share for shares so likelihood of getting yeses from are much higher.
OK then now that I've done the how.
Now I just need to move off into any other information that I need to state.
Like for instance when they need to do this what their goals are what I expect from them so I might
say I need someone who can spend say an hour a day doing this until it's no longer needed and then I
might give some parameters like prefer people in North American time zones just because that's going
to be a lot more useful especially if I'm trying to inadvertently target people who are in the north
american time zones that might be useful just because I don't want to be in a situation where every
time I give them new instructions it takes them 12 hours to implement it because they're asleep.
So I might say that.
OK.
Now the last thing I might do is just ask for a trial.
So in order to do this job this job please message me and your message with two accounts you have found
Instagram sickroom that meet these requirements.
OK.
Now trials are incredibly effective with freelancer you're going to get a ton of people messaging you
because there's a ton of people with very high skill sets that are not very distinguished from each
other.
It's very much a low end.
Work doesn't require a lot of thought just because someone with a good Internet connection who can follow
rules and does basic internet research.
So I'm going to say this and to be honest probably 10 percent of the people who are smart will even
do this and then one out of 10 percent maybe five percent get it right.
But remember you're going to like 50 applications maybe even 100 if you leave this up long enough.
So I want to make sure that we have our get is competent enough to read all of the instructions and
then basically carry out a very simple task.
We should take them two minutes never wanted a really really narrow this down to someone who really
really wanted it.
I could say Give me five accounts.
OK.
You might run into the problem where a lot of people won't do it because they think like oh you're just
trying to collect accounts for free by having us all do this.
And of course that's kind of stupid because why would you have 100 different people give you two accounts
because then you have to go and search through every single one to verify that it was even correct to
begin with.
And that's the same amount of time it would take you to just do it yourself.
But these people don't really think about it that way.
They're only thinking from the narrow scope from which they're applying to their job.
They don't know how your system works so it's I guess somewhat understandable.
OK so that's pretty much it up to you if you want to add other things other requirements you might say
like we'll communicate through Skype because the freelancer messenger system is not great.
But I mean you can also just use it.
You could say that you want them to update you after every fifty that they add or something like that
whatever it is.
You might even go into a little bit more about what they're going to do.
So I might say I'll give you access to a Google feed and I want you I want you to fill it out and message
after we you know say 50 accounts have been added.
Now I'm thinking about doing this in two different phases.
One they can pilot and two they start reaching out in mass and that makes probably more sense.
But I could do it either way.
Keep in mind even though this is a human doing it you still could get in trouble with sending too many
messages too quickly so keep that in mind that SCRAM doesn't like that behavior because they think it
looks like a bot.
And yeah I mean from their perspective it might be hard to tell a difference.
OK so let's post that and then in the next lecture we'll catch up and see who has applied to our gig.
OK.
So choosing names your project doesn't really matter.
Just say what it is.
Compile Instagram accounts and send templated message.
I'm going to give them a template message.
We'll talk about the next lecture for them to send.
It's going to be very very basic because of my experience.
So I mean once you are shout out you don't need to convince them of a whole lot.
Then we can copy and paste this description.
Make sure the formatting didn't come on all funky.
Did it go great.
OK.
And there we go.
Then what next.
Then what skills are you interested in.
For this kind of thing it's just data entry data entry.
You might say internet research.
So that's a pretty common one.
You might say excel means people are used to using Excel or as Google sheets kind of same thing and
then I might say Instagram although this is going to dip into a different pile of people.
So ideally if someone's already familiar with that scream there you know how to find people.
And that's great.
And hey if they want to use a tool that they've used that's perfectly fine as long as the results match
what I told them to look for guys I don't want to pay or to pay by the hour.
Now you could do fixed price if you want to but we're doing this as an automation system.
I want them to continuously do this so I can keep this going.
Now if I just wanted to try it out I could do.
Pay fixed price and say I need 100 accounts and you get a message 100 accounts.
Once they're done it's over.
Then is I ask you for your estimated budget you don't need to pay that.
I mean that's this is about as simple as it gets so I usually go with basics.
Hit next.
OK.
They don't sell you on something that's not useful and not something I'd recommend at all.
That's great if you're trying to do like a big project maybe but for the most part for 10 bucks you
don't get a whole lot of help from them.
OK great so now postman project.
All right now that it's posted.
I will get back to you in the next lecture and we'll start looking over the people that did.
All right see you then.