All right guys, welcome back. This lecture,
we're going to tackle captions. Now, captions are the little bit of text that you see from the poster underneath the photo or video.
A lot of people mistakenly think these are just comments,
because, well, they look exactly like comments.
I'm honestly not sure why they do it like that.
So when you're writing a caption, what exactly do we care about?
Captions are meant to be an auxiliary to your post.
They can explain what you posted,
they could complement the post and expand on it,
they could simply tell the users how you made
the content, how you found it, or really anything.
Most commonly though you see is
either one, a reaction to the post,
this is especially common in comedy accounts,
and two, an explanation of the post.
Oftentimes a photo is of something
that just isn't in context.
So if you posted "I quit my job,"
well, you probably need to explain.
And there's not enough space in the photo to do that.
Now the third thing I call expansions.
That's when you post a photo of your favorite place on
the beach to get your day drunk on and in the captions
maybe you tell a story that goes along with
how you found it and what you love about it.
That thing with the captions is that
you really don't have a limit here.
They're kind of an exception to the
brevity rule we talked about before.
You wouldn't want to put a long rambling story in your
photo or video, but in the caption it's perfectly fine.
Well, ok, there is technically a limit, and it's
2,200 characters, which is like half a page,
if you are using a regular Word doc, single spaced.
You don't need to fill that, and I seriously doubt you'll
ever really have to contend with this issue ever.
But for the most part, you have a free range here.
If you make a super long post, it's not going to turn off
your followers who are obsessed with quick learning
and quick engagement.
Captions are a perfect self-selection tool. After
a certain limit, it's usually like 10 to 12 words,
the caption gets a dot dot dot.
So if you want to read the rest, you have to expand the caption.
People browse it, see that first part, and then
they decide if they want to go further.
If it's too long, they just move on,
and they don't ding you for it.
If you have a user who is totally into what you're writing
about out, then they will, and all the better for that user.
So with that being said, I prefer long captions, multiple
paragraphs. One sentence is just not enough, unless
you're going for comedic effect, or
answering a question your post asked.
It just looks like you don't care and that
you're not putting effort into your post.
If you're not putting in effort, then why
should others care and follow you?
So with that being said, take advantage of the
minority of users that are really interested.
Remember, we live and die by the algorithm, and what
does the algorithm care about? Engagement rate and
time on post. Longer captains will make some users read longer, thereby extending the average time spent on the post.
People that read more are more likely to engage,
thereby raising the potential engagement.
So how can you make your caption long?
What exactly do you write about?
Well, one way to do it would be to tell a story.
Human beings are wired such that stories are our
preferred form of information consumption.
Would you rather read a list of facts about a
business or hear the story of how it started?
So an easy way to do this is just to find
a story, even if it's not that remarkable,
it can still be worth telling because it shows
your account as authentic and human.
You can make a story honestly of anything.
Selling makeup?
OK, let's say you post a photo of a mix
of makeups that you have on someone.
You can tell the story of the model putting it on.
You can talk about how you discovered this mix, you can
tell stories about customers that love the combination,
you can tell stories about frustrated people you know who
can't figure out makeup, and then used this, I don't know,
there's a lot of options.
Let's say your account is, I don't know,
let's say it's for promoting events.
You can show a photo of an event.
OK, now, in the caption, tell a story of something that
happened at the event, something that happened at
the last event, the prior one,
something funny someone said, why you started
the event or why the founder started it,
how you discovered the event, how the event usually
progresses, whatever, there's a lot of options.
If they're interested in your account there's
a good chance they'll care about this.
Maybe you're a logo designer and
you're showing off your logos.
Tell them what you were thinking of with the design,
what it reminds you of,
and hey, if there's anything personal in there about why you
love a certain color or how it evokes a certain memory.
That's always a plus, because people like comments that
show you're human and not just some corporate account.
So there's an infinite number of things that you can write about.
You're the person who came up with the post.
So what do you think is interesting about the piece?
Chances are, that's what other people will also find interesting.
At a minimum put something valuable in the caption.
A story, an anecdote, a fact, a funny comment.
It gives them two reasons to like the photo.
They can like the photo or like the caption.
Now, let's talk about some tips and tricks that
can really help you to bump up your captions.
These are my favorite things worth doing.
Now, the first thing is to be aware of
what your text wall looks like.
No one likes a block of text with no spaces or visual breakup.
Break up your thoughts in easy to read chunks.
My favorite thing to do is even put line breaks in
the post to break up what they're reading. I might
have a couple sentences intro, then a line break,
then a list of five things I thought were interesting,
or tips for whatever. To do a line break, write your
post again in Notes, or if you're an Android person,
I think you can do it really on anything that takes notes.
Before we did a Google doc. Evernote, for example, you put underscores for your lines and then copy that back into Instagram.
Next thing, sometimes your post might go on and on,
and that's perfectly fine, but if you're going to do
that, consider putting periods to make
each line break instead of a blank space.
That way, Instagram randomly blocks
off your text below the screenfold,
sometimes users might not know that the
rest of the message actually keeps on going.
And you'll notice a lot of people do this.
Tip number three, don't ever put hashtags
in your caption, just don't do it.
Looks awful and makes you kind of look
like you have no idea what you're doing.
You put them in the comments, and
that's, well, we'll talk about that later.
Tip number four, if you don't have anyone to
tag in your caption, then tag yourself at the end.
So it says @ your own username as
the last thing on the caption. Now why?
Because a lot of people who don't follow you will read
the post, and if you wrote a decent caption, there's
a good chance they'll click through that tag to your profile.
That's what we want and that's how we get people to
like multiple photos and follow us more frequently.
You can tag yourself in the photo, but no one
really sees that. Tip number five and the last one,
believe it or not, you can put website URLs in your comments.
Yes, you can just write the name of
your website in there if you so please.
It's just not going to show up as a clickable link, which
means that fewer people will actually go to it,
But hey, who cares?
Any attention is better than none.
So, for instance, if you go to foreverjobless, that account, you
can see that Billy does this in pretty much every post, and
I think for the most part it works. All right, in the resources
we've attached captions that we think are worth
reading, at least for inspiration. You'll generally find that
popular accounts have a special style for their captions.
Kind of their signature.
That's a big reason they grew a following to begin with.
Now that's enough for now.
Tell a story, be valuable, and don't be lazy and brief.
Break up information so it's easy to read and try things like
tagging yourself or linking to your site.
Also, never ever put hashtags in your caption.
That is what makes puppies cry.
All right.
See you next lecture.