Hey guys, welcome back.
OK.
Last lecture, we created a Google sheet where we set up
a little framework for collecting and sorting accounts
that are in our space and therefore worth knowing about.
In this lecture, we're going to add
two more things worth sorting by.
So, first off, I want to mark accounts that I consider
worth watching. This could be an account that posts
similar content to you,
it could be one that has an interesting
content strategy just in general,
maybe they interact with their users in a way that
you think is effective or unique, maybe they just
have a great content mix, or just post really high quality
stuff, or hey, I don't know, maybe they're just popular.
These are all reasons that you might want to watch
an account. Later on, when you're stuck or just feel
the need for inspiration,
you'll have a list of go-tos that you can
check in with and see what they're posting.
So take a second to mark these in some way.
You could put like an extra column and then put
an X in it, or you could just highlight them.
Doesn't really matter.
Just some way you can remember them later.
This might require going back to the
accounts and then looking at them.
But honestly, if they didn't stick out to you in the first
place, then they might not be worth watching.
So the next thing I want you to do after that
is add a column and label it "complementary."
What we want to do with this is we want to mark accounts
that we think, number one, don't compete directly with us,
and number two, have stuff that we think our audience might like.
If we're using the travel app example, for instance,
someone who posts, let's say, tips about flying
would probably be targeting a similar enough
audience - frequent flyers or travelers.
Now, would someone who cares about travel tips
also enjoy funny photos of airplane mishaps?
Yeah, probably. One in the space that's not complementary
might be, you know, those people that are posting
luxury first class section photos, those are probably
first class flyers or people who want luxury porn,
so showing them photos of things that happened in the class
they don't want to fly in probably isn't what they want.
They pay in general to avoid that stuff,
they pay a lot of money too.
So try your best to make that critical judgment for these accounts.
The reason we're doing this now is that so when we
get to the marketing portion of the course, we can
hit the ground running.
One of the fastest ways to grow on Instagram is through
what are called shoutouts, which we'll explain way
more in depth later on, but they require
complementary accounts to work with.
Marking them now puts them in your head and hopefully
will help you build relationships now, so that
later the promotion partnership is way easier.
OK, go ahead and mark these,
and I'll see you in the next lecture.