All right guys, welcome back.
So this lecture, what we're going to do is we're going to talk
about five different ways that you can up your comments.
Now, why do we care about comments?
Well, comments are one of the criteria that Instagram
uses in their algorithm. We don't know if comments
are as important as likes, or views, or saves,
but we do know that they're very important.
Typically speaking, if you look at
hashtag pages, look at the top posts,
those usually have a lot of comments.
Now, I don't know if that's indicative of just being a
high engagement post in general, but we know that
there's a correlation between comments
and better treatment by Instagram.
Also worth pointing out that these five are not comprehensive.
There's a lot of different strategies
you can use to up your comments.
These are just the five that worked for me.
If you guys have something that worked for you, post
in the Q&A or the Slack and say what worked. I'm not
saying those don't work, I'm just saying this worked for me.
So the first one, and this is actually something we kind
of mentioned before, is respond to every single
comment you get.
It's very, very easy, especially at the very beginning,
when you're only getting 5 to 10 comments.
Just go through and get in the habit
of responding to each one.
Now, the reason why is pretty obvious.
This doubles your comments, and this does count
towards your engagement. Instagram doesn't care if it's
you commenting or the other person,
the random person, commenting,
they still give you a bump, so that's what we care about.
There's also a secondary benefit of if you respond,
a lot of times people respond back to you,
so now instead of one comment you now have three.
The way I generally handle this is I just get in the habit of
responding maybe twice a day. If you're using Iconosquare,
it's pretty easy to go and just go to their "Manage comments"
section and you can kind of do it all in one place
there, it's really hard to respond to people on the web version,
so you kind of have to do it with your phone, that's a pain,
that's why I usually use Iconosquare.
Now, what do you do with the people that comment
and they're obviously just like mass follower accounts
or maybe they're just really unoriginal commenters?
A lot of people respond with just an emoji, like a thumbs up.
I usually just respond back with another emoji.
That's it. If they put a thumbs up,
give them an OK signal or give them a thumbs up. If it's
the case that they responded with just a set of emoijs,
I usually respond with a set of emojis, it takes
really no time at all and I usually just kind of have
a habit of dishing it back to them whatever they gave to me.
So number two strategy I use for upping comments is to always
respond, if you can, when this is relevant, with a question.
Okay.
Now, this is obviously different than
just responding to every single person,
but when you can, try to respond with a question.
So if someone says, you know, on Innovation Station
we get this a lot, someone will say like "This innovation
is bad because [...]."
So a lot of times I'll just respond with "Why?" or "Why
do you think that?" You know, "This is what I think.
What do you think would happen if...?" You don't
really have to put a lot of thought into this, honestly.
People love answering questions, so it's really simple.
The benefit here is that you can start a thread of
comments really easily, especially if you're on the
ball and you're checking this at least twice a day.
It's very easy to get one person to respond like
10 times, and also increases the likelihood that
they'll comment on the next post and hang around,
and that's how you kind of start snowballing support
within your page and getting higher
and higher comment counts.
Number three has to do with the call to action in your caption.
Now, a lot of your success with comments comes down to your call to action, and I am the first to admit that at Innovation Station
we don't have as many comments as we should have
we're probably below baseline, and that's mainly because
I haven't spent a lot of time trying
to optimize the call to action posts.
So if you are looking at the follow along section, you
can kind of see that. We still get a lot of comments,
but it's not really what you would expect, I think,
although our engagement rate's still very high.
So what you can do in those calls to action is use
something that frequently gets people to respond.
Now, there's two examples that I like, because
these always seem to get people to respond.
So like, number one is a fill in the blank statement.
So you could say "My favorite food is [...]" or "My favorite thing
about this post is..." and then people just fill in the blank.
Basically, the idea here is that you're trying to lower
the bar as low as possible for the commenter.
People are lazy, and honestly, unless they feel really
strongly about making a comment, they're not going to.
So if you set it up for them, "Hey,
this is fun, I can just add in my word."
It's kind of like playing... not Mad Gabs, but it's like
Cards Against Humanity, where you literally
fill in a gap and people have fun with that.
Now, another way of doing it is a preference test.
So if you post something, you can easily
just say ,"Do you like it or not? Tell us why."
And people, again, love to state their opinions.
Keep that in mind.
People love talking about what they like, why,
and they just love talking out loud
to themselves, so facilitate that.
You also notice that some people's
entire posting strategy is around this.
They'll post two things and say, "A or B?
Which one do you like better?"
Coke or Pepsi kind of thing.
And typically, it's a very successful tactic.
Number four, this is something I sometimes use, is you
can offer to shoutout the best comment on each post.
So what you'd say at the very end is just "Shoutout to the
best comment" or "Shoutout to the top two comments"
and then all you have to do is, once you pick whoever the
best comment is, maybe the next day, doesn't really matter,
you could either do one of two things. One, in the
next post, you could say "Shoutout to" and then tag
them, and people love that, or you can just edit the
post that they actually commented on and then put
their names at the very end.
It's fairly simple, but people like social recognition.
It's a big reason why Patreon is popular, because
a lot of YouTube creators will do Patreon
campaigns and they'll say "Hey, if you pay me
$10 a month, I'll put your name on the screen."
That's really enticing to a lot of people.
And the last one that's worked for me, number five,
is tagging a friend. So what you do at the very end is
you just say "Tag a friend who" and it could be "who would
like this," "who would need this," "who would want this,"
"tag a friend who this reminds you of." The reason
why this ups your comments is it just brings
more people into the thread. So they tag someone,
well, that's one comment, but then if the friend responds,
that's another, and sometimes you can get these
people to go back and forth having conversations,
and even you can have third party people jumping into
these conversations.
The whole point is you're just racking up comments by doing this.
All right, guys.
Those are the five.
Number one, make sure you respond to everyone.
Number two, when you can and it's relevant, ask a question
in return instead of just a standard statement response.
Number three is use some type of call to action
that is really easy for them to participate in, like
a preference test or a fill in the blank.
Number four and number five, we're
offering shoutouts for the best comments
- people love social recognition -
and the other one is asking people directly to tag their
friends, it brings more people into the comment thread,
that just means more people
are going to comment and you win.
All right, guys.
See you in the next lecture.