Hey guys welcome back.
OK.
This lecture that we're going to do is Rafal long as I set up our Instagram live giveaway.
Now the idea here is that I'm going to try to give away something I did a poll earlier.
What people want an eco dot or a instax six Polaroid camera people one of the Echo datt.
So what I'm going to do and because we're a themed account we're kind of limited right now.
This is a personal account I just flipped over my phone and just start talking to it or do a Q and A.
Or something like that.
And if I was a business.
Yeah I kind of do the same thing like a tutorial or a walkthrough but my face isn't really on this as
it seemed to count right.
So it's kind of anonymous which means what I'm going to try to do is do my Instagram live by pointing
it directly at an iPad mini.
So I have an iPad mini.
It's been sitting on my shelf for quite some time I don't know why I own it.
And what I'm going to do is just create an image on Kanva and then I'm just going to point the camera
at that.
Now the reason why I'm using this iPad is just because it has a vertical screen and and lives there
are always going to in portrait mode so it makes it a little bit easier.
But you could absolutely do this just with your computer.
You could even do it with a piece of paper.
I've seen people do that you can just get creative It doesn't really matter because again it's alive.
So it's not supposed to be high production quality.
And this is the first time I'm doing this so keep in mind there'll be some kinks.
OK so on my iPad I have Kanva downloaded and then I have a blog graphic because it's a portrait size.
And when I save this on an open as a photo I can zoom in to kind of make it fit the screen.
It's not going to be perfect but as long as people can read it we should be fine.
OK so first off we need an image for the Amazon echo.
And really if I was doing this was maybe a little more prepared what I would do is do multiple screens
like the first screens like the giveaways in 15 minutes and then tries to garner some time to get people
to join.
But the problem I'm having is just I don't really know how to swipe between photos to get that going.
I could try though.
So let's go to Google images go images so we can get the Amazon echo image.
To you image.
Great.
Kanva object or blog graphic.
Pull this side thing out.
So what I do is I just get uploads to photos.
OK.
He's accessed my photos.
Great.
OK.
There we go.
Perfect.
Now we have that thing.
Amazon I go there.
OK.
So yeah maybe it will make two different screens.
So it's put some text in.
We're not going to make this match the text from everything else because we don't have all those fonts
is or kind of Instagram fonts.
Great.
Pick a font that doesn't look looks somewhat like it.
So you don't want Abdal fat face on something and actually fits what we were using before
it's copied.
Put the text in here and I'll say
just so I can prime them a little bit to know what it's about to happen to change the font size.
And decorating this stuff was really hard on your iPad.
We will try our best.
So color skillet it like a red color.
And when these pastel Reds OK.
Not brilliant but should be good enough to get the point across.
Right.
So now what I need is a download so Dalen is an image go right.
All right.
That's what it's going to look like.
Right.
So I click it can zoom in like that and that should get the point across.
The Echo looks really pixilated but honestly it's probably just because of the size of the image on
the whole I can do about that.
So maybe I want to maybe shrink the size of it or something.
See how that looks.
A little messy using your fingers.
Fortunately so at download so that make sure it's saved or photos check or photos this is probably a
lot easier if you guys have an android version.
You have a lot more control but you can do it on this one and you can do it on anything.
So that is what will probably start with zoom in like that.
OK.
And then yeah.
So what I'll do is I'll take my phone and pointed at it and all should have an image right here.
You can see kind of set up I was using I'm using this tiny little stand like this that you plug into
your phone.
Props these legs out.
This thing was like.
So I think it is $8 or something.
Ironically on Amazon.
And then what I'll do it I'll just swipe over like that and pension's zoom probably.
And that's pretty much how I run this.
Now it's not going to be pretty but this is a first run out.
If you guys are watching a follow along we'll probably try to perfect this a little bit assuming that
we actually get some followers from it.
That's a big thing too.
So we'll need to check our followers to make sure that we know how many we go into it.
Right now we have 26000 So that's kind of the number to see if that moves because we'll we'll see if
we at least get a couple of hundred from it.
If not then it's probably not worth it but hey it's worth doing.
OK so to take the second one lead it.
So I don't confused.
OK.
Now back to Canada.
We'll give them the actual instructions.
This is something I kind of struggled with.
I wanted to give them like a riddle or something where they it's kind of like hard to answer but the
problem is that the internet ruins everything.
So there's no like a riddle I can ask them that they can't just Google.
So I don't really know how to prevent that.
I think I'm missing let people know that it's going to run for 15 minutes and they won't know who the
first person answer is.
So at the very end of it then I'll say the winner is.
OK.
And I don't know what all this will be hard to do it on the screen as I'm looking at it.
So it be hard to type in like who the winner is most likely have to do it as a post right afterwards
and do they I'll say in that post this is the winner and I'll put in a story.
OK.
I think that's the best way to do it.
I mean if I had a better set up than I could reach over and type it in as it's live you want to make
sure that people in a give away believe what you're doing and believe what you're saying.
So yes.
We'll see.
Right now we're really just kind of demonstrating the bli features.
So that's really the focus.
OK so I'll make one more see.
OK.
So I'll take this text or say
rules
and give them two instructions.
So I'm going to try.
And again this takes a lot of trial there.
Number one is you have to answer this question and then the second thing is they're going to have to
tag people.
OK so what I'm thinking is if you get the answer right and tag as many people say whoever gets the right
tags most people that's who wins.
And I think that the tagging thing hopefully hopefully it's not too tacky and it's something that people
will actually do.
So what I'll say is
then the last thing I'll just be like whoever gets it right.
So
OK.
So there's a little bit smaller
to this.
Twenty eight
OK so then I'll at the riddle.
I need to just copy this and then make it really small.
So I pulled up a riddle just online.
It's a tech.
It's kind of lame but I don't know what riddle they can't just look up.
That's the biggest problem I have.
So
OK so I think that's relatively easy to read.
Just do some second changes to make sure it looks like crap.
OK.
That's pretty much it.
I'm going to add is just a name up at the top.
It says what the prize is I'll make this a different color.
It turns out a little bit
OK.
So there we go now and we're going to download this now as an image and we'll check that the image is
OK and then we should be good to go.
Then I'll just be a matter of me setting this up make sure we save it.
So hopefully what it will look like like that and I'll have to just reach over Penge over this.
There we go.
Well position like that.
OK.
So that's hopefully what will look like.
You'll see how this works.
I will save the Instagram wise and we'll upload it.
Hopefully nothing falls apart.
Hopefully this works out I can figure it out but you will learn from my mistakes either way.
All right.
See you then.