Hey guys welcome back to this lecture are going to do is we're going to post a story on innovation station
just to kind of go through the motions or show you what it's like now the next lecture We'll talk about
our story strategy at innovation station and how it's kind of evolved over time it's changed a couple
of times but we're just going to use stories to fulfill a purpose.
So what we'll do is we'll just go to the app and what I'm thinking is I'm thinking about trying some
giveaways later this week.
And if you guys want to check out the giveaway section there is a section on it in this course.
And in order to do that I thought it would be interesting just to run a poll and a story to ask people
what they wanted as a giveaway since we're just a cool tech account.
There's a lot of like small gadgety things and I think it's pretty important to get some feedback beforehand.
Before I go and pick something that nobody wants and no one participates.
So what I'll do is just go over the home screens operate and get into my story mode then I create an
image over here.
So my idea was I was going to give this instax 6 away or this Amazon echo and they're both kind of equal
value.
So I was kind of curious what people cared about more.
I don't know if the tide has kind of gone out on Amazon Eco's or if people didn't know what these instax
Polaroid cameras are anyway so I made this image in Photoshop.
All it did is I just took two images.
Google Image searched through them together and then put a white background is really easy you could
do it in Kanva to some people.
For some reason you can add multiple images to their stories.
It was a feature that's on some accounts maybe Android accounts can do it.
I can't seem to figure out how to do it.
It might have been an older version of Instagram so I had to just make the image myself which is not
that big of a deal it took me two seconds.
OK.
So this is what I have and then I will do as I will right at the top giveaway and then I'll give them
the date.
So it's a good.
Change it to something that doesn't look like crap.
Sort of background like that.
So give away and then I'll put the day underneath it.
So I see six.
OK.
So Saturday timber eight and I'll say 3 three.
So put that right there.
Change the color of that sticks out in a red you know as I twisted it twice showing it like that.
So I could twist it in a little bit larger.
The easiest thing in the world to do.
But there you go.
OK.
So Saturday September 8 3 p.m. I should really put the time zone in it just because other people don't
know what it is to change this to.
Same color shrink.
Oh boy I'm really stretching my fingers here and put it there.
Ok cool.
So give away and then we're going to do is put a pole in the middle so we'll put a pole you remember
I can change the question and the answer.
So which one do you prefer.
You prefer a question mark and I'll put it simply echo.
Got the swan instax 6 Hopefully they know what these are.
If they don't who knows sea so can't really change the color unfortunately.
But what I can do is I can put something behind it.
So what I'm going to do actually because I can't see it in the background as I'm trying to get rid of
the tax of the top and I write that out.
So we see some of issues here.
So I put it there.
So trying to put this so it doesn't block judges.
If I had to redo this I would put some spacing in between these.
So I think that's decent.
I mean it cuts off the image of the instax which is not a deal.
So I can do it like death with the text in the middle.
The voting down at the bottom.
And then I'll draw like an arrow see or something that I can point it out with.
So am going to use like this.
So pull down an arrow pointing at it that way they can't forget and just throw some moseys on there
just to make it look more festive.
I don't know.
So put some confetti.
OK.
So give away Saturday September at 3:00 p.m. Yes.
Which one you prefer.
So I don't think there's anything else that I need to do with this one or that so it doesn't have any
volume on it.
I didn't have any volume going with.
And then we just go to send to and we'll go to our sharing options for a story and then we'll go to
share to our story.
And that is pretty much it.
So it's safe just in case you know exit out great here and I should be able to see it go OK.
So give away Saturday September.
Which do you prefer.
And then what they can do is just click to one they prefer.
So it's easy to show up at the end of our post today.
There you go Sarah someone one of the unstacked six.
There we go.
Now it's 100 percent OK.
And then what I can do is later on when I actually gotten votes from people I can just pull up the analytics
on it.
So scroll to it and then go to the give.
And as you can see it always shows a one person seen it perfectly fine.
But yeah.
So that was pretty easy right.
It's a great way of getting engagement with people.
It's a great way of reminding people that hey we're going to do a giveaway on Saturday and it's a really
quick easy way to get them involved.
Hopefully people actually will mark down the date for the give away.
It was kind of a secondary purpose but I just showed you how easy it is to make something like that.
The only problem was just putting the images together.
I just did it on the computer really fast.
You can just do it by phone.
Go to Google Images find something throw it on there and then throw in some tax and it's pretty easy
to make it look decent.
You know I don't think this is fantastically great but this is exactly what you'd expect in a story.
All right.
So guys that's it for now.
The next lecture will do is it will go over the innovation station story strategy and I'll give you
a little bit of background on what we do for our stories.
See that.