All right guys welcome back.
So this lecture we're going to go over a giveaway that we did on Saturday for innovation station.
Now have you guys watched the Instagram live section.
It's a little bit redundant.
It kind of went over how to make this work for Instagram live give away but we didn't have to do it
necessarily as an Instagram live give away we were just trying to do that because we thought that was
a little more interesting at the moment.
Instagram lives get a lot of attention because they pop up on everybody's screen and it's like a push
notification to get their attention.
That's kind of why I went that way.
But you could do it as a story or you can even just do it as a regular post.
OK so this was the general route we were going technology account so I wanted to give something away.
I also wanted to make sure that whatever I gave away was under $50 I also wanted to make sure that whatever
gave away it wasn't something that's actually interesting.
Right.
So I picked Amazon echo Daut which are the tiny Amazon Alexa devices.
And then the instax 6 x 6 is a kind of handheld like New-Age Polaroid.
So you take a photo and it prints out a Polaroid image right on the spot.
They're very popular.
OK.
So what I did was about two days before I posted a story exactly like you're seeing right now or I put
an image of both of them and I said Which one do you prefer.
Now I use this as just a way to announce that hey we're going to give a give away and I want to make
sure that everyone has a say and that whatever I give away is going to be popular.
I don't want to give away the camera.
No one wants it because even if they're there when I start to give away they're not going to participate.
So I just set this up and it had a little though down at the bottom that was pretty simple and I set
a defined day and time when it was going to happen.
So I said Saturday September 8 3pm p.m. Yes.
Make sure you get the time zone.
So that's what it looked like when it was running as an actual story.
OK after a day 24 hours of voting it looked like 58 percent said Ecko.
I think I had about 100 people participate and say that they preferred that once not a strong preference
but again they spoke with their words therefore I use that as a way to get more attention and then what
I did was I reposted the results.
That's pretty easy to do because all you have to do is when you post a story go over to insites in your
account and then go to content and then you can go down to your stories it see all and then find the
one where they voted on it.
So this is pretty easy to just give away and then scroll up OK.
And then only share results.
So that was easy.
So I got to hit them twice with the same thing.
So on day one I said Which one do you prefer.
They told me the next day I said here are the results so it reminds them again this is coming up now
in two days.
Then what I did is I ran a story the next day promoting that it was indeed going to happen.
So then I posted another story and a Post the day of just to give people a heads up like hey it's coming
right now.
What I said is I said give away a lie and 45 minutes that I had a hash tag just so it gets more visibility
than I tagged myself.
Just so if they're reading the story then click that to go to my account and then I put the date on
I'm giving away.
And then I said live in 45 minutes and I did that just as a reminder because oftentimes people use Instagram
will use it for 20 30 minutes at a time.
So if they're using it right now and it's going to happen in 45 minutes that might be enough for them
to hang on and stay for 45 minutes at least know to check their phone in 45 minutes.
That was the strategy I went with.
I did this is a story and as a post when I got to the actual give away this is what I did I actually
just filmed my iPad screen.
As you can see and I put give away starts in five minutes it will give instructions to complete the
first version do so wins.
And the reason why I did this was because it was in scrammed live you can't use static images on screen
live.
You got to actually just put it next to a screen if you want to do that.
That's not generally on the screen lives for.
But you know in the future it might be the case that they have some way of doing this.
Now I did this saying give away starts in five minutes because I wanted people to pile into the live.
So when you're doing a live you can see the live counter of how many people are watching.
So you don't immediately just go in and start the competition or the giveaway because someone might
figure it out very quickly and anybody else who joins it maybe five minutes later isn't going to want
to participate.
So I said give away starts five minutes in everyone kind of pooled together started commenting started
liking.
And that allowed me to essentially start ranking higher on the tech giveaways hash tag page.
Ok then what I did was I literally just flipped the page to the next set of instructions and that's
how I ran the competition like so.
And I set the competition rules like this.
That was the prize.
I said the rules.
What Adam do is two things to answer a riddle in the comments and the riddle unfortunately was just
it was something you could have googled.
That was kind of all of the problems I need to think of a riddle that has an answer that you can't find
online because that's pretty much the easiest thing in the world learning how to think about it.
So ideally I would have designed that one better than it's as tag as many friends count as you can.
Now I didn't specify what different account was.
That was a mistake.
I should have specified this is someone you know or someone who follows you or something like that then
I just said we're going to run this for 15 minutes.
Whoever gets the correct anti-X most people wins Amazon Ecko I didn't do it just because I didn't do
it.
Just saying get this answer correct and you win because then it would have been over in a minute.
Let's ask you the hard question which you don't know until you actually watch it.
Then the second thing was that you had to tag as many people as possible.
So let's say in the first five minutes everybody gets the answer right.
Then you have 10 minutes to see how dedicated you are to attack as many people to bring them into the
chat rooms bring their attention to your account.
That was the idea at least.
OK now we can look at the stats from when we did the promotion to see how that worked out.
So if you go to a Konno Square we can kind of look at the followers graph.
So you go to analytics community so follower growth and then oh this.
So it was on the 8.
OK.
So you know this right here we gained 189 followers that day.
Now in order to decide whether or not this was worth it it's really hard to tell because there is a
lot of moving parts.
We had just downshifted our posting strategy to using new content.
We didn't know if it was going to do really well.
And then immediately after we switched back to top 10 percent of engagement quality posts and then all
of a sudden you know it's more and more people are falling so really hard to say how many of these hundred
89 would have came normally.
The best thing you can do is kind of just get a weekly average or a daily average over the last month
and then use that as a baseline and see whether or not you went above that I would say that probably
we gained last maybe a hundred followers maybe yeah maybe $75 is probably a good guess.
Now $75 worth $50.
No not in the slightest.
But like I said before this is something that you do repeatedly and at first it's not really something
that has a great R-N.Y.
Typically the people that do really good giveaways do it every single week the same exact time so everybody
knows when to show up and they know that it's a set routine and eventually they get to a point where
you can kind of automate these without having to sit there and you know manage the whole thing right
you'll come up with a an ask from your followers and apprise such that you don't really have to do a
lot of management.
Like for instance I said that at the end of 15 minutes we'll say who wins based on the riddle and then
based off of how many people they tag because I didn't want to sit there for 15 minutes and watch people
and tally it up I just did it so that later I could come back and check in and see.
And in our live we got something like 200 people in it.
So the next time I ran it would be kind of the number to beat right.
My guess is probably got $75.
So we obviously optimize that.
The second thing is how many live count like people in the actual live.
Could we get.
And that would be another way of measuring whether or not we're improving.
What I did immediately after it ended because I didn't want people to freak out about not knowing where
the competition was or who won.
I did a quick story that said Thank you everyone who didn't give away.
And I just did that by going to the text.
If you go to your camera and there's different types of cameras you can use the far left is text so
you can just type this out really quickly and it's great for dashing out a message.
Then the next one said we are watching the video to see who won and it is incredibly tedious.
I'll be honest so you can do this repeatedly.
Figure out a strategy for how to figure out who the winner is.
Otherwise you'll drown.
Did what I did as I posted a regular post in case they didn't see the story and said Give us a sec we'll
announce the winner shortly.
Made this in quite literally 10 seconds using the tools that we covered in the story section.
Then when it is I found the winner it was the winner.
This guy only has one follower.
This is what happens often times you giveaways not competitions.
You get a lot of kind of low quality participants but it's fine.
And then what it is I just took a screen cap of his account and I just wrote winner and then said Will
D.M. you and I tagged him so that he would get notified of the you automatically get a direct message.
Then what I did is I made a post where I post that as well and I tagged two of the people who were the
follow ups.
The people who came closest to winning besides the winner just so I could get their attention so they
wouldn't leave thinking that this was a complete scam.
This is kind of what the page winds up looking like.
And then I left those up for maybe 12 hours just so that everybody who potentially came in contact with
it saw it and then I ended up deleting them and we went back to our typical post composition.
All right guys that's pretty much the summary of the giveaway we did.
If you want to watch it in live action go to the Instagram live section.
You can watch me do it there.
But really what we learned is that we've got about 200 people into the live for the give away and we
spent about fifty six dollars on an Amazon echo and only got about 75 followers.
So it's like one and a quarter followers per dollar spent which is not very good in general.
Typically if you do a promotion inside the app you can get two to one three to one.
You do a shout out even like a page shout out you get like five to one sometimes even you're really
lucky.
Ten to one.
So from our allies standpoint not great but the jury's still out because this is something that you
have to do as a consistent strategy so keep that in mind.
All right guys see the next lecture.