All right guys welcome back.
So in this lecture what we're going to do is show you the truly automated way of doing outreach for
collaboration.
We did do that using the tool called Jarvi that I explained in the zombies section and it might have
covered it in the advanced hashtags section.
But either way you should have this set up if you haven't done this go back to the zombie section and
watch how to set this up.
Jeremy if you forgot runs on a virtual server.
Now if you have a Windows PC you can run it on your computer but you have to leave your computer open
the entire time.
That's not realistic.
We're trying to do a 24/7 strategy so I covered how you can open up a very three US account and set
this up very easily so it will just go to the account that I have automatically set up and it looks
like this.
All right I don't get overwhelmed by all the options on Jarvi.
It's a lot.
And we covered it a bit in the zombie section.
So if you're unfamiliar I'd go and check that out again.
Really kind of just breaks down in these sections right here at the dashboard just shows you that it's
working.
Social profiles is where you hook up all of your accounts so we have a lot of zombie accounts on here.
And also innovation sation is on it as well as you can see right there.
And then you have things like tools Gobal tools settings proxy manages my account proxy meaning it doesn't
really matter because I'm using my main account settings doesn't really matter and I really could touch
that same with global tools where we care about here is tools.
OK once we are tools and we see all of our accounts just go to your main account which you should have
hooked up at this point if you haven't then go through the process we covered before and hook it up.
All you have to do is go to social profiles and then add profile you add your information and it's really
as simple as that.
To go back to Tools click on your main account.
All right now here we have all of those tools at Jarvi gives us some it's kind of overkill iks can't
use them all.
But what we're going to do specifically is we're going to use the section right here called contact
right now in contact we have it set up into six different sections.
Now what contact is for is for automatically contacting people.
Right.
So as we covered it before in the lecture we hired someone to do this.
The whole idea is we need to find accounts to match a certain criteria and then we need to automatically
message them.
OK.
So the Jervy we're going to have their system automatically find them and automatically message them
we're going to set parameters such that it doesn't get out of control.
So what you do here is you always start over on the far left with extract users or auto extract and
then what's going to happen is then you're going to set the message that gets sent to them here and
they use extracted users and then work and ignore the send message you follow because that's not we're
going to find people and an auto reply to new messages.
Again that doesn't matter to us because we're doing an outreach strategy.
We're not trying to get accounts to follow us and then message them.
And then the last thing is send messages.
That's where he said all of your main criteria for how to run this.
So we'll go to extract users and extract users the way that this works is it's a manual tool.
OK.
What we do is we tell it how many accounts we want are out there and then we give it some parameters
for what to pull another way that this works is you type it in kind of programmatically.
So if for instance I wanted to pull all of the people who follow.
And so the example is Barack Obama I put following slash Barack Obama I'd hit extract users.
And then what would happen is they would start compiling them over here and use extract users.
So we would see total rate here start to increase.
You can also do it ways like through Leiker So people who like posts from Barack Obama people who comment
on his post.
But you can also do things like people who comment on a specific post or people that tag a certain post
or even just specific users if you know them or even if you want to target the people who watch your
own story views.
That's great but that's not how we're going to do it.
Now if I was trying to think where can I find a lot of accounts that potentially are the right size
that post about technology or innovation.
Well I probably go after hash tag search right so hash tag search meaning if I type in this hash tag
it can give me all the users either post or interact in that area.
And again it doesn't really matter because as long as they give it the criteria of the size of the account
it's going to get rid of all the random people that we don't care about.
So for us we're going to say hash search slash and then we're going to give it.
And then say innovation.
OK so that was one of our biggest ones.
So let's say yeah give me 50.
We're just in to this as a test to make sure we have it right.
Then we're going to the auto extract.
Now now here we have similar criteria that we can set that we set before when we are doing follow backs
and auto follows.
So do want to skip non-English names.
Yes.
Because we only want English speaking people in our account.
Otherwise there are going to be able to appreciate our content skill or engagement right.
There's a number of followers and it follows that a specific range.
This is essentially the jackpot.
This is what we really want to focus on and make sure you do it.
So right here it says the number of followers do we really care about followings.
Well I don't know that's kind of hard to say.
So what we'll do is the same criteria used before so we'll say minimum is 15000 and then the maximum
is going be that 75 in the range then for the wings.
Well we might want to keep this below a certain amount just to make sure it's a real account.
It's not an account that's just catering to mass followers.
So the ratio really we really actually do care about it so on the low end let's say if it's 15000 then
I wouldn't want someone of 15000 to have more than say 2000 followers and it's 75000 again 8000 followers.
Is that still pretty liberal.
If they have that many followers It means that they're clearly using follow boughts which is fine.
It just means that they're not doing a very good job of it.
Ok then I can look for things like user bio or must contain any of the following words I could do this
if I wanted to say something like technology like innovation like iPhones or something like that.
But for me I don't really care enough to do that because I'd have to put a lot of keywords to get a
good spread and I have to keep coming back here to figure out what keywords you've already exhausted
which I don't really want to do.
And then you can do some you know doesn't have certain keywords.
We can look for people with a minimum number of posts that could be important.
Right.
So I might say that one just because it might be the case you find an account that has 75000 people
on it but they only post it 10 times and that just means that they bought all of their followers so
we might want to be a little more discerning with this.
But again remember there are accounts that don't post that many because they delete them and repost
them.
But I think typically like 50 is a good low baseline to go for.
OK now down here we have other ones like Skipp business counts.
No it doesn't really matter.
Skip account to the Web site now again and we don't really care about any of these.
These are all perfectly fine extract only doesn't really matter.
We don't know and we care about his languages.
Great.
OK.
So now we're going to run the extraction just to see if it seems to work.
Then we'll extract users get it then it's going to post down here and it says The link is going we have
our search innovation it's a status pending.
OK so it says it's a system we just kind of have to wait for it to do it.
But in the meantime we can set up our auto extract.
We always go back and check that once it's done.
So with auto extraction we would do the same thing we did over here.
But again remember try to test this out a couple of times just to make sure that you're getting the
right group of people.
So we might say hash tag search ovation and then we can always add another one if we want to like hash
tag search so we can say like future is Twan Ashtar search could say like cool science maybe try that.
OK.
Now since it's automatic We just have to tell it when it needs Iran so we could say run extraction daily
at a specific time or an extraction every whatever.
And then how many do we want over time what time they extract it.
Well this is just something again you're gonna have to work on and tailor my experience.
You can have it run.
Let's just say run every 24 hours I that's perfectly fine and say get.
Well you could.
I'd say 50 is fine because it's going to pull 50 and automatically message 50 so is it OK to auto contact
50 people in a day.
Yeah that's normal if your auto contacting 200 there might be a problem unless you were really really
doing this laser targeted.
So again since we're doing the autocrats will use the same tools that we use before they skip on those
names on a set the same settings here
OK.
So now that we have that we can go ahead and start the extraction process and what it should do is start
compiling a list which we can then use and use extracted users.
OK.
So let's go ahead and run it.
All right so gives us the same message had before it says pending.
But it has three different ones this time.
OK.
While we're waiting on these to actually extract their users can take anywhere from 10 minutes to an
hour.
Not really sure.
Kind of just depends if Jarvi is doing other things at the moment so we can set up this section right
here.
So typically the way it works here is it'll say Click here to start attracting users.
So your group names should show up once these start extracting and then you can just select them then
you have to do is add a message like Should users.
Now it has this crazy thing called Spin tax and know what it is you can use these keywords right here
to make the message sound like it's much more personalized.
And also the more you use it the more different your messages will be which means that to Instagram
it looks like you're less likely to be a bot because bots just send the same message over and over again.
So I might just say like hey and then fullname is not good because he's a business account so doesn't
it make sense like a human wouldn't say that.
So I just say something like you know and then I'll say their username and then I might say something
like I think our audiences would enjoy each other's posts.
And I'll just say I want to do a story shout for a shout and then I want to jumpstart this process what
I could do is actually just automatically link them to a video that I would use for a story shout out
and then I can just say like here's the video.
So if they wanted to go ahead and do it that already starts the process for me so I actually kind of
like doing that.
So I'll go to my Dropbox and look at the story that I had before on and that was this one
which is moderately effective.
So I'll just try to use that one.
So click share and I'll copy my link over to here.
I'm going to throw it into a short answer.
Just for simplicity's sake doesn't look like gobbledygook of information although be careful with it.
With these you are as short answers.
It might look like you're spamming someone so just keep that in mind.
So go to him and say OK.
So then I can tell them like here is my story.
Maybe you're wrong.
I just put something in the very end that just says send me a video or a post I can use if you want
to do something like that and then obviously I will try to monitor this and improve this over time so
I get a message that's more appealing.
It might be even simpler just to send someone else for ass write articles to help her out.
Sure you know you can make it as simple as possible.
I'll try this first and then see how it goes.
Never want to I could just send them the video.
Now that is just kind of a pain.
I'm not entirely sure if I want to do that because automating it like that might throw off the red flags
of Instagram.
You're sending videos to everybody so just kind of keep that in mind.
You do things like send secondary messages so like for instance if after 24 to 40 hours they have not
responded.
So I say send only if the user has not replied.
Then it'll send a secondary message and if I want to set a secondary image it edit and it will just
be.
I'll just say look interested.
Just as a nice reminder.
If not no worries.
There you go.
OK so now I have a secondary message in automatically.
If they don't respond and then I want to make sure that I don't message the same people twice to remove
the selected user after they click send and then ignore users received the message up automatically
send messages.
You know I already know.
OK.
OK so that's set up.
So it's already started pulling names up here.
Looks like we have 6 and this is coming from the manual one we did.
And then all we can do is see this one only pulled three from Cool Science.
OK that's fine.
I mean it's we're using very strict criteria so I might have to add more and more to that to get enough
people so that I can just click select all and then I'll do add to send messages list.
OK so $9 them and sent to said message.
Now the last part is we go here to send messages and we want to set up our criteria so that it does
this correctly and then we wanted to make sure that we monitor how it works.
Sorry your queues up all the messages that are going to be sent.
That's great so we see that this is working now we just need to get our criteria appear correct and
then go from there.
So what I want to do is make sure that it waits between well only when X message say 40 to 50 people
a day.
So choice between 10 and 30 minutes.
Yeah it probably should message.
Assuming that I'm awake 18 hours makes me want to act like a boss because only bots and messengers every
30 minutes on the 30 minute mark.
So I think yeah 10 to 50 and I'll make a range in there and then send between 1 between message operation.
So I'm fine with that sending multiple.
That's fine just because I think Instagram is used to people doing multiple at once.
That's perfectly normal.
So I say 1 to 5.
The delay of an up this just because I have the luxury of doing that.
So I'll say like a minute to two minutes between.
Because the assumption is like well I would I'd have to go find another account look to their account
for I can message them and then message a maximum of.
Now this is important you want to start really low and then start cranking this up right.
So we'll start it way low like 10 to 15 and then increase each day by 5 until we get that maximum.
I don't want to over 50.
Right so that's a great way of easing into it and scream doesn't like it when one day you just show
up and you're sending hundreds of messages.
This is a good way of keeping this normal.
Ok I didn't even do things like a secondary reply.
How long should we wait when we're sending them back.
I don't think this is going to make a huge difference.
Just because you know it's only sending 50 a day so how many aren't going to respond and.
But you still use the same kind of criteria so I'd probably wait 20 to let's say 45 minutes in between
and when it sends these messages I think it's perfectly fine to send a lot at a time and then put the
delay will raise this up quite a bit and say whatever and then message a maximum and we'll do the same
thing here right.
So this is always going to be less than the other because assuming someone's going to respond so we'll
still lower this down though so we'll say 10 to 15 kind of the same thing and will slowly increase this
one three until it reaches 4 you don't ever want to exceed it.
OK.
Then it says pick a random member instead of the first from the list below.
That doesn't really matter.
Delete pending messages doesn't really matter.
That could just be help you so that you don't bog up your direct messages but at the moment it's not
a huge deal for me.
So I think if the messages are older than like let's say 10 days I think that's going to be well let's
say like five days I think is perfectly fine.
Keep the maximum how any message you have in the pending messages.
It doesn't matter.
I don't want to put a limit on that.
Shorten all your calls from messages doesn't really matter because I've already done that.
Ansen direct messages after whatever.
That's just one way of not looking like your spammy.
But again it's a very strange operation to do to consing go back and delete it and then it's just also
just looks very strange though if you have a system that's sending the message today and deleting 50
messages so it's not always something that I would try to do.
Now I typically like to add in the same intervals you expect from me being awake so you execute between
say 9 a.m. to 2 a.m. OK.
You could randomize it if you wanted to but again it doesn't really matter.
OK so I think that's perfectly fine of 9 messages queued up.
So once this does run I'll check back in with you and then we can look at how it happens.
Well it'll be pretty easy to notice once it starts working as we'll start getting direct messages from
people orrible least see sent messages that I sent to people who were not responding.
I also need to make sure that I check this to make sure that it's running as you can see 7 10.
I'm going to have to add more hash tags.
But other than that this is pretty much the basis of how you set this up.
Look at scenics Archer.