Hey guys welcome back to the course.
OK.
So we are now going to dive in and look at paid shout outs.
Now Target others before paid shout out to you just pay for people to promote you.
This is often the case.
What you'll do when you want to have exposure on an account.
But they have way more followers than you.
I mean oftentimes it'll happen as you do these tradeoffs where let's say they're twice as large as you.
So you do two shout outs for one but sometimes they're just so much larger.
The only way you can do this is paying them.
So let's explore that and wants to do that for innovation station.
So OK this is what I did.
Now I went to three online places so we covered these earlier we had Buy Sell shout outs.
Another one is plug hype dot com and then shout cart dot com.
And I think there's one other big one but these are kind of the major ones.
What I also did is I did direct messaging but look at that in a second.
So what I did a shout cart was I kind of just didn't have a technology section so I specifically just
checked it so that I wouldn't have things like meemies or things like food or lifestyle.
And then I just searched for keyword Tech.
And so what it gave me were four accounts.
So we had this one grain attack extreme PC.
There was this one it showed up and then Tech next.
OK so then what I did is I just kind of looked at each one.
OK so I found those ones I didn't exactly dive into it just yet.
Then I went over and found on by cell shout outs we had brilliant inventions we already had that one
up here and the other one I found them was philosophy of science.
So a little bit of a different angle.
And the science appreciators as opposed to people who just like inventions now on plug hype.
I found 24 hour success and odds about it.
Honestly like plug hype.
The only category they had was remotely relevant was entrepreneurship and everything down here was just
kind of I don't know.
Somewhat relevant.
Usually these are just big Coke machines that just plug quotes onto backgrounds and then just post away.
Some of them are just you know they just reposed fancy things like this one.
So I mean I'm sure I could get some followers from that.
It's just not exactly my knees.
So what I do on the phone was I just went inside to find one account that probably looks like a business
account.
So great entrepreneurs arise out of that is OK.
This obviously is a business account you can see they have an email there.
OK.
So great.
And so then what I basically did was I contacted them.
I didn't actually contact these guys specifically but I hit the next button and it just gives you more
and more and more like them.
And chances are all of these have the same thing going on.
So what I could do is just let's say they wanted to go to Hunter or entrepeneur 100 x success.
Let's see.
And then what I could do is just message and say how much for a show.
OK.
That's really all I was doing.
And so what I came up with were.
See I got responses from three different people.
I said one of them was a smart success quote.
OK.
I just have a shot in the.
What do you want.
Because they say you know specifically what exactly do you want in a story shout out do you want a permanent
shout out.
Or the caption a bio link.
There's a bunch right.
We covered all of those so you need to be specific so I responded let's just say you know told our repots
with the caption tag I have yet to hear from you.
It was an hour ago but I did get prices from inspiring DOS.
They were pretty much ready for this template email so I could get a close shout out where they use
their own photo.
But they put a link to us that's 10 bucks promotion with no link in the bio.
15.
I think that just means that they post one of our posts and then they don't obviously link in the bio.
I don't know how long they leave it up so it's kind of hard to say.
Did they have things like story shout outs with clickable links and if for instance I wanted to promote
a specific product they could link outside to that.
OK so these ones are pretty dang cheap.
And then the other one was entrepreneurs quote.
Turns out it's the same person who runs this.
You can tell by the template.
So the same story really is a little slightly larger account so their prices were slightly larger.
OK so I got some of that information.
That's great and then what I did is I just created an Excel sheet and this is where I started putting
all of my information.
Right.
So I have granite tech and I put the links over here.
PC technical philosophy says Brilliant right for us.
You got to know what it is.
I listed off their followers.
OK.
And you can just usually grab these on the web page so this is my fault of the followers right there.
Sometimes it's not accurate so it's useful to go to their page.
So see granitic right here.
Yeah 194.
So it's accurate.
Not all the time though worth checking so I did that.
Then I just kind of took a guess at what their demographics were.
And sometimes on these pages they'll tell you.
Right.
So it says right here 17 to 24 men and then they post in the morning and that's based on U.S. time zones.
So I took all that information and I inputted it in.
So male younger right after I put it this I just then went and checked to see if any of these accounts
just didn't fit because some of them just don't.
And it turned out that for instance this one that did this is while his prices are reasonable I just
kind of found out that his account right here it's if you look at it you're like oh ok that's cool.
You know people who are interested in cool sites nice photos and you click it and it's all Arabic.
OK.
So no offense to people who speak Arabic.
I just I'm trying to grow an English account so that's not useful to me.
Then I checked the other ones and everything else pretty much checked out some of these are right on
the spot for my audience and their audience and some of these are kind of adjacent related souls so
that they know what I did was I stuck all these into auditor.
I bought it for super useful tool and then got a score for them and also an engagement rate.
OK.
So for instance let's say Grand Attack OK.
Their score was 70 which is good.
And then their engagement rate 2.2 percent.
Right.
And then we can go here and put it all of that just there.
Now 2.2 percent.
We go on engagement is actually good.
OK.
So usually average is 1.5 5 for their category.
So that's good.
Then the scores basically tell me very quickly is that if I promote with them what type to follow is
it made to get.
So if the score is pretty low it means I might get a lot of robot accounts mass followers or just people
who are sporadically active.
So that's something worth keeping in mind.
Now what I did to make a decision or to give myself some clarity here was I put it the following things
I put in their engagement right right here.
I knew what I did is I calculated the expected engagement.
Now we did this calculation before and really all that was and this is napkin math it's not exact.
It's not even remotely what I would expect but it's the only way we can compare them is I took their
followers.
Their engagement rate and that's the expected engagement.
So that just means on average when they post this is what you'd expect on a post.
OK.
So then you can kind of see how this changes.
Right.
All while brilliant inventions is almost a million.
Their engagement rate is really low right.
So it actually makes it a I expect less from them than say like for our success.
This one's slightly.
Let's see.
And then you can also notice now like for instance if this place has seventy four thousand and it's
only 1 percent now then you're not going to get a whole lot from that.
OK then what I did was I put in the cost for a two to four hour shower.
Now I had to find a base line for those.
I had to find some common denominator.
Everybody offer something different some of them only offer story shout outs or some of them.
Only do six hours and 12 hours.
But the most common one I found was they'll give you a two hour three hour or a four hour.
And so I just went and found the price for all of those.
Now one group didn't do that.
The smallest one they could offer was six hours.
So I just kind of shaved it down.
So I took their price which was like 20.
And it was $30 and so I just knocked it down relative to what a three hour would be or a four would
be and that's kind of how I normalized this information here.
OK.
So that's the cost of doing pretty much like the minimum type of post.
And I honestly would not get this expect engagement if it's only for two hours.
These are all based on ones that have been up for probably a while.
So then what I did was I calculated my expected engagement per dollar.
So that was pretty easy.
Then you just take this number divided by this number.
That's how you come up with this.
So per dollar I spend I would expect to see 285 engagements now with them 129 76.
So this really is the number one criteria I could care about.
I want to get the most bang for my buck.
So what is basically tells me is that some of these larger accounts like this one brilliant invention
which is close to a million.
It's terrible bang for your buck.
It's almost a quarter as valuable as the or I would spend for instance grain attack.
Now this data could be off but this is the only way we can really tell before we actually go and then
test them.
Also running an audit on finest inventions.
They have an insanely high engagement rate of five percent.
There are 11 million.
And I was just curious to see what they would have and what their prices would be.
I have to reach out to them on kik.
OK so I went to their profile and they just said here's my email here's my kik and it says a business
for business inquiries so they clearly have this set up so I'll reach out to them.
And once I get that information I'll put that in here.
Once auditor is done calculating extreme PC and tech next week I can input this information.
So tech next 55 for quality.
Three point one for it's actually quite good.
So for them and they come in a roughly like a like number three now I get to try multiple these so don't
really worry they're so cheap that why not.
I mean it's just it doesn't really hurt.
My only concern maybe is getting too many robot accounts because then when you start doing shout to
the people just your score will be lower.
And that's just obnoxious.
It's not a huge deal but we'll see.
And so what I'll try to do also is try to do a mass of one like a big time one and then I'll try to
use some smaller more targeted ones and we can compare them.
Now here I just a shout out results.
What I'm gonna to do is put the name I going to put what I paid them and then I'm going to track for
the period of time that that post was up.
How many followers did I get.
Now I can do that.
Nikonov Square.
And then I can do expected engagement from a peer.
I'll just put it down here and then I can see what the over under was so I can just I can you know how
could it based on how many followers I got or how many Likes and Comments on the post it got.
So now tell me how good the post is.
But this would tell me how many followers I got and then I can just say like was it 20 percent lower
than what I expected 50 percent lower or whatever.
I just have to do it to the baseline and then I can kind of tweak from there.
OK the last thing I would have to do is go and look at each account and what I would want to do is try
to look at their account and then see what post I have that would match them or if I have to make a
new post like extreme PC it's all PCs.
So do I have a post on my account that is similar enough or is somehow about PCs.
I'm going to probably guess.
No.
That's like a hard one to do.
But if I did let's say yeah mean Graham attack.
These are all kind of quirky cool tech.
Now there's actually quite a few of them.
And I would also go to whatever intellects tool we're using I'm using a kind of square and then look
at my most engaging media and liked and commented just to get an idea of what performs in general because
I want to give them a good post good or bad post that I'm just not getting what I pay for.
So those are all the things that you have to take into consideration.
I will go and run these and see how it works out.
Then I will come back here and tell you what the results were.
OK.
Cool.
See next picture.