Hey guys welcome back.
OK so we are on day.
I want to say 21 or 22 something like that.
I might have lost track of that.
Anyway so just checking in to tell you what I've done so far in the last three days I want to say OK
so as you can see we have 157 posts and about fifty nine hundred followers.
Give or take following still pretty loud about a thousand.
So first off what I have done is I've recently switched entirely to posting during the U.S. space times.
Now that's just part of the content strategy.
I want to focus my followers in one general time zone region and then also I just think that U.S. based
accounts are going to be more valuable later when I try to monetize.
And also just probably more interested in what I'm posting.
There's also English base so that also makes sense.
So the way I've done that was by working with someone I think it was South Carolina.
Don't call me on that.
But anyway she has taken over posting from the original person who was in charge of posting.
We're still doing everything in later.
So but what's happening now is you know I'm in a different time zone so I don't actually see a lot of
the posting it actually happens all the sleep but it's pretty easy so let's see.
OK.
Yeah.
So I'll start posting at 5 o'clock my time and then it goes away to 3am which is you know I'm asleep
at that point.
But that lines up pretty well with the US.
So yeah I mean we've seen a decent change and engagement just from that.
Here's a look at my iconv square I can also see that I'm getting increases in the U.S. based audience
versus say other ones that are you know like Middle East or India or China or things like that.
I guess I said China I don't know even if they block it.
And then let's see other than that what I've started doing is I started doing that weekly carrousel
post.
Now you remember this from before.
The idea was to look at the last week and choose which of those performed the best.
And I was just going off of engagement so let's see last week we posted let's use this one and always
pick the one that has the most interesting thumbnail to run as the first video.
So we post these in class the bones the 3-D pedestrian walkway and then kind of the idea was that I
would every week post that.
It's an extra piece of content and then hopefully we can try to promote it.
So we're trying to do this year this week was post this one and I tried promoting it by working with
one of the other people.
It was Grann a tax account.
And so we tried to promote this one but it didn't really work out just because of some errors but you
could still see that the insights we still had working on are like 21:00 close to 22:00 engagement which
is much much better than say like the average post.
So it took an average post.
Ok actually this one did really poorly.
So you see your average is like 150.
OK.
So what I did for that was we just kind of had a deal before that if I paid them originally was $10
but now they opted to $30 they would promote it like that.
And for me it's just an experiment.
So why not will I do it next week.
Probably not.
I'll still do the carousel posts because those perform really well but I don't think I'll pay to have
this boosted anymore.
It also seems that we kind of screwed it up.
We didn't do it the way that he wanted to because he wanted to make sure we only did one video and then
picked one with a better thumbnail.
And the reason why is because when you do carousels it doesn't show right on the front views.
Instead it shows likes Now that then becomes the way the hash tag pages and explore pages.
It's going to get ranked.
So that's the primary engagement indicator.
I kind of was aware of that.
I just didn't really think it made much of a difference.
I don't even know 100 percent if that's what went wrong but that's kind of what their complaint was.
I'm going to put all of these conversations and the resources.
You can read these whenever you want to just to see kind of what worked and what didn't.
OK so other than that we started doing what's called like exchange and also I started kind of fanning
out the zombie strategy.
So if we look on the computer case it will go to Jarvi.
And so what you can see is I've actually created about five zombies and I've also added the main account
Jarvi.
Now I want to start integrating the main account into Jarvi because pop social was the system I was
using for doing the auto follow bots and they're just not doing a great job.
I'm not particularly happy with that for the price you pay just doesn't really sense Charlie seems to
be a lot better.
So I'm going to switch to that and then slowly start to ramp up that again for innovation station.
But as you can see over here these are the ones that I started creating the ones with the names of the
ones that have actually started setting up now newest intact.
One thing show us and this one is actually doing pretty well.
And the way I set it up is I just have it posting the same stuff from innovations station that's all
it's doing is just picking posts that innovation station has and then setting it so that it only posts
things that have higher than average engagement.
And so so far it's doing fine.
I mean it's got 130 followers and I started this about 36 hours ago.
So it's actually growing faster than the main account.
So that's perfectly fine.
It's got a terrible ratio of following your followers but I don't care it's a zombie that's the whole
idea behind this is that you just do this in volume and then you can see very clearly that every single
time I post something you have innovation sation bottom right.
And then we have obviously the end cap video that says follow innovation station.
But then also we have it at the bottom pretty much everywhere.
We can take a peek at the settings that I was using.
So I go to Tools all I'm pretty much doing with these two right here.
My God technology and tomorrow technology is just reposting and once you get to say like 15 posts then
I'll start turning on followers and likes.
So the settings I have here are pretty straightforward.
Just on the reposte section I have it posting something like say 7 a day or something like that.
So it says 32 posts a day but that's not true.
So it posted here between 7 and 15 a day repost and it's all pulling images or videos.
I said don't obviously repo's done English go for ones that have 30 percent higher than the average.
So that's why you see these ones on here are just more of the popular ones.
And it's only posting from that account.
Now also what I did was I because this is a brand new account I know engagement's can be low.
So what I did is I went to the master hash tag list that I had created for my other main account and
I just started pulling a lot of tags that are on the lower end so the ones that are very unpopular let's
just say that so better chance of ranking in those.
That was my idea behind it.
Really all I did is just pulled like 100 of them and then plugged them into Jarvi suggested hashtags
tool.
And then from that kind of went through and picked out the ones that are wrong.
There's tons of wrong ones but that's kind of how I put that together.
So you can see it here on this list.
I started the top where we have like five million posts per hash tag.
I was pulling them all the way at the bottom here.
These ones like they started at the lowest one I think had like 2000.
And then went all the way up to I think like 25000.
So now they're at 32000.
So that's what we're starting with.
And then over time as the average engagement goes up I will switch out and start putting in higher or
just larger more popular hashtags.
The syntax I'm using is just simple it's just taking the original post without hashtags because I occasionally
put hash tags in the caption then comment meaning anything after this go in a comment.
Then I put original post hash tags.
So what happens is I did this plus enabled dynamic hash tags.
So it ends up happening is sometimes it posts the original ones and then sometimes it posts these and
it picks 50 50 from here 22 to 30.
But typically it's going to pull from here because these are the small ones and it's sometimes that
does this general is not it doesn't work 100 percent of times.
You'll notice this pretty quickly.
Like look at some of the older posts.
They just all came out wrong so like this has no hash tags no comment anything really.
So this one worked out fine.
Looks like it probably pulled.
Now I saw it pulled from the new list.
So anyway they don't always work the same you just kind of tweak it sometimes it makes sense the way
you set them up but you just got to get to a point where it works.
And then I have follows and I think likes set up.
Now the other thing that I've started doing is a new tool actually through Jarvi which is like exchanges.
And we talked earlier in the actual course about like exchanges and the different ways of doing it.
But so far this is probably the easiest way of doing it.
It does cost extra.
They haven't announced how much extra cost but I'm guessing it's probably going to be like $5 a month
or something.
So the way this works is you just upload accounts that will every 30 minutes like other posts that are
from counts in their system.
And so what I did is I put my zombies up here and said OK they can like up to 300 a day 20 per session.
Great.
And then that essentially earns me currency that then other people will like my main account.
So I don't want likes going back to the zombies is not really what I'm trying to optimize.
I'm just trying to use them to get some favor or to point them towards innovation station where we can
notice pretty quick that some of these posts actually have a lot of engagement.
So you know there's 3300.
This is not a boosted post but you can see 684 likes like that's where it's coming from primarily then
that's from the engagement group.
Now whether or not you guys use engagement groups up to you.
I use everything that's out there and if it works I keep going with it.
Otherwise I move on.
It's really up to you.
The engagement groups are perfectly fine.
The likes you get are real there are real accounts.
So you don't really have too much of an issue of you know making Instagram angry but it does definitely
screw up your analytics.
So when I look back at my systems it can be a lot more confusing just because all of a sudden I went
from getting average 100 likes.
Now I'm getting like average 600 to 700 so it just kind of had to keep that in mind.
Hopefully if I keep doing this like exchange then it will start to normalize and I'll know I have a
better sense of what's relatively doing well.
OK so other than that what I have done is I just for the hell of it decided why not.
I'm going to try doing a paid promotion with a really really big account.
So what I did is I went to the biggest count I knew and that was finest inventions and they have about
11 million.
And unfortunately they're private.
So I couldn't actually do an analysis on the account itself but I just decided to reach out to them
because they listed their kick escaped hell basically in their account and then I just looked at similar
ones to them and the similar ones to them all do the same thing with all the big ones.
Post their kik in their bio.
And the reason I think is just because these are older accounts if you get to 11 million you've been
probably doing this for six years.
So they're pretty old school and that's how they communicate.
So I just went on kik and his message to a whole bunch of them and it's you know half them responded
and of the half responded then I actually went down the process with them.
So like DIY Furius has 4.2 million.
And this actually didn't work out very well for me.
So I used a story promotion that we had before but then we cut it up so it wasn't the same format as
an actual story because stories are portraits whereas Instagram posts themselves ideally or square.
So we just took that old version and turned it into as you can see a square version.
It's the same length all we did of the change the cap that called the action and made it simpler.
So as opposed to being 15 seconds which I just thought was too much.
It would just basically encourage people not to watch the entire thing.
I just made it something like five seconds.
So there you go and then it's done.
Now if I could redo that one I would simplify the call to action but whatever.
So we tried that with D.I.Y. furious and it just didn't really work out very well.
I think I paid them.
I want to say a hundred bucks something like that and gave them this caption and it just didn't really
work out.
So what I did is I picked top five facts of the day and I just picked five facts that were the most
interesting to me out of my entire list.
I just went through my quote posts and just looked at them and said OK these are interesting.
Like for instance Steve Jobs I mean the company Apple because he was a fruitarian when he did it.
Facebook's dominant colors blue.
Because Mark Zuckerberg is colorblind.
For instance I was fascinated 97 percent of the e-mails sent in the world are spam.
So anyway I put that there and it didn't work out.
I guess it's probably because of my caption was too complicated and that just didn't result in a lot
of people clicking through.
But yeah I mean that's my guess because it got a lot of engagement on their account it just didn't result
in a lot of followers.
So what I'm doing was I just said OK skirt and I'll just pay a lot of money for a really really big
account.
And you guys don't have to do this remember.
Like I don't suggest doing this.
I just wanted to do it so I can show you how this works.
Like if if you were to go and you want to have an 11 million person account promote you how you would
do it and this is what it will look like and this one is quite expensive.
So end you're paying $300.
He's got the wrong guys.
Yeah $300.
And this guy was incredibly difficult to communicate with.
He would just disappear for like two days at a time.
He's supposed to go on a Friday.
Disappeared so supposedly Saturday.
Disappeared eventually posted on a Monday.
So whatever.
But it did end up working out pretty well.
And the reason why is you can just see pretty quickly if we were to look at our stats it I think it
added about 2200 followers.
So that's that's decent.
That's probably the most return I've ever gotten from a paid promotion.
And just from a dollar value that means that per dollar it's getting like for followers which is pretty
expensive if you're trying to run this organically you're not you know trying to actually pay money.
But as far as paid promotions go that's actually fine.
I probably am going to transition out of OK so iconic square doesn't update for whatever reason.
See if we can find on the web I guess you can see here that there's just a big uptick you know is growing
at pretty much anywhere from 30 to 90 a day something like that probably average out about 50 a day.
But would end up having forty five hundred.
And then we ended up at 50 800.
So I discount that by about two to three hundred because that's how we would have naturally grown.
But yeah you can clearly see that you know it gave us at least a thousand followers.
So that's I'd say that's good.
Would I do it again.
No because I don't want to keep doing paid promotions and I'm not going to.
I just want to see how it works so now we know.
Right.
This is what should happen when you do larger paid promotions.
They're probably more worth it then say medium sized ones as you've noticed a lot of times I'll pay
a medium size $150.
But it doesn't give me anything you know only gives me like 80 followers.
So I mean you just do the math on that.
That's just not really the same like some of the mediums will give me two followers per dollar.
That's what got me close to about four followers per dollar.
So that's perfectly fine.
Now what I mean to do is kind of start transitioning into using my zombies to do promo promotions.
The only other thing I started doing is I've started looking at accounts to buy and this is part of
the course.
So if you go back to that section we cover a little bit of buying accounts and the way that that works
well when you buy accounts it's pretty simple.
I mean you just find an account that's similar enough that already has an audience built out.
Some of them are really cheap so you can get one for I don't know spend a hundred bucks you can probably
get one that has 20000 followers or something like that.
And then what you would do is just look for something that you can easily keep posting on and then just
use it as a advertising platform for your main account.
It's like basically buying a shout out except you buy the entire account so you can shout yourself out
pretty much every single day.
And once I do that I'll show you what my strategy is.
One thing I'm struggling with is just finding technology based accounts for sale for whatever reason
the people who sell accounts only like to sell things that are like fitness models or like bodybuilding
or cats and animals or humor and memes and things like that.
So anyway I want to try to find one and when I do I'll show you where I found it how much I paid and
then I'll show you what my strategy is for basically taking all of its followers and trying to get it
to go to my main account anyway.
So yeah doing it for science doing it for you guys so you can learn and see how this works.
OK so I'll check back in.
I'm moving on to Malta.
And so you probably won't hear from me from at least two to three days but then I'll check in and you'll
see where we're at.
All right.
Thanks guys.
Later.