Hey guys welcome back.
OK so this lecture we're going to do is what are you what we've been doing for stories at innovation
station.
I can show you the two different types that we were have been trying and give you a little insight into
why we changed it.
OK.
So with our story strategy is pretty straightforward we just saw it as a way to bring engagement to
my regular posts so what I did was I just posted a story every single time there was a post and I was
it was just a preview of it.
And then the idea was to bring people in and they go check out my post and hopefully engage and then
hopefully look at other posts.
You're the only thing I did was I made a little intro and outro sequences.
So the idea was posting the top of the day or the top of the week.
And so I kind of wanted to preface that with people first.
Although in retrospect it's something I probably could have dropped actually because it's kind of unnecessary.
So it looks something like this.
All right so top innovations of the day September 5th right.
Then the outro would look like this and say see of the videos at.
And then it says swipe up to watch.
Now swiping up.
I can't do it I'm on my account but what it would do is it would take you to my account.
And again that's not ideal.
I need to update that reality it should just be I should just tag myself there and have it so they can
click it and then go.
Now for the longest time this is how we did our stories what we were doing is we would take our posts
and since our posts were square videos we would then turn them into a story version.
So in order to do that kind of how to start from the very beginning where people were writing captions
about their posts.
So if you look at this as our Trello showing the progress we've been making with captions and I can
show you an example.
We for instance here is a game that inoculates people from fake news.
This is the person who posted.
This is the person who always puts their hashtags just for reference.
This is a person who works on the captions.
Now what.
I had them do was write a full caption and we talked about this and the content strategy section but
then I just had to add a one sentence summary.
Now the idea was that we were going to post the videos as stories with a one sentence summary and that
if people were interested in it enough they could then go look at the videos all the videos are longer
than 15 seconds.
They're like 45 seconds something like that whereas a story can only be 15 so it's probably like a teaser
and then they'd move over to it.
That was the way that we thought it would work.
So I can show you kind of what the end result kind of looked like.
Let's see so let's say July 1st 2013.
It would start with top innovations of the day July 1st.
Nothing too surprising here.
So that would wash away as there always are a short like five seconds.
They don't go to like this.
So we would have the same video that we use as the post but it only have one sentence as opposed to
multiple sentences one sentence corresponded to the summary that the person wrote then at the bottom
we would do is we put the logo innovation station just to make sure that people knew this as it was.
We just use a generic background for the back has the same background that we had used in the intro
and outros and then we just did that for every single video.
It was really easy because if you're an editor was making a video pick very easily just then copy and
paste it into a different template that was taller or like a portrait mode video and then just snap
and these icons really quickly.
And it really didn't take any time and we used the same music too.
So there wasn't a big change at all.
So it would look something kind of like this Bob you're a very quick simple flip and then say the sentence
you can read it and then we kind of moved on and it took a lot of back and forth to figure out what
period we could show that it wasn't so long they didn't feel like they had to go look at the post.
But it also wasn't so short that they couldn't read it.
So that was kind of the style that we were doing for a while.
But what we essentially started doing is simplifying it because I added a feature where you can just
share a post and it automatically gives you a template for the posts and that is way easier and people
respond to it better.
So as opposed to doing it like that what you can do is just go to an individual post and then down here
where you have the paper airplane press that and says share.
Now all I have to do is actually just say add post to your story.
So I click that and then automatically it creates a background for me.
It puts my tag right there and it shows that it's a playable video so it makes it incredibly easy for
people to click through.
This is a great strategy also if you're posting someone else's post because you can do the same thing
and put it in your story and then highlight it and say Hey check this out.
And then it was a matter of just putting in some hash tags that fit with it.
So we could say something like I don't know computers at the top of the bottom doesn't really matter.
And then you know we like tag some people or something like that or we might even put text up at the
top or bottom so we could very easily say like check it out and throw that up at the top.
So that was really easy.
I mean I could easily throw this up right after I made a post and especially if I'm doing the same thing
every single time it makes it really easy.
The last thing I might do is just tag myself.
Just give them an extra thing to click on.
So long as you're not trying to be too cluttered obviously.
So I could put it like that if I wanted to and there you go.
Then I get send that and that's what we've been doing.
Much much easier.
Looks better.
And when we look at our stats actually people are responding to this a lot better.
Now we can look at our analytics for our stories and I can kind of show you what the general trend has
been.
So we look at the past year.
I haven't been doing this for a year.
So this is pretty much everything you post posted 661 stories.
That's largely because we started this a month or two after we did regular posts but we know you were
posting several a day so it kind of makes sense.
Total photos total videos for the most part we were just posting the videos and not the quotes just
because we didn't think the quotes were engaging enough average stories per day 2.7 sorority's history
yada.
So our total impression is 1.2 million that's pretty good average impressions on point 1.9.
So as you can see here our reach.
It's hard to kind of tell but it is a very steady slower upward trajectory so that either means that
people over time are finding these useful or the account is just growing larger and therefore more people
are seeing the stories every single day.
Down here is the average completion rate.
Ninety five point seven percent decently good.
Now this is all screwed up because Ill say highest Screecher most completed.
And obviously it's going be the first one right because everyone sees the first story.
So it it's also the shortest So it kind of makes sense that they would be most likely to get through
it.
So a lot of this isn't terribly useful.
This one story is no tap backs.
I think this is just because maybe this one was a little more confusing or something like that.
Yeah.
So for the most part our average restraint rate there is 13 percent which is pretty good.
It's kind of hard to say some accounts do better with their stories it's been a lot of time in their
stories.
One problem is that we've been doing the same thing over and over again so people kind of get used to
it.
But of course on the flip side some people get used to it and expect it so frequently will consume it.
So this is what we've been using it for for the most part I think it has increased engagement quite
a bit.
I think it's worth doing mainly because it's just an extra 5 percent effort.
It's really not particularly hard.
So if you have someone else doing this for you you can just write it into their schedule it's just one
more thing they can do.
But I will say I don't think stories are a big part of our strategy it's just kind of nice to have it
makes people look at and go oh this is a more active and well put together account versus ones that
say don't have a story.
All right guys with that being said next hour we'll talk about some of the best practices stories and
we'll move on from this action.
See you then.