Hey guys, welcome back.
Let's talk about hashtags. Now,
a lot of you know what these are and you
are more than welcome to skip this lecture.
If you don't, or you feel like you don't have a great
grip on them, then stay on for a little bit longer.
Please leave if you know what they
are and you don't want to hear more.
What's a hashtag and why does it matter
so much for your posting success?
A hashtag is any word that's
preceded by the pound symbol.
Now, why the pound symbol?
Well, the reason kind of makes sense.
Apparently, somewhere in the U.S. or Europe,
I don't remember where, this pound symbol is actually
called a hash mark, and it has a bunch of other silly
names, but hash mark is the one that apparently
lived on. Combining hash mark with the word tag,
and well, you get hashtag.
Brilliant.
The basic idea behind a hashtag is that it's a way
of quickly tagging or categorizing something.
It's different than just tagging something, because
you are doing it in line with the text itself.
Typically, when you organize documents, you use
folders to separate and delineate what's what.
You might even change the title or use
prefix or suffix codes to designate types.
When you're posting on social media, you can't do that,
so instead people hashtag it.
Now, this method of doing it has gotten so popular that
you even see it as a feature in non social media apps.
Now, if you use Bear, that app you
see me a couple times use it,
for instance, you can hashtag your documents
inside a document, which is kind of cool.
Now, you put some word that relates to
your post and then you post it as a hashtag.
If you posted a photo of your breakfast, you might put
#breakfast and #healthy and #dopeoplestilldothis.
If you posted a photo of Space X's Falcon Heavy rocket,
well, you might tag it with #spacex, #rockets, or
#cool but I don't understand the implications.
Then, when people want to explore posts related to
some category, maybe Space X just did a big launch,
so, you know, they want to see the photos from it,
they might search for posts with the hashtag #spacex.
It's actually quite useful for curating what you see
by having users self-select what they think their
content is relevant to.
Now, on Instagram, hashtags are a big deal. If you're
just using Instagram for fun and you're not trying
to grow your account, then hashtags,
to be honest, are kind of pointless, unless you are
using them in like a weird snarky self-referential joke.
In fact, they actually look pretty tacky.
So it's really only something that businesses ever try to attempt.
You occasionally see other people do it but
I don't understand why they're doing it.
Next lecture, we'll talk about how
to do this without looking tacky,
but I want to get a couple more points across. Instagram,
as you've heard me say before, is pretty restricted as
a platform, restricted in what you can do, see, and
what information you get.
There aren't a lot of ways of super boosting your post to
every person that would ever want to see it.
Well, at least not at the moment.
So instead we need to use hashtags to automatically
put our posts in the category feeds that people might
be searching. When you normally post something,
it just goes out to all your followers.
Instagram might show it to people who are not in
your followers list, but you can't rely on that entirely.
You have to give your system some hashtag information
so they can throw it out there in front of new
followers that could potentially like your stuff.
Ok, I think it's fair to say that you know what a hashtag is now,
presumably - it's just a code symbol
that's used to categorize your posts.
They work differently on each social media platform,
but on Instagram, they're actually quite a big deal,
especially to business users.
We add them to our posts to increase our reach.
How you use them and pick them,
we'll talk about next lecture. Peace.