Hey guys welcome back.
So this lecture and talk about the fourth way that you can potentially make money on Instagram.
And that is through leads.
Now when I say leads I mean that you have some other business model or business that resides outside
of Instagram and that you're going to use Instagram as a DB generator for that other business.
Now how you make money on that other business.
I mean there could be a hundred different ways you can do it but the most common ways are going to be
things like driving people to a blog and your blog is monetized or driving people to an email list and
you use e-mail marketing to monetize them.
Or it could be that is the case that you sell your own stuff on say like an e-commerce site.
But that's again off of instagram.
But I don't think it's just limited to those.
I mean you could have a local business and you make an Instagram account that's related to that and
then you use the traffic from there to get funneled into leads and you can then somehow turn those into
something you work on.
I've seen this work with even web development companies who just post about technology and then they
use the link in their bio to drive people to either sign up for a free console on to build a web site
or directly just to their Web site where then they can see what's in your portfolio and how to reach
out to you.
So I'm not going to say what it is that you use to make money but I'm going to show you how you can
kind of bridge to bridge Instagram with your outside business.
And this is a powerful way of using Instagram.
Not everybody needs to grow their own massive native Instagram follower base.
It's actually quite powerful even if you have like 5000 followers.
It just depends on how valuable a lead is.
If you only sell it say it like digital music or something that maybe the maximum value can get from
someone is 10 bucks but if you sell a high ticket item or you're during consulting services one lead
could potentially mean thousands of dollars.
So what to do this lecture as I might show you a pretty cool tool.
It's called Link tree and I to show you how you can set that up pretty easily in your bio and then use
that as a way to funnel traffic to whatever it is you use off the platform.
OK so this is what it looks like.
It's called Link tree.
Yeah I believe that's the stony suffix for domains.
There's another one called link in bio and that's made by later and you might think that hey why don't
you show me this one because it's made by later and we use later for auto scheduling.
But I'm actually more interested in a linkage because they were the first to do this and they have a
lot more features and they're easier to use.
Perfectly happy you guys know if you want to check out linked in bio to see what the difference is.
They're kind of jockeying between the two or every other week it seems like they change their features.
So it's very hard to say right now which one's better.
Personally I think I have a preference for Link tree though like a cigarette linked tree with.
Yes the domain suffix.
And so the basic idea here is what they're going to do is you're going to set up a mobile optimized
Web site that they've tested over and over and over again with Instagram.
And then you're going to change your bio.
See that tree link right there so that anybody who clicks on it then gets taken to this mobile optimized
site and you use that to then funnel people in whatever direction you want them to go to.
It's pretty simple and it's also pretty useful if say like you're a creative or a content creator or
something like that where you have multiple destinations you might want people to go when you want them
to go see your blog.
We also Im torn between maybe I want my traffic to come in contact me instead.
While this can cater to what you're looking for.
So go to the website you sign up with and keep in mind though if you do like using this it does have
pricing.
The free version gives you a lot but if you pay six bucks a month which is really not much then you
can really kind of go pro at this or move their branding use a lot more of the tools they have.
Personally I'm find using the free version but if you guys like it then you can upgrade from free to
paid.
So go here you're like sign up for Instagram.
OK then all you have to do is authorize your account gool.
Then it's an auto populate your full name and you can put your email
then you can decide which one you want to go with the words.
Use the free version.
All right.
Now is this really a simple on the right side.
We have a preview screen of what it's going to look like when someone clicks a button and they've already
put our handle and our logo in there for us so that's a good head start.
Now up here it says my bio link and this is where you can customize this to whatever it is that you
want to believe you have to customize this.
You have to be a free account that doesn't really matter because people are used to seeing link trees.
And if you have it slash your name well.
And that gives it enough credibility that people might actually be interested and clicking on it.
OK.
So over here all you have to do is add new button or link to add a section where you can link people
to whatever it is that you want.
So let's say we wanted to link them to a blog.
OK.
So then right here we have a title and then a u r l and it's quite really simple.
So go my title it's a blog about innovation OK and then we'll put the L we don't have a blog about innovation
but I'll link them to let's say my account.
So this is my blog.
OK.
All right now when you click that little info button and slide this on now you can see hey look we've
added a little button right there.
Then we can check out some of these other features so here we can add an image but you have to be linked
to the pro for the most part.
You know if this really works out for you then you can start adding thumbnails.
But keep in mind this is all about conversion.
OK.
So if someone clicks your link tree by on they see this and it looks like he spent a whole lot of time
trying to make it beautiful then that actually might lower your conversion so keep that in mind.
Dave another section called priority links and that is just in case say you have like 10 different links
you can mark some of them as priority and what that does it just makes them show up at the top.
It's really that simple.
Here is a schedule link function.
This again would be say if you're doing a flash sale and you want people to go specifically to let's
say one product page or something that's time sensitive what you can do is you can schedule your link
so if I know this week I'm selling one item next week I'm selling another and click that button and
have them scheduled so I don't have to keep going in and removing these as I go.
And then last thing here is link click so this will show you how many people have clicked your link.
Keep in mind Instagram actually tell you how many people have clicked your link.
So if you go to Instagram and just look at the basic analytics you'll get numbers that say link clicks.
Also if you remember this iconic square does this as well.
You actually have an entire section that says how many people over time have clicked it.
So that's a great way of checking if I change the wording.
How many people have clicked it and then the last thing is you can just throw it away.
Now here is where you would just move this button so that you can rearrange it yourself so let's add
another button let's say bye.
Cool stuff.
So this would make sense if you know enervation station we were selling any of the items that we cover
which actually happens all the time.
People keep asking like Harry where do we buy this.
So it actually could be pretty interesting.
Buy my stuff.
If we had a second button where they could go and find whatever it is that they're looking at and one
smart thing you could do is that if I added a new item today that means people with attention are going
to be on it today then I could put that item right there.
So most likely anybody who's going be clicking on this could be interested in it.
And then in the post what I can do is just post and say if you're interested in buying this link in
the bio.
OK and then let's say I wanted to put one other on.
And this is going to be just a contact me button me.
Now there's a lot more ways you can handle this.
You could link them to the contact form on your blog.
You can want them to the contact page on your local store like a Google place page.
In this case what we can do is a little bit of a hack because I just want people to e-mail me.
I could just say mail too.
OK.
Now that's a code such that if someone clicks it it tells their computer hey open up a fresh e-mail.
So then I would say mail to and then my e-mail address.
Cool.
OK.
And then I turn this on and bam there we go.
Contact me by cool stuff blog about innovation.
Now I might rearrange these just so that it's whatever priority I think is most important.
I think contact me is kind of like a catch all for everything that's not related to these other things.
So I usually use that as a last resort.
But if you guys are a business that uses a leads and you're on the phone or good on e-mail then that
might be something you throw up at the top.
OK now last thing we want to check out our pretty simple.
Go to settings and we can change the color so they automatically give us looks like some color schemes
that match my logo I don't know if that's coincidence or want but that right there kind of looks like
my logo that also looks like my logo.
I think I like this one a little bit better actually.
I'll go with this one.
And then if you want to customize your theme while you get to pay the six bucks so it's not that big
of a deal anyway.
So that was pretty much it.
And now I can use this as a mobile optimized landing page that I know convert's really well so I can
put this link already just in my bio and pretty much good to go.
OK so if we went over to my account I could do this or would it just want to go over to edit profile
and then where it says Web site that's where I'm going to put my link and just yes
slash
wink are dot the innovation station
and station okay that that's deal it done and we all there we go.
Now we actually have a link in our bio now to point out probably two different things one remember when
we talked about Lincs we were setting up our account your link is pretty much your main driver of business.
So it would make sense in this case that I change my last line to actually highlight that hey there
is a link so I need to do a call to action.
Otherwise people dont know why.
For instance if you click on that link.
Now obviously you can do this in posts you can click on the link in the bio to check out whatever this
whatever the theme of the post was.
But for the most part people who my profile who didn't necessarily come from one of those pages are
not going to see that link because they have nothing that's driving them to it.
So what I want to do is change that.
Put an arrow down and say click the link to contact me or click the link to find out more to see cool
tech or whatever it is.
My main goal is now the second thing I'll point out is that you guys can actually use your real short
inners Now that might actually be useful but it's really kind of up to you.
For instance I have the custom short enter and then dot It's Evan K..
I m OK so if my account is called Evan Kimbrell that might actually be a better link for someone to
click on.
But for the most part people recognize link tree so it's not the end of the world but if you really
want more control in your branding I would probably use a linked corner.
Again I don't suggest using TITLEY because people just have an unfortunate association with Billy being
linked to something that is not great right.
Because why else would someone want to mask the name of their link.
OK so then we can preview the link just by clicking on it and it looks like that.
Here we go.
I mean that's exactly what I expected it to look like.
This is moblie optimize it's very easy.
Big open button someone can just click on it to figure out whatever they want to do.
So I could just click Bhag about innovation that should take them to Evon gmail dot com and there you
go.
That's my Web site.
I don't use it all the time.
If you notice it's not really updated.
But if I was using it for whatever reason.
There we go now I drove people directly to my blog and my blog is my main goal and perfect.
Ok guys.
That's it for now.
Next we'll do is we'll look into a landing page software and actually show you how to do it for FREE.
Very quickly to make a landing page that might give you a little more control over whatever it is you're
trying to drive leads to.
OK.
See you then.