Hagar's Welcome back.
OK.
So this lecture we're going to talk about how to make logos very quickly for your zombie accounts.
Those are really just kind of an extension of the strategy that we talked about in the first section
where we talked about making logos.
You obviously want to follow the same bits of advice that we had then about your logo be easy to understand.
Having bright vibrant colors and generally you want something that's like an icon versus say text.
There's a lot of people use text.
The problem is just that the thumbnail is so small that it can be pretty hard to read.
So just keep in mind different ways that your profile image is going to be displayed.
OK so if you guys are doing a personal account and you're making zombies your personal account Well
then taking a profile photo is pretty straightforward.
Pick photos from actual post in your main account or pick photos that are very similar to the one you
use in your main account something of if it's you always see of you.
Now if it's your company and you want it to do zombies now I already said before I don't really suggest
doing that for your company.
But what I generally suggest is taking your logo and using multiple varieties of colors Typically companies
or businesses will have one logo and then you can tweak the colors or tweak.
Like for instance the name making an abbreviated or adding an icon to different kind of arrangements
like that.
And by just changing those small criteria you can create a good batch of logos that would make sense.
Now if you doing a themed account which you were doing for this course and I believe most people watching
probably are trying to do then here are my suggestions.
So I really come down to two different things.
One as I like to use the same logo maker that we covered before and that shape factory.
Now the reason why is because they just have really good icons and really good colors and they do a
really good job of giving you lots of different variations to work with.
Now they're a little bit pricey right because there's like $40 a logo.
I think if he's at a discount it's down to like 30 something that's still a lot.
Right.
So I've heard him make 100 zombie accounts.
That would be a problem.
So what if I ended up doing actually was I use them but I would only buy a logo and then I would just
save multiple variations of that logo.
So I would use different gradients and different colors for the icon.
And out of each individual logo purchase I got like 10 different ones.
So give me an example.
Here's one of my zombies.
Oh my God.
Technology.
So as you can see it's like yellow in the background and red in the foreground for the logo.
And then in the next one the newest attack it's just two different colors.
And typically I would just do this and get at least like eight to 10 logos So each individual one costs
like $3 and then I'm done.
Now this probably isn't ideal if I were to create hundreds and hundreds of them because I would get
pretty expensive pretty quickly if that were the case.
What I would end up doing is probably doing one of two things.
Well one thing you can do and this is viable if you are someone who's pretty comfortable using Photoshop
or using design tools even like scatch.
What I'd say is go to the Noun Project Home and this is an open source icon repository where they just
have thousands and thousands of it's a million icons and they're all royalty free and they have them
on anything you can think of.
You know I said biology I would just get tons you know beakers and just genetics that doesn't make any
sense but all.
So I could just scroll for days on this.
And these are all pretty relevant.
So then what you would just do is pick one of these and say it's just the standard beaker.
And then I can say get this icon.
You have to create an account but it doesn't cost any money then you just download the royalty free
version of it.
Take that into Photoshop and then just play around with it there.
Keep in mind remember your profile needs to be 110 pixels by 110 pixels.
What I would usually do is just take this and then create a basic bright colored background and then
turn this white or keep it black or just change it to some color that has a nice contrast.
Now that's a little too manual effort.
One other option.
You guys can do that I think is really useful is just use Kanva right.
Canada is free.
I have a paid version but it doesn't really give me anything that you wouldn't have in the free version.
What you do is just go to Canada after you create a design.
It'll give you all these templates you can choose from.
Instead just go to use custom dimensions.
And here you can just type in 110 by 110 which is exactly what we need.
Then once it populates it they have tons and tons and tons of icons that are free that you can use or
even illustrations charts whatever and they all have pretty good color schemes right off the bat.
So let's say I was trying to make a technology one so I don't know it's just a computer and see what
we get.
OK so we have a lot of flat design ones.
I would probably stay away from these royalle these stock image ones just because those look pretty
bizarre is a icon as a logo.
So I would probably pick and see something like that.
Like that's pretty simple.
And then what I could do is just play around like background colors.
So I do this is maybe just go to background over here and pick something in the background that I think
contrasts well with it because remember we want to make sure that a thumbnail makes sense and sticks
out.
I might even shrink this just because the way Instagram is going to display it.
And then you know I can do as much as I want to it I can even go with like a funky background.
Really go for contrast.
I think this is probably fine.
I might actually just go back to that solid colored one.
And then if I wanted to edit the colors here it's just a matter of clicking it up here I can change
the screen color to whatever I want.
I have a bunch of default palettes that I have.
But if you want custom colors you just press this plus button right here and then you can put in the
hex code if you know it but you can also play it on this color wheel until you find something you like.
They don't say is again try to save yourself time to see the same icon to make multiple.
So you can do this in a batch so just doesn't Garvie crazy.
But with Kanva there's hundreds and thousands of good quality flat or non-flat skew morphic design icons
that I think you could pretty much go the distance with just takes a little bit of tweaking and uploading
on to your profile and then pretty much from there you're all set.
So we did actually just take this and then upload it to the account that we were using before.
I just want to spice it up just because I'm in a rocket right in the middle of it.
Just to give it a little more visual signature.
Not everybody likes rockets.
So it's even I don't think it has these snap grid lines that are super easy then appearing just get
download does it really matter what file tape you use if you have a background that's blank then use
a PMG.
But keep in mind Instagram's is going to convert your background to white.
It doesn't actually give you transparency.
So I could just go here back to the account when you create advanced technology today.
But a mouthful that's fine because this is a numbers strategy going to change profile photo.
And we can upload our design and it pops up right there.
That's a little raster.
So I might actually go back and try to increase the size of it.
Now the way you do that is actually pretty simple it's called The Magic resize there is no change dimensioned
is custom.
So it's the
read download it to J pay
OK and that's a little bit better.
What I would do is I would resize this a little bit more just so it doesn't look like these tips or
the icons are hitting the edges.
And I might blow it up a little bit larger just so it has a bit of a better resolution look to it.
Now this might just be the problem of having this on a web version web version is always larger than
the mobile version so a lot of times it just stretches it out.
But regardless that's something we can fix pretty easily.
All right guys so in the next set of lectures what we're going to do is we're going be talking about
setting up a V-P ass.
Now you just learn a VPN was earlier of an hour type of Piazza's.
Those are virtual private servers.
The reason why I want to set those up is so we can use an application called Jarvi which is going to
help us run our zombie accounts in bulk without going crazy.
All right.
See it.