OK we are back.
So last lecture I just showed you what the SCRAM live looks like.
Well I mean it works.
I think it got 200 people to view it in total and then add a lot of people tagging.
You noticed kind of towards the end some people were getting a little out of hand so you might need
to think in the future about how to restructure something like this maybe such in a way people towards
the end don't feel like there's no way to win.
They just start kind of scurrying around but of the most part that went relatively smoothly.
One other thing you might have missed was I just was playing a youtube playlist in the background because
any live is going to have audio.
So I just kind of threw that on his Labi music.
Now what I need to do though very quickly is tell people hey we're relaunching the video to figure out
who won.
Right so I don't think I just ran away with whatever their time i guess.
So what I'm going to do is post the story really fast so we'll go over here so we'll go to type so tap
to type you
put this ad in The Kids way.
And then I will do I'll post this and then I'll just post another one.
All fast.
Save it.
I'll send it to a story share it.
Really fast.
All right now the next thing I'll do is give everyone say or
change the color something all that different.
Great.
OK.
So I'll send this to my story OK.
Now that should be done.
He loves it.
Great.
OK so now people know that this Brack's doing something.
I'll try to make a regular post.
Really quickly.
So do it like we're doing before.
I'll take out the image.
Take them on I go.
I'll put this up and I'll put
up.
Beautiful but gets the point across.
Now what I'll do is I'll share this as a story and then I'll put this as a post really quickly.
So throw on innovation station just doesn't mention
OK.
So now I'll save this to my story.
Great.
And we'll post a regular post.
So this one or it says give us a sec Well the winner shortly.
So I'll just post that and I'm not going to post this with any like hashtags or anything.
It's not really worth it.
I'll put the location just in case.
So
we watch video to see on
you know try something or I think the question I had was way too easy someone got it within like five
seconds.
I think it's just because they Googled it.
I need to put a little more thought into something that you can't Google it you know like you could
answer it.
Not everyone will immediately know that's the answer.
I think that's one issue that kind of ran into it.
So as someone said keyboard than everybody said keyboard.
So.
We go.
And then I'll say like really quickly.
See you next door to the next.
Give me whether or not I actually do this next Saturday.
I don't really know.
I'll have to look and see how it actually worked.
See if we got any followers for a minute.
I also noticed there's a lot of people who are attacking people but they weren't tagging their friends
they were tagging like me are huge accounts like Amazon.
I need to probably specify that a little bit more.
It's just a problem that you don't want to make is too complicated.
OK.
So OK.
And Share.
OK.
So that pretty much sums it up for the live section.
You saw how that went.
I'm going to go figure out who won this.
But since we're in the live section or are we going to get into that when we get into giveaways later
we'll talk about what auctions you have for giveaways story giveaways post giveaways live giveaways
we'll try some of those out to see what works there's also different mechanics that you can use for
giveaways that make the model more effective.
There's a lot of things we tried tag all your friends and also telling the answer turns out the riddle
I used was too easy and I didn't really specify who to tag but I did get a lot of people tagging people
except towards the end.
Also one thing that's worth noting now is I know there are some bad actors some people that are posting
really bizarre things and so I can block them or hide that story from them.
So you guys remember when you do live you can go to the settings and it says like hide story from when
it's a story it means live so I can do that.
Ok cool thing I'll do is delete the old give away post and then.
Yeah that's it.
OK.
So you guys saw that worked out.
That was one way of doing a live strategy that works in tandem with giveaways certainly role for themed
accounts.
If I was doing a personal account that I would have just done like a Q&amp;A and I would have set up a bunch
of stories over the week to gather a bunch of questions and then I would have done it if I were a business.
I don't know I could've done behind the scenes that could I did it in a tutorial something educational
an announcement or something like that.
But with D-Md. accounts I think you're kind of limited.
It's really up to how creative you can be.
One thing I think it's really useful those to make sure that you are following a lot of similar accounts
in your space to see what they do and see what they use Instagram live for because it might be the case
if someone else figures out something and that's something you might want to emulate.
OK.
That being said the next lecture.