Hey guys welcome back.
So last lecture we went over link tree and that's a great way of dividing up your traffic and pointing
them towards whatever direction you need them to go in order to collect leads.
This lecture actually going to do is we're going to create a mobile optimized landing page ourselves
using a tool called lander.
Now the reason why I'm covering this is because with the link to tree it kind of assumes that you already
have a page that you have to send people to and also it doesn't really give you a ton of control over
what you want.
Now there's is only one thing you want to drive all traffic towards the trees.
Probably not a great idea because the whole idea with that is that you can set up multiple links and
do that easily in a way that you know converts.
All right so check it out a toad Lander app dot com.
There are a lot of landing page softwares out there.
You guys have taken any other courses.
We've go over other ones.
There's like on bounce there's the one I personally use which is insta page but they're kind of expensive
and considering you are only trying to make a landing page for our Instagram page.
They're kind of overkill.
I obviously have nothing against lander.
It's just that I use other ones for different purposes for Instagram.
I think this is the easiest it's easiest to set up.
You can do it the fastest and also their pricing is completely reasonable compared to the other ones.
Just keep in mind they don't have as many features but again you're not going to really use any of those
other features for a mobile optimized site that's just for Instagram so you can see right here their
basic starts in about 16 a month and they go all the way up to 83 whereas like insta page for instance
believe they start at like $60 on unbound starts around $50.
So keep that in mind so it just laner app dot com.
OK.
So if you wanted to set up a page let's just go and get a free account.
Now I can give you a 14 day free trial which I think is plenty of time to create your own page and figure
out whether or not it's going to work for you.
So fill out your information and you get started.
Click Start free trial now.
Right now we just have to check our inbox and verify it.
All right now we verified our account.
This is what it pushes us into.
So what's going to happen is going to choose a folder name.
And so any page that we use on land or they're going to give us an automatic u r l.
This is obviously auctioned off to you if you want it to run from your own domain.
They have tools for that.
But for simplicity sake we can just use their system.
So will the innovation station OK available.
Great.
Done.
All right then he gives us some videos to watch on how to use your thing.
But for the most part their system is not very complicated.
So just hit new landing page.
OK name our landing page this is all just internal.
So we'll say innovation station and next.
Right now it's good to give us a bunch of templates.
This is one of the best parts about this.
You don't have to sit down and pay a web designer and a web developer to make your own web site.
This is great if you are driving people to one specific purpose.
OK so if we were making an Instagram page to promote an app that we made Here's a great template for
that and take them directly to your app page and it's very obvious that the goal that page is to download
your app.
There's also ones for like announcing an ebook.
Here's a it you know get this awesome book today.
This is a great Legion tool as well a lot of people write e-books or just templates or guides or something
that's really useful and then drive traffic to that people sign up and then you can put them into an
email sequence and sell them things later.
Here's one for just a standard software subscription.
Let's see there's other ones for like events that's pretty useful if you want to do a web and are here
some women are ones.
Here is a physical in-person event.
These are all things that you could be driving leads to coming soon which is pretty useful.
Let's say you wanted to build a pre-launch list for a Kickstarter or a launch list for who knows what
you could use one of these.
These are all pretty easy to use.
You can even put a timer right here so people know when to sign up.
But for the most part yeah this is pretty simple.
So let's say our innovation is Asian we're going to be launching a YouTube channel.
OK.
Haven't launched it yet but we want to get people who are interested in watching longer form videos
about what we're doing.
So what I might do is pick something like this.
So let's see if this works for what we're trying to do.
So that create then it says Welcome to our editor.
You guys can launch a tour if you want to.
Otherwise I'll just show you what matters.
And there we go.
Now we have your logo we have a countdown timer.
Hang in there soon and then.
Website coming soon.
Then we'd have down here is typing in an e-mail address.
Subscribe.
And that's pretty much it.
You want to move the branding.
Unfortunately you have to be a paid account.
We're in a free trial we can't do that right now.
But if this is useful.
Very easy for us to get rid of this and justify the cost of paying 15 bucks a month.
OK.
So let's just assume that we're making a YouTube channel.
So what we could probably do see is change this logo over here and where we can say innovation station
plus YouTube nation plus YouTube.
OK.
Simple enough.
We should probably add to the image so we can throw in our logo.
So we clicked this ad image over here then it shows the gallery that we've already uploaded.
We don't have it yet so we're just gonna browse for the file we want.
So here is one logo that we can try out.
So it should have a blank background.
What we want.
OK great.
Up here put it in the corner just so we keep the same semblance of branding.
OK.
Now let's just look over some of the tools over here pretty dang simple.
As you noticed here the basics these are the tools for adding in basic things like a line break to break
up your content adding in a video.
This might be a smart thing if we are doing a YouTube channel we can make a video introducing people
to it.
A button if you want them to click through to something else.
Here's some text.
Here's a box if you want to frame some of the content you're using and then obviously the image.
The things you can use are basic social so you can add things like a like box widgets.
Twitter followers followers etc..
Personally I'm going to get rid of those because I think those are a distraction.
If the sole purpose of my landing page is to get them to go to a YouTube channel so I'm saying no other
things are in the advanced column.
So you can type in your own HVM mouth.
That's something that you really needed to do.
You know if we were doing a local event and this would be really useful you could show a map to where
it is.
If you're a local store that's also pretty useful as well.
You're trying to make money off your landing page let's say trying to make a really simple page to sell
something that's in your profile.
You could put a PayPal button here and have people pay you for whatever it is.
So over here we have some global settings for the page so we can set the width of the page height.
You can change things like the metadata.
So if someone searches for this we could set that up.
That's not parable important for us just because we're trying to make this for Instagram only we can
put in scripts too if you want to do basic like pixel tracking like Facebook pixel or if you want to
do google analytics or something like that lander gives you basic analytics so you can see as people
hit your page you don't really need that unless there's something very specific you're looking for in
your traffic data.
Here is where you can change the background see it's white right now.
But if I wanted to I could change to something else also change things like color or opacity.
And yeah pretty much that's it.
Right you are weakening goals and I believe if you're in a pro account you can add multiple goals.
That's obviously not a very good idea.
You want to focus everyone on one thing at a time.
So we have a form submission.
So what happens is if say like I unchecked us then when someone goes and fills this out it works all
the same.
It's just that lenders are not going to tell me it's not good to track that.
So right now lenders thinking oh form submission is the goal.
So when we give you analytics we're going to give you a percentage of how many people hate your page
and do this goal.
All right so do this form submission.
OK passed and everything else is pretty simple.
I personally like to rely on their templates as much as possible with you have your own page you can
do that.
But again this is probably not the best tool to use for that.
So I just spent a little time customizing this so it looks a little more legitimate.
So innovation and put the year OK then up here we have the timer.
So if we want to modify this we just click it and then automatically press properties tamps gives you
everything you can change about it.
Now there there's a lot obviously here's the sizing here's the time zone here's the date that it's essentially
counting down to.
Right so it's like 600 for these days.
Let's go down to Torrini 22.
So let's say we're going to launch our channel.
Let's see.
So it's July.
So we're going to launch it in a couple of months.
Well we're in a launch in a couple of months.
I don't know November 14th sounds like a nice one.
There we go 61 days.
OK.
Now obviously you probably would want to do a landing page for something that's going to launch that
far out in advance.
Hard to get people actually care if it's that far away so keep that in mind.
Now that we've changed it so there's actually one digit missing.
We can move this over to center again and you notice we have these snap grids that pop up.
See how that means it's left aligned.
This means that center aligned.
So we want that to be center aligned.
Now we can do different things so if you guys want a 24 hour clock you can set this up.
You can set it up so that these numbers mean something else.
You can bat some goofy branding If you want to here you can change the color opacity.
You can do a reflection which is very common.
The upside down version of it that's fine to use out if you want to just make sure you turn up the opacity
so it doesn't really ridiculous then the animation.
So I was scrolling down kind of like a slot machine.
They have other options so we can do Faid instead.
I personally think that's maybe a little less obnoxious although it flashes on a screen so that's probably
killing me.
And then delay this is how many microseconds it delays.
So if we set this higher it's just going to take longer to move.
So here the delay is 100 Sonera So it's like very abrupt and shaky.
So you know it's kind of up to you personal preference.
All right pass that you can set the color here or you can set the inside border.
So this separator really up to you.
You know I think solved works perfectly fine.
We wanted to we could do dotted all together on the sea makes much of a difference or none at all.
I think that's probably the worst.
Then we can change the font to fit whatever it is that we want animation and we use it.
Do we typically use flaunt.
Proxied and no I believe.
No it's U-Boot too.
So certainly don't have that one but you can just pick something that matches as close to you as you
can get it to as possible I'm pretty sure under the pro versions you can change this.
OK.
So then you want to go down here and change our.
Pretty simple.
So we might want to give something that entices them to watch long form tech videos.
Ok that might be a little wordy or whatever but I need to give them some reason to sign up so I might
want to simplify this so I might just say something like low tech videos I think that might be a little
more to the point.
It doesn't look like crap.
OK.
There we go.
And then down here is the subtitle.
So it says new website coming soon.
But for us it's like you know we could say YouTube channel launching soon.
OK.
Now we noticed that this headline is smaller than this one.
So what we can do is just highlight this right here and change the font size over here.
So I'm not sure what it has currently at 14.
So we could probably put it.
Yeah.
So put it at twenty two.
Put it at 28.
Let's put it at I think 36 is fine.
There we go.
Now it has a little bit of what we call kerning meaning the letters are really squished together but
that's perfectly fine.
OK I want to be the first to know why launch just fill out the form.
There you go.
OK.
That's pretty simple.
If I were to do really actually launching a YouTube channel I would probably put in a video and I would
probably play around the background colors.
I probably make a logo specifically for the YouTube channel.
Honestly.
So I might even call this like let's call innovation tube.
It sounds terrible.
It's a little bit more catchy.
Innovation tube.
So I might even put something like the YouTube icon on YouTube iconic.
You go to YouTube PAGG you go and download that back now it's at an image brows and there you go.
OK then I put this up here just so people get a little bit of an idea what we're talking about.
I can automatically resize this right here by grabbing the corners.
Now notice it will constrain the dimensions so it doesn't make the image look screwed up so if I go
like this it always keep it like that.
So let's just make it at a reasonable size throw it right there.
OK.
There we go.
OK great.
So I think that perfectly gets the point across.
This should be a good mobile optimized website.
There's a lot of other small things on here.
This is useful for grids.
So this shows you where the grid is is going to help you line things up correctly such that if you don't
know the center line or you think there's not enough spacing you can kind of get more detailed with
it.
Here are the guys who can turn this off with a snap grid guides drive you crazy.
For me I don't really care.
And then last thing here is we have the layering.
So for instance I had this image on top of the YouTube for whatever reason and I wanted to be in front
of the YouTube I could say send forward.
Like just imagine it's like a stack of pieces of paper.
And I want this to be higher on the stack so I get sent for it.
Up there you see now it's covering it.
OK.
So use that to your heart's content.
So then we're not going to check it out by hitting preview tenacity to save it or to say yes.
All right so then once it's done saving it preview and this is what it looks like.
OK.
Pretty simple.
You also notice that it has equal spacing on both sides.
This bar appears just to remind you that hey we're looking at a preview I can click X out to remove
it.
But keeping this equal signs like this is actually very useful because when we want this to be viewed
on mobile it's very easy to get resized on mobile when it has this grid system.
OK.
So back to here we are.
And let's just finish.
All right so now we have this is the you are l link.
It's innovation innovations there's an innovation section with we want it to post we can publish it
we want to do a basic AB test meaning like we have two different pages of different wording or different
images I'm going to see which one performs better.
We can put new variant what that will do is make a copy of this page and then we can make changes to
it and then set it up here to run some basic tests.
Usually it's pretty simple.
Then down here you have a bunch of other tools that you can hook up pretty easily.
You guys you zippier that are useful if you use an email marketing software so you like say you want
the sign ups to go directly to your software.
You can do things like that consing contact a web very popular MailChimp too.
Now down here you can get a welcome email so when someone signs up you can send them a follow up e-mail
which is usually a very good idea.
Either way it's just that publish.
OK now let's publish we have this link so let's see it live.
OK so it looks like that.
All right so now you do have a page and it's ready to go after you publish it.
We'll publish anything you have.
You want to make changes you have to keep going back and doing this.
Now the last thing you have to do in order to make this work for mobile is is very crucial step as you
go down here to Mobile.
And you want to hit go to Ed..
So you have to change the mobile layout.
It's worth doing because this is what we came here for.
So now we have the mobile out right here.
Unfortunately it just takes you right back to the same page you made before.
But with some very quick editing we can change this up.
Obviously it's a good idea to have a mobile version and a web version because people might still go
to your web version or they might be on the web version of Instagram so it's worth having both.
Also keep in mind what looks good on a Web site does not necessarily look good on a mobile system.
So we'll just make our edits really fast.
OK so that didn't take very long at all.
Now it's updated.
Now I just want to make sure that everything is center aligned right.
So it's line up that.
And then once we get that bar I should be good.
OK.
Everything else has been updated on the Get rid of these buttons and let center line this just for the
sake of statics go.
OK cool.
Now what we can use you can save now we can preview the mobile version.
It should look like that.
And we go back and publish it one more time we should be good.
Let's finish.
OK.
So as pending changes well it's because I updated the mobile site so it's at republish they republished
this landing page and there we go.
OK.
Now we can look at it on our mobile phones and then put it into our Instagram.
So this is what it looks like.
There we go.
Pretty much optimized for a mobile phone.
I think it looks perfectly fine.
It's very dynamic it's got to form right here it can enter in very easily.
Cool.
So let's just copy and paste this and right there and then it's good or Instagram
then are just good at it profile.
It's at our Web site.
It in and hit done.
OK.
So there we go.
That's our link now.
So if I click it it takes us to that page where we're promoting our innovate our innovation too.
Now you notice that it's going to push you to a window that's through the Instagram browser so some
of the rules might be different than your Safari browser.
So what I would want to do is go back and say for instance move that YouTube icon slightly off just
because I know that this version of the browser overcompensates.
And also if I got to the point I like this I would get rid of that powered by laddered crap right there.
Now you notice that the link is kind of crazy.
So in this case what I would suggest doing is using a real wrapper.
Right Billy B.
T L Y is a great way of doing it.
Although again I know there's somewhat of a negative association with it.
If you have your own branded domain we talked about this earlier in the course when we talked we were
getting pretty Lincs.
That's a great way of doing it as well.
You can also just take any domain that you have and then do what's called a redirect and doing a redirect
is relatively simple just google it.
It's pretty simple depending on who your web host is almost all of them will just have buttons where
you can click and say redirect to then you'll set the URL to this so that then someone could say go
to Edinburgh dot com and send them right to this instead.
That is very useful.
Now that we have this set up though we also have analytics from Instagram.
And as people start to see it there will also give us our own analytics.
Keep in mind that you have a limit to how many people can visit it and it's 25000 which is consciously
a lot.
If you've gone through 25000 visitors so and decided if you like Lander Well then that's your problem
I guess.
All right guys and that's a pretty easy clean way of doing that.
Save you at a special event say you had something you wanted to collect.
An e-mail address for say You just wanted to collect leads somewhere.
Then you can do whatever you like what we did and we could do an e-book you could direct them to a page
about you.
They can contact you.
There's a lot more flexibility with this than linked tree.
All right so that's it for now I'll see you guys in the next section.