You guys welcome back OK this lecture we're going to do is we're going to talk about some odds and ends
to the shout out growth strategy.
There are some tactics out there that I would consider a little more advanced but I also consider them
pretty creative and creativity.
I mean it's a big factor in whether or not you're successful on Instagram and especially with some of
these growth remedies like shout outs.
Shutouts are pretty simple on the surface right.
You just repots someone else's stuff and then you tag them in the caption and Mimi in the photo.
It's sometimes you know dawn on a shared share basis so you do one they do one sometimes you buy them
right.
Well there's other ways of using this as well.
And that's what we're going to cover in this lecture.
So I have four obscurer strategies that hopefully will stoke some creativity and if you're up for it
try it out.
All right so the first strategy is the one day unsolicited shout out strategy.
So one thing I've seen work pretty well with newer accounts is in the first 30 to 60 days you're not
gonna have enough followers to be able to do these one to one shout out so you even get the attention
of some of the larger accounts.
So it might feel like I just can't use this strategy at all.
Well one thing you can do is set on your habit schedule.
Go to your To Do list of your momentum or whatever and set that every single day for the first day like
30 days you're going to make an unsolicited shout out an unsolicited one would be you post someone else's
stuff and then you can and you tag them in the captions and you just do that one sided entirely.
What that does is it allows you to start building a relationship with some of the accounts that later
on you'll want to actually do some collaborative back and forth with.
Now there's only really works if you pick accounts that are really squarely in your niche.
And if they're posting things that you legitimately think your audience will enjoy.
If that's the case then you can pretty much get away with anything you want.
What's great about this though is that sometimes there are big accounts out there and millions of followers
and you think to yourself I'm never going to be able to get shouted out on their account.
Well in some cases when you do unsolicited shout outs it's not actually uncommon that a large account
likes what you did and returns the favor certainly because you put the foot forward and didn't really
ask for anything in return.
But also if that doesn't happen I know that's like hitting the lottery.
It also gets their attention and starts that relationship.
I mean you can comment on someone's post you can like it.
You can follow them.
They get notifications for that.
But tagging someone reposting their own post that actually is something that can get their attention
and you kind of build the relationship from there.
Now if you do that for 30 days you could easily have 15 accounts ready to work with.
You've already started a relationship with.
So you can kind of bust out the gate past that point.
This leads me into one of a weirder strategies I've seen when you tag someone in a repost.
What'll happen is it'll show up on their profile.
And the little tab or chose mentions.
OK.
One thing you can do and it's hard to pull off but if you do it it actually can work pretty well is
you take an account that you really wish would shout you out right and they have lots of followers and
they're similar enough to you if you'd like Konno square which you covered before you can actually see
when they post most often.
And if you time your reposts and your tag with when they post their post what can actually happen is
they'll bring in thousands and thousands of viewers to their page who might then bounce to their profile
and then see the mentioned post.
It's like I said really hard to pull off.
But if you can do it it can actually be a sweet boost.
All right now the second strategy is using shout outs to incentivize engagement.
Now it's not just for getting other accounts to give you you know some free exposure you could actually
use it to get people to give you better comments or to tag other friends.
So for instance you know you see that stuff all the time like best commande gets blank.
Well you can do.
I'll show you out in the next comment.
Best who ever makes the best comment.
OK that's another very common way of doing it that gets people who are just sitting there thinking about
the post who like the post but have nothing to say given that it's enough to actually jump in and do
something.
You can even do it kind of like a lottery too.
So some people see it and be like oh this guy wrote three paragraphs and I can write anything.
So you could say is I'll randomly pick two people out of my comment list and shout them out in the next
one.
And that kind of evens it out so you just get people posting anything.
The point is it gives you more engagement that increases your engagement rate that then increases the
reach of your post and Instagram's algorithm thinks you're a better account now.
An alternative way of doing it would be those.
Tag a friend who you know needs this product that I'm featuring or Tag a friend who you know this reminds
you of what you can do things like I'll shout out whoever tags the most people so you could say tag
friends who need this.
I'll shout out whoever tags most people.
That's a very common one.
To do let's say you have like a makeup account right.
And you say tag your friend who needs whatever.
OK maybe it's an actually interesting product.
You're going to get lucky and hit the jackpot with someone who has like 15 valley girl friends who will
tag all of them because not only would they actually be interested in it.
Now they have the incentive to actually sit there and do the tagging.
All right obscure strategy number three and these are called shout out groups.
Now later on we'll talk a little bit about things like engagement pods and effectively what these are
groups that you get together who are in similar ish enough spaces who all work together to help each
other increasing Ajman of their posts.
They do it by liking each other's posts or commenting on them or in some cases sharing them.
Well a shout out group specifically is when you get together with a group of people and every single
person takes turns posting one of their posts in the group and then when they do that everyone else
has agreed to read post them.
So what ends up happening is on Monday one person gets shouted out to say nine other accounts of 10
people in the group and twos that's the next person's turn wins the next person's turn.
Now why is this different than just getting a group of 10 people and you guys reach out every single
time someone post something.
Well it's because it concentrates the attention on one post at a time.
So if you did one every single day and someone just you know you only got one shout out for each post
but you got it for every single one.
Well I mean that gives you a boost and that's nice.
But if you had nine people hit one specific post that's enough of a concentration to raise your engagement
rate to actually push that post out to new people doesn't really work the other way around.
How exactly you go about doing this is kind of up to you.
There aren't really public groups that you can do this where it is usually for accounts that have worked
together before trust each other or you're friends with them or Usually it's between more established
accounts.
So as you start getting followers you start posting things you actually have a little bit of a tracker.
You can actually reach out to people and say do you want to start you know a shout out group.
Does it have to be 10 people you could just do it with four or five people.
It still has the same effect.
All right now the fourth and the last I'm scared what I'm going to mention are mentioned shout outs.
Now this is kind of strange and it's not necessarily something I endorse but I've seen it work and it's
something that if you feel like it just look into it and see what works for you.
What some people do is they'll go right for they make a post they'll go to a competitor and look at
their followers list or look at who are their most active commenters or like yours or something like
that.
And then all the deals are compiled list of those.
And then when they post a photo in the actual photo tag they'll tag a bunch of them.
OK what that does is you pre-select a bunch of people who probably like your stuff because your competitor
probably posts similar things to you.
You bring them over to your section because they get a very unique notification saying you are literally
tagged in a photo.
That's not something an average person sees every single day.
They come over and their likelihood of actually posting or commenting or liking goes up considerably.
So it's one way of maybe grabbing 20 people or 30 people who have a very high chance of engaging with
your post.
So it almost kind of sets a baseline for each one.
It's one of those ones you happy kind of careful with though because some companies out there I've seen
people do it with several thousand.
And it's something that the Instagram algorithm will look for because at that point you're kind of abusing
it and missing the point.
I think you could probably get away with like 50 but anything above that anyone who clicks the photos
just can't notice that you're clearly using this as like a cheap strategy to grab people below that.
It's actually a kind of a nice way to pull in people who you think really might actually like the photo.
All right guys.
Those are four strategies I think worth looking into.
They're more advanced and they're harder to pull off but they're definitely creative and they're definitely
interesting.
All right.
That being said.
See your next lecture.