Hey guys welcome back.
OK so this is day.
I have no idea.
I think after the fact we're gonna have to figure this out and label it.
Greetings from New York City.
OK so I have an update on three different things so you can see we're at twelve thousand nine hundred
followers.
I got a promotion from a large account.
They just picked up one of our posts kind of randomly and posted it so that one day we woke up and next
like 700 followers.
That was nice.
I would imagine that will happen more as the account gets larger and we get more attention.
We're going to show you this by e-mail looks like any other spike.
So right here and then it goes up like that.
Look at the table.
You pretty much always over 100 at least for the last week and then there was one period of time where
for whatever reason we just weren't growing very fast.
OK so some updates one we're going to try a new posting strategy.
OK.
So now we have 394 posts.
And the thing is with Instagram's new algorithm update they just don't give any attention to nonperforming
posts.
And if you post something and it just doesn't do well immediately like let's see this one.
378 views 52 likes.
And then if you look on the actual app because you know they don't give you data on the web version
to get the insights.
Yeah.
So literally one less than one percent of the people it reached weren't following you and you can see
most impressions came from the home screen or from the home screen basically.
So that means that people who were following me already like they're not going to pop up in the home
screen if they don't follow you.
And then other would be you know that's where those three people went over who were knew saw it.
So you'll notice quickly that like it either performs or it doesn't.
So if we went and tried to find one that did perform well it's like this one.
Yeah 24 percent weren't following us.
That's good right.
So I actually pulled in some people that I hadn't before but then if you look at the next one I see
that one one did fine.
This one did fine over the suitcase one for instance.
Yeah terrible less than 1 percent.
Turl So it's pretty much open or shut within Syria now which kind of sucks but so what we're gonna do
is we're going to go to the 394 post and we're going to pick out the best ones the ones that did get
at least over 20 percent distribution and had the highest engagement rates.
Now I do that using iconic square.
And then also just some manual work just scrolling through and then seeing what exactly which ones obviously
did better you know off the top of my head already know some of them like that plane that can land in
the water.
One of my favorites was the upright seats on airlines.
That was a funny one because you got huge amounts and occasionally gets people does he hit which I understand.
So we're going to do is take those and then see how many we have and then we're going to do is we're
just going to post those repeatedly and delete them as we go.
So you know there's a lot of other ways to do it.
We're going to play around with that.
But my idea is that we're going to take the best winners let's say there's 20 of them and post them
in the same exact pattern as this post.
You know one after the other after the other and then once you get to 20 then we essentially start deleting
the beginning of that loop and then you basically at the end of whatever two weeks three week period
he to be back here.
So you have these three hand it might look for a second like we had been posting a lot but that's it
because we're going to start the loop over again.
And the idea here is just that if I can just only post one side to well then my per day growth rate
is going to be higher.
Now some accounts do this some of the multi million follower accounts.
All they do is post like the same three posts over and over again.
And all they do is focus on making their wall as high quality as possible.
They make sure that you know they post three that are really popular.
Someone sees it and then when they go to their profile it's already a wall of the best hits so basically
they're focusing on it seems like is conversion right.
Because you look at my account you'll see how many people click through to a post and then you can see
how many followers.
That's effectively like my conversion rate.
So like this one right this glowing there was was a company building selling lantern that runs and you
cool.
OK so 15 profile visits and out of that one.
OK so one out of 15 essentially is the conversion rate.
Now there's other ones that just have better conversion rates so we're going to focus on those.
See if we can find on this one for some reason.
Wow there was huge amounts of 173 Wow and 130 followers just from that.
So like that one for instance just does really well for whatever reason.
OK so that's all we're going to focus on upping our conversion rate and only posting the best.
And we should see that we're going to grow a lot faster.
The big question is one to insert new content because we still have a lot of content in the content
pipeline and how long is this leave going to last because if it only lasts like a week then people are
going to notice you just post the same stuff over and over again.
So that's probably going to be a negative.
So I don't know.
We'll see how that works and we'll kind of decide.
My inclination is that we're going to slowly kind of trickle in new content to see how it performs and
if it does perform we add it to the loop and if it doesn't well then it just kind of stays up on the
screen and it you know it'll get buried over time OK the next thing with the zombies we were running
into that problem where they all want phone validation all the time.
And what sucked was I was using alcohol burner and I was just annoyed because I had to pay credit every
single time and they only last a certain amount of time and you know so I get a burner account less
14 days and then after 15 days the count needs phone validation again.
So I don't want to do that.
So what I'm going to do is I'm setting up the person that does a lot of the project management virtual
assistants to be able to do it herself she's in different country though so she can't always use these
phone numbers.
So what it it is I found in a system called next mo.
You guys are familiar with Twilio.
It's basically just as a mass system.
It doesn't look like much to someone who's not a developer but it allows you to create text message
applications easily somebody and it's a lot of gobbledygook.
But what you can do really easily is you can buy numbers right here so you go to numbers.
You were number by numbers and then I can ask for whatever I want so I can say United States on this
mess mobile lines.
And then if I want to be really picky like I only want numbers that are in San Francisco which start
with 4 1 5 or 1 4 1 5 Yeah I know there's like 6 5 0 as well too but doesn't matter anyway.
So these are all like San Francisco numbers and I can pay sixty seven euro cents which is like I don't
know depends on the conversion it's something like 75 cents and 80 cents U.S..
So I can buy that and pay that per month.
That's a hell of a lot better than doing the burner with the burner on it being like fleeced like three
dollars a month per account to keep doing them over and over again.
So got a bunch of numbers right here and there what I do is I just take a number like this and then
I insert it into one of the accounts for phone validation like so.
So for six nine I have to write it down because I can't copy my clipboard over to the Microsoft remote
server and I go to my remote server.
Let's say we want to validate science of the world.
And I can do this I can do it easy and lazy.
But the number here.
One two three.
OK.
Now verify my phone.
Now check your phone verification.
Then I can do really easily just go here.
A mass and then down here search messages and it's kind of clunky because it's just like a log system
and display in live time.
But whatever.
So then I can just paste that number I had search and there we go.
So it's 4 6 7 5 9 3 4 6 7 5 9 3.
There we go verify with code and walla.
OK.
So it's not necessarily faster than the burner.
I think it's maybe a little bit faster but these are persistent numbers going on to keep buying them.
But also I can just hand this off someone else so they can do it whenever they need to be validated.
Now that's fine.
And if you notice they grow when they're valid when they're enduring the phone validation they disappear
so they don't grow.
So you can notice like they go down they lose followers when that happens so we're just going to focus
on making sure they're constantly validated while I spend some time and experiment with phone verified
accounts and aged account see if we can get around that.
We did take some time and go through these and change all the settings so that they weren't just posting
this one account my main account.
They're also posting from other accounts and also that they didn't have blatant like they didn't have
an station over everything.
Change it up a little bit and it didn't really seem to matter I think because these accounts are essentially
flagged as being probably Spammy.
So they're not really going to change their minds about these accounts.
We to create new ones and start from scratch.
But he didn't use phone validations.
I think it still should be worthwhile just to keep them constantly validated.
But because now we have a system that's faster it should be something easier.
I thought about making a new application for this and making it really simple.
What would happen is you put in a number of click verify and then you go to a u r l and it would just
display the numbers for all of them so you don't have to go to the log screen and then search the number
and then find it.
But you know it only saves you like two steps.
So it really wasn't worth having to figure out and then deal with that like do you store the messages
what framework do you use to post it.
Oh you need S-sh access on your server but I know it doesn't work that so.
Yeah.
Anyway that's hard to do now.
So these should be running a lot more smoothly.
The last change is that Instagram just released what are called Blake quote stories.
So the idea is that when you do stories a lot of people want to reference a post they have right now
when we do stories we've been doing that but we've been having to edit them independent Lee.
So we would make the video for like this suitcase right.
But if we go to this story we would have to do no because nothing we had to do a really short version
of it with a one sentence explanation.
Here's the suitcase and that was fine.
It's just that again if I want to go and see the account do I have to do like I have to scroll up.
Well if you're an account you can scroll up because it'll say see more and then it'll take you to an
embedded browser to the Instagram account.
So it's just not it's not useful like that it's not going to get a lot of lot more engagement doesn't
stay within the app.
Now all we can do though is just share the videos themselves and it'll show it as if it's like a card
and automatically get the background.
So what you do is you go down here and click on this little paper airplane thing and then go and post
the story.
OK so then right here I have the post you know automatically does the background and then I have to
do is just put a quick description up here.
Click it and then I'll you know say it's a baby seat suitcase and then I'll put you know the face whatever
at the top and then you know the rest of it's up to you will probably do is put a tag for the account
down here so they can just click it if they want to do that and then maybe a hash tag.
Right.
Because remember these can show up and hash tag feeds.
So this one I don't like child innovation or like child technology or something might work so you can
do.
I don't even know there's a hash I would have to look at it first.
But you kind of get the ideas of child trafficking.
No child technician no tech child tech teltech whatever.
So there you go.
And be careful you don't delete these.
There you go.
So that's what the posts are going start to look like.
And then what can happen is if they want to see the post they just click it and it goes see post takes
him directly to my sis my account.
And that's way way better.
More people are going engage more often.
They think they also work better personally in my opinion.
But anyway so just following up with the trends that'll be a lot better.
OK.
Pass that one I'm working on I'm going to start working more on the aged accounts for the zombies and
then also spending more time getting these best hits kind of post like the post loop.
Correct.
And then I'm also starting to kind of conceptualize what some of the giveaways and the live video strategies
are going to be.
So those will be coming up.
All right guys.
Cool.
I'll see you next time.