All right guys welcome back.
Now that we are at the point where we are pretty confident that we've identified the types of contractors
that we need to hire to work with to get each section of our content strategy done.
It's now up to us to make a job posting into posts on up work.
Now it's up to you if you want to use people per hour freelancer gooroo dot com or virtual assistant
dot com I believe is one.
But you use up work just because it's the widest net it has the largest variety of people.
So for like for instance I can hire writers and I can hire editors and I can hire people who can do
keyway like quality assurance or testing or pretty much anything I can really think of I can find someone
there.
Other other platforms that are more optimized for say like data entry like freelance or dot coms better
for people who are doing really really simple kind of monotonous rote tasks and you can get a better
value there.
But there is value in being able to keep everything in one platform so that's what I'm going to use
for now.
OK.
So once you create an account up work you only have to give them a credit card or anything you can just
say post new job.
OK.
Now they change their onboarding screens quite a bit.
So keep this in mind.
It might look slightly different.
They seems like every month their process a little bit different.
So when you go to create a new job post then we'll continue.
OK now the name of your job post.
Well really the simplest way of doing this is just to describe it in one sentence.
There's really no benefit to trying to sell them on it because that's not really going to get more people
to check it out it's actually kind of weird if someone says quick an easy task.
Generally that's just not good.
You don't track people who don't want to do difficult tasks which I think is just counterproductive.
But for the most part I try to give them the main keywords right so like if we were hiring video editors
what do they need to know.
Right.
It's going to be I need.
It's going to be need video editors right many self-identifying the group I'm looking for not just someone
I need video editors need.
I can say that plural meaning I want to hire multiple people to pile videos on new tech for Instagram
account.
OK so that's a pretty decent idea of what's involved here.
I don't need to give them any of the parameters like 60 second videos or we're only using lower thirds
taxed or you know any other requirements on what type of media to collect then what I can do is go down
here a job category and it says event video production that's literally going to be looking for people
that are in person usually.
So easy is going on to design and creative and then it's video production.
So that's a wider category.
This is just too specific.
We're not necessarily making advertising videos there's people who specialize in that.
And that's not what we're doing.
And then obviously these are other specialties as well.
Like I said I'm making it next.
Now here is where we put our description and any other information that we need to kind of get across
what it is that we're doing.
So I generally suggest is pull open your handy dandy text editor and pull open a new tab then what you
can do is say job post and we'll say this is for the video editors.
OK.
Now the best way that I found to break these up and keep in mind you don't have to write something that
is just perfect it's not something that you'd expect like a Fortune 500 company to write.
It just has pages and pages of information.
You need something that gets like 80 percent across simply and ideally doesn't leave anything out.
But at the end of the day people are going to message you if they're interested in it and if there's
any more details you can then fill them in.
I like to do it typically like this.
I like to start with the what.
Then tell them the why.
Then tell them the how.
And then tell them when and then I like to do extras.
OK.
So all of this pattern it's pretty hard to leave anything out.
You might find you know that you miss something we can always go back and edit the job post.
So what would be a usually one to choose description of what you're doing.
I need video editors to help make videos or my Instagram account and share an account that I might give
them a little bit more information about what it is.
These videos are only say 30 to 45 seconds long and they cover new and new and impressive technology.
OK.
Now for me that's typically going to be enough because if I say you're going to do it with this software
Well that's that's not what.
Anymore.
That's how.
So that's usually enough for a one to two maybe three sentences on the one.
Now I like to follow this up with a why just because I'm a person who likes context and I don't think
that you're going to get a lot of people motivated about your project if they don't know why you're
doing it even if it's just to fill in.
OK.
Well we're doing it for making an online course or making an Instagram account.
Even that is helpful it's not going to change the way they work but knowing why they're doing it is
helpful.
No one likes being a cog like hammering something together and they have no idea what it's even going
to go into or become.
So for the why I might say I'm starting a new Instagram account cover's cool new technology and science.
I want to make videos similar to it's always useful to use anchor points to say similar to this.
So it kind of frames their understanding of it.
Now it's similar to what exactly like.
So I might say similar to.
And then I might give say like the link to tech inciter.
Right or whatever it is that we've identified as something that we want to emulate.
OK.
Now then we might say the how and this is where we worked on our requirements before Howard going to
be the requirements.
You can write them from scratch here perfectly fine if you are going to do that.
I like to start from the very first step.
So I would say I would just give a description of how the process will go and then I can maybe put in
the requirements of written them or you know write them from scratch.
So I would say first you will take a new article or it will take a new article that isn't listed in
a Trillo column and then I'll give them an example such as you know here's an example of a web or a
technology we might cover then I need you to take the pre written caption for it and copy it over and
over.
Next you'll find video clips that match each miniature match each caption and then I might put parentheses
captions are added up into one two two sentence chunks that explain the new technology and a basic narrative
format.
OK.
So then I'd say like then you'll reduce each clip down to a five to nine just kind of making this up
seconds per clip and attach in a lower thirds box the the caption stated with each clip OK and then
really kind of getting into the requirements and parameters so if you can watch the requirements lecture
go back and look at that but it would basically come down to.
I might even just say requirements like this and it might just list off some things so I might say videos
must be less than 60 seconds but longer than 30 seconds.
Videos must be exported at least 10 ETP.
Then I might even give them some requirements with the clips that they're collecting and that honestly
I might even do that is an entirely separate job because finding the right clips is really kind of the
secret sauce to making a good video.
But I might give them some basic instructions if I was going to go for this integrated route where the
video person who's assembling all the clips putting the captions doing the timing in the music.
But if I was really going to go for this integrated approach with this person is assembling all the
clips adding music and exploring everything and handling that whole process well then I get it maybe
give them some tips at least the ones that I can think of right now so I might say like clip's must
be directly directly relevant royalty free and have no jerky movements or overlayed text.
So you know I might rewrite that to be a little more clear but what I basically mean is if you're going
to have a clip that's talking about recycling I need to show recycling don't show the Earth OK that's
not relevant.
It needs to be more specific than that.
It also needs to be royalty free.
Don't grab something from someone who has a claim to this who might tell you to tear down the video
that's a huge pain on Instagram.
And then also things like no jerky movement trying to get them to read text over a video.
It's pretty important that you don't have a camera that's just going like flicking crazy.
That's just a recipe for motion sickness.
And then we might say or overlayed taxed.
I don't mean for that is don't grab a YouTube video that already has text overlaid on it.
Then I might just say something like.
All video clips must be at least 720 P and that's just because if you're going to make video it's a
good idea to make sure it's all at least consistently high resolution.
If you have a choice between low resolution very relevant and high resolution but decent or irrelevant
you should probably go with the high resolution.
It's very rarely the case that going to run into that type of situation where you can't find anything
more relevant.
Hi rez.
I mean it is an 18 and 19 already.
So most things are already at at least intonated 10 ATP but occasionally you might actually run into
that and you might have to make a decision.
And the last thing I might say and you might have forgotten to do this is make sure to add music from
the list provided songs.
Ok then when this is when I'm going to describe how much I need from each person and how many of me
these videos were in a produce per week so I might say we're producing I think we're doing three to
four videos a day so twenty to twenty or thirty videos a week 20 to 30 videos a week and I need someone
who can spend.
I mean this is just a calculation in your head right.
Because you've made the videos for you know how long it should take.
You should also know that you'll get better at it.
So it's a little bit faster.
Originally took me two hours.
So I think ideally we'll get to a point where it's like 45 minutes maybe 40 minutes.
So if I need 20 to 30 I want to hire two people minimum so they're going to need to do.
You know it's probably like two hours a day right.
So in at least two hours a day and then that's just me meeting bare minimum right like this isn't even
a recipe for stockpiling videos or going to other things you might want to say you might want to just
say like what time zones.
They need to work and if that's something that's important to you if you need to be there with them
have communication with them you might want to say how long they have to turn it around.
That is also something that I consider when because it's a time requirement other things you might want
to mention could be let's say when they start.
That's another big thing especially video editors tell you it's freelance video editors as they always
kind of plan these in advance so a lot of times you'll find someone you really like and they'll say
well I can't start until you know Thursday or X from now or whatever it is.
So make sure that you stay.
You give some kind of statement as to I need to start now or I need to start within the week or maybe
even have a set start deadline.
I don't think that's particularly realistic.
But again it's kind of up to you and the other thing is letting them know how long this will last so
you might say you know this is a long term position something that we're going to do for the next six
months.
That's usually a good thing people like long term work they don't like pickup work that they do for
a day and then they have to find something else to do.
And that's kind of the bane of freelancers is they end up spending a lot of their time finding jobs
and not as much time as they would like actually doing what they're good at.
OK.
Now let's run a little bit long so in the next section we're going to do is we're going to talk about
what goes under the extras which pretty much we're going to talk about running trials and then we'll
take what we have and we'll throw them into an up or post I can show you the rest of the process and
then after that what we'll do is we'll look over the real posts that are used to hire the people that
have been making the post for innovation station.
OK.
It in.