Hey guys, welcome back.
OK, this lecture we're going to talk about a really easy
optimization for your posting, especially at first,
and that is picking the right time to post.
Now, everything we do is about optimization. An unoptimized
account on Instagram will grow, and chances
are you've seen accounts that do everything wrong, you
pretty much see the opposite of what we're talking
about in this course, and they still have followers.
That's fine.
They will grow, but they won't grow very fast, or at least
they won't grow as fast as they could if they chose
to do the right things, or at least optimize something.
And one of those ways to ensure you grow a little bit faster
is to make sure that you're posting at the right time.
We've already talked about what stuff to post, but we
haven't talked about when to post during the month,
during the week, and during the day.
You might not have thought that this makes much of a difference to you and your Instagram strategy, and I honestly
don't blame you.
I never would've thought this really makes a huge difference, especially if you have an international community
of followers, you would assume that posting at midnight is fine because it's, you know, noon somewhere. And well, it actually
makes a significant difference.
It's not game changing.
It's not going to turn your account upside down,
but it can make a pretty decent boost.
I mean, generally when we see people use an
optimized posting strategy, they get something
like 20% to 30% more engagement.
Now, first we need to preface this with asking, when
we're saying when do we want to post during the day,
what do we care about the most?
Do we care about when people are on it?
Do we want times when the posting
is lowest so it's less saturated?
Do we want the times when people engage the most?
Well, I'll just tell you right upfront.
Primarily we care about when people engage
and then secondarily we care about
when are people on the platform.
And luckily those two things overlap for the most part.
So you can think to yourself,
when is it the case that during the week a lot of people
are on Instagram but they're not engaging, they're
not liking, they're not following, they're not commenting?
Well, if you guessed "during work,"
that's a pretty good guess actually.
We see that a lot.
So especially, say, East Coast time zone in the U.S.,
you'll notice that people who have accounts over there
look at a lot of things, but they don't spend
a lot of time clicking or commenting.
So it's kind of like, they're just looking down at their
phone and screwing with it in a meeting and
they're not using their fingers yet because
they're not really committed to it.
Now, the opposite would be, say, during a commute.
So we notice that right before the 9 to 5 period,
you see a lot of people engaging
and a medium amount of people on it.
It depends if you drive, it kind of depends if you
have to do work before you show up at work.
Now, the other thing I want to say is that picking the
best time based off of the general population of
Instagram is good, but it's not as good as picking the
best times based off of your audience specifically.
Your audience is the most relevant and the variation in when people post and when they engage for your audience
is going to be stronger than the general population.
Later on, we'll use some of the tools that we
actually previously signed up with, remember
we talked about Iconosquare and Social Rank.
We'll use those to figure out our audience,
when are they on, because that often deviates from the norm,
but for the most part now the rule of thumb, at least
in the first month of posting, is that we're going to
stick to the general population guidelines. So with
that being said, let's start with the first graph
that we need to pay attention to,
and that is days of the week.
Now, there's not really a big difference here.
What you'll notice is on Monday people engage less, probably that's something to do with that whole work thing, probably
focused on work, they're not really
in the weekend mentality yet.
And, for whatever reason, Wednesdays
are the days that people engage the most.
But we will notice that the variation between
these, 4.4 to 4.9 is just not really that big.
And this is the average number of engagements per post.
It's just, that's not a big jump.
That's really only something like a 10% difference.
So it's not something that I think you really
need to spend a lot of time thinking about.
But if for some reason you have to choose between posting
on a Monday or posting on a Wednesday, you post
on a Wednesday. Now, the next graph is a lot more relevant
to us, and that is the 24-hour graph, showing when
throughout the day people post, and this is way more important, because you'll notice the variation is quite a bit bigger.
You notice that the worst time to post is at 9:00 AM,
with the second worst time being around 6-ish PM, and
the best times to post, actually it's a tie between 2:00 AM and 5:00 PM, and then the runner up to best time is around 10:00 PM.
Now, what you'll notice between the lowest minimum
and the highest maximum is the difference is about 1.2.
So that's actually a difference close to about 29%.
So if you post during the correct time,
you could theoretically have 29% more,
couple that with posting on the right day,
it could almost be like 39% more.
What's interesting to take into account
is just looking at this and then trying to guess why it is
that it spikes at 2:00 AM, 5:00 PM, and then 10:00 PM,
and I'll let you guess,
but for the most part it's just downtime.
This is something you'll notice, people usually get off
work at 5:00 PM, so they probably have some downtime
right at the end of the day, they're probably checking in to see maybe what's something to do later on that day, probably
clearing through messages or DMs that they have,
at 10:00 PM it's kind of that weird twilight zone
where you've done pretty much everything you need, you're
done with dinner, and now you have this blank bit of time
before you go to bed, and then
2:00 AM also is just for people
who stay up late, can't sleep,
that's often a time that they'll browse. Now, the local minimums
we have that 9:00 AM, and then that 6:00 PM, so the 9:00
AM is probably because that's right when work starts,
so people probably are going to try to focus,
it doesn't really make sense right
when the bell starts for work, you're on Instagram.
And then 6:00 PM, you know, that kind of, it's probably
a rebound from using it at 5:00 PM, and then
you're not using it at 6:00, because I don't know who sits on Instagram for two hours from 5:00 to 7:00. From 7:00 to 9:00,
you notice that it slowly starts to rise and that's
really because people are going into dinner, and
that's not when they're not going to be using it,
but as people, earlier eaters start
finishing around 8:00 and then 8:30,
you see it starts to tick up, and then
most people are done by 9:00.
All right, so what does that mean for us?
If you're going to post, try to post when there's
a peak. Try to post at 2:00 AM, 10:00 PM, and right
around 5:00 PM. Try not to post at 9:00 AM
or 6:00 AM, just try to time it as well as you can.
I personally not going to follow this religiously, and
you'll see this in my posting.
But for the most part when I'm scheduling posts, you'll notice that the first three posts I'll pick on exactly these time periods,
and then I'll kind of move on to the second best ones,
and the third best one, and then eventually I just get to a
point where I'm posting even at the low points.
All right, guys, that's it for now.
Take this set of graphs and kind of internalize it,
keep it in mind, just generally consider it best practice.
Later on we'll have a lot of data about our own audience,
and that data is definitely going to trump this, but for
now, this is the default we're going to use when posting.
All right, guys.
See you next lecture.