PR is welcome back.
Cause this lecture going to do a another post and I'm going to switch out from videos to photos.
Now I'm not going to show you me posting every single one up till 10 because 10 was the goal we're trying
to get to but I'm going to show you the photo because this is a change of format for me.
OK so down here we have the post that I just put I've been trying to record this over and over the last
half an hour.
The iPhone just stops recording randomly.
So I'm sorry.
So what I did was over here and there I wrote it out and I put the image here.
I made that and Kanva just like the way we made the dean common quote then.
But what's your favorite fact about Steve Jobs That's called action.
I'm going to try putting it at the top and then down here have the top five facts you know.
And then I put some facts and kind of rewrote them so they're a little more punchy.
Cool.
OK.
So the other ones that's just not the style music for the videos.
But I mean it's I don't really know how else to do it so what I'm going to do for clothes is I'm just
going to write about the person who told the quote OK I think that's a little more educational and it
makes sense.
And we had one issue you notice that we originally posted on the dummy.
Dummy didn't do so hot.
So we had some screw ups there.
And in the main one that's haunted by it just again I screwed up a little bit.
So it kind of is wrapped around.
Mean you need to break that up again and I need to add a couple more comments too high.
The hashtags that I.
So here with the hashtags now I change the hassocks slightly.
Word of Wisdom.
Instagram doesn't like when you use the same exact hash tags over and over and over again.
So if you just get a copy and paste halftracks make sure that you have a couple of hours in between.
Otherwise I don't think you're spamming and it can be a bad thing.
So for this I mean later on we're going to optimize hash tags and then we'll get into like how you cycle
them out and pick the ones that work.
Right now I just copy paste the old ones and then I just took out the obvious ones like I took out like
Kickstarter it was a hash tag.
OK so I remove that and I put in some stuff like motivational clothes Steve Jobs and Steve Jobs quote.
Sure.
OK.
So that's where I'm going to be getting some traffic from now to crack this whole screw up and see if
we can do it over here and there.
So you what actually happened.
Is that an extra little space right there.
That's bad.
That's what happened.
We got it.
Yep.
That extra long just kills it.
You've got to understand that sometimes your keyboard will just add this stuff.
So where did it go.
B.
Now we can do is copy this back if we correct the problem.
Now we just want a quick here at the whole thing.
Oh leave it there.
So that should work.
I agree.
Yeah it looks better.
So a fear factor of Steve Jobs whatever.
Right.
That's what it looks like.
And I put hashtags and so you actually see some traffic come in on this which is a little weird considering
that I'm not actually trying to actively go out and get people yet but whatever.
So let's see.
It looks fine.
I think it might put an extra space on that top line.
But other than that I think I like this.
It's hiding right there so we shouldn't see that.
OK so that's good.
I'll check in two years later when I have all ten posted and then we can kind of see what it looks like.
I'm not going be changing anything substantially so I don't need to really update you guys.
All right.
So the next letter.