You guys will come back.
OK so I'm going to give you an update on where we're at as of September for something like that.
OK so we finally hit 25000.
I apologize for not doing more updates since the last one the last time I checked in or something like
14000.
So a lot's changed in terms of followers since then but the reason it really check in is just because
I haven't done anything.
Honestly I really have not been touching this at all.
Only thing I've been doing on my regular routines of getting on and commenting on other people's photos
and then responding to all of my comments the content team pretty much takes care of the rest of it.
So that means I haven't even done any of the giveaways of the lives yet.
Yes I now I really should do this.
I just keep convincing myself is a better time to do it.
Maybe I'll do that in the next video or something like that.
But so what.
The only thing that has really changed I think since the last time we posted and I think we talked about
it in the last one was that we're going to try a more unmodulated version of the best hits.
So I talked with us in the course also in the fall of Long's where one strategy is to take your best
posts and then consistently repost them and delete them.
A lot of accounts do that.
And so we kind of tried this hybrid version where we were posting what we thought were the best posts
mixed in with some of the new ones because we were still producing new posts and then we kind of had
to like a 21 day cycle something like that so after 21 days we go back and delete all of the ones that
were repo's leaving the new ones there.
And then we kind of like start over again.
So that kind of worked.
The thing that really made a big difference and I'll show you there is a big change in our growth.
Unfortunately I kind of square.
Has this problem where it keeps disconnecting and reconnecting.
So what will happen is it will look like I have no followers for four days and there are a ton of followers
in one day and that's just because it disconnected for some reason and I didn't get to it in time or
I thought I did but it didn't.
So let's look at the last.
I don't know let's see where we're at.
OK.
So yeah.
So these ones are all screwed up when you lose 123 followers.
That's just an issue with iconic square.
I also didn't gain 625 in a day or 487.
It was just trying to catch up I think does a really bad job of like really configuring its calculation
once it does get reconnected.
I honestly don't know how this works but you can kind of see here that we had a really consistent clip
of 300 400 300 200 300 400 300 etc days and it kind of started around.
See this was a shout out.
We actually got some free thank God around Yeah about three weeks ago.
So that was kind of the start of our current round of best best hits posting.
So we're 175 that's fine 200 200 but you notice it just starts to stretch up and then we start really
kind of hitting consistently in the three hundreds potentially of 400.
So that was a big factor in our growth.
I mean it's big when you add a thousand every three days whereas before you're out a thousand every
like eight days.
And that's really just because we had change up our posting strategy a little bit of the tweak that
we had made.
So originally we were just looking for posts that from the I had higher engagement because I chorus
girls are your best posts but it won't show you all of them based on engagement.
So we are trying our best to just say OK well we think this one is popular this one is popular and we
are posting like that it didn't really make a big difference.
So what we did was instead used in Seagram's own analytics to tell us what was getting us more exposure
because that's the biggest thing.
I mean it doesn't matter if we keep sending our selfies same people it's going to grow or count.
So we would find accounts like this where you get viewer insights and to the eye it doesn't really look
like it's that different.
It only has seven comments that's not a ton although we don't have a ton of comments on our account
right now.
U.N. site says 19 profiles is at 6000 reach.
OK that's kind of the first hint that it had more but this is the big one.
It just says 21 percent weren't following you.
Now that's not remarkable.
I mean if you remember the very beginning of the course before Instagram's apocalyptic update we could
get 60 percent new people every single time we posted.
But now a post that doesn't do well you might get 1 percent to 5 percent.
So we just started looking for these as if it was anything over like 15 percent or 10 percent.
Then we know it was something that was worth to be posting and so we really just focused on those.
See if we can find an unpopular one.
Let's see that one was doing better I guess these are all kind of our best ofs So let's see.
It's battery because that's a 10 percent it's a little bit lower we might have ignored that one.
Let's see.
I remember that one did well.
OK so let's take one of the older ones that just was not good.
And so like this one there was a health and well-being app hopes of boosting happiness great.
So if you look at the viewing insights one profile visit only 5 percent weren't following us.
So that was the real indicator that kind of helped us figure out what's going to work because engagement
right doesn't necessarily mean anything.
You know if you're using friends it's like a like exchange or using a follow BOD or doing a lot of things
at once you don't really know if it's the content that's doing well or if instagram likes it or what.
But we were able to figure out.
So let's see this one.
Nine percent.
OK so that's still pretty low.
Right like is it a threshold we're looking for was over 10 percent.
See this one.
Seven percent.
Yeah I mean these are pretty low.
So we just kind of focused on ones that were just anything over 10 percent.
And so you would get a lot of like see like this one yeah.
I mean 28 percent are following you.
Look this is an incredible one.
This was a carousel kind of like a weekly Delio but because it was the best of the best sets it did
really well.
So that was the biggest modification we made.
That was largely responsible for the uptick in growth.
And now you'll notice we're actually posting from the very beginning because we've essentially run out
of content.
We're not producing it as fast as I'm posting but it's zero 674 Post currently.
These are not all unique.
By the way that means that I can start posting from the very beginning and there's no way that someone
would remember that we posted this one.
This is one of the very first ones we ever posted.
And it was way back when I think it was one of the third or fourth ones we ever posted.
So no one's going to remember that and if they do we're kind of scanning the Commons just to make sure.
So that was the biggest change and besides that we still have to follow OBOT working on Jervy.
So that brings in who knows 50 to 100 maybe a day maybe 50 to 80 something like that me liking stuff
and commenting and people tagging that's a big one but I think the biggest thing is just figuring out
what Instagram likes.
Now whether or not this is a sustainable strategy I don't really know because best hits means it's the
best and if I have let's say 500 unique posts and rolling to post the top 20 percent and even that's
kind of pushing it that's only 100 posts.
So why would run out pretty quickly.
I mean I think I did make that last for twenty days.
Ideally what we are going to try to do is we're going to try to slip in New ones as we go just to test
to see if we have more goodies and we'll keep reposting the ones that were really good with.
The ideal range of about a month I think because I think if we post for a month the best hits and then
rehash them and start posting them again the next month and that's enough time that people aren't really
going to notice anyway.
It's just a battle of stretching your content.
OK so next check on all show you what's changed.
I'll tell you if we tried new strategies or hey if I did nothing.
I mean I really did not do much on this one in the last like three weeks.
That's kind of the beauty of this system.
I have not touched this and we've gained almost 10000 followers so.
All right so pretty sweet we see in the next lecture.