All right guys, welcome back.
OK, now that we've hopefully gotten the username of
our dreams, we need to do the next thing in line, which
is to set our account name.
Yes, I know they sound exactly the same, because they're
kind of the same thing, but they also kind of aren't.
It's just for some reason this idiosyncrasy of Instagram
that your user name isn't your actual name.
Now, remember this was originally created for people to
share photos, specifically ones that were self-conscious
about the quality of their photos, and hence
that's why they had filters to begin with.
So each account was only supposed to be a person.
Well, that's great.
So why not just make the username the name?
Well, because the username has to work on a URL,
so that people can access your page, and well, you
know, URLs, you can't have a space in them, for instance.
Now, seriously,
try to go to Facebook.com / your name with an actual space in it.
It just explodes.
Also, the username has to stay lowercase.
Why? Again, because some neck beard 30 years ago
thought it would make sense that capitalizing letters
in a URL would take you to different content
on a server versus the lowercase version.
Again, try that one. Try to go to your name on Facebook
and try to capitalize one letter, it doesn't work.
That's also why special characters
don't work in your username.
So if you wanted your username to be an actual name,
it would need spaces and capitalization.
Can't do that with URLs, so we have this ungodly mix of
name and username, not the same but not completely different.
What's that?
You never really wanted to know why
there were separate parts of the profile?
Well, excuse me for imparting you with a useless factoid.
Anyway, they're different.
Your name shows up in two different places, here at
the top of your bio in bold, and here in the search
results. And that leads me to the key takeaway of
picking a name. When you search on Instagram,
it only uses two fields, username and name.
Yes, it is surprisingly unsophisticated in that way,
especially when it has so much more information to
use, like your bio, to make a decision on relevancy.
Also, there's plenty of algorithms out there now that
can figure out what's in a photograph, so that would
make sense, they could parse that up
and use it in their search, but they don't.
Anyway, this at least clears things up for us.
We know exactly what matters - name and username
for search, because search is pretty important.
So when choosing a name, we're going to always
be thinking of keywords. What keywords do we
want to rank for, and being honest, are our theoretical
fans or customers going to be searching for us?
If you make WordPress plugin tools, are people going
to be searching for WordPress on Instagram?
Wouldn't that be something you'd
more likely search for on Google?
So what I like to say is pick 2-3 keywords that you think
people might be searching for and that relate to you.
If you don't know what relates to you,
my favorite thing to do is go to ranksonic.com/generate-keywords.html, I'll put it up on the screen.
OK.
It's also in the resources. What you can do is
just plug in the URL of your website, and it'll just
look at what you have going on and give you a
list of keywords it would assume your niche is
interested in. When I plug in evankimbrell.com,
I get things like start a business, online classes,
business ideas, I also get like web development, which is
a little bit weird. So I might scratch some of those down,
although of those three, I would imagine really only
someone searching for, like, probably business ideas,
although I could be wrong.
That's my general take on Instagram right now.
I don't know why they'd be searching for the other stuff.
It only takes a couple seconds to proof this out.
I mean, just go to Instagram, go to search,
and just type it in, and see what happens.
Once you do have a couple keywords though, just
set those aside, and then follow along as I ask you
a couple of basic questions.
How would you summarize what the account is? If you're
a business, what's a clever one short sentence, it's about
30 characters, so maybe four or five short words that
summarize you? In the business case, it's usually pretty easy.
Use the headline on your home page for instance.
You could use your brand motto or slogan, or you can
even use the subtitle you chose for your website, and
I mean, subtitle meaning,
like when you search for your name in Google, what actually shows up as the first sentence underneath the link you click.
Hopefully you set that, because
that's actually pretty important.
It's part of the meta data, if you don't have
that, Google doesn't like you. Anyway,
one of those will always work, and it's generally the same
case if you're creating account for a person or personality.
If you haven't yet built a business around yourself,
then you might have to get a little bit more creative.
So what exactly do you want people
to think about you and your profile?
What do you do on this page?
Answer that question as succinctly as you can.
Remember, we can always go back and change this later.
And if you honestly can't think of anything at all,
it's perfectly fine to just put your name or your brand name.
Actually, it's pretty easy.
You don't stick out because probably
80% of the accounts you see do this,
so it just doesn't look that weird.
It's really just that it's more of a
wasted opportunity than anything else.
So I think of it kind of like blogs and headlines. To go to a blog,
you go to a URL, and then you get blasted with a
giant headline that essentially summarizes the post
and it entices you to read on. When you share the blog
post, you usually only see those two things as well,
the URL and the headline.
So it's kind of like that. If you wrote a blog post about
your account, what would the headline say? The
next step is basically to see if you can get one of
your keywords in that headline. If you can, great.
If you can't, it's fine, you can always try later.
So that's really it.
I mean, what's the one-two punch that will get people to click
your account and get what you're there for, and do that quickly?
Mystery in this case really doesn't work.
If I can give you one piece of advice here, it's don't use
the same thing for both your username and your name.
Not only do you look amateurish,
but you're wasting that space for search.
If you're trying to rank for entrepreneur and you
just put "entrepreneur" four times as your account
name, Instagram doesn't count that
four times, it doesn't make a difference.
Now, let's look at some accounts
that are actually doing this well.
Again, we'll look at that company called Foundr Australia,
they do pretty well on Instagram. Foundr is
their username, that's the company name,
but then for their actual account name,
they put Young Entrepreneur Magazine.
Yes. OK.
Now, if you saw Foundr and you didn't know what
it was, that title in bold and in the search would tell
you instantly what it was, even before you clicked on it.
Double points because they got entrepreneur in
there, since that's a big thing they're going for.
OK, now here's an individual, let's look at Dan Martell.
If you don't know him, he started a website called Clarity
FM, it's actually a tool I referenced in my other courses.
He put Growth Minded Entrepreneur great. It's a three
word summary of essentially who he is, or who he
wants to be, he specializes in growth and entrepreneurship,
so that works pretty well, and he
did a good job of doing that.
Now, here's another one on a totally
different vertical, 1minutemakeup.
OK.
If you read just that username, you wouldn't know what we're talking about, but the name in bold explains it instantly.
It says, oh, what's 1minutemakeup? It's makeup tutorials.
Now, why am i looking at this page?
Makeup tutorials. Great.
So hopefully this makes sense to you.
You don't have to do it this way, but it's the
way that I would consider the best practice.
There are a shocking amount of accounts out there
that just copy their username into their name field,
and well, I shed a single tear for them. You use them
to summarize your account or who you are, and you
want to try if you can fit some relevant keywords in.
Remember, you only get 30 characters, so choose wisely.
All right, guys, that's it for now.
See you next lecture.