Practical Tools-User Stories.
Our first Practical Tool is User Stories.
So, what are User Stories?
User Stories are an agile term for what traditionally
have been called software requirements.
User Stories are brief statements of the intent or need that
the system must do for a particular user.
User Stories are not detailed requirements.
We will address detailed requirements later in this module.
This is a simple User Story template.
So, as a role, say a sales clerk, I want or need to perform a particular feature,
say a split tender transaction, that's using,
say, cash and maybe a credit card at the same time,
so that there is a benefit.
What is the benefit?
The customer has more payment options.
That is a simple example of a User Story.
What is very important is that User Stories help bridge
the gap between users and developers.
That is one of your main jobs.
If you do this well,
your resulting system will accurately reflect your user requirements.
Practical Tools-User Stories.
It is very important that User Stories are written in the user's own words.
User Stories are written from the point of view of the user,
and written in the language that your customers would use.
No techie-talk here, please.
User Stories focus on the value or result users get from doing this thing.
So, when you are facilitating a workshop,
be sure you coax out the benefit as part of the user story.
A User Story is performed by one or more user types, also known as actors.
An example of an actor would be a clerk or a manager.
Many times, User Stories are very similar,
or just variations of a main User Story.
I suggest you aggregate them into User Story Summaries.
Here is an example of a User Story where a student
can enroll in a class via email.
Here is an example where a student can drop a class.
Certainly the key actor is the student, and since they both apply to the student,
you might consider a User Story Summary as containing those two stories.
Summaries are informal containers that help you group User Stories.
Here is a User Story to open a class.
What User Story Summary might this User Story be contained?
Since an administrator, the actor, can only open a class,
it would be grouped with other administration stories.
Practical Tools-Use Cases.
Use Cases are similar to User Stories,
in that they are still written in the user's words
and express the expected outcome, but provide a little more detail.
Again, no techie-talk, please.
Use Case Template comprised of a Use Case title, or name, like drop a class.
A brief description, just one or two sentences is usually enough.
Actors or users that relate to this Use Case,
such as a student or administrator.
Flow of events.
Express the main flow of events and interactions between
the actors that use this Use Case.
There are optional elements, as well, that you can add.
Alternative paths or extensions.
These would be variations on the above cases.
Preconditions.
The things that must have already happened in the system prior to this Use Case.
Success scenario.
What is supposed to happen, described as a series of steps.
Post conditions.
What the system will have done by the end of these steps?
Scope Validation.
Remember our Project Definition Template from Module 1?
It included a high-level scope.
So, our User Stories must fit into the context of the project definition.
Look for gaps/overlaps of the User Stories and cases,
and work with your customers to refine, and especially fill in the gaps.
A simple, visual representation of all of my User Stories,
Cases, and Summaries can be very helpful, just to see how it all fits together, and to ensure the scope is covered.