Practical Tools-Workflow Diagrams.
When should you use Workflow Diagrams?
When Use Cases are just too complex to understand,
many times Use Cases, or collections of Use Cases,
are too complex to be shown as Mockup,
or a Wireframe is insufficient to fully understand the business rules.
This additional clarity, or richer understanding of the business rules,
will be needed before you begin to develop your Mockups,
and especially your screen navigation.
If these conditions are true, consider using a Workflow Diagram.
A Workflow determines the logical progression of tasks
that will be performed and by whom.
There are many types of Workflow Diagrams you may want to use,
such as State Diagrams, Swim Lanes, Activity Diagrams,
Data Flow Diagrams, and many others.
We will talk about two of them.
Practical Tools-State Diagrams.
Creating a Workflow includes identifying the states and the
valid transitions between each state.
A state is usually a status condition, such as new or active.
In this example,
this Workflow is the process of managing backlog features for a new system.
If the Workflow is in the new state or condition,
then the flow of work is that an implementation has
started for this backlog item, then the current state is now active.
State Diagrams help to clarify, in your mind,
all of the possible user and application interactions.
This increases the chances that you will at least
consider coding for all the possibilities,
simply because you now know them all.
And this reduces the chances that you have buggy code,
or worse, forgot to handle specific functionality.
Practical Tools-Swim Lane Diagram.
A Swim Lane is a visual tool used for Workflow Diagrams,
also know as Process Flow Diagrams.
Key attributes are as follows: Visually distinguishes responsibilities
(roles) for sub-processes of a larger business process,
so it makes it easy to see who is doing what.
Roles can be arranged either horizontally or vertically.
Typically, roles are arranged vertically.
Time or flow is arranged horizontally.
Now, let's see an example.
Swim Lane Diagram, Part 2.
This diagram is a complete Swim Lane Workflow.
You can see the five horizontal lanes that represent
the roles or responsibilities.
Okay, enough of an eye test.
Let me zoom in now.
I have zoomed in on a portion of two roles.
The first is nursing operations.
So, within this Swim Lane,
we illustrate the process flow that is the responsibility of nursing operations.
Here, we show the process flow with red lines,
but you can choose any look and feel you wish.
The rounded, rectangle objects represent the status of a clinic,
such as ordering.
In the second Swim Lane is pharmacy operations.
Note where the red Workflow lines cross the horizontal boundary,
the responsibility now passes to pharmacy operations.
Remember, you can choose any object shape that helps you convey the Workflow.
Be creative so that you can illustrate, in the most straightforward way, the Workflow for easy understanding by your users.