Module Summary.
You have learned that Agile does have process,
documentation, requirements gathering,
and follows a plan; not like the myths or naysayers suggest.
The essence of Agile is to constantly adapt and re-plan your work
and activities throughout the project lifecycle.
You learn how you must 'break up' your requirements gathering
process into multiple requirements gathering iterations to
adapt to an Agile-type project.
Managing a product backlog with priorities and
estimates is critical for each release.
Users and customers will not likely easily embrace Agile.
Users want budget predictability, a project end date,
and hence, you may need executive sponsorship for a greater chance of adoption.
Lastly,
effective collaboration with all participants will foster trust and therefore enable honest feedback and increasing motivation for all.