Speaking of which, this is a screenshot from a Windows 10 workstation.
It's part of the Disk Administrator console that I'll demo for you momentarily,
but I thought it was important for us to quickly go through the major
vocabulary terms that correspond to hard-disk storage.
Specifically, we have the disk, and in this context,
we're referring to primarily fixed disks that are mounted permanently
in the chassis of a desktop or laptop computer,
potentially even, say, a Surface tablet,
running Windows 10.
When you install a new fixed hard disk, it's going to be uninitialized,
so the first step is to initialize the disk and choose
what kind of bootloader system you want.
Once you've done that, it's time to partition the drive out.
Drives can have just one big old partition that
covers all space on the physical disk, or you can create logical partitions.
Now the benefit of these logical partitions isn't as important as it used to be.
You're not working with a separate physical disk,
so it's now like you're spreading workload across
different sets of physical spindles, in the case of mechanical disks.
It's more of a logical construct, such that,
for instance,
your C drive that contains your operating system and
applications will be separate from, say,
your data drive.
And then if you need to wipe and load the operating system,
as long as you're working on the C drive and not the D drive,
your files will be protected.
Now a partition is simply an area of a hard disk that's initially unallocated.
A volume refers to a partition that's been formatted,
and formatting a partition involves laying down a file system.
We can look at a file system essentially as a map on how
storage is going to be assigned on that volume.
The other thing besides a file system that comes along
with the term volume is a drive letter.
Most drives in Windows for them to be user usable need to have a drive letter.
Although, you'll notice the System Reserved partition,
which is a hidden partition used by Windows; that does not have a drive
letter because it's not intended to be seen by the user.
The file system, as I said,
references the way that data is laid out on the drive.
And over time,
Microsoft has updated their file systems to accommodate trends in storage,
namely, the fact that we have gigantic storage capacities nowadays,
so we need to redraw the map, so to speak,
to make file allocation make more sense,
and also to add features, performance features,
diagnostic features, and security features to those file systems.
For instance, this E drive is formatted with FAT32.
That's not a preferred file system for Windows computers,
and I'll explain that to you later.
The cluster refers to the fundamental allocation unit in a volume.
Let's say your Windows volume, or let's say you have a D drive,
a data volume, and it uses 4 KB clusters.
If you save a 4 KB file, it will occupy 1 cluster.
If you save an 8 KB file, it'll neatly fit on 2 clusters.
But what if you save a 2 KB file?
It will still occupy a full 4K cluster.
So clusters need to be small enough to be granular enough to minimize wastage.
That's been part of the deal in Windows file systems over time,
and by definition as a volume gets bigger and bigger and bigger,
as you make bigger and bigger volumes I should say,
the cluster size eventually does have to scale because you
can have only a certain number of clusters per volume based
on your system architecture.
Let's compare the major file systems in Windows.
File allocation table, or FAT, 32 is the address length,
so you've got 2 to the 32nd clusters per volume.
That, if you do the math, turns out to a maximum volume size of 4 GB.
FAT32 came about back in the Windows 95 days,
and at that time, the idea of a 4 GB hard disk was almost inconceivable.
Now it's laughable.
You can have a microSD card that's about the size of your
pinky thumbnail that contains much, much more than 4 GB.
But the benefit of FAT32 is that it's optimized for smaller drives,
smaller portable disks.
Like flash disks will be useful candidates for FAT32,
as well as compatibility with other operating systems.
MacOS,
if you want to transfer or read files from a Windows machine on a Mac machine,
you could format your thumb drive as FAT32.
Otherwise,
you may need to install software on your Mac computer and your Linux computer,
for that matter, to read, say, an NTFS volume.
Also, embedded hardware, smaller gadget devices that use flash storage,
they oftentimes require the FAT32, just for backward compatibility,
older technology purposes.
The new technology file system, or NTFS,
has been the standard file system for Windows for
both desktop and server systems.
The reasons for this, number 1, it has a hefty volume size,
256 TB max, and it gives you features like permissions,
encryption, and compression.
It unlocks a lot of nice capabilities for use in business.
FAT32 does not allow you to set file security,
so if multiple users are on a single system,
everybody can see everybody else's files.
That's not the case with the NTFS,
as long as you're setting your file permissions correctly.
Newest in the game is ReFS, or the Resilient File System.
This is the next generation file system in Windows.
We see it predominantly on Windows Server,
and even more so in special use cases.
Its advantage is self-healing and self-repair, so resilient file system.
So normally if a server computer were to have a sudden power outage,
that can wreak havoc, especially on mechanical drives.
ReFS is constantly checkpointing data,
such that its capabilities are good at resurrecting data that otherwise
would've been lost in the case of some malfunction.
The maximum volume size is one yobibyte, which a crazy metric value.
Check the exercise files if you want to know exactly how many terabytes that is.
The disadvantages of ReFS,
and they're not exactly disadvantages if you understand what's going on here,
what this is used for, it can't be used for your boot volume or your C drive.
It also does not have deduplication,
which is useful if you have a file server with a whole bunch of different
files and there may be multiple copies of each file,
dedup will only store one instance of the repeated file,
which saves you quite a bit of disk space.
The reason why these aren't really big issues is that in my experience,
you wind up using ReFS on virtualization servers that host virtual machines.
That self-healing, self-repair is especially important because a virtual machine,
its storage is a file on a volume.
And if you have that virtual machine's virtual hard disk file on an ReFS volume, then you're adding additional layers of availability.