Okay,
I'd mentioned to you that I have a story to tell with
regard to Control Panel and settings.
That's absolutely true.
Let me begin that story just in Windows 10 land where we are right now.
This is a Windows 10 enterprise edition machine that I'm using
for this course that there are various entry points into the
settings/Control Panel system, in other words,
how you configure your system.
In the previous module,
I instructed you to get in the habit of right-clicking everything on the screen.
For instance, if you right-click an empty area of the desktop,
we have some options regarding display settings and personalize,
and if we hit Personalize,
it takes you into settings specifically into personalization.
If you right-click and go to Display settings in the shortcut menu,
it takes you into settings once again under System,
Display.
So those are ways to dive directly into what you're looking at,
and again, the same rule applies,
right-click an empty area of the task bar and select
task bar settings and there you go.
Now to look at the settings application from the root level,
I could've actually done it from there come to think of it.
Let me try that one more time.
I'll right-click the empty area of the taskbar,
select Taskbar settings,
and then I'll click Home to go to the Windows Settings home page.
I'll close that and come back to Start because another way to do
the same thing is to click the settings gear,
there you have it.
Yet another thing to do.
I hope that you're enjoying the notification system in Windows 10,
if you left-click the notifications icon,
you'll find All settings right here.
In addition to specific options, as I've said before,
that open up specific settings areas.
So all of this deals with the new Windows 10
settings app and this is the home page.
It looks kind of like a web page, doesn't it,
and everything is hyperlinked, which again,
is very webby.
You see we have these options grouped by category.
Now of course, we don't have the time or scope to go through every single option,
instead,
I'm giving you the power user skills such that you know how to
navigate it and then how to determine where to find settings is
going to be part of your practice actually.
To that point though,
check the exercise files because I have some documentation
links that give you a ready reference and description of
every possible Windows setting.
Now instead of trying to figure out which category you're going for,
you can always come right up here to find a setting.
What if you wanted to change the screen saver.
You can start to type and one of the options should be what you're looking for.
Here we have turn the lock screen slideshow on or off,
change screen saver, turn screen saver on or off.
And looked what happened here.
Here's a good example of that story I have to tell.
Microsoft and specifically the Windows client product
groups are slowly transitioning, and I do mean slowly,
transitioning the Windows settings from what historically
has been in the Control Panel applet.
I'll put up a floating screenshot on the screen now so
you can see what I'm talking about.
What you're looking at now is the Control Panel collection in Windows 7 and
that motif has been around all the way back to Windows 3.
1, okay.
So it's been many years and I dare say most Windows users are
accustomed to the traditional Control Panel.
Slowly as I said, beginning with Windows 8.
1 that we've seen a migration of configuration settings going
into this interface here where you can drill into categories
and then they're nicely documented, they're nicely hyperlinked,
I mean, they're fine, it's really nice.
But yes,
it's going to cause some confusion and it has when you
suddenly get this old-fashioned interface here.
This screen saver dialog has been like this for many, many years.
You might be wondering, okay Tim,
how do I know whether a particular configuration setting is
in the old Control Panel or in the new.
Well I would suggest that you start with the new and then chances are
good that you'll be clicked out to the old as need be.
I believe power might be an example.
Yeah, in fact, if you've typed power,
notice that you can see a difference in the icons.
You can see these I think they're blue icons that
should represent settings options, and sure enough they do.
It looks like this one brings us into power and sleep options.
You notice that each category has subcategories and the current one you're
on is highlighted and then you can use the controls here.
Now let me test your knowledge.
If I make changes here and say that I want the screen to
turn off or sleep after say 45 minutes,
where is that change actually being stored.
Do you remember?
I hope that you're saying the Registry because that answer is correct.
Let me come back and get to where I was where I typed power and you
notice that Edit power plan and Choose a power plan have what to my
mind looks like an old-fashioned icon, and sure enough,
it does in fact take us to the old Control Panel.
Again, this dialog has been a part of Windows for a long time.
Notice that you can use the breadcrumb navigation to come
back to the home page of Control Panel, and if you been here,
done that, bought the T-shirt,
you know that you can display them by category or you can display
them by individual icons either large or small.
I have the latest and greatest updates applied to
this Windows 10 virtual machine,
so it looks like we have settings instead of Control Panel.
It used to be not too long ago actually,
that I could right-click the Start button to get to
the old-fashioned Control Panel, but it looks like that's been changed.
This speaks to the fact that the Windows client product groups are
really intent upon changing things kind of rapidly over time as opposed
to waiting 2-3 years to see major changes,
you can expect twice a year at the least to see some of
these changes and they can be frustrated, frustrating I should say, but overall, I think they're a pretty good thing.