Now let's look at the Malicious Software Removal Tool or MSRT for short.
The historical perspective here is that Microsoft has had some
built-in utilities since pretty much the beginning,
but back in, say, the Windows 3.
1 days when Windows really began taking off as a graphical
operating system there was a company called Norton,
and they had the Norton Utilities.
Actually, the Norton Utilities predate Windows,
and the original versions of Norton Utilities would work on MS-DOS,
that was Microsoft's command line operating system
before they developed Windows, and this is an old version of Norton Utilities.
Norton became Symantec, and the products have been broken out since,
but the idea was that Norton Utilities gave you much more control
over your system's security and file system,
as opposed to just using inbox utilities with Windows.
Disk Doctor, for instance,
typically could do a better job of repairing and optimizing your hard
disk than could the Windows own Check Disk tool,
for instance, an old MS-DOS utility.
Norton Antivirus wasn't the first antivirus or antimalware client,
but it was among the first industry standard ones.
Now then,
MSRT is a mysterious tool for many because you normally never interact with it,
but you do see it when you're inspecting your Windows updates.
You'll see it flash across the screen,
and you'll notice that you get a new one every month.
That's true.
This is on-demand software,
and by on-demand I shouldn't really have used those words on this slide.
You can run MSRT interactively, in fact,
I'll do so in our first demo today,
but normally what happens is each time you run Windows Update once a
month you have that month's version of the MSRT,
and it downloads and runs silently in the background and fixes any
problems without you knowing any differently,
okay?
Patch Tuesday is the second Tuesday of the month.
That's the normal release date for Microsoft updates.
Now, of course,
depending upon what vulnerabilities are found in the wild
Microsoft may release out-of-band updates,
but that is meant to be a dependable,
once per month day that systems administrators can plan for because
in an enterprise environment you don't want to just blindly push
Windows updates to all of your endpoints.
You want to make sure to test them first on some development boxes
to make sure that the updates don't inadvertently break
functionality that your users need each day,
you see?
So MSRT comes down automatically, and it's meant to fix specific vulnerabilities.
If you've ever heard of the term Zero-Day Vulnerability or
O-Day Vulnerability that is a software bug,
in most cases, a weakness in, say, Windows,
the Windows code, that no remediation exists for yet,
you see?
So Zero-Days are particularly nasty infections.
MSRT is meant to address an already infected system.
It's not an antimalware program in itself,
and as I said,
you can start the tool by just opening a command prompt or
a PowerShell prompt or the run dialog, and typing mrt. I'll show you that momentarily.