In this demonstration we'll take a look at service accounts,
as well as the Malicious Software Removal Tool.
I'm going to right-click my Start button and go to Run.
This is one of my favorite techniques.
If you know the command line or, specifically,
the file name or the executable name that you're interested in
you can often save yourself a lot of clicking.
I mean, it's true that we've also been using the Cortana search,
as well as the Windows search just by typing.
Maybe this is a remnant of the fact that I'm so accustomed to
using the Windows key R key combination typing,
for instance, services.
msc to open the Service Control Manager Graphical User Interface.
So here we have an alphabetical list of all of the services
that are currently registered on this machine.
When you're doing performance tuning and least privilege stuff it's
often useful to aggregate all of the running services,
so I'll click the Status column a couple times to put
all the running services together,
and then you can audit them one by one to make sure that the
ones that you want to run are running.
I have some third-party software installed on this machine,
so you see Netwrix Auditor has a whole bunch of services here.
I'm not sure I'm particularly happy with that.
Let me double left-click the Core Service,
and you'll notice that you can stop, start,
pause, or resume services through this control.
You can change the Startup type.
There's Automatic (Delayed Start).
That's useful for services that take longer than normal to start.
Then there's Automatic, Manual, and Disabled.
Sometimes you'll set a service to Manual expecting that it will
be stopped unless you explicitly start it,
but sometimes if it's a service that Windows needs or if you
start an application that requires that service it'll start
automatically at that time, which is fine in many cases.
Be careful with disabling.
That can break functionality on your system,
but you can reduce attack surface and increase performance by
disabling services that you know you don't need.
I'm going to manually set this to Manual,
and I'm going to stop it because I want to show you that you can also,
let me actually do an alphabetical sort now and come down to Netwrix.
Here we go.
Core Service, it's set for Manual, and it's not running.
You can right-click and do a Start or Restart or something else.
Now in some cases there's dependencies,
and you won't be able to start or stop a service because of its dependencies.
In this case,
it looks like the Netwrix Core Service depends upon Remote Procedure Call,
and then specifically a couple subservices,
so it's important to take a look at that.
Whoops,
I shouldn't have closed that out so quickly because
I also want to show you this.
Looks like Netwrix, because it's a network capable application,
defaults to use the Network Service identity.
Now I did not add this.
I didn't do anything with the password.
This happened as a handshake between Netwrix and
Windows as I installed the software.
Probably run into problems if I flip that down to Local System account.
Finally, there's recovery.
When you're troubleshooting it can sometimes be helpful to attempt
to restart the service automatically on failure.
Sometimes specifically on web servers I'll set this for the Internet
Information Services service that if there's a failure restart the
service because if this is an important website that your customers
and your users use a transient failure the service just glitching and
stopping for a moment, you'll want to auto-remediate that wherever possible.
Now coming down to the W's.
Here we have a number of Windows Defender services.
There's the Advanced Threat Protection.
This is the client software that is only necessary if you're onboarding the
machine to an Office 365 based instance of Defender ATP.
There's the Antivirus Network Inspection Service,
the Antivirus Core, the Firewall, Security Center.
Make sure that those are all running,
and it looks like the Network Inspection is set to manual,
and it will only kick in when network connectivity is active.
Let me open this up and just for grins let's take a look.
It's running under the Local System context,
and notice that it's not letting us override that. That's a good thing, I think, because Windows Defender is protecting our system.