BitLocker Drive Encryption.
The BitLocker use case is simply this: A person steals the
hard drive from a workstation or server with the intention
of accessing privileged data.
You never want that to happen in business.
Nowadays, employees walk around with company-issued laptops.
Someone leaves theirs behind on a bus or on a train or
in an airport and it gets stolen,
what's going to happen when the person starts the computer?
Well, if you have the drive, the C drive,
locked with BitLocker, you'll need to provide some kind of authentication.
And if you can't provide that authentication,
you're not going to unlock the drive.
It's as simple as that.
Even if you were to take the hard drive out of that computer,
put it in, say, a USB enclosure, and attempt to mount it as an external drive,
still, unless you have the proper unlock authentication key,
you're not going to get that data.
It's a whole disk, BitLocker is a whole disk drive encryption technology.
Now options here, first of all,
you're going to get the best mileage out of BitLocker if your system
motherboard has a little chip called a Trusted Platform Module,
or TPM.
So if you're shopping for a new laptop,
make sure that that laptop supports TPM V1.
2 or later.
The importance of that is that that TPM allow you to do pre-boot integrity.
This is Secure Boot where all of your boot files are digitally signed and
verified and vetted against the Trusted Platform Module.
So if someone were to put a keylogger or try to install
a boot sector virus on your system,
that would violate the Secure Boot environment,
and the system would not start up.
You see what I mean?
That's good security.
Another thing that TPM does is it stores the keys
for BitLocker Drive Encryption, so if a disk is removed from the motherboard,
it no longer has access to the TPM.
It's not going to boot.
Now if you're thinking, woah, well, what about a failsafe?
What if the motherboard dies, and I need to take the disk to another computer?
Well,
you can add additional or alternate layers of authentication like a
password or a personal identification number as well.
You can even use a USB-based dongle as a substitute for the TPM.
So as I said, other protections include a USB startup key,
a PIN, unlock password.
BitLocker can be used to protect not only your system volume
or your OS volume or your boot volume,
you can think of your C drive in all of those ways,
but also your data volume.
So you can fully protect your system this way.
BitLocker To Go allows you to use BitLocker encryption on
removable disks and USB flash media.
Now we don't need to get really down in the weeds as far
as how BitLocker works technically.
You can learn that by searching the Pluralsight library.
But for now, for our purposes,
I want you to understand that we can manage BitLocker directly in
Windows 10 through the graphical user interface,
no surprise there.
From a systems administration Active Directory standpoint,
there's Group Policy management, we can use good old PowerShell.
There are two command line tools, manage-bde and repair-bde,
that you can call from an elevated command prompt.
And then we have something called MBAM.
Now what the heck does MBAM mean?
When I say that, it reminds me of the Flintstones.
Remember them?
Bamm-Bamm.
MBAM stands for BitLocker Administration and Monitoring.
Now this is a tool that's available as part of the
Microsoft Desktop Optimization pack, or MDOP,
M-D-O-P.
Check the exercise files for info on that.
It's not free; you have to be a Software Assurance
license holder with Microsoft.
There's a couple other ways to be legally qualified to get this tool.
But this, if you're using BitLocker in business,
is very, very useful, if not required.
The MBAM console, as you see here, is web-based,
so you can get to it theoretically from anywhere in
your network or using a VPN remotely.
And this is going to solve problems like your employee has
BitLocker set to boot with a startup password,
and they can't for the life of themselves remember what the password is.
Or they're using only TPM, and the motherboard on their system is fried,
and you need to supply the drive recovery key,
which is essentially the super-unlock password to get access to that disk.
Well, MBAM allows you to support those drive recovery options,
as well as manage the TPMs on enrolled workstations in your
environment and servers on your environment. Super-useful tool for businesses that are using BitLocker.