File History.
Now the first thing I want you to know about the Windows 10
File History feature is that it's intended by Microsoft as a
replacement for Windows Backup.
Both Windows Client and Windows Server have shipped with built-in
backup utilities since the beginning of Windows,
but now that we're in Windows 10 land, and cloud storage is so ubiquitous,
we have alternatives for traditional backup.
Now that, quite honestly, what I just said,
don't put much stock in that, because if you've done work with cloud storage,
you know that a cloud storage provider's aim is to
provide high availability for your data,
and not recoverability.
Please don't lull yourself into a false sense of security thinking,
oh, well my data is automatically backed up.
You want to be double and triple checking that to
make sure that that is the case.
If you don't have Windows Backup set up on a schedule,
then you're not backing up your system.
File History is analogous to Apple Time Machine.
If you use Mac OS, it's a way to create a data repository,
normally an external drive, a plugin USB drive,
and then automatically over time Windows,
or Apple in the case of Time Machine,
will target your user profile folders and just automatically back up
your files periodically to that external storage.
And that means if you make deletions in your profile folders,
if you clear out your Downloads folder, for instance,
and then realize hours,
days or weeks later that you needed a file that was in there,
you do have a fallback mechanism,
and you should be able to pluck the file from your File History archive.
It's actually a really good product, however,
as of this recording in January 2018,
the status of File History is still a little shaky.
Over 2017,
Microsoft for a period of time actually marked File History for deprecation.
Deprecation means that Microsoft isn't formally developing the product anymore,
and it's subject to complete removal in a future
version of the operating system.
Now I think Microsoft got quite a bit of blowback from
customers who rely upon File History,
and it's still with us as of the Fall 2017 creators update,
but I just wanted to make you aware of that,
and to stay on the forefront of that news.
If it does become deprecated,
you'll have to look for another automatic file backup solution for your system.
What the conventional wisdom is,
the reason why Microsoft did mark File History as being deprecated,
at least for a time, until mysteriously suddenly bringing it back,
is that the notion is Microsoft wants to roll File
History capabilities into OneDrive.
That hasn't happened yet, though, so again,
as of early 2018,
File History certainly has a good place in the Windows 10 users toolbox.
OneDrive, I want to be really clear about this as well,
is for file synchronization, and not file backup right now.
In fact,
a little bit later in this module we're going to look at how
to retrieve previous versions of a file,
or how to retrieve a file from the Recycle Bin,
but there's no backup that happens in OneDrive. If you delete a file and then delete it from the Recycle Bin, it's gone forever,