Now let's look at the Malicious Software Removal Tool.
Again, you'll probably notice that if you run an update,
let me go into Start Settings, and we go to Update and Security,
and it looks like I haven't done updates for a while here,
so if I click this to start a search, and if we're patient,
I don't know if I have the patience to have us sit here and wait,
but you may see flash by Malicious Software Removal Tool for the current month.
Guess I ran out of patience sooner than I thought.
I'll right click my PowerShell icon, choose Run as Administrator.
You always want to start PowerShell as an administrator,
so it can do what you want it to do,
and if you type mrt that will launch the current,
whatever the most current MSRT tool is on your system.
I'm recording this video in January 2018,
so this looks like the current version.
There's a link to the documentation.
There's a link to the specific threats that it seeks to destroy.
Now these are going to be Zero-Day or previously Zero-Day
threats that Microsoft now has a remedy for.
So this is only going to look for machines that are already infected
with one or more of these malicious software packages.
If we click Next we can do a quick scan, full scan, or a customized scan.
I'm going to choose quick scan,
and I'm hoping that we're not going to have any infection.
Good news.
No malicious software was detected,
and there's a link to view detailed results of the scan.
This is just a graphical little window as I'm scrolling through,
but if you want a more permanent log you can actually get to that.
Let me open up my PowerShell prompt, and do notepad,
and I'm going to path out to C:\Windows\debug\mrt.
log.
Let me bring this down so you can see that path again.
C:\Windows\debug\mrt.
log. Any time you or Windows runs the tool you'll see those results.