This is an old tech net diagram.
You see the attribution in the lower left.
I want you to ignore most of it.
I'm going to call out what's relevant for our purpose.
The reason I selected this image is that it shows the various ways that a
server can make a printer available on the network.
Technically,
you can host a shared printer on a client device on a Windows 10 machine,
but in business you'll generally have a server,
that is, a machine that's running Windows Server,
maintaining that printer.
And that shared printer can be physically cabled to the server,
maybe using USB is all likelihood.
Alternatively, some older printers rely upon an external print server.
I guess it would make sense for me to briefly define
what I mean by a printer server.
A print server represents a network-aware device.
It could be, in the case of Hewlett-Packard,
they have a device called Jetdirect.
It's a standalone print server that you put on your network on one side,
or connect to your printers on the other,
and it serves as a proxy to receive network printing requests so that print
server is able to receive printing requests from over the network and despool
those jobs to one or more physical print devices.
But more commonly nowadays,
you have printers that have a network card already installed,
and they're able to join the network directly,
and they are logically managed by a print server computer.
I'll show you how that works in the demo by the way.
Another thing I want you to know in general is the network
printing process what's happening with spooling.
The print spooler service is critical.
You'll often be able to solve many print problems by restarting the spooler
service on either the affected client or the print server.
Again,
the print server in this context is going to be a
Windows Server machine on the same domain.
But that print spooler is what on one hand,
when the user submits the print job, the job is spooled out,
either locally to a local printer, or in a network printing context,
it'll go across the network and get spooled on the print server.
When I say spool, think of a physical spool,
but instead of yarn or thread being wound around the spool,
it's actually each page of the print job.
The print job is broken down into a page definition language.
We don't need to get too deep in the woods there,
but just know that that print job could be coming from
N number of different applications, and it really doesn't matter.
As long as the printer can translate that print job into a
down-level format that it recognizes, it will faithfully print the results,
and then the network print queue will then despool the job page
by page to the printer that's on the network or perhaps even
locally cabled to the print server.
There are a number of ways to control printer management.
Now that's not so necessary on a standalone local Windows 10 machine.
There we can just use the printer's control panel and look
at the individual print queues that way,
but on a server side, on a print server,
a single server may host a number of shared printers.
So in that case, we have an MMC console,
a Microsoft Management Console,
called Print Management that I'll show you how it works.
There's also PowerShell.
There's a dedicated module appropriately called PrintManagement.
There's Group Policy.
You know by now that Group Policy is used as a way to centrally
perform configuration and desktop management.
You can actually deploy network printer connections
conveniently to your users via Group Policy.
And then there's management tools.
There's first-party tools developed by Microsoft,
System Center Configuration Manager is one that I mention an awful lot,
but there's plenty of third-party alternatives that also offer different
abstraction layers to make it easier for you to deploy, manage, and troubleshoot your network print devices.