File Explorer.
File Explorer was called Windows Explorer for many,
many years, and even before that when the first versions of Windows came out,
Windows 1, 2, and 3, it was called File Manager,
and this is a graphical way to browse the directories and files
on your hard disk and your removable disks.
This, as I said, is a screenshot of File Manager from Windows 3.
1.
You could cut and paste files, move and copy them around,
you can create files, very useful skill to have.
I submit every bit now in 2017 as all the way back to 1992.
The Windows 10 File Explorer, as it's called, has grown quite refined indeed.
There was a time where in Windows you had a couple
different Windows Explorer views.
You had a preview and a Details view and they could
actually be opened in separate windows.
Let me walk you through the major parts and pieces of
the unified Windows 10 File Explorer.
If you're familiar with the recent Microsoft Office Applications,
then you're familiar with many of these controls like the quick access toolbar,
this allows you to place buttons that will always be available for
every File Explorer window instance that you open.
The ribbon, as I said,
originated in Microsoft Office 2007 and it's a fundamentally different
way to navigate commands from how it used to be where you would open
up menus and select from menu options.
This is the address bar and you can click in there and override
whatever is there to browse anywhere in your file system.
The search is a function that I use all the time practically
every single day because let's face it,
some of my disk volumes are huge and they have tens of thousands,
hundreds of thousands of files and I need to find specific ones quickly.
We have our Navigation pane here and this has a lot of magic built into it.
You can customize which shortcuts appear under the Quick Access area.
You can set up libraries to aggregate documents of different types.
As you install software, they will add their own shortcuts.
For instance, I have Microsoft One Drive, as you can see in this screenshot.
You also have your removable disks like your USB disks and
your optical disks showing up here as well and you can
navigate that in a Tree view.
Ultimately, you have your Contents or Details pane,
which allows you to view specific resources in a variety of different views,
very intuitive, and it's crucial that you master this, especially if you're going to be in a support role helping end users.