Let me go to Settings to verify who I'm logged in as.
It looks like I'm logged on as just an ordinary personal user.
There's an Auto Save tab.
Choose where you want to save your desktop documents and pictures.
I have them set to the PC instead of OneDrive because File
History has already taken care of those files,
so I'm glad I have that level of support.
If we right-click OneDrive, let me open my OneDrive folder,
and if I go into Documents, I have a Calendar 2016.
docx file that I'll delete.
It tells us the file will be deleted from your PC,
but you may be able to restore it from the web,
are you sure you want to do this?
I'm going to say Yes.
So now this is going to sync to all my devices, but let me try that again.
Open your OneDrive folder, go to Documents, I no longer have that calendar.
To do restores from OneDrive, as I said,
you have to go to the web, so let's right-click and go to View Online.
Edge appears,
and it's going to pop into either OneDrive for Business or OneDrive personal,
depending upon your account.
I'm at OneDrive personal.
And if I go to the Recycle bin, sure enough is see Calendar 2016.
docx.
I can select that file and restore it from the Recycle bin,
and now it should show up in my files list in my Documents folder.
Yep, here it is.
The nice thing about OneDrive on the web is that you have
browser-based access to the major Office applications,
in this case Word Online.
And if I come back to my OneDrive client and open the folder,
go to Documents, I have my Calendar back.
Pretty nifty, huh?
The other thing, like I said, deals with versioning,
and if you right-click a file in your OneDrive web
portal and go to Version History,
it'll show you any versions created for those files.
I don't know if have versions for any of these.
Not all of them have versioning enabled.
Let me see, I did a Microsoft Virtual Academy course,
does this have a version history, let's see.
Now, it doesn't.
How about this PowerPoint?
Does that have a version history?
If it's a recognized file type,
notice that the version browser actually pops open in a separate tab.
You get the idea though.
If we had multiple versions of the file,
we would be able to preview, download, save to OneDrive that particular version.
So you get the best fidelity with office documents, as you see.
I opened up the version history for this Word file,
and again, I just have one version, but you get the idea.
Long story short,
what you're going to have in your OneDrive is version history over time,
and then the Recycle bin and the capacity to recover from it subject to retention policies.