Windows Backup.
Now,
we have quit a bit to untangle here with the notion of
an honest to goodness backup program.
If you've used traditional backup solutions in Windows,
you know that you can backup files and folders and
set that backup on a schedule.
You can back up to another hard drive, a network location,
the cloud, whatever it is that you want to do,
and that capability exists.
You can also create a system image backup which
backs up your entire disk volume, like your C drive,
your entire environment,
such that you can restore that system image to put your entire system
truly back in time to when you created that image.
I used to do that as a general practice on my home computers.
I would install all my applications, get everything up to date,
and then snapshot a golden image that I could roll back to
if something went wrong in the future.
This shows the Settings dialog, and it shows the reset option, Reset this PC.
If you're going to sell your Windows 10 device,
you'll want to make sure that your system is reset to a pristine
environment with all of your personal data being gone.
You certainly never want to hand off a computer to somebody
that still has remnants of your work on it.
The Reset functionality actually does two things.
In previous versions, like Windows 8 and 8.
1, you could reset or refresh.
Now it's all under one heading here.
You have a choice when you go down the reset path to either keep your files,
which is essentially you're just reinstalling the operating system,
or you're doing a true reset where you're deleting all of your personal data.
As far as the Backup and Restore program,
like I said, this is a screenshot from it,
we'll walk through the process in a demo.
The product is actually called Windows 7 Backup and Restore.
This speaks to the fact that as of Windows 8, 8.
1, and 10,
Microsoft is really looking at File History as the
way to backup files and folders,
but you can still use Windows Backup proper as you see
here to backup entire disk volumes,
you can do a system image backup of your C drive,
you can backup individual files, individual volumes.
It's a pretty flexible tool. And it comes with the operating system, there's no additional cost.