Okay,
I wanted to show you a little bit more about Edge protection with SmartScreen.
This is a pretty cool demonstration site that Microsoft developed.
The URL is https:/demo.
smartscreen.
msft.
net.
I have that in the exercise files too,
but these are demo pages that do not actually contain malicious calls.
You're not putting your computer at risk,
but it's nice, for instance,
if a web page might be a phishing site you'll see something like this.
This might not be the site you want.
Does this look correct?
You can report it as safe or report it as unsafe,
and then depending upon what kind of code the site wants to run
it looks like it's asking for Adobe Flash.
You can choose to allow that if you want to.
Isn't that cool?
Let's come back to our demo page.
Here's a page known for phishing that should be blocked.
This is what SmartScreen will show you, and you can get some more information,
and then Back to safety to go away from that site.
This is definitely something you want to train your users in.
Malware page, a page that hosts malware.
They're going to see a page like this.
Blocked Download.
If it's URL reputation matches known hijacked software SmartScreen will say,
this is unsafe to download and was blocked.
Now if you're thinking to yourself, wow,
this is super useful, but I want to be able to capture all of this information.
I don't want it to happen on my user's computers one off
because I may never know about it.
That's a good entrée point for you to look into the
Defender Advanced Threat Protection, ATP.
Maybe your company already has an Office 365 subscription,
which makes it even easier yet to onboard your Windows 10 clients.
So this goes through a number of different possibilities.
I encourage you to visit this demo.
smartscreen.
msft.
net,
so you can get a better feel for how the SmartScreen
filter actually works in practice, and we've also talked about the store,
the Windows App Store or the Microsoft Store,
as it's known right now.
This is where you can shop for applications.
You can even shop for Xbox applications through here,
which I think is pretty darn cool,
and the SmartScreen filter will track any apps that you obtain,
their calls to the internet,
if they raise any red flags in the Microsoft SmartScreen online database you'll be made aware of that.