In this demo,
we'll look at the so-called Windows 7 Backup and Recovery tools in Windows 10.
To do that, I'm going to open a Run prompt and open Control,
because this is a tool that exists in the legacy or classic Control Panel.
If I type backup, it brings us to Backup and Restore Windows 7.
Remember that this has the Windows 7 to remind us that
File History is the current gen backup, but it's not exactly.
The Backup and Restore for Windows 7 allows you to do file and
folder backup as well as system image backup,
you see what I mean?
Now this Windows backup hasn't been set up yet on this computer,
so we have a user account control to set it up,
and let's actually step through this wizard together.
First we're asked where you want to save.
You can go out onto the network or you would choose a disk volume,
either a fixed volume or removable storage that has
enough space on it to store your data.
I'm going to choose Drive F.
What do you want to back up?
You can either let Windows choose, or you can take control of the process.
I'm going to choose Let me choose.
If you choose Include a system image,
it's going to snapshot both the System Reserved partition that
contains your boot files and your C drive,
which is your system.
This is going to give your entire environment back
snapshotted as of this moment.
Alternatively, you can pick out volumes manually as you see here.
Specifically, you can go into data files,
you can go into your libraries, data for newly created users,
step through it that way.
Save settings and run backup,
that's going to go ahead and take off and run that backup,
as you see here.
We have metadata.
Here is the backup target,
here is backup in terms of whether you've created a schedule.
I've just selected the defaults here.
So it's grabbing a system image, it's grabbing file system data separately,
storing it on Drive F, and the default setting is that every Sunday at 7:00 P.
M my local time it's going to rerun the backup.
We can change that schedule right here, as you see.
I'm going to switch over to another machine that already has
had these backups going on for a while.
So if I reinvoke the Control Panel and type backup,
Restore data files or computer from backup (Windows 7).
Again, it takes us to the Backup and Restore wizard.
You can look at your last backup results that says that the backup completed,
but some files were skipped,
and it looks like it had a problem backing up my contents due to a WAIT error,
so that would be something to check out and test if I wanted to.
We can change the backup job settings by invoking the Windows
Backup tool separately and examining the properties of whatever
backup job parameters I had set,
and by doing this it'll allow us to customize the
schedule if we want to create one.
I'm going to cancel, we don't need to actually do that.
So that's the long story short.
The legacy Backup and Restore, it's good for creating system images,
also good for picking out files and folders,
even though Microsoft wants us to use File History as much as possible.
As far as the Restore workflow,
you see that again in the Backup and Restore Windows 7 Control Panel.
We have that you can restore your files that were
backed up to the current location, Restore my Files.
It looks like on the system I must not have done a file and folder backup,
but instead just did a system image backup,
but if I had backed up individual files and folders I can select them,
sort of like you can select a system restore point that matches your timeframe,
and it's going to put those files back in their original location.
So be careful about that option.
The common criticism I've heard and what I've experienced in practice,
is that this utility is fairly, not inflexible,
but it's less flexible than many shareware products out there,
for that matter.
There's independent software vendors like CloudBerry Lab who
make fine backup tools that are very expensive,
if not freeware,
that allow you to schedule file and folder backups that run really well.
You can back up to the cloud and so forth.
As you can see, this Backup and Restore surface is showing its age,
and I suspect it's going the way of the Dodo.
If you're wondering, Tim, how do I restore a system restore image,
well in that case we're going to need to reboot the
system into the recovery environment, and we're actually going to do that in the next module.