Ah, this is quite a marathon journey, isn't it?
Our last subject is Recovery Drive, a brand-new feature in Windows 10.
Here's what the Recovery Drive does.
Let's discuss the workflow, and it'll become apparent.
You're going to point the Recovery Drive creation tool to a USB disk.
This could be a USB thumb drive or an external drive.
You're going to build the Recovery Drive,
which is kind of sort of like a system image backup,
but not exactly.
A system image backup is an exact duplication of your entire
Windows environment as of that point in time.
The Recovery Drive allows you to snapshot the core operating system,
as well as its updated drivers and Windows update files,
you see the difference?
This allows you to, in a troubleshooting scenario,
to recover your system minus programs and files.
It will give you the activation state,
that is the Recovery Drive will keep the Windows activation
so that you don't have to do anything special after
recovering from a Recovery Drive.
Drivers and Windows update are included.
So long story short, Recovery Drive is not going to bring back any of your data,
so please don't look at it in that context.
As a matter of fact,
you could really have a bad time if you do a Recovery Drive
restore and expect that it's going to bring back your data
like a system image backup will.
No, it's not going to, and for that matter,
your system image backup is only going to bring back all your document
files as they existed at the date of that backup.
You see these complexities?
Recovery Drive is where you want to effectively refresh your system,
but put yourself ahead of the game in terms of not having to go back to
Windows Update and re-download a whole bunch of updates and go through
the driver acquisition process if you have vendor-specific drivers that
you've gotten from their websites.
So summing up, we looked at a lot of different backup products.
Let's put them all in context to make things really clear.
First we looked at System Restore,
which is for troubleshooting a failed installation of a
device driver application registry change,
not an entire system.
File History allows you to "sanity check" recovery of individual files,
predominantly your OneDrive files and your profile files.
They get automatically backed up to an external disk,
and you can bring them back from the dead,
so to speak, if one becomes corrupted or missing in your live installation.
OneDrive is a cloud storage solution that gives you high availability,
but not necessarily high recoverability,
so don't ever forget about backing up OneDrive.
And then both Recovery Drive and Windows Backups are mechanisms to bring
back the operating system in more of a bare-metal way,
with Recovery Drive giving you just the operating system,
activation status, updates and drivers,
Windows Backup being able to come back with individual files and folders, or an entire system image from a previous point in time.