In this demonstration,
we'll look at the new Recovery Drive feature in Windows 10.
Let me open up Start, type recovery drive,
and we get a link to create a Recovery Drive in classic Control Panel.
Specifically, this starts a program called the Recovery Media Creator,
and the one option here is to back up system files
to the Recovery Drive as well.
It's going to scan and look for media.
Now as it happens, I've already worked behind the scenes before I started this.
You're going to use a USB stick,
you're going to need at least a 32 GB volume on that disk.
I actually created a disk on my virtual machine here,
labeled it Recovery, 32 GB in size,
and if I open it up it looks a lot like the root of a
Windows 10 operating system image.
It has your boot files,
it's going to put you into the Windows recovery environment and
allow you to resurrect your operating system.
You have under Sources, you have Reconstruct.
WIM, and maybe additional WIM files.
This is the actual image that will come back if we
decide to boot from this partition.
So that's the process.
This Recovery Drive wizard is going to be spinning its wheels for a long time.
Essentially, all you do here is you choose a disk partition,
preferably a USB thumb drive, like I said,
or an external drive,
and then click Next and it's going to go through the
process of creating the drive.
There's really nothing to look at.
If you're wondering, as I said, again, how to use the Recovery Drive,
that's where we boot into Windows recovery environment.
You would boot the computer off that drive.
And if you're wondering, well, how do you do that?
Partly it depends on whether you're using UEFI or legacy BIOS.
You're going to use a startup key to invoke that interface,
and then you can customize the boot order and make sure that
you're booting from the Recovery Drive partition.
You may also be able to start your computer and then press F12 to
get a list of possible boot volumes from there.
Finally, it looks like the Recovery Drive stopped spinning,
and it shows us available drives.
It says that the drive must be able to hold at least 8 GB,
but as I said, 32 is pretty standard if you're using Windows to go,
or other Windows recovery-oriented features,
32 is a pretty standard drive.
I'm going to choose G, which has a system image backup on it.
Now you want to be really careful here,
because whatever you choose to be your recovery file,
or your recovery drive rather, is going to be deleted.
You see what this says, everything on the drive will be deleted, and then click Create.