In summary, what we've learned in this module.
I didn't tell this until now, so let me say it right now,
that I know many people who make a great living for themselves
doing simply disaster recovery planning.
It's enough of a job to warrant a full-time career.
And you know you're going to be loved by your clients and customers,
because you're helping them preserve their business.
It's for a very good reason that disaster recovery planning is
often called business continuity planning,
because a data loss can really shorten the life,
or outright kill a business flat.
Public cloud makes it easier than ever to run backups.
You can actually use the cloud, Microsoft's Azure cloud,
for instance, as a data restore center, a data recovery center,
for your entire environment, your server environment,
if you're using servers.
If you're a consumer and you have Office 365,
you can use Azure as an individual or as a small business owner,
and you can backup to an Azure storage account no problem.
Discipline is definitely necessary.
We don't get into restore so much here,
but the notion of a good backup is only as good as its verification.
That is, is the backup legitimate, is it corrupted,
I hope not, can you actually restore it,
and do you perform periodic trial restores to make sure
that your backup scheme is functional.
So we have one more content module left,
and then we're going to wrap up in module 20,
the final module, looking at the MTA certification.
But in that last content module,
we're going to essentially bookend to what we're doing here,
we'll look at Windows 10 Troubleshooting. Thanks for your attention, I'll see you then.