About the MTA certification.
The Microsoft certification hierarchy functions like this.
We have at the entry level the Microsoft Technology Associate,
or MTA, credential.
What the hallmark of this credential is,
is that no prior experience in information technology is required,
so it's a perfect starter certification for those who want to get into IT,
either right out of school,
or perhaps you're what's called a career changer who is coming
into information technology from another field.
There are a number of MTA certifications that each focus on
different elementary aspects of IT: networking,
cloud computing, databases, development,
and this one, of course, is operating system fundamentals.
The mid tier is what's called the Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate.
I'm speaking most particularly of the IT pro or the IT
operations job role as opposed to the developer.
There are a whole suite of developer certifications that
we won't talk about in this module.
The MCSA is a really nice mid-tier credential that demonstrates your
competency with a particular Microsoft product or product family.
For instance,
Windows Server is a very popular candidate for MCSA
certifications for those who may have begun with an MTA.
The top tier credential is the MCSE.
This credential has been around as long as I have been in IT.
I became an MCSE in 1998,
but in those days MCSE stood for Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer.
Those four letters carry quite a bit of industry clout,
so they're retained even today in 2018,
but notice that it's now Solutions Expert instead of Systems Engineer.
Once again,
you can attain your MCSA in several different
Microsoft enterprise server products, like cloud platform,
Windows Server, and SharePoint Server.
Some analogous certifications to the MTA would be,
for instance, certifications by CompTIA.
CompTIA Is a vendor-neutral industry consortium.
Microsoft belongs to CompTIA,
as do most of the other major vendors in this space.
The A+ deals with computer hardware of all types,
and also operating system support.
Network + is a vendor-neutral approach to Ethernet networking.
Those two certifications taken together give you an incredibly
well-rounded validation of entry-level IT skills.
MTA, same thing,
but of course the scope with the Microsoft MTA Operating System
Essentials is the Windows 10 operating system in particular.
Another, I want to say competing,
but I don't really mean it in a competing sense,
an analogous certification to the MTA would be the Cisco certification,
Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician,
or CCENT.
Now, of course, the bent there is on Cisco routers and switches,
but CCENT does its best to be vendor neutral,
because really when we're talking about fundamentals of Ethernet and TCP/IP,
those are absolutely cross-platform technologies.
Okay, so you have the lay of the land, in general, high-level view.
You have vendor-specific certifications like Microsoft,
Apple, and Cisco,
and you have vendor-neutral certifications like CompTIA and ISC2.
If you're thinking ISC what Tim? Check the exercise files, because I give you some supplemental links.