What is MSCONFIG?
MSCONFIG is called the system configuration utility.
It's been in Client Windows for many years.
This is a screenshot of what it looks like in Windows Vista,
yet again, we don't have much change really.
We talked in the previous module about Task Manager and its evolution.
We've noticed that from earlier versions of Windows to Windows 10,
Task Manager has taken on some additional tabs and
allowed you to have some deeper insights,
but it's still the basic same application.
Similarly,
you use the system configuration utility to modify how
your Windows 10 computer starts up.
I'll get into more specifics when we get to the demo.
Just know that it's been around since Windows Vista and its basic
functionality hasn't changed too much since then.
In this demo, we'll look at Administrative tools in Windows 10,
the MSCONFIG utility and the MMC framework.
We're not going to have the time or scope to get
really in depth with every tool, that's not really the point.
The point is I want to make sure you know where to find them,
and in general, what they're used for in Windows 10.
Now I've brought out the Cortana search box.
You'll recall in the previous module we set up this machine for Cortana
and I have to say I've become quite taken with Cortana functionality
despite what I thought I would feel about it.
If you're wondering how to do that, we right-click an empty area of the task bar,
come up to Cortana, and instead of showing the Cortana icon,
I'm showing the search box itself.
And if we come in here and type administrative tools,
as long as you're running an appropriate Windows 10 SKU,
you'll see that as the best match.
I'm going to press Enter to accept that and it takes us again into the
traditional Control Panel into Administrative Tools.
Now what are the most important of these tools?
Well, that's difficult.
Some are certainly ones that you'll use more than others.
One that I'll start with here is Computer Management.
I like the Computer Management console, let's me maximize this guy,
because computer management is actually a rollup of
several administrative tools in one.
Now the Microsoft Management Console,
you notice that it works on the basis of panes.
You can control these panes, their visibility, by using these buttons.
Now the right Actions pane tends to reflect what happens when you
right-click a node in the first pane so I tend to turn that off.
Your mileage may vary.
And then the way the MMC works, we have these components called snap-ins,
the idea that MMC consoles are fully customizable.
Now computer management is not customizable because it's a built-in console,
but I'll show you in just a minute how to create your own ones.
So for local users and groups, we can pop in here,
and if you wanted to change a password or create a new user,
you can certainly do that, and again,
right mouse clicking is a good way to go for that.
I love the right mouse button.
If you want to manage the disks on your system,
if you've popped in a new USB thumb drive and you want to format or reformat it,
this is your tool for doing that.
Device Manager has been part of client and server Windows for
seemingly forever and this is where you can view the devices that
are detected and the drivers that are loaded for those machines by
Windows and make customizations, disable hardware,
enable hardware, etc, etc.
So this is just one example of many of these MMC console tools.
Another one that's really important is services.
When you're troubleshooting Windows 10 Client machines,
maybe if the user complains that they feel their system is running too slowly,
you'll want to open the Services panel and take a look at it.
You can sort on these different criteria.
Let's look at only services that are running.
Now in contrast, remember with Task Manager in the previous module,
if we right-click the Taskbar settings and bring out Task Manager,
we can look at our startup items with their startup impacts.
These are certainly going to be mapped to particular services and we can
actually go to the services list here and this seems to give us about the
same information that you see in the Services console,
including the ability to start, stop, and restart the service,
but if you want to do anything more dramatic than that,
then you'll want to open the services console specifically.
And if you double-click one of these, you can control its run state,
as well as whether it starts up automatically,
or manually, or if you've decided to disable a service.
You may find that if a user has connectivity problems or application problems,
you may find that its underlying service had been disabled accidentally and
you can fix the problem simply by reenabling that service,
okay.
So those are Administrative tools.
Now check this out.
I'm going to right-click the Start button and go to Run,
of course, you could always do Windows key+R,
and if you type MMC, as long as you're an administrator,
once again, we're hit with this User Account Control consent thing,
we get an empty MMC console, it just shows Console Root.
Before we do anything, I'm going to do a Save and notice if I open the Save in,
it's going to want to put it in the Windows
Administrative Tools folder under my user profile.
It's a really long path, AppData, Roaming,
Microsoft, Windows, Start Menu, Programs.
So wherever I am,
whatever machine I log into assuming that the network is
configured for roaming user profiles, I'll be able to get to this console.
I do this a lot actually as an administrator.
I might call this Admin Console as a matter of fact because it allows me to
bring together my most powerful Administrative tools.
This gets saved as a.
mmc, Microsoft Management Console file.
So now I can open the File menu and select Add/Remove Snap-in and we
have a list of all available snap-ins on this machine.
Event viewer is really good for diagnostics purposes because it
shows you all of the messages that Windows,
as well as other applications write.
And check this out, many of these MMC snap-ins are remote computer aware.
They're going to default to your current machine,
but you can also connect to another computer,
and in many cases, not all, I want to be careful not to use a global statement,
but in many cases,
you can connect to machines running older versions of Windows Client,
Windows Server.
I mean, there is a limit there.
In fact,
check the exercise files for some documentation on that and you
may also need to provide alternate credentials.
This shouldn't be a problem if you're logged on as a network administrator,
but that actually brings in another set of problems related to
security that we'll leave there for now.
I'm going to select local computer and we can just
keep bringing other items in here.
If I want to manage the digital certificates that are the system,
and here,
it's asking us do you want to see just your own user
account certificates or the entire computer.
I'll just leave the default here and click OK.
And now if I do a File, Save, I have this custom console,
and remember, what's neat is that we could have,
for instance, multiple snap-ins of the same type where one looks at our machine,
another one looks at another machine on the network,
another one looks at a server,
that's the power of the MMC framework and that's probably why
it's still around because it really works.
I'm going to save the console settings, and if I come down to Cortana,
let me see if I can type admin console and have it show up.
Nope.
It's not finding it unfortunately.
Let's see if it's showing up in here.
No, it's not.
Hmm.
Well, no problem.
We can always come back to Run,
open up a new instance of mmc on this machine and do a File,
we've got our recently opened consoles down here and it's not lost.
I can do a Save as and put it wherever I want to.
I'm going to actually put it on the desktop.
There we go.
So now at my ready reference, I can double left-click, consent, and then I have my console.