In this demonstration,
we're going to lay the groundwork for doing a Windows 10 installation.
Now I mentioned in the slide portion that one of your buying
decisions is going to be which edition, that's certainly true.
Editions come mostly in 64-bit versions because the vast
majority of any computer nowadays is going to have a
64-bit and not a 32-bit processor.
As far as knowing those system requirements,
let's open up an instance of edge and I'm going to do a search for Windows 10
system requirements and we've got right at the top here,
Windows 10 system requirements.
I'm not going to read these, but it's important for you to be aware of this.
If, for instance,
you're considering doing a fresh installation on an existing
computer or certainly in an upgrade situation,
how do you know, for instance, if you're running a Windows 10 machine,
how can you verify what its current hardware profile
and hardware configuration is.
That's a good question, isn't it?
Well there is some ways to answer that.
This is going to come to the floor in the next module,
but I might as well show it to you now.
Msinfo32 is also called the System Information app.
I actually have it running down here on my taskbar.
This is a great way to determine the metadata on a running
system and it's been in Windows for many years.
This is not a Windows 10 specific thing.
The System Summary just gives you right out of the box the OS Name,
edition, version, and build.
It also gives you your processor, your memory,
your storage,
but you can dip into the hardware resources to a pretty darn
granular degree just by clicking through the list and you can
export this data from the File menu,
you can bring it out all into a standard text file.
Again,
that can be useful when you're working with customer
equipment and you're planning a fresh reinstallation or an
upgrade installation of say Windows 10.
There are third-party tools, CPUZ is one,
Periform Speccy is another, that's what you're looking at right now.
I have links to these in the exercise files.
Speccy is cool because it gives you the metadata in a well I think
a pretty appealing way graphically and it can give you information
that you can't get from the msinfo32 like the temperature that your
motherboard is running at, your CPU temperature,
that kind of stuff.
Detailed info, it's good stuff.
Now to set up our next demo where we actually perform a clean installation.
What I recommend you do is to do a search for the Windows Evaluation center,
we'll go there right now.
This is where you can download fully functional trial version software.
Let me scroll down to the bottom and you can do this for anything in the family,
that is not just Windows client or Windows Server,
but the System Center tools I mentioned before,
it's all there.
I'm going to go to Windows Client and Windows 10 Enterprise sounds like a
really good edition to trial because it has all the features.
The evaluation terms here,
it looks like it's 90 days and we have to register in order to download it.
So you fill in your contact information and it will normally come down as a.
iso DVD image file and that's going to bring up questions like
well what the heck do you do with an ISO file.
I mentioned that there is the Media Creation tool,
Windows 10 media creation tool, there we go,
I'll select it from the list here.
And this tool allows you to, for instance,
create installation media on say a USB flash drive
from that ISO that you've downloaded.
Now I'm not going to step through all of that in this demo
because it gets too far out of scope, but once again,
check the exercise files for some links,
that's how you're going to solve that.
Now specifically in the next demo,
I'm going to use that ISO file itself by attaching it to a new VM, a new virtual machine.