In this demonstration,
I'm going to show you how the library system works in Windows 10.
The user interface has changed a little bit,
but the core functionality is still the same all the
way from Windows 7 on forward.
Let's open File Explorer, and as we're working through here,
I want to show some tips and tricks here that I may not have discussed before.
Now when you navigate,
you notice that the File Explorer path is actually clickable.
So I'm in this path, Pluralsight, tim-warner,
microsoft-operating-system-fundamentals,
and as I go further in, you'll notice that it expands.
You can work back and forth through that directory
path just by clicking back and forth.
Another thing you can do is open this chevron,
and it takes you back as far as you want,
all the way to the root of that local or remote volume.
You see what I mean?
If you know where you're going, let's say I want to go to my D drive,
I can just come into this, click to the right of it,
and that shows the actual full path.
I might need to right-click and copy that to paste it into
a script or something else I'm doing.
But alternatively, I can come in just like you can use a web browser,
the address bar, to type a path, you can do that here.
So I'll go d:\,
and then I can just pick from the list or start to type and use tab
completion and Enter to go to a new location.
I want you to be aware of these as really useful power-user tricks.
The View tab is where you can get to the libraries,
and also it brings us to a discussion of this left Navigation
Pane area that you can turn on or off if you want to use it
or if you don't want to use it.
As you see, I'm opening the Navigation Pane drop-down,
and you notice Show libraries.
This is how you can show or hide the libraries in that Navigation Pane.
As you're working, frequently used folders,
you can pin them to Quick access by dragging them
over here and go under Quick access.
Make sure you're getting a horizontal black line,
and you're not putting it inside of an entry that's there.
But when you let go, it becomes pinned,
and you can relocate that just by dragging and dropping.
And I use that feature all the time for my current projects that I'm working on.
When you want to remove an item from Quick Access,
right-click it and choose Unpin from Quick access in the shortcut menu,
and it's gone.
So that's Quick Access.
You also have a node for This PC,
which shows common folders in your user profile,
and then fixed drives and ones that have been mapped across the network.
Each of those drives also shows up as a separate node.
All of this can be expanded or contracted,
and then there's a Network tab as well.
This ties into the network discovery protocols in Windows.
In the real world,
you'll find that many systems administrators do not like
those discovery protocols because number one,
they're fairly chatty.
They put out what many consider to be unnecessary network traffic,
and they can have security issues and unintentionally
expose resources that users shouldn't see.
But anyway, all that is to serve the function of describing the library system.
So we have these default, or built-in libraries, as we see.
You can hide them by right-clicking and choosing Don't show
in navigation pane on a one-by-one basis.
If you want to hide all the libraries, I already told you about the navigation.
If we right-click a built-in library and come down to Properties,
it brings up a browser, really, where if we want to,
we can add additional resources to this list.
So if we use our desktop folder as a document repository,
we can browse to that location and choose Include folder.
The Optimize the library for allows you to choose
what's called a folder template, Documents,
Music Pictures, and Videos, and then General items are the defaults.
And the document template is what determines what view you see by
default and also what kind of columns you see.
Document templates are a pretty useful feature themselves.
Check the exercise files for some more information on that.
And actually, to that point,
I often will use this View menu here to go between the different views.
Oftentimes, when you're looking at documents,
it may show a view that you're not interested in,
like maybe the Content view.
And I'll go Details,
that happens to be my favorite view because I like being able to
quick sort on column properties like Date modified,
etc.
As far as the columns go,
you can right-click any column to turn columns on or off,
you can size the columns to fit, and if you go to More,
you can bring out additional columns and then add them to a current template.
That's in the exercise files because that goes beyond our scope for today.
Now I want to show you how to create you own library,
so let's right-click the Libraries node,
come down to New, Library.
Let's say we're performing a new research assignment,
so we've got a research project here.
I'll call it Research.
Once again,
we can right-click and go to Properties to optimize the
library for a specific media type.
This will largely be document files, so that's fine.
We can change the library icon if we want to.
Not sure if I want to do this.
Oh, what the heck, why don't I choose the magnifying glass.
And then we can add assets to include in the library.
Let me come to the right here and browse to my, I think I have a G drive.
No, I have a D drive, anyway, so let's go to D drive,
and I have a folder called docs.
I will select to include that folder,
and I have an F drive that uses the Resilient File System,
ReFS, so let me come up, type F:, Enter,
and I have a folder called projdata that's useful there.
So if I click OK, I know can browse into Research.
And you'll notice that the view here shows us file
lists based on those locations.
Isn't that cool?
So if we're searching, we can now search across multiple locations on our system.
Like if I'm looking for any content that involves Linux,
I can type Linux, and the Windows Search service not only searches on file names,
but also searches on file contents, which is really nice. I love that.