Cortana.
The historical perspective with Cortana doesn't go as far back as
many of my other historical perspective slides have.
Here, you see virtual digital assistants,
Google Home on the right, Amazon Echo in the middle,
and iPhone on the left, and each vendor has their own digital assistant.
Apple has Siri, Amazon has Alexa, and Google has the Google Assistant,
and the idea with these is that they're supposed to make
your life easier because you can use natural language to
give these devices instructions.
Will it rain tomorrow?
What is my drive time look like today?
What is the time in Los Angeles, California or Shanghai?
You see what I mean?
Now the tradeoff with all of these virtual digital assistants is
that you're giving up a little bit of privacy because you're
sharing some of your habits with the vendor.
This speaks to a larger point of cloud computing where in
order to get this really nice personalized experience from
these digital assistants, you wind up needing to trust that Microsoft,
Google, Amazon will handle your personal data responsibly.
Now how does this fit into Windows l0?
Well Microsoft has its own virtual assistant,
it is named Cortana, code-named Cortana.
Now it's officially called Cortana.
If you play the Halo video games, Cortana was a character from that echo system.
Microsoft, from what I understand, had a different name in mind for Cortana,
but so many users loved the code name that it became
the formal name for this product.
Now at the right,
you see a screenshot of a Windows 10 Start menu and you know that you
can press the Start button on your keyboard or click the Start icon and
just start to type to get search results.
That's using the Windows search and indexing service, that's fine.
Now you can put your searches on a much higher plane by integrating with
this Cortana virtual assistant that ships with Windows 10.
Now up until Fall 2017 when Microsoft released the Fall creators update,
you were unable to get rid of or disable Cortana fully.
If you do want to do that for privacy reasons or performance reasons,
I'll actually show you how to do that in a demo,
but if you are willing to let Microsoft know some of your web browsing habits,
potentially your contacts, calendar details,
seems like a lot.
So again, I just can't stress that enough,
this does require a fundamental element of trust.
You need to trust Microsoft.
If you choose to accept those terms,
what you get in return is the ability for Cortana to
give you all sorts of well assistance, directions,
you can set reminders, and you don't have to do this with a keyboard,
you can actually use your voice.
Cortana can be trained to respond to your voice as well,
and what's kind of novel, I think, about Cortana,
Microsoft from what I understand actually used real physical
personal assistants as the model for Cortana and they found by
working with real live personal assistants that these assistants
pretty much run their lives through notebooks to keep track of
everything they need to remember.
And the way you configure Cortana,
the way you can retrieve what she knows so to speak or supply her
with additional intelligence is through the metaphor of the notebook and that's what I'm highlighting here.