And what we can do there is I'll open Start and type Computer Management,
and hover over that guy.
Start it up.
Computer Management is a really nice rollup console that has a
lot of neat stuff in it for troubleshooting,
and performance optimization, and device management,
but what we want to look at is Local Users and Groups,
and here we can see I haven't yet renamed my local administrator account,
so I'm going to do that now.
I'm going to right-click, and I'm going to call it thc1038.
Does that Id ring a bell with you at all?
Maybe it doesn't because it's not 1038 it's actually 1138.
I'll leave that to you to research the significance of this Id.
You can change the password for a local account by choosing Set Password,
as you can see here.
I do have a Guest account on this system, surprisingly.
I think I might have upgraded this from an earlier version of Windows.
If you go to the Properties of any account you can adjust things
like whether the account's enabled or disabled,
whether it's been locked out due to too many authentication attempts,
which groups the account belongs to.
I'm logged on as Tim.
You're wondering on a Windows 10 box how you can figure out who's logged on.
You can open up a PowerShell prompt, let me cls to clear the screen,
and type whoami, and that'll tell you either a computer name or a domain name.
I happen to know that devbox is the name of my computer,
backslash, and then the user who's currently logged on,
so devbox\tim is my full identity.
Hostname, by the way,
is another one I use a lot when I need a sanity check on the machine name,
okay?
So there's groups which provide a way to manage users in bulk,
and really not too necessary on a client system.
Systems administrators manipulate the membership of these groups all day long.
Now there's a number of special purpose groups,
depending upon which optional features you've enabled.
If you enable client-side Hyper-V notice that you get Hyper-V Administrators.
If you have the IIS web server installed on your
Windows 10 box you'll have an IIS group,
but the main ones are Users, and Administrators,
and then to a much lesser degree, Guests.
Those are the three that have been around in Windows the longest.
Final thing I want to show is domain join.
This is a Windows Server 2016 machine.
I'm going to open the Run box and type dsa.
msc to open the Active Directory Users and Computers console.
This is, like the local users and groups we saw on the Windows 10 box,
but this is a central console that can be spread
across an entire business network.
You see what I mean?
Now I've created a domain identity called trainer.
I don't remember what the password was, so I'm going to reset it right now.
Okay, that's been changed, and notice that there's a Computers folder,
and I haven't joined any workstations to the domain yet,
but that's actually going to change.
The name of the domain is company.
pri.
Back in Windows 10 what we can do, open up Cortana,
and let's see if it recognizes join domain.
Nope, it doesn't really like that.
How about if I open the Start menu and do join domain.
No, it doesn't like that either.
Well that's unfortunate.
How do you join a domain from Windows 10?
You might be thinking,
well why don't you fire up PowerShell and run add-computer?
That's actually very valid,
but I want to show you how to do it through the graphical interface.
We do that through the System Control panel,
so let me type System, press Enter to select the best match,
and under system we can come under computer name,
domain, and workgroup settings.
Change settings.
Look at that shield.
That shield denotes that this is an administrative activity
that requires user account control elevation.
I'm kind of surprised that I didn't get prompted for consent there, hmm.
In the System Properties old school control panel we'll come
down to Change for to rename this computer or change its
domain or workgroup click Change, and I'm going to say,
I want to be part of the company.
pri domain, and it says, okay, well you need administrator credentials for that.
I have an administrative account called tim.
I'll provide my creds, and a hand shaking is going on.
Oh, it didn't like the password.
Let me try that again.
Click OK, or maybe it was trainer, come to think of it.
Company is the name of the domain, in this case.
Trainer, put in my password, let me retype that,
okay, and as I was saying, some handshaking is going on.
I'm going to have to reset the credentials.
I'm going to pause the video.
Hang on just a second.
It turns out that I can use that trainer account
because it is an administrative account,
and I actually, so I think I have the password correct this time around.
There we go.
Welcome to the company.
pri domain.
If I click OK it tells us that we have to restart in
order for this to go into effect.
Now while that's restarting I'm going to come back to my
server because if we go under Computers now it looks like
it's not showing up quite yet.
Let me right-click and refresh.
There we go.
We have a computer account now because we're managing that DEVBOX computer,
and we're going to log on to that computer,
not as the Tim account that I've been using so far,
as a matter of fact,
if I try those credentials they're going to fail because I don't have an
identity on the domain under that name and password,
so I'm going to need to choose an Active Directory user account name.
I'm going to choose trainer.
Okay, so I'm being prompted to log on here.
It wants to log me on as Tim, and you know I can supply a password here,
and I'll be authenticated just fine because this is assuming
that I want to log on to the local computer,
but I don't want to do that, so I'm going to come over to Other user,
and notice it says, Sign in to: COMPANY.
Just for grins let me try to submit my credentials, my Tim credentials.
It says, the user name or password is incorrect.
Try again.
Alright,
but if I do trainer and put in the correct password it should recognize me,
there we go, and it's giving us the little welcome to Windows 10 business,
and then it should give us our desktop momentarily.
So here we are logged on as a domain user named trainer,
and we're off and running.
If we want to log out we can open Start,
expand the left side, come down to the currently logged on user,
trainer.
We can change account settings, lock the system,
sign out, or switch the account,
which allows multiple users to be logged on at the same time.
I would choose sign out.
If, for instance, I wanted to sign in as the local Tim identity it asks us here,
are you sure you want to sign out?
This Task Host is still running in the background.
That's fine.
I'll sign out anyway, and this time I'll come back to Other user.
Now this is a good tip I'm going to show you.
You saw that if I just use tim it's going to fail
because it says Sign in to: COMPANY.
If I want to do a local identity I need to know the name of the box,
which I think is devbox\ then the user account name.
It has to be a backslash, not a forward slash,
and notice it says Sign in to: DEVBOX, so now I can put in the password,
and away we go. Here's our original environment.