Local disk maintenance.
Now depending upon what kind of disk you're using in Windows 10,
namely if it's a physical or virtual disk,
and whether the physical disk is HDD or SSD,
you'll want to perform routine and regular maintenance to
maximize the efficiency of the disk's performance,
as well as to extend its lifetime.
So we have a number of tools built into Windows 10.
Some are new, like the Windows Automatic Maintenance tool,
and some have been around so long they even predate
Windows and existed originally in MS-DOS.
The Windows Automatic Maintenance tool is essentially a wizard,
it's very difficult to turn this off actually,
Microsoft really wants it to be on and running,
that will routinely perform some of the other
utilities that you'll see on this slide.
Disk defragmentation has been around for a long time.
It's relevant primarily with HDD storage.
You might remember way back when,
when we talked about disk partitions and volumes and the fact that on
a volume you have these clusters that are the fundamental allocation
units when Windows stores data for you, and over time as you're copying files,
moving files, deleting files, saving new files,
it's possible, and likely,
that the different clusters that make up a particular file or
application may become spread across the disk,
and that's going to slow read performance of course because your
physical disk's going to have to wander all over those disk platters
to round up all of the associated clusters.
Defragmentation software puts all of the file clusters right next to each other,
what's called contiguously, and this of course improves I/O.
Now there's another operation mixed up with defragmentation
called trim that you can do on solid-state drives,
but we're not going to be concerned with that necessarily.
In the demo I'm going to show you all these tools,
so more will become plain as we go along.
In general though,
you don't want to run traditional disk defragmentation on a
flash drive because a flash drive doesn't store data in a
cluster map like what happens on HDDs.
Disk Cleanup has been around in Windows for a while.
It's a way to purge temp files.
Of course, in your browsers you can purge temp files,
but Disk Cleanup provides a centralized interface to
give you back some disk space.
Frankly,
this tool used to be more important years ago when
disk storage was more expensive.
Windows Update is a service that's non-optional.
You absolutely need to have your Windows 10 machine updating,
depending upon which deployment and update ring you're in.
If you're in the regular semi-annual channel,
you're going to receive updates on a schedule.
We'll have more to talk about Windows Update in detail later,
but the bottom line is if you're not using Windows Update,
you're rapidly expanding the attack surface,
or potential attack surface of your machine.
System Restore is a way to roll your system back in time.
If, for instance, you install a bad driver,
or if you install an application and you really regret it,
and even trying to uninstall the application is unsuccessful,
System Restore takes snapshots of your system periodically,
and allows you, as I said, to roll back.
Now a common fear that people have, some people have,
about System Restore is that well, if I restore my system back to,
say, last Tuesday, I'm going to lose all of my data that I created.
That's not true.
The only stuff that's going to be rolled back are
application and configuration changes, which still might be inconvenient, but a heck of a lot more convenient than potentially reinstalling Windows.