Configure Desktop Applications.
Now the section we just came out of I taught you how to
manage optional components in Windows.
Those are applications, many of them,
and specifically we would call them Traditional Desktop Applications,
but they ship with Windows natively.
Now I want to turn your attention to first and third-party applications
that you would install separately on a Windows system.
This screen capture shows you PowerPoint 2017 running on a Windows box.
Now this is a little meta,
but if you look at the slides there on the left hand part of this window it's
actually the slide deck that you're looking at right now,
so it's one of those cool things like if you take a
picture of yourself taking a picture, and then take a picture of that picture,
you know, that recursive kind of thing.
Anyway, a traditional desktop app is what you're accustomed to,
it seems to me, since the earliest days of Windows.
It's installed separately on each system.
Most applications nowadays are network aware.
Some of them pull maybe the majority of their data online,
but they're actually installed locally.
They register themselves in the Windows registry, although there's exceptions.
There's portable desktop apps that are fully
self-contained executable program files.
These traditional desktop apps are normally referred to as
thick client or fat client apps because they do have
footprint on each systems hard drive.
Now the trend that Microsoft began with Windows 8 is what's
called the Universal Windows Platform App,
and we haven't formally defined UWP yet,
but I want to get you thinking of some more
characteristics that define the desktop apps first.
Desktop apps are not centrally curated by Microsoft.
If you've ever gone in the Windows store,
the application,
all of those apps that you see listed have been vetted or tested,
and proved, approved I should say, by Microsoft.
That's not the case with desktop apps.
There's just too many of them.
Microsoft controls the Windows App Store by contrast.
Desktop apps are not sandboxed, generally,
unless they've been written that way or permissions-constrained,
nor are they optimized for touch gestures,
again, unless the application has been specifically programmed for that.
They're not necessarily consistent with user interface across platforms.
Now that we can look at Microsoft Office as a good example of that.
Not too many years ago the experience between,
say, Microsoft Word, Excel,
PowerPoint on Windows was very different from what you saw on Mac OS.
In the latest version of Office for Mac Microsoft has done a good
job of creating a consistent user interface,
but still you run into that,
the Mac version and the Windows version being very different,
and even from a mobile standpoint, the interface of an app on an iPad,
which is Apple iOS, Surface, which is Windows 10,
and Android that runs Google Android,
those user interfaces can be very inconsistent and require
a separate learning curve per platform.
I want to go back to that second bullet point,
the fact that traditional desktop apps are not
sandboxed or permissions constrained.
That's actually important because if you install a desktop
application that is either you've downloaded a modified version of a
legitimate app that has malicious code in it,
or the app has been affected after you've installed it,
either way,
the no sandboxing means that potentially malicious code that attaches
to the desktop app can do anything on your system up to the level of
permissions of the currently logged on user,
and if you're logged on to your system as a network administrator,
or in the Windows world a domain administrator,
then you could potentially, not intentionally of course, but unintentionally wreak havoc in your network environment.