Diagnostic Startup Options.
Now we're getting into the real meat and potatoes of
troubleshooting a Windows system.
We looked in the previous module at backup methods,
where you could do a System Image backup or a Recovery Drive backup,
and then if your system becomes unstable and you suspect that your Windows
installation has become hopelessly damaged or corrupt,
you have options for reinstalling Windows with the idea of fixing the problem.
This screenshot shows in the Settings application,
Update & Security, the Recovery area.
I mentioned the Reset possibility in the previous module,
notice that you can also go back to a previous version of Windows 10.
What that means is you may have the ability within a certain
timeframe to roll back out of a major update.
You know how twice a year we have a major update released by Microsoft,
it's a twice-yearly cycle,
but depending upon how Microsoft service level agreements,
or SLAs, work, that may or may not be available.
And notice down at the bottom, that Advanced startup,
that's an important control to be able to know about,
because historically in Windows if you wanted to start using
what's called the advanced startup options,
where you're booting into a recovery environment to do
troubleshooting that requires more work than just,
say, rolling back a system restore point,
you would normally have to restart the system and very early in the process,
right between the boot, the system motherboard boot,
and when Windows takes over you would press F8 to invoke that menu.
Well, with UEFI systems in particular that's never going to work,
UEFI is not going to allow that, and it goes by too quickly anyway.
So I want to show you in the next demo convenient ways to
restart the system in a diagnostic mode.
The diagnostic mode in Windows 10 is called the Windows
Recovery Environment or Windows RE.
You know that System Reserved partition that you have at the front of
your System Drive that doesn't have a drive letter,
you can't interact with it directly,
that contains the Windows Recovery Environment.
You can also boot your computer off your Windows 10 DVD if you have that.
Of course,
you may have to adjust your UEFI or BIOS boot order to accommodate that.
If you have a Recovery Drive set up on a USB stick,
you can boot off of the USB stick.
There are a number of ways to go to get into that Windows
RE or Windows Recovery Environment.
Another way is using the System Configuration utility.
This is what you get if you type msconfig from a
command prompt or the Start menu.
You notice that on the boot page here you can choose if you're
dual botting or tri-booting your system,
you can choose a different OS to boot into,
and you can also customize how the boot occurs.
We'll talk more about Safe Mode in just a moment.
Before we get into the demo,
I want to walk you through the screens in Windows Recovery
Environment just so you're familiar with the workflow,
and then in the demo it'll become hopefully more intuitive.
When you reboot your system into a recovery mode,
you have mouse support, you have the potential for network support,
the days of the old blue screen text-only interface are long gone fortunately,
you're presented with some options that you see here.
To continue,
which comes out of Windows Recovery Environment and
boots boots back into Windows 10, Troubleshoot,
which is what we're going to choose, or Turn off your PC.
Turn off your PC can be handy, for instance,
if the machine is suspected to be riddled with malware.
You want to turn it off, disconnect it from the network,
and then, again, do a diagnostic startup to get troubleshooting.
When you go to Troubleshoot, you see an option to reset this PC.
If you're booting from a Recovery Drive USB stick,
you'll see an option to recover from the Recovery Drive.
Reset is, as I said in the previous module,
gives you a flexible option to either remove all your
personal files and reinstall Windows, or just to reinstall Windows,
what's called a refresh scenario.
Now from a troubleshooting perspective,
does that clear up the ghosts in the machine?
It really depends, quite honestly.
A lot of times big businesses, enterprises,
if a user is suspected of having an operating system problem,
their entire hard drive will just be re-imaged from scratch,
which is really a true reset operation,
but in a smaller shop you might want to think a little bit more carefully before
doing something invasive like that in the interest of time.
If you click Reset this PC,
this is where you get the choice to either keep your
files and just reinstall Windows, or remove everything,
which is what you'd do if you're going to destroy your computer,
or pass it on or sell it to someone else.
If you choose Advanced options,
you get a separate menu that allows you to hit System Restore.
This is good for doing restore points in an outside
the operating system context.
You have System Image Recovery.
If you used the Windows 7 Backup tool to create a system image,
you can bring it back here.
Startup Repair,
which looks at your boot files and will replace them with fresh
pristine copies form your Windows 10 installation media.
You can get a command prompt,
which you can get into PowerShell with and do scripting automation,
or you could do Startup Settings to change Windows startup behavior.
Again,
depending upon how long it's been since you last applied a bi-annual update,
you may have go back to the previous version,
or you may not, but if you choose Startup Settings,
you're then given a prompt to restart again,
and that is the so-called Advanced options menu that we used to,
in previous versions of Windows,
boot into if you held down or pressed F8 repeatedly,
and the Startup Settings dialog looks a lot better than it used to back in,
say, Windows 98, Windows 2000 days.
But the options are largely the same.
You can do debugging mode, which is pretty much an edge case; boot logging,
where you want Windows to record a file of every boot file that it
loads into memory; low-resolution video; Safe Mode,
notice that there's three different varieties of Safe Mode.
Safe Mode is where in all likelihood you've installed a bad device
driver and you either have no video once you get into Windows or
it's just all wonky and messed up, or you've enabled another driver,
like a network driver, and it breaks connectivity.
Safe Mode is a really low overhead way to boot into Windows,
and you can take care of your registry and drive problems,
and then hopefully be able to start a second time into normal mode.
This is a screenshot of Windows 10 in Safe Mode.
It's quite apparent you still have to authenticate
using a local or domain account,
but it's quite apparent that you are in Safe Mode.
You see the build information up on the top center,
you see Safe Mode markers, the desktop wallpaper is black,
and most notably, the screen resolution is super-duper low, 640 x 480.