What I'm showing you here are various manual methods for inventorying
the software and hardware on a Windows 10 machine,
but in an enterprise where you may be responsible for dozens,
hundreds, thousands, or tens of thousands of systems,
it's obviously impossible, not to say impractical,
to do these manual tasks.
When you get to enterprise-level configuration management,
that's where tools like good old System Center Configuration Manager,
which I've mentioned a lot in this course thus far,
can automate that aggregation,
and you can generate reports across all your workstations on any hardware.
Show me machines that have such and so a network card,
show me machines that are running this version of Windows,
but in this context here,
this is perfect to get you started because you have to
learn to --- what's that old saying?
You have to learn to crawl before you can walk, and you have to walk before you can run.