User Account Control.
UAC or User Account Control was introduced in Windows Vista,
and it had a rocky start because it was pretty intrusive.
The idea is that a task is either requiring
elevation or not requiring elevation.
Something like starting Microsoft Word or a web browser shouldn't
require that you be an administrator to do so.
Open the registry editor, on the other hand,
that would certainly be considered an administrative task,
so UAC represents a layer to protect the computer operator from
inadvertently running high privilege tasks.
They'll either be blocked from doing so,
as I said earlier, unless they have administrative credentials,
or they'll be prompted to continue based on the settings.
When UAC happens the screen dims.
This is a special mode called Secure Desktop,
and the idea there is that any other system,
any other process on that machine I should say,
is temporarily suspended,
and that answer to the UAC prompt or the input of administrative credentials,
you're only communicating with the Windows Security subsystem,
and that's it.
It's meant to kill any malware that's trying to
steal credentials through elevation.
Now the best practice is to actually turn the UAC prompts up.
They're nowhere near as intrusive as they originally were in Vista,
where they seem to pop-up every other action you wanted to try.
Now enough years have passed to where the UAC elevation,
while still is regular if the person is regularly doing administrative things,
isn't anywhere near as annoying as it once was.
I want to make sure that you understand not to get numb to those prompts.
You don't just want to become in the habit of
clicking yes to agree to a UAC prompt.
Make sure you're inspecting what's going on and what is
expected to happen is what actually is happening,
and as far as your standard users go they're going to have to
maybe contact you to put in credentials if they're not able
to do an administrative task.
That's going to be on your shoulders to ask yourself and ask the user, why is it that you're trying to do said administrative task?