Where to go next.
Well, your career is up to you, isn't it?
I would suggest that you let your passion be your guide.
My late Grandpa Cook used to say, Tim,
you know you're in the right job when it's not a job,
when it's a career, number 1, and what makes it a career?
According to my Grandpa Cook it was if you're doing work that
you would do even if you weren't getting paid,
you've found your career,
and that's how I feel about teaching and information technology.
What's your passion?
Well, your passion has three elements.
This is the world according to Tim Warner,
but I hope you find my analysis useful.
One would be interest.
Think of Grandpa Cook.
What aspects of IT inspire you the most?
Are you allergic to programming or does it actually intrigue you?
Are you interested in helping individual users, maybe in a help desk role?
Do you like architecture and planning systems?
You need to have an interest,
because otherwise you're not going to last very long in IT,
I can assure you of that.
Aptitude is, alright, you're interested in development,
but what native ability do you have with mathematics and logical thinking?
How are you understanding flowcharting, for instance?
What kind of intuitive feel do you have for troubleshooting problems?
You need to align your interests with your natural abilities.
And thirdly, availability.
Are you in a position in terms of time, money,
your family and life situation, your willingness to invest in learning,
because you're going to need to get your big break if you're getting into IT.
You're going to have to convince a business to take a chance on you.
Once you gain your sea legs and you can demonstrate your effectiveness,
then subsequent jobs, subsequent contracts as your career evolves,
will become much easier.
In defining your skill set more granularly,
I myself have largely been a generalist,
so all five of these categories fit in my wheelhouse,
but I'm probably in the minority really with most people.
Most people tend to gravitate toward one of these categories.
Server,
this would be the Windows Server product and the different
enterprise servers like SharePoint and Exchange,
perhaps Microsoft Azure.
This is system administration, system architecture.
Then there's desktop support, Windows and Windows-capable,
Windows devices, this could be hardware,
software maintenance, data center technician,
although that's kind of blurring the lines between server and desktop.
Application support, Office applications, Office 365 is a huge subject nowadays.
You can build your whole career doing consulting work in Office 365.
Any business is going to have databases.
Microsoft's own flagship product is SQL Server.
And then if you have determined that you're really interested in programming,
there is Visual Studio and the.
NET framework language, there's SharePoint applications,
there's Azure development.
The bottom line is, and this is all just within the Microsoft wheelhouse,
if you go outside of Microsoft into, say,
the open source world, all five of these categories are listed there as well. Pretty exciting time to be in IT, I hope you'd agree.