Now let's look at work and school accounts.
Work accounts, school account,
and organizational account are all aliases for an
Azure Active Directory account.
To formally define an Azure Active directory is
Microsoft's cloud information store.
Now if you have experience managing on-premises Active Directory,
you wonder if this is the same thing, the answer to that is no,
not at all.
There is not parity between true local forests and
domain Active Directory and Azure AD.
Azure AD is a much simplified account store, okay.
Office 365 actually uses Azure Active Directory for its identity management,
and Microsoft Azure natively uses it.
It's a great flexible store for use in authentication
scenarios with cloud-based applications,
as I've said earlier.
Here is the UI for connecting to an Azure AD account.
As you saw in the first demo, the user experience is still in flux.
Microsoft is gradually, very slowly,
migrating the classic Control Panel applets into the Settings app,
but as it is it's very messy with user management,
ping-ponging between those two experiences,
and I daresay it's messy even here,
attaching to your Microsoft account and certainly authenticating to Azure AD.
But in settings you go under Accounts, Access work or school,
and you can connect to an Azure AD environment there.
Now what benefits does this give you?
It gives you a few.
One is administrators can use Microsoft Intune to manage the device.
This is good for businesses,
predominantly smaller businesses that don't have the money or the human
resource capital to maintain an on-premises domain.
They can still do device management using Intune,
and to do that you're going to need to actually
register and then join an Azure AD domain.
I'll show you that workflow in the next demo, as a matter of fact.
I don't want to get too deeply into this,
because we get beyond the scope of this course strictly speaking,
but that's the main reason.
It's called mobile device management, or MDM.
I'm not a great fan of that term with Windows 10 because,
yeah,
I guess we could consider a Windows 10 phone and
Windows 10 based tablet mobile devices,
but if it's a desktop computer it's not particular mobile,
but those desktop computers can be managed right alongside
phones and tablets using Microsoft Intune.
Now you may be wondering what is the guidance from the Microsoft
Windows team with these different accounts.
Here's the deal, Microsoft accounts are predominantly aimed at the consumer,
not for business, for the aforementioned reasons.
In business,
Microsoft suggests that you continue to use Active Directory domain
accounts as your source of authority for your users,
and your baseline for management.
However,
you might consider setting up a synchronization between your on-premises Active
Directory to an Azure AD tenant in the Microsoft cloud to facilitate single
sign-on with SaaS apps like Office 365 and others,
and also potentially for integration with Microsoft Intune mobile device management, etc.