Okay, in this demonstration, let's work with SMB file sharing.
File sharing in SMB is exposed through a couple services,
and I'm going to right-click the Start menu,
or the Start button, I should say, on my Windows 10 box.
Go to Run.
This is an Enterprise edition system, so I have all the business controls here.
I'm going to type services.
msc to open the Microsoft Management Console.
Because I'm logged onto this system as a standard user,
I'm going to need to actually authenticate as a domain administrator.
By the way, this system belongs to an Active Directory domain.
So I've launched services as an administrator.
I will sort by name, and if I go to s, I'll find a service called Server.
The service name is LanmanServer.
And this service needs to be running on a system in order for it to
share resources using the Server Message Block protocol.
If I go to w, I'll see a LanmanWorkstation service.
The formal name, or the short name, is Workstation.
And this is the SMB client service that's required.
You'll also want to look at the network interface card level.
Again, I'll right-click Start, go to Run, and type ncpa.
cpl.
That's the short name for the network connections dialog.
And if right-click my Internal Lan, the one that's connected to the domain,
again, I'm being prompted for credentials.
This is user account control in action,
saying that I do not have sufficient privileges.
Yikes.
Well, let's try that one more time with feeling.
I'll do Properties, and I'll supply credentials that I know are powerful enough.
And there we see the File and Printer Sharing for Microsoft Networks component,
and that is enabled on this network card.
Now technically, we can share resources here on the workstation,
but in business, that's really not how it's done.
It's done on the server,
so let's switch our focus over to the Windows Server
2016 machine here and this fileserver.
And I have a folder here called reports that contains a number of documents.
If we right-click that folder and go to Properties,
we have two tabs that are important for our purposes.
There's Sharing, and you can see I've already shared this folder,
but the way that works, you can go the simple method or the advanced method.
I'm not even going to show you the simple method because it's too simplified.
I want you to have full control and know exactly what's going on here.
So you go to Advanced Sharing,
and you can toggle Share this folder from off to on.
You advertise the folder under the share name of the folder itself.
That's what happens by default.
But let's say you're sharing a folder that has a
really wacky non-intuitive name.
You can actually add an additional share name to make it
easier for your users to file that, to find,
I should say, that resource.
Permissions is where you can set those permissions,
and this is what's called a discretionary access control list,
or DACL, for short, D-A-C-L.
And you know the general best practice is to set
the share permissions wide open.
And the Everyone identity is about as wide open as you can possibly get.
Do you see the logic of setting the shared folder
permissions to Everyone Full Control?
Notice that when you choose a lower-level permission like Read,
these are standard permissions, by the way,
the other are cleared.
The permissions are only going to dictate which identity has which permission.
Change gives you read plus the ability to write.
Full Control gives you change and read and also the ability
to edit the actual access control list.
Any explicit deny will override any corresponding allowance.
There's a logic to this, but it takes a while for it to become intuitive.
I don't expect that you're come away from this single demo
being a master of shared and NTFS permissions,
so don't have that expectation.
You'll want to search for this, NTFS permissions,
shared folder permissions, Windows, SMB,
in the Pluralsight library to get some remedial advice.
Now if you really want to be more secure,
we can look for another identity, and I use the term identity advisedly.
Everyone is not an account, a group account,
that's going to show up in the Active Directory users and groups tool.
It's an identity that's used that you can add to access control
lists or remove from access control lists,
but you can't interact with it more than that.
There's an identity called Authenticated Users that
some administrators prefer to use.
Let me do that for Allow, and let me remove Everyone.
And this identity is only those who have been
successfully authenticated to the domain.
Everyone really represents a security hazard because it
involves non-authenticated users.
You see what I mean?
So some contractor could come into your business who doesn't have a
domain account and potentially see these resources.
So if we do Authenticated Users, Full Control,
Allow, that's wide open at the share level.
Now the share is what actually makes the folder available on the network.
You have to do the sharing step in order for your users to see the resource,
and then the Security tab is where you have the access
control list for NTFS file system.
And here we have the SYSTEM identity, which is the local operating system.
You want to leave that one alone.
Administrators, which are your systems administrators, that's fine.
And then this DACL has Domain Users with modify,
so anybody who's at least a user in this domain will be able to read and write.
Well, if we were to cut that down to Read & execute instead,
let's go to edit, I'll choose Domain Users,
Read & execute.
We've got List folder contents, Read & execute.
You can read about these different standard permissions
by investigating the exercise files.
That's going to cut down on the shared full control permissions that we set at the share level.