Alright, in this demo we'll look at Resource Monitor and Performance Monitor.
We mentioned in the previous demo that Reliability Monitor is a great
way to look at your system's behavior over time.
Resource Monitor is an extension really,
at least I consider it to be an extension of Task Manager.
So let's open up Start and type resource monitor,
and that comes up as a Desktop app here that runs in a
traditional Microsoft management console.
Now if I collapse CPU, you see at the top level here on the Overview page,
we have a panel devoted to each of the four major subsystems of a computer.
The processor, the hard drive, the network,
and memory,
and we can see what's called a heatmap that shows the
average usage on those metrics, and then the peak.
So our CPU, at least my CPU, has hit 100% maximum frequency,
my disk has had 2-3% Highest Active Time,
that's not bad, very low Network Utilization,
and about half of my Physical Memory is used.
Well let's expand one of these and we can see what's going on.
We're going to get a list of processes that are in a couple different states,
Running processes and ones that are sleeping,
or Suspended.
Now let me quick sort by a couple criteria.
Let's do Average CPU, and we have this MSMPEng.
We can select that process and then right-click it to
end the process and the process tree, analyze the wait chain,
in other words, are there other processes or actions that this one is blocking.
We can search online, and it looks like it's going to hit up Edge, bing.
com, and just search for that executable image name, MsMpEng.
exe, and we see here that it's a component in Windows Defender.
Okay, no big surprise there.
And you notice that we can go per subsystem here, CPU, Memory, Disk, Network.
Again, I'll do a quick sort, and when we select an image here,
notice that sometimes the view changes.
For instance, on the CPU page, we've selected MsMpEng,
and its associated service is in this case the Defender service.
And notice that right from here, you can Stop the service,
Restart it, or do a Search Online.
That's really useful.
Let me deselect that, and now I've selected the SearchIndexer process.
This is an important process that indexes all of the files and folders on
your system so that you can find them conveniently.
It looks like its associated service is Windows Search, again no surprise.
And then under Handles,
let me collapse these other ones that I don't need right now,
it shows you specifically what that process is doing,
what kind of activity it's performing, is it a file event?
Is it some kind of trace event that could be logged?
Where in the registry is that SearchIndexer process accessing?
Now of course this is a huge amount of resources that SearchIndexer
is touching because it's such a pervasive service,
so much so that I know some people who disable it in Windows Client.
I don't recommend that.
I would never do that myself because I rely upon Windows Search so heavily.
So like I said, the theme goes on here, and it actually will keep,
Resource Monitor will keep your selection,
so you can then go to each subsystem individually.
In this case, it's showing how much RAM SearchIndexer is using,
and it's actually using quite a bit.
I'm not surprised.
Search does in fact exert a pretty good hold on the system.
And we have disk and network.
Let me select OneDrive for instance,
and we can drill down and look and see what kind of
network activity that process is doing.
In my system it's very quiet.
What TCP connections are involved.
Notice that the remote port is 443.
That means that OneDrive is completely firewall friendly.
You know that SSL/TLS uses TCP 443,
but this can be a good spot to look at a suspicious
process and its associated TCP connections.
Frankly,
I don't normally think of Reliability Monitor as a
troubleshooting tool as far as malware,
but it actually could be very helpful for that indeed.
So that's Reliability Monitor.
Before we look at Performance Monitor,
I want to go out to the Sysinternals live page,
live.
sysinternals.
com.
We've looked at a few of these tools thus far,
we've look at, in particular, auto runs,
and I did show you Process Explorer, but I want to bring that back.
I want to re-download it.
I'm going to bring down Process Explorer 64, that's the 64-bit version.
I'm going to save it to my desktop, I'm going to open it as an administrator,
we'll confirm that, and this is an alternative to using Resource Monitor.
It does have a learning curve associated with it though.
I like it because it's hoverable.
Notice that these service hosts are oftentimes difficult to figure out which
services each service host process is actually hosting,
but here nothing is left to the imagination.
It tells you exactly.
And this one I'm hovering over now,
it looks like all it's doing is Plug and Play.
This next one looks like it has quite a bit going on, DCOM, System Event Broker.
You can look at these processes and focus them on a particular CPU core,
that's what called processor affinity.
You can Kill, Restart, Suspend the process.
You can go to Properties, and again, this is another course unto itself.
As far as looking at the Performance metrics for that process, it's all here.
The threads, the TCP ports, the strings,
it's all here in Sysinternals Process Explorer.
I wanted to double underline that tool.
My colleague and friend, Sami Laiho,
does Sysinternals training for us at Pluralsight,
so you can remediate those skills if they need remediation.
Final thing we're going to do is Performance Monitor, or PerfMon.
I'm going to open Run and type PerfMon, one of many ways to open this tool.
Performance Monitor has a live view, that's the Performance Monitor as such,
and then there's Data Collector Sets where you can run a
Performance Monitor trace and save the results.
What you're seeing on screen here are live results that
will go away when you're finished.
And it shows you percent processor time by default,
and you know that it's been that way since before the turn of the century,
since the late '90s, even I dare say mid '90s.
Performance Monitor has been around and percent
processor time has always been the default.
Now in the interest of time,
we can't really deep dive on this as much as I want to,
but we have plenty of deep training in our library.
And what I want to say is,
Performance Monitor first of all focuses on the local computer,
but you can absolutely browse and hit a remote box.
You do that here, this is one spot to do it in the Add Counters.
These counters refer to metrics that you can load in.
The specific counters are rolled up under what are called objects.
So we have this Processor object,
and then underneath that Processor object class,
we have all sorts of instances.
So for CPU, for instance, you could look at just CPU 0,
CPO 1, CPU 1 rather, or across All instances or Total.
And the specific objects you see here are going to depend
upon what software you have installed.
There's a whole bunch of these, hundreds,
that are just natively in Windows,
but then as you install additional software that reads
into the Performance Monitor system, I have SQL Server installed,
so you'll see I can load up counters for SQL Server here all day long.
Then there's some SMB, did you see that?
SMB Server Shares, Server Sessions, you load up your counters,
and they'll show up as different colored lines,
but you can change the view.
There's three different ways to show the view.
You can open and look at a Histogram bar, or you could look at a report.
Being colorblind, this is what I like to see here,
and each time it updates, it presents some new data.
So Performance Monitor is cool for that.
Performance Monitor is also cool because it allows you to view logged data,
and you can view that logged data from a saved log file.
Where do you get the log file?
That's under Data Collector Sets.
This is where you can set a Performance Monitor
trace to happen locally or remotely.
These DCSs, as they're called,
you have a bucket for any that you create from scratch,
and then there's some that are here by default.
There's one called System Diagnostics and one called System Performance.
If I double left-click the Performance Counter,
we can see which counters have been added into this System Diagnostics DCS.
And at first blush you think, well that's not a whole lot.
It looks like we're going to grab counters on Process,
PhysicalDisk, Processor, Memory, System,
but if you're familiar with what the star means,
that means all Processes, all PhysicalDisks,
all processors.
It's going to be an enormous amount of data.
So when you run a DCS, or Data Collector Set, you want to put bounds on it.
When you look at the properties of one,
one of the things you can do is create a schedule if you want it to recur,
and you also want to make sure to set a stop condition.
You can have it stop after a certain amount of time,
and then you could even have a task happen when the data collector sets stops.
A notification task, a PowerShell script, whatever.
Long story short, Performance Monitor is super useful,
but the main caveat is which counters best suit the
need that you're working with?
Are you doing troubleshooting, and if so, what kind?
Are you doing performance tuning and optimization?
If so, what kind?
With all of those counters to choose from,
you're going to need some guidance on the highest
impact Performance Monitor counters.
Check the exercise files because I give you some heads-up links on that.
Your goal is that you want to choose enough counters to give you a good,
well-rounded baseline picture of what's happening on the target system,
but you don't want to bring back too much data because then
the signal to noise ratio gets too big,
and you just don't have --- it's too difficult really to look for trends and to spot problems.