In this demonstration we'll spend some time with more of the UWP
apps than desktop apps because I trust you're pretty good with
traditional desktop applications.
In the Start menu, as I mentioned before,
any application that you install, like I've installed Auslogics Disk Defrag,
this is a traditional desktop app.
Now apps can be written to work under standard user
permission or administrative permission.
If you see User Account Control pop-up,
then this is indicative that Disk Defrag needs a higher level
of privilege than other applications do,
but it's still not the robust security that you get
with the Universal Windows Apps.
Now again, we'll open up Start,
and then if we scroll down we can see some of the UWP apps.
The one that I tend to go to just habitually is weather.
So let me right-click this, pin it to Start,
and then click it to open the application,
and it doesn't open full screen like the old Windows 8 apps run.
Looks like I've got, yet again, some internet problems,
so I'm going to pause the video to fix that problem.
Okay, we're back in business, and so as I was saying,
you can maximize, minimize, and restore this.
It doesn't occupy the entire screen.
We have various controls that if you hover over them they're a tool tip.
All of this stuff is marked in the Universal Windows Platform
specification that Microsoft publishes,
and the Application Programming Interface or API.
As I said, from a security context,
these run in a much more secure sandboxed way.
They're much more self-contained than the traditional desktop applications are.
Then we close and come back to the start menu.
We right-click and resize this.
I'll make it large.
I'll right-click it again, and go to More,
and Turn Live Tile on to make this widget actually come alive.
So this is what I meant by the fact that the Universal Windows
Applications are actually more than just a static icon.
Normally an icon for an application doesn't do anything,
but with the advent of the iPhone and mobile devices where
the icons actually reflect real stuff,
like the clock icon on iPhone will actually display
the honest to goodness correct time.
If you go under Cortana or Start and type Start settings
we can go under System settings here, and Use Start full screen,
if we turn that to On let's take a look at the ramification there.
Well, we don't have much to see here,
but if we had more live tiles on the screen it would fill out the
screen much more like what we see in Windows 8.
1 and old Windows 8.
Let me come back to System settings, turn off Use Start full screen.
Now as far as controlling application behavior,
like we said before,
we can right-click an empty area of the taskbar and open up Task Manager,
and there there's Startup, and there's also Services.
Often times you can improve the security and performance of a system by
stopping services that are not necessary for your use case.
This is, again, a case where you want to do due diligence and research.
Just because a service looks unfamiliar to you does not mean that it is.
Like BITS, for instance, you might think,
well I don't want Background Intelligent Transfer Service running,
so I'm going to disable it.
Right-click, you can open up the Services console.
Unfortunately it didn't go right to BITS, but anyway, here it is.
If I open it up I could set it to be disabled.
Well,
you're going to have problems with Windows Update because many of
these services are needed directly by Windows.
On the other hand,
as you install software sometimes they will put a
service in here that's set to auto-start,
and you may get away setting it to manual,
and only starting it when you need it,
or if it's something with much more potential blast radius,
so to speak, a service like Remote Registry for instance is fine in a business,
but on a stand-alone computer,
especially one that you take out to airports and cafes,
you don't want to even have the door available for
remote registry access on your system,
so you'd want to set that service to disabled.
Coming back to Startup, this gives us a list of auto-start programs,
as well as their startup impact, and if you right click you can disable,
you can go to the file location, which is pretty nice,
especially if you see a program listed that's unfamiliar to you.
It's nice, but like I said,
you want to go to sysinternals and download the tools.
Here's a nice site for you, live.
sysinternals.
com.
If you're not familiar with sysinternals,
these are all freeware system utilities designed and developed
originally by a guy name Mark Russinovich.
Mark is the CTO of Azure right now.
He's been with Microsoft for a while,
but before he was with Microsoft he and a guy named Bryce Cogswell developed
this whole suite of utilities that do very useful things.
Microsoft bought the tools from Mark and eventually hired him.
The one that we want to look at is AutoRuns,
and there's a 32 bit version and a 64 bit version.
I'm going to right-click Autorun64, Save target as,
and I'm going to bring it down to my desktop.
I want to start this as an administrator,
so I'm going to right click the icon and choose Run as administrator.
I will consent that I do want to run that as an administrator, and here we go.
You'll see a lot more as an administrator,
as opposed to opening the tool as a standard user.
AutoRuns shows you everything on the system that is set to
run either on a schedule or automatically,
every time the system starts, or in the case of Internet Explorer,
every time you start that app up.
Now notice that this is not Edge.
This is the Internet Explorer 11 browser that's included in
Windows 10 for backward compatibility.
I would suggest you go to the Logon page.
Now you might remember in Task Manager it only had
I think three elements listed.
Notice that we go much deeper in AutoRuns where we can see that my
Google Chrome browser has an auto-start entry,
Windows Media Player had one,
and sometimes it can be alarming when you look at the path,
and you see that it says file not found.
What could that mean?
Is it nefarious?
Not necessarily, but it's again, potentially worth looking into.
If you right-click there's a whole bunch of stuff you can do.
Do an online search, you can look at specific properties of the executable.
You can browse to its location.
You can check its virus total scores.
All things considered, this is a tool that you want to learn to master,
and my colleague at Pluralsight, Sami Laiho,
has a whole series of Pluralsight courses that dive into not only AutoRuns,
but many of the other key sysinternals utilities.
This is fantastic for malware identification,
as well as troubleshooting, performance tuning, and optimization.