For further learning in the Pluralsight library,
start by looking at Mike Halsey's course,
Providing Troubleshooting Support for Windows Users.
I like his course because he injects a lot of soft skills.
The ability to know technical troubleshooting in Windows is great,
but also the ability to put the people you're helping at ease.
They're likely afraid that they did something wrong and
their system is hopelessly broken, they may have lost files.
Soft skills, really,
will go so much farther in your career if you have good
interpersonal communication skills.
There's also Mike's course Troubleshooting Difficult Problems in Windows.
He gets into the deep waters pretty quickly,
it's very intense, but the course is really good for you,
because, again, regardless of what you're doing with Windows 10,
you've got to be at least somewhat interested in technical
stuff to be studying this course anyway.
This is going to be a good course for you to broaden and
deepen your troubleshooting skills.
You might want to look at troubleshooting courses,
just do a search at Pluralsight.
com,
because we have a lot of excellent training on developing a good system troubleshooting methodology.