In summary, what have we learned in this module.
Well first, it's becoming more difficult.
I was going to say impossible when I wrote this slide,
but now I don't want to be too blanket.
It's becoming increasingly difficult, let's just say it that way,
to avoid virtual digital assistance.
I would bet you my bank account that your phone that you carry has
a digital assistant of some kind built into it,
and it's nice that if you choose to adopt that trust model
that I said with Microsoft that you can help,
you can work with Cortana and really be much more efficient and
make it easier for you to learn new stuff.
Second,
Client Hyper-V gives you an excellent environment to test not only Windows 10,
but other Windows versions in a safe sandboxed environment.
Much of this course actually involves some demonstrations that if you're
not careful and not being conscious in what you're doing,
you could wind up maybe not hosing up your system totally,
but at least putting it in a non-desired state.
Thus, by using Client Hyper-V, installing a test instance of Windows 10,
check the exercise files, I'm pretty sure I mentioned this earlier,
but the Microsoft evaluation center allows you to download any of
their operating system software as a free fully featured trial and
work there because there you can do anything you want without fear
of losing any of your real work.
So that ends that module.
As I said at the end of the previous module,
this one here has been a book end of sorts.
We're going to look at the administrative applications in Windows 10 next.
Thanks for your attention. I'll see you then.