When you need sub‑millisecond response times or need to ease
the load off of databases and applications,
you can use Amazon Elasticache.
Elasticache works as an in‑memory datastore and cache and
can scale up to hold large datasets.
It sits between your requests and other back‑end sources
like your database or application server,
allowing faster in‑memory speed for retrieving values.
Elasticache is fully managed,
so the hardware provisioning, software patching, setup configuration, and
monitoring of your clusters is taken care of for you.
Elasticache is compatible with both Redis and Memcached.
Each engine offers some different features,
so depending on your requirements, you may choose one over the other.
Redis supports more advanced data types and operations such as lists,
sets, and sorting.
Redis also allows persistence and can run in multiple availability zones.
Memcached is better suited for object caching and is simple to implement and use. Memcached also scales out to hold much larger datasets.