Hi,
this is Craig Golightly, and welcome to Migrating and Deploying Databases.
If you're looking to migrate a database to the cloud,
there are several tools available to make your job easier.
We're going to cover some AWS‑provided options,
as well as how you can make use of native database migration tools.
Moving large amounts of data to the cloud can also
present logistical challenges,
especially when you're dealing with petabytes of data.
We'll discuss some solutions AWS has created to help you quickly and
securely transfer your data to the cloud. We'll also cover some planning
aspects to consider when performing a database migration. Building and
maintaining test environments for your databases is another task that can
present some logistical challenges.
We'll cover some strategies to automate your deployments,
as well as requirements that can put constraints on your test environment
design. When migrating from a source to a target database,
one basic approach could be make a backup of your source database,
restore that backup to your target database,
use replication to catch up on what happened on the source in between
taking the backup and loading the backup to the target,
then switch traffic over from the source to the target database.
While that sounds easy enough,
there can be significant challenges when trying to execute this in real life.
For example, taking a full backup can be taxing on your source database,
so you'll need to make sure that normal operations can
proceed at an acceptable level of performance.
Do you have enough disk space to store a full backup?
How long will it take to transfer the backup from
the source to the target database?
Will your migration require any downtime?
If so, can you fit that downtime into a planned maintenance window?
AWS provide some tools to help make migrating to the cloud easier.
Over 300,000 databases have been migrated using AWS Database
Migration Service. With AWS DMS, migration starts while the
original database stays live.
It takes care of replicating any changes that occur in the
source database during the migration process, so you don't
have to worry about missing anything,
and you can migrate with virtually no downtime.
It's also highly resilient and self‑healing,
So if there is an interruption,
it automatically restarts the process and continues migration from where it
stopped. You can view metrics to track the progress of your migration, and
you can also use AWS DMS for replication tasks across regions or to help
build databases in test environments.
AWS DMS supports most commercial and open‑source databases.
You can perform homogeneous migrations such as Oracle to Oracle,
as well as heterogeneous migrations between different database platforms
such as Oracle to Amazon Aurora. For heterogeneous migrations, you can
first make use of the AWS Schema Conversion Tool,
which will determine the complexity of the conversion and
perform much of the conversion automatically,
including psSQL and T‑SQL code.
If there are any code fragments that cannot be
automatically converted to the target language,
it'll flag those for review. For homogeneous migrations,
you can also make use of native schema export tools
available for your database engine.
You can use a VPN or set up a Direct Connect connection between your
data center and AWS to securely transfer your data.
However, if your database has tens or hundreds of petabytes of data,
transferring over traditional data connections just isn't practical.
For example,
it could take more than 20 years to transfer 100 petabytes of data over a
direct connect line with a 1 gigabit‑per‑second connection.
For these cases,
you may want to consider the Amazon Snow Family to securely
migrate data into or out of the AWS cloud.
AWS Snowmobile is a 45‑foot long ruggedized shipping container
that can transfer up to 100 petabytes of data.
It's delivered to your data center where you can then load your data, then
it's driven back to AWS where your data is imported into S3.
Snowmobile uses multiple layers of security and encryption for secure
transfer and full chain of custody of your data.
If you don't have quite that much data to transfer,
but still need a physical device,
you can use AWS Snowball. Snowball is about the size of a desktop
computer case and can transfer up to 80 terabytes of data.
You can also chain multiple snowball devices together for larger transfers.
Simply load it with data and contact the designated shipping carrier in
your country who will pick it up and take it to AWS.
Once your data is transferred to AWS, if you need to perform any extract,
transform, and load or ETL activities, you can use AWS Glue.
Glue is a serverless data preparation service.
You can use it to catalog multiple AWS datasets without moving the data.
This allows you to search and query the data using
multiple AWS database services.
It can also run ETL jobs as new data arrives and provides both visual and code‑based interfaces to make data preparation easy.