Hi.
This is Craig Golightly,
and welcome to Monitoring and Troubleshooting Databases. We're going to
cover some monitoring strategies for your database services,
including Amazon CloudWatch. We'll also discuss strategies
to deal with common database issues.
Finally,
we'll cover some options for database performance optimization and how your
options are going to vary based on your database type.
Amazon CloudWatch provides visibility into your cloud
resources and operations. You can collect and store logs, as
well as view built‑in and custom metrics.
CloudWatch has several features to enhance the data you collect,
including dashboards to visualize your metrics, alarms to trigger alerts and
actions based on certain conditions of your metrics, insights to run queries
across CloudWatch data and determine the health of applications, and events
to respond to operational changes.
While most AWS services integrate with CloudWatch for certain metrics and logs,
some database services have additional tools available
for monitoring and troubleshooting.
For example, if you're using RDS,
you can utilize RDS Performance Insights to analyze and tune your database
performance. For a given database instance, it shows load over time and the
top queries, users, and hosts that are generating that load. You can use the
interactive dashboard to change time ranges and drill into your data to
identify performance issues.
Redshift provides a similar dashboard that you can access from
your cluster menu in the AWS console and gain insights into CPU, RAM, storage used, connections, query runtime, and query load.