(upbeat music)
(keyboard keys clicking)
All right, we're going to take a break now
and look at search algorithms.
So what does a search algorithm do?
Well, a search algorithm will find a value
in a data structure
and so the search algorithms we'll look at will find a value
in an array.
Now you can use them to search linked lists
and other data structures but we'll look at arrays.
We're not gonna look at as many algorithms
as we did for sort because there is one search algorithm
that performs really, really well
and so we're going to look at the linear search algorithm
and then we're going to look at the binary search algorithm.
So let's jump right in.
I'll see you in the next video.