(upbeat music)
Okay so let's implement the quick sort algorithm
using the implementation we went through on the slides.
We're going to code two methods, one called quick sort
and one called partition.
So let's start with the quick sort method first.
So we'll say public static void, quick sort
and we're gonna pass the array we wanna sort,
the start index, and the end index.
And as we saw on the slides, the end index
will be one greater than the last valid index in the array.
So the first thing we're gonna do is check whether
end minus start is less than two.
Because if end minus start is less than two,
we're dealing with a one element array,
so we don't have to do anything, we just return.
If we're dealing with more than one element
than what we want to do is figure out where the pivot
will belong in the sorted array.
In other words, what will be the index of the pivot
when the array is sorted, what is it's sorted position
and so we're gonna say int pivot index equals
and we're gonna partition this array.
And we'll write the partition method in a minute.
So what this will return is the position
of the element in the sorted array,
so it's corrected sorted position.
So in the slides we had 20 as the pivot
and eventually the pivot ended up in position four
and so what this would return is four,
so it's basically returning the position
at the pivot and at that position everything to the left
of the pivot will be smaller than the pivot
and everything to the right will be larger.
And after that, we want to do the same thing
with the left array and the right array.
So all the elements that are smaller than the pivot
and all the elements that are larger than the pivot.
So we're gonna call quick sort,
with start as the start index and the pivot index
as the end and then we're gonna call a quick sort
with the same input away, pivot index plus one
as the start index and end as the end index.
So what we're saying here is in this step,
we have put the pivot into it's correct sorted position
and we have repositioned the elements such as everything
to the left of the pivot is smaller than the pivot
and everything to the right of the pivot is greater
than the pivot and then we wanna do the quick sort the left
sub-array and we wanna quick sort the right sub-array.
And once we've done that, the entire array will be sorted.
Now of course these are recursive calls,
so what actually happens is when we call this quick sort
it will deal with the left sub-array
but then it's going to make a recursive call
to then deal with the left array of that sub-array,
et cetera until it's completely handled,
the left sub-array and then and only then,
will we start working on the right sub-array.
So keep in mind what happens with recursion
and if you need to go back and review the video
on recursive methods.
Okay so let's write the partition method.
So we'll say public static int, this is going to return
the correct position of the pivot
in the sorted array, partition, we're gonna accept
an input array, a start index and an end index.
So I'm gonna put a note here that says this is using
the first element as the pivot, as we saw in the slides.
So we're gonna start out by saying that the pivot
is equal to input start.
Now of course this is the start element in the array
or sub-array that we're passing.
So it's not necessarily index zero.
Later on in our example, we have put 20 here
as the first pivot index and so the right sub-array
would be starting at index five and so that one
would actually be the pivot when we call
partition with this right sub-array.
And then as we did in the slides,
we're gonna set I to start and we're gonna set J to end.
And now we're going to do the traversal,
so remember that I is going to traverse from left to right
and J is going to be traversing from right to left
and we want to stop when I and J cross each other.
So we're gonna while I less than J
because if I is greater than J, it means they have crossed.
Okay, so what we're going to do in here
is we're first going to use J to look for elements
that are less than the pivot.
So we're gonna say while I is less than J
because we wanna stop if I and J cross,
so if J crosses I we wanna stop
and while input minus minus J
is greater than equal to the pivot,
that's all we wanna do.
This is any empty loop, I'm gonna put a note here
to say note empty loop body.
And so we're not doing anything within the body of the loop
so we're just basically using the loop to keep decrementing
J until we either find an element that's less
than the pivot or J crosses I.
So what do we do when we fall out of this loop then?
Well we've gotta make sure we didn't
fall out of it because J crossed I.
So if J hasn't crossed I, if I is still less than J,
then we want to move the element at J
into position I because basically we have found
the first element that is less than the pivot
and so we wanna move that towards the front of the array.
And so we're gonna say input I equals input J.
And if you're confused about this, go back and review
the last video with the slides,
but essentially we're saying we've used J
to find the first element that is less than the pivot
and we wanna put all the elements that are less
than the pivot to the left of the pivot
and so we're going to move that element at J,
the one that we found that's smaller than the pivot,
we're gonna move it to position I
and on the first iteration I is actually at zero.
So if you'll remember the slides, the first pivot value
was 20 and we're moving backwards and we found minus 22
and we moved minus 22 into position zero.
Okay so now we wanna alternate and go to I.
We wanna traverse the array from left to right,
looking for the first element that's greater than the pivot.
So we're gonna say while I is less than J,
'cause once again we wanna stop if I crosses J
and input plus plus I is less than or equal to the pivot
and once again this is an empty loop
and I'll put a note there 'cause it's easy to miss.
And so this time we're gonna be moving from left to right
and we're looking for a value that's greater than the pivot
because when we find a value that's greater than the pivot
we wanna move it to the right of the pivot.
And so once again, we're gonna check when we drop out
of the loop whether we've dropped out because I
has crossed J and if that's not the case
then we've dropped out because we found an element
that's greater than the pivot
and so we wanna move it to position J.
Input J equals input I and it's okay to do that,
we're not gonna be losing any data
because in the previous loop, we've already moved
what was at input J and so at this point,
it's safe to assign to input I and in the next iteration
of this loop it's safe to overwrite input I
because we've already moved it.
So it's the fact that we're alternating
between I and J and which direction we're traversing in
that lets us do these types of assignments
without losing any data.
Now one important thing to note here,
we're using the prefix decrement
and the prefix increment operator so what this means
is when we execute this statement, we'll decrement J
and then we'll use the result as the index
and recall that end will always be one greater
than the last index of the array
and so if we didn't decrement we'd get an index outta bounds
exception, if we pass the entire array in
or we'd actually be indexing one element past the end
of the sub-array that we wanna work with.
And it's the same thing here, when we first come in,
I is start, I is the pivot, we wanna start with the first
element after the pivot and so we're always gonna be,
we wanna increment first and then use the index.
And then on subsequent iterations, we'll want to increment
first because we've already handled what's at I.
So whenever we enter this loop, we've already handled
the element at I and so we wanna increment
and then use the index, we don't wanna use I
or we're gonna be looking at something we've already handled
and that's not gonna work.
Okay, so when we drop out of this loop,
I has crossed J and that means that we've finished moving
elements that are smaller than the pivot to the left
sub-array and elements that are larger
than the pivot to the right sub-array
and so at this point, the value of J will be the index
where we want to insert the pivot
and so that's all we have left to do
and so we'll say input J, J not I, equals the pivot
and then we have to return J because remember what we're
returning from this method is the index where we inserted
the pivot because that's how we're dividing the array
and we need that to then call quick sort for the left array
and quick sort for the right array.
And you'll notice that when we called quick sort
for the left array, we passed the pivot index
because as I said, the end index is always going to be
one greater than the last valid index in the partition
in the array, the sub-array that we wanna partition next
and so we really, for the left sub-array,
we'll go from index start to pivot index minus one.
And so we pass pivot index 'cause we wanna pass one greater
than the last index we're interested in.
And that's it, that's our quick sort algorithm.
Keep in mind that this is recursive so when we come in here
we call quick sort on the first left sub-array,
this is not gonna return until the first left sub-array,
this sub-array here, remember the first pivot element is 20
and we end up inserting it here, so the first left sub-array
that we're gonna call this with is this sub-array here.
This quick sort call is not gonna return
until this entire thing has been quick sorted
and so by the time this call returns,
all of this will be sorted and the same thing goes
for this quick sort, by the time it returns,
this whole sub-array will have been sorted.
So let's run this to make sure it actually works.
And of course I did not, doesn't work because
I haven't actually called quick sort.
So we're getting here the unsorted array.
So we're gonna call quick sort, we're gonna pass
our int array, we're gonna pass zero for start
and we're gonna pass, should be int array,
zero for start and int array dot length as the end index.
So let's give this another shot.
And now we have our sorted array.
It always helps when you actually call the sort method.
So minus 22, minus 15, one, seven, 20, 35, and 55.
So if you're having trouble understanding what's
going on here, go back to the slides
and the key point to remember is that we're alternating
between I and J, we're alternating between traversing
from right to left, looking for smaller elements
and going from left to right looking for larger elements
and because we're alternating, we can do all of this
in place without losing any data.
And if you're having trouble understanding the recursive
nature of it, go back and review the video on recursion.
So that's it for quick sort, that's the second divide
and conquer algorithm we've see,
but we're not out of sort algorithms yet.
So I'll see you in the next video.