(lively music)
(keyboard clacking)
In this video, we're going to take a look
at the Radix Sort and this is another sort algorithm
that makes assumptions about the data it's sorting
and in this case, the assumptions that it makes
is that the data has the same radix and width.
Now, what do I mean by that?
The radix is the number of unique digits
or values in the case of characters
that a numbering system or an alphabet has.
For example, the radix for the decimal system is 10
because there are 10 possible digits
in the decimal system.
Zero to nine.
For binary numbers, the radix is two
because we use two digits in the binary system, zero and one
and for the English alphabet, the radix is 26
because there are 26 letters in the alphabet.
So, that's what we mean by radix.
Now, by width I mean the number of digits
or letters, for example, the number 1235
has a width of four.
The string hello has a width of five.
The number 10 has a width of two.
So, 1,235 or 1235 has four digits,
so it has a width of four,
the string hello has five letters, so it has a width of five
and the number 10 has two digits
and so, it has a width of two.
And so, the radix sort assumes
that all the values have the same radix and the same width
and so, that means that we can use the radix sort
to sort integers and strings.
The decimal point isn't a digit
and so, floating point numbers can't be sorted
using radix sort.
So, how does it work?
Well, we sort based on each individual digit
or letter position and you'll see what I mean
when we go through the algorithm on the slides.
So, we start at the rightmost position
and we sort based on that position,
the digit or the letter at that position
and then we move to the rightmost minus one digit
or letter and we sort based on that
and we keep doing that
until we've done all of the digits or letters
in the values.
Now, the important point here
and this is key, this is an absolute important point,
is we have to use a stable sort algorithm
at each stage, so when we sort the values based
on the rightmost position,
we have to use a stable sort algorithm.
And then when we sort the values based
on the rightmost minus one position,
we have to use a stable sort algorithm
and once again, you'll understand why
when we take a look at going through the algorithm.
So, let's do that now.
So, we have a different array here now
at the top of the screen.
It's got six integers in it
and you'll notice that they're all decimal numbers
and they're all of width four.
They all have four digits
and so, we can sort this array using the radix sot.
First we're going to sort this array
based on the one's position
and so, let's take a look at the first value,
4725, the number five is in the one's position
and for the second value,
4586, the number six is in the one's position
and so, what we're doing here
is we're sorting by the digit
that has the least weight
because the one's position has the least weight
in a decimal number
and so, once we've done that,
the bottom array will be the result.
1330 will come first
because it has zero in the one's position,
that'll be followed by 8792
because there's a two in the one's position.
Then we have 1594,
4725, 4586 and 5729
and if you look at their one's position
or the rightmost digit,
you'll see that the values have been sorted
according to what's in that position
and now we move to the second position
from the right or the second least significant digit
and we sort based on that.
And so, at the top is the array we just had
on the other slide
and now we're gonna sort based
on the second to last rightmost position.
So, for 1330 that will be three,
for 8792 it will be nine,
for 1594 it will be nine,
for 4725 it will be two et cetera
and so, down at the bottom,
we've now sorted based on that digit,
so we have 4725 'cause it has a two,
5729 which also have a two,
1330 'cause it has a three,
4586 because it has an eight
and then 8792 and 1594 both have nines.
Now, as I mentioned,
critically important, this is a stable sort
and so, you'll notice
that we have a couple of pairs of duplicates here,
4725 and 5729
both have twos in their rightmost digit minus one position
and you'll notice at the top
that 4725 came before 5729
and in the bottom, 4725 still comes before 5729
and that is critical
and that's because we have to use the stable sort algorithm
and the same thing goes for 8792
and 1594, they both have nines
in the second to right position
and in the top right, 8792
came before 1594
and it still does
and so, that's critical.
We have to use a stable sort algorithm.
So, now we're gonna sort based on the hundreds position.
So, we sorted here based on the tens position,
and now we're gonna sort based on the hundreds position
and so, when we do that,
1330 comes first 'cause it's got three in that position,
followed by 4586,
1594, 4725, 5729
and 8792 and once again,
we have to use a stable sort algorithm
and so, you'll notice here
that we have two fives in the hundreds position
and 4586 still comes before 1594
as it did in the top array
and we have three values with seven in the hundreds position
and the relative positions of those three values
have been preserved.
So, 4725 still comes before 5729
and that still comes before 8792
and then the final step is we sort based
on the thousands position.
And so, 1330 has a one, 1594 has a one,
4586 and 4725 both have fours
and then there's 5729 and 8792
and we have sorted our array.
Now once again, this had to be a stable sort
and so, 1330 had to come before 1594,
4586 had to come before 4725.
Now maybe you can understand at this point
why the sort has to be stable.
If it wasn't stable, this radix sort wouldn't work
because at each stage, for example,
in this stage, if 1594 could cross 1330,
we wouldn't get the correct sorted order.
If 4725 could end up before 4586,
we would not get the correct sorted order
and it's kind of interesting
because when we first start doing a sort,
it just means, you start to wonder,
how is this ever going to work?
Because when we sort on the one's position,
we got, we go back there,
we got a certain array
but then when we sorted on the 10 position,
all the elements are changing positions again
and you're wondering how is this ever going to end up
in sorted order?
But the key is we're sorting
from the least significant digit,
the one with the least weight
when it comes to the value
to the most significant digit
and at every phase, it's a stable sort.
And so, because of that,
as we move from right to left,
as we go from the least significant digit
to the most significant digit,
you'll see that a sorted order is starting to emerge
and then on the final step,
because it's a stable sort,
all of the previous sorts that we've done still count,
they don't get undone at each stage,
it kind of looks like we're not sorting at each stage
but we are, the data is gradually becoming more
and more sorted
and the fact that we're using a stable sort algorithm means
that on that final sort,
when we're sorting on the most significant digit,
values that have the same most significant digit
will not switch relative positions
and so, the values that have a higher hundreds,
a higher digit in the hundreds will remain
after values that have a lower digit in the hundreds
and the same will go when we do the sort with the tens.
When we do the sort based on the tens,
values that have a duplicate tens value,
well, the value with the higher digit in the one's position
will come after the value with the lower digit
in the one's position
and so, you can see
that because we're using a stable sort algorithm
at each phase
and we're going from the least significant digit
to the most significant digit,
or letter depending on what we're sorting,
the results of previous sorting phases are preserved
and that's why radix sort works.
So, counting sort is often used
as the sort algorithm for radix sort.
In the last video I said
that the implementation I showed you was not stable,
so when we implement radix sort,
you'll have a chance to see the stable version
of counting sort.
Now, once again, because radix sort makes assumptions
about the data, we can achieve linear time.
Even so, this often runs slower
than O to the nlog of n
because of the overhead involved
and by overhead,
I mean that you have to isolate each individual digit
or letter at each phase
and so, there's overhead involved
just to figure out what value you're supposed to be sorting
at each phase and because of that,
even though it can achieve linear time,
it often runs a little bit slower than that.
Now whether or not it's in place
will depend on which sort algorithm you use
because as we've seen, some sort algorithms are in place
and some aren't.
So, radix sort can be in place
or it might not be place.
It's gonna depend on what sort algorithm you choose
to do the sorting at each phase.
It's a stable algorithm as we've seen
because the sort algorithm we use at each phase
has to be stable, radix sort turns out to be stable
and in fact, that's key to making it work
is that the sorts in earlier phases
aren't being undone as we sort based
on the more significant positions.
So, that's it for the theory.
Let's move onto implementation.
I'll see you in the next video.