(upbeat electronic melody)
(typing)
What is a tree?
Well, a tree is a hierarchical data structure.
So here is a visual representation of a tree
and we're gonna go over some basic terminology
in this video.
Every circle in this tree, is called a node
and so, this is a node, this is a node, this is a node.
Nodes can have children and so we'll see here that the node
with the value 15 has three children, 22, 4 and 17.
Now, each node can have one and only one parent
and so 22's parent is 15, 18's parent is 4,
you'll notice that no nodes have two incoming arrows,
we can't have 4 pointing to 9, and 22 pointing to 9
because that would mean that 9
has more than one parent and that's not allowed.
So in a tree, every node has one and only one parent.
Now, there's a special node in every tree called the root
and the root of this tree is the node that has value 15.
The root node does not have a parent and every tree
can have one and only one root node.
And so in this tree, as I said, the root node is 15.
And this is how trees are usually visually represented.
Now you might be looking at this and wondering
about the practical applications.
Well, trees are ideal when things can contain other things
or when things can descend from other things.
So for example here 22 is a descendant of 15, right,
because 15 is a parent of 22.
19 descends from 22 because 22 is the parent of 19.
So when you have a situation where items can contain
other items or there's a hierarchical relationship
such that items can descend from other items,
trees are a good data structure to use.
And a couple of examples would be the Java class hierarchy,
that's a tree because a class
can extend only one other class,
meaning that each class can have only one parent.
But you can have multiple classes extending the same class,
so a class can have many children,
'cause when it comes to trees,
you can have as many children as you want.
You can only have one parent but you can
have as many children as you want
so if you wanted the node 4
to have 50 children, that's allowed.
And getting back to the Java class hierarchy,
it only has on root and can you guess what the root is?
Well, it's the Object class, right,
because every class in the JDK
ultimately descends from Object.
Now another application of trees would be the file system
on your hard drive.
Every folder can have children and those children
would be folders or files.
A folder or a file can only belong to one folder,
so it can only have one parent
and if you're wondering about the root
well the file system could have multiple roots
in the sense that it can have multiple drives
but each drive is a tree and so the root of the C drive
would be the C directory, the topmost directory.
So as I just said, in a tree
every item in the tree is a node,
the node at the top of the tree is the root,
and every tree has one and only one root,
every non-root node has one and only one parent.
A leaf node has no children,
so if we go back up to our tree here,
19, 9, 18, 3, 11 and 0 are all leaf nodes
because they don't have any children.
And if you have a tree with only one node in it,
it's called a singleton tree and of course in that case,
the only node would be the root
because every tree has to have a root.
And so, here's our root node.
In this tree, 0 is a leaf, it has no children.
The same is true of 11, 14, 18, 7, 25 and 19,
and each of these arrows is called an edge.
And so, there's an edge going from 15 to 22,
there's an edge going from 15 to 4,
and the arrow always points from the parent to the child.
Now a few more terms, every tree
consists of one or more subtrees
and for subtrees you can start at any given node,
so let's say we start at node 17.
Node 17's subtree consists of 17, 11 and 0.
So a subtree is if you start at any given node,
it's the node and all of its descendants.
And so, if we wanted to start at node 4,
the subtree for node 4 would be this entire thing,
it would be 4, 9, 18, and 3, 25, 7, and 14
because if you follow the edges from 4
you can get to all of those nodes.
And so a subtree consist of a node,
you can start at any node in the tree,
and all of its descendants,
and the descendants are all the nodes
you can get to by following the edges.
Downward, 'cause we're talking about descendants.
And so, if we start at 4 we can't get to 22
'cause we have to go up to our parent,
and when it comes to subtrees,
when you start at a given node
you're only interested in all of the descendants.
And so, to figure out a subtree of a node,
you start at the node and you include
all of the nodes that you can get to through the edges.
For 17, that would be 17, 11, and 0.
And of course for 15, it would be the entire tree.
Now the subtree for 9, if we wanna start there
is 9, 25, and 7, so it's the subtree here.
A path is the sequence of nodes required to go
from one node to another, for example,
the path between nodes 4 and 25 are 4, 9, and 25.
So the path from the root to node 14 is 15, 4, 3, and 14.
Now, one important characteristic of trees
is that you can't have cyclic paths.
And so, we can't have a path that crosses
a node more than once.
And so, we couldn't have a path
that would go 15, 4, 9, 18, 4, and off somewhere else.
So you're not allowed to have cycles in your paths,
that's a defining characteristic of a tree.
A root path is the path going in the other direction,
it's how to get from a node to the root.
So the root path for 3 would be 3, 4, and 15.
Now, the depth of a node is the number of edges
from the node to the root.
And so, the root will always have a depth of zero
because there are no edges on the path
from the root to the root, obviously.
If we look at 14, that would have a depth of three
because as we just said the path is 14, 3, 4, and 15,
and so there are three edges in the path from 14 to the root
and so 14 has a depth of three.
18 would have a depth of two,
so the depth for 18 would be two,
we have to go through two edges to get to 18.
The height of a node is the number of edges
on the longest path from the node to a leaf.
And so if we look at 4 here,
we'll see that the height of 4 is two.
It can get to 18 in one edge, that's not the longest path
because it takes two edges to get to 25, and 7, and 14.
And so, the height of 4 is two
because the number of edges on the longest path
from the node to a leaf is two.
So the height of 4 is two.
Now, leaf nodes will have a height of zero, right,
because if the height of a node is the number of edges
on the longest path from the node to a leaf,
well, leaf nodes we're already there.
The number of edges on the path
to get from a leaf node to a leaf node is zero.
And so, leaf nodes always have a height of zero.
Now, the height of a tree is the height of its root node.
In this tree, the longest path
from the root to a leaf is three
because it's these leaves down here that take three edges
and so the height of the root is three,
and that means the height of the tree is three
because in this tree the largest height
will be the longest path from the root to a leaf node.
So once again, the depth of a node is the number of edges
from the node to the tree's root node,
so when we're figuring out depth,
we start at the node and we work up to the root
and we say how many edges does it take me
to get up to the root, that's the depth.
But when we're talking about height,
we're going the other way.
We're looking at what's the longest path from the node,
and it doesn't have to be the root,
down to a leaf.
And so, when we're talking about depth
we calculate that by moving up the tree
and counting the number of edges to the root.
And when we're talking about height we start at the node,
so if we're trying to figure out the height for node 22
we start there and say what's the longest path to a leaf,
well there's only one leaf, and we figured that out
by counting the number of edges, is one.
And so, 22 has a height of one.
Now you'll notice, its sibling 4, has a height of two.
And so, nodes that are on the same level
don't necessarily have the same height.
And the height of the root is the height of the entire tree
because obviously, the longest path from the root
to a leaf node is going to be the height of the root,
and that's going to be the height of the tree.
Now, a level of a tree contains
all the nodes that are at the same depth.
So, the root is at level zero
'cause it has a depth of zero.
22, 4, and 17, are at level one
because they have a depth of one.
All the nodes along here are at level two,
so 19, 9, 18, 3, 11, and 0, are all at level two,
'cause they have a depth of two,
we have to travel along two edges to get to them.
And these three leaf nodes at the bottom
are at at a depth of three
because we have to travel along three edges to get to them
and so they're at level three.
So the root's at level zero,
its immediate children are at level one,
the grandchildren of the root are at level two,
and the great-grandchildren of the root are at level three.
So, we've talked about how the children are descendants,
of course, nodes also have ancestors,
so one of the ancestors of 4,
well the only ancestor of 4 is 15.
We say that a node is an ancestor of another node
if it's in the node's path, which makes sense.
So 3 has two ancestors, 4 and 15
because we have to pass through 15 and 4 to get to 3.
So a node can have multiple ancestors and basically,
its ancestors are all the nodes on the path
from the root to that node.
And so now that we've looked at general trees,
we're gonna move on and look at binary search trees.
And so, let's move on to the next video.
I'll see you there.