(upbeat music)
So I'm here at the Javadoc for java.util.stack
and our first thought is gonna be oh well
that's really cool, Java has, JDK has a stack class.
We'll just go ahead and use it,
but there's a but, if we read the documentation
we'll see that the Java team recommends
that we not use this class, it says right here,
a more complete and consistent set of LIFO stack operations
is provided by the Deque interface,
remember because stack is an abstract data type,
the behaviour is most likely going to be dictated
by an interface and so it's saying,
the documentation is saying that instead of using
the stack class we should use a class
that implements the Deque interface.
In the que section we'll learn more about what this Deque
interface is, but we can see in the docks
that there is an array Deque class.
Right here they're suggesting that one of the classes
we could use that implements the Deque class
is an array Deque and if you think that means it's a
Deque backed by an array, you get a gold star.
So if we wanted an array implementation
of a stack, this is one of the classes
we could consider using.
That's one option.
But we've already seen another class
that implements the Deque interface
and that's the LinkedList class.
The LinkedList class in the JDK implements
the Deque interface and implementing a stack
using a LinkedList is a great choice
because we don't have to worry about resizing the stack
when we're pushing items.
So what this means is if you want a stack
in your Java application, you can go ahead
and just use the LinkedList class.
One potential problem with this is the class
allows us to do more than push, pop, and peek items.
I mean we looked at the LinkedList class
and you can add items, you can remove items,
you can get the index of items
and you know you can randomly access stuff in the list
so you could in your code, in your use
of the LinkedList class just limit yourself
to calling the push, pop, and peek methods.
Let's go to the LinkedList class.
I think, let me see.
Well actually let's go to the Deque class
and from there we can get to the LinkedList class.
So I'll go to the Deque class and then we can get
to the LinkedList class from here 'cause it implements it.
So you'll see that in the methods, because this class
implements the Deque and if you look at the Deque briefly,
we'll see that it has peek, pop, and push.
So because of that, the LinkedList class has
pop, peek, and push and if we wanted this LinkedList
to behave like a stack, we should really
only be calling those three methods.
So you have two choices, you could just enforce that
yourself in your code or you could create a class
that has this LinkedList as a field.
So essentially we create a stack class
and it would have a field for the LinkedList
and so the only methods you would expose from that class
would be push, pop, and peek
and that's what we're gonna go through here.
So instead of using our own implementation of a LinkedList
and using that to back a stack, we're going to use
the JDK LinkedList class and we're going to write
an implementation that uses this class to back a stack.
And so let's go over to the IDE.
So here we are back in IntelliJ.
I created a new project and I put the code into
package academy.learnprogramming.linkedstack.
I've copied over some code into the main method.
I've copied the code for creating the usual employees
and I copied over the stack calls we made
in the last video just to give me a head start
and then as usual I've added the employee class
and it's exactly the same as it usually is.
So let me add a class now called LinkedStack.
And in here all we need is one field.
So I'm gonna say private LinkedList
and this LinkedList is going to hold employee instances
and that's gonna be our stack.
And so this is the JDK class, java.util.LinkedList
and this is what's gonna back our stack
and so in the constructor for LinkedStack,
we're gonna create our LinkedList.
So we'll say stack equals new LinkedList.
And to avoid having to change the language level,
I'll just specify that we want employee.
Now one thing to remember is this LinkedList
is actually a doubly LinkedList
and for a stack you don't need a doubly LinkedList
because you're always working with the item
that's at the front of the list.
But normally memory won't be an issue
and so you can just go ahead and use this LinkedList class.
If memory was an issue, then you would have to
write your own singly LinkedList class
or use an array instead.
You could look at the other classes that implement
the Deque interface and see if one of those
would be more appropriate.
Okay, so let's add our push, pop, and peek methods.
So we'll say public void push
and we're gonna push an employee.
And all we're gonna do here is defer to the LinkedList.
So stack.push employee, because we know our LinkedList
class, the LinkedList class in the JDK
implements the Deque interface, so it has push, pop,
and peek methods and so we're just gonna call them.
And then we'll say public employee pop,
we'll just say return stack.pop.
And finally we'll have public employee peek
and we'll return stack.peek and that's it.
That's our stack implementation.
Now we could implement an is empty method,
like we had in our other stack.
So let's do that.
Public boolean is empty and we just return stack.isEmpty.
And we're done.
Now we went through this exercise because we want users
of our stack that's backed by a LinkedList
to only be able to call push, pop, and peek.
If we used the LinkedList directly as a stack,
then somebody might come along, perhaps a new developer
on the team or something like that who is not familiar
with what we're doing and start calling other methods
like add and index of and stuff like that
and we don't want that to happen
so we want a class that behaves like a stack
so you can only work with the last item that was added.
You can only call push, pop, and peek
and so that's why we went through this exercise.
So when we push an item we're adding it
to the head of the list.
When we pop an item we're removing it from
the head of the list and when we peek at the item
we're basically just returning the head of the list
but we're not removing it from the LinkedList.
So last thing I'm gonna do is add a print stack method.
So I'll add that in here, so I'll say public void
print stack and I'm gonna use a list iterator.
So I'll use iterator equals and it wants to know
which class, which list iterator I want.
Ask me again, oh there we go.
So I want java.util and we're gonna call stack.listIterator
and then we'll just say while iterator.hasNext
system.out.println iterator.next.
Now this iterator traverses the list from head to tail
and in a LinkedList implementation of a stack
the top item is always at the head.
So just like when we implemented a stack backed by an array,
when we print out the stack the top item will be printed
first followed by the item that's below the top, et cetera.
So it'll be printing from the top down.
So now let's go back to our main method.
And I'll first remove the print stack.
We haven't created our stack yet.
So I'll say LinkedStack stack equals new LinkedStack
and let's push all our employees.
So we'll say stack.push Jane Jones, stack.push John Doe,
stack.push Mary Smith, stack.push Mike Wilson,
and stack.push Bill End.
And then we'll print our stack.
So let's run.
And we'll see that Bill is at the top of the stack,
followed by Mike, Mary, Jane, and John.
So let's peek at the stack and see what we get
and then we'll print our stack again
to show that we didn't remove anything.
I'll comment this print stack out.
So let's run.
And we'll see Bill twice because this print line here
is from peeking at the stack and then when we print
the stack out, Bill is still on the stack.
He wasn't removed.
And then finally we'll pop the item off at the top of
the stack and then we'll peek at the top item.
So let's run and we'll see that we popped Bill
and the next employee or the employee
that's on the top of the stack after Bill is popped is Mike.
And that's exactly what we saw when we implemented
a stack using an array and once again,
with a LinkedList implementation the time complexity
for push, pop, and peek is oh of one.
It's constant time because we're always working
with the item at the head of the list
and so the steps involved don't depend
on the number of items on the list.
Now if we try to do something like stack.add
with an employee, you'll see that we can't do that
because that's not really a stack operation
or stack.get a certain employee.
So even though the LinkedList class
has those methods, if we come in here,
and I'll just, in here I'll just stay stack.add.
You'll see that there's the add method
or stack.get you'll see there's a get method
where we can specify position in the list,
even though the LinkedList class has those methods,
we don't want people to be able to call those methods
because then our stack wouldn't be behaving like a stack.
And so that's why if we wanted a stack and we wanted
all the developers on a team to only use the class
as a stack so that they can only push items,
pop items, and peek at items, then we just wrap
the LinkedList with another class and we only expose
push, pop, and peek methods
and you know you can expose stuff like is empty,
that's not allowing them to do something to the stack
that they're not supposed to do.
And that's it for stacks.
They're not all that complex a data structure,
especially once you understand LinkedLists and arrays,
because all a stack does is limit the operations
you can do on whatever data structure
is being used to implement the stack.
I'll see you in the next video.