(upbeat music)
(typing)
Alright so let's talk about deleting
items from a heap.
Now just as with a binary search tree,
when we delete an item, we need to find a replacement
value for it, but this is a lot easier
than when we delete a node with two children
from a binary search tree, because we always use
the same replacement node
and that node is the rightmost value in the heap
and so it's the rightmost leaf in the tree
and the reason we do that is because we want the tree
to remain complete.
Remember that one requirement for a heap is that
it be a complete tree
and so if we're gonna delete a node from somewhere
in a tree and we want to replace that node,
if we take the rightmost leaf from the last level
of the tree and we take that node and we delete it
and we use it as the replacement node,
after we've done that, the tree will still be complete
and so that's why we do it that way.
Now of course, after we've replaced the deleted value
with the new value, we may not have a heap anymore
because a heap property might be violated
and so after we've done that, we need to heapify the heap.
Now when we were doing insert, I said that for delete
we look down the heap,
but I forgot that there are times when we also
have to look up the heap.
It's more common to look down a heap
because when you're taking the very last leaf
and moving it to the left in the array,
it's more likely that you're gonna end up
putting it somewhere where it turns out to be
less than its children,
but it is quite possible that you're gonna put it somewhere
and it's actually greater than its parent
and in that case, we need to fix the heap
upwards not downwards.
So the way we decide which direction to look
is after we moved the rightmost leaf to its new position
and that position would be the position of the node
we deleted, we have to look up the heap
and fix up the heap if that value
is greater than its parent.
If it's less than its parent, then we compare against
its children and if it's less than one of its children,
then we have to look down the heap.
If we're going to look up the heap,
we do the exact same thing we did for insert.
We're gonna swap the replacement value with its parent
until it's in its correct position.
If we're gonna look down the heap,
so we need to fix down the heap,
we're gonna swap the replacement value with the larger
of its two children and the reason we do that
is if we swap it with the larger of its two children,
so the larger child will become the parent
of the replacement value and its old sibling,
then we know for sure at that point,
that that larger child is larger than both
the replacement value and its old sibling
and so the heap property is preserved.
If we were to swap the replacement value
with the smaller value of its two children,
then obviously when that smaller value became the new root,
it would be smaller than the replacement value
and its old sibling so we'd still have a problem.
And then in both cases, whether we're going up or down,
we rinse and repeat until the replacement value
is in its correct position and as I said
we'll only need to fix the heap upwards or downwards,
we never have to go in both directions.
So here's our heap.
I just wanted to remind you of what it
looks like right now.
And so let's say we decided we wanted to delete 75
and so the replacement value is going to be 67.
It's always gonna be the rightmost leaf at the bottom level.
Because if we took the replacement value
from somewhere else, we'd no longer have a complete tree.
I mean if we said well we're gonna replace it with 40
and so we're gonna knock 40 off and put 40 here,
we'd no longer have a complete tree.
And so if we knock off the rightmost leaf
and use that to replace the deleted value,
then after we've done that, the tree is still complete.
If we had a child here, it would be this child
that would replace 75
and then our tree would still be complete
and so when we're dealing with heaps
and we're doing a deletion,
the replacement value is always the rightmost leaf
and that ensures that after we've deleted
the node with the replacement value,
we still have a complete tree.
And so what we're gonna do is move 67 into 75
and of course it'll be deleted from here.
And so now we have this,
but this is no longer a heap.
And so we're gonna have to heapify this heap.
We're going to compare 67 against its parent,
it's less than the parent so we know that
we don't have to fix the heap above
and so we're gonna compare 67 against its two children
and we're gonna swap it with the largest
of its two children and so we're gonna swap it with 68.
We want to swap it with the largest
because if we swap it with 55, and put 55 up here,
then we still don't have a heap,
because 55 is smaller than its two children.
So if the replacement value is less than one or both
of its children, we want to swap it with the largest child
because after that's done, we know that that largest
child will be larger than the replacement value
and larger than the other sibling
because we took the largest value of the two
and so after we've done the swapping,
this is what we'll have and we have a heap again.
So that's how we do a deletion in a heap.
So now let's delete 40.
Let's do another one and once again,
the replacement value will be 67.
It's always the same replacement value,
it's always the rightmost leaf, at the last level,
and so we'll move 67 into 40
and now we're gonna compare the replacement value
against its parent.
Well it's greater than its parent and so this time,
we need to look up the heap
and we're gonna do it the exact same way
we did it with insert.
We compare the replacement value against its parent.
If it's greater than its parent, we swap it with its parent,
and then we rinse and repeat.
And so we're gonna compare the replacement value
against its parent and it's less than the parent
and so we're done.
Now we'd also rinse and repeat with the child swappings
so here if we go back up, when we replaced 75 with 67
and then we did the swap,
if there were children here, we'd then compare
67 against these children and if necessary we'd swap
and we'd keep going until 67 was in its appropriate place.
And so that's it, that's all there is to deleting
a node from a heap.
It's a little easier than binary search trees
because the replacement value is always the same
and because we usually are backing a heap with an array
basically the replacement value is always
at position size minus one.
If size is the next available position in the array,
then the last index for the heap is index size minus one
and so we can just go straight to that location
and you'll see that in action in the next video.
I'll see you there.