Hi.
Before we go on and learn about U.S. development.
We have to make sure that we have necessary tools available in our Mac books in order to do that.
We are going to download something called X code from the Apple Developer Web site so that we can write
our codes inside of that software.
So you have to open a browser and go to this Web site developer that's Apple dot com.
So this is a fantastic Web site by Apple.
They let developers know the latest technologies latest developments latest available tools like X code
or other operating systems as well in this Web site.
And we can actually browse through this Web site to see the documentation how we can leverage the latest
technologies how we can use the latest news in our own apps.
But right now we're interested in this development tap.
And if you click on here you will see the latest technology is available for the developers.
OK.
And you can browse this in your own spare time.
But right now you have to go to this download tab.
So if you click on this download tab it will bring you to a Web site in which you can download the necessary
tools.
But first you have to give your Apple I.D. in order to reach those tools.
And this is a basic Apple I.D. So if you're using an iPhone or an iPad or a Macbook I I believe you
have one Apple I.D. If you don't have one you can create here to create yours and create your Apple
I.D. for free and you have to give your password and you have to love this.
And then it will take you to this download section.
OK.
So if you don't have an Apple I.D. yet please create one and sign in.
So in here you will see an operating systems tabs an application tab.
So not only we have the ability to reach the applications but also we see these operating systems here
as well.
So if you click on the applications you will see the x codes and in the operating systems we have like
Mac US Catalina and others.
So in here we have two options one is beta and the other one is release release means it's open to public
now it means that we have completed the development phase and now the public is using it.
But generally they provide the beta version to developers much earlier than the public because developers
might need to adjust their apps to upcoming features upcoming technologies for example every September
ISIS launches a new version of the IRS.
Right.
Like all U.S. wildfire I 13 I years 14.
So they get we get these releases in September.
So around like June or July we have to download the beta version of The X code to see how to implement
the new technologies to our apps so that we will be ready when the release is there so that we can push
our new apps new version apps to the public.
So by the time I'm recording this X called eleven is in the beta.
So I'm going to download it from here.
If you see it in the release done it's going to be okay.
You will have to download it from the release tab then but I suggest you go for X Code eleven and beyond
X code 10 is the old news now because we have to be working with X Code eleven swift five and a U.S.
13 and upwards.
So I'm going to show you how to download this and how to is sold us.
And if you click on this download it will just start the download process and it's a little bit big.
So it's kind of eight or seven point five gigabytes right now.
So it's going to take time.
So feel free to pause the video and come back after your download is finished.
Of course I downloaded it before.
In order not to make you wait but feel free to pause the video.
OK so after it's done what you have to do you have to come to your Downloads folder and you will see
something like this.
So let me move this to trash so you will either see the zip or it will direct you to the App Store or
items connect.
So I'm gonna show you both ways.
Don't worry if you get the zip rather than App Store or ife ice I TOS then you just have to double click
on the zip and it will bring this exe code beta out in your folder.
OK all you have to do then just take this EXCO beta and move it into your applications folder here.
So let me open my applications folder in another finder.
OK so let me go to your applications and as you can see my ex code beta is already there so I'm not
going to move it again but only add to this.
Just move it then place it over there and then after you can just double click on this and I'll put
it to use the x code beta.
We're going to see that in the next lecture.
Don't worry as well and you can find it in your Launchpad as well.
And I believe mine should be here.
Yep it's here.
I can open the ExCo beta from my Launchpad as well.
So what happens if you click on that download button and instead of starting downloading it brings you
at the App Store page like this then all you have to do is just click on this get and then install the
app.
It will ask you for your password and this is the password for your macbook.
Or you can just do a fingerprint scan as Vo.
It will start installing the X code for you after it completes.
You can find the X code in your applications folder or your Launchpad one more time so that's it.
That's all you had to do to install the X code but there are some questions there may be some questions
in your mind regarding the operating systems as you can see I'm using Mac OS Catalina in my computer
right now.
Do you have to install Mac OS Catalina.
Not necessarily.
You can use Mac OS mahogany or Catalina with X code eleven.
Of course if you have a newer version you're more than welcome to use it as well but it has to be at
least Mac OS more Harvey.
OK so if you have an old mac book like you can not upgrade to MacOS Catalina or Mac or Somali then you
will have to find an X code 10 version and use it instead of X code eleven.
But the latest one is X code eleven and there might be some changes in the codes like in the 94 95 percent
of the time.
There are still the same.
But I suggest you upgrade to the latest version and if you encounter any problem using one of the old
Mac books with X code 10.
Just post your questions in the Korean a section and I will be more than happy to help you because I
know all the older versions as well.
Don't worry about that.
And at the near of the end of this course we're going to learn something called SWIFT UI and it actually
requires MacOS Catalina.
So if you're waiting for to upgrade to make us Catalina I suggest you do that with X code eleven so
that you will have a complete set up to start with.
So that's it.
If you're done by now let's stop here and within the next lecture we are going to discuss how to create
our first X code projects.