Hi.
Welcome to The X code within this lecture regarding to see the overview of the X codes.
For example we're going to see what does this left brain do or what does this right pain do.
And if you don't see the space over here the left little windows over here you can just go to this button
and if you click on this you will see it will hide or show the left pain and the right pain.
Okay.
So if you don't see any of these windows over here you can always come and show and hide over this bottom.
So these are generally the helper pays in the left pane we see the files and folders on in the right
pane we journalists see these options and attributes I'm going to show you.
What are they.
Don't worry.
And in here we have the files and folders.
So let's start with the first one.
If you click on the top you will see this general settings page.
Okay.
This is where we do the general settings of our app like display data.
So whatever I write here it will appear when I actually upload my app to the App Store and then somebody
downloads it it will see this name on their iPhone.
Okay so this will be literally the display name for me.
And in here we can see the bundle identifier that we have chosen.
Let me create this app of course we can choose a new bundle identifier if you want from here.
So we have something like a U.S. church in order here and on the right hand side you can see iPad or
iPhone.
So if if I want to disable this app to be working on my iPad I can just uncheck and check again.
And the important thing to do is right now just go here to signing and capabilities in which you will
see this checkbox.
So make sure this is checked.
Okay.
Automatically manage signing.
So this will sign you in using your Apple I.D. so you can say you enable automatic and in here if you
don't see anything you can just say edit count.
And over here it will pop up a window asking you to just enter your Apple I.D. And if you don't have
an apple either you can create just click on this create a I thing and then you can create a free Apple
I.D. for yourself.
Later on we're going to see how to create a developer account as well.
Right now I have my I.D. signed in so I can just select one and it will just automatically manage the
signing for me and this will associate my Apple I.D. with my project so that X code and the apple will
know this project actually belongs to me.
So do this for general settings right now where are you going to come back here later on.
Then we need something for these projects settings.
OK.
And in here the most important file is the view controller.
That's first.
So this is very right.
Our code.
OK.
This is where we're going to code our app.
This is where we're going to do our stuff.
This is where we're going to do everything.
And in here we see some semantically generated swift files like app delegates.
So we have a lot of codes here.
And right now you don't understand any of this.
We're going to come back to here later on.
Don't worry about it.
So this is another automatically generated file called Scene delegate in which we actually define the
UI window the window that we're seeing in our app and where you going to come back here later on just
for right now know that we're not going to do much in the app delegate or seen delegate.
We're just going to write our codes inside of our view controller dot swift and in here you will see
something called me in that storyboard.
If you click on this file it will open an empty iPhone screen for you.
So in here we do the design of our app user interface of our apps.
So we drag in images we drag in texts we create some user interface in this file.
OK.
And D file this file is actually connected with the view controller dot Swift.
It means that we get to design our app in this mean storyboard you can zoom in out like this in here
and we get to write our codes in the view controller.
That swift.
And actually it's very easy to work with main story boards and we're going to see that later on.
And here we have some folder called a SATs and we play some images we play some icons in this folder.
Okay we have some launch screen that Storyboard So this is a welcome screen for you.
If you put something over here it will be shown in the Vulcan section of your app like a logo of your
icon off your app.
OK.
And in here we have an info that peerless this file.
We're going to change some of these options over here.
This is for general settings.
Again we're going to use all of those files during government court.
So don't worry about it right now know that we're going to use you controller.
That's Swift.
And we're going to use main that storyboard and lots.
OK.
Because why.
Because this is very rewrite our code.
So let me go over these buttons over here you will see something called Ed options adjust just Ed options
at just EDS.
So this is the main page.
This is the main section in which we write our code but we can change the screen.
So if you click on Ed only nothing will change.
But if you click on Ed and canvas if we were building for a swift UI it will open a preview layout for
you.
Right now we don't have to worry for that because in the regular programming way without the swift UI
we don't need.
We won't have any canvas instead of cameras.
We have main storyboard in this project.
OK.
And in here we have some other options as well like editor assistant if you click on this it will open
another editor for you.
So you get to write code in the both screens right now and we're going to see how to leverage this to
Ed. think in our apps because you can't choose any file over here so you can compare the files or you
can work with view controller that swift on the one hand side and on the other hand you can work with
the storyboard and we're going to do all of those things so we can closes Ed right now and we can continue
actually seeing the other options over here.
So if you go to your main that storyboard and if you click on this you can just say editor and assistant
so you can work with the main storyboard on the one side and we have controller on the other side.
So you get to design your app here and you get to write your code over here and we will connect our
viewers connect our objects like images to the code using this technique later on.
So again in here we see an ad editor below bottom.
So this does exactly the same thing.
You add another editor over here so that's it for the main section actually.
So on the left hand side we see the folders files on the middle side.
We see the coding section or design section on the right hand side.
We generally see the properties OK of the chosen object our Chosen View.
So for example in the main that storyboard if you choose something from this section.
OK.
Like a weave controller or a view and we will have some images or texts or we're hearing later on.
You can see the properties of that V you can see the properties of that object in this page.
For example we see something called history over here and this is related to get that.
We have talked about so does like save point checkpoint control in the first place you will see where
it is located on your computer.
So in here we have help section.
So this is the official documentation of Apple.
We can read on that always and in here we see the identity Inspector code just connecting we use with
each other we're going to see what this does later on.
So in here we see these attributes Inspector it's really gives you the options to choose the like if
you're working with a taxi you can check change the forms and the size of the text color of the tags
and everything.
And for the fifth one we have this V over we're here in which we can choose the place and the size of
the related object.
And on the last one we have something called Connections Inspector K we going to connect some of the
views with the code and we can break them or change them if we want to later on.
And this doesn't make any sense to you right now because you don't know anything yet about U.S. programming
or swift but I'm just trying to explain the options the bodies the veil of this X scope to right now.
Okay.
In here you will see a button called library if you click on this you can see these objects you can
see the views that you can take and drag and drop on your view controller in the main that storyboard
just for an example you can choose any of this and tried to drag and drop on your iPhone screen for
example is a button you can't click on those and you can write that code the inside of a button and
this is a label.
This is just a tax you can write whatever you want inside of your labels.
So for right now for example just take this label and drag it on your screen and as you can see we can
place the tax anywhere we want.
And right now if you click on these attributes Inspector we can change the color of this label.
We can change the font size of the labor.
We can do whatever we want.
So this is actually very easy you can change the alignment you can make it black you can make it bigger
you can make it smaller whatever you want.
And this is actually fun.
And this is very easy to create user interfaces.
And again if you double click on this you can change the size or you can change the actual text or here
like we can write helo Swift.
So this is cool right.
This is very easy to work on so we can create some stunning user interfaces using this mean that storyboard.
If you go to hear X code preferences you can access the settings of the X code we can change the settings
of X code using display over here.
Okay.
If you come to general or let me closes down line go to weave controllers so you can see it better because
I'm going to change the font size of X code and you will see how to do that.
So let me go to X code preferences one more time if I come to general I will see the general settings
of the X code.
It's actually why still leave those as it is.
And in the accounts tab you can see your own applied.
Because you have already connected to your app lighting designing and capabilities section.
So I'm going to just skip these behaviors and navigation and I'm going to go for fonts and colors because
you can start with the basics and the most verbal be you will start with the basic one.
And this is too small for me.
So I'm going to go for presentation light or dark so since I'm recording this video I'm not going to
go for presentation large.
OK.
I'm going to go for presentation because the presentation large will be too big for me.
If you like darker things you can go for dark.
I'm not going to do that since I'm recording this.
If I wasn't recording I would have definitely gone for the dark.
OK so presentation light is the choice for me you can choose your own from here and you can just go
over these other settings as well.
But if we need something from here in one of our projects I will definitely show you have to do that
later on.
But right now I'm going to leave all of these settings as it is.
So let's stop here and continue building our first app within the next lecture.