Hi within this lecture we are going to write our first SWIFT code.
So this is a big thing for us right.
So far we have connected our views to button clicks function over here and we have our image view right
below our view controller.
So when you see this curly braces it means the coding block.
OK so we have a coding block in the class and we have a coding block inside of this button clicked.
So we write our codes inside of these blocks.
So right now this button clicked created coding block for us and we're going to write what will happen
then.
And button is clicked inside of this function and here you see something called V did load.
This is automatically generated for us as you can see.
And this is what will happen when I open the app first.
So this is the first time a real controller is loaded.
So you five want something to happen then user opens their app I write it here but I don't want something
to happen.
When we first opened the app I want something to happen.
When I first click the button.
Right.
So I'm going to write my code under this coding block rather than did loads.
We're going to go into the details of we did load later on for right now.
Come over here to button clicked and we're going to call the image to you that we have defined as you
can see Image view refers to the image view that has been defined by us.
If you say Image view dot you can see the properties you can see the methods and attributes of the image.
What do I mean by attributes.
For example when we were doing something in the main that storyboard V can change we changed actually
the attributes from the attributes pane.
Right now I can reach all of these attributes and even more from here from the code.
Now if I say Image view dot I can see the ad too is like image in here Nancy can see it gives us a description.
So this is the image displayed in the Image view.
So if I choose this property I can just change this.
OK.
Inside of the coat.
And again this is going to change the image view that image.
Van I right.
So let me show you what else.
So this will ask us to create an you eye image.
So this is kind of an object type.
OK we're going to need a UI image type object in order to change this.
So I'm going to type UI image and open parentheses so you don't understand by the UI image right now
because you don't know what the classes and you will understand this code later on very clearly.
But for right now let me write the code and you will see what I mean.
If you open parentheses you will see some different options here.
I'm going to go for names because I'm going to create my image from a name I own already have my Metallica
to image over here.
If I say Metallica to here in the quotation marks OK so open a quotation and this is double quotation
marks not a single quotation so double quotation marks if I say Metallica to it will find the Metallica
to imaging my project it will convert it to be an image and it will display this image in my Image view.
So that's what it stands for Image view is the object that I have created.
So let me run in this simulator by the way.
So while it compiles I will explain the code one more time Image view is the object that I have defined
over here.
That image saying that change the image attribute.
And if I click on change as you can see the image actually changes to you I image named Metallica too.
So if I clicked on the change again it won't change my march time because it's already Metallica to
image and you may think at this point how do I make an app that if I click on this change it will change
the image to Metallica one if I could that it will change the Metallica too.
And we're going to do that later on.
Don't worry about that.
We are going to see how we can achieve this result.
But for right now you don't know anything about swift yet.
So we have to learn the basics first.
This is just to get you comfortable with X code and congratulations on your first app.
By the way you have just written an app in which you can change the favorite band image of yours.
So let's step here and we're going to continue with the next one.