High within those like Chip re going to see different kinds of Ray.
So far we have been talking give us some types right.
We have talked about strengths for example.
So let me take note over here so that you can follow it better when you finish your apt finish your
section.
OK so this is a string section and this is a string.
When you put a quotation mark between valleys it makes them a string.
He makes them a text.
Okay.
So this is not anything fancy.
This is just a text.
We call texts strings.
So let me delete all of this and I'm going to make this into a string section.
So if I say user name dot it means that I'm going to reach the methods and the attributes the properties
of the string.
Use your name.
So what do I mean by method or purpose your attributes.
We didn't learn any of these terms.
It basically means options that we can do with the user name.
Ok so using name is a string.
And then you hit dot.
You can get some options regarding two String objects.
So right now I can do whatever I want to do with my user name.
For example in here you will see something called a patent.
If you click one of this a patent and if you add a character between quotation marks of course like
oh OK if you hit the play button or shift enter then you will see that this will add something.
This will add the old letter to James.
And if you look over here you will see that James is now James so because we have a pen that and 0 to
James.
So that's another feature of variables actually you can reach their methods you can reach their options
or attributes and you can do whatever you want to do with that.
For example you can see a lower cased option in here.
We have J is capitalized in our string right.
If I choose user name that lower cased it will make J lower case as well.
So here you go we have a small James so I can do the same thing with upper case of course.
So go down below you will see the upper case if you double click on this you will see on the right hand
side.
After of course hitting the play by them you will see James so upper case letters.
So that's the idea of variables working with variables.
And that's the beauty of working with strings.
So we took one string like James and we appended something we made them lower case upper case then everything.
And of course we can do much more with the strings and I'm not going to go into every metals every attribute
every aspect of the strings in this lecture because we're going to learn a lot while we are on the route
to the ends.
We're going to work with strings and other variables in all projects that we're going to have.
Anyway later on I'm going to go for numbers.
OK so in teachers doubles and slots and doubles and floods are actually numbers with decimals while
integers are whole numbers and they're completely different from each other.
As long as the technicality of this 50 is considered.
So if I do something like this it will think that user age is an the.
Okay.
This is an integer does a hold no it doesn't have any decimals.
And this is a double because this has some decimals.
And as you can see we cannot interact with each other we cannot multiply it in the integer with a double.
Of course there are ways to overcome that problem and we will see them later on.
Don't worry.
For example let me create a number like for.
OK.
And this will be again my number.
Now I can see.
I can just say that user age divided by my number and what will it give me.
It gives me twelve and twelve multiplied by four actually close to 48 not 50 right.
But since these are integers again the result will be an integer as well.
So I cannot see the decimal.
And this might give me something wrong like this.
So this is not very correct.
Right.
This is this has to be twelve point five not twelve but since I am doing this with integers I'm getting
this resolved as expected.
So what can I do.
How can I just calculate this in the right way right.
So let me do it with doubles for example let me say that user HD for double OK and I'm going to set
this to fifty point 0 and I'm going to set this to 4.0.
Now there doubles altogether and not if I just do something like this.
User age D divided by my number D.
So let's see what will be our number results.
So let me click on the play here and on the right hand side we're going to see twelve point five.
So this is what I want to write.
So if I want the exact results like this then I'm going to go for doubles decibels instead of whole
numbers and there is actually a method to convert an integer into a double or a doubling to integer
and actually there is a method to convert everything to everything as long as it makes sense.
How are we going to see that later on.
Now let me tell you about something called a boolean.
So this is one of the most basic things in programming.
So this is either true or false.
For example if I create my boolean variable I can set it to false.
As you can see this say that this is a bull boolean OK and this only has the value of false or true.
So I cannot do.
I can't just go and say My boolean is five anymore.
OK.
Because this is a boolean but I can say my boolean is true.
And why do I need this.
This is too basic.
Maybe I'm doing gay gay.
Maybe I'm just controlling something like if my character is alive or dead so I can just do my character
is alive and I can just go and say my character is that and I can do something like If controls we're
going to learn what they are.
Something like if my character is still alive do this or if my character is that do that.
So these are actually a basis for logical expressions.
OK.
And it's going to be much more clearer to you once we use those variables in real examples.
But for right now just try to understand what they do a stand alone values.
We're going to see how to use them in real apps.
OK.
So far we have been learning a lot and we have learned about the teachers levels and maybe you realize
that when I say let the user age is 50 the Swift is actually understanding that this is an integer because
I have initialized this to be an integer.
Right so what if I want to change this type.
If I say something like My number is not for anymore but it's rather James will it work.
Actually it's not going to work.
So let me change these two were for example.
OK so this is a Vrabel rather than a constant.
And let me run this one more time so it will be stated as were so I can come over here I can just say
where my number is three pointer All right.
And this will work.
But what if I say my number is Kirk rather than 3.0.
And as you can see it says that you cannot is signed as value of type String because this has the type
of double.
So it means that once you assign it Type 2 available it just takes.
So in some of the programming languages this is a lot like in Python but since fifth this is not allowed.
Once you define the variable you shouldn't try to change the type of the variable anymore.
So let me say it doesn't stop here within the next lecture I'm going to try and deep dive into this
type taenia a little bit more.