Hi within this lecture we're going to learn about a Neve loop called for loop.
Again we will use this for loop in order to do some operation repetitively until a condition breaks.
So let me rename this to for a loop and re going to start writing in here.
So for loop basically works perfectly that array.
So you're going to see a lot of examples where we use for loop with arrays and in fact I'm going to
tell you with an array example so that it will be on your hats for loops go perfectly and synchronized
with arrays.
So let me create an array named my fruit array and I'm going to named as banana apple.
Maybe we can add one more like orange.
Okay.
So we have an array with three elements in.
So let's suppose that I have to print out these three elements.
So how do we do that.
I believe right now you know the answer right.
We have seen this.
So let me comment out.
Just prints that we have been doing so far so that the logs will be clear.
OK.
When we print something and let me run this in order to just delete everything from here.
So right now I can easily say Bring me the first element.
Do you know want to do this right.
My fruits are a zero and I can just call print my fruit there a zero and then I can copy and paste this
line and just say my foods are a one two right and this will bring me banana apple and orange in the
log.
So that was easy.
So what would happen if I had that thousand fruits in my fruit tree.
Then I will be copying and pasting these four thousand times and it won't make sense to do such work.
So we don't do it this way.
We use a for loop in order to have every element do something in our race.
So you start with four keyword.
OK and you choose and the variable name so I'm going to call this fruit but it doesn't matter you can
call it distinct.
Anything you want.
I'm going to explain what it does later on right now you have to add one key word in.
OK.
So this in keyword after just in keyword you have to say in what in your array.
So choose your array and open curly braces and will create a coding block for you.
So what does this do.
Let me explain.
So we're doing this inside of our my fruit tree and this loop will take these elements one by one and
then sign it to be a fruit.
So in the first loop in the first of the fruit will be banana in the second loop.
It will be Apple and the third loop it will be orange.
So if I print this fruit see what will happen.
We got the exact same results over here so let me explain one more time what happened here.
So we started with iterating through these elements so to banana.
And they signed it to we fruit.
So we printed out banana and then it went to Apple and then it went to orange.
And this continues as long as there is an element inside of an array.
The condition here is that there is an element if there is not the loop breaks.
So we went through this loop three times and then it broke.
So let me do another example let me create my numbers array and it will be some integer type.
Okay 10 20 30 40 50 60.
Can we do 40 for loop thing in an integer array.
Of course we can.
And it would make much more sense to you right now because we're going to do some mathematical operations
for each element inside of this area.
And as a practice I suggest you posed the video and try to come up with a for loop that takes these
numbers and divides them by five.
So you're going to have to divide each element inside of my numbers array with five.
I hope you got it by yourself but if you couldn't it doesn't matter I'm just going to show you how to
do that.
I'm going to create another for a loop and I will call this num or number K in my numbers.
I will open my curly braces.
Then I'm going to print out num divided by five.
OK so this will take num.
This will take every element and then assign it to be NUM and divided by five as you can see now we
can see the results.
As you can see by using for loops we can do things very efficiently.
When you use an array in your app I believe there should be or will be probably a time in which you
have to use for loop because they bring so much efficiency in system and this is not the only place
that we can use for loops in fact we can use for loops by their own as well.
We don't need some array but it would make much more sense to use this with arrays we generally use
them for array iterating through purposes.
Let me do another example I'm going to call this my number.
I'm going to say in 1 3 that's 5.
So what does this mean.
It means that create an array like object and it will come from.
It will start from 1 and it will end in 5.
So let me change this by the way because this is going to be a mess in here we named everything my number.
So let me call this my new integer and let me run this as you can see we got the result of 1 2 3 4 5
so we can do stuff like this we can just multiply it by five as well so we will get what five 10 15
20 25.
OK so as you can see we can do it like this without arrays but it doesn't make sense but we as it makes
might says it's great to use for loops with arrays and we're going to do that a lot.
Just don't forget that when you use an array if you do something with each element of it you must use
for loops and if you feel kind of lost right now it's perfectly normal you're just starting to learn
about a new language a new development the environment it's perfectly normal.
We gonna do a lot of examples.
We gonna build a lot of apps in which we will practice all of this information right now.
You're just learning learning learning and you're not practicing yet at all.
Don't worry Regan I'll take care of it.
So let's stop here and within the next lecture we're going to use some if controls.