Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to define the views into a real controller and then we're going to work
on them.
So let me add a new editor over here and you can click on this view controller to bring you controller
on the right hand side or remember you can choose the view controller that Swift from here as well.
So this is the same thing.
And in the left hand side we already see the main storyboard.
So all we have to do is click drag and drop the view.
So remember you have to press control in your keyboard and then drag and drop inside of the class.
But outside of this function so inside of this class I'm going to call this first number or first text
number.
OK I'm going to call his first text.
I believe this is the simplest thing that I can call.
So does his first text let me add some couple of more lines and I'm going to bring in the second text.
So does a second text OK so let's say connects and then I believe we have to bring our label and then
our buttons as well.
Remember if you made a mistake you can break the connections over here and delete everything a redefine
but if not just don't go with it.
So I'm going to need some more actions to connect to over here.
But first I'm going to get my result label.
So let me bring this over here on call this result label.
OK.
So we're done with the tax feels in labels.
Now let's go for actions.
So first will be my adding summation function.
So let me try to take this and bring this over here and this is going to be an action and let's call
this something like some action or some button clicked.
OK.
Let's call it some clicked on connect to our view controller.
So we have our first action.
Let's let's go for others so the second one will be deduction.
So I'm going to call this minus clicked.
I'm not being coexistence or here one is some clicked and the second one is minus clicked.
Maybe I could have called a deduction clicked or clicked or something but it doesn't matter.
So third one will be multiplied clicked.
OK.
And we are here for the last one.
So let's go for the last one and drag and drop to our view controller.
So I'm going to call this device clicked.
So let's call the lights clicked and on connect.
So here we go.
We have defined everything in our view controller.
So we are now ready to go and write our code.
So let me close this down and let me choose view controller and the run does on my simulator to actually
see how it looks like on a real phone or a real simulator screen.
OK.
It's wise to do that at this point because if you see any problem without going to all of the changes
in the coding section you may want to adjust the views a little bit and then continue writing your code.
So let me bring this simulator up and see if we can get the results over here and maybe we can just
take a look at the simulator settings as well because we have seen how to run the simulator but we haven't
seen the settings of the simulator here as well because they simulators have their own settings and
then you click on the simulator you can reach their menu.
OK.
So these are two different kind of softwares and they have their own menus so you can access them from
here.
So we see our app we click on first number for example and we can try to write something.
Yeah it will.
Right.
So everything seems to be in order.
And let me show you what I mean by settings if you go to debug section over here for example you can
see some location or if you go to hardware you can see the keyboard so maybe you can just say toggle
software keyboard and it will pop up the keyboards for you.
OK.
So you can type it from here as well.
Generally developers don't like to use it that way so they can't type it from their own keyboard.
But you can change the settings from this keyboard menu as well so you can do whatever you want with
the simulator you can change its location you can change its name.
So these is great tool and as you can see nothing happens as I click on these buttons because I haven't
written them yet so let's stop this and go to we've control that swift in which very we're going to
write our codes.
So we're going to start with some collect.
We're going to test the first function and if that works we're going to reapply the same techniques
to other functions as well.
So what do I want to do in the some clicks.
First I want to get the first number right and then I want to get the second number and I wanted to
display the results of their summation together in the result label.
So let me create first number variable.
So the first number will be first text.
Right.
So this will be the place.
This will be the view that our user is going to be writing.
They were inputs.
So I'm going to say first text dot text.
So if you just look at the attributes and methods over here you will see something like text.
So this is the text display by the text field.
So whatever has our user written in this text field we can get it by saying first text not texts.
So this is cool.
We already got what is written the inside of the first text but this is going to be in strings.
It's not going to be any teacher.
OK so we just got this first text out text and it doesn't make sense to add this string to another we
have to convert this to into an integer or a double in order to make the same thing with the second
text.
And they sum it up together so wrapped this around an integer and this will convert this text into any
integer.
What is the problem here.
So we have to force casters or rehab to provide a double question marquee night in order to make this
optional and provide the default value as you might remember.
So I'm going to force a wrap this first.
I will try and see if that works with force some wrapping is that fur.
Very good.
If that doesn't I will change it.
OK.
I'm going to do the same thing for a second number as well.
So I'm going to say let's second number is going to be the integer of second text text OK.
Second text that texts.
So that's OK.
And we're going to sum this two together and we still haven't done yet.
So we have to force our read this one more time I'm going to show you why I'm going to create a not
their value over here.
I'm going to call these results.
This is going to be the integer.
This is going to be first number plus second number.
Right.
So this is first number but we see this as integer optional.
So this isn't good.
So second number is integer optional as well.
And guess what.
We cannot do that because these binary operator of summation binary operator of something these two
numbers together cannot be applied to integer options.
So we have force I wrapped this why it is an optional because right now the first exclamation point
only stands for First tax that tax is going to be a taxed we are certain of that and if we put in not
there exclamation point over here it means that this is definitely going to be an integer.
So as you can see now this doesn't give me any error because the first number is not an integer optional
anymore.
So let me tell you one more time.
The first exclamation point means that this first Tax that tax is going to be definitely over there.
And we know that even if the user doesn't give the input we're going to get a string from their right
an empty string.
We're not going to get any real value I'm certain of that.
So this is over here we are certain that first tax is defined and it's not going to return us.
And Neil value it's going to it's at the verse it's going to return us an empty string and we're making
certain of that by putting this exclamation point in this stage.
And if we add the other one if we add the second one it means that we're certain that we're definitely
going to convert it into an integer.
Let's see if we delete this.
And if I come over here and if I write first number it will make this integer an optional integer.
Okay.
And this is okay for X code.
This is optional but if I put this this is going to be and not optional.
This is going to be a regular integer.
And by this time we're batting we're saying that this is definitely going to be a string and the string
is definitely going to be converted into integer and later on I can just take this result label and
I can say result label dot taxed is now results.
OK.
But I cannot say that because a result labeled that tax is expecting a string from me and I'm giving
an integer to it.
Right.
So I have to convert does into a string.
So I can just go like this string results.
So this will convert result into a string and I can definitely do that once I got the result.
I can definitely make an integer into a text right.
This is going to be okay anyway.
So let me run this and let's see if this works.
So we're going to get the first text.
So let me give this something like 40 or 4 5.
So let me give this 10.
Let me just some them together and here we go the 15.
So let me give minus 10 minus five.
So let me give you a big number and let me give a very big number.
So that's still working and it doesn't seem to be crashing but if I come over here and say Apple.
OK.
And if I want to sum them together as you can see it's crashed.
So this is definitely going to be this way because as you can see it says that it is unexpectedly found
nil while our opinion optional.
So we have said that this is definitely going to be over there but it's not there.
We could we couldn't even convert this to be an integer.
So since this integer is not there since this integer is and nil D application crashed and the good
thing is you know how to make this safe.
Right.
You know what to do in a situation like this of course you can go with double question marks or you
can go with default values but v do not want that.
We just want to have a safe number and have a safe calculation so that even if the user doesn't give
the right input we would not crash the app and we would get the result that we want.
We are going to do that in the next lecture.