Hi we didn't this lecture we're going to see how we can use some mathematical calculations in order
to make our views relative to the screen size so we gonna get the width and height of the current screen
that we are on.
So you know to that I'm going to create two variables.
First of which is that so we can get the vids by real dot frame.
So remember we had frame in our label and we had a frame.
We have a frame in our view as well.
And the frame of the view is actually the screen size of the phone.
So if I see a view that frame that size that width it gives me the current width right.
So I can do the same thing for the height as well.
So I'm I'm going to go with that frame that size that height.
So right now I can use those two values in order to create some good mathematical operations.
For example I can't say here with multiplied by 0 point five or 0 point 0 or just divided by 2.
Right.
So this will take the current that and divide it by two and then place it in the middle of my screen
so I can do the same thing in y axis as well I can just take the height okay and divide it by two or
just smile supplied by 0 point five and in fact let's multiply them by 0 point five so we can make kids
0 point 4 0 point forty five if we're not satisfied with the result later on and in fact I can do the
same thing for width and height as well right.
I can just say that make with like 80 percent of the current screen size and make height like 5 percent
of the current security size.
So let's do that let's see widths multiplied by 80.
And height I don't think we have to go with relative size over here we can just do like something like
50 because we just create and get taxed.
Maybe if I was working on an image I can go relative own height as well.
But right now I don't need that.
So let me run this and see how this works.
If I manage to put it in the middle of my screen as you can see.
So we're somewhere close so in the y axis we are somewhere in the middle right.
But in the x axis we're not even close.
We're not in the middle.
So we're skewed to the right.
So why does that happen.
So let me tell you this in a visual way.
Suppose that this is our screen and we are creating a text label over here right.
So our label looks like this.
So we're creating a width of 80 percent and height of 50.
So we're trying to place this into the middle like this but we're doing this instead of placing this
into middle.
We are seeing that start from X multiplied by 0 point 5.
So it's starting from the middle but it has its own width as well so it overflows to the right hand
side.
So we don't get what we want.
Instead we have to started from not here but something around here in order to find this point we have
to actually find the X middle looks like we THAT AND SUBTRACT THE HALF OF THIS.
IT'S OVER HERE FROM HERE.
OKAY.
SO IF I subtract half of this bit from the X point I can't find this starting point.
Right.
So I can do that for the y value as well.
And y valued doesn't seem to be causing problems because we made this vat y value like something like
50.
So it's a little so it doesn't cause any problems or it doesn't seem to be causing.
But it's actually something like this right now.
So we have to make sure that this stays here and here in order to be centered.
So let's go back to X core then do that.
Okay.
So I have to find a way to make sure that the half of this with is subtracted from the x axis.
So this would be in the middle of this x axis.
I'm going to do that for the y value as well so that it will be on the y axis half of the y axis.
Okay.
And this is a very good way so that you can find the middle screen middle point of the screen and you
can actually place this other views that you're going to have in your app are relative to this point
as well.
So let me try to subtract the vids or half off of it from here.
So I currently have 0 point 8.
So if I say something like this.
So let's see.
Can I get the exact weave that I want.
As you can see now I have this test label on the middle of the x axis so we can go and do that for the
Y as well.
So rather than saying kite multiplied by all point 5 I can come over here and deduct 50 or 285 actually
from here.
So 50 divided by 2 so you may understand what's going on when you go back and look your notes.
So here we go.
We managed to create a label and we managed to put it on the middle of the screen using mathematical
operations so we can do that for other views as well because we have our width and height variables
right now created.
We can use this technique in order to create some relative views and we can exactly find where it's
supposed to be located on the screen in different sizes.
So right now it doesn't matter if you're working on an iPhone AC or iPhone 6 these sizes will be relative
to the iPhone screen size.
So let's stop here and within the next lecture we're going to see how we can create a bottom.
Using this technique.