Hi.
We did this lecture.
We're going to see how we can work with more than one screen.
So far we have been working on a single screen apps.
We haven't added new we controllers.
We haven't added new screens to our apps.
And in this lecture we are going to see how to do that.
And this is basically going to show you how to create new wave controllers have to create new Swift
files and connect them together so you can add as many as you want.
Then you build an app.
OK.
I'm really going to need that information in the upcoming apps of course.
So choose single view app and I'm going to name this Segway app.
OK so you're going to see what the Segway is but it's basically connection between view controllers
in your swift projects.
OK so I'm not going to check in and swift UI or core data over here and I'm going to hit next and I'm
going to places under IRS complete and we're just going to go into the main storyboards in order to
add our four new controllers.
OK.
So let me go to main sorry Bert over here and we're going to see what we usually see you and me create
a project an empty iPhone screen.
So let me zoom out a little bit.
So this is our view controller right.
And this is our storyboard.
We can have as many as we want in here as many as screens we won and we can actually order the screens.
The first will be the second will be this charge will be this hey we're just creating the blueprints
of what we're building here.
So can I add a label over here and just make this a little bit bigger because I want to call this first
screen or first view controller.
Okay.
Because we're going to be working with more than one.
So I'm just going to differentiate you controllers using labels.
So this is first we have controller.
OK.
And let me make this central.
That's great.
So I'm just going to need another one to call second controller.
And how do we add a view controller over here how do we add a second screen.
It's fairly easy.
We're going to use library one more time and we're going to look for a real controller.
So you can just drag and drop this as a view.
So here you go.
This is view controller that we are looking for.
Just drag and drop here.
So here at this our second screen second view controller so I can just drag and drop whatever I want
to in the screen as all I can use library.
And as you can see in the left hand side I have a different view hierarchy right now.
So if I drag it label as you can see I can drag and drop it and I can just design it in a way that I
want exactly like I'm doing in the first view controller right.
So let me name the second wave controller and that's OK.
So here we go we have first V controller we have second we controller.
Now when I click on does this yellow dot over here in the controller it means that I'm choosing the
view controller itself.
And let me add and then another assistant editor over here and choose which controller from here.
And let me go to my first view controller and tried to drag and drop this view and as you can see I
can do it right.
I can call this my label and connect it.
So can I connect my second view controller label to here.
So let's try.
Let's see it's control and try to drop it as you can see we can not do that because this view or here.
This view controller is not connected to my view controller.
That's first.
So this controller is actually connected to this swift file.
OK.
And the second one is not connected.
So we can create a new Swift file and assign it to be connected to this view controller right.
And how do we do that.
If you click on this yellow dot one more time you can drag and drop anytime you want.
By the way to a line.
This view controllers and it doesn't mean anything but it's good to be aligning this.
So let me create the view controller file first so let me go to file new file and here I'm not going
to go for a third file.
I'm going to go for cocoa touch class so we haven't seen them yet.
This is the first time we're seeing it and I'm going to explain what is this.
So basically cocoa touch class is the way to go when you try to create something like we have controller
if you click or here you will see a lot of view type.
So you either you controller table view cell we're going to see what our deals later on but if I want
to create a view every related file you need to go with the cocoa touch class and you need to choose
what kind of you you're trying to create let's kind of class you are trying to create from here.
And after that of course you can choose whatever name you want just make sure that your subclass is
you either you controller OK and make sure Swift is chosen and for class name we already have a view
controller.
So I'm going to the second wave controller.
OK so that's it.
I'm going to create hit next to create this and it will just make sure that this target is selected
and it will just put this inside of my project folder.
As you can see now we have another controller file.
So we have another Swift file and we can use the swift file with our newly created weave controller
right.
So let me delete this comment lines and let me go to main story about because right now I've created
this but does X code.
No.
This is going to be connected to this file right now.
Of course not.
I have created this but I didn't connect it.
So far maybe I have created five Coco touch classes on file.
We have controllers it's called couldn't know which one is which.
So I need to manually connect.
So again this is you either you controller as you can see because we have chosen to be bound we create
a Coco touch class so let's connect it let's use these yellow dots one more time choose we have controller
OK.
It has to be view controller itself.
So make sure you touch this yellow button and here I'm going to go for this identity Inspector rather
than attributes Inspector.
Okay.
So if you go to this identity Inspector you will see something called class.
So if you click this dropdown Biden over here you will find the second view controller that we have
created.
So make sure this is selected and make sure when you click on it one more time you will see secondary
controller.
Now this view is connected to the real controller file that we have created.
So let me test.
Let me go to a second wave controller that swift and let me go to say can we even controller main storyboard
and drag and drop as you can see now I can actually create my label here so you can call it my label
one more time or you can call it whatever you want because these are completely different swift files.
You can just use the same names or you can just use completely different names.
It doesn't matter.
So that's how you create new use but we don't know yet how to connect these two together right.
How to reach second view from the first few.
That's what we're going to do within the next lecture.