Hi within this lecture we are going to learn about timer's so timer's are some structures that allow
us to do some operation repetitively within a given period of time and it arouses operation in the background
so you will see what I mean by telling background and you will see what I mean by telling within a given
period of time.
So in order to do that I'm going to create a single view app I'm going to call this timer project simply
and I'm going to hit next to create this project and save it on my OS folder.
After that let me make this project into a big full screen and then go to real controller dot Swift.
So here we are going to define our timer object and suppose that I want to have a countdown timer I
want to count from ten to zero.
Okay so let's suppose that I'm making a game in which we're competing against time.
So I will need a time label in which I will count from back to ten nine eight seven.
And it goes all the way to zero.
Okay.
In order to do that we are going to create a timer and you do it like this.
So with big timer with caps slice T and says that this is a timer that fires after a certain time interval
has elapsed.
Okay.
So if I say one second for example it will send a specified message to a target object for example to
we have controller.
Okay.
If you hit comment and click over here you can jump to definition or can go to quick help to see the
documentation file and if you click over here to open in documentation developer documentation it displays
a more detailed message to you.
So if you read over here you will see that it runs something called the run the loops and this maintains
strong references to your timer's.
So what does it mean.
And in the below you will see something called threading programming guide.
So it uses some treads.
So what is a threat.
So this kind of a collection that you run your operation on.
So if we are running everything on a single threat if we are doing something that can block the other
operations then the current thread will only work on one operation and we cannot do something else during
that period.
For example if I tried to use some conventional methods other than timer's in order to run a timer that
counts back from 10 to zero for that period of time I cannot do anything yet as I cannot interact with
the user interface I cannot click on anything.
I cannot see what's happening or my user interface in the background maybe it's running from 10 to zero
but I cannot see it.
So let me go and create this design first.
So let me have a label in which I will have a time variable which counts back from 10.
Okay so let me call this time okay.
And this will be counting down from ten.
But let me just for now make it like this and create a button and then make it a little bit bigger.
And this will start our timer.
I don't need anything else to complete this app so I'm going to leave it as it is.
And before we actually find these views into our revealed controller let me reset to suggested constraints
and then open an assistant editor in which I will call have controller that Swift.
And here I will take this time label and define as a variable over here.
I will call this time label.
OK.
And also I can just drag and drop this button and for actually I will say button clicked.
So that's it.
It's going to be very simple.
So let me say a print button clicked under this button clicked function so that's it.
Let me close this down.
We're done designing this app.
Let me go to have controller dot swerved.
I'm I'm going to first count down in a way that you will think that will work.
If you don't know about timer's so first of all let me run the simulator OK and you will see if I click
on this button I see button clicked.
Now if you didn't know about timer's maybe you would think that yeah I can do this in a for loop right.
I can create a for loop that will around 10 times.
So in this for loop if I can make a way to wait for one seconds then it means that I get to run this
loop for 10 times and it will wait one second between each loop.
So I will count back from 10 to 1 or 10 to zero.
And that's a good idea but it's not gonna work.
So let me do it for you.
So I'm going to say 4 and I'm going to come up with a variable name in here.
Like time and I will say in 1 3 that's 2 10.
So we have seen this before right.
So it's going to run this loop 10 times and we're not using time variable in this case but it doesn't
matter.
I'm just going to say time label is something.
OK like ten nine.
And in order to do that of course we we're going to have to come up with a variable because in this
variable I'm going to deduct one.
So if I create a counter variable here I can set it to be 0 or initially 10.
I can deduct one each time this loop runs so in the we did load.
I'm going to say counter is 10 and in the loop in the for loop I'm going to say counter is counter minus
one.
OK so this will deduct one from counter every time these for loop runs.
And it will display this counter in my time labels.
So this may be your initial target if you don't know about timers.
And then later on we're going to have to come up with a way to wait for one seconds.
Okay.
Because if I run these right now I will just see zero because it will count back from 10 to 1 even before
we see the view.
And it will just happen instantaneously.
We won't see it.
So in order to make this work maybe we can come up with sleeping for one seconds and actually there
is a way to do that.
Okay.
If I can come over here in my for loop I can say tread that sleep and again trade is where we run our
operations.
So if I slip for given time interval for example one second it will just block everything for one second
and then continue running this loop past.
But this won't work.
So we're going to wait here for 10 seconds before we see the view and then we're going to see the zero
as you can see because maybe you can think that because you run that in the we did load.
So we did load actually gets called before we see the view.
Maybe you have to run this in we will up here or we'll do that pier.
So let's try to do that for 100 seconds for example and this will make things even worse because we
will not be seeing this time label for like six under you know 1000 seconds so we're going to have to
wait for Ron thousand seconds in order to see the view right now.
So this doesn't work.
OK.
So the next thing is to try the view will appear or with the day pivoting so that we can be sure that
view actually did load and we see the view now it's time to do this operation and in order to do that
I'm going to call the function first in here if you say view you will see the view did they appear right.
So I'm going to take everything in here and cut with command X and then paste under my weave did appear
so I'm certain that this will get run after I see the view itself.
So let's do it this way.
So let's start.
And as you can see we see the time label right now but we cannot see the time and I cannot click on
the button so as I said before it blocks the entire operation so user can not interact with the user
interface.
Within that given period of time.
So for 10 seconds I couldn't do anything.
So we're going to go ahead and do this operation in another treads.
And in order to do that we're going to use timer so timer's traumatically manage that for us.
We can do this operation in the background.
So users can interact with the user interface.
The other operations will continue as it is but also we will do counter minus one in a given period
of time repetitively and it will be perfect.
It will be in a way that we want.
So let me see how timers are created.
So we have defined our timer but we have to make sure that it's fired as well.
So far right now I'm going to say time label that tax is actually time counter and then later on I'm
going to change my time or value in a way that I want.
What do I mean if you come over here with small timer object that you have created you can't say timer
that's scheduled timer.
So this will ask you for a couple of parameters and we want this one.
Okay.
So we want that not this one but this one timing terrible and target and selector user info and repeats.
So we have a lot of parameters here.
Let me explain one by one.
So timing terrible is the really interval that we want this operation to be carried on.
So I want every second.
Okay.
And the target will be south.
One more time because that's where we're going to write this selector function.
So selector function will be called each second every second lowercase or let me write it down.
Object to see func timer function.
And whatever I write here will be executed for every seconds.
OK.
So this will be timer function or you can just write.
We've controller timer function user info.
We don't want to send any user info so I'm going to say nil and does this repeat.
Yes this repeats and we can call it whenever we want.
We can stop it.
We can restart it and this repeats.
So that's it.
We actually finished our timer initialization so under timer function while I want to happen is to just
go over here I say time label that tax is again time and the reverse slash counter.
OK.
And then I want to say counter is counter minus one.
So you can say it this way counter minus equals one.
And then later on do I want to do anything.
Yes I want to check to see if counter is zero and if it's zero I want to stop this timer from going
on right.
So I can say timely will that tax is now time zero or times over.
I can come over here I can say timer dot invalidate in order to stop this timer from going on.
So that's good.
Yeah we're checking to see if timer has reached zero and we're invalidating our timer.
So let's start this and let's see if this works.
As you can see it counts down and we're seeing this and we we can actually click on that button as well.
So it's not blocking the user interface.
It's doing its job in the background just like we want.
So that's how you work with timers and you can do any operation with timers not only create countdown
timers you can do whatever you want inside of this function if you wanted to repetitively for a given
period of time.
So that's it.
We're going to stop here and within the next section we're going to write our first game.