Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to implement counting down functionality into our game.
And you can imagine that we are going to use timers for that.
K So you now know how to use timer's right.
We can just create the timer and we can just create a time counter like counter variable and we can
make sure that we display this in our counter time label.
So here we have our time label.
It can just start with 10 or 30.
You can choose it whatever you want to choose.
And then we going to create another timer actually within the next lectures to estimate the Kennedys
as well.
So whatever you decide for the number you may want to refresh it at does mean that storyboard as well.
But it doesn't matter.
I'm going to do that on the.
We've added loads so it will be on there even before user sees it.
So let's go.
Let's do that.
I believe you can do that on your own by the way you may want to post a video and try this on your own.
If you haven't completed this assignment yet so this will be our variables and this will be our view
so I'm taking some notes.
Zach good practice.
Right.
So this will be our images and we're going to have a lot of coding here.
That's why I'm doing that.
So after you open your notes open your code you will know what you have been up to.
So let me create timer over here so we can reach that timer from everywhere.
Right.
So this is going to be our timer.
Of course we're going to redefined is actually change the value to scheduled timer in the way of the
load.
And we will need the counter variable as well so that we can subtract one from this counter every seconds
so we did that before.
You know how this goes.
So let me go to we did locked in here.
First of all I have to make sure that this timer or this counter will be displayed in the time label.
OK.
And then we can actually create our timer with scheduled timer.
So this is where we will be doing the timer stuff so time Labour or counter I'm going to go for 10 in
order not to wait too much between tests.
OK.
So you can adjust this number later on.
I'm going to make sure that time label that text is the counter.
Of course I cannot say counter because this is an integer.
I have to count convert this into a string.
It will give me an error.
OK.
And in order to do that I'm going to do it like this.
And this will convert this into a string as well or you can just say string wrapped with counter like
this.
So you can choose your own way.
So this will be our counter.
This will be our time label actually.
So next I'm going to take my timer and I'm going to create a scheduled timer out of this variable.
So this will be scheduled timer.
And we want this timing terrible target selector user in and repeats.
So timing interval.
I'm going to go for one second one more time because I just want to subtract one from the counter every
second target will be self and self refers to we've controller and selector.
We're going to create another object to see function and we are actually going to call this count down
or just subtract one.
You can call this whatever you want.
Okay I'm just going to go for count down.
So next step will be to define selector in here.
I'm going to go for countdown.
So this is good.
Later on for user E4 I'm going to go four nil and repeats true.
So here you go.
We have our timer.
So what do we want to do in the selector function in the countdown function.
This is going to be fairly easy.
We're just going to deduct the one from our counter variable and then we're going to display that on
our time label.
So let's see.
Count three minus equals one and our time label dot taxed K will be again counter of string representation
of counter end them.
We can check to see if counter has reached zero.
So we're going to have an if statement in here I'm going to say if counter is actually zero and open
curly braces here and you can go for a timer that invalidate.
OK.
This will stop our timer and we will do some other stuff like displaying alert message to the user.
Right.
And in this alert message we will just provide some replay functions and other stuff as well.
But for right now I believe we can create our alert message only.
So how do you create alert messages of course you use UI Elliott controller class.
Right.
So first let me do the alert and say let's Allard will be a you eye alert controller not action controller
but just controller if you open parentheses so you will have a title.
So what do we do for it's title.
We can say something like time's up or time is over.
OK.
And this is good for a title for message maybe we can say want to play again.
So that user will know what to do.
And let me say do you want to play again and forward a preferred style.
I'm going to hit enter and see that dot and then say Elliott.
So do we have a bottom line here.
Yep we have a replay button and we have no of.
Right.
So we have to create two actions.
And you know how to do this you just have to use UI alert action in order to do that.
Let's start with the cancel button.
Okay.
So I'm going to call is okay by then and I'm going to say you a to action.
And the title can be cancel or.
Okay.
And the style let's go for cancel this time to see how this looks.
So the default will be more highlighted.
Okay.
And the handler.
We don't need any handler.
We don't want anything to happen when user taps on this cancel.
So we're going to have a replay button as well.
Right.
So that's where we want handler in this case I don't want any handler.
So let me create the replay by them now.
So a replay button will be again a UI alert action.
Right.
And then we're going to go for replay and then for a style I can go for default this time.
And the handler.
Yeah.
We want handler because we have to have a replay function in here.
So hit enter and hit enter one more time to make this visible and in the coding section we're going
to write a replay function.
Right now I'm not going to do that.
We're going to do that last.
So we have to add these buttons to our Ellard.
So I looked that ad action.
OK button alert that ad action replay button and then we're ready to present this view.
So I'm going to say South dot present and it will ask me what to present.
Right.
So I'm going to present this alert and it will be animated.
Why not.
So let's say true.
And the completion I don't need any completion because I'm doing what I had to do in the replay button.
So far so good.
Let me test is actually because we don't have to write anything else at this point.
We're just going to take care of those things later on at the end.
So far I don't know what to do to create a replay function.
So here we go.
It's already started counting down from ten.
And as you can see I can still click on the scores.
And here you go time's up.
Do you want to play again.
So if I click or replay or okay nothing will happen.
So because we didn't write our handler obviously we didn't write our replay function.
We're going to do that later on.
But right now I can say that we're making progress and we are ready to estimate the Kenny.
So we're going to stop here and that's what we're going to do within the next lecture.