Hi.
We did this lecture re going to go ahead and find ourselves some landmark images and landmark themes
from Google.
So that's kind of boring but I don't like to give you a ready dataset because if you were building your
real app on your own you would just go disk tabs by and one by one you will have to google it yourself.
You will have to find the images and descriptions maybe yourself.
So we're going to go over this in this lecture.
So let me search for coalesce Hume and I misspelled it obviously.
So this is called less Hume and I'm going to download this image.
OK.
And maybe we can go for Great Wall of China.
OK you can choose your own landmarks obviously and you can even find a whole other concept like this
on your own.
But I'm going to go back to landmarks.
So let's go for Kremlin and this is obviously not Kremlin.
This is a Cancer Journal so let's go for that image.
Yep.
This is Kremlin.
So I'm going to save this to my downvote and then let's go for another like Taj Mahal.
OK.
Let's find Taj Mahal his picture.
So just choose a suitable one and download it to your folder and let's find a final one.
I'm going to go for Stonehenge okay and choose one of these and save it to your downloads.
Of course we can go for more.
But I believe that's enough for now because we're just building this app for an example.
So I'm going to close these down.
OK.
I'm really going to take these pictures take these images and actually rename them.
So this is great.
Well OK.
So this is great hold up JP.
So this is called assume and this is Kremlin.
OK.
And let's see this one these Taj Mahal and this is Stonehenge and that's all.
So let's open the assets folder and let's bring in those images so you can drag and drop to here or
else you can drag and drop these pictures drug and drag and drop these images to here as well as we
have seen before.
So choose your way.
It doesn't bother you but just make sure that you have to select these at two targets and you have to
select the copy items if needed.
So they will be actually copied to your folder.
Ok.
So as you can see now they're inside of my project.
So we can reach them in our image views as well but I'm not going to go for image views right now because
we will work with table view first and then we're going to pass this information to another view in
which we can display the image and the name of the selected landmark.
So I'm going to create an array in fact I'm going to create two areas in which I'm going to search the
names of this landmarks and then store the images of these landmarks as well.
So we're going to go for your eye image as we did before.
And as you can see if we say Stonehenge for example we can just reach the Stonehenge UI image right
button.
Right now I'm going to store those values inside of an array so it can be done right.
We can just show these values like we store Strings.
So let's go for Landmark names first.
So I'm going to initialize this as an empty string array so this array consist of strings.
But this will not be initialized.
So we have an empty array right now.
So if I say landmark names that append I can append the new name to here.
Of course we could have just save our landmark names and just added all the names like we did in the
previous lectures.
However I'm going to go for appending here so that we can see the order that we are storing these values
and I'm going to explain why later on.
So call assume grateful Kremlin and then we have Stonehenge.
OK.
Do we have any missing.
Yeah I believe so we have Taj Mahal as well.
Right.
So let's say Taj Mahal.
So after that I'm going to create a landmark images array as well in which I will sir do you I image.
So I had to do that in the exact same order because I'm going to use the indexes.
OK.
I'm going to explain in a minute.
So let me say this landmark images will have this UI image type and this will be an empty array initially
and then I'm going to append everything like we did in the strings.
So let's go for Landmark images and as you can see this will consist UI image.
OK.
And as a new element it asks for a UI image.
And I will just give a UI image names OK coalesce Hume.
So I'm going to just follow the same order in here like I said before.
So let me check this is name.
Yeah.
This is Coliseum.
So it will ask me to first unwrapped is or do provide the default value.
I can force unwrap this as long as I am sure that coliseum that JP is added in my project folders.
OK if not it can be nil and it can crash my app.
And when you do that without the SARS folder I believe we have to add this JP extension as well so that
it will understand the exact file that we are talking about.
So this is great wall JP Kremlin JPM.
OK.
So the next Stonehenge and for the last one we going to go for Taj Mahal.
So why do we follow the same order.
Because we're going to work with indexes for example if we click on the Colosseum I'm going to say we're
going to get landmark names zero landmark names first of the month and this will be in sync with each
other.
OK so this is great wall to grateful Kremlin to Kremlin's Stonehenge to Stonehenge.
So if I have an index like zero I can come over here two landmark names and put zero in here.
It will give me the name of Colosseum and if I say landmark images 0 it will also give me the image
of Colosseum as well.
So it is vital that we follow the same order.
Then we add these valleys.
So that's why I have used the pens in order to make clear that I'm following the same order when I'm
adding these values into my race.
So that's it for right now we're going to stop here and within the next century going to see how we
can display those values in our table.