Hi within this lecture regrouping to see how we can display those values in our table we use using this
table view functions that we have created before.
So right now I'm just displaying tasks for 10 times.
So how many data do I have in here to display in my table view.
I have five data right.
So coalesce assume great while Kremlin Stonehenge and Taj Mahal.
So I can easily come to my number of rows in Section.
I can just say five fine it will work as well but I'm not going to go for that because there is a better
way to do this.
I'm going to go for Landmark names dot count.
So we have seen this before right.
We have a dot count method in our landmark names actually in all areas.
So if you come over here and say landmark names will give you the array and if you say dots count it
will give you the number of elements in that area.
So later on we may decide to add new landmarks.
So it's wise to use landmark names dots count in here rather than just saying five.
But I cannot reach that right now.
How can I do that.
Of course we have to define these variables outside of the we did load.
But inside of our class so that we can reach those variables from all the functions inside of our class.
So you know how to do that right.
So you you just can copy this or you can just even cut this with command X and paste the here and then
later on I'm going to do the same thing for this one as well.
Cut this and pasted in here.
So all right now I can't reach those values from everywhere.
So here I can change landmark names I can upon new values let me delete this as well.
And here we go.
So we can reach landmark names landmark images from here.
And let me create a note here saying that these are landmark book deep data.
OK.
And then later on I can come to my number of ROVs function.
I can call landmark names that count.
So this is landmark names that count and it will return five.
To me anyway.
But it would be much more practical if we want to add some more data here later on.
So here we go.
We have our rare number of rows in Section function ready.
Now we have to find a way to display those names in our row cell that text labeled so rather than saying
text I'm going to refer to my landmark names.
So let me run this and let's see what we get.
We're going to get test five times.
Right.
Because we are creating five rows in here but we're just displaying tasks in those rows rather than
displaying this task.
I'm just going to display the elements inside of my string list one by one and we have indexes in order
to achieve this result.
As I said before table view has its own index and a race has its own index as well.
So if you go over here and say landmark names then you can choose an index to show in relate to the
rows.
And there is a very good way to do that.
If you open a parentheses in here you can just go for index path that is given to you in this function.
So this is the current index that we see in the row.
So this is 0 for this row one for it is two for this tree for this and it goes and on and on.
So it has its own index since I am algorithm and it says it's only indexing logic and it overlaps with
the logic of array in the same place.
So that's why we use table view with arrays because it's so efficient.
If you come over here as a index path that's your.
It will just you do related to row to you in each related array elements so that we will get coalesce
Hume first grateful seconds Kremlin Stonehenge and Taj Mahal.
So that's very good.
Right.
That's very cool.
So that's it actually.
That's all we have to change in order to make this work so we're calling landmark names and we are saying
index path.
That's row in order to get 0 1 2 3 and 4 in order.
So here you go.
Now we see the Colosseum Great Wall crumbling Stonehenge and Taj Mahal here.
So that's good.
Right now we have learned how to display those arrays inside our table view but we don't know how to
make them clickable right.
So what we want here is actually to let the user click one of these rows one of these cells so that
we can pass this data to another real controller in which we can show the details.
That's what we going to do within the following lectures.