Hi within this lecture we're going to add our second we've comptroller and we will make it so that when
we tap on one of these elements it will take us to the other we have comptroller.
So in order to do that let's go to our main story board and first thing we're going to do we're going
to add a new view controller.
Right.
So in order to do that open this library and search for a real controller we have done this before right.
So you know how to do it.
Just drag and drop when we have controller to here so that we can have a Segway from here to this wheel
controller.
And you know I have to do that as well.
Just click on this yellow dot and we'd control Drag this to the other controller and say show.
So this will create a Segway a connection between our UI view controller and the new View Controller.
So this is connected to we have controller that Swift.
And the second one is not connected to anything.
So before we do that let me embed in the navigation controller.
And remember what it does.
It creates a navigation bar inside of our UI we have controller and also a navigation bar in the have
controllers that are connected to this table view we they show Segway so that we can have it back by
then automatically in our navigation bar.
So it will make us our life much more simpler when we go back and forth between this view controllers.
So we have to create an image view inside of this view controller right.
We we will have one image view and we will have one labeled that's it.
We are going to display the image of the selected landmark every going to display the name of the selected
landmark.
So let's go for a label.
So this is where we're going to display the name.
So this is going to be name.
Let me make this a little bit bigger because we might have that long landmark naming here.
OK.
So that's good.
Let me zoom out a little bit so we can see better.
So let's make this centrally aligned.
That's all right.
So we have an image view and we have a name label.
And of course later on if you want you can add that description label you can add a country label whatever
you want.
Don't forget to reset to suggest the constraints.
So we will have a proper view here.
OK.
And the next thing is to define those images into a controller which we don't have right now.
We have to create a Coco touch glass like we did before.
Remember how we can do that.
We can just go to this landmark book folder right click here and say new file a rather dense file I'm
going to go for cocoa touch class and this will be indeed a view controller a UI weave controller but
I'm not going to named his view controller.
I'm just going to name this image view controller or you can just call these details we have controller.
OK can choose a name and it's UI controller and Swift is perfect for me.
So I'm going to say next and create and this will create this new service file in my project folder.
So we're ready to go to mainstream birds and connect this view controller to my image view controller
within the identity Inspector.
So I'm doing this kind of fast because we have done this before.
So you know what to do.
We are just re practicing it so that we can do it better we can really understand it then we have to
write our own apps later on then we finish this course.
So let me open the assistant editor over here and let me bring in the image of you first.
OK.
Control drag this imagery to here called Image view and we only have one more reading here which is
a label.
So let me choose this label and drag and drop and let's say label.
OK landmark label and connect it.
So we're good to go.
Let me close this down.
We're done here so we can have an identifier to these Segway as well.
So make sure that the Segway is chosen and go to identifier.
You can say something like to image V.C. or image view controller.
OK we're going to use this identifier in our code.
So make sure you remember this so too imagery controller and everything seems to be right in the main
that's Tory Burch.
So we can go to our real controller dot swift and re going to call another function.
So since we are a delegate of disabled we we can call the related functions remember and this time I
want a function that understands if I tap on the table to use cell I will explain what to do 2 x code
in that function.
So if you search for did select row m looking for did select throw.
Okay I'm not looking for did these select throw I'm looking for did select a row at.
So this is did select row and it gets cold.
Once a user taps on one of these rows.
So what will happen when the user taps on one of the rows.
Basically I want to do and say grey right so I can come over here and I can just say present or perform
Segway not present performed Segway and the identifier that I'm looking for to Image view controller
OK and center is nil.
And this will just take me to Image view controller.
So let's try this.
Let's run our app in simulator and then we tap on one of these landmark names it will just take me to
the imagery controller in which we won't see anything yet but later on we will see.
So let's choose Coliseum.
As you can see we see a label.
So this is working well.
Each time we click one of these landmarks we get to go to Image view controller.
Now it's time to stop here and within the next lecture.
We're going to make it so that we pass this information to Image view controller so that we can display
the image and the name of the chosen landmark.