Hi.
We did this lecture.
We're going to create our first project in order to understand classes a little bit more.
Rather than going with single view app.
This time I'm going to go for Mac OS and I'm going to create a command line tool.
If you remember I showed you this technique in the beginning of this course.
Before we dive into the playgrounds.
So if you had a problem with playground there is a high probability that you have worked with this now.
But if you haven't it's not an issue.
Just create a new Mac OS line comment tool and you can name it musician class.
So that's what we were going to build in this lecture we're going to create a musician class and we're
going to see almost every aspect of classes so that we can understand them better and we can just implement
them in our projects as well.
So this is going to Iran.
This code's inside of our mac and we're not going to be dealing with main that storyboards or simulators.
So if you just run this it will print out the result in logs so we can actually follow and track what's
going on inside of logs as well as you can see printed out how low earth can we do this in playgrounds.
Of course we can but we're going to learn a lot and we're going to work with different kinds of control
there's really going to see how to work with multiple view controllers or dot swift files in this case
not view controllers so that it would make sense to work this inside of command line too.
So come over here and just say final new OK because we're going to add a new file.
So let's say file okay.
And rather than cocoa touch class I'm going to go for a swift file because I'm going to create a class
in the swift file and I'm going to name my class musicians.
Okay.
So this will be my musician class.
This will be my model actually.
So in order to create a class it's fairly easy.
You can just write class.
Okay.
And then we going to start with that in uppercase rather than lowercase remember in classes v use uppercase
like this.
Musicians.
And then after you can open a curly brace and it will close it for you.
This is your class.
Right now we actually created our class so we can have some attributes you can have some actions in
this class right.
So let's cert what can a musician have it.
It can have a name for example.
Okay I'm going to initialize this to be an empty string first.
So later on it will have an H.
I'm going to say this is zero and it will have an instrument as well.
So you can make this an empty stream too.
So suppose that we will have these musicians class k.
And it will have this tree attributes.
So how can we create a musician object.
Since now we have our class.
It's fairly easy.
We can go to our remains.
That's fifth file.
Suppose that means that Swift is your real controller and we have created a musician class.
And now I can't create an object out of that musician class in here.
So first musician will be James and you fire right musicians.
It should have show up.
Yeah.
It sees the musicians as you can see if I do a command be it we'll build up the project or we can come
over here to product and say Build.
So the files will be synchronized inside of our X code project.
So if I write let James or let's something else if I type musicians as you can see now it sees the musicians
class.
So double click on this.
And as you can see there is a C character on the left hand side.
If you do a string this is kind of creating a string object like I'm creating a musician's object right
now.
So if I open parentheses and close this it means that I'm creating this object out of the musicians
class.
And right now my object is actually created.
So I managed to create an James instance of this musician class.
So as you can see James has the type musicians.
And if I say dot it can see these attributes like age instrument and name.
So these are the attributes that we have given here.
So let me say purpose to your attribute.
OK.
So I can just define the age of James here so I can say 50 and I can come over here and say James that
name is James Hetfield OK.
And then later on I can define the instrument as Vo.
So this will be a guitar.
So do this for your own favorite musician and you will see it will work.
So let's try to print age of James.
Here you go.
We now see the 50.
That's cool right.
We have created the musician model and we have created an object out of that model and we can set the
attributes right now.
Now suppose that we're getting this information from internet we're downloading from a database like
far your base.
OK.
So if we work on a model this will be much more structural than ever before.
So we can actually save all those values into arrays different areas and we can try to synchronize these
arrays using indexes.
But if we just create a model out of these values and we can just add those model values to an array
it will be much more structure.
And we're going to do that in the following lectures.
Don't worry.
Right now suppose that I didn't define the values as I did in the James.
So we have those previously defined values.
Right.
So let me try to prevent James that age without giving the values.
So what will it be.
It will be zero because why.
Because I have initialized this to be zero.
Right.
And if I do this print James that name it will be an empty string.
So what's the problem about that.
So maybe I don't want to initialize this.
Maybe I just want to say this will be an integer or this will be straight.
Because I don't want to get numbers zero when I don't give the age value.
OK so can I do this yes of course I can but it will give me an error.
So as you can see class musicians has no initialize.
So if I create a property if I create an attribute without initializing I will get an error.
But there is a solution to that problem as well.
We have something called initialize here and maybe you have heard this as a constructor in other programming
languages.
So there is a spatial function in this musician class in all classes actually.
It defines what to do when we create this object when we create an object out of this musicians.
So I can do the initialization as well to make this go away but if I don't want to do that if I don't
want to initialize these properties then I have to create an equalizer.
So if you write in it as you can see this is initialized declaration and this is what happens when an
object is created for the first time or second time it doesn't matter actually when you create an object.
It will happen.
So what exactly can we do inside of this.
We can do anything we want.
It doesn't have to be related with class musicians at all.
So let me do an example so you will understand it better.
So if I initialize these and these and these last one the error will go away.
OK.
And I will just print something inside of my.
In its function so I can say musician created for example.
So whenever I create an object it will print this log.
So let me create this James as you can see this is only creating the James and this will only print
out the James that name.
But before it prints it says musician create it.
So whenever I create another instance of this musician class it will again print musician created.
So it isn't related with properties or attributes at all.
Of course we are going to make it relate to but let me do this example as well so I'm creating another
instance from these musicians.
And if I run this you will see there will be two musicians created luck.
So in in it you can write what you want to do when an object is created.
So this is initialized or came.
And again you may have heard this as a constructor in other programming languages.
What we actually want to do in here is to get some name age and instrument property values and assign
them as our properties as our attributes.
We are going to get those values from the developer in Maine that Swift.
So let's stop here and do that within the next lecture.