Hi we this lecture we going to learn about access levels.
So what are those.
They define very we can reach the variable or functions that we have created.
OK we have five of them.
It starts with private.
And it goes down to the open.
So let me start with the open and public.
We don't generally use them.
Why.
Because they're not kind of safe to implement.
If you make something you open it means that it can be reached from anywhere in the project and it can
be changed from anywhere in the project.
Public also can be reached from anywhere but they cannot be changed.
So why are we not using them and who uses them anyway within the next sections we're going to work with
external libraries.
So we're going to just download some software kid development kits as the case to our project for example
order to work with a cloud server.
In the case of fire base we are going to see how we're going to do that.
Don't worry about it.
But right now know that we're going to implement and download some project files into our own project
and this file your base developers make their files public so that we can reach them and use them in
our own project.
But other than that there is no way there is no actually a logic to implement public and open rather
regrowing to Burke private file private and internal mostly so private means.
This is actually private.
This is spatial to the class that we have created in.
It cannot be reached from anywhere else.
So if you're want to make it private then you have to be careful because you cannot reach it from somewhere
else and internal is the default one and file private means you get to reach it from the file.
For example you get to reach it from these musicians that swift file not in the class only but from
this file.
OK.
So let me make an example because you will understand it much better this way.
For example let me make this function sync private.
So if I make this private it means that I can only reach this sync function within my musicians class.
I cannot reach it from anywhere else in my project.
So let's try.
Actually I met made this private right.
So can I call this from Maine that's first or can I call this function from other classes or other service
files.
I cannot do that if I do command B or if I try to run this as you can see it gives me an error and it
says that Singh is inaccessible due to private protection levels.
So James cannot sing right now because I made it private.
And in the Super musician class also even though I'm inheriting this I cannot reach the function sync.
So if I make this private data they cannot call this sync function from anywhere in my project.
So it doesn't make sense to make this private because I am inheriting this function.
I am using this function in my objects.
So I believe we should delete this but there will be some cases that you may want to make things private.
For example if you tried to come up with a variable inside of your main that swift or inside of your
controller and if you're not going to use that variable inside of this nother class for example you
can make it private and you can make it for functions as well.
For example in my musician that Swift.
Let's suppose that I have a test function OK I am just testing something.
So I can print out test.
For example let's say that we are again working in a big group.
So I'm duping musician's class and I'm testing something but I don't want anyone to create a musician
object and reach the test function.
So as you can see they cannot call test for a main that's fifths.
So let me do a command B as you can see they can call sing but they cannot call tests.
So this is good.
Right.
We can make things private if we want to make them really private if we want to use them only within
the current class and we can make it failed private if we want to use it inside of that particular pop
file.
So this is all we want to talk about access levels and this is all we want to talk about object oriented
programming.
So Regan gonna stop here.
I mean did the next picture re going to create a model and display all of this information in a real
app.