Hi.
We didn't this lecture.
We're going to go ahead and create our user interface in the main that storyboard.
So what do we have in the ZAP.
First we need to have a table view in which we can display the names of the yards.
Right.
So let's open our library and drag and drop one table view.
So it will have the constraints of 0 0 0 so that it will reach out to the edges.
Right.
And are we not going to have anything else in this view controller actually we're just okay.
Too good to go with this table view.
And then of course we going to add another UI view controller in which we will display the details.
But for right now let me give the zero zero zero constraints so that our first free controller will
be ready.
So remember we had this UI navigation bar over here in which we have this plus button when we click
on this the new details we have controller opens.
So let me embed in an aviation controller to my view controller so that we will have this bar.
OK I'm going to add a button here.
I'm going to show you how to do that later on.
But right now I need another wi controller so that if I make a Segway from this to another one it would
have the UI tab bar as well.
So let me drag and drop from your controller over here and let me align this a little bit so I can do
a Segway from here to there.
I'm going to make it show.
And as you can see we got the back button here.
So let me give you an identifier to this Segway.
I can call these details wi controllers I'm going to go for two details V.S. and I'm all doing this
kind of fast because we have been doing this for a lot of times right.
So let me create another file in here.
Okay.
And it's going to be a cocoa touch glass because I'm going to create this as a UI view controller subclass.
I'm going to connect this to my newly created view controller.
So let me name those details we see.
OK.
And make sure the target is selected.
And then I can create and put those files in my folder.
So let's go to main storyboard so that we can connect that file to our details view controller.
So let's choose this view controller and let's go to the identity inspector in which we will find the
class and assign it to it.
And we cannot see the details view controller.
And here we have a question mark.
So I believe there is something going on something like a bug in X code.
I'm going to show you have to come over this problem.
So let me click and manually write this.
So if I click on this button it takes me to details we see.
However I am still suspicious that if if there is a question mark in here it's never a good sign.
So best way to understand is to create our views and try to connect them with our real controller file.
OK so let's do that.
What do we have in details we see we have to have an image right.
First of all so let me drag and drop one image view to here and make it a little bit bigger so that
our art will be displayed in here.
And the next I'm going to need some text fields right in which I will display the name of yards and
the artists and the year.
So let me make this a little bit higher over here and a little bit bigger.
So that's good.
Let me go to you.
Attributes and find place holder and called his name.
So this will be the name of the art.
That's law.
Let me zoom in a little bit so I have to copy this on pace this because I'm going to go for an artist's
name in here OK.
I'm going to call these artists and also I'm going to copy and paste one more time to go for year.
So are we going to take note of the year as well.
So let's say a year.
OK.
And finally we we need actually a save bottom right.
So that we can save all this information into core data.
So drag and drop a button and make this a little bit bigger and make it central.
And then I'm going to call this save and hit enter.
So that looks good.
So here we go who we re going to reset to suggested call strains and this kind of setup in which our
user actually chooses their own pictures rather than we're providing them.
I suggest you try div width and height constraint as well.
Because we cannot know the size of the picture that is going to come from the user.
OK.
So if you go for a fixed with height constraint in here by checking these two boxes and adding these
two constraints it would be much more concrete.
So as you can see it breaks up the view a little bit.
So in order to overcome this problem I'm going to manually drag and make this a little bit bigger.
OK.
And then it will show us some orange constraints which means that these constraints are not yet updated.
So let me go over here and say update constraints constants.
So let's see if we have another problem.
This is the UI image view is now okay with width and height constraints.
But I believe we have some problem in below.
Let me see.
Do you have problem in here.
No.
Let me see the Web problem in text fields.
No but we have some in Save button.
So it's a little bit to the left.
So let me go over here and make this a little bit bigger and drag it to the central.
And let me do update constraints.
Constance again so that's good.
Of course we can make this view much better but I'm not going to spend any more time on this because
we may still have a bug in here.
Let me try to understand thus by adding this assistant editor and choosing details we see from the right
hand side.
And let me delete all of these comments.
And let me have some room in here.
And on the left hand side we have our details we have comptroller.
So let me drag and drop image view.
Yeah it seems okay.
Yeah right.
So we have the imagery we have this circular thing that is filled up so it means that everything is
OK.
So let me bring up the name text.
So far so good.
It's going on.
Let me bring in the artist's text.
And for the final thing I'm going to bring in the year tax as well.
So that's working.
Let me try to define the save button as an action.
So say button clicked OK and here we go we have a problem in here as you can see the circle is not filled
as in here it means that these outlet is not connected even though I made this connection it doesn't
work because this is a bug actually.
And in order to make this right I'm going to go for outlets here and as you can see it seems connected.
Let me choose these details we see and go to the outlets.
And here you go.
We have a lot of warnings.
So there is no reason to get this warning that unless there is a bug.
OK.
Because we made everything right and we should solve this problem before we proceed because.
And by the way if you're not experiencing this kind of problem that we see this outlet is not being
connected or something you should not do what I'm about to do I'm just going to delete all of these
connections and define this from beginning.
However you should learn how to solve this problem because you may experience this bug for some time
because it's been going on for some years right now.
It's not related to latest version.
So I believe this is good for you to understand what causes this problem.
So I'm going to delete every connection in here except the Segway.
OK.
And as I delete as you can see this is not field anymore.
It means that the connection is broken.
So I'm going to delete all of these functions and outlets and I'm going to solve this problem by coming
over and fixing the details V.C..
OK so if you right click on the main story board if you go to open as we're opening this as an interface
builder.
But right now I'm not going to open this as interface builder but I'm going to open the source code
and the source code is actually an E email code.
So if you work with Android Studio for Android development you know what an example is this kind of
a code representation of the main storyboards.
But we don't generally used this because it's not necessary to use this and it's not very user friendly
in the X code but if you come across a situation like this we have to come to the source code and define
some values ourselves in order to solve this problem.
For example we see the view controller definition in here.
We have some custom module custom module provider under the V controller and below we have the details
we see and again we have the view controller custom class and scene member I.D. but we don't have some
of the members some of the values that we had about.
So I'm going to add those values manually and in order to do that I'm going to copy this and paste this
below so we can compare them side by side.
So let me paste here.
I'm going to delete this later on.
As you can see both has ideas both has custom class but deep details we see doesn't have this custom
module and custom module provider.
So I'm going to copy these values from here okay and I'm going to paste is in the same place that he
has to be in here.
So that's now OK.
It has seen member I.D. so I'm going to delete this and this is how this bug gets fixed.
So if I do product clean and product builds it will get synchronized.
OK and then we can try to define our outlets and define our action in the details we have controller
now.
So let me go over here I say open as interface builder.
And again if you're not experiencing this problem you should not bother doing this.
But as a general information I believe it's good to know for you.
So let me go to details of you.
And let me try to bring this save in here as an action and call this Save button clicked OK and here
you go.
Now this is Connect.
So I believe the bug has now been fixed.
So let me create my other outlets as well like image for you.
And let's go for a name text OK name text and let's go for artists.
OK.
So let me drag and drop here.
Artists text and then finally year text so year text.
So this is now OK.
Right.
Of course we have to make sure that this works.
And in order to do that you can come over here and go to the outlets and you still see these those warnings
here.
But I believe the actual problem has now been resolved.
But we're able to see it.
So let me print something here so we can test this.
OK in the site button clicks and if it's not fixed it's going to crash because it will not find the
necessary function to call.
Then we hit on save.
So we have to make sure that we define the table view in the we did vote in the controller not in we
did load.
So table view here.
OK.
And we are done with this.
Now I have to add a button on the bar site here on the right hand side of the bar so that I can click
on this button and it will perform a Segway to bring me here so that I can test if the saved bottom
works.
So we're going to do that in the next lecture.