Hi.
We didn't the section we're going to learn how to work with maps in order to do that.
We're going to build an app called travel book.
So this is kind of a travel app.
Suppose that our user is travelling and she sees a good landmark that she wants to tag on the map so
that she can find her way back when she wants to visit that place again.
For example let's click on the note rhythm as you can see we're tagging the notes for them canter ruling
here and there is a pin on the note rhythm category.
So this is pinned by the user herself.
Okay.
If I click on it it will display an icon over here and if I click on that I can.
It will take me to that Notre Dame Cathedral within navigation.
So this is my current place and I can just go by driving walking or whatever I want.
And also I can tag other places like cafes restaurants anywhere in the map I won't actually say if I
want to add a new place I can hit on plus by them and it zooms in the current location of the user.
So I'm here right now and I can choose whenever I want to whatever I want to tag on the map and I can
just come over here.
For example let's say that this is my hotel and I want to take my hotel so that I can find my way back.
So let's say that this is hotel invited ace.
And the comment will be my hotel.
So I fly long press over here for three seconds.
It will bring a pin.
And if I click on that pin it will just display the information that I have written.
If I hit the save button it will just add it to my list.
As you can see we're using the card data so that this information will not be deleted defy open and
close the app.
If I go over and open and close my phone.
So we're going to practice the core data one more time and we're going to learn how to do this kind
of things with the maps like navigation like tagging using the maps finding the user location zooming
in zooming out.
We're going to learn them all and we're going to learn by practicing by building this travel book app.
This is a real app that you can really improve and put on your app store after you complete this course.
So if you're ready let's get started.