Hi.
We didn't this lecture.
Where are you going to see how we can actually zoom in to the selected landmark from here or selected
travel from here.
For example if we choose the artsy Triumph right now we're showing the annotation but you're not actually
zooming in.
If we had another location like this.
Let me go to location and change this and you will see that the map will display whole another location.
So rather than saying 48 let me do this forty nine for example if I hear okay it will show us a completely
different location so that even though I added the notation of the selected place now I cannot even
see that annotation in order to do that.
I have to disable this location updates so even die I change my place even though I am completely in
a different place then I can still see the arch there trying for I can still see the Eiffel Tower right
now I cannot see it because I'm in a completely different place.
So let's go to location one more time and let's go back to 48.
And as you can see if we if we are on the same place that our selected landmark or site took place then
I can't see it and that's not what I want.
So what shall we do to make this problem go away.
So here in the location manager we started updating location right.
And if we select some other places some other places from the table view then I'm going to come over
here and say stop updating location if I choose a previously created the record.
Now I don't need to get the location at all.
All I just want to show the notation or a selected place to the user on the map.
And furthermore I'm starting to getting location in the wooded lot so I will have the location anyway.
So it's not harmful for me to stop updating location because when I start updating location every time
this gets updated this function we'll zoom in to the turn location off the user.
So rather than zooming in the current location under here under the annotation I'm going to call what
I have been doing in here.
I'm going to create a location I'm going to create this pen and I'm just going to set the region to
the selected place.
So I already have the coordinates right.
I already have a location so I can come over here and say let location I let chosen location as your
location coordinate 2D but I have already done that in here.
I have this as a coordinate here.
So there is no need to do that.
I just I have to just call and create a spend and then I can set a region to show on the map.
So let's do this Ben.
It's will be an M K coordinate spend.
OK.
And this will ask for as ask us for our latitude Delta.
I'm gonna go 4 0 point 0 5 and longitude Delta as well.
And then we can create a region combining these coordinates and spots.
So let's say caught in that region.
OK.
This will ask for us as center so let's give the coordinators a center and let's give the span is a
span.
OK and then we can just say not let actually we can just call the map view right.
So let's say they let's say that Matthew Dowd sat region.
OK.
And let's go to the region here and animated.
Why not.
Let's say true.
Here we go.
Now this will focus the map view onto the chosen place onto the chosen title.
And Beaver that we're only doing this if the selected title is not empty string.
So it means that we have a selected title.
For example if I click on this it will show me my current location anyway.
But let me change the current location here.
OK.
Let me go to forty nine.
One more time.
So I'm in a different place right now.
So if I click the ad button it will show me here.
So this is good.
So if I click on the ad button I can still add a place from my current location.
But I want to see the arch the triumph when I click on it.
And as you can see we're not seeing it yet even though we stopped the location updates even though we
made sure that we zoomed in to the selected place we cannot say it.
Maybe if we try a lot more times like when I click on the Eiffel Tower now I get the result that I want.
But when I click on the arch to triumph it won't show me.
And this is a problem that we may experience because we're dealing with some asynchronous tasks in here.
For example we can see these actually trying for right now but before we couldn't see it.
So this is not the behavior that we're looking for we have to be sure many user clicks on one of the
selected items.
It directly takes us to this screen.
And if the user clicks on the ads button then it will just take us to the current location.
So in order to make sure I'm going to come under it as did update locations and if and only if if the
selected title is not an empty string I'm just going to disable it.
OK.
So I'm just going to say if selected title OK if selected title is actually an empty string then do
this else I'm not going to do anything at all because if the selected title is not empty it means that
I am trying to show something to the user.
Just don't update my location as you can see if I hit the Add button it still shows me the current place.
But now when I go to one of the records that I have previously made it shows me that selected place.
So now it works like a charm.
So that's what I have wanted in the first place.
So since now we fix this problem I believe we still have something to figure out like when we add a
new record.
It doesn't take us back to the lists we have controller and it doesn't display the last added data in
the real controller reel table.
So we had to make sure we fixed that.
And then later on we had to make sure to add a navigation from the current location to the selected
place.
Let's do all of those in the following lectures.