Hi within the section we're going to build our first app interacting with internet data.
So we're going to be downloading data from the Internet and re going to pass.
We are going to process that data so that we can show this data to the user in a format that we want.
And in this section we're not going to be working with cloud servers like we're not going to be creating
users.
We're not going to write into any database.
We're not going to upload any pictures.
We're going to learn that later only in the following section then we deal with the five year base in
here.
We're going to get data from the Internet through something called API an API sense for application
programming interface.
So let me show you how it's spelt.
So this is API.
OK.
And if you search Google for API as you can see it stands for application programming interface and
we're going to see whether that is.
Don't worry.
Now we can use this application programming interfaces in order to provide data to mobile applications
to web applications to softwares from our server from our platform.
For example Google has some API is Facebook some as has some API and Twitter has some API with using
this API so we can reach the data of Facebook through either Google and other platforms other Web sites
or other servers so that we can use their data safely in our apps.
OK.
That's what we're going to do within this section we're going to get data from application programming
interface and we're going to process that data so that we can use it in a way that we want.
For example if you search for Facebook API you will see this Web site.
This is developers dot Facebook dot com and you can actually use those API s in order to reach data
user data in Facebook.
For example you can ask users to sign in with their Facebook account so that you can reach their followers
you can reach their friends and do something with it and you can get their statistics and you can do
that in three there as well.
So if you search for three either API as you can see this has some documentation regarding the Twitter's
API as well.
So again you can use this API of Twitter in order to get the user data up from twitter servers.
So as you can see some platform some servers some applications use API is in order to provide data to
other softwares like mobile applications web applications.
OK.
And not only these big projects not only these big companies do that you can actually use whatever API
you want.
For example you can search for a vendor API.
OK.
So you can get the weather forecasts out of various API is as you can see we have a lot of examples
in here.
And in this section we're going to build a quote currency converter.
OK.
So if you search for currency converter API you will see a lot of options as well.
And in this section I'm going to be using one of these API is actually in real time so that you can
see how we can get data out of that Web site and how we can integrate that data in our application.
So we are going to be converting currencies.
We are going to display some kind of different currencies to the users.
So we're going to get the euro currency zone we're going to convert that currency into dollars Japanese
yen like Swiss franc.
OK.
And I'm going to use this fixer dot I.
So this is one of the API guys and I randomly chose this I tested it and it works fine.
So we're going to be using that in your own time.
You can try to work with another API as well.
However at the time being since you don't know how to work with API is I really suggest you stick with
me and I'll follow this fixer that I owe.
Example.
So in fixer that I oh we're going to get a data like this.
Okay.
As you can see it provides one hand.
One hundred and seventy worlds curiously so this displays a huge data to us.
This displays a lot of currencies in their own data.
And if you click on this price you will see we have a free option and that's one of the reasons why
we're using this API.
So we're going to work with free version of course.
But as you can see there are a lot of options in here like a basic one a professional one.
And of course we have some limitations on the free version like we get only hourly updates we get limited
support historical data and 1000 API calls per month.
So in hearing the basic version as you can see you get 10000 API calls in the professional Virgin get
a hundred thousand API calls and in the professional plus you get like 500000 API calls.
So if you if you're going to be working with more of course you can just contact the fixer that's IO
and you can get a pricing out of day your sales representatives and if you have a big Web site or if
you have a big application you can use this professional plus for example in order to display the real
time data as you can see it provides 60 second updates.
So this is actually real time.
So you get the real time currency numbers around the world so that you can display them to your user
and coding will not differ between these versions.
OK.
We will just write the same codes whatever we choose in here.
So that's why we're going to go with the basic form.
We're going to go with the free one in fact.
And after that we're going to process this data and show this data to the user.
That's why within the next lecture we going to cover something called Jason for Matt.