Hi within this lecture Regan going to see how we can actually get the data to display to the user later
on or we can just print IDs in our logs so that we can be sure that we are getting the data and in order
to make this work we have to do two more things in order to ensure we are creating this request and
getting the response as you can see we have a warning in here as saying that you have created this task
but you have never used it.
Remember in the previous lecture I've told you that I'm doing this task I may signing this to a variable
for a reason and you're going to see why.
Because we could have easily done this in the same line as well we can we could have just said your
Alsatian that shared the data task but we want to resume this task of to recreate it.
So we have to say task that to resume.
So this doesn't make sense at least from a grammar perspective.
We're not resuming does viewers starting this in fact.
But we have to use this methods in order to start this.
OK.
So once you create the task you can just say task that resume in order to fire these up.
So this will start our task up but we have to do one more thing because we're working with an H TTP
rather than H TTP yes.
So we're trying to reach an age TTP Web site.
And if you come over here you can see it displays.
This website is not secure because we're not using HDTV secure HDTV.
Yes.
For example let me go to my own Web site which is this Web site.
Any here as you can see this displays a look icon indicating that this is encrypted with an SSL cert
difficult.
It means that everything that is coming or going out of those Web sites server is encrypted with an
SSL certificate so it's safer to use HDTV.
Yes because all data transfer will be actually encrypted.
So if you have taken my complete ethical hacking course you will have remembered dad there is an attack
called Man in the middle attack that are done by hackers in order to steal your data when you're on
the same network.
For example suppose that you're connected to a router and some hackers is actually connected to that
router as well.
That hacker can easily be a man in the middle.
That means that they can actually monitor they can actually track the packets that you're getting and
giving to the web servers.
And if this packets are actually encrypted they cannot see the contents.
So even though they know there you're going to that Web site they cannot see the contents of that packets
but in this case you are using an HDTV.
And this is not secure as a CTP yes.
So if this was an HDTV has done it wouldn't have matter.
But in this case we're going to have to go to info that piece lists.
Are we going to have to find something cold at transport security.
Yes it can be on the upside or the downside when you first open this drop down menu.
So find this app transport security settings and then click somewhere outside of this info appeal list
then you're going to have to click on this live their little arrow to make it face dumb Mertz.
Once you do that you can't come over here and click on the plus side and it opens a new menu under the
app transport security settings and in the settings you're going to have to find some menu called Ello
arbitrary Lopes.
And this has a default value of no make it.
Yes once you do that then you can create a request to the HDTV Web site.
So rather than HDTV.
Yes.
So in any case if you're working with an HDTV connection you're going to have to do this.
OK.
You're going to have to make your app transport security settings modified so once we do that now we
are rated to get the data and try to printed out so that we can be certain that we are getting the data
in here.
If data is not nil it means that we actually have some data for right now.
We're going to use something called adjacency realization.
Remember it's called Jason serialization and this is a class that converts between Jason and the foundation
objects.
So we're going to be converting our Jason format into strings into boolean as into integers or doubles.
So this is how it goes you you're going to have to say Doc Jason object and it will ask you for a data.
And of course this is the data and it will ask you for some options.
And as you can see this chose an error which means that we are going to have to do this with try he
worked OK.
So this is obviously the data that we are looking for.
Then I believe we can just force our Raptors because we have already checked if this is Neil or not.
And if you hit enter or is reading up shows and hits dot it will give you some options.
And in here we're looking for the mutable containers so the containers actually allow us to work with
arrays and dictionaries and remember the type that we are getting in our Jason data kind of looks like
dictionary.
So it has some key value pairings that we have seen before.
So we don't have any immutable containers so mutable means it can be changed immutable means it cannot
be changed.
We're not interested in changing anything but we are interested in the container so that we can work
with dictionaries.
So we're going to choose the mutable containers after that of course.
This gives it an error does gives an error because we are going to have to work with try and in fact
I'm going to assign this to a variable and I'm going to try to make this happen.
So let me say something like let Jason result or Jason response.
OK.
And I'm going to try this and assign this to my Jason response and let me do this overdue try.
Catch.
So do try catch.
And if we catch any error we can just print out some error.
Okay.
And in here after trying to convert this to be at Jason objects let me print error over here before
we forget we can just get the data and print it to the user in a Jason response format.
So after dat what I'm going to do I'm going to print this out to see if we get the results or not.
If we can get the data done we can go on and pass it process it to get the single value like us the
Turkish lira and other stuff.
And before we do that of course we have to be certain that this is working so far because we have created
a lot of codes in here and the way that I'm going to do this to be as some kind of a synchronized operation
like we did in the face recognition lecture.
So we're doing all of this in background meaning that it won't affect the user interface it won't block
the current process that is going on in my app.
So that the user can actually interact with the user interface user can actually see what's going on
in the app they can click on the buttons they can play with the app whatever they want and it won't
block it want into interfere with the current processes on the other hand after this operation.
I'm going to change the user interface as well I'm going to change the labels so as I have gone into
face recognition lecture I'm going to use this as sync erroneously vets using this patch.
Q OK so if you haven't watch the face recognition app I suggest you go back and see what's going on
in that lecture.
So synchro Niels means wait for every process to be finished and then move on to the next one is in
Coroneos means it doesn't have to be synchronized so we can do two things at once and we're going to
see what's going to happen after the other process is finished as well.
And it won't affect the way that we're using the app so it won't block the user interface.
Remember we did that in the candy section in the countdown timer section as well.
Right.
So I'm going to go for dispatch cue and I'm going to say this main OK so I'm going to be working with
the main track but as sinker erroneously.
So this will create me a coding block and I'm going to print out the data.
Our Jason response that we have got from the Web site and we're going to use this response.
And I believe now we're ready to test this.
Right.
We have been writing so much code and we got to see if this is working or not.
So let me run this in our simulator and if this works out we going to be seeing the same result that
we have seen in the browser.
But this time we're going to see that result in our logs.
So make sure you print this Jason response out and try to be ready for what's you going to see in your
logs.
Because this is the first time that you're interacting with the Internet in this U.S. development cars.
So this is the moment of truth for us was the simulator opens click on the get right button.
And here we go now we have the data in our logs and this is exactly the same thing that we have seen
before in our browser.
So if you come back to your browser you can just compare this data as you can see we have the rates
we have every other data that we have seen like the USDA the Turkish the euro the Japanese yen and we
have the timestamp the success and everything.
Now let's stop Iran within the next lecture we're going to see how we can actually pass this data.