Hi within this section we're going to be building this fantastic app in which we're going to create
a clone of Instagram.
So let me log out from here and I'm going to start telling buy from scratch.
So we have a log in page in which our user can give their email address and password and if they match
with the server they can log in to the app and let me show this by example if I say last at Metallica
dot com and this user does not have this password.
As you can see we cannot sign it and we can't try with a user that doesn't even exist on the database
like Kirk hit Metallica dot com and it won't even sign in again if the passwords match of course we
can't sign it but we.
But we can do.
We can create a user called Kirk at Metallica dot com by clicking the sign up as you can see we are
inside and I can go to log out whenever I want.
So in the upload section if I choose a picture from the gallery I can write a comment and I can share
it to see it on my feed later on.
So if I say upload it will upload this picture and the comment to the server and it will immediately
download it and show me in the feed as you can see there are different kinds of users sharing this page
is sharing this posts and we can see them all we can even like them if we want like here.
So Bambi tap on this like it goes to the firebase database it uploads the current value and then just
downloads it and immediately refreshes the like label.
So in here you can see my database we're using Firebase and in the authentication we can see the users
and we we we're going to learn how to work with database where you're going to learn how to work with
storage.
We're going to learn how to work with authentication as well.
So if I can open this one more time.
Furthermore aside from firebase we're going to be learning how to work with Tab bars how to create custom
use surely this app will teach us a lot.
After completing this section you're going to be much more confident in U.S. developments and you will
be able to come up with an idea to create your own dream app on your own using this kind of technique.
So if you're ready let's get started in the next lecture because we have a long way to go in this section.