Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to create our user interface.
We're going to see how to work with Tab bars.
And before we go on and dive deep in our main dot story board as you can see this is indexing processing
files after you integrate the parts before you do anything.
Please wait to make sure that this indexing is done because there are too many files in your project
right now and they're newly integrated in order to make things synchronize.
You just going to have to wait for them to index and remember for the step five.
We have this importing Firebase and adding this firebase app dot configure in our app delegate.
So let's do that.
And then we can go back to our main story Bart.
So first thing to do is just importing this file your base here.
OK.
And as you can see we see the other modules as well.
So everything seems to be working right now but it asks us to import the firebase itself.
So I'm gonna go ahead and do that.
OK.
And under D did finish launching with options I'm going to configure the firebase so this is one of
the first functions that is I executed actually when our app is opened and something like we've did
load but it's not specific to a controller.
OK so we did load these specific to a controller and did finish launching with options of KERS is related
to whole app.
OK.
So even before the view controller gets slowed this gets cold.
So I'm going to configure my firebase app in here so I'm going to say fi your base app.
So let me go back and check one more time.
Yes firebase app dot com figure so far based app.
Yes this one dot com figure.
So this will actually start our firebase process now generally after we integrate some parts some external
libraries we want to come over simulator and test that to see if that's working but we don't have any
tab bar we don't have any user interface right now.
So quickly let's go to main dot sorry Bert in order to make sure we have a user interface then we can
see what's going on.
So in here we have an empty controller and that's good because we're going to need a sign in sign up
view controller as you have seen in the previous lectures.
Right.
We're going to use this we have controller for that reason we're going to have our sign up and sign
in.
But also I want to have a tap bar and some we have controllers connect to that tap bar as well.
So remember we could have chosen that when we first create the project but we got we have gone for single
leave up anyway and now we're going to manually import this and in order to do that if you search for
tap bar here you will see something called Tap Bar controller if and if you drag and drop this and it's
quite large as you can see it will drag and drop.
So let me just take this view controller and take it to the right side.
So here you see a tab bar controller and two we have controllers connected to that tab bar.
So you see these item one and item two here.
So this is for item 1 and this is for item 2 If we click on the item want first will we.
Controller will open if we click on the item to the second view controller will open.
So this is kind of cool.
This is very easy to work with.
We have this tab bar controller and we have two we have controllers connected to that tab bar and we
can actually add tab bars until 5:00 we have controllers.
OK.
And then the first tab bar I'm going to use a feed view controller and in the second one I'm going to
use a upload we have controller.
So here I'm going to have a sign and sign up.
We have controller I'm going to ask for the user e-mail and the password.
I'm going to have a two buttons and I'm going to of course do I say go away from here to that tab bar
controller so later on when and when a user signs in.
We will take them to their feet.
So in order to do that let me do the Segway here.
If I say show Segway as you can see this is not we expect we're going to take care of this just hit
on Segway and you see this is kind of a show Segway without navigation controller.
OK.
So this is kind of a pop over over here but I don't want that.
And in this case I don't want a navigation controller as well because I don't want to go back to my
sign in.
Once I signed in you shouldn't take back take the user back to the signing we have controller unless
they log out OK so we don't want navigation controller but we don't want that Pop.
Our feature as well until we have to change our Segway type this time.
So far we have only been working with show say grace and we have dealt with this kind of problem with
navigation controllers.
But if you click on the Segway and go to the identity Inspector you can see the other selections as
well.
For example let me choose one by one.
If I say show detail for example nothing will change.
So let me go to another one like presents model.
So that is the one that we were looking for but I'm going to show you later and this is present as pop
over.
And this is not we want actually.
And then here we have some deprecated ones of course we are not going to use them.
So if you go to present Maudsley you can see the presentation and you can see this.
What we want is the presentation.
If you go to automatic or full screen you will see we want this full screen as you can see we don't
see a pop over here anymore.
So this is exactly what we want.
If you go to if you go to automatic this will be the default one and you can actually try and see the
other ones as well.
But in most of the cases we want to go go to full screen OK so let's choose full screen.
And here you go.
And we are changing the presentation not the one below it.
OK so presentation full screen.
So this is not a show Segway present model the Segway.
And we are doing a full screen presentation and of course we have to have an identifier as well.
So I'm going to call this to feed view controller.
OK.
So if you click on this item over here OK if you E You can change the item one to feed for example and
you can change the icon as well.
Right now we only have some kind of square.
I can hear and you can choose whatever you want from this image if you want to import an image you can
choose that one as well.
For example I'm going to choose the F icon.
OK.
Four feet and indie item two.
I'm going to go for upload and I'm going to look for you circle.
Ok so now I have a good tab bar in here with feed and upload and I have my Segway.
So next thing will be to bring in the buttons and tax fields in my signing we've controller.
OK.
So we're going to have two buttons in here one for signing in the other one for signing up.
Signing up means registering for a new account.
OK.
So let me change this to sign in and this is for you accounts that have that have been created before.
And this one is going to be signed up.
So that's good.
We have our buttons.
Let me try to bring in the text field as well.
So first one will be the e-mail tax free.
OK.
This is where we're going to take the input from the user.
So let's say e-mail to here.
Now let me make this into a central way.
So let me put this into the center and copy and paste it.
The second round will be the password.
OK.
And that's it.
Actually let me just make this a little bit in line with each other.
Let me shake this down a little bit so that we can have a label as a title over the top like this.
So this is of course not mandatory.
I'm just doing this so that we would have a good looking sign in view controller and I'm going to name
this Instagram clone.
OK so you can name yours whatever you want.
And I'm going to increase the phones a little bit.
So here we go.
We have a good looking signing we've controller in which we will have to sign the user up or in.
So here you go.
Now let me give the suggested constraints here so that they will be sitting on the right place when
we open it up and the next thing will be to actually define all of these values in my view controller.
So let me go to buttons first.
First I'm going to drag and drop as an action and I'm going to call the sign in clicked.
And of course we're going to have a sign up clicked as well.
So let me bring in this one.
Sign up clicks and we're going to have to text fields here.
So first of which e-mail tax.
OK I'm going to call this e-mail text.
And the second one will be the password text so password text.
So here you go.
We're done with the sign in button and sign up by but then signing view controller user face in fact.
So in the sign and clicked let me perform a safe way for right now as an example.
OK.
To see if my tab bar is working.
I'm going to call this to feed we and sender will be Neal.
I'm going to run this so remember I have imported why you're basing my project and I have opened the
workspace project even though it got indexed it will still take a little bit time to build all of these
files for the first time after you do this once it will get much more faster it will just start like
it used to starts in general a examples like when you don't use Firebase but for right now we're going
to have to wait to build all of this file based modules so that we will have a working simulator.
And of course feel free to pause the video and come back when it's done so that we can see if our tap
bar is working in a way that we do we want it to.
OK.
By the way on the left hand side you see a lot of warnings and they're all in the firebase pops.
So when they're in the pods you don't have to worry about that.
And the yellow means warnings and red means errors if you get any error you won't even be able to run
your project on a simulator.
If you get a warning it just warns you to take care of possible future problems.
And if you're working with a pod you just don't have to worry about that.
So here you go.
We're good looking in here and if I hit on this sign in as you can see it doesn't pop over or anything
it just brings us to the tab bar in which we have two tabs first of which feed.
Second one is upload.
So when I click on this it just actually changes the view controller but we cannot see it because we
don't have anything in them.
But right now we know that this is working.
And of course we have some problems here like we don't have a logout type bar or we don't have a logout
button so we cannot go back to our design in we have control or even though if we wanted to we have
to add a new wave controller here we outside the need tab bar and then later on of course we re going
to have to check the user.
We're going to have to create the user and check to see if they're giving the right credentials.
Only then we're going to perform the Segway and let them in.
Let's do these in the next lecture.