Hi.
We didn't this lecture re going to add a new wave controller to our tab bar because we have to have
a low got functionality as well.
And we're going to connect this view controllers to a Coco touch class.
Okay so far we have our feed we have controller and upload.
We have controller but we don't have their Coco touch classes.
And in addition to that we're going to have to have a turd tab bar.
We have controller as well.
So let me open the library and bring in one controller.
So this is going to be a regular controller so that you can drag and drop to anywhere in your story
board.
So let me take this to the below and a line them and then we going to how to have I say way from our
tab bar we have controller tab bar controller I mean to the need we have controller and in here don't
select show Segway because that's not what you want.
So what do we want in order to understand that let me click one of these same ways that connect tab
bar controller to our view controllers.
If you go to properties you will see that this is a relationship Segway.
So we haven't seen it before.
So a relationship Segway actually creates a relationship between a tab bar controller and the wheel
controller connecting to it.
So let me do it one more time and select relationship Segway.
So now as you can see this is connected and we see the third item here as well.
So if I go to item here OK I can change the title as I want like as settings we have controller and
for the icon of course we can go for s icon here as we did before.
So let me see where is the S I can.
Yeah I can not seem to find it.
Yeah.
Here.
Yeah I can find it s circle.
OK.
That's what I want.
And now wi fi zoom in you will see that settings is here with an S I can.
So this is perfect.
This is what I wanted but now I have to create the cocoa teach classes as well.
So let me click here and right click and see a new file.
Of course we are going to go for cocoa touch class and this is going to be a UI weave controller.
OK.
So the first thing I'm going to call feed we have controller.
So this will be my weave controller feed we have controllers cocoa touch class I'm going to say next
and create in my in cyclone five your base project.
And here we go we have our wheat feed we have controller.
Let's do the second one as well.
Let's add another cocoa to each class.
And this time I'm going to call those upload we have controller.
OK.
So this will be the upload we have controller and say create.
And for the third time I'm going to go and do the same thing.
Cocoa touch class and this time I'm going to call the settings wi controller.
And in fact in the settings we have controller we're only gonna have the logout functionality but I'm
doing this for an example so I believe that's OK.
So let me put all of this in the upper site so that we can see all we have controllers in one place
and the next thing I'm going to go to my storyboard to open it as a source.
So remember this I have this bug when I add a new wave controller my application fails my application
crashes if I don't change the values from this source if you don't come across this kind of a bug in
your X code then just don't do this step.
Okay but in case you have in case you experience this problem I'm showing you how to do that.
And again if you don't come across this problem if you open your app without crashing it when you add
a new controller just don't do it.
So here as you can see my regular old view controller I have five attributes like custom class custom
module custom module provider.
But in the other way controllers there are added by me manually I don't have those items so I have to
copy and paste this custom class custom module and custom module provider so that I won't get an interface
failed.
Error when I run this app.
So let me copy this and go back to the feed we have controller for example and paces in here.
OK.
Again if you don't have this problem then just watch and see how this is getting the result but don't
apply it because in the exam we're seeing an exam out cold right now.
It's likely to make a mistake.
OK I'm copying and pasting the view controller missing attributes to all you controllers so that I can
resolve this buck and we have seen this before so I'm not going to go into the details and I'm going
to go back to interface builder.
So this is very you can continue if you don't have this problem in your ex coat.
So right now in order to see if it's working I have to define some variables here so let me create my
button in my settings view controller OK.
So let me make this a little bit bigger and change the name to log out.
I'm going to connect this logout button to my settings view controller cocoa touch glass in order to
that I'm going to select settings and come to this identity inspector and this is not going to be a
weave controller but it's going to be a settings weave controller and it doesn't show up here.
So I suspect there's something going on still even though we have corrected everything.
And if you click on this little button it will take us to the settings we controller.
At least it seems to be working when we write it manually by.
But I still suspect there is something wrong.
So let me write upload view controller here manually.
OK.
That's OK.
And let's go to feed.
We have controller identity Inspector.
And let's say that this is feed we have controller.
OK so that's cool.
I believe we are ready to connect this logout button to the settings we have controller cocoa touch
glass so open a new assistant editor.
And in here drag and drop the logout button with control and define it as an action and say logout clicked.
Yeah it seems fine.
Yeah it seems to be working so we're going to test this.
OK.
As you can see this is not connected to settings wi controller and I believe we're OK.
So let me give you some constraints to the logout button as well.
OK.
And we're done actually.
So in the low gobs clicked I'm just going to perform a Segway for right now.
Later on we're going to have to implement a logout function as well.
But I don't have the Segway right because I didn't create any Segway between settings with a controller
and our initial weave controller.
So let's do that.
Let's drag and drop from settings to our view controller signing we've controller and say show.
And when I say show it's displaying this as a pop over issue.
I'm going to change this to be present model.
So let me choose the Segway.
OK.
So present mildly and again in here I'm going to go for a full screen so it makes everything right.
And I'm going to say that this is to weave controller.
So here you go.
We are ready to test is performed Segway.
So let me go to two view controller in here and center will be nil.
So let's test to see if everything seems to be all right.
Because we have changed the exam code even though if you didn't do it you have to test us and see if
this works because we added a new tab bar controller.
So let's see the initial we have.
Controller.
Yes.
That's good.
And when I hit sign in it sucks it gets sucked and I believe we crashed the application for some reason.
Let's wait for the error message in here we don't have any error message.
But we see the black screen.
And if you go to the lugs as you can see it doesn't see the image of you.
The settings view controller.
All the other way controllers that we have connected so far.
So this is the bug that I was talking about then we corrected that in the source code.
But I believe we have to do it again.
So let me open the source code and if we don't have this problem just don't bother with it.
I'm not cutting this on purpose because if you come across you have to know how to solve this.
This is not specific to I started in this has been going on for years.
I don't know why they couldn't figure it out yet but we sometimes get this bug in next code.
So as you can see in the view controller we have this custom class custom module and custom module provider.
So let me look below.
We don't have anything else.
So let me copy this custom module and custom module provider because as you can see the wheel controller
we're missing that.
OK.
The other in the other we have controllers we are missing that for example in the feed we have controller.
We don't have that so I'm going to paste it in and in the settings of your controller we don't have
them as well as you can see and in the upload view controller we don't have them at all.
So let me paste it up.
So let me say this and let me go to interface builder one more time and we're going to have to test
this one more time.
But before we do that before you test is before you run this in your simulator make sure that before
you hit the sign in bottom go to your tab bar controller.
OK.
This one I mean not that we have controllers but the actual tab bar controller after you copy and paste
examples.
This class can get confused in the identity Inspector make sure the class is not think OK.
It shouldn't be a controller or like there's a feed controller.
If you see any value in the tab bar controller class just delete it OK.
As you can see all other controllers are in place and this should be empty.
So if you see any value just delete it hit enter and then run your simulator one more time to make sure
everything's seemed to be in place.
So let me open my simulator and click on sign in and as you see now it's OK in the upload them feed.
We don't see anything by the fee go to settings.
We see the logout button.
And if I click on it.
Here you go.
I'm in this I need the view controller if I click on it again I can go to my feed view controller and
as I explained before I could have easily just pulled the video and fix the bugs myself without showing
you guys.
But maybe you come across this kind of problem you're not right now or maybe you will in the future
so you will have to know how to fix those problems.
So apologies for taking too long for adding just one meal controller to our tab our controller but that
is just what we had to do in order to learn this.
So we're going to stop here and within the next lecture we're going to see how to create users.