Hi within this lecture regrowing to take care of our problems by figuring out how to start this pulse
by date and starting to implement like function as VO in order to do that.
We are going to use a native method of Firebase so when we get this information from the five star database
we just add the snapshot listener.
So if you hit enter or we're here before we add the snapshot listener we gonna add in other methods
called that order.
OK.
This will enable us to order data in any way we want.
So if you say that order you will see that it will ask you for a field path or a string.
So if you give a date here OK you can specify whether it's going to be a descending or ascending.
OK.
So we want this one at descending boolean by field path.
OK so I'm going to say data here and for descending it's going to be true for me.
So it's going to take the data and it's going to order all of these posts by descending structure so
that I will see every passed by descending order regarding to day or dates.
So let's test this and let's see if we can get the last supper in the first position when we run this.
OK.
You remember this is the last post that we have posted and here you go.
Now we see all of this posts in order by day or date.
So let me try this.
Let me add another one.
OK.
Let me choose starry nights this time and for comments I'm going to say.
Let's say one go or test.
I don't know let's say one go ok and hit the upload button it will upload this and download then in
the feed and as you can see we see the one go in the first position.
So our Instagram clone actually works at this point.
So these dots are their works.
So this is how you order your queries.
This is how you order when you try to retrieve information from the database.
And we re going to have to filter the results as well.
And in order to do that we are going to implement like function.
OK.
In order to learn that actually in the like button clicked.
Now we're just going to print like button clicked and you will see whenever we tap one of the like bundles
it will print out this statement in the logs.
OK.
So we're we will be certain that this works.
So you can just click one of the like buttons here as you can see in the logs like button click appears.
So let's try this one as well as you can see wherever retype wherever we hit on the like button it just
prints out in the logs.
So what do we want to do in the light by them.
When we tap on that we want to increase this likes.
Okay.
By one and then upload the net value to the server.
So we're going to see how we can filter our results just by the roulette related posts.
OK.
So if I click on this post I just want to take this like value from here or I just want to upload to
it is like well not the other post.
OK.
And it's also I want to not touch the other values from here I just want to update the likes.
So we're going to see how to do that.
And this is important information because if you don't know what you're doing you may end up by uploading
likes a value to the all of the posts or you can delete everything in a post by mistake.
So we're going to see how to do that properly working with some other methods of firebase.
So let's see how we can do it.
Let's go into the light by them.
OK.
And in here we're getting all of this information and we're getting the like array and we're getting
this document I.D. as well but we're not using this document I.D. We didn't save this document I.D.
into any area yet.
So let's do that because we will need that document I.D. in order to differentiate posts from each other.
We have to know how to get the current passed.
So I'm going to use a technique in order to do that.
I'm going to add another label here and assign my document I.D. area to that label so that I can reach
that value inside of my feed cell as well.
Because that's where I want to write my like function inside of my feed so OK you will see what I mean.
Let me just write this.
So this is going to be a document idea array and this is going to be a string array.
And in here I'm going to remove all the values to prevent duplicating.
OK.
And in here in the for loop I'm going to appoint this document I.D. to my document ideally.
So far so good.
You know how to do this.
But now let me add this.
Now I have to reach this document I.D. from the feed cell.
So that's the trick.
So it gives me an error because I misspelled it.
Yes.
This one I want this one.
So inside of freed cell how can I reach the related document I.D. I don't have an index path in my feed
cell.
So how can I know which a user tapped on which picture.
OK.
Which passed.
So I'm going to add a hidden label in here.
OK so that I can reach from the feed cell user won't be able to see that label but we know the document
I.D. label is there.
So I can get the current value from the document I.D..
This is a technique that you can use of course you can come up with another solution as well.
But I believe this is the easiest one.
So let me show you how it goes.
So you had to bring in a label.
You can put it wherever you want because it's going to be hidden.
If you go to properties here DIY property inspector OK you can check this hidden box and it will be
hidden from the user.
So let me add the missing constraints as well.
And in fact it doesn't matter if I add the constraints or not but it's good to add this because we will
be getting errors if we don't do it.
So let me bring in this label to my feet so.
So let's say that this is document I.D. label OK document I.D. label so let's connect this.
So now I have this label.
Let's go back to our feed we have controller not feed your controller feed Sal actually in here rather
than printing out now I'm going to increase the like label by 1 and create a post create a like post
like a firebase post ok for your store pulse and upload the current value to the five your base of course
in the South for a row at index parts we have to say Soledad document I.D. label zip code to document
array in order to do that.
I'm going to do a comment B to synchronize everything.
So when I say Sal dot it will see the documents I.D. label as well.
So this one Yep document I.D. label dot text is actually document I.D. array index path Doctorow.
So all the values will be assigned to this label and we will see the texts in here.
Actually we're not going to see them because it's hidden user will not be able to see those but we will
be able to get those information using that label inside of our feet so.
So let's stop here and within the next picture we're going to continue implementing our like feature.