Hi.
We didn't this lecture regrowing to finish our like function.
We going to use this like label and document I.D. label in order to get related information for our
like function.
So all we have to do is just increase dislikes by one and upload devalue to the server in order to do
that.
Of course we are going to import firebase in the feed cell as well.
OK.
And in the Like button clicked function I'm going to call this fi your store database like we did before.
So it will drive from the fire store that fire store.
OK.
This is going to be our instance.
And now I can come over here and say fi your store database that's collection.
OK.
And collection will be passed.
And if I say that document it will ask me for a document path.
So now if I get one off the document I.D. like this one.
Okay.
And if I put that document I.D. in here whatever I do next will be related to only these documents.
So if I work within this document if I try to upload any value it will be only uploaded to that document
only.
So that's how you filter.
That's how you limit your operations.
And in order to get this.
Of course I'm going to use the document I.D. label that I have just created.
So as you can see we can do document I.D. label dot text.
Now if I say something like that said data or get data it will only bring the current values of that
document or it will only upload data inside of that document.
So before we do that I'm going to take the like count and I'm going to do this with an if left because
we're trying to convert something into an integer.
So you will have to say int like label dot text.
And this will bring us the current like count.
OK so let me cut this and paste the inside of this if let and inside of this if let's we have the current
like count right.
And we want to increase it by 1 and save it inside of our file use star database in order to do that.
Of course we have to come up with a string to any dictionary like we did before.
Even though we are going to upload only one value it asks us to create a string to any dictionary and
that's what we're going to do in here.
So let let's call this something like like post our like Star or I don't know like dictionary whatever
you want and it will have the likes as key.
Okay.
And for the value we going to have to use like count but we will increase like count by 1.
So it will be like count plus 1 and we have to convert this as string to any.
So this is good right.
We're casting this as a string to any dictionary and we're going to set this to be a data inside of
a word.
These fires star documents if you say set data you have to find the option that has the merge parameter.
So merge means we're uploading this like star like dictionary.
OK but we're merging with the existing values.
So we're going to update the likes but we're not touching the post comment dates image you're out.
If you don't do this if you don't say merge it will just delete the other values other than likes and
you will end up with a broken past broken document inside of your database so make sure you say merge
true and this is how you update the database value without breaking the other values inside of your
file your base file your store.
So let's try this.
Let's open our simulator and let's see if we can like this picture.
So as you can see the current like zero if I hit like it will increase it to 1.
And as you can see changed.
So in here I see the likes as one as well.
So it's working right.
I can like this picture I can like this picture as well.
And let's try the last one.
So here you go.
Our like function is in place.
So of course we have a kind of let down in here if I hit like more than once it will just like it more
than once.
And even though we are same user in here.
Okay.
We are the past owner and we your liking of our own picture we get to like as many as we want.
Of course there are alternative ways to implement like function like we can create another collection
like something like likes OK and inside of that like function we can store which user liked Veatch document.
OK so we can keep track and we can say that if this user has like this document before then don't increase
the count so we can have that kind of controls in real apps but I'm just implementing this like function
as an example to show you how to use updates how to use document I.D. and how to use merge so that you
know how to work with file your base.
Once you learn how to work with file you saw you can do whatever you want.
You may have more than 10 collections you may have more than 2000 documents maybe you may have a complex
structure but right now we to do what we have to do to understand how to use fire your base.
So let me create another user here to test if everything works fine.
So let me try to like this pass by James.
As you can see it still works.
So our app can work with multiple users as it's supposed to and we can see and like the other users
posts as well.
So if you want to follow our collection here for example you may have one and you can actually save
the information who is following Q so that you can only adds a filter when you try to retrieve information
from fire bays and they can only see the pictures of the users they are following.
Okay so for example let me upload a new picture in here and this will be seen by Lars and James and
all other users in our app.
So if you want to implement the follower you can do that with firebase if you want to implement a better
like feature you can do that with firebase base.
If you understand how this works you can do whatever you want to do with your app.
So this is a very powerful tool.
I'm sure you will understand it better than we do other clones as well so make sure you keep up with
the cars and try to implement this features on your own while following this.
So let's stop here and talk about security in the next lecture.