High within the section we're going to learn how to implement push notifications in other apps in order
to do that.
I'm going to use the Instagram clone that we have made in the previous section because it's so convenient.
We have a like functionality over here and then we hit on like we want to display a push notification
to the Post owner so that Post owner will see a push notification in his or in her phone saying that
somebody liked your post.
For example if you're using this with James then if Kirk likes James Post James will see a push notification
indicating that Kirk has liked your post so that when James hits on that push notification it will open
his app and we will have a complete push notification solution in our Instagram clone.
Of course you can try this with another app or you can create an app just to try this as well.
But this is so convenient so I'm going to go with this.
We don't even need Instagram or we don't even need firebase in order to make this work.
But anyway I'm going to use this as an example so if you haven't watched the Instagram clone section
I really suggest you go back and watch this to understand how this works.
And second thing in order to test push notifications you have to have an iPhone device and you have
to have a developer account.
So in order to upload your apps to the App Store and in order to test some features like push notifications
you have to have a developer account and it costs a hundred dollars annually.
So if you're not ready to put your app on the App Store or if you don't want to try and test push notifications
maybe you don't want that.
But if you're ready and if you really want to implement this in your app then I suggest you come over
here to developer dot apple dot com and under a counter you can create your own developer accounts.
OK.
Again it costs a hundred bucks.
So it's kind of expensive but if you're going to be an iPhone developer you will need one.
Of course if you're working for a company you can use your own company's Apple I.D. as well.
So this is how we go to developer dot apple dot com and just sign in our developer account.
Once you hit the account tab it will ask you for your Apple I.D. and password.
You can just give these credentials and open this dashboards where we will adjust our push notification
settings.
OK.
And again if you don't want to test this but if you want to learn how push notifications work you can
actually watch this section to understand how this push notifications is implemented.
But you cannot test it without an apple developer account.
So first of all I'm going to show you what we will use in order to implement push notifications.
And the tool that we're going to use is called One signal.
OK.
So if you come to one signal dot com.
So this is a platform.
This is a tool that actually gives you a tool to use for free.
And you can just send as many as push notifications you want from your apps using this one signal.
So this is a great tool and big companies use this tool and it's completely free.
So why not we use it.
Right.
So we can use this with IRS apps we can use this with Android apps and we can even use this with that
push notifications as well.
So if you're building an app that works on some other platforms than does one signal will be the choice
for you.
And I'm going to show you how to work with this tool how to set this up and how to do all procedures
in order to get this work.
Don't worry.
So after you come to your one signal dot com you have to create an account which is fairly easy.
So come over here and find log in or sign up.
OK.
So I have an account so I'm going to log in.
But in your case you have to click on the sign up and provide some email address some password and your
name or your company's name and just hit create a count and after you sign up you can just come over
here to sign it.
And as you can see it says that no credit card required.
It's completely free.
So let me log in from here.
And as you can see I'm already logged in and I can see all my applications in those lists.
So I have some test applications over here and I can add a new one and I can delete the existing ones
or I can adjust the existing settings.
So let me add a new app and in our case our app will be called instead glorify your base.
OK.
Once I add this app it will ask me to do some configurations.
And we're going to start with choosing our platform.
So as you can see it works on a lot of platforms and of course we are interested in Apple I guess at
this point.
So I'm going to go for a polite U.S. but in any case if you're working with other platforms you're more
than welcome to do it later on.
So once I choose the Apple II OS it will ask me to configure this platform and it will ask me to create
a p twelve file.
So this is a production certificate for push notifications.
OK.
So we have to create this file first and in order to create this file we need a developer account.
So that's why we need a developer account.
So I'm going to show you how this works.
So if you can come over here to read the documentation you can follow along the documentation and guides
as well in order to create yours.
I'm going to open it anyway and I'm going to show you how to do it manually as well.
So you have to go to your developer account and open it first of all and come back here to read the
documentation as you can see they have an automatic provisioning to Lesotho.
So if you give your apple IDM password over here it can create all these things for you but I'm not
going to do that.
I'm just going to do it manually in case it fails or in case if you don't want to give your credentials
to one signal.
So I'm going to show you how to do that manually because if you do it manually it will work in every
case.
OK.
So first of all we're going to need something called and Certificate Authority it's actually called
as he has are it certs kids signing request.
OK.
So in order to do that we have to access something called Keychain Access.
And we have to come over to this menu and say you request a certificate from a certificate authority
so maybe you have never worked with Keychain Access before.
It's kind of a tool that we store every password every search could in our Mac books in order to reach
that.
You have to hit command and space in your keyboard and write key chain access.
So that's the one that we are looking for.
So let me minimize this and let me just move this a little bit further.
So here we see all the logging related things in our mac book.
OK.
I remember we have to request a certificate from a certificate authority.
So if you come over here to certify get assistant you will see some different main your here so it's
not saying request a certificate from authority.
It says that request a search for good with your user name.
So if you see something like that you have to click something else rather than all items or log in.
OK.
So try to click on system or system routes for example as you can see it still doesn't work.
But if I click over here to system routes and let's try it one more time come over here to key chain
access and certify get the system.
Now you will see request a search goods from a certificate authority.
OK.
That's what we want.
Now if I click on this it will ask me for my e-mail address and my name.
So over here you have to give your developer accounts e-mail address and your name or your organization
name and our here choose saved to disk.
OK.
So after doing that you will just continue and it will create this year are for you.
So search good a request.
That's what we need in order to create some short cuts later on.
So after you do that you can just close this down and go back to your developer account.
OK so in the documentation it explains how to do that actually.
And over here as you can see there are some other things to do in the developer account.
I need a actually explains all of them but I'm going to show you anyway first of all we need to come
to this sort of goods identifiers and profiles.
Over here we will see the identifiers so this is why we register our app.
It's kind of registering your bundle I.D. to your developer account.
And as you can see it says that do not enable push notifications in that face.
I'm going to show you how to enable push notifications later on.
Don't worry.
So come over here to identifiers as you can see our app is not listed over here and we need its bundle
I.D. in order to register it.
So come over here to general and try to copy this bundle identifier.
OK.
So let me go back and let me see if we have this over here.
Nope we don't have it.
So then we have to bring in manually OK all we have to do is just come over here to plus sign and hit
the plus side to create our new Bundle identifier.
So let me hit over here and as you can see it asks for some options and we need of an app I.D..
OK.
So we have other kind of IDs as well but we need to register our app so I'm choosing app I.D. And over
here we need to give this bundle I.D. that we have copied.
So let me copy it one more time just to be sure gave it command seat and let me bring this down and
paste it over here with comment V.
And here you have to write a description for your app.
I'm just going to name this is clone five your base as it is.
OK.
And then later on we see this capabilities over here as shown in the documentation.
I'm not going to enable this at this phase but later on I'm just going to enable those inside of X coat.
So once you give that you can just come over here to this menu and register your app it means that your
bundle I.D. is registered to your developer account.
So now you can see instead glorify your base in that list.
So far so good.
Now we have registered our app.
And if I hit on that I can't see it.
I can't remove it.
I can just see the bundle I.D. and other app I.D. profile numbers and everything.
OK.
So as shown in the documentation I'm going to come over here and say push notifications is enabled but
I'm not going to configure it because we're going to do that inside of X code as I've said before as
shown here.
You have to enable this but not configure it.
OK.
So next thing would be to create a new search.
That's what we're looking for actually.
And we're going to do that in the developer account as well.
So I'm going to show you where this but as you can see it's under services an apple push notification
service SSL.
So let me go back to my developer account after enabling this but not configuring it.
Let me confirm this.
Save this and just go out of this identify your section because let me check if it's enabled.
Yep.
It's enabled.
OK.
It saved.
So let me go back and create our certificate.
So in here we're going to go for certain tickets and our here is just going to add a new certificate.
OK.
As you can see I you see my existing search goods but we're looking for a new Apple push notification
serve as an API and as SSL certificate.
OK.
So we're looking for that.
So come over here and hit the plus button and over here we will see something like services.
And under these services we have some options.
You will see a U.S. Apple push notification service and you will see Apple push notification service
SSL.
So we need Apple push notification service as described in the documentation.
OK because this is for production.
So let me come over here and you will see to select Apple push notification service SSL.
So after choosing that you can just continue and create your certificate.
It will ask you for an identifier.
And since we have registered our app we can easily choose that identifier.
So let me choose is the clone file your base OK so yep I believe that's it.
After choosing my app I can register I can create a certificate just for that app.
So it it asks me to provide a CSR in this step as you can see that's why we have created this CSR in
the first place.
So since now I have that I'm going to say choose file and I'm going to go over to my desktop where I
can find the CSR and just choose it.
So this will actually provide the proof that I'm really the developer that is trying to sign this up.
After that you can just download your search kit and as you can see now we have this dot c e r file.
So this is our search.
OK.
And let me go back to documentation because we have a lot more things to do after downloading this.
As you can see we have to bring this in to the key chain and then we have to create a provisioning file
which we will upload to the one signal.
So let me show you how this goes.
Let me open keychain access one more time and over here under my certificates I'm going to bring in
the certificate that I have created.
OK so let me bring this down a little bit.
Let me go to log in and my search.
So choose log in form key chains and in the category choose your certificates.
OK so that you can see all the certificates related to you and your apps.
After that we have to bring in the newly created search kit and say export apple production push services.
So let me try to do that.
We are going to need our newly brought in CRM.
So if you double click on that C.R. It will appear in here.
So if you cannot see it over there you can just double click or you can bring this in manually.
So let me try to do that.
So if I double click on this it will be displayed in the key chain or I can just bring this in like
dragging and dropping as you can see.
Now let's see which one I believe that's the one that we are looking for Yep instead glorify your base.
So not right now I can't come over here and right click and say export Apple push services and it will
create a p twelve file for me.
So I'm going to name this my inside column.
And as you can see this is P. twelve and that's the one we were looking for all the way along.
Right.
So now I can just say this and I can just upload this to the one signal I'm going to save this on my
desktop so that we can each add three easily and it will ask me for a password and we're going to use
that password later on.
So make sure you remember what password you're giving right now because one signal will ask us to provide
that password.
OK once you do that you can just hit on.
OK.
To create this and let's say OK and then it will ask you for your key chain access expert key.
So this is the password for your own computer.
So let me write my passwords.
Okay so this is the password for my old MacBook.
If I say hello we will create these certificates for me.
So here you go.
Now I have created my p twelve file so now I can go over to my one signal configuration and I can just
upload this production certs get over here.
So let me choose that file okay.
And let me go to my desktop.
Yep that's the one that we are looking for.
So when we upload this it will ask us to provide the password that we have just given.
And if you don't remember your password you have to do all of those things from scratch.
So make sure you take note of your password.
Okay.
And after you provide this password you can just say Save and move along with your configuration.
So this has been a long lecture.
Let's stop here and do the rest of the things in the next lecture.