Hi we didn't this lecture we going to see how we can send a push notification from X code.
Now we know how to send one from this dashboard.
Right.
Manually but we going to do it automatically so that we can learn how to send it to X code with code
so that we can send a push notification when somebody like some posts.
So let me come over here to documentation and show you how it's done.
So it's sending push messages but it shows me how we can send that to the dashboard.
Right.
So we have already done this so we don't need this documentation at this point what we need is ice native
documentation so that we can see all the SDK related codes.
So let me come over here and as you can see there is a section called How do I send a notification to
a single user.
So that's what we need.
We're going to send a notification to only one user.
So whenever Kirk likes the post of James or James likes the care posts of Kirk then the other one will
get a push notification.
Okay.
So that's what we need.
And don't worry if you cannot find this documentation I'm going to show you how to do it anyway.
But it's a nice thing to read the documentation and see the other modules as well.
So what we're going to do we're going to take this play your idea and we're going to send only one notification
to that specific play your I.D..
OK.
As you can see it says that the eye you have to use this method called include play your I.D. and you
have to include that specific player I.D. that you want.
So if you come over here to user user messages or transactional messages guides you can find what you're
looking for.
So I'm going to go over to user user messages.
So there are two steps actually first we have together the player I.D. then we have to send the message
to that player I.D. And we know how to get display your I.D. right now from dashboard but that's not
what we want.
We have to get that from the access code itself so that we wouldn't go over here every time someone
is trying to send a push notification.
OK.
So I'm going to open this mobile SDK reference and I'm going into the IRS native SDK so that we can
learn how together it is play your I.D. and how to send a push notification using that player I.D..
So this is a U.S. native as the Kay documentation.
OK so what I'm looking for is to send a push notification and I believe it's under here somewhere.
So let me search for it.
So let me come over here.
Yep.
This is sending notifications.
So if I click on that it will take me to this post notification method and that is exactly what we are
looking for post notification.
OK.
So it's really easy method.
So you can easily send a push notification as you can see it says that you have to call 1 signal that
post notification and then you create the content and then you include the player I.D. that you want.
So I'm going to cope with this one I'm going to come over here.
OK so let me come over here to my iPhone X R because I'm sending this not to my iPhone sir but I'm just
sending this to my iPhone but I can use a simulator to send it to my iPhone.
OK.
Even though simulators do not actually support push notifications we can still send one right.
We are not receiving push notifications in the simulators but we can send some push notifications using
simulators anyway.
So what I'm about to do I'm just going to put that code that we have copied into my X code I'm going
to run this using my simulator so I'm going to delete the existing is the clone firebase from here so
that it would ask me if I want to receive notifications and I will allow it even though I won't be able
to receive one.
I will be able to send one.
So let me come over here to my feed.
We have controller because that's the controller that we will see when it first loads.
So under we did load.
I'm going to try this code.
OK.
So I'm going to say post notification or push notification.
As comment.
So let me say push notification and I'm going to paste it in.
So in order to do that I'm going to import the one signal over here as well.
So once it's done let me come over here and see how it's done.
Now let me paste this code in.
So in this code I have to specify the content and test messages.
OK for me right now but I'm going to change this so that I can try to send my push notification to my
iPhone.
OK so let me paste as in so that will send a push notification called text message to my iPhone when
my iPhone X are loads.
So let me run this.
And also on it that at the same time I have to open my real iPhone as well so that I can see if I get
the message or not.
And once we open the simulator it will ask us to give permission for push notifications.
I'm going to love it but we won't be able to receive any notifications.
And I believe you're logged in with Kirk but I'm going to make sure that you're logged in with Kirk
anyway.
So I'm going to say Kirk adds Metallica dot com and give some passwords that we have created before
I believe it was 1 2 3 4 5 6 and sign in.
Here we go now we're logged in with Kirk now wi fi come over here on refresh this page I will see my
simulator over here subscribe.
But as you can see it says that even though it has a player I.D. It says that I Os simulator unsupported
so we cannot receive any notification using this simulator but we can send one as I said before.
So what I'm going to do I'm going to open this.
OK.
So let me run this one more time to see if you're really logged in with Kirk and it will just run this
one signal code.
OK.
And once it's done I will receive a push notification in my real life form.
And here you go.
Now I received that push notification as you can see if I tap on it it will direct me to my app.
So here you go.
That's how we actually send push notifications eastside of X code.
So what we have to do right now is to find out how we can gather the player I.D. so that we can send
the push notification of whenever we want to whichever device we want.
So let's do that in the next lecture.