Hi we within this lecture regarding to add an if statement to our player I.D. saving function so that
we won't create a duplicate its value of this James said Metallica dot com.
When we run this Instagram clone from scratch.
OK so we have to check if this play your idea exists in our five your store.
Right.
So let me bring in this fire store to our we've added loads and I believe we have this fire store over
here so let me do that over here so that we can use the same fire store in the get data from fire store
function and in d we did load.
So let me run this over here and rather than creating new fires stores we're just going to call this
5 years store database.
OK and down below.
It still works because we can easily reach the a variable that we have just created.
Right.
So over here I'm going to use fire star database and before we go on we have to do a query over here
and say Play your I.D. So we have to get these play your idea of the current logged in user.
So at this point we have to choose between adding this snapshot listener or getting the document for
once.
I'm just going to get the document because I don't need to add the snapshot listener because there won't
be any changes during we use this app.
Right.
So I'm going to say gets documents and it will only give me the related document just for once and that's
what we need.
And over here I'm going to filter the result before I say get document.
So I'm going to use a I feel like we did in the previous section and I'm going to say Email is the current
user's email.
OK so remember it asks I have fields for us and I'm going to provide email over here.
And the value will be the current email.
So I'm going to get this from all that of that current user and I'm going to force our app this and
say email.
So this collection will return the documents related to the current email that we have over here.
So I'm going to call this snapshot and I'm going to call this error and if error is nil I'm just going
to go for is nil this time rather than is not nil.
Of course it's your call you can go for is not nil and display an error message to the user as well.
But I'm going to keep things simple and we will get a snapshot over here so you can check to see if
snapshot is empty is false or you can check to see if snapshot is not Bill because we're going to do
what we have been doing over here.
So we will go into a for loop after we say snapshot that documents.
So I believe it's best to check to see if snapshots dot is empty is false so that we will be much safer.
So we're here we can come and save for document in and I believe I have forgotten to add the snapshot
is not new.
Yep.
So let me add this one as well so snapshot is not nil.
And then I can safely come over here and say four documents in snapshot documents.
OK.
And I will force wrap this when I do that.
So can I come over here as a snapshot but documents.
Yep.
I can say that but once I do that it will ask me to make it optional or for shoring up this so I'm going
to force our wrap this.
That's why I'm doing all this checks.
So I'm going to say for a document in snapshot that documents.
OK.
And as you can see it makes it optional but I'm not going to make it optional I'm going to force I'll
wrap this.
And over here we need a value right.
We can get this out of our document and we need the player I.D. So remember before we were working with
areas and getting all of these different values but design we don't need those we only need the one
values.
I'm going to say document that gets and the field that I'm looking for is the play your I.D..
So that's the one.
Yep.
So it will give me the player I.D. And I'm going to say if let the name player I.D. OK display your
I.D. I think is can be casted as string as optional string if that's the case it means that I have a
previously created play your I.D. So if that's the case.
OK so let me call display your I.D. from firebase so we won't get confused because we already have a
player I.D. over here.
So player I.D. from fi your base if this exists then I don't need to create a new one right because
I already have one so I can check to see if they are equal or not.
So let me just print this out and let me just test if we can get this.
So let me say play your I.D. from fire base.
OK.
And I'm going to say play your I.D..
Player I.D. from 5 your base and later on if we want to do a merger if you want to update the current
documents we will need the document idea as well.
So let me created for any case so I will call this document I.D. and it will be document that document
I.D..
OK.
So remember that's how we get document I.D..
So let me run this on my simulator to see if we can get the player I.D. of the current logged in user
from firebase.
Of course we're doing all of those things like play your I.D. dictionary and saving IDs to define your
base again.
So it will be a little bit complicated.
It will save the same thing in the fire store one more time.
But we're going to take care of that anyway.
So as you can see we can get the player I.D. from Firebase and we are getting it twice because we have
this data twice.
Now of course we have to take care of this problem.
So what I want to do.
Let me just cut this from here.
OK.
And under if let's let me paces over here rather than printing this out I'm going to check to see if
the player I.D. If the current player I.D. is equal that this player I.D. from firebase.
OK.
So that's what I'm going to do.
If they're equal then I don't need to do anything else.
So let me say play eve play your I.D. and I'm trying to refer to that play your I.D. but I believe we
have to use play your new I.D. because that is not an optional string.
So if player new I.D. OK is equal to play your I.D. from five year base then it means that we have the
same I.D. in the firebase already.
So we don't have to do anything over here.
Right.
If that's they're not equal then we have to save this.
Then let me cut everything from here OK and paste the play your knee why these things on there over
here.
So this will create the Navy dictionary for me.
And if they do not have the same value then I'm going to upload it.
So let me check.
Yep.
This is getting the current user e-mail and this is getting the player I.D. from firebase if they are
not equal.
We are just uploading them to the fire sir.
And in here I believe we have to say self-taught fire star database in order to refer to the fire star
database.
OK.
So that's good.
If they're not equal I'm going to upload the value.
So let me test is let me come over here and delete the duplicated values.
So let me delete one of the Turks and let me delete one of the James says well so that we will only
have one Kirk and one James says they will be equal it won't upload a new one to the fire base of Kersh
we can do this some alternative way as well.
For example if they are not equal.
But I suppose that the player I.D. has changed then we can do an update.
We can do a merger as well.
Right.
So let me test this.
And as you can see we don't have any data over here duplicated so it works.
But also we have to figure out a way if they're not equal but if we don't have any snapshot if we don't
have any data.
So what do we do.
Right.
Because this time we're going to go or to play your I.D. and we're doing this very fields in which we're
trying to figure out the current player I.D. of the user.
But if this snapshot does not exist if snapshot is empty it means that maybe this is the first time
this user is using this app.
Right.
And in this case we're not saving the player I.D. right now.
So we have to make sure to find the L statement of this if snapshot is empty statement.
OK.
And I believe that's the one.
Nope.
We have to open an aisle statement over here.
Yeah I believe this is the one.
Yes.
If snapshot is empty then we have to save this data to defy your story again.
Right.
Because we won't have the data in the fire store at this point.
So let me copy this one and paste the under L. says well not cut but copy and paste over here as well.
So this will just save the play your I.D. for the first time into the fire store.
Right.
So let me just make this right by leading this unnecessary indentation over here and here you go.
Now we're ready.
Of course we can improve and improve this algorithm as I said before we tend to emerge up in the first
US block and we can try to update the current value or we can delete the current value.
So here you go.
As you can see our algorithm is working since we have the player I.D. over here.
It won't say 1.
So let me delete the Kirk's I.D. and let me run it one more time to see if we get the Kirk's I.D. in
the fires sir.
And if that works out as well that it means that we have a complete algorithm.
So let me come over here to fire your store and here you go.
We really have the Kirk's play your I.D. saved in the fire store.
So that's it for right now.
I believe now we are ready to go into the like functionality and find the related player I.D. and send
a push notification to the liked post to the Post owner of the liked post actually.
So let's do that in the next lecture.