Hi within this section we going to create a Foursquare clone beat using pass instead of fire.
So let me show you how this looks.
As you can see there is a username and password text fields here and this is our sign up our sign in
page.
So if you give any user that you have created previously you can sign it.
Of course you can sign up as well.
So in the stable view we see the previously created places like a restaurant or a pub or a diner or
any place that you may want to add.
So if you click one of them you will see the image the name the type and some description of that the
restaurant doors or that place and in below we see the map and we see where it is located on the map
so that we can click on that place and we can navigate from our current place to that place.
This looks like our travel book but it works on cloud server.
So if we want to add another place from here we can do it by clicking on this ad buy them and we get
to choose a name like Rob Cafe.
OK.
So this will be a cafe and for example this will be a student Cafe.
If we can select a picture from here then we can click on Next to choose a place from our map.
OK.
So let me zoom in a little bit so that we can choose a place from here for example if I click over here
for three seconds then it will just add a location here and I can just save it and this will be saved
and displayed in my table view.
And again this works in cloud.
OK.
So this is not specific to my iPhone.
This is not with core data but now we are doing this with cloud server and for cloud server purposes
we use parts rather than fire base.
So in here as you can see we have our database we can access all the data's we can change anything that
we want.
We are going to see the differences between fiber based on past and we are going to understand why we
choose one on another.
And we are going to learn how to use parse and it's back end services in our apps.
So now if you're ready let's get started on build our Foursquare clone.