Hi.
Now that we know how to write data to pass server we have to figure out how to read data from the power
server as well.
Now we have only one row here with Apple and one hundred calories.
So I'm going to change this to have two data that please.
I'm going to go for banana and one hundred fifty.
So if we run this one more time then it will upload this data to the PA server so that if we go back
to here and say refresh.
Now we see the banana and 150 calories as well.
Now I have two rows here two data.
Now how can we retrieve that data.
Let me comment this out so that every time we run does it won't get uploaded to the database.
OK.
And we're going to do what we give to you in here.
So first of all in order to retrieve past objects we use something called Pass query.
OK so this is how it looks like.
So we're going to create a Curie here and this will be a P F Curie.
And as you can see this lets us retrieve data as P.F. objects from a class.
If you open parentheses it will ask you for a class name.
And in our case that's fruits.
So this has to be exactly the same.
So we that capitalized f we the uppercase at fruits.
OK then we're going to specify if we want any filter right now.
And I don't need any filter.
I just want to get all data.
In my case OK.
We're going to see how to filter the results later on if we see if we say something like that find.
We will see some kind of similar options that we have seen when we try to save objects.
If we select find objects it will do it sync erroneously.
If we do it in background we get one option with block and one option without block.
And of course if we want something with block because we get to see the results in a P.F. object array
if we do that or we get an error if there is any error.
OK.
And this is where objects in an array.
So we're going to have more than one objects in most of the cases and they will be given to us in an
array.
OK so if we do something like a for loop or any other operation that you might think of we can get these
objects by one by one.
OK.
So I'm going to call these objects and this one error of course I will check to see if error is not
nil and if areas not nil I'm just going to print out the error OK so that we can keep track or else
I will just print out the objects in most of the cases you may want to do a for loop here if you're
going to get something out of that object.
Individual objects but right now I just want to see if we can get these objects.
So let me run this in our simulator and it will get the objects imprinted in my luck.
So let me see.
Here we go we have the first class we have the Epsilon 100 calories and we how the banana with one hundred
and fifty calories off of course we have the additional columns as well like object I.D..
OK.
So that's good.
Now I can use something like for loop to get individual objects but let me show you how to filter the
results.
If you say dots there.
So this will ask you for a key and some condition something like If calories are actually equal to 100
or if calories are less than one 100 or if calories are greater than one hundred or you can go for name
of course like you can just say something like name being equal to Apple.
Now if we run this from scratch now we will see we only get the apple as you can see we don't see banana
because we filter the results so that we only get the name being equal to Apple.
Of course we can do something else like we can do pureed dots of our key OK.
And we can go for calories like calories less than two or calories greater than to something like calories
greater than one hundred and twenty so our calories in Apple is actually one hundred.
So we won't get that result but rather where going to get the banana and it's calories are actually
greater than one hundred and twenty.
So if you need something to filter to results you can actually use this very key.
And it's very similar to what we have done in the fire base as well.
Maybe you remember that we had this very key in the fire base but it's actually very easy to use in
Paris so that you can do your retrieval operations very efficiently using these techniques.
Right now we know how to write and we know how to read data using parts database that's actually all
we need to work with pass.
Of course we are going to learn how to create users how to work with files like images so that we can
upload the images to this database.
And when we deal with authentication we are going to be saving information in this user class and they
all have their own methods.
But before we dive into them I'm going to go over and create start creating my Foursquare clone because
right now our current information is sufficient to learn this along the way.
OK so I'm going to stop here and I will start working on my main story boards and sign in page in order
to understand how to work with authentication in pass.
That's what we're going to do in the next lecture.