Hi within this lecture Regan to finalize our user interface by adding the last week controller.
So we're going to have to add a new wave controller because once user clicks of one off the table view
items we have to display the name the type the atmosphere the image and the location of that place in
a one single view controller.
So we cannot use these older real controllers because we have to view controllers in here.
We have to combine everything in one controller and display to the user.
So I'm gonna create a new wave controller or here.
Okay.
And in this we have controller we're going to have everything together.
So we're going to have another Segway from here.
And if the user clicks on the table view Reagan around the Segway.
If user clicks on the Add button we're already running the other Segway.
So this will be two details we have controller.
I'm going to call this detail we controller.
OK.
And makes sense to have back button over here so I'm not going to change the show type.
So under this view controller I want to have some image view first to display the image of the restaurant
or image of the cafe the image of the place.
So let me make this into the full screen in terms of width and in terms of height.
I believe this is kind of good.
Maybe we can decide that later on after we bring in the labels because I want to bring in three labels
for the place name place type and place atmosphere.
So the first one will be the place name labels.
So I'm going to call this place name night label.
OK as a place holder over here so that I know where I'm putting all of these labels.
So let me put this into center and let me copy and paste this and bring it down.
I'm going to call this place type label OK if I can a line this hopefully.
Yep.
Place type label.
And then we're going to need another one of course to display displays Utmost Fear label and you can
call the something like place description and place information maybe you can just give some basic information
like if this place accepts credit cards or accessories aeration or something.
So this is goods we will have three labels and under this tree labels I'm going to have a map.
So let me put this a little bit down so that I can make this image view a little bit bigger because
I have enough space here to bring in a map kids view.
So this map kids view will fill up all the way to the bottom from the middle of the screen.
Yep this looks good.
So I have the image view about.
I have three labels in middle and I have a map view on the bottom of my screen.
So I believe this is OK and this will let us show you all the information that we have gathered from
the user to another user.
So let me come over here and create a cocoa touch glass and this will be details we've controller details
we see so click on Next to create your view controller and put that under your Foursquare chrome project
and come over here to me and sorry bought to identity Inspector.
They choose the details we see class that we have created.
Open your assistant editor and choose details we see over here to define everything every view inside
of our weave controller.
So let me delete all of this comment lines and I'm going to start with the image view.
So I'm going to call these details image view.
OK so this is going to be something like details place name label.
So let me bring in details.
Name label.
OK.
We're going to have two more so details type label details type label and bring.
And the third one.
So this is details Utmost Fear label kind of long name.
And finally we're going to bring in the map view as well.
And rather than map you I'm going to call this details map you because we have another map for you.
I just want to avoid any confusion and I'm going to import the map kit over here to get rid of this
warning.
Here you go.
Now we are ready.
So we have this detail we've controller in order to just provide every information to the user in one
single weave controller.
And finally we're done.
It's our user interface.
As you can see in the main story board we have a very big main story worked in here because we're working
with a lot of weave controllers so we're working in a big project right now.
And we completed our first drafts.
Now we get to go into individual weave controllers to write our code.
That's what we going to do in the next lecture.