Hi.
We then this lecture we going to add our choose image function to our ad place we see so that the user
can tap on this picture in order to go to the photo gallery and choose an image to display in that image
of.
You know how to do that already right.
Because we have been doing it so far.
So I suggest you pose the video and try to do it on your own.
So we're going to work with this place Image view and first of all we have to make this user interaction
enabled so that the then we add a new gesture recognize there to it it gets recognized and we get to
call whatever function we want.
OK.
So what I'm going to do I'm going to say.
Place Image view.
So this one place Image view.
That's easy.
User interaction enabled is going to be true.
After doing that.
Of course I can call.
I can create my gesture recognize there.
So this is going to be a gesture recognized.
And this is going to be you.
I tapped yes you recognize her.
So Target will be self.
And of course we're going to have to create a new selector function.
So let me do that over here.
This is going to be an object to see function choose image and we can come over here I say choose image.
And after that we have to add this to our replace Image view and say add gesture you could nicer and
the right gesture recognizable.
So the gesture will be tap and then we recognize this gesture we're going to create you.
I pick her image picture actually not pick her UI image pick her controller over here.
So the speaker will have the delegates of our self our current we controller.
And of course in order to do that we have to come up over here and say this is indeed the UI image picker
controller delegate.
And on top of it it's actually a UI navigation controller delegate sending this kind of fast because
we have done it so many times and over here we have to specify the source type as well as photo library.
And then later on you can just call some present and present the picture animated the Why Not completion
will be nil.
So after that we have to specify what will happen once the user choses the image in order to do that.
We're going to have to work with us not did finish launching but did finish peaking media.
So if you were I did finish peaking media it will just pop up.
So this is did finish peaking media with info.
So what are we going to do peak.
We're going to say place Image view dots image.
We're going to peak that image from this info and this gives us a dictionary in which we will give original
image as a key and with this will give us a value and we're going to cast that value as a UI image and
then we going to dismiss and say completion is nil.
So of course if you want any description to give you can come over to enfold foldout P lists and give
it yourself because you know how to already do that.
So let's run this on our simulator and let's see if we can get the image.
So let's click on the ad button.
Let's click our over imagery while we're here and it will take us to our photo library and choose one
of the images.
And here we go.
Now we see the image.
If I click over one more time now I can get another image as well.
Now I can write the name type on atmosphere and I can't choose any image so that I can hit next to choose
the cartoon.
That's right.
Now all I have to do is just find a way to transfer all of this information to the map view so that
I can upload all of this information along with the coordinates with latitude and longitude to the PA
server.
That's what we're going to do in the next lecture.