Hi within this lecture regarding to set our map we see up so that we can get the current location of
the user so that we can zoom that location and people that will get to choose to create whatever place
they want.
By choosing from the map.
OK so you know how this works we're going to have to create a location manager we're going to have to
work with M.K. map delegates.
So let me just bring all of this things in.
So this is going to be m M K map.
We have delegates and see our location manager delegates.
So if you haven't watched the map section I suggest you go back and watch because we're going to do
some maps specified corporations and lots in this lecture.
So I'm going to say map view that delegates is going to be our turn.
Delegates our we have controller and remember we have to come up with a location manager so that we
can actually get the location of the user.
So this is going to be a single location manager and this location manager will again have the delegates
of self.
So now we can use this map view and the location manager now location manager will have the desired
accuracy of the best.
So remember if we write Casey out we have the options here and we wanted the best available accuracy
before and we wanted to write.
Now remember we have some other reasons to choose other options as well.
But right now we don't have them so if you say location manager that request I'm going to request one
in use authorization.
So later on I can just say location manager dot start updating location and when we do that.
Remember we have to give some description to let people know why we are even asking for this permission
in order to do that.
I'm going to had to you for police and search for privacy location when in use description.
So you have to come up with a good description over here for right now I'm just going to say to see
your location.
OK but in your own apps you have to be more explicit.
And after that we have to call another function to actually specify what will happen once we update
the location.
So this will start the updating location process and we are going to call this did update location function
this one in order to specify what will happen once the location gets updated.
So I'm gonna create a location and this will be SC a location coordinate to the.
So this will ask us to give a latitude and longitude so latitude will and longitude will come from these
locations array and I'm going to say this locations locations zero to get the first location out of
that location and not let to do the actual location zero that coordinates that's latitude.
OK we're going to do the same thing for longitude.
So location zero dot coordinate dots longitude.
So this will give us the current latitude and longitude of the user.
And remember we have to create a spend and this will be m k Cardinal spend.
And this will ask us for latitude Delta and longitude Delta.
Remember this defines the width and height of the current map so that we actually defined the zoom level.
And I'm going to go for all point 0 5.
Later on we can adjust it if we want and we have to create a region which is and I'm okay cause in that
region this will ask us for a center and the span and the center will be our location.
OK.
Not locations but the location and spend will be the spend.
And finally we can just call the map view to say map view that set region and the region that we want
to focus on the region that we created.
Animation.
Of course true.
So let me try this in our simulator and let's see if we can get the current location of the user.
OK.
Here you go.
Now we see the table we we see this and I'm going to click next I cannot click ness next because it
will give me an error so I'm going to give some dummy values.
And here you go.
It asks us to give the location permission.
And once I do that it just zooms in.
Remember in the debug section we can give a custom location and in the last section I have given Paris
as custom location.
So let me find another location to have a variety.
So we have been working in Paris for some time and I'm going to go for Amsterdam this time.
So let me choose Amsterdam floor from Google Maps to see the latitude and longitude of Amsterdam.
So this is I believe yep this one the latitude and longitude.
So I'm going to copy both of these values.
I'm going to change my custom location.
Of course you don't have to do that.
I'm just doing it so that you won't come across with same examples over time.
So let me change those values.
It has to be common up dots.
OK.
In this a simulator and this has to be common as well.
Once I do that the location got changed.
And here we are in the Amsterdam.
I'm going to make this a little bit zoomed in so I'm going to say oh point all three five and I'm going
to try that.
So I believe it's will be much better because we will be choosing cafes restaurants.
We have to be as close as possible.
Right.
So let me try this.
And here you go we're in the Amsterdam we're more zoomed in and I believe this is better.
So the point is one user opens this map.
They will see their current location but they may want to wander around like this in the maps and if
they change their location if they're walking or something they did update locations may camp may get
cold again and they will actually be relocated so resumed in the current location.
So if you come across in a situation like that you can just call a location manager that stopped updating
location in here.
Under deal update locations so that you would get the current location but you will stop updating locations
in this did update locations functions so that they can actually wander around the map freely.
And of course you're going to have to try this on your own in your own phone.
I suggest you try that with a real iPhone rather than simulator to see how your app behaves.
And it's fairly easy to do.
You just have to put your USP in in an iPhone and just try that on your own phone.
OK.
And you don't have to do that immediately you just try that when you want to publish an app on the App
Store so that you will actually try that on a real device so I'm going to comment this out right now
because I don't seem to be having that problem.
But just keep that in mind.
So let's stop here.
I'm within the next lecture we're going to see how to select a location from this map.