Hi within the lecture we going to add the function that is necessary to zoom into the chosen location
in our details we controller.
So far we're getting all the data that we need from parts and we are showing the details to the user.
But right now even though we have this chosen latitude and longitude.
We didn't go into the maps and just zoom into that led to to the longitude.
So after we get this latitude and longitude we may continue to do that under this function.
Right.
Because we cannot do that under the load actually let's try to do that on the we did load on you will
see why we cannot do that on there we did load.
We had to do that in here because this query actually works I think erroneously so that when we tried
to do something under we did load maybe we won't have that data so what do I mean.
For example after having this get data from past executed let's try to are called this chosen latitude
and longitude and this tried to print them.
So even though we call this get data from pass and even the even after we print this we still get this
as zero point zero the initial value of this chosen latitude.
Why is this happening.
Because this works as synchro Knisley and even though we just called this after we execute this since
it's not being sync erroneously it won't print out.
So if I print out in here OK after we get this done this will be called in order.
And after we get this long it's done we can display it in the logs as you can see.
Now we have the right parameter.
So when you try to work with asynchronous functions if you do something if you want to do something
with order then you have to do this inside of your asynchronous function as well.
Joe I'm going to do this over here.
So these are all four object operations.
OK.
Objects and I'm going to continue my maps operations under the same function as up.
So I'm going to create a location and this will be a square location coordinate to D and this will ask
me for a latitude and longitude.
So let's try to get SDR chosen latitude and south that chosen longitude.
Yep.
So this is good.
And let's try to create a span.
Again we're going to use the M K M.K. Cardinals spend on K coordinates span and this will ask us for
a latitude Delta and latitude Delta will be all point all three five and longitude will be all points
all three five.
And I'm going to create an M K coordinate region.
So this will ask me for a center and the span and center will be location spun will be spent and then
I can call my map view okay details map for you not image view details map view.
Now I can just say details map view dot sat region.
And I'm going to focus on that region with that animation so far so good.
Let's try this.
Let's see if we can see these chosen locations zoomed in.
If we can then we're going to have to add an annotation as well.
Here you go it zooms in the Amsterdam so it's working.
So we have to show the exact selected location without a rotation as well of course.
So let me create my own rotation.
So this will be M.K. point out rotation and this will be actually we have to give some coordinates.
So a rotation that coordinate is the location that we have just created.
Right.
And if we want we can give some title and subtitle as well.
We already have our title and subtitle over here.
Right.
And we assigned it to be our details name label so we can come over here and say a notation that's cardinals.
Yeah I believe I have deleted something.
So this will be a location and a notation that title will be details self-taught place details.
No this not this one details.
Name label I believe.
Details namely will that text.
Yep.
This one.
And we can have a subtitle as well a notation that subtitle is going to be solved that details type
labeled up text.
And finally we can add this annotation to our map.
You say s stop detailed map view dot ad rotation.
OK.
And give this annotation.
Here you go.
Now let's Chesters and see if we can get D James restaurant pins in on our map.
Let's click on this.
Here you go.
Now we see the James first round.
Let me click over here to zoom in.
If I just hit over here we will see the title and the subtitle as we want.
So only thing left to do to finish our app is to add navigation by then over here.
Remember we have something called Disclosure by them and that's what we were going to add in the next
lecture to open our maps and do some navigation from our current location to the selected place.