High within this lecture regrowing to ads navigation by using the detailed disclosure button in our
notation and we know how to do that from the travel book app.
Remember what we have to do we have to call for V for a notation to customize our annotations.
But as you can see we cannot call you for a notation right now because we haven't made our details we've
controller a delegate of our map view right.
So let's do that.
Let's come over here and let's say that M.K. map view.
Yep this one map view delegate I remember we used to say see our location manager delegate as well but
I believe in our case we're not going to use this because we're not getting the user location at this
point.
So afterwards if we need this we may have to edit later on but right now I just need those details map
view that delegate itself once I do that I can come down and I can call for V for a notation so let's
call for we for a notation.
Here you go we are looking for this function and in here we're going to check to see we're going to
actually customize it the annotations that we have but I don't want to deal with location on notations
of the current user.
So remember how we do that we we actually begin to check to see if annotation this one.
OK.
This notation is M.K. user location on notation.
So I'm going to return nil if that's the case.
And later on I'm going to create an annotation.
I remember how we do that.
This is giving us an error because it expects us to return that notation which we will later on I'm
going to create this annotation and I'm going to call this pin view and this will be map view that D
Q reusable levitation wheel and this will ask us to give you an identifier and actually we're going
to use this identifier more than one time.
So I'm going to create a reuse idea here call it pin and give this reuse idea as an identifier and then
I'm going to check to see if this pin view is nil or not if it's still done we're going to give it some
odd notation to it.
We're going to create our own notation here for real.
So this will be an M K pinpoint our notation real.
This will ask us to give it a notation and an identifier.
The notation is this one okay and the identifier is the identifier that we have created.
So give it some reuse I.D. and then later on we have to say pin me dot can show call outs.
So this means that we can actually show the button that we're about to show on the right hand side.
So if we don't do that even though we added it won't display it so let me create that that's button
that we have been talking about.
So the type of this button will be disclosure detailed disclosure.
OK.
So it will display something with I like in an information button OK.
And we're going to add this to be air right.
Call out accessory view to our pin view.
OK.
So that it will display the button in the right color accessory.
Else if pin is actually not nailed down pin where you are location is d notation that is given to me.
So that's it.
I'm referring to design notation by the way.
I'm going to return this pin view so that I have my customized notation.
So if you haven't watch the map section I believe you should go and watch for a refresher because I'm
explaining everything in the details in that section.
And again I'm going to call for call outs accessory control tapped.
And this specifies what will happen once we click on that button over here we have created that button
remember.
So this defies what will happen when a user taps on that bottom.
So what we want to happen is to open the navigation actually and in order to open that navigation remember
we need something called Place marks.
And in order to get that place marks object we need to have a reverse geolocation operation and in order
all of these things to happen we have to create a location to begin with.
So under this call out accessory control tapped function we're going to control we're going to actually
create a location first.
So we have our chosen latitude and longitude here right.
So I'm going to check to see if SDR chosen longitude is not zero that's the euro.
So we have some values and if South are chosen latitude again is not zero that's the euro.
So I can come over here and I can create a location.
And at this point it doesn't make sense to have these values zero that zero.
But again to be on the safe side I believe we can just do it after we check this I'm going to create
this request location.
OK so this request location will be a at location.
So this is not a single location according to the.
And you will see why in a minute.
And again this will ask us to give some latitude and longitude.
So this will be chosen latitude.
And this will be chosen longitude.
Okay.
And after we give this after we create this request location then we are going to use this yellow geo
coder that I was talking about.
So this actually converts place names to coordinates or vice versa.
So I'm going to do a reverse geo called location this one and this should in fact ask me for a request
location as here location and I cannot see it right now because yeah I misspelled it.
I have to add this parentheses over here and say reverse geo location.
Yep this one as you can see it asks us to create a second location and it gives us a completion handler.
So that's the one I want.
Let's let me give a request location and hit enter.
Here you go we have our place Mark Rey.
So let's call this place marks an error.
So I'm going to cast my place marks array as a place Mark variables so that I will make it not optional.
By doing that.
So after that I'm going to check to see if placed mark that count is actually greater than zero meaning
that I have something inside my array so that I can create my M.K. place Mark object.
So this will be M.K. place Mark.
OK.
So this is a description of the chosen location.
It will ask me for a place Mark.
So this one and I'm going to get this from place Mark zero.
So first element of my place Mark object and then I need a map item because that's what we need to open
in navigation is and it will drive from it will be coming from this M.K. place Mark and this one yep
that I'm k.
Place mark that I have created later on I'm just going to use this map item and we can give it a name
if we want to display in the navigation as well and we can get this name from our details name label
right.
So details.
Name label dot text so that we can see the name in the navigation as well and actually now I can just
come over here as a map item that's open in maps but it will ask us to give some specific launch options.
Let's take care of that as well.
Let's create launch options.
So first we have to give some key and the key is M.K. launch options directions mode key and the value
that I'm looking for is more driving.
So I'm okay.
Launch options directions more driving.
So this will by default.
Show me how to get there by car.
So let me give this launch options and let me try this.
So let us Iran does in our simulator OK and let us try to go to James a restaurant and if I click on
here you will see the disclosure button.
This is the detailed disclosure button as you can see.
Now if I tapped on this if I tap on this actually this will get cold colored accessory control tapped
and will bring me into a navigation in which I will get my current location to the destination location
navigation.
So this is showing drive by default.
And here you go.
That's all we wanted again we are using map item to open in maps.
So and we are checking to see if the location is not empty and we are creating our request location
because this will ask us to give us some MTA map item and in the MTA map item we need some place marks.
And in order to get this place marks yep we have to create this place marks array and in order to create
this place marks a we have to have this reverse geo called location and in order to have this request
location we have to make sure there is latitude and longitude is not empty.
That's why we are doing all of this.
Now I believe we are okay right now.
We can go ahead and test to see if our app is really working by adding new places.