Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to bring in the images that we have imported every going to start working
on our design in the game scene that SARS.
So we're going to be working with sprites here as I said before and spread this kind of a view that
you can change it.
But James it's background and change its color so that you can have a view that you can work with inside
of your sprite kid project.
So when you first bring in a sprite you will see something like this.
Okay.
As you can see we have a red color right now and I'm just expanding it so that it will fit inside of
my frame or here.
So I can't change its background I can change its color.
But for right now I just want to open my simulator to see if we really see the sprite over here as you
can see now we have this red.
And let me rotate my device to the left so that we can use it in an landscape mode.
So here you go.
This is our game right now we have a red background and we did it with our colors sprite.
So let me close this down.
And rather than having a red background over here can I have my background image.
Yep.
I can use that.
It's called texture.
In this case as we move on to the games the all terminology changes as you can see now we have a sprite.
We have textures rather than background.
I'm really going to have to get used to the fact that this terminology changes once we move on to these
bright kids.
And as you can see we now have these images over here and if I choose the background as a texture to
my Sprite kids now it will just bring in this background over here.
So I'm going to make this a little bit smaller so that I can just feed it into the frame or you can
exceed the size a little bit so that it would work on bigger screen sizes as well.
So this is a main disadvantage of working with game scene that is scarce.
If we were to define this in code we would have the chance to define it for a reality of screen sizes
so that it would actually work better in different screen sizes.
But in game scene that is cast we just define the size in a given way then heights and we're going to
see how to do it in code.
Don't worry so I'm going to change this background to something white right now because we already have
our background but different image right now so that we can't see better.
I believe this is better for you to see.
And here you go.
This is our frame and we're exceeding the frame a little bit.
You can make this a little bit smaller as well.
Where are you going to try this in our simulator to see how this looks like and if it looks like good
then I'm going to leave it as it is and I'm going to bring my next views like trees or birds.
Here you go.
I believe we could just make this a little bit smaller in height to see the base as well like this.
So let me run this one more time and let's see if we can see the base here again.
Now we see this green base which is good.
Now I'm going to bring in my tree and then my bird and my bricks as well.
So far so good.
So let me open the library one more time and bring in one color sprite.
And in here I'm going to choose the texture as tree.
So this will bring in my tree.
So let me try to actually make this a little bit smaller so let's seats it has a huge size as you can
see you can't change the size from here.
Like you can say six hundred to something or you can just make it smaller like this.
OK.
So I'm going to make this smaller this way.
So I'm going to place it on my grass like this.
And you can just play with it until you're satisfied with your tree.
You can try to make this smaller.
You can try to make this around from here for example.
OK I'm not going to do that.
I'm just going to use it exactly how with this like this.
OK.
Now this and I believe that's good for our tree regrowing to use it as a slingshot.
Anyway it's not going to do I think rather than holding our Bert.
And then later on let's run this one more time to see if we see the tree over our background.
And here you go.
It looks nice right.
So we arranged to bring in the bird.
So let's open the library and choose color Sprite and choose texture.
As bert.
So as you can see our bird is a little bit bigger so I'm going to make this smaller.
Yep.
This is good.
Let me put my bird over my tree and let me use this as a slingshots.
Yep this is good.
So we're going to stretch the bird from here and this will turn of the bird as we do that of course
we're going to have to write that code for that later on.
Now I believe we can bring in our bricks.
Right.
So let's open our library to break in a color sprite.
And this time from texture I'm going to go for brick and let's make this smaller.
And let's just put it over here.
Let's make this a little bit smaller.
Yep.
This is good.
Now I'm going to copy and paste is why pressing comment see and comment V.
I'm going to do this a couple of times to how I like a tower of bricks over here.
OK.
I'm going to have five bricks in total so let's placed is over here.
And here you go.
That's good.
So make sure you have your bricks on top of each other because they will have some physical mass and
they will be affected by gravity later on.
So they won't fall off from each other.
So make sure they're placed carefully.
OK.
So far so good for our design.
So let's try to run this on our simulator to see if they're on the place that we want them to be.
As you can see them the open these simulator some of the views are not here.
Actually none of them are over here.
So this must be related to their z position.
So there is something called z position.
It's kind of a turd dimension and it defines which view is in the foreground then which view is in the
background.
For example if we make this Z minus one for the background it will be in the background begins because
it's already the background.
OK.
So it makes sense to make this minus one and have all other views in zero.
For example if I want this bird to be in the foreground then it compares to the tree.
Then I can make this one and I can make the 3 0 and I can make background at minus one and I can make
brick zero as well.
So when I add a number to the z position it means that it will get the priority to be shown in the foreground
as you can see we still have the circle things floating around.
Because we haven't deleted the cold yet we're going to take care of that because in the next lecture
regrowing to work on coding in the sprite kids so that we will know how to create views create sprites
using coding section and we will know how to do other operations as well.
Let's do that in the next lecture.