Hi within this lecture we are going to see how we can create views inside of our game scene that swift
file.
So far we have been doing that inside of our game seemed out as gay yes and we know how to bring in
views using sprites and textures.
Now where are you going to do that in codes.
So we haven't even looked at what's inside of our game scene that's 50 yet.
So in here we have did move to function.
So this is kind of we've added loads inside of our receipt.
So far we have this hello world label coming on and off and creating some circular views but I'm going
to delete all of this because we're going to write it from scratch.
I'm just going to leave the functions as it is.
Because we may use them later on I'm going to tell you what these functions do.
Later on when we need them.
OK for right now I'm going to delete everything from here like under touches began touch his mood touches
and that and touch his canceled name of these functions are actually self explanatory right.
For example in here we have touches begin and when somebody taps on the scene when the user taps on
their scene dysfunctions gets cold.
So if they touch touches begin will get cold if they actually move their finger touches moved will get
cold if they end their touch touches.
And that will get cold and if some reason if it gets cancelled touches cancels will get cold ever again
to use most of these functions later on.
Don't worry we're going to see how to use them and a site from these functions.
We have a touch down touch mood and touch up functions as well.
And this gives the exact point that a user touch down for example we're not going to need this function
in this course but we're going to learn most of the functions so that you will know how to work with
Sprite kids eventually.
Right now I just want to create and v2.
So I'm going to delete everything from here and I'm just going to go ahead and create a sprite called
Bert.
So I'm going to bring in the bird as we did in the game scene that is scarce but this time I'm going
to do that with the inside of our coding section.
I'm going to call this bird too because we already have a bird right.
And this will be an s case bright note.
So this one as you can see this is an image or a solid color.
So I remember when we create scenes when we create sprite nodes actually been inside of scenes we may
give them colors or remake we give them images using textures.
So let's do that.
For example if I want to create a bird to I'm not going to use any of these functions yet I'm going
to do what I have to do.
Undo did move to function and inside of this did move to I'm going to called Bird 2 and I'm going to
assign bird texture for my bird to sprites note.
So let's do that first let's create the texture itself in order to work with textures you have to call
SDK texture class as you can see this is an image and this can be used to render various sprite kid
objects.
So that's what a texture does when you open parentheses it will ask you for a data or an image.
So we're going to work with image Nate because we're going to get this image from our assets library.
Remember our image is named Bert.
So what we're going to do we're going to assign this texture to be our texture of our sprite note.
So I'm going to say Bert to is an escape sprite note and if you open parentheses you will see an option
asking for a texture parameter.
That's the one that we're going to use you can see it's asking for a color in other options as well.
But we want the texture in this case and the texture will be the texture that we have created previously.
After that we have to actually assign the position of this bird too.
So this is the.
This defines the position inside of our scene.
So this asks us to create the C.G. point and if you do that it will ask you for an x and y coordinates.
So when we were talking about the anchor point that's what I was talking about right.
So if I say 0 0 right now it will place my view in the middle of the screen.
So let's do that actually and see how it works.
So zero zero means the middle of my screen right now because I said my anchor point to be the middle
of the screen.
Later on I'm going to give a size and this will be a C G size.
So this is actually very simple.
It asks us to create a width and height.
Right now I'm going to go four hundred to under it and we're going to change it afterwards.
Later on we can define the z position as well.
Remember we made our Berg to have a z position of 1.
I'm going to do that in here as well.
Finally we can just say self-doubt at child and add this bird to to be shown in my seat.
So here you go.
Now we are ready.
So let's run this in our simulator and see how our bird looks like.
Here you go.
That's our bird.
As you can see it's in the middle of the screen and it's has the weight of hundreds and height of hundreds.
And actually it's good for with and height.
But as I said before having done this in codes I have an advantage I can make does relative to screen
size.
So what can I do.
I can just call s that frame and make it relative to the frame of the current screen size.
So if you say self-taught frame that that it will give you the current width of the screen.
Right.
So you can just go for something like s start frame that divided by 15 for example.
And for height you can just go for a self-taught frame that height divided by 10 am making this up.
So we will see how 15 and 10 looks like and we can adjust it later on.
So here you go.
It looks good but it's a little bit squeezed vertically so I believe we have to make our with a little
bit smaller.
So let's try 16 for example and let's see how this looks like and the up.
I believe this is better.
So we have a rounded circular bird right now and looks like our bird.
And I'm not gonna waste time to create all of the views inside of this code because we have already
done our design using game scene as chaos.
But in your app or in your own games you may actually do that in order to comply with different screen
sizes.
For example in this case if I want this bird to be here I may have to adjust the position a little bit
so that I can have my bird over here.
For example I can use the s that frame again to specify some position to my bird too and I will have
to do everything for this tree for this break and for other views as well.
So I'm not going to waste time doing that in this section but let me show you how this works.
For example I can come over here.
OK.
Not here but here rather than saying 0.
I can just say something like minus self-doubt frame dot width and divide it by something like 5 for
example.
Let me see how this looks like.
So let's see.
Here you go it's moved to the left a little bit but not quite what I want right.
So let me try this like for and let me try this why.
Something like minus self that frame that height over for.
So let's run this and see how this looks like and this time it's much better.
So we have to decrease the why we have to increase the X so that we will to have the same position as
this bird.
But do you understand the point.
You can't do everything inside of the coding section as well.
And this will be compliant with every other screen sizes as well.
So I'm going to comment this out and I'm going to continue with.
Well what we have right now but we're going to create views with code later on in the section as well.
So let's stop here.
Continue within the next lecture.