Hi.
We didn't this lecture regrowing to see how we can actually move the bird around the scene in a free
way because I want to give him an initial push to throw him off the air right in order to do that.
I want to take him and drag him around the screen in a free way so that I can stretch him in the sling
shot.
So how do we do that.
Of course we're going to use touches began and touches moved functions but we also want to make sure
that we have a control in order to understand if the game is started or not because we want to do that
only if the game is not started.
So after game starts of two we push him off the air.
We don't want to grab him and move him around accidentally.
So we have to have a boolean controlling if the game is started or not.
And it's easy to have right.
So we can't come over here and we can just create a boolean called game started and it will be false
initially because game will not be started when you first open the app right.
We can just change it to be true.
After we push the bird to the air so let's come over here and rather than flying the bird I'm just going
to move him around so I'm going to comment this so that you can have this as a note in the Github page
and over here I'm going to start by checking to see if game is started or not.
If game is not started then I'm going to do it.
If game is actually started then I'm not going to do this.
And here I'm going to work with both touches begin and touches moot because not only user will tap was
but he or she will drag the bird around the screen so touch his mood will be necessary in this case
as well.
So I'm going to write my function over here and then I'm going to copy everything on their touches moves
so I'm going to start by checking to see if game started is false.
Right.
So if this is false I'm going to do what I have to do.
So what I have to do is to understand very user touched so I'm going to say if that touches and as you
can say if that touch is touches dot first.
So this will give me the first touch that user has done so this touches come from the function itself.
So this is kind of a UI touch object and it actually tells us the point that user has touched so I can
create a touch location out of that touch and it will drive from touch that's location and it will ask
before a scene or view.
I'm going to say self and this will create my touch location later ohm I'm going to see what nodes that
the user touch arm.
So if you say nodes as you can see it asks you for a CGI point you can give a touch location over here.
So this will give me the touched notes so I can understand if the user has touched on the bird so I'm
going to come over here to the touch nodes and I'm going to check to see if they're empty or not.
If this is not empty it means that user has tapped on some notes and I'm going to go into a for loop
in that touch nodes as K node area.
And in here I'm actually going to check to see if the node is actually the bird.
So if this is in fact the bird then I'm going to move the bird around.
So if user touches on bucks I'm not gonna do that right.
I'm not going to move around the boxes I just want to move around the bird.
So let me say that if let's sprite node as an S K sprite node because this is an escape note now that
this case bright note then as you can see my birth is an escape sprite nodes that I can check to see
if my escape sprite node is actually the bird.
So come over here I'd say if sprite is Bert then do this.
So what I'm about to do here to move the bird's position.
So I want to move the bird to the current point that user has touched so you can just come over here
as a bird.
That position is now touch location.
Here we go.
Now you moved the bird to the touched location.
So of course you have to do that under touch.
Moved as well because we just don't want to do it once.
We want to do it continuously until user just lets off the touch.
So let me try this on my simulator and let's see if we can move the bird around.
So here we go.
Now we can drag the bird around as we want freely and we cannot do that for boxes because we're checking
to see if our sprite is actually the bird.
So this verse.
Now I can stretch this bird around and I can push him off the air so that it will just go off the air
and it will just hit on or hit to the boxes.
Of course we're gonna have to figure out a way to understand if the user let go of their finger from
the bird.
Let's do that in the next lecture.