Hi within this lecture we're going to see something called mutating function and it's again related
to immutability of this drugs.
So can I have a function inside of our class.
Of course we can.
Let's create a happy birthday function.
And in this function I'm going to add one to our current H So s that age will be plus equal to 1.
OK.
So that's easy.
Can I do that in musician struct.
We will see let's try that first with our existing class.
So let me comment this out.
So let me comment.
All of the prints out so that we will have an empty log.
Okay so let's comment out let's comment out this as well.
So over here I'm going to call this function versus mutating function.
Okay under here I'm going to call my James class.
Okay so Class James sorry.
Class James starts H if I print this let's actually run this because I don't even remember what was
our current H.
Yeah.
It was 52.
Now let's call class James Dot.
Happy birthday.
And let's then print out one more time to see the new age of James.
It will be fifty three right.
This is what we expect and it will be fifty three.
Yep.
This is good.
And this works as we expect.
But can we do that with struct.
Yeah of course we can have functions inside of our struct but let's create the same function over here
and let's try to change the s that age and add one.
This will give us an error window.
Age is a variable.
This have isn't movable.
Okay.
The struct itself its is is immutable so we cannot change this in order to change this.
There is a keyword that we can use in front of our function.
We can make this function mutating function.
Okay.
And then we do that you will see the error will go away so that we can use this same function as we
want inside of our main that Swift.
So let's try to do that.
Visit our struct James.
Okay let's print out this struct James H.
Let me comment this out and this one as well.
Let me run this and let's see if we get the fifty one.
Yep we have the 51.
Let's call struct James that's happy birthday and let's print destruct.
James age buy more time.
So let's see if we get fifty two.
Here you go.
Now we have the fifty two.
So you have to keep in mind that if you want to change ever able inside of your struct you have to make
that function mutating function because the S is immutable instructs So Reagan's top here and within
the next lecture we we're going to see a new concept called tuple.