Hi within this lecture we we're going to see a new concept called guards left.
So far we have been working with if left to manage the optional zone side of swift.
But we're going to see guard let this time and it's very similar to if left.
But there are some differences in syntax and there are some differences in implementation as well.
So what are the differences and why do we use guard led or why do we use if let in some certain cases.
So this is not an official way to teach these or this is not an official way to tell about guard led.
But I'd like to remember it like this.
So if I'm certain that this is going to work and there is no other way to make this work and if I'm
confident that I should guard this I should have these value then I use guard let and it's kind of a
negative thing.
So it asks me what will happen if that doesn't work first.
And then if let it's kind of positive we're not very certain that if does this will work or not but
in guard lad we are certain that this will work.
So let me create a string and you will know what I mean.
So let's suppose that my string is five OK but this is a string and I'm going to convert this to be
an integer and apparently I have used my string before up here we have used my string.
So we have to change this to something else.
As you can see your re declaring it.
So let's call this my number.
But this is a string okay not an integer.
Every going to convert this to be an integer using that function.
So I'm going to do this with guard led and if let's.
And you will see the differences.
So first of all I'm going to convert this with guard light and it will ask me for a string input and
give me an integer.
OK.
As an output.
And we're going to use.
Guard let led in here.
And of course we don't know how to use guard left yet but we know how to use it if let's.
Right.
So let me write another function called convert to integer if and this will again ask me for a string
input OK.
And this will be a string and this will again give me an integer and we can just say if let's.
My integer is in parentheses my number or string input sorry String input.
OK.
Because we're we're going to take this by number as a String input and if that's the case if we can
make this then I'm going to return my integer.
Right.
And else if that doesn't work I'm going to return 0.
So that's how we do it with.
If let's.
So let's try to write the same thing with guard let's.
So if I say guard let over here I can again say my integer is in parentheses String input but this time
not string interpolation.
Yep this is String input.
But this time I cannot even do that because that's the that's not the proper rate to use God let you
have to say else before you open the curly braces and this is asking for you what will happen if this
doesn't work in this if that case it asks me what will happen if it works.
So in guard let it's kind of negative as you can see it's certain that this is going to work and it's
asking you for a first thing to do if this doesn't work what will happen.
So you can come over here as a return zero.
Right.
And else you can just return my integer over here.
You can't just say you returned my teacher and as you can see in under this function we are certain
that this is going to Virg and we are providing a valley.
This is if this doesn't work.
So we're really guarding it.
OK.
So this is negative and confidence.
And if that is not that confident and it's kind of positive attitude.
So again this positive a negative think actually is for you to remember this is not an official documentation
or official way to teach you.
But I believe this will make you a good way to remember this by so that you will know when to use which.
Well let's try both of them right.
So let's print out convert to integer if and again for String input we get to give my number and in
here we're going to call convert to integer guard.
And this time we're going to give my number again.
So let me try to run this and we will get the same result.
Right.
Like 5 5 because both functions are doing the same thing and instead of five if I write Apple the both
functions will return me they're zero.
So guard lad and if that eventually brings me the same result.
But there are some differences then we implement them.
So I hope you enjoyed the advance with sections so far.
Where are you going to stop here and continue within the next section.