Hi within the section where you going to learn how to work with swift UI in order to create stunning
user interfaces.
So Apple has just recently released the swift UI and it's better than ever before.
So now we can create very structural good user interfaces with this framework.
So go ahead and create your first project and choose single view app.
And this time make sure that you check this use swift UI bucks as VO And I'm going to name this my first
swift UI project.
Okay so first swift UI app or swift UI project.
And of course if you're going to discuss what is swift UI and what is the difference between swift UI
and the regular method of building user interfaces.
OK so let me put this on my OS folder and let's say update to this and let me make this into a full
screen mode.
OK so like that and you will immediately realize there are some differences between the swift UI projects
and regular swift projects.
For example here we have some content to view and we don't even have a v controller over here right.
Rather we have some struct ends in the left hand side you will see that we have the app delegate.
We have the scene delegates as usual but we have this content v rather than we have controller and this
is the content view that we are already seeing right now.
So again on the right hand side you will see something like this.
And if you don't see it you can come over here D me and say canvas sell within the canvas we will see
our preview.
So if you say resume you will see the preview of your app like this.
Even though I'm not running any simulator right now in my project as you can see I'm seeing the project
in the preview I'm seeing it as in as simulator and be very that I'm not running any simulator right
now but X R is chosen and it's showing my project inside of an X R framework x x r layout.
Okay so that's cool right.
I can make changes in my coding section and I can immediately see how it looks like in a real life environment
by using this previews.
So this is very good.
So over here we have this text okay.
For example rather than saying Kelo swift Hello world I'm going to say swift UI and as you can see it
immediately changed the text over here so I can do what I have to do.
I can just see the results on the right hand side in swift UI and that's very cool.
So that's one of the biggest advantages of swift UI.
So let's see some differences.
Maybe you realize that we don't even have a storyboard right now because we're not going to work with
storyboards.
We're not even going to work with the view controllers from now on we will have views rather than view
controllers.
OK we won't have we have controllers we won't have labels.
We won't have table views.
If you open your library you will see some other options like we have something called stack over here
and you will see whether this and we have some other options over here like a list like a text and we
see some old schoolers like button and toggle and other things but we have so different options over
here right.
And we're going to see how to use them later on.
But know that right now we don't have we controllers we don't have old views we have everything in a
new way but the good thing is the coding doesn't change.
We can use the swift knowledge we can use the swift structure as it is in here.
So we have this struct right and the inside of our struct we have a body and inside of our body we have
some views.
So that's what we're going to do.
We're going to create views inside of our body and we're going to work with those views inside of swift
UI.
And once you master suite UI you will be free more than ever to create stunning user interfaces.
And again it's a little but different.
It's a little bit more difficult compared to the conventional ways to create user interfaces but once
you get to know it then you will love it.
OK so within the section where you're going to have a crash course on Swift UI and we're going to see
the basics the introduction part of swift UI so that we can create good user interfaces.
Let's continue within the next lecture.