Within those picture where are you going to start building our favorite book app.
So you know to do that I'm going to go ahead and create the new X SCOPE project.
And of course I'm going to go with single we lap one more time.
And don't forget to check the swift UI bugs.
And this will be our favorite book.
So here you go.
Now I'm going to place this under my U.S. complete folder.
And let me make this into a full screen.
So remember the app.
We have two screens in which we have the list and we have the details of the selected element.
Right.
But before we go on that list and the other design we have to create our models.
So I'm going to create my model first and I'm going to build my way up from there.
OK.
And in order to do that I'm going to work with trucks.
I'm going to create another Swift file in which we will have other struts.
And yes we will have more than one struct so that we can work this with very structurally and very professionally
of course along the way.
We're going to have to deal with images we're going to have to deal with some sample codes.
And it's going to take time but I believe this will be a good practice for you to understand how to
work with structures how to work with structures.
OK.
So let's create a new file and I'm going to go for swift file a rather than Swift UI view because we're
not going to need any views inside of our model.
And this time I'm going to call this favorite model cars you can call those favorites as VO But I'm
going to be explicit over here and I'm going to call this favorite model.
So in here we have the foundation and we're just going to have our struct.
OK.
So remember how we create struct.
It's actually very similar to the classes.
All you have to do is just come over here and right struct and write your struct name.
So in our case it's favorite model.
I want to make this favorite model identifiable OK.
We have talked about this before.
Remember how we had to give you a manual idea when we deal with for each loop or for lists.
Now if we do this as an identifiable struct then we can just skip that step because this will be identifiable.
And if you cannot reach the identifiable maybe then you will have to import the swift UI but if you
can reach it doesn't matter and all you have to do to make your struct identifiable to have is just
to have an I.D. In your struct as an attribute or as a property.
OK.
So come over here and say var I.D. And this area will go away.
So you can have your I.D. in some different ways like you can come over here and say I.D. is a you you
I.D. and remember what is a you you I.D. It is universally unique I.D..
So every time you create an instance of this truck it will just a sign and universal unique I.D. to
that object so that you will have a made up string and you will have a made up you you I.D. and you
can do it like an integer as well.
But this time you will have to manually give some I.D. like 0 1 2 3.
So I'm not going to do that.
Rather I'm just going to say you you I.D. and swift with take care of this for me.
So inside of my favorite model I'm going to have a title and this title will refer to my titles in the
lists.
OK.
So remember our titles like favorite movies favorite bands favorite.
I don't know if you want to have another example like favorite books.
So this will be our title.
OK so this will be like the categories that we are going to work with.
And inside of that categories we are going to have some elements.
OK.
And in fact I'm going to create another struct to have elements because we're going to have some properties
too in our elements as well like an image like a description like a name.
So you have seen how this app works.
Right.
And we click on Metallica and we see the image we see the description and we see the name of the Metallica.
So let's create another struct for that and you can just call this something like favorite elements.
OK and you have to make this identifiable as well.
And over here you have to just say Wah I.D. you you I.D. one more time because design identifiable.
So I'm going to have a name and this will be a string.
I'm going to have an image name.
And this will be again as string.
And again I'm going to have a description or something like that over here and this will be again as
string.
So I can come over here and say this will be an array of favorite elements.
So if I can open this area Yep.
This one favorite elements.
OK.
So our favorite model will have a title and a favorite elements area.
So maybe I can create one example you would understand it much better.
So let's come down here and try to create our favorite musicians or favorite bands.
Of course I'm going to start with Metallica.
We're here as usual.
So I'm going to say let's Metallica.
OK.
And this will be a favorite elements.
So I named its elements but it doesn't matter as you can see we get two options one asking for ideas
and one that does not.
So I'm going to choose the second one.
If you choose the first one you can write you You idea with the parentheses and it won't matter.
So for image name I'm going to say Metallica and for description I'm just going to say something like
no one band or no one musician.
OK.
So for the image name we're going to have to find an image and name it's Metallica later on.
So I believe we have this image because we have previously used it in the same section.
So I'm going to bring in the Metallica image.
And here you go.
Now I can create this.
OK I can create this with image as well.
Of course we are not going to need image for until like two or three lectures right now but no doubt
we have to find images for other musicians as well like mega that let's call this I remained in.
OK.
And let's change this a little bit so let's make this.
Number two let's make this number three and four image name I'm gonna go for Megadeth and this time
I'm gonna go for I remade them and let's change the names as well.
So this is Megadeth and this is I really made them and let's create our favorite model right now for
our favorite musicians.
So I'm going to call this something like favorite bands OK or favorite musician model.
I don't know I'm going to call this favorite bands and we are going to have to give some title which
is favorite bands and we're going to have to give some array of elements and inside of that array I'm
going to have Metallica.
I'm going to have Megadeth and I'm going to have I remade them.
No here you go.
This is how our structure will look like.
Of course I'm not going to stop here because I believe we need to have at least one more example to
understand this app in a better way.
So I'm going to create a favorite movie favorite model and favorite elements as well so that we will
have enough examples and we're going to have to find some related images as well.
So I'm going to stop here and continue within the next lecture.