Hi within this lecture we are going to finalize our app by passing information from this content view
to the details we use so that we can use this model's properties in order to display the image and other
information and best way to do that is to create a variable inside or of our details view so that we
can get the chosen model.
So I'm going to call this chosen favorite element and this will be a type of favorite elements.
OK so this will ask us to give a favorite elements instance when we try to initialize details view.
So when we do that whenever we write details view it will ask us to choose a favorite element.
So now I did that and if I do a command B to build this up.
So I am getting some weird error.
So let me do a command B.
And as you can see I'm even getting that error under this preview struct.
So we haven't talked about this yet but this displays the preview.
OK.
So this defines what will be displayed in the preview on the right hand side as you can see now we are
displaying the details view this struct over here.
And since we're initializing these details view it's asking for the the chosen favorite elements.
So if we give some exemplary chosen favorite elements over here it will display as an example on the
right hand side.
For example let's give the Dark Knight as an example.
Of course this won't affect the real app itself but it will only affect the preview.
We will see The Dark Knight as an example in our preview.
Once we do that.
OK.
So let me try to resume this and let's try to build this and we get on air.
And the reason for that error is because we're actually calling details view inside of our content view
as well.
And this time navigation link destination is asking us to provide the same parameter to here so that
we can pass the information.
Right.
So it's easy to get the chosen favorite element right now because it's already given as an element here.
So if I write elements here then it will pass this information to the date details view and so that
I can come over here and get the chosen favorite element and do whatever I want to do with that element.
For example let me wrap this inside of a V stack because we are going to have more than one text for
right now I'm just what I'm just going to display the name of the chosen favorite elements.
And for example this will just display the Dark Knight name because I'm using the Dark Knight as an
example inside of my preview.
Right.
But in the real app I'm not going to see The Dark Knight all the time I'm just going to see whatever
I choose.
So let me resume this and let me try this from here.
OK once it's loaded you can click over here and you will see whatever you choose like this.
So as you can see what I'm choosing is shown in the details view.
So that's good.
That's what I wanted.
Now all we have to do is just to come over to details view and have the other views as well like an
image.
So when I write image it will ask me for a name.
And we already have that name stored in chosen favorite element dot image name right.
So I can get this and displayed on my screen and of course this is going to be too big.
So I'm going to resize it as usual and I'm going to give some aspect ratio to this image and I'm going
to say that fit and let's see.
Yep this is good.
But this is far too close to each other.
So maybe we have to make this a little bit bigger.
OK.
And let's see.
Yep.
This doesn't work.
Let me give this some padding.
Yep.
This looks good.
Now we have to display the description as well.
So let me call text chosen favorite elements.
Yep.
This one chosen favorite element dot description.
So let me give you some padding over here or some other font as well.
So I believe the current font is good and current padding is even good so we can use this same details
view in every element that we have.
Let me run this from the scratch.
And here you go.
We have the Metallica image.
We have the Megadeth image and this looks good to me.
So let's try the others as well.
So this is a little bit big but it looks good.
So here you go.
Now we are done with our app.
The good thing about is that I can come over here and change whatever I want since I have only one view
regarding this view.
It will affect everything.
So if I'm not satisfied with the image size for example I can just change it for once and I will use
it for every other view as well.
So this is cool.
Now you have learnt a lot about swift UI.
But again there is a lot more to more to learn about swift UI as well.
So if you're ready you can't go over here to developer dot apple dot com and into the documentation.
You can't go for a swift UI and try to figure out yourself if you're not ready to do that.
I suggest you go on and check out our other cars on Swift UI so that maybe you can feel a little bit
better run You tried to learn about all these things but this the Apple has a really good documentation
regarding swift UI and they have this landmark book app that's they're doing in swift UI.
It's kind of the landmark book that we are doing in this class but it's poorly written in swift UI and
they believe swift UI will take its place in most of the apple projects in a couple of years because
now there is a better way to create user interfaces and there is a better way to work with data and
all other things and people will choose it over Main storyboards and other things in the upcoming years.
Now it's too early to switch all your projects to the swift UI because it will be only effective as
of us 13.
So it will take a couple of years at least.
But keep in mind that this swift UI has a great feature ahead.
So let's stop here and continue within the next section.