Hi.
We didn't lecture re going to go ahead and start working on our user interface.
Well I'm going to do I'm going to try and finish our user interface at least most of them so that we
won't focus on user interface anymore.
From that point on every going to focus on coding.
So in the first week controller re going to have design in capability.
Right.
So I'm going to come over here and say refactor and rename.
I'm going to rename this week controller to be signed in V.C. once we refactoring rename this.
It just changes all the names related to view controller in anywhere in the project.
Okay so I'm going to say sign in we see and I'm going to rename this and now that's OK.
So let me come back to my main board and see if you're connected over here from identity inspector as
you can see class name here is changed as well.
Now let me bring in what I need what I need is text fields right.
Because we're going to ask for input from the user like user name like user email and password.
So let me bring in one and then let me open the attributes inspector and say a name or e-mail over here.
First we have to ask for e-mail because it's really necessary to create an account and then we are going
to ask for a user name.
OK.
And then for lust one we can ask for password.
So let me zoom in a little bit so or here I'm going to ask for a password.
And of course we're going to need two buttons.
First of which is sign in.
OK.
So let me make this a little bit bigger.
And this will sign the users in if they have a count.
So let me copy and paste it and bring in another button and this will be a sign up button.
So if they don't have an account they will register from here and let me choose everything from here
and bring down a little bit so that I can have a label over here and I'm going to call this label Snapchat
clone so that we can have a title.
So let's me come over here and say Snapchat clone.
So that's it's Snapchat chrome.
So let me increase the font size a little bit.
So it will look better.
Here you go.
Now I believe we are ready.
So let me give the constraints and then later on we can bring all of these views inside of our signing
we see.
So let me come over here and bring in the e-mail text.
OK so say e-mail texts.
Yes.
It doesn't seem to be working.
And if you get any error like this it should be a bug.
I believe it's because we have changed the name of designing easy.
So let me do a product clean and try one more time.
So let me come over here and say e-mail text.
Yep it doesn't work.
So let me closes down Kay and open it one more time so it will resolve the issue.
So if you ever come across in a situation like this.
So you're certain that you assigned the class in the identity inspector but it still doesn't work.
Just close it down and open it one more time.
You will see it index sync over here OK.
It means that it's indexing the files it's synchronizing the files.
So after the indexing completes you will be able to bring in the viewers one more time.
So I'm going to wait until it's done and then try the e-mail text over here.
So e-mail texts.
Yep.
Now it's working.
So let me bring in the other views as well.
Like this user name text.
So this is going to be user name text.
And then finally I'm going to need my third one the password text.
So this is password text.
And then we're going to have two actions.
First of which is sign in clicked OK and then sign up clicked.
So let me bring in this as well and say sign up clicked.
So here you go.
Now we have the buttons we have the text fields as well.
So we are done over here so let me bring in a tab bar controller because remember we had the tab bar
in our prototype as well.
So let me bring in the tab bar.
So this is going to be our tab bar and we need another run.
But for right now I'm just going to do a Segway from here to here.
If you choose present model Lee and if you come here and choose the identity Inspector you can go for
full screen and then it will be OK.
So over here let me give you an identifier as well so this will be to feed we see.
So I'm going to call this feed we have controller one more time.
So rather than saying item 1 I'm going to say feat and for image.
Yep I believe we have new images over here so that's good.
But I'm going to go for the old one like the F widths circular image.
OK so let me look for it a little bit.
If we can't find it we can just choose a random image right now because we are just doing a test.
Yep.
This one this looks good.
So f circle field so I'm going to do the same thing for upload as well.
So this is where we're going to upload our pictures.
And let me find the new letter with feel circle feel.
So let me find it over here.
Yep.
This one use circle field.
So now it looks good I believe.
Feed and upload.
So what we gonna do we going to bring in the coco touch classes.
Right.
Because we need Coco touch classes for item one and item two.
So say new file and choose Coco touch class and make sure its UI we have controller and say feed we
see once.
Once you do that you can hit next and save it under your current project folder.
Now let me bring this up so that I'm their main story board.
We can choose it but I'm going to go ahead and create the other ones as well.
So this will be upload V.S. OK.
And finally we're going to need another one.
So let me do that as well.
Before we continue.
So I'm going to say new file and new crocodile cottage class.
I'm going to call the settings wi controller OK.
So here you go.
Now we have our we have controllers of course we going to need another one later on but I believe that's
OK for right now.
And since we have so much I'm going to create some groups over here because we're going to have a lot
of file in this project.
So my group will have the name of we have controllers.
So I'm going to choose area we have controller I have and I'm going to bring it under my weave controllers.
So let me make sure this is closed.
And if I bring them over it will just put them under we have controllers folder.
So now it looks a little bit better I believe.
So we can do that for delegates as well.
Right.
So we have this app delegate unseen delegate.
So let me create a new group and call these delegates.
So I'm going to bring in those two inside of my delegates folder.
So now I have a neater look.
So let me come over my main story board and find feed.
We have controller.
OK.
So I'm going to choose feed ABC from the identity inspector over here.
I'm going to do the same thing for upload.
We have controller as well.
So now I have my upload.
We have controller I have my feed we controller.
So let me bring in a new controller.
OK.
And this will be our settings.
We have controller.
So in the settings view controller we going to only have one button.
But anyway we're going to have the Segway.
OK.
And this will be a relationship Segway because we're doing it from the tap bar.
And this will be cold.
This will have the class of settings we see.
So let me choose it.
OK settings we see.
Yep.
That's good.
So let me come over here and say settings.
Ants.
Yep display settings.
And for image we're going to have to find the circular s again so that it will be consistent with each
other.
So I cannot seem to find it.
So let me try to see is this it.
So let me just choose it.
Yep.
This is an s but I believe it's not circular it's kind of square but in the others we have circular.
Even though it doesn't better I'm just going to find the circular one as well so that they will be existent
with each other.
So here you go.
Now we can't see it so we have real nice icons we have real nice tap bar.
So let me bring in the settings bottom over here.
OK so let me place it in the middle of our reel controller.
Let me make this a little bit bigger and I'm going to call this settings and let me give you the constraints
as well.
So say reset to suggest its constraints and let me try to open the assistant editor with settings you
controller and let me bring in this.
And by the way this should be logout or other down settings.
Yep.
So let me bring in the logout and say logout clicked.
So once I do that yeah I still got this error.
So I believe there is something wrong with the project but I'm going to close it down and I'm going
to open it anyway to let it index.
So it should be automatic but sometimes it gets stuck like this.
So I believe we're good to go after this index is itself.
So once it's once its index is I believe it would be better for us because it would work on feed ABC
and upload V.C. as well.
So let me say logout clicked and here you go.
Now it works.
So we're done with settings and in the upload we're going to have only one image and also an upload
button.
So this is very easy.
So let me bring in one image of you ok like this.
So let me bring in and we can make this ad a little bit bigger than usual I believe because we're only
going to have this one really so after that we're just going to bring in some real small button so it
can be big.
No this won't create any problems.
So let me bring in a button and this will be our upload button.
So let me call this upload.
And here you go.
Now let me just reset to suggest constraints.
And I'm going to give fixed width and height in order to prevent any distortions over here right now.
Once I do that it gives me some errors regarding constraints I'm going to say update constraint constants.
And now it's OK.
Now we can bring in these views inside of our upload view controller as well.
So let me choose this.
And let's see if this works.
So I'm going to call this upload image view.
OK.
And here you go.
Now it works.
So bring in the upload button as well.
So let me delete everything from here and say upload clicked.
So here you go.
Now we are done with upload.
We see.
Let's move on to our feed we have controller.
We are going to have a table over here.
OK so let me bring in the table view and I'm going to say 0 0 0 2.
All constraints to stretch it out because we are only going to have table we are inside of our we have
controller.
So let me bring this in INSIDE OF we've controller feed we have controller.
OK this is going to be our table view.
So here you go.
Now of course later on I'm going to create a new prototype cell in the feed we have controller.
But right now we can just skip it and do it later on.
So let me bring in another controller.
Remember when a user taps on one of these snaps it pops open another controller and displays an inside
of an image slider.
So we'll need another wi controller to display the snaps.
OK.
And I'm going to call this snappy controller so after you click over we have controllers folder.
You can go ahead and create the Coco touch class for SNAP we see.
OK so make sure this is UI we have controller and create this under your weave controllers.
So now I can come over here and I can click over here and choose snap we see from these lists.
So here you go snap.
We see now it says signed as snap we see.
So I'm going to do a Segway from here to here and this will be a show Segway.
It displays as a pop or we're about.
I believe that's OK.
In our case.
So again this will have an identifier and the identifier will be to snap.
We have controller.
OK.
And in the snap controller we're only going to have a timed label and a big image slider right.
And for image slider we're not going to use an old UI image view.
I'd rather re going to bring in another library later on.
Right now I'm just going to create our label in which we will display the time left.
OK so let me say something like time left over here.
So this will display the time left to deletion.
So this will be time left and make it centrally aligned and make does a little bigger so that we can
put it over here.
And here you go.
Now we can just bring this in inside of this snap we've controller and let's control drag and say Time
label.
OK so that's it.
So let's close this down.
And let's not forget to use some suggested constraints over here and we are done with user interface.
Of course we need some more tweaks over here but we're done for most of it.
And now it is time to focus on coding.
So let's stop here and within the next lecture we are going to create users and sign them in.