Hi.
We didn't does lecture.
We're going to change our upload functionality so that we will have two images inside of only one document
so that we can consolidate all snaps and show them in only one post.
So how are we going to do that.
I'm going to show you a way to do that but you can actually come up with a better idea later on if you
want.
So let me show you how this goes when I upload an image.
This will create a document because I'm making it do so rather than uploading one single image.
I'm going to upload an image URL array to the fires store and then later on I'm going to check to see
if the snap owner has previously uploaded that snap.
So if that's the case I'm just going to take the same document and upload a new version of that imagery
so I'm not going to add a new document but I'm just going to update the current document.
OK so before we go on and use the snap dictionary over here we're going to have a check and in fact
this is all related to storage over here right.
So let me write storage and from this point on we're working with fires start.
So we're going to leave the storage as it is because we want to save them to the storage eventually
anyway.
But in the fire store we're going to have an if statement before we do that we have to have an if statement.
So as I said before I'm going to check to see if this snap owner has a previously published snap on
the fire store.
So I'm going to go over here I say fire started that collection snaps.
Okay.
And I'm going to have a very field.
So this very field will look for the snap owner.
So I'm going to say snap owner.
OK.
And this will be equal to user Singleton that shared user info that user name.
And if that's the case then I'm going to get the documents.
I'm not going to add Snapchat listener because I just need to do it once.
So I'm going to say get documents and this will give me either a snapshot or an error.
So in here I'm going to check to see if error is not nil.
So if this is the case I can just show an error error message to the user.
So let's say error that's error that localized description over here with double question marks with
error.
OK and else if that's the case then I should have some snapshot.
But in any case I'm going to check to see if snapshots dot is empty is false.
OK.
And if snapshot is not nil.
So like this snapshot is not nil.
So if that's the case then I should have the snapshot so I can come over here into a forward document
for loop for document in snapshot that documents.
OK.
So I'm getting going to assign every document to a variable called document so that I can get to see
its image you're all right.
OK so let me get the document I.D. because we're going to use it later on as I said before because we're
going to update one single document you're not going to create one.
So we need this document I.D. right so you know how this works as well.
We have seen this in the like functionality in the Instagram clone but don't worry I'm going to show
it show it anyway.
So after that we have to check to see the image your real array.
But right now we don't even have an image url.
We array we just have an image here.
So first we have to make sure that we're saving this in an array not a single string.
So I'm going to come over here to my saving initial saving function and I'm going to call this image
URL array and I'm going to wrap this inside of an array braces so that it will be uploaded as an image
every image your gallery.
OK.
Actually this is just a string array string.
OK so later on I can come over here to my if statement and I can check to see if I can get this image
rural area out of my fires sir.
So let me call this image your Earl area.
I'm using it for because I'm going to change it later on.
So rather than just saying it flat you can just say far and just say document that.
Get image URL array.
I'm going to cast this as an array of strings like this.
OK if that's the case if I can get it what I want to do is to update this.
So I'm going to say image I'll array that append am going to append the newly created image here Elif
over here OK.
And I'm gonna first cast as one more time first line wrapped as one more time.
And if that's the case then I'm going to re upload this to the file your store so that I can update
it in the document that I'm looking for and the way to do this is to qualify your store one more time
and go to the snaps and you have to specify the document path as well because we're only interested
in that document.
So that's how you actually updated document.
You can come over here on set data.
And remember we have to use this merge as well in order to prevent other values from the leading yes
vote.
So let's choose this one.
And remember we have other values over here.
I think we don't say merge it will delete the existing one and we will only end up with the image you're
all airy and we will lose the Post owner and date values.
So merge will be true.
OK.
And the error will be given to us if there is any error you can check to see if error is not nil or
is nil actually.
So if error is nil then we want to go to our feed we have controller over here.
But right now let me create my additional dictionary because we're just doing an additional information
over here we're just uploading an incrementally information.
So we're going to upload the image URL array only and it has to be exactly the same.
So it has to be spelled exactly the same.
Okay.
So be aware of that and you can come over here and say additional dictionary.
So that's it.
That's how you update the value.
Okay.
And of course you're going to have to cut this from here because if that's the case we don't want to
do that.
Right.
But if that's not the case then after uploading my image to the storage then after I check to see if
this snap owner has a previous snap and if that's the case I'm doing my thing to update the value okay.
And if that's not the case if this user doesn't have a previous snap in the fire store then I should
just create a neat document.
Right.
So I can come over here to if var or I believe.
Yep.
This we have to come over here.
Actually we have to come over to the snapshot right.
If snapshot is not nearly it means that I have a snapshot and I how free we is.
Snap over here.
So if I say else then I can just cut my uploading function to here so that if the user doesn't have
any previous snapshot if the user doesn't have any previous snaps then I can just upload a new one so
that I can create a new document over here.
Right.
So this is how our upload functionality will look like this is a little bit complicated than what we
have been doing so far but this will give us a great structure to continue building our Snapchat clone
so if we succeed over here it will take us to the tab bar controller.
And if we succeed over here it should take us to the tab bar controller index 1 as well index 0 as well.
So I'm going to say South tab bar controller that selected index is zero.
And of course I'm going to change the upload image view as well and I'm going to call this UI image
and it will have the name of select image that PMG lets see select image that PMG yes.
So here you go.
Now we are ready to test this.
So let me come over to my father's star and delete everything before we test.
Because I want to see if my original functionality stays the same or not.
And we don't have images URL areas inside of that document anyway.
So after deleting everything just run your new code in the simulator and there comes the moment of truth.
So let me come over here and upload new things.
OK.
Like this one this monkey and hit the upload function and here we go.
Now we are inside of the feed.
So if I come over here and refresh this I can see the newly created document.
Right.
So let's select that document.
And here you go.
Now we have an image rural area rather than an image URL string.
So let's try to add one more image to see if we get the additional image over here.
So if I click on over here and select another picture like this OK and upload it.
So pay attention to the file.
Yes sir.
Let's see what will happen.
Here you go.
Now it got uploaded and it didn't change the documents at all but it only added VAM image URL to the
image you're all right.
And that's exactly what I want.
As you can see now we are seeing the real time updates.
So let me try this one more time and so that we can see it one more time.
OK.
Pay attention to the firestorm.
Once I hit the upload button.
So here we go we clicked the upload button.
It takes a little bit time but it adds the image you're all to the image you're all array.
Now we can use that to create our post creates our snaps and everything.
So that's it for the upload functionality now it's time to retrieve those data to show them in defeat.
We have controller.
Let's do that in the next lecture.