Hi within this lecture regrowing to see how we can make our spaceship more.
And of course we are going to see the other animations as well.
To sum up we're going to end the meta version spaceship and by using this we're going to learn how we
can animate anything that we create or that we bring in the augmented reality as well.
In order to do that I'm going to show you a way and technique to work on.
And later on when we create our own views it will make much more sense to you.
But right now just try to understand that we're working with something called nodes and I'm going to
show you what a node is don't worry and we're trying to reach the nodes of the sea.
So I'm going to create a for loop and within this for loop I'm just going to say for node Ensign view
that scene.
OK so I'm getting this scene.
And in this scene actually we have a root node and child notes.
So we want everything we want every node that is placed in this scene.
OK.
In order to get that you can just call this root note.
So this is the root note of our scene.
And in order to get the child you have to say dot child notes.
OK so this will create a node variable and gets every nodes inside of the scene and assign them to be
our node variable.
OK so let me do it like this child note we that capitalized N and I am talking about nodes all the time
but we haven't seen what our day.
So let me write something like SVM node so we're working with CNN node objects.
Actually you haven't seen it yet but you will see it now.
So if you write a S.A. you will see the object type.
So this is an element that we use to represent a shape or represent a a represent a geometry or an lights
and so on.
In fact this shape isn't much by itself.
OK.
It just defines that our objects reveal be on the space coordinates where our objects will be displayed
in which shape they will be displayed.
And it gets the objects it gets the materials it gets the contents and it displays them inside of our
scene.
When we create our own objects you will much better understand this.
Okay.
So far right now know that we're working with views inside of our receipts.
And if we run no doubt around action we can add an action to them.
So as you can see it asks us to create an ICN action and that's what we're going to do.
There are a lot of CNN actions but I'm going to show you the most common ones for example moving and
objects so I'm going to call this move ship and this will be an in action and a few say adapt and move
by.
It will ask you for an x y z coordinates.
So right now we're working with 3D so we don't have only one X and one Y but also we have Z the Z coordinate
as well.
And we need that duration here.
So x and x is the horizontal and by is the vertical or axis.
And as you know the Z is the third axis.
It's coming toward us or is going away from us.
For example in the z axis.
So for X I'm going to say zero but for y I'm going to say or point five.
And in order to make up an object move further from us we have to say minus.
And if we want them to come closer to us we have to say 0 point 5 and a positive 0 point 5 for example
or a positive one.
I don't know when the metric over here is in meters.
OK.
So don't go crazy over here like a 10 or 20 because it will move the object in meters.
So let me run this on my phone so we can see how it goes and pay attention because we will only see
for like a second.
OK.
So as you can see it opened up and it moved towards me and it moved up a little bit.
So like 500 centimeters I believe.
So let me go back and change the numbers.
Maybe we can't see it better because it's moving toward us right now.
I'm just going to give in that give you the x axis as well and I'm going to make this move away from
us by making this minus so let me run this one more time and be very we're going to see it for a second
only.
OK so here you go.
It's moved a little bit up a little bit right and a little bit further from us.
Now I believe you.
You managed to say it but this doesn't make sense really just to move it for one seconds.
Like a health meter.
OK.
So what if I want to do it repetitively continuously.
Is there a way to do that.
Of course there is a way to do that.
We can call a repeat of the action and we can just repeat whatever we want.
So I'm going to call this repeats forever.
OK.
And this will be an ASEAN action and ASEAN action that repeats forever.
So this will ask us to give an action to repeats forever.
I'm going to say move ship and rather they're running more ship.
I'm going to round the repeat forever over here.
So this will repeat this moving ship action forever.
So let me run this and you will see what I mean inside of my phone.
So let me run my phone.
Let me come over here and you will see it's moving and it will move away continuously as you can see.
Now it's almost leaving my sight.
So it's kind of cool right.
And that's not it.
Actually we can see other actions we can add other actions as well and even we can make a loop out of
those actions.
So let me show you fade in and fade out actions because that that these are common too.
So let's start with fade out.
So this will be ASEAN action.
Dot fade opacity.
OK.
So we have two or passes over here one is two and one is by.
So by is relative value.
And two is we just give the value.
So I'm going to go with two and I'm going to make it all point five.
So this will make this transparent like 50 percent and I'm going to call this fade in and make it 100
per percent.
One more time.
So this will fade out this ship and this will fade the ship in and I'm going to make a loop out of this
tree actions.
OK.
It's called a sequence in here.
So I'm going to call the sequence.
OK.
And let me say sequence and this will be an AC an action one more time.
But rather than repeat forever I'm just going to say sequence this time.
And this will ask me to give an array and within this area I will have the moon ship fade out and fade
in and this time rather than repeating the moves ship I'm just going to repeat this sequence.
And over here I will run the repeat forever action.
So when I run this on my phone you will see my ship moving.
But again with fading in and fading out.
So this will be cool.
Pay attention to here and here you go.
My ship is moving and fading in and fading out.
So this is cool right.
We now see the ship in our living room fading in fading out flying out.
So I believe that's good.
And my dog is still sitting over there.
So here we go.
Now we know how to move around the objects inside of our augmented reality projects.
And I believe it's now time to see how we can bring in the own objects like bringing our own views use
our own textures to create what we want.
And eventually we want to create an application in which we can display some Galaxy's some planets like
Mars or convenience or like Earth.
So let's do that within the next lecture.