Hi.
We didn't expect you re going to see how we can create this fear rather than a box so that we can create
our worlds create our planets so that we can build our solar system app.
So it's easy I'm going to comment this out rather than creating an ICM box.
I'm going to go for a science fair.
OK so I'm going to call this my sphere.
OK.
And this will be an ACNC fear.
And if you open parentheses it will ask you for one radius because the radius will be okay to create
a sphere.
And again I'm going to go for something small like 0.01.
And of course we have to make sure we change this my box to be my sphere in order to add this to our
scene view.
So this is my sphere.
Here you go.
Now we can test this and we will see will that JP G wrapped around our sphere so that we will get a
wooden sphere.
Okay.
So let's see.
Here you go.
Now I believe this is good right.
We can do something with that.
As you can see we have this round image that looks like a planet but it's like a wooden planet.
And it's OK.
And of course we're going to find some textures to wrap around our spheres later on like a virtual texture
or Venus texture.
But for right now we're good to go with that.
So what I'm going to do I'm going to create a function in order to create some spheres later on because
we will add more than one and it will be not efficient to copy and paste everything over here.
It's better to do that with code.
Better to do that with functions.
Okay.
So I'm going to take everything from here.
I'm going to cut them with command X and I'm going to create a function called Create sphere.
Okay.
And under that function I'm going to paste in everything and I'm going to get some inputs over here.
First of all I need the radius.
Right.
And our radius will be as he felt type and rather than saying radius we're going to say radius over
here and we need a content name.
Right.
Like a Would that JP.
So I I'm going to call this content and it will be a string.
And finally we we will need a vector and this will be an ACM vector tree.
So if we give these inputs we can easily create some spheres later on.
So rather than saying Would that JP I'm going to open a parentheses here with a reverse slash and say
content and let me see where the radius is.
Yep it's here.
So rather than single point one I'm going to go for radius.
OK.
And rather than giving the SC on vector I'm just going to give the vector over here so this function
will return some N.S.A. to me.
OK so I'm going to make it return on a C and note and I'm going to return the note over here that we
have created so that we can assign this note to be a variable over here.
For example let me say let my sphere is a create sphere function.
I need to return as a node and over here it will have 0.01 radius and a content of all dots PMG and
a vector of ACM vector tree and open parentheses and I will give the same numbers one more time like
a zero 0.01 or and minus 0 point 5.
And I believe we test this with 0 point 5 all the time so I'm going to change this to be minus 1 and
let me do this something like 0 point 2 so we can see how it looks like our other than saying note of
course we have to say my sphere to make this work and now I'm going to run this on my simulator on my
iPhone actually not simulator on my real device to see if we can see this fear with Waldock PSG.
So let me open my phone and here you go.
We see walled up PSG wrapped around our sphere.
So it's looking good.
It looks like kind of Star Wars planet over here.
So I believe that's good.
Now we can find some other textures to work on but but before we do that I'm just going to show you
one more thing.
In order to verb vids shadows more efficiently you can come over here and say seeing view dots automatically
updates lighting.
And this will be true.
And then I run this.
It will be much better in terms of lighting and in terms of shadows.
So maybe you cannot see it as if it has at this point because it was already looking good.
But in other cases you will see the difference when you do this.
It will take care of lighting and shadows by it so so it will be much more realistic.
It will be much more lively.
Okay.
So I believe we can't stop here and in the next lecture we are going to find some planet textures and
we agree to finalize our solar system app.