Hi within the section going to discuss how we can make money out of those IRS development skills that
we have been monitoring so far.
Now you know how to work with Swift now you know how to do all of ISIS apps.
Now the big question is how we can make money out of that skill set.
Of course there are a couple of ways to do that.
For example you can get a full time IOW developer job.
And of course there are pros and cons for that.
For example you will get a stable income every month and that's a big pro because you won't be thinking
about what project that I'm working on next.
So if I cannot make a project how I will just pay my rent or something.
But of course there are calls as well.
So you will be doing what you're told so you will be only involved in a small part of an app development.
Most probably for a long period so you will be mustering some skills but you will be left out of or
from others.
So you know how this works.
You work 9 to 5.
Most probably 9 to 9 so you will be working after hours and you will be getting your paycheck every
month.
So in fact at this point it's your call to whether I apply for a full time job or not because you have
other options as well.
For example you can try working freelance right and there are pros and cons for working as a freelancer
as well so you will be getting some projects and you will be making and delivering these projects in
a given breed of time.
When you work as a freelancer and for example you will be free when you do that.
You can just work from your home.
You can just work from another country.
You can work while you're travelling.
You can work wherever you want.
Then never you want but of course the money will be in stable.
So if you cannot get a freelance job for a month you won't get paid.
And if you get too much work done you will be working like 7 24 and you will just do your best to finish
the projects that you get and projects can be messy.
At some points for example customers may demand some other extra features and they will try to negotiate
you to do that for the same amount of money that you will initially get for less job.
And of course another con is that you will be working alone whereas in the IRS developer per job you
will be working within a team and working within a team actually improves your IOW development skills
very much because people share ideas people share knowledge with each other when you work in that team
and they aside from all of this of course you can't create your own app as well.
And when you create your own app you can give it that prize and you can sell it with a price.
If you trust your app if you trust if your app you really has some features that any other app does
not in the market so you can sell it for a price and you can have in app purchases or advertisement
in your app as well.
If you're just distributing it for free.
So now if you're distributing it for free in order to make money you can display some advertisement
with Google for example and within the section we going to see how it's done and there are a lot of
calls of pros for this option as well.
A big pro so you can do that while you're working freelance or in a real IOW developer job as well so
you can do that on your own time and you can release your app publish your app in the App Store whenever
you want.
Of course it's not easy as it looks.
For example if you look at very big games they do have huge advertisement budgets.
They get advertisements in their apps but also they give advertisements in order to make people play
their games as well.
But if you make it work then you will have a side income every month flowing into your bank account
so that you can increase your freedom.
Maybe sometime you can build that company out of that app as well.
So within the section we're actually going to see how we can implement ads in our apps so that we can
make money out of that.
So let's stop here and continue within the next lecture.