High within the section where you're going to learn how we can upload our app to the App Store.
And in order to do that I'm going to use a test app so I'm going to create a new app from our X code.
But if you want to use your previously finished app of course you can do that.
OK.
So I'm just doing this for an example and I will show you all the necessary steps to take to upload
your app to the app sir.
So here I'm going to go for a single view app and I'm just going to name this something like app store
test.
So once I do that I'm going to hit next and create my project.
So let me create this under my AOS complete folder and in fact in this lecture I'm not going to go ahead
and upload my app directly because before we go on and do that I want to show you what you can do to
ensure your app is ready to be uploaded.
So Apple is actually very strict about apps.
So they want quality apps in the App Store or else they will reject your app.
So make sure you select some different options from the simulator menu and you try your app in various
simulators to see how your app looks like in different kinds of screen sizes different kinds of phones
and even maybe you may want to plug your iPhone and test your app with a real device and you can come
over here to create new additional simulators as well.
And if you're building for a pad make sure you create some iPad simulators and test your application
in iPad simulators as well.
OK.
So it's very easy to do that.
You just select one of these and created like we have seen before.
So generally when you develop your app you work with one or two simulators but after you complete your
development make sure you adjust your app to different sizes you adjust your app so that you can work
on both iPad and iPhone.
If you want to.
And after that come over to Google and search for Apple human interface guidelines.
So this is a really good documentation to understand what Apple wants from us.
Just click on this and it will take you to the developer dot apple dot com in which you will find some
guidelines about apps.
For example we see some different guidelines in respective for other platforms as well like Mac OS watch
AWS but we're focusing on us in this course.
And when you know swift vine you muster the swift you can easily develop four apps for like a Mac OS
and watch us and other platforms as well.
All right.
Now let me focus on AOS and as you can see there are a lot of explanations and descriptions over here
describing what Apple expects to see in the App Store.
So for example if you come over here to user interaction you can see some modules like authentication
and if you come over here you will see some tips and tricks about you authentication usage in an app
like you can use signing with Apple you can use face I.D. and touch I.D. which we have seen in this
course.
And of course you can find further information regarding two authentication here as well.
So I really suggest you go here and try to read at least the related parts for your app.
OK.
And try to understand what you can improve better in your app to be accepted in the App Store because
Apple doesn't accept every app Apple rejects.
Most of the time actually and they make you improve your app and they make you bring out your best in
your development skills so that you would have some good quality apps in the App Store.
OK and for example when you work with data Apple asks you to have a privacy policy and refer your users
to your privacy policy in case they have questions.
And don't worry I'm gonna show you how this works and how to do that later on in the section.
But I'm trying to make a point here so that before trying to upload your app you have to make your best.
You have to be sure you are trying to improve your app in a way that Apple wants.
Apple guides you.
Okay so that's it.
Actually before you go on and upload your app make sure you try your app on different simulators make
sure you try your app on a real iPhone and make sure you at least take a look at this human interface
guidelines.
And after that of course you will be ready to go to the developer that I pulled out come and create
your certificates and other procedures and upload your app to the App Store.
Now let's stop here and see how we can do that in the next lecture.