Hi.
We didn't his lecture where you're going to see how we can upload our app using x code so that we can
finally submit for review once we're done with all of this configurations.
So let's go back to our project and let's make sure to open keychain and double click on this provisioning
and cert get tools so that they will they will be included in our key chain.
And you can actually drag and drop the distribution certificate over here but make sure you double click
both of them.
OK.
You cannot drag and drop the provisioning tools but you can drag and drop the search.
Forget so that they will be included in your key chain so that you would not experience any synchronization
problems regarding to those cert gates.
And later on you can go back to your ex code project re going to do a different thing over here we haven't
done it yet.
So choose generic asked device from here and say product and archive.
So this will kind of compile everything in your project and it will archive your app so it will be ready
to be uploaded as a package.
So once it completes it will create something like this for you.
If it doesn't open you can't come over here to window and find an option called organizer.
So in organizer we see other apps and if we haven't done these archiving thing it wouldn't appear in
here.
Now I can click on this distributes app and of course I want to distribute on App Store and I can just
upload it from here and if I say next it will try to find my credentials and it will try to see if there
is something wrong with my app and I will say next and here it will ask me if I want to do this signing
thing automatically I'm going to say yes because my developer account is already defined in the X code
as you can see it cannot see the distribution certs forget that we have defined.
Even though I know we have created this now we cannot see it over here.
So let me say many certificates and over here if you hit this plus button and select April distribution
it will synchronize your latest distribution certificates with developer that Apple dot com.
Then you can click done and it will just get you a page like this where you can hit the upload and upload
your app to the App Store.
So once you do that it will start uploading process.
And don't worry it's not uploading directly to the App Store after you do that you're gonna have to
go back to your app store connect that Apple dot com and hit submit for review.
OK once it's it got accepted by Apple team then you can just release your app publish your app on the
app store every app is actually reviewed by the Apple team and every update is actually reviewed by
the Apple team so they are very strict on that policy.
So I believe in my case I'm not going to be able to finish this upload section but in real cases you
can just come over here once it's done and fill out every necessary tool and hit submit for review.
The reason that I'm not going to be able to finish this because I'm working in beta X called version
so I'm trying to make this video available before I use 13 comes out.
So now I'm inside of X Code eleven beta.
So in the real life example you won't be dealing with this kind of problem but I don't even have some
logos some icons in my app so I don't have anything in my app so I believe it won't let me upload this
to the app store anyway.
So after you complete your upload all you have to do is just come over here and hit submit for review
button.
So that's it for uploading our apps.
The app store if you're ready let's meet in the next section.