Hi.
We didn't this section regrouping to focus on how to build a website in order to market our app.
Right now you know how to create mobile apps in the U.S. and you know how to upload them to the App
Store as well.
But it doesn't end there unfortunately you got to market your app so that you can have in stone once
you have enrolled using your app.
Right.
And we are going to see how we can build this website with the Web hosting package that comes free with
this cars.
And we are going to see how we can use vert press in order to customize this page so that we can change
whatever we want whenever we want.
And also remember we had to have a privacy document to show to the user in argued to upload our app
to the App Store as well.
So we're going to learn how to do that in this section as well.
And in the Eco Web hosting that code at the UK.
Now you should have a free count if you haven't watched the second lecture of discourse in which you
learn how to get free stuff.
I suggest you go back and watch it and sign up in the Eco Web posting that the UK so that you can have
your free back posting.
Of course you don't have to use eco Web hosting but since you have a free vote posting for one year
why not.
We use it as you can see we have a lot more features in eco Ecolab posting but right now we're interested
in creating and hosting package.
OK.
So click on this hosting package and you you get that come up with a domain name.
For example I'm going to go for cat years 2016.
Let's suppose that I'm building an app showing the cat years OK the age of the cats.
So I'm going to name this cat years 2016 dot com and fact the domain name and housing are completely
different things.
So domain name.
Is this the name of your Web site and hosting is value save your Web site.
For example we're going to go forward this advanced unlimited linux server to save our Web site.
So after you choose this just click on this create hosting package and this may take a few moments to
create your server and create everything that you're going to need in order to have your Web site.
OK.
Now after that you will be presented in a page like this.
And it will be e-mailed to you how to log in.
But let me show you how to log in easily.
All you have to do is just go to this Web site code that UK CB list domains.
This will list the domains that you have created hosting for and as you can see I have a lot of domains
over here but you will just on the sea once and that is the one that I'm looking for.
OK.
So after you click on this domain it will take you to the set up page and in the setup page you're going
to be presented with a lot of options.
That's going to look for wordpress because remember we're going to use WordPress to create our Web site
and you're going to see what WordPress is.
Don't worry.
So here you go.
We now see these options like files e-mail and Web states sigs and logs and everything.
But we're looking for work press tools.
So scroll down until you see wordpress blog after you see it just click on it.
It will take you to this Web site.
And in fact we're going to do only one thing over here we're just going to activate the word press install
it on our servers so that we can set it up and start using it immediately.
But in fact you have to wait like maybe an half an hour or end up to an hour in order to activate this
because this will require scripting to be effective scripting to be active on your hosting.
It generally takes something like an hour to be active.
OK.
So after you are sure that you waited for an hour or an half an hour you can just click on install.
If you get an error just you have to wait a little bit more.
But if you don't then you're OK.
So here you have to choose your domain name and domain name is actually something that you should buy.
OK.
This is a service provided by eco Web hosting as well.
But you can just get your domain name from other services as well and use the free hosting that comes
with Ecolab posting if you want to buy a domain name you can't just go to Ecolab posting that calling
out the UK C.P. and sign up.
And again you don't have to do this at this point if you don't want a domain name you can just go for
it is say 1 9 1 7 0.
Think and this is completely free.
This is the IP address of our hosting.
OK but if you want to have a domain connected to your IP address then you're going to have to buy it.
So here I'm just going to install the WordPress buzz.
But as you can see it tries to go to these domain names which we don't have at this moment because we
didn't buy it.
So I'm just going to cope with this I'm pasted over here.
OK.
With slash index that BHP in order to make this work.
Once I do that it will take me to the set up page initialization page of the WordPress.
So here you go.
I'm going to choose a site title which is can't years and I'm gonna go for a user name admin and it's
actually not a good idea to go with admin user names so just write your own name over here and use a
strong password.
And I'm just going to go for the default one and after you give your email you can just hit those safe
Wordpress and let me say this to lust past.
This is just the software that I use in order to save passwords.
You don't have to do that and I'm just going to say log in and it will take me to the log in page.
So we're here.
I'm just going to say admin and I'm just going to use the password that I have created.
OK.
So after you do that you can just say you remember me and tried to log in.
So once you do that it will take you to the dashboard of the work press.
So in order to reach the dashboard you can use this slash WP dash admin think and if you see something
like this saying please update now you can just click on this please update now in order to update your
WordPress I really suggest you do that before you dive into anything because of WordPress is so commonly
used and hackers know that.
So they try to hack the websites they are using Wordpress and work presses constantly releasing security
updates.
And if you update your work press it won't be a matter for you.
It won't be a problem.
But don't forget to update it.
So once you do that you can just go over to these dashboard one more time in which you will see some
options.
So WordPress started as a blogging template.
OK.
So you will see a lot of write your first blog create your first post and everything but in fact we
can use this word press in order to create Web sites as well.
For example if you click on visit your Web site you will see our Web site is currently something like
an empty block but we are going to take care of that and make it look of some like this using this free
team that we can gather in WordPress as well.
Now let's stop here and within the next lecture we're going to use this Apps team in order to make a
stunning Web site.