Hi.
So far we have been learning care about a U.S. development.
And actually we have learned a lot so that you can create your own apps you can make money out of your
own apps.
You can apply to be an professional AOS developer and so much more.
But right now you don't know how to do a design a simple design like you don't know how to engage in
user interface and user experience situations.
So I'm going to show you a way to enhance your design skills.
OK so re going to be working with design software is we going to see how we can create easy images to
use in our apps so that we can take care of little image you lead a live visual problems.
And in order to do that we have to come up with a software that tool to work on.
So I'm going to show you a couple of alternatives so that you can choose one.
So if you come over here to Google you can search for our first option which is sketch.
Actually it's not our first option where you're not going to use this because it's not free but it's
a very popular tool.
And in fact I believe this is the first choice when it comes to you eye and you X design for mobile
apps.
And it goes like this sketch dot com.
OK.
So this is a digital two designed to as you can see it kind of looks like this where it lets you create
new good designs for your mobile apps.
And the other two that I'm talking about is the adobe extreme.
So if you search for it they'll be extinct.
Will being you in a Web site like this so deep as you can see this is the adobe Steve Web site.
And if you search for the Big Steve I believe you can just easily find this.
And the most beautiful part of this this is for free Adobe.
Steve is completely free.
Where as you're going to have to pay for this catch.
I believe they're pretty much the same.
And since we're not looking for to be a designer or a UI UX person I believe we're good to go with Adobe
Steve because they're almost the same thing.
And Adobe.
Steve for free and you have to pay I believe like a hundred dollars per year for a sketch.
Right now I have sketch in my computer as you can see I pay for it and because I I got used in a long
time ago and Adobe still only came out like a couple of years ago.
So I'm still using this sketch as you can see it's pretty easy to use this and you have seen me doing
some stuff some visuals on my computer before in the development section as well.
But right now I'm just going to go with it.
They'll be Steve.
So as you can see if you come to the pricing of sketch you will see.
I will ask you for a hundred dollars to pay and it will only give you one year of updates.
So if you want to update your schedule later on then you're going to have to pay it one more time.
So it's not cheap.
It's kind of a hundred bucks like getting an apple developer account.
So it's kind of an expensive to be an IRS developer as you can see but you can make it for free as well.
So I really suggest you come here to.
That week Steve's Web site and just download this and if you have any existing tools on your computer
like photoshop or something then you're more than welcome to follow the section with Photoshop as well.
We're going to discuss why are we using Adobe d rather than Photoshop and other tools later.
All right.
Now if you click over here it will ask you to create an account.
So this is an Adobe account so it won't ask you for a credit card or something.
So if you just click over here to create account you're going to have to give your first name last name
email and everything and it will create the account for you.
So since I how an account let me come over here and sign in and I don't want to go to any phone number
or we're here right now.
After that you can just come over here and it will ask you for permission to download.
If you click on Download it will download not the adobe Steve but this Adobe Creative Cloud application
for you.
OK.
So maybe you're going to have to do some little installing but I believe you can do that.
If this asks and as you can see in my kids in my case it won't asking a thing it just opens this up.
And as you can see this is a tool to manage old adobe softwares.
Right now I only have extreme in my computer about Adobe has a lot of other tools as well like Photoshop
actually belongs to the adobe itself.
So after you install these tools as you can see you can update them using this Adobe too easily.
As you can see there are a lot of options over here but I'm just going to go with Adobe Steve and I
don't even know what those bios software is do.
Most of them actually.
And you.
You can use the photoshop if you have it on your computer.
As I said before but photoshop is actually for editing the photography doing some big images of focusing
on editing and creating new visuals.
But in Adobe 60 and in sketch we focus on designing mobile apps.
So if you see the install button right next to the adobe.
Just click on it it will start to download it for you.
OK.
So after you download you can come over here to your launch pad and find the adobe steam or you can
hit Commandant space in your computer to find the adobe 60 and open it as well.
Right now I believe my yeah my update is completed for me so if I click over here to open it will pop
open at page like this.
So when you see this maybe you can see some little differences as well because Adobe the actually gets
updated every month.
So that we is doing a very good job of keeping this up to date.
They're very current.
They're adding new features to the other weeks every month.
So it's kind of super cool.
OK.
And don't hesitate to try out this catch as well you will see it's doing the same thing either as Adobe
is.
So if you're thinking that I'm missing out something in sketch because I'm not paying for it that's
not really the case.
OK.
So after you select this then you're ready to go into the next lecture because that's where we're going
to create our first project.