Hi.
We didn't this lecture we're going to create our first project on.
They'll be the envy you're going to see the overview of the next two legs.
So as you can see we're not presented with some predefined sketches like predefined layouts for our
project.
For example we can't see the iPhone acts we can see the eye pad and so much more.
And it doesn't even matter what we choose over here because we can't change it afterwards.
It's called something like art board and we're going to see what an art board is and how to change it
as well.
Don't worry so if you see something else over here like an iPhone access Max or other iPhone access
it's really super cool to just go along with something because later on when you choose one of them
you will see how you can change it easily afterwards and you can even create your custom size.
You can just specify some dimensions like 300 to 300 because you will get to change it afterwards as
well.
So I'm going to double click on this iPhone X and as you can see it creates me the project.
And now we are inside of our Adobe Steve.
So here very we do the design.
Okay so we do design in this little blank box over here and it's called an art bought.
So if we click on some things we will see these Inspector her right hand sides on the right hand side.
So it's called the property inspector like in X code actually.
So it's almost the same and we click over an object we see its properties on the right hand side for
example we can see the width we can see the height and other attributes over here.
And if we had any other view if we click on them we will see the related attributes related properties
on the right hand side as well as you can see I can't change the within height as I want.
So it doesn't make sense to choose anything in here when we create the project.
In fact it makes sense to choose something but it doesn't matter because we get to change it like this
easily so we can make this bigger we can make the smaller we can create another template for another
phone we can do whatever we want.
We are completely free over here.
OK.
And on the left hand side we see some views that we can bring in like a rectangle like an ellipse or
like an art board.
So we're going to see a we have one of them one by one in the section.
Okay we're going to test them all.
And over here we have an extra menu as you can see and it's called plug ins for me if you come over
here to view.
If you don't see the plug ins like this you can open this menu up and you can change it to assets or
layers.
We're going to use layers most of the time because we can see different views different objects inside
of our outboard or inside of our haste boards.
OK.
So this gray area is actually called pasteboard so we can create views inside of place where we can
create views inside of an art part.
So pasteboard is actually infinite.
You can have as many as art boards or as many as views inside the inside of this pasteboard.
So why do we even need an art board.
Right.
So it's actually to see better when we deal with a frame like this.
So we're if we're trying to design something for iPhone X. Now it's very good idea to use iPhone X as
a frame.
If you come over here to this prototype section you can see we can create some prototypes like this.
So if we have more than one art person we can connect them together like as if we have been creating
say grace.
Okay.
And we can actually play this in a simulator like view so that we can see how it looks like on a real
life form and we can't if we were designers already fever aiming to be and UI UX people then we can
just create these prototypes and we can just passes along to the developers to say yeah I have created
this design for you.
Can you just implement this on your code on your app.
And we're not going to be using prototypes very much in this section in this course because this is
not a UI UX course.
It's just to get you a long to create basic visual basic images in your own apps.
So if you hit this play button over here then you get the simulator like V where you can actually play
the prototype by yourself so we have our menu as you can see.
Are we going to see the different menus different options that we have over here.
And I believe that's it for over real.
So let's stop here within the next like you're going to start inspecting these views one by one.