Hi within this lecture we going to see the text and the outburst.
So let's start with tax because it's pretty easy you can just write something when you choose tax like
this OK and you get to change its properties over here.
Like this you can just make it lower case upper case you can just make this a superscript subscript
you can change its alignment you can change its form like this but in order to change the font in order
to increase the font size you have to make sure that you have enough space like this OK so that it would
take effect.
So if you hit your upper arrow over here you can increase the font size you can change the font by clicking
over here like that and you can even change the full color of the font like that.
OK.
So you can change any color that you want from the coloring spectra were here and you can do it.
You can even give some borders to your fonts and you can even give some shadows as well.
So it's pretty easy to work that text like that and if you double click on a attacks you get to edit
it.
And in this case editing means just adding some new characters or leading the characters.
So as an example let me delete everything from here and we can do the tap to select in image thing that
we have done in the previous section.
OK so let me create a rectangle right now like that.
OK.
And let me delete the border so that I can come over here to tag so I can just create a text or a year
and say tap to select.
After that I can just select the select tool and just make does a little bit bigger.
And then I'm going to give some white color to my text and let me put this over here and try to adjust
is a little bit so that it would be more central like that.
So here you go.
Now we can export this and use it on our projects and we're going to see how to export we use and how
to use an x code later on.
Don't worry.
Right now I'm just doing some practice to show you that you can really easily create visuals to your
using your own apps and there is a zoom over here and it's pretty basic so if you just choose it you
can zoom in or zoom out like that.
OK.
And here we have the art part.
So if you choose the art part if you click some are some there over here in your password it will just
add a new art part.
And as we have discussed before art birds are just too great.
Great.
Give us some frames so that we can easily do our design like that so we can just choose any size that
we want from here like an iPhone or an eye pad or an Android phone and we get to change its size once
we created like that.
So I you can just create any art bird that you want that you can use it like a frame or we're here and
we can actually put some views in the pasteboard as well but we generally prefer doing that in the airports
so that we can really see what will our design look like in the real foam.
OK.
So that's why we're using art boards actually to be more structural to be much more organized and to
see better what our design will look like in the real life.
So let's stop here and continue within the next lecture.