Now that we have the foundation of a program and program management, and how
these both help enable a business unit to achieve its business goals, let's go
through an example of designing program requirements.
Let's say the executives of the sales and marketing business unit meet
and arrive at the following business unit requirements.
They want to increase revenue, they want to open markets in the UK,
and they want to develop a new product.
These are the three main business unit requirements.
The executive team decides to set up a program focused on increasing revenue.
They set up a program management office and select a program manager.
The executives and the program manager set up a stakeholder
team that will be led by the program manager.
The program manager and the stakeholder team decompose the business
unit goal of increased revenue as follows: increase order revenue;
improve customer order stickiness, that is,
after a customer orders something, can we keep that
customer coming back for more; and lastly,
at least equal the competition for ease of ordering, since
our ordering interfaces are a bit clunky.
So we have moved from business unit requirements to program
requirements, and typically this process needs a seasoned
experienced business analyst to help out.
Now we want to determine the program application domain, that
is, what applications will be affected.
Here are our program requirements from the previous slide.
Now the program manager,
stakeholders, and business analysts need to determine which applications,
systems, and operations would be affected by the program
requirement to increase order revenue,
improve customer order stickiness, and equal the competition for
ease of ordering. The program manager and stakeholders determine
that the vehicle order system, the order management system,
the vehicle allocation system, and the dealer customer
support operations center will all be affected by the
business unit requirement goals.
But we still don't know the impact to each of those systems,
so let's go to the next step.
Now we need to determine the application requirements
for each of the identified systems.
On the left are the four systems that the program stakeholders identified.
For each system, the business analyst needs to do the following: identify
the application stakeholders, contact information, and stakeholder type for
each application domain. Determine involvement, there are application
stakeholders we'll want to inform, consult,
partner, and then there are the decision makers. Determine the
interactions, identify forms of communication and interactions
with each application stakeholder.
Please recall, these are all the steps we set up in the relationship
model in preparing to work with any stakeholder.
We're doing our homework and we're doing our groundwork,
and we're progressing step by step.
Let's do a quick recap.
Sales and marketing define their business unit requirements, those are the
high‑level requirements for a particular business unit.
A program was designed and defined to tackle one of those
requirements, the increase revenue business unit requirement.
We also set up a PMO, program management office, and selected a program
manager and stakeholder team to help steer the program.
Next, the application domain was identified,
and there are four applications in that domain,
and we performed our stakeholder preparation as to whom to
work with and what the interaction will be.
But before we drill down further and perform more
decomposition into epics and features, let's transition for a moment to discuss the broader business analyst role.