In our journey from waterfall, let's now look at a few models,
spiral, RAD, and Rational Unified Process, that,
in a sense, they were the prototypes of agile and lean.
Spiral put a real strong placement for earlier requirements.
This model is also known as a discovery‑based model.
Because this model helped answer the early questions
that executives and fiscal people ask, that is,
how much and when,
we learned much faster in the cycle about what it
would cost and how long it would take, but those estimates were indeed softer,
but at least that's a good start.
So in a way, this was a compromise approach.
Rapid application development Has a good ring to it, doesn't it?
Software process model coming on board in the late '80s and early
'90s. It had iterative development and construction.
Well, we like that.
Incrementally increasing feature capabilities.
Well, we like that too.
Also associated or called 4th generation languages,
such as products like NOMAD, FOCUS, and many,
many others.
Speed of deployment and feedback was the primary goal
over performance and capability.
Customers couldn't wait to get data out of the mainframe without
having to wait for long project lifecycles.
They needed data now.
So it was used more for analysis and decision‑making applications,
and not so much for operational transactions, unless
there was really a small amount of data.
So RAD brought the advent of prototyping to
functioning results very quickly indeed.
I was lucky enough to lead a RAD project many years ago.
We developed an HR decision‑making tool in one week.
Yes, it was a bit crude, and it wasn't the best performer,
but we beat the mainframe team.
In fact, the mainframe team was still working on the estimate,
and we were done with our project.
It's things like this that drove users, managers,
and executives to push IT for better ways to do things.
RUP, or Rational Unified Process, began in the late '90s, and is still used
today. Based on the spiral model more than the RAD model,
it applied to large‑scale application development projects,
not small projects, really.
The tools had a really big footprint. Needed to invest in it,
do a lot of training, and things like that.
It embraced the fact that the steps can overlap,
unlike waterfall,
where the steps don't overlap, so that's a lessons learned from
waterfall. And it has the following phases: inception,
elaboration, construction, and transition.
Okay, here are a few more items.
Developing requirements with RUP is certainly better than waterfall, so
here a few more points. Requirements gathering was spread over the
inception and elaboration phases, and RUP embraced requirement changes
throughout all the phases, so that is better,
whereas the waterfall was more like a bolt‑on process.
So if you're curious,
here are some example products that you might want to dig into.
Rational Software Architect, AWS CloudFormation, ER/Studio Data
Architect, erwin Data Modeler, Planview Enterprise One, and
Sparx Systems Enterprise Architect.
You can check these out and see if you have any interest in looking into these.
Here are our historical lessons learned.
We began moving away from big upfront requirements design.
Requirements were now spread across multiple phases.
That's good. We added in a notion of discovery‑based approach, that is,
learn a little, adjust, learn a little more, and then dive into development.
We also began using lighter‑weight documents and
artifacts, such as vision statements, use‑case models,
data models, and others,
which took less time to define and enabled an iterative process to
unfold. So we are starting to show results quicker.
Please also note: technology and tools have changed, which enabled this to happen easier.