Now let's emphasize the benefits of requirements
gathering in an Agile environment.
As you have already realized, requirements gathering with Agile is different.
Let's emphasize two Agile principles,
highest priorities to satisfy the customer and welcome changing requirements,
even late in the process.
Those will drive the underpinning of any Agile or Lean
requirements development process by being flexible,
that is adaptable to change, interactive with the customer,
and just‑in‑time.
For those not familiar with just‑in‑time,
or JIT, it is basically, don't do anything until right before you need it.
And in our case, it means don't write detailed requirements until you need to.
If you write them early and wait four months until you develop,
they will likely be only 80% correct, if you're lucky.
So writing requirements too early can be a waste.
This doesn't mean, though,
writing high‑level epics or high‑level user stories early,
to at least put a frame around a requirement,
is a waste.
You need to decide what makes the best sense to you and what level of
requirements and detail requirements you need to do and when.
Let's take a moment to look at the different
adaptive methods commonly used today.
You can see that Scrum, or a variation of Scrum,
accounts for over 70% of practitioners,
so we'll take the next slide to quickly give you the highlights of Scrum.
If you are curious about other statistics around Agile Scrum and Lean,
check out the reference below from the 13th Annual State of Agile Report.
It's quite interesting.
The most popular of all the Agile project management
methods and approaches is Scrum, and I like it a lot.
Scrum uses the concept of a backlog,
which is a prioritized list of all things that need
to be completed within a project.
A backlog is comprised of mostly user stories, but again, it can be anything.
A user story is a high‑level definition of a requirement.
Now that's what it is in the perfect world,
but many times the backlog is loaded full of very fuzzy requirements,
and it is up to you and your job to try and reduce
those into understandable user stories.
Scrum has some predefined rules.
There's the Scrum master, who really facilitates the Scrum process,
but does not do any analysis or development.
Now, I have a ton of opinions on this role.
Anyway, moving on.
the product owner is the focal point for all
requirements and all backlog priorities.
Another role, pretty large role, is the multi‑skilled developer team.
Now, besides being populated with technical engineers,
business analysts can be on this team as well.
That is why I use the term multi‑skilled.
So any skills that are needed for this team will join up.
Timeboxing.
A timebox is just that, a box of time.
That is a limited amount of time for a Scrum event.
And there are many Scrum events, one of which is the stand‑ups.
Stand‑ups are timeboxed to be no more than 10 or 15 minutes, for example.
But again, you can decide on the length of your timebox.
Sprints.
The team will get a fixed amount of work done in a sprint.
Sprints are typically two or three weeks, so it's a two or three‑week timebox.
And the team does sprint after sprint, maybe for months or even years.
Those are iterations.
Sprint planning.
Sprint planning is another Scrum timeboxed event,
and it looks at the backlog requirements and determines which items in
the backlog are to be worked in the next sprint.
I have barely touched on Scrum,
so you might want to check out my class on sprint planning titled,
Developing Effective Agile Sprint Plans.
Now let's apply some of what we learned to your analysis work.
Let's see what discovery iterations might look like.
To mitigate the issue of how much and when,
consider the first release of the system,
that it's a broad analysis of the requirements and is not software.
Gather any stakeholder guidance, direction,
high‑level scope, and chunky backlog items.
Not too much detail here.
Remember, too much too soon is not Agile.
Consider each iteration of the requirements gathering as an
opportunity to produce more refined requirements.
Provide feedback to your stakeholders and solicit guidance with each iteration.
Here's a simple example of your discovery iterations.
Maybe in iteration 1 you document the vision and capture
epics and high‑level user stories.
In iteration 2, maybe you create workflows,
diagrams, and other high‑level analysis artifacts.
And maybe in iteration 3, create screen prototypes and wireframes.
And iteration 4, maybe create some screen mockups,
data model, and some business specification documents.
After every iteration though, there are reviews with your stakeholders.
Now,
it may be that your findings are such that there is no reason
to move any further forward since there is no return on
investment or value to the company.
That's okay.
Or, it's exactly what they want,
and then you'd begin to assemble a full Agile team to accomplish your
findings and build a complete complement of a development team,
with your participation.
Agile Scrum is not just for making software.
It could be used for making any product, such as a discovery specification.
Let's see how Agile optimizes the return on investment for a company.
Let's compare Waterfall with Adaptive methods.
With Waterfall, the ROI begins at the end,
that is when the software is fully deployed.
That may take some time to get there.
With Adaptive, the ROI begins at the end of the first iteration,
and again at the second iteration, and again at the end of the third generation,
and so forth and so on.
We call that Cumulative Feature Delivery.
As you can see,
the business begins to realize more immediate benefits
and value with Adaptive methods.
Here's an update on the triangle dilemma.
With Waterfall, the dilemma was we have a fixed scope,
and then we determine the schedule and resources.
With Agile, it's flipped around.
We have a fixed date that is the end of each iteration,
and we apply whatever resources to the team as needed.
We also get dependable delivery of working software
at the end of every iteration.
So we have a greatly improved quality, and,
well, that's me on the left being excited.
I love Adaptive methods, I love Agile, and I love Scrum.
It works really, really well and adapts well for any kind of thing you're building.