Now, let's look at analyzing the optimal agile team composition.
In other words, who should be on these teams?
You want to build each agile team to best complete the requirements,
so you will use your business analysis skills to
influence the optimal agile team composition?
So many companies are organized in the following way.
You have a business unit like engineering,
marketing, sales, manufacturing,
etc., and let's say this business unit is sales and marketing.
And we have an IT organization with developers,
test engineers, user interface and experience engineers,
and business analysts.
Of course, there are other business and IT roles not shown,
but I want to make this example a little easier.
In traditional development, and it still happens today everywhere,
work is given to the IT organization, and the requirements are separated,
and then they're passed down to each department or team separately.
Now, I'm okay with the organization per se,
but not how the work is passed down and assigned.
The better approach is to create horizontal agile teams.
You can see here we have an agile team, F1,
formed by members of 6 vertical groups, and the same here with F2,
another feature team, and the same here with H1,
and this is a hybrid team of features, user stories,
and services.
With this approach, we have removed the functional silos,
and we are much better positioned in adding value to the business.
Multi‑discipline teams are always better.
They're diverse, different points of view, and produce better outcomes.
Let's recap what we just covered and emphasize the benefits.
We organized the requirements users stories by feature team,
service team, or a hybrid team.
We then horizontally created the agile teams by members
of vertical functional organizations, where we need the skills and talents from.
Our two benefits is that we optimize the user story
work packages to the right teams,
and we optimize the agile team membership from the functional organization.
And even another benefit is keeping like people and skills
together in the functional verticals, thus enabling technical growth,
knowledge transfer, and career pathing.
We have covered driving epics to user stories,
assembling the user stories in the backlogs,
and assigning the backlogs to the appropriate agile multi‑functional teams.
Sounds good so far, right?
But it's not quite enough at the business unit or program level.
We need to analyze and develop a roadmap on how
best to release the user stories.
We need to set priorities and plan one of the best
features and user stories to do and win.
So to do that effectively,
we need a roadmap to provide a view we can use to communicate our
objectives to our product owners and stakeholders.
They want to know,
maybe even demand to know, the general idea as to what features
will be provided and when will they be provided.
Roadmaps are pretty basic and consist of planned release dates and a
list of prioritized features and user stories.
It is not in concrete and can be revisited,
say,
every other week or maybe once a month in the team of
teams or scrum of scrum meetings.
And at the program level, we don't have just one stakeholder,
but maybe four or even eight stakeholders,
all competing in negotiating to get their stuff first.
This is why an agile release schedule is essential,
and what I mean by an agile release schedule is that it should not be fixed
but be flexible and adapt to changing business requirements.
Remember, release features span multiple backlogs and agile teams,
thus requiring thoughtful leadership.
Let's look at an example of mapping our backlog items into a release roadmap.
Here's our timeline,
and I have set up R1's features and user stories for
October 14th and then R2 for November 30th,
and lastly, R3's features and user stories for January 15th.
Notice my numbering system.
I give a feature number like F1, followed by the user story numbers.
Because I don't have much space on this slide.
I would follow each user story with the text of the user
story so we know what it means very easily.
And also, if we had multiple epics,
I would add that to the numbering system as well,
like I've shown, E1.F1.US.3.
Each release lists user stories that are from multiple backlogs,
that is, agile teams, so you should track that as well.
Since we gave user stories to the agile teams by
feature number on an earlier slide,
we are already tracking it just by looking at the F or the H number,
F for feature team, or H for hybrid team.
But if a team could have multiple features to implement,
that is multiple user stories, then you want to track those as well,
maybe something like this, E1.F1.US.3, (assigned to T3).
That way,
it's very easy see in the release schedule which team is working on which item,
what the user story is tied to, that is the feature,
with the feature's tied to, that is the epic,
things like that.
You can only do this if you have deep business knowledge and analytical skills,
but it should be done as a team, of course.
Trust me, your product owners, managers,
executives will ask you the following question. When will I get my features?
So you better have a roadmap.
This roadmap is dynamic and agile, that is, priorities
will change as dictated by the business, and you must adapt the release map as needed.