Hello, and welcome.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module,
Applying Key Learning Objectives, in the course, Best Practices
for Effective Requirements Gathering. Well,
you made it through the course.
Congratulations! The outcome of this module will be to cover the key
points of this course and encourage you to begin applying what you
have learned quickly and successfully.
I won't just reiterate things,
but instead illuminate topics that are important and provide key takeaways.
In my opinion, the business analyst role is undervalued and underappreciated,
but only you can change or improve that perception.
Hopefully, by applying the ideas, techniques, and methods you've learned,
you can truly change your organization for the better.
Here are the highlights of the module, The Value of Requirements. The
toughest part of requirements development isn't the act of documenting
what the users need, but is the process which results in helping users
discover that what they need provides business value. I truly believe
that how you gather, specify,
analyze, and recommend requirements can make or
break an organization or a company,
and that is why you need to have a solid analysis framework with processes and
effective soft skills. By adopting Agile and Lean approaches,
tools, and techniques such as Scrum and Kanban into your
requirements development process, you can minimize, but not
eliminate the uncertainty of requirements,
but greatly improve the quality of your requirements' outcomes.
We talked about setting up your own requirements' backlog with
iterations to manage and drive your analysis work activities.
Create your own requirements development framework.
This is comprised of your artifacts, templates,
checklists, processing tools, training,
etc. so that you can quickly pull out and use.
You want them to be Agile and Lean oriented and
suited for each business context.
Keep this with you no matter where you work.
Here are the highlights of the module relationships, The
Secret to Successful Requirements.
The secret to developing quality requirements is through influencing,
nurturing, and cultivating relationships with all your colleagues.
Those relationships will yield the requirements you need.
One area I emphasize was identifying,
classifying, and collaborating with your stakeholders in
creating a stakeholder preparation template.
Work closely with them and design your collaboration from what they
want from you and not what you want from them.
The business analysts is a key integration point or bridge
between IT and the business. Therefore,
you need rock‑solid interpersonal and communication
skills to best accomplish your role.
Interpersonal and communication skills are a must,
and there are many, as noted in the module.
But here are my top five, team builder, able to motivate,
dependable, flexible, and you are an amazing presenter.
Here are the highlights of the module of the
evolution of requirements gathering,
sequential and stepped requirements and the triangle dilemma.
We discuss how the sequential and step process for
developing requirements and systems, also known as waterfall,
could not accommodate changing requirements and business dynamics,
thus resulting in more defects and lower quality.
Hence,
it forced us into the triangle dilemma where schedule and cost
dominated requirements. Next up, incremental and iterative
requirements development was a great learning laboratory,
and many of the great ideas from this phase were carried
forward. Adaptive or Agile requirements, well,
we learned much from those previous models,
and we incorporated incremental results provided over multiple iterations and
also inserted prototyping and lighter‑weight specifications.
We explored Lean as a requirements gathering approach, and in particular,
Kanban is the most adopted method of requirements and systems development using
Lean. Initially, Agile and Lean will make users nervous for a few reasons,
something new, it changed the way we do things, it appears less predictable.
Yet, it is actually more predictable,
and we emphasize that you would need to educate and support your
customers and users and stakeholders on how Agile and Lean can
provide more consistent value to the business.
The next three module summaries is where I will summarize
the requirements development by context.
The first was working on smaller teams focused on a single system or a
few systems that are called the product context.
Second is the business unit or program context where
you may have dozens of systems,
applications, and complexities that must be managed.
Lastly, the enterprise or portfolio context.
This is the entire enterprise,
which includes all application systems or any CAPEX spending.
The approaches to each of these is different,
and it is important to understand that difference. Also, these
contexts are not cut and dry, and in reality, very fuzzy.
It may even be non‑existent in most organizations,
but as I mentioned,
I need some categorization to help frame the discussions. In this module, we
covered how the business analysts can contribute to requirements development
for a new product, and here are the key takeaways.
We discussed the composition of the Agile product team and how the BA is a
member of that team, though the BA's membership on the Agile/Lean dev teams
is underrepresented, in my opinion. Normalizing the product backlog. We
learned that the product backlog can have all sorts of odds and ends in it
and that the business analysts can normalize those odds and ends into
succinct user stories that can be understood by the product owner and the
technical developers.
There are benefits to normalizing the backlog.
Besides creating quality user stories,
the process itself to normalize the user stories is a mechanism for you to
learn even more about the business domain and to further illuminate the
product owner's understanding of the requirements.
Use the user story template and the invest checklist to
create consistent, quality user stories.
No matter where you are organizationally in your company,
you will have the best success with your projects by
partnering closely with your product owner.
Here are the highlights of the module gathering
requirements for the business unit.
Our goal throughout this module is to manage the effective
use of business unit resources. That takes strong analysis
and interpersonal skills.
Program management strengthens the alignment of resources and goals to
the business unit strategy and ensures better control and focus on
realizing those intended and expected benefits.
I outlined four forms of expressing user requirements, user stories,
features, epics, and themes.
This approach greatly helps us articulate requirements from a
program or system level to features to even broader business unit
or program‑wide requirements, and lastly,
enterprise‑wide requirements known as themes.
Driving epics to user story backlogs,
defining team assignments, and releases, we emphasize your important
role to translate epics into more detailed and refined notation in
the form of features and user stories.
Next, we then propose a method to optimize the workload of features and user
stories and assign them to backlogs of your Agile teams.
All managers and executives want to know when they will get something,
and they don't always care about Agile.
They care about revenue or business, so you will need a release roadmap,
and I provided you with an approach for that as well.
Here are the highlights of the module, Gathering Requirements for the
Enterprise. Portfolio themes are strategic business initiatives.
These are very high‑level and propel a company forward.
It is the long‑term vision of the company that themes represent.
Portfolio themes drive the creation of epics and implement the
theme and portfolio backlogs are the collection of epics and not
the themes themselves.
Themes aren't just business oriented,
but also architectural and technology themes that are
critical to the success of any company.
Both business and architectural themes drive epics. Portfolio management is
essential to ensure the themes are managed and successful.
Portfolio management decides what is to be worked on and the rationale why.
Something we should all keep in mind, changes in technology will drive how we
perform requirements development in the future.
As you see new technologies,
consider adding them to your analyst framework or toolkit.
The professional discipline of requirements development is a continuum,
and you will need to grow and adapt to requirements development skills throughout your professional career.