Hello, and welcome.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module, Gathering Requirements for the
Enterprise, in the course, Best Practices for Effective Requirements
Gathering. Our backdrop for requirements gathering in these last three
modules has been by business context.
In the previous two modules,
we covered how the business analyst would perform
requirements development for a product,
working within an Agile or Lean team, and working with the product owner.
And we discussed requirements gathering in a broader context
within the business unit, also known as a program where you
may have dozens of systems,
applications, and complexities that must be managed. And in this module,
we will cover the requirements gathering in the enterprise or portfolio
context. As a reminder, these contexts are not cut and dry and maybe
not even existent in most organizations.
But as I mentioned, we need a form of categorization to frame our discussions.
Here are our forms of expressing user requirements within an
organization that we discussed in the last two modules,
user stories, features, and epics. And lastly,
in this module, we will cover themes or business strategies, which cover
an entire enterprise's business drivers. The forms in which these are
expressed are described and documented as follows from right to left.
Themes are very high‑level descriptions,
epics may be list points with slightly briefer
descriptions, then comes features,
which are detailed and programmable, and lastly, user stories,
which is the most detailed,
succinct, and follow a well‑defined template used for constructing them.
Here are the topics of this module, the enterprise
and portfolios, portfolio themes, portfolio backlogs,
portfolio management, architectural and technology themes,
epic identification and creating backlogs, the BA's role at an enterprise
scale, and wrap up with my point of view and module summary.
Okay, let's get after it.
This module will focus on the requirements gathering at
still a higher level of abstraction, the enterprise itself,
and we will address the enterprise‑wide requirements process.
The module outcome is to enable you to improve your
enterprise requirements development skills,
including tools,
techniques, and approaches for requirements development from an enterprise perspective.