Now let's talk about portfolio backlogs.
What's a portfolio backlog?
Themes are not part of a theme backlog.
There is no theme backlog.
Themes have a much longer lifespan than do epics.
Epics get implemented, and then they are complete,
whereas themes may be around for a while,
maybe even a long while.
Let's say one of our themes is to develop a brand‑new,
high‑efficiency commercial jet that reduces fuel
usage by 50% among other things.
Well, that jet may be around for 20+ years or more.
Epics deliver the value to the business in support of the theme.
Therefore, epics need to be identified, prioritized, estimated, maintained.
Within the portfolio backlog,
epics are treated just like any other agile backlog.
And, of course, epics drive features and features drive user stories.
Business analysts can help perform these activities,
and it's critical that they do.
Remember our examples of portfolio themes from the last section?
So we have our themes on the left and ideas or examples on how
we might fulfill those themes on the right.
These are likely brainstorming ideas, say,
from a workshop with company leaders and senior business analysts.
Those ideas we had on the right on the last slide, well, they are epics.
You could imagine that you may get 20 ideas or 20
epics for cross‑selling services.
Well, which ones are the best?
Which ones should you do?
So we're going to need a group of people to help identify,
prioritize, estimate,
and maintain the epics in our epic backlog that we created from each theme.
Let's talk about the role of the business analyst or,
I should say, senior or principal business analyst,
since this is definitely a very senior experience role indeed,
something I suggest you aspire to.
Here are the types of activities you would perform: Collaborate
and partner with the executive sponsor or sponsors for each
theme you are supporting; help translate the themes into epics
and ensure they are visible, well understood,
roughly estimated,
and planned; help translate the epics into features
and ensure they are also visible, estimated,
resourced, and in a release,
and I would suggest that you create a team for each epic; using your new team,
help ensure features are further translated,
refined, and articulated into user stories.
Be sure your user stories are in alignment and support the
theme and nothing got lost in translation,
so to speak.
Note: Your involvement will be heavier in the beginning and
will lessen as you move down to user stories.
User stories will be most likely developed by other business
analysts and developers closer to the business domain,
whereas your actions in this role are at the theme and epic level,
and you will really be providing guidance and direction
to those writing the user stories, since you will have in your mind a clear understanding of the theme and epic.