Now that we have identified all the stakeholders that you'll need to
interact with and how you will interact with them, now it's time to
interact and collaborate with them.
Here's a quick definition to make sure we're on the same page.
Collaboration is the action of working with someone to produce or
create something. So not just working with someone, but working
with someone for a specific outcome.
There are two key parts to the elements of collaboration: working with others,
of course, and producing or creating something.
Every collaboration should yield a result. Prior to every
encounter with a stakeholder, have your outcome in mind as to
what you need accomplished in that encounter.
Don't leave an encounter empty‑handed. Collaboration requires a mix of
interpersonal, problem solving, and communication skills that you need
to build and sustain your working relationships in order to produce
your expected project outcomes.
I'm going to already assume you have some pretty good problem solving skills.
In the rest of this module, we will touch on interpersonal skills and
communication skills to make you more effective with those outcomes.
Collaboration and analysis activities. Your analysis activity is to develop
the requirements to add the ability of dealers to order accessories when
ordering new recreation vehicles.
Your task is driving your collaborations with key
stakeholders to better understand this new feature.
Let me mention a few undertakings that will help build
collaboration and solidify your relationships. Requirements
workshops and other discovery activities,
discussing alternative solutions and approaches, maybe there are a few
ways to accomplish this feature, and discussing potential impacts to
development team and the deployment team. Also, discuss whether it could
be a build or buy, evaluation of the resourcing, costs, and skills,
impacts to other projects.
These activities in blue are conducted with your system‑oriented stakeholders,
for example,
product coder, development team, etc. And these in green, you would
likely do with your project or business stakeholders,
for example, project manager,
finance manager, senior IT, etc. The blue are focused on the task
itself, and the green are more like the metadata,
if you will,
of all the extraneous things around the project that are more
financial and schedule, and cost and resource‑oriented. Find
and resolve relationship gaps.
Look for relationship gaps between team members.
Is the health of your team good? If not, determine why not and
try to resolve, even if you're not the team leader, behave as
an individual contributor leader.
Periodically check in with your project manager or leader of
the activity or project you are working on.
Ensure your relationship with the manager or leader is solid.
If not, have a one‑on‑one and get it fixed.
In fact,
I recommend a one‑on‑one regular meeting of at least 30
minutes once a week with your team leader.
If you see a rift in your relationship on a project, and even if
you don't think it'll affect your specific work,
it may well affect the results of the team's work,
which ultimately might reflect on you and your team.
Be proactive, and build and nurture relationships.
Now that takes guts, and you may need to be bold.
We tend to focus on the nuts and bolts of our work, that
doesn't really matter if the team and the stakeholders are dysfunctional. Keep that in mind.