Now, let's look how you can work with your product owner to
develop and create effective user stories.
In order to create effective user stories,
you need a common approach on how to build user stories.
You see, English can be a fuzzy, ambiguous language,
and we cannot code great software from fuzz. Our
user stories need to be succinct, clear, and in a single style.
They need to follow a standard user story template,
and you want to use a common language that is understood by the product owner,
you, the analyst, and the development team.
Here's an approach for building your user stories,
and there are three major parts.
First, the type of user is the who or the role,
for example, a student, a teacher, or a cashier.
Next, you need a goal or an outcome, that is what are you trying to accomplish?
For example, a student is trying to find and register for a course. And lastly,
a benefit or reason for doing the user story in the first place.
For example, the benefit is enrolling in a course.
This is a very common approach,
and you'll find it described in books and articles, so you can
read up on it. Let me show you the user story template that I
use. First is the role. So as a role or type of user, so when
discussing requirements,
try and figure out what type of user does this user story
apply to. Next, you want to achieve a goal or an outcome.
Again, when discussing the requirements,
try and figure out what goal the user will have.
And again, when discussing requirements,
try and figure out what goal the user story will have.
And lastly, what is the benefit, reason, or gain from doing this user story?
Here's an example.
As as student, student is the role or type of user, I can search,
find, and select classes, that is the goal or reason of the user story, so
that I can successfully enroll, that is the benefit.
This approach can be used for anything in the product
owners' backlog, features certainly, bugs,
research, and analysis activities.
You name it.
If you struggle with a user story,
then you need to do more analysis, since that means you
don't know enough about the requirement.
You can see how normalizing requirements to user stories in and of itself is
a tool to clarify and enlighten you on the requirements.
Plus,
if we have multiple product owner authors, we can normalize the
writing styles. This is very important to have a common approach to
improve communication between team members.
What makes a good user story?
INVEST. These are known as INVEST because each attribute that I'll
talk about will spell out part of the word INVEST.
The first, independent. Independent means that a story can be coded,
tested, and even delivered all on its own, that is,
it is not waiting for another story to be completed and can be independently
assessed as to the value to the business. N for negotiable.
A user story can be discussed and potentially accepted for development, a
process of negotiation is conducted between the product owner and the
development team, and very important here, each party respects and jointly
collaborates to arrive at the best approach and solution.
Also, each is aware of the others' limitations and strengths.
V for valuable. The team's most important goals to deliver
the most value to the business, therefore,
I will suggest to you that this is one of the most important INVEST attributes.
Remember, the backlog is prioritized by value and value alone,
hence the importance of this attribute. Estimable. A well‑written
and debatable user story is estimable.
Backlog items can be any size really, but let's face it,
a more decomposed user story is more likely to be estimated with accuracy. In
the event you are facing a challenge of producing an estimate,
then it's quite likely you need to decompose or break down
the user story into smaller stories.
And speaking of small, how big is small?
Well, small,
that is a user story you can finish in one iteration is the most desirable.
Most iteration time boxes that I have observed are 2 or 3 weeks.
That gives you an order of magnitude from an elapsed time perspective.
Smaller stories in your iterations are more likely to come out faster,
but again, it's not uncommon for user stories to span multiple iterations.
Lastly, testable. In the agile and lean world,
all code delivered is tested code, but if you think that the
user story cannot be tested in the iteration,
then it is quite likely that the story is not well written,
maybe linked to other user stories, or just too complex.
Vague and fuzzy words in user stories will usually come to
light when discussing if something is testable.
Now,
don't worry if not all six attributes apply to your
user story, this is a guideline,
but try to do all six if you can. Use the INVEST principle as a
checklist against every user story you write,
and it will greatly improve your team's ability to write them.
Remember, better stories result in better outcomes, yielding value to the business quicker.