Now let's look at how you can work and collaborate with your product
owner to develop and create high‑quality user stories.
One of the most key activities of partnering with your product owner is
not just helping them create quality user stories,
but also guiding them on how best to prioritize the backlog.
The responsibility to prioritize the backlog is owned by the product owner.
Your role is to help them prioritize by providing key information,
guidance, and support that will help them determine the priorities.
Estimates greatly help the product owner make decisions and set priorities.
Let's face it,
will you buy a brand‑new car without getting a quote from a dealer?
Would the estimate of the purchase price help in your decision process?
Well, it certainly does.
So, get good at developing quick, high‑level estimates for your product owner.
Here's a quick priority guideline checklist.
So you'll want to consider value of the item in the backlog,
cost of not doing the item, cost of doing the item,
and return on investments.
Those are some very key ones, but add your guidelines as you see fit,
and use it as a checklist to go one by one through
the backlog to help you prioritize.
I also recommend representing your product owner or jointly
attending the daily stand‑ups as an option as well.
Product owners are busy, very busy,
so they may welcome you helping them by filling in for them at the stand‑ups.
It should not be the norm, but this can provide better project continuity.
Trust me,
developers will appreciate your attendance to keep things moving forward.
Provide any backlog changes, items, and priorities to the agile or lean team.
The product owner may make last‑minute changes,
and you can quickly convey them to the team.
Provide further requirement clarifications to the agile and lean
team so that the product owner is not bothered.
Document the stand‑up outcomes and provide a short and succinct status to
your product owner as a quick email and CC the full team.
Always keep the product owner in the loop if he or she is not available.
Stay true to the product owner's vision, backlog, and priorities.
And remember, you are not the product owner, but partnering and helping them.
Just a note here,
agile and lean team members can fluctuate shape and size over time.
That is normal.
Of course, when team members remain consistent,
productivity is usually much better.
People get used to working together, they understand the cadence,
and the teams really start functioning well.
Product owners may change.
That can happen and can be quite disruptive,
especially if they have a different vision.
So be prepared for a bit of a setback, and get to know your new product owner.
Provide any education,
and build your new partnership using the relationship
templates we discussed in the relationship module.
The number of team members can change based on workloads,
budgets, and company macro requirements,
things really beyond your control.
The types of skills required in a team can change.
For example,
early on you will need more user interface and user experience engineers,
and later, more test engineers.
You will likely have more analysis activities
earlier in a project than at the end, as we previously discussed.
Now roles and skills can be spread over multiple teams,
especially for the examples I just gave you,
user interface, experience, testing, and analysis roles.
Availability of members over time can change too,
such as out sick, vacation, reassigned to hot projects,
and the like.
Being aware of these allows you to plan and adapt to provide better service to your product owner.