Required interpersonal and communication skills.
We have identified all the stakeholders and got all their pertinent
information and documented how we want to interact with them, and we
have some good pointers on collaboration techniques, but we are not
yet done in our preparations.
Let's think through about the required interpersonal and
communication skills that will help us. A quick recap.
Sometimes when we start our analysis activities,
we don't spend enough time or effort really trying to
understand the makeup of the entire user that is
stakeholder community. We've identified,
classified, and determine the interaction with our stakeholders.
So for each of your activities or projects,
these are the people you will most likely be working with.
Then we discussed a prescriptive approach to
collaboration and key collaboration tips.
Now we get to the hard part. Next up, interpersonal and
communication skills, an essential element of success.
Now the first two boxes on the left are relatively easy to understand
and adopt into practice, they are very prescriptive,
but interpersonal communication skills can be more of an art than a
science, but I will try and break it down for you and give you some
important best practices you can begin using tomorrow.
Here is an important note.
Typically,
the business analyst is the integration point between IT and the business.
You may have also heard of the term that BAs bridge
the gap between the business and IT.
Therefore,
you need a rock solid interpersonal and communication set
of skills to best accomplish your role.
Here are the key interpersonal skills that I think you need.
Teamwork.
You must be able to work well in teams and different kinds of teams,
some more business‑oriented,
some technical‑oriented with members having a wide variety of skills,
perspectives, and motivations.
Responsibility.
You need to be responsible, not just for what you think your main job
is, but responsible for others need to take on even more
responsibility when you see your stakeholders struggling and needing
your help and guidance. Dependability.
I can't believe I am saying this, but you must be dependable.
Sadly, some people are not, not just show up on time,
certainly, but they mean what they say and they do what they say.
You need to show that you can be counted on. Motivation.
Do you think your stakeholder wants to see an unmotivated person?
Certainly not. Not only do you need to be motivated, but provide
motivation to others to keep the team moving forward.
Flexibility,
Every activity or effort I begin in my professional career has
never ended exactly as I thought it would.
If I wasn't flexible,
I won't have been as successful as I have been. Facilitate a give
and take atmosphere with your teams. Patience.
Well, I wish I had more of this one, that's for sure, but if you push too hard,
you may just be pushed back.
And also, pushing too hard can be very disrespectful to
your coworkers or your stakeholders.
Now I know it's a tough balance.
You want to be patient,
but as respectfully as you can, keep things moving forward,
it's a tough balance.
Communication, a component of interpersonal skills is certainly communication,
and I will dive into that one a little more on the next couple slides.
Leadership.
Not sure if you've noticed, but all these attributes illustrate a true leader,
and I will go into more attributes of a leader in a
couple of slides from now as well.
Lastly,
you will find you get more out of what you want professionally by
living by these characteristics, not just at work,
but at home as well.
Oh, one more thing.
Quickly look at the list in front of you.
I want you to think about each item and rate yourself on each.
Say one for maybe not that much, two for medium, and three for pretty good.
For those you've rated yourself a one or two,
you might consider improving on those.
If you gave yourself 16 points or more, well, you're doing really well.
Keep it up.
Communication and interpersonal skills do overlap,
certainly, but they have a bit of a different emphasis and focus.
Here is a list of key communication skills that you need. Active listening.
This means good eye contact, and if you have good eye contact,
you do not have your head buried into your laptop.
Pay attention and listen for accuracy and meaning in what the speaker is saying.
If you are not sure what was said or need clarification,
just repeat back to them for validation and confirmation,
show empathy, and look for common ground. Writing.
Okay, don't get me started.
I have had the pleasure of working with many highly
technical and gifted engineers, but they can barely write a grocery list.
Writing is so important for specs, emails,
presentations, for just about everything.
Think about your writing skills.
Can they be improved?
Creating presentations. I have seen many more poor
presentations than good presentations.
I have a few more tips on this in the next few slides,
so we'll get to that then. Presenting. Even a harder lift for most
people. Presenting material in front of a group can be challenging, it
was certainly a challenge for me, and again,
a little more on that in the next couple slides. Speaking, that's meetings,
presentations, video calls, you name it.
Speak clearly, politely, succinctly,
that is avoid extra words that don't add any value.
Speak in a lean fashion, less is more.
And don't let speaking ruin your listening.
Leading meetings, again, a very essential skill, and again,
most of what I've seen is, well,
poorly led meetings. Creating quality documents,
certainly related to writing skills above,
but a little different.
Remember, people really don't want to read anything,
so make it as clear and concise is it can be. Okay, same thing.
Quickly look at this list in front of you.
I want you to think about each item and rate yourself. For those
items you rate a one or a two, you might consider,
of course, improving those.
If you gave yourself 14 points or more, you're doing great.
Keep it up.
Here are a few presentation tips. I'm calling them Michael's
four P's plan, prepare, practice, and present.
I want to have a complete slide dedicated to presentations since to be
successful you will need to communicate and influence others and
presentations are one of the best mediums to do that.
Okay, here they are.
Plan.
Have the outcome in mind, know what you want before you
start planning your presentation,
know your audience, research your topic, organize the main points,
align your presentation with your outcome. Prepare.
Write a script ahead of time, and also open with something intriguing.
Understand why they are there and try to address the reasons why they are there.
Try to minimize the number of your slides.
No one wants a 50‑page slide they have to go through in a half an hour.
Display one topic, one thing at a time, and please,
no long paragraphs. And practice, practice,
practice.
And yes, practice does make perfect.
Sometimes I even stand in front of a mirror.
Try to hear yourself speak, project your voice, and please don't
memorize, and don't just read your slides,
either.
And then you're going to present, and you're not just talking,
you are delivering a message.
Maintain good eye contact, engage your audience, speak clearly
and with confidence, manage your stress, there may be some, and
maybe vary your tone and pitch.
You don't want to be monotone.
Also look presentable.
Think about your audience when you make your choices.
I believe, at least for myself,
that delivering presentations was my most effective way of
influencing others in my entire career.
A quick callout if you want more on this topic. Check out my
course Leadership and Communication Skills.
I can't emphasize enough how important these another
interpersonal and communication skills are in performing
your business analysis activities.
Please check out this course. You won't regret it.