Key leadership skills. Interpersonal, communication, and
leadership skills are highly synergistic,
and they begin to blur together and support each other in
building a solid soft‑skill platform.
For me,
my career was the most enabled and propelled by leveraging
my interpersonal, communication, and leadership skills, and
maybe they can for you too.
In addition to what we've talked about,
here is an additional list of key leadership skills you need.
But, before I go over this list,
I want you to think about how you would rate yourself for each of them.
Embrace and be a champion for change. Leaders drive
change and are change agents.
Do you like change?
Change is typically not a natural attribute of most people,
but it is of leaders.
Earn credibility across your organization. In order for you to be successful,
work hard to earn credibility, that is, you are honest,
have integrity, and always follow through with what you say and do.
This will enable you to be more productive in your organization and
enable broader career opportunities within your company.
Ability to build trust.
This is a critical leadership quality you must
master. Strong negotiation skills.
Most business interactions entail discussions and arriving at a consensus.
Therefore,
you must have the ability to communicate clearly and effectively to
others during the discussions and negotiations.
Strategic planning skills.
I think this is important, as people want to know,
where are we going and how are we going to get there?
Project and team management skills. Yes,
leadership is paramount and essential,
but you still need some basic and practical project and team management skills.
These will really help you in being an analyst as well. Strong
communication and marketing skills. Like we talked, certainly
verbal and written skills are essential,
and what I mean by marketing is that you will need to ensure
that the business and your stakeholders know what you are
doing clearly and succinctly.
This will result in you receiving better projects to work on, more
resources, and maybe even better career opportunities, and,
of course, strong interpersonal skills, which we've all talked about.
You want coworkers to feel that they can approach you,
talk to you, and share information with you.
The use of these skills with your stakeholders and teammates will enhance
your ability to bridge the gap by helping you elicit and capture business
requirements and then bring forward and communicate those business
requirements to all of your stakeholders.
Okay,
how did you rate yourself? Using the same scale as before, if
you gave yourself 16 points or more, well,
you're doing well and keep it up.
Here's a good quote.
"Difficulties mastered are opportunities won," by Winston
Churchill. I discussed the important need for interpersonal
communication and leadership skills.
Some of these may be uncomfortable for you.
Trust me, I,
too was uncomfortable with speaking to large groups, working with senior
management, as well as other situations during my career.
The meaning behind this quote is something like this.
You should strongly consider getting out of your comfort zone and face your
individual challenges. I found as I improve these skills,
I was more successful at my work and was presented with more career opportunities, as you will be too.