In this video we're going to wrap up our discussion of command line arguments by setting up yards to
support some options for each of our comments.
For example the ad command needs the title and body of the note you're adding the remove command needs
the title of the note you're trying to remove and last up R reads command.
It needs the title of the note you're trying to read.
So we have to figure out how to configure options for those three commands.
And the answer is that we set up another property on the configuration object we pass to command this
property which I'm going to add right here.
After describe is called BUILDER Builders value is an object and own that object we can define all of
the options we want.
This is given command to support now in the case of ADD.
Once again there's two title and body.
Let's start with title to define a new option.
We set it up as a property on the builder object.
So if I want to be able to provide a title when I run the ad command from the terminal I can set up
title right here in builder.
Now the value for this property is an object and in here we can customize how that option works.
And the first thing we're gonna do is set up the describe a property just like we did for our command
up above.
Describe for an option allows us to describe that option and right here.
I'm just going to say note title perfect with our option defined.
We can now access that in the command handler down below and we get access to the arguments via this
first argument that's provided to our function.
So we give this function to yards and when the command is executed yards runs the function and it calls
it with our V which contains all of those arguments.
Let's go ahead and print that to the terminal so we can see what we got right here after our string.
I'm going to pass a second argument to console dialog and the second argument is just going to be the
ARG the variable.
Now we can save things and run our application from down below what we're going to do is run node app
and Dot J S add we are going to provide that title option and I'll set it equal to something like shopping
list.
I'm going to run the command and what do I get.
Right here we have our console dot log printing adding a new note followed by ARG V from inside of the
handler.
And right here we have the title property with shopping list which means we have access to ARG the DOT
title which we can now use to actually define a note.
Now one thing to point out is that these are not required which means that I could run the command without
title node app dot J s ad if I do that what do I get.
Things still seem to work even though no title was provided.
Now it's up to us as the developers to decide whether or not a given option should be required if it's
not.
You can leave the configuration as is if you want it to be required.
You can set that up as well.
Right here we have the demand option.
Property.
This is set to false by default.
We can go ahead and flip that over to true meaning that you have to provide it in order for the command
to work correctly.
Now let's try to run the script again without providing title even though it's now required.
When I do that what do I get.
I get an error message printing it saying we are missing required arguments and it lists them out.
In this case we are missing title.
Right here it even shows the available options for the ad command and we can see that we have title
as the last one and it is indeed shown as required over here on the right hand side which is correct
now the other thing we want to make sure is that we always get a string value for this particular option.
So if you provide the option but you don't give it a value it's going to show up as a boolean.
Let's see what I mean by that node app.
J ust add here we will use hyphen hyphen title but I'm not going to set it equal to a string like we
did previously.
If I do this we can see the value for title is true which is not what we want.
I want to make sure that the ARG V that title property is always a string.
We can go ahead and enforce that by setting up another property on our little options object configuration.
Right here it is a type.
And we're going to set the value equal to one of these supported types which is string in lowercase
now that we have this in place.
We are always going to have a string value for a title and it's required which means it's always going
to be there.
Now it could be an empty string but that's OK we can always perform a little validation later on to
make sure the title has content.
But if I rerun that previous command we can see that at least we have a string value for a title instead
of a boolean which is a great step in the right direction.
And obviously if I provided a string equals something like my title that's going to show up right there
which is indeed ideal.
So now we have this title option.
We have a description for it.
We've said that it needs to be provided and we've said that we're always expecting a string which is
awesome.
You'll notice in the terminal that we're getting the args printed twice because we print them once inside
of the command handler for ad and then down below we print them again in a little console dialogue call.
It's important to note that this is actually doing something.
If we were to comment this line out and save the program it wouldn't work as expected.
If I rerun it the exact same command which worked a few moments ago we can see we're not getting any
output.
So how exactly is printing the args making all of this work.
Well when we access the ARG the property on Yahoo's yard's nose to actually do its thing and pass those
arguments.
Now if we don't need to access it that can be less than ideal.
So there's another way to get that done it is yards dot pass it doesn't take any arguments and we can
just call it like that if we save the program and we rerun the command.
Now things are working once again and we're seeing our arguments printed just a single time.
So yards pass actually goes through the process of passing the arguments with all of the configuration
details you've provided with your yards command calls up above.
It's almost challenge time but before we get there we are going to print the title explicitly.
Down below as opposed to printing the entire object.
So I'll remove our console log and replace it with a new one.
And I'm going to print two things.
First up I'm going to print a little title for the title so I'll say something like a title colon space
and then I'll concatenate on the actual title value which is on ARG the DOT title where the title property
matches up with the title property.
We chose to create up above.
Now if I run the script again things are just a bit more organized right here.
Title my title is showing up.
So now let's talk about what I'd like you to do as your challenge for the video.
As always I have some challenge comments right here describing what I'd like you to do it is gonna be
your goal to add a new option to yards and that's going to be for the ad command.
So right here you're going to use what you've learned in the video to set up a body option for the ad
command which means you'll be customizing the builder object we have right here adding a second prop.
You're going to configure the body option to have a description.
You can pick something that makes sense for you.
You're going to make it a required option.
We're gonna need a body and you're going to force it to be a string using the correct definition.
Next up you're going to log the body value in the handler function like we log the title down below.
And finally you're going to test your work.
So you're going to run the command from the command line a few times.
Try it once without providing the body.
And make sure that fails try it again while providing the body and make sure you see both your title
and body printing.
So all you need to do is edit this object add some stuff inside of this function and test things out
from the command line.
All right take some time to knock that one out.
As always we're going to work through these solution together.
So take a moment to pause the video and when you're done come back and click play
how'd that go.
Let's kick things off together.
We're gonna be setting up a new body option which means we need to add a new property onto the builder
object.
I could add it before or after title.
Either way works.
I'm just gonna add it right afterwards right here.
If he knew property is called the body it is also going to have its value be an object like we did for
a title and this is where we can customize it.
So we want to set up a description.
I want to make it required and I want to make it a string for the description we use are handy.
Describe property.
I'll use a description of something like note body for this one.
Then we're also going to require it by setting demand option equal to true.
Remember the default value is false.
Finally I'm gonna set the type for this one equal to a string.
So we always get a string value provide it.
So that's the steps 1 and 2.
Next up you needed to log the value in the handler.
So down here we log out the title I'm going to add a new console dot log call to log out the body so
body call in space.
Then I'll concatenate on ARG v dot body where the body property comes from the same value as the name
up above.
Now that we have all of this in place we can move on to the final step which is to test our work and
make sure we can now use body successfully.
I'm gonna save app dot.
J.S. I am going to clear the terminal output just to give us a little bit of thinking space so it's
not so cluttered and we're gonna use our new command.
So node app dot J S I am going to run ad and I'm going to do it with title.
I'll provide a title I'll just use a title like buy and I'm not going to provide a body and that's intentional.
When I do this I'm expecting it to fail and it does right here missing and required argument body.
I can see both title and body showing up both required.
Which is fantastic.
The next thing we're gonna do is rerun the exact same command but this time we are going to provide
a body.
So after a space hyphen hyphen body equals right here inside of double quotes.
These are what I need to buy.
Period.
Now if we go ahead and run this command what do we see.
We see our two messages.
I have the title console that log right here printing by.
That comes from line thirty three and I have body.
These are the things I need to buy.
Coming from line 34.
So there we go.
That is it for the challenge.
Our ad command now takes in all of the options necessary for it to actually create a new node and save
it to a data store.
Figuring out how we're going to save our data how we're going to save our notes is the topic of the
very next video.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.