In this video it's going to be up to you to use the object properties shorthand and d structuring which
we covered in the last video inside of the weather application.
Now to start I'm going to take our D structuring and object property shorthand playground file and I'll
move that off to the right hand side.
So we have all of our weather app scripts side by side over here and from the terminal.
I am going to switch back into the weather app directory since we'll be running that application.
In this lesson so S.D. dot dot forward slash weather hyphen app.
Now once we're here the goal is to figure out what exactly we're supposed to do and as always with challenges.
I have a set of challenged comments describing what I'd like you to get done.
The big picture goal is to use both the destruction thing and the property shorthand syntax inside of
the weather application.
First up you're going to use de structuring an apt.
J.S. forecast dot J.S. and geo code dot J S all three of these have an instance where we're using properties
from an object that we could just d structure instead.
Down below we grab things off of data those properties could be d structured into individual variables
in forecast.
J.S. end in geo coded dot J S the only thing we ever use off of the response object is body that could
be destruction as well.
From there we can talk about using the property shorthand syntax.
This can be used in forecast J Yes and in geo code J S in both files we set up the options object we
pass to request and we could use that syntax in there.
So take some time to knock out all of those re factors in the files listed for each.
Then when you're done test your work so make sure you can still run the application and get the expected
weather output.
All right.
Pause the video knock that out and when you're done come back and click play
how'd that go.
I'm going to kick things off with app dot J S now in here we can use d structuring but there is no use
case for the object property shorthand syntax and that's OK down below geo code has its callback called
with two arguments and the first is error which is a string and the second is data and we know that
data is an object we use three properties from it latitude longitude and location we're gonna go ahead
and destructor those instead of accessing them off of data up above we have data I'm going to remove
that and we are going to d structure the second argument passed to the callback right here we are gonna
grab three things from it first up we have latitude then we're gonna have longitude and finally we're
gonna have location.
Now at this point our program is broken because we're still using that data variable but it no longer
exists we're going to remove data and Dot in all three locations.
Now we're just referencing latitude which is indeed defined we're just referencing longitude from up
above and down below referencing location.
Now that we have this in place we can actually test our work but more before moving on to the other
files.
It's always a good idea to test your work as you refactor.
So instead of getting to the end and having a bunch of different files that could have caused the error
it's easier to isolate the problem if you run the program multiple times.
So node app not J S if this works with a search term like Philadelphia then we know our refactoring
here is good if it doesn't work we know that it must just be the changes we made to this particular
file making it easier to figure out what went wrong.
Now let's move on to the other files forecast.
J.S. and geo code dot J.S. both which can use de structuring and that shorthand syntax over in forecast
J J.S. we can use these shorthand syntax in the object we pass to request instead of referencing you
are L variable to get the U R L property we can use these shorthand syntax which does the exact same
thing.
This is still setting up a U R L property whose value comes from the variable up above because the names
are identical.
Now we can also use a little bit of distraction bring down below we have error and we have response
we know response is an object but the only property we're ever using off of it is body.
So we could just de structure that.
I'll remove the response argument set up my curly races and list out body right here down below.
We can now remove any use cases of response replacing them with just the call to bodies.
So right here instead of response body dot error I have body dot error and I'll remove response dot
down below I have it three times as we generate the forecast and I'll remove it in all three.
Now we are just referencing body which does indeed exist as a standalone variable because we d structured
it up above.
Last up we can move to geo coded dot J S which is very similar to the forecast file I can use the shorthand
syntax right here once again when setting up the U R L and once again I can d structure a body off of
response.
Now there are four situations where we used response before.
Once you write here to fetch the length of the features array that's going to be just body dot features
dot length now and down below we used it for each of these three property values.
So I'm gonna take all three I'm gonna remove response dot accessing just dead body object.
Now that we have this in place we've done all the refactoring that is steps one and two and we're going
to move on to step three and actually test things out for a final time.
So down below from the terminal.
Let's go ahead and rerun the program right here.
What do I get.
I get my forecast.
Still printing it is for the correct location Philadelphia Pennsylvania in the United States.
And I have my forecast rain in the morning.
Yep it is indeed raining outside.
It's currently a bit chilly with a zero percent chance of rain as we continue through the day.
And now that we have this in place we are all done and that is an introduction to yes six D structuring
and the object property shorthand we're gonna use both of these extensively throughout the class.
Now that we know about them.
Sure there are other situations where we could have used these in notes Scott J S but we'll just continue
to use these features going forward instead speaking of going forward.
Let's go ahead and jump right in to the next video.