Now that you have your SS H keys in place you're ready to start sharing your code with those third party
services.
In this video you're going to get your code pushed up to the get hub servers and in the next video you'll
get your code pushed up to Heroku so your application can be deployed.
To start let's head over to get hub dot com.
Now you should already be logged into your account as we did that earlier in the section on the left
hand side.
You'll notice I have a list of repositories.
These are projects that I've been working on for clients and for other classes.
What we want to do is create a new repository.
So we're going to have our local repository on our machine.
It lives in that dot get directory which we explored earlier in the class.
We're also going to create a repository for the project on Github.
That is how github is going to be able to get access to our code so it can show it in the user interface.
And so we can do other great things like track issues and collaborate with others.
Now creating a repository on GitHub dot com is really easy.
There is a plus icon near the top right of the screen.
We click new repository and then we fill out a very simple form.
The only thing we need to do is pick a repository name.
Now this does not need to line up in any way with the name you chose for your project.
Locally you can pick anything you'd like as long as you're not already using it for a repo name on your
account.
I'm going to go ahead and use Node 3 hyphen weather Web site once again you can pick whatever name makes
the most sense for you.
Next up we have an optional description which I'll leave blank and then we have the option to create
a public repository where anyone can see the code or a private one which you could use for private proprietary
projects.
Now in this case you can stick with public as private does require you to be on a paid plan.
I'm going to switch mine over to private though so I can keep this project hidden from students so no
one will know I'm working on the course until the whole class is ready.
Once again though you can just leave yours as public.
Next up we have an option to initialize our project with various things like a read me file a get ignore
file or a license.
We're not going to do any of that.
We're gonna move on to the next step which is to create the repository.
So right here when we do that it's not gonna be able to show us our repo code because there is none.
Get hub doesn't know what code is associated with this project.
So it's simply giving us some instructions for the various ways we can get started.
We can create a new repository from the command line and send that to get hub.
We can push our existing repository up to get hub or we can import it from some other version control
system.
In this case the second option is what we want.
We already have a repository with commits locally on our machine.
We simply want to send it to the github servers.
Now there are two commands here to get set up.
But before we run them I want to explain what they do.
So you can actually understand what you're doing.
Right here we have the first command get remote add origin followed by a long you are well.
So to start we are indeed using get like we've done from Visual Studio code plenty of times already
and we're using remote to manipulate our remotes a remote is nothing more than a version of your project
hosted somewhere else.
So we're gonna have a version of our project hosted on GitHub dot coms servers and on her Rochas servers.
Next up how are we trying to work with our remotes.
We're trying to add them.
For example you could also use remove to remove a remote.
In this case though we don't have any.
So we're setting up our very first one.
Next up we choose a name for their remote.
This value could be anything you like but by default your first remote should have the name origin.
This is a common convention you'll see across the web.
After that we have a nice long you are this you are L contains two nice pieces of information.
It has our user name right here.
You should see your user name and it has the name of the repository that you picked.
So right here I have the name that I chose.
Now when we run this command we're not actually sending our code to get hub.
All this command does is it sets up that channel of communication.
You can think about it like adding a contact in your cell phone.
You pick a name for the contact and then you pick their phone number or in this case the U.R.L. but
we're not actually sending anything to that or just setting that up.
So it can be used in the future.
Right here we're going to take that command.
Copy it to the clipboard and from the terminal we're going to run it from the web server directory.
Once again it's important that you run these commands from the right location.
So I'm going to paste it in.
I'm going to run it.
And now we have a remote called origin which we can push too.
And that's going to send our code to get as we add new commits we will push those new commits up to
get hub making sure that get hub has the latest code.
That's where the second command comes into play.
We have get push with you flag origin master so get.
Once again is just the Get Command followed by push push allows us to push our commits up to a given
remote.
Then we provide the remote name origin now Master is the default name for what's called a branch and
get.
We're not going to get into branching in this course as it's a more advanced concept.
If you are interested in diving into the advanced workflows and get I recommend checking out a get course
on udemy or checking out that free get book that I talked about earlier in the class.
Now the EU flag allows us to set the upstream which is essentially the default and in this case we are
setting the default to origin which is where we're going to push to the most.
So in the future after we run this command once we could just use get push to send our latest commits
up to get hub share we'll be pushing to other remotes like Heroku but we're not going to do that nearly
as often.
Now we're not actually ready to run this command yet if we tried to run it it would fail because GitHub
isn't sure of exactly who's sending it the code but we need to do is finalize our SSA configuration
so to get that done what we need to do is take the public key file and give that to get hub dot com
so it can create that secure connection.
We do this in our settings so up top I'm going to go to my little profile picture.
We're gonna go down to settings and then the left hand sidebar you should see an option.
SS H and GP G keys in our case we're trying to setup a new SS H key and we can go ahead and do just
that by clicking new SS H key here it's asking for two things.
First it's asking us for a name to identify this key.
I typically use something like work laptop I have other keys like home desktop or home laptop.
It just makes it easy to identify the given key and the next thing we need is the contents of that public
key file that is I d underscore RSA a dot pub to get the contents of that file we can use the following
command from the terminal that's going to be a cat which simply concatenate the contents of a file out
to the terminal.
So it's going to print the contents of our key file followed by the file to actually print that is Tilde
forward slash dot SS H forward slash I d underscore RSA dot pop.
Now when we do that we're going to get the following.
It's a really long string which starts with SS H hyphen RSA and it ends with that value you put for
the comment and in our case we put our email.
We have to grab all of that including the SS H RSA all the way to the end of the email.
We're gonna copy that to the clipboard and we're gonna bring that over to this big text field.
We paste it in click Add SS H key and now that's been added to our account.
Now right here you can notice it saying it's never been used and that's true.
We have this key setup but we've never used it to communicate with get hub.
We can test our connection by running the following command from the terminal.
If you're on Windows make sure to use get bash for this one that is SS H hyphen the capital T then space
get at get hub dot com.
This is going to test our SS H connection to the get hub servers.
If it works then we know our key has been setup successfully and we can push our commits up.
If it doesn't work.
Then we know we have a problem right here.
I'm gonna run it and we're gonna get the following message.
This is not an error.
It's simply saying that it can't confirm the identity of the server but we can indeed accept that by
typing.
Yes.
Since we can see that things look good and once we do that we can see the final line.
Hi.
Followed by your GitHub username.
You've successfully authenticated but GitHub doesn't provide shell access if you're seeing this.
That is a good thing.
This means you are able to correctly authenticate with get hub and now we're ready to push our code
up.
No actually creating the SSA keys and configuring them with GitHub is something you only have to do
once it's setup and we can use it for all of our future projects.
I'm gonna head back over to the dashboard the home page.
Then I'm going to grab that repository I just created.
I can search for it over here Node 3.
Weather Web site.
I click it.
It brings me back to those instructions and we can run that second command.
This command is actually going to take our commits and it's going to push them up to whatever is at
the following.
You are L from the previous step.
I'll bring that over to the terminal.
I'm gonna paste that command in I'm gonna run it.
And now our code it's getting sent off to the servers.
We can see various pieces of output about that and we can see exactly at the end what happened.
It set up a new master branch to coordinate with our local master branch.
This is a good thing if we refresh get hub dot com we're actually gonna be able to see our project.
No longer will we see these setup instructions.
I'm gonna refresh the page now that there are commits to show.
That is exactly what we see right here.
I have a lot of great stuff.
Obviously I have the files and folders that make up my project.
If I dive into those I can see exactly how they've changed.
I can see who's contributed to them.
I can view the history of their changes.
I can also use this service to track issues.
So right here I could set up issues I could set up various projects outlining what I'd like to complete.
I could set up a wiki for documentation.
There are all sorts of great features that get provides when you're using their service.
Now in our case we're just using them for a basic setup.
We're going to keep our code backed up to get hub.
So if things do go wrong locally we always have a backup of our copy.
Oh right.
That is where we're gonna stop before this one.
We now have our code up on the Github servers.
Don't worry a little bit later in the section we'll talk about how we can push our other changes up
to the service and there'll also be a challenge will you have to do the same.
For now though the goal was just to get that basic configuration set up with the SSA keys in place.
We can now use the same setup with any other projects we end up creating the next video is all about
pushing up to Heroku and getting our application deployed live to production.
It's the grand finale of sorts.
So let's go ahead and jump right at.