In this video I promised we'd be connecting to our database from to J.
S I'm actually going to push that off to the next video as there's one more important thing we need
to install before it really makes sense to interact with the database using Node.
What we're going to install in this video is a mongo D.B. admin tool.
This is gonna be a gooey a graphic user interface for managing your Mongo DB database and the data it
contains.
The goal of the database admin tool is to provide us with a nice visual interface for managing our Mongo
DB data.
It's not meant to serve as a replacement for connecting to your database from node j s we're still gonna
do that.
The whole point of the admin tool is just to provide us with an easier way to manage our data as developers
as we're building out the application.
Now we can find the tool that we're gonna be using by heading over to a new browser tab and we are going
to Google robo three ti.
Now the reason I'm having you Google the product name as opposed to entering an explicit U.R.L. is because
they recently rebranded themselves.
This tool was formerly known as robo Mongo.
It has since been renamed to robo three t and this is the Mongo D.B. addon tool.
We're going to use as a companion throughout the class.
Now this is a free tool available for all operating systems.
So let's go ahead and get it installed right here as we head to the robo 3 home page.
They have two product offerings they have studio three T and they have robo 380 robo 3D is the Mongo
D.B. gooey the tool that we want to install.
Studio Three T has more advanced features that we're not gonna use in the class.
Everything that we need to manage our database is available in their free offering.
So right here I'm going to click download robo 3 T.
Which just brings me over to another page where I have to click the exact same button and once I click
it a second time I'll be able to view the installation options for Linux for Mac and for Windows for
Windows.
You get an E XY executable for Mac you get a DMV installer and for Linux you get an archive.
So right here I am on a Mac.
So I'm going to take a quick moment to actually get this installed so we can set it up together in this
video.
I'm going to download the DMV file and once that's downloaded we'll take a quick moment to install it
and set it up.
Take a quick moment to grab the correct installer for your operating system right here for the Mac.
Once I open up the DMV all I need to do is drag the application file over to my applications folder.
Then we can start it up.
So right here I have robo 3D.
I'm gonna drag that over to applications then I'm going to open up applications and navigate to R for
robo 3 T and down below.
I have the program sitting right here.
I'm gonna right click it to open it and I'm doing this for the first time to confirm that I do want
to open an application downloaded from the Internet as opposed to one downloaded from the Mac App Store.
I'm gonna confirm it and this is going to open up the robo 3 tee program right here.
Robo 3 T is bringing up this Mongo DB connections panel where we can connect to our local Mongo DB database.
Take a quick moment to get robo 3D installed and opened.
Then you can come back and continue on with the video.
So right here it's asking us to manage our connections we don't have any.
So we're gonna go ahead and actually create one when we create a connection.
There are a ton of different options we can configure up here.
We have a whole bunch of tabs for more advanced setups and we'll explore some of these as we setup a
production Mongo DB database a bit later in the class.
For now for our local host setup the only thing we need to change is right here name.
This is a label for the connection and we can call this literally anything we like.
I'm gonna call this local Mongo D.B. database now down below on this first connection tab I also have
address and port address is correct the database is running on local host and the port is also correct
it's using the default Mongo DB port which we saw in our connection message when we first started up
the server.
We saw that the server was listening on Port 2 7 0 1 7 and here that's the port we're trying to connect
on.
Now before we actually say of the connection we can test it out if we click this test button over here.
We should see green checkmarks for everything allowing us to actually confirm that the connection settings
are working.
We can now close the connection test panel I can click save and we can connect to our database for the
first time.
Right here we can just double click that connection to connect and as long as you're not seeing an error
pop up.
That means things were connected correctly.
Now for the moment there's nothing interesting to look at because we haven't inserted any data into
the database.
We'll get to that in the next video.
For the moment though we are going to run a single command on the database asking for the version of
Mongo DB it's running as long as we get the version back then we know for certain that robo three ti
was able to connect to the database successfully to do that.
Oh we're gonna do is right click our connection over here in this left hand panel and we're going to
click open shell.
This is going to allow us to run a command directly against Mongo D.B..
And in this case we're gonna use the following.
That's D.B. dot version which we're going to call as if it were a method on the DB object.
Now right here what we have looks a whole lot like Javascript and that is because it is javascript when
we're working with Mongo D.B. and interacting with it via the Mongo DB shell.
We're just using JavaScript to manipulate the database.
So in this case we are asking for the version of Mongo D.B. that's running.
If we fire this off we should get the correct version back confirming that our connection was able to
connect to the database and that the database was able to respond right here to actually run this.
We just click that green play button.
It's going to fire off the command and down below we get our version back here I get the version of
Mongo D.B. that I installed for point zero point for you.
You should see the version of Mongo D.B. that you installed with this in place.
We've confirmed two things.
We've confirmed that our database is up and running correctly and that robo 3 T is up and running correctly.
And now we're going to continue on to the next video where we're actually going to connect to the database
from node j s and insert our very first documents into Mongo D.B..
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next one.