Welcome to section number eleven on a REST API eyes.
In the last section you learned how to interact with a database using no J.S. in this section.
Well we're going to do is start to create our very own express based REST API using what we now know
about data storage.
This is going to allow a user to perform an operation such as signing up for a new account creating
a task or fetching a list of all of the tasks they still need to complete.
Now along the way we're also going to explore Mongoose mongoose is a really popular library when working
with node and Mongo D.B..
It gives us a really easy system for modeling our data for modeling things like a user or a task.
We'll be able to set up the various fields and data types as well as things like data validation which
is going to make our lives a lot easier and our applications more secure.
I'm excited to get to all of that and more let's jump right in and talk about mongoose.