In this video we're going to focus on setting up helpful options for the consumers of our API to use
these options are going to allow them to better target the data they're trying to fetch.
Now the route we'll be focusing on in this video and in the next two videos is over in the task router.
It is the second drought right here.
The get tasks route where you can fetch all of your tasks.
Now why this route.
We have a dozen or so different routes between the tasks and the user router but the only one we're
going to add these options to is this one.
That's because this is the only one that's sending back an array of data with all of the other routes
we get back.
A single document with this one we could potentially get back hundreds or thousands of documents depending
on how many are in the database.
So why is that.
Well imagine I'm using the app for a couple of years and I go ahead and add a couple of tasks each day
knocking them out.
Eventually I'm gonna have so many tasks in the database and using this request to fetch all of them
is going to do two things one it's going to be slow because it has to fetch so many old and unnecessary
documents and two it's gonna be fetching things that the user interface isn't going to actually use
if I'm just trying to render the three tasks that I have not completed.
There's no reason I should also have to fetch the other two thousand that are already completed.
So what we're going to do is set up helpful options allowing the consumer of the API to better target
the data they want to get and we're going to do this using the query string as part of the U R L structure.
And this is something we saw with the weather app way back when just to refresh your memory if we go
into the weather app and we open up inside of utilize our forecast file in here we had set up latitude
and longitude as part of the U.R.L. that was via a U.R.L. parameter where it's part of the U RL structure
over in geo code.
We had done it using the query string.
Right here we started with the question mark and we set up access token sending an equal to the following
value.
Then we used a limit to limit it to the first result.
So this is the approach that we're gonna be taking to allow the user to customize which task data they
get back.
So I'm going to collapse the weather app folder and I'll close down those two files and we're gonna
start to focus on actually setting that up for get tasks.
Let's explore the you are L structure we'll be using before we actually write any code.
Right here it is get forward slash tasks.
Now this is still going to return all of the tasks both incomplete and complete that you've ever created
but optionally if you want to you can use the query string to set completed equal to true or false if
you set completed equal to False you'll only get back the tasks that you still need to do the incomplete
ones where completed is false if you set completed to true when making the request you're only going
to get back the ones that you've already done and this could be useful if you're trying to show the
user some sort of archive page where they can see all of the tasks they've finished and now let's go
ahead and set up the router down below to actually support this.
And the first thing we need to be able to do is limit what tasks we get back.
Now if we were using tasks that find we know how we could get that done by providing that first object
and specifying completed to be true or false but we can also do the same thing with populate.
So let's see what that looks like right here we're going to customize a populate.
No longer are we going to provide just these string tasks.
Instead we're going to provide an object.
Now we still need to let it know we're trying to populate the tasks.
If we provide an object it expects that property name to be set on the following path.
So path will equal tasks.
So what we've done is we haven't changed any of the behavior yet.
All we've done is refactoring it allowing us to explore new options and one of the new options we have
access to is match.
Match is an object and in here we can specify exactly which tasks we're trying to match.
For example I could match those where it completed is equal to true.
Now I'm only going to get the tasks that I've already completed over inside of postmen.
I have created a task for this user and it is incomplete which means that if I do run read tasks I would
expect to get nothing back.
And that's exactly what happens.
Now if I were to switch completed two faults I would expect to get my one task back I'll save the file
rerun the same request from postmen once again and that is exactly what shows up so in the end of the
day.
This is exactly what we want to do.
We want to customize this object but we want to do it based off of the query string values provide it.
So let's go ahead and kick things off by setting it up over in the U.R.L. and figuring out how we can
access it and express right here.
What I'm going to do is set up the query string using the question mark and I am going to set completed
equal to true.
Now once again down below we can see that it's automatically set up that key value pair under the parameter
tab.
And we can go ahead and fire this off to send off the request.
Now it still works.
It's just not using that data over inside Express.
Let's go ahead and actually change that by setting things up on line one of our handler function.
Now we've already used request dot query in the weather application we had done this to get the address
for the end point we created.
We had used request dot query dot address in this case request dot query dot completed is going to contain
the value that was used whether it's true false nothing or some other string altogether.
Now it's our job to figure out what we should provide on match should completed be false should it be
true or should it not exist altogether.
Remember if we don't provide completed at all.
I want to be able to get all tasks back regardless of their completed value.
So to get this done and what we're actually going to do is the following We're going to start off by
creating an object which will store in a variable called match then down below.
We're going to use that as the value we provide for match and since they have the same name we can use
the property shorthand.
Now along the way we are going to potentially make some modifications to the match object if completed
is not provided we won't change it at all.
Getting all tasks back both complete and incomplete if completed is provided we will set a completed
property on match to the correct boolean value.
So right here we can set up our if statement to start to get this process done.
What I'm gonna do is set up if and we are going to see if completed was provided.
I'm gonna look at request dot query dot completed and then down below we'll go ahead and do something.
If a value was provided.
Now in this case we're trying to set match dot completed equal to a Boolean.
Now even if someone types true what we get back is not a boolean it is D string true.
If someone types in faults what we get back is not a boolean it is D string false.
So it's not as easy as just setting request dot query dot completed equal to that value.
This is not going to work as expected.
And why.
Because we're not setting completed equal to a Boolean or setting an equal to a string.
It's gonna be our job to take this and convert it into a boolean value.
What we're going to do is see if completed equals right here the string true.
So if this which is a string equals D string true we'll set completed equal to true.
If this a string does not equal true whether it's false or anything else we'll set completed equal to
False.
This is gonna give us exactly what we want where you have three options for specifying which types of
tasks you want to get back.
Now that we have this in place we can actually test out our work from over inside a postman.
I'm going to save the tasks router and I'll leave this little line comment in place so we can remember
the various ways we can request our data and I'll head over to postman and the first thing we're going
to need to do is create a couple of more tasks.
So we have some more interesting data to work with.
Now in this video and in the next two we're going to continue to modify tasks and it'll be easier for
us to make sure that our projects work as expected.
If me and you have the exact same task data I only have one task so far for this user and what I'm going
to do is actually remove it and start from scratch so I'll fire off a quick delete task request to remove
that task and once it's removed we'll head back over to create task and to give us some interesting
data.
We're going to create four tasks right here.
The first one will be called first and we are going to set the completed value equal to true.
I'd recommend using the exact same data.
So it's easy for you to verify that your app is working as expected.
I'm going to fire this off and down below we can see it's been created.
Next up I'll create a task with the description.
Second and I will the completed value for this one to false that's been created.
Down below.
We're going to create two more.
The next one will have the description of third since it is our third task I will toggle this back to
a completed value of true which is showing up down below.
And then finally the fourth task with a description of fourth and a completed value of false.
So I'm trying to give us some variable data so we can actually see how all of this is going to work
in the real world.
We have some tasks that are completed and others that are not.
Now back over here let's go ahead and remove the query string and fire that request off.
We should see our four tasks I have first second third and fourth.
Now I'm going to set up completed once again and make sure it's working as expected.
So if I set completed equal to true I would expect to see first and third the two tasks which are completed
and that is exactly what I'm getting down below.
Now if I were to set completed equal to False or anything else I would expect to see just second and
fourth which are my two tasks that have not been completed.
And there we go.
They're showing up as expected which is fantastic.
So now there are three ways you can fetch your tasks you can get all of them or just the complete ones
or just the incomplete ones.
Now that we have this in place we're going to move on to the next video and continue to learn how we
can customize this request.
The next thing we're going to talk about is Paget nation.
It is a really important topic which I'm excited to get to.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.