Welcome to Section 15.
On email sending in this section you're going to learn how to set up email notifications in the task
manager application.
And we're going to do this by simply calling a function and providing the necessary data like who the
email should go to and what the subject and body of the email should be.
Now to do this we'll be using the very popular send gridded service send the grid as a service specifically
designed for developers who want to send emails from their applications and it's not alone in this space.
There are other similar tools like postmark and man drill but send grid is definitely my favorite sand
grid also comes with a handy NPM module which means that we can install it and load it into our application.
Sending emails with maybe 15 lines of code.
All right let's jump into the section and integrate e-mail notifications into the task manager app.