In this lesson we're going to head back into the chat app in Visual Studio code and we'll actually be
setting up web sockets support for our server.
Now to get that done we'll be using the very popular socket dot I O library which provides everything
we need in order to start working with web sockets in node j s the socket dot Io library provides everything
we need to set up the server in our node j s scripts and it also provides client side code we can use
in the browser to communicate with that server and we'll explore how all of this is going to work and
how all of that is going to let us build out this real time application.
But to start what I'd like to do is just pull up these socket dot Io library in the browser so you know
where you can learn more in a new browser tab you can head over to socket dot I O to learn more.
Now this is a great Web site.
There is a bunch of articles available under learn.
We have getting started.
And we also have documentation which we can use to explore the various methods that are available to
us and we'll work through everything covered here inside of the class.
So the first thing we're gonna do is install socket dot I O.
And then we'll learn how we can actually connect to our server and transfer data back and forth from
both the client to the server and from the server to the client.
So to get started let's go ahead and move into visual studio code and install this library from the
terminal down below.
I'm going to use control C to shut down these server.
I'll use clear to clear the terminal output and then we'll use NPM ie.
Now the library we're installing is called socket dot Oh at the latest version which is to point to
point zero.
Let's take a quick moment to let it actually install the library and once the library is installed all
we're going to do is start up that Dev script once again.
So right here I can cycle through my previous commands using the up arrow key.
If I go back three that'll be NPM run Dev.
I'm going to start that up and from here we're actually going to use the library to make some changes
to the server we're gonna set up support for web sockets and we'll see how we can actually connect to
the server from the browser to get started.
The first thing we need to do is perform a little bit of refactoring with the code we already have in
place.
So when we're creating a node server it can use both express and socket dot I O.
It just requires us to set up express in a slightly different way.
So that's what we're gonna do first.
The code we're about to write is not gonna change the behavior of our server whatsoever.
It's just a different way to configure Express.
The first thing we're gonna do is create a constant called H TTP and we're gonna use require to load
in the TTP core module something that we've already used.
Next up right after we create our Express application we're going to create a another variable called
something like server though you could choose whatever name you wanted to write here what we're going
to do is use that H TTP library and a method available on it called Create server.
And this is going to allow us to create a new web server and we're going to pass to it our Express application.
Now if we don't do this the Express library does this behind the scenes anyways.
So once again we're not changing the behavior.
We're just doing a little bit of refactoring now down below what we need to do is change how we're calling
listen instead of calling app dot listen we're going to call server dot listen to start up our TTP server
created right here now.
That's it.
Those are all the changes we need to make.
And if we save the file we're going to see we have the exact same behavior over in the browser we'll
pull up local host three thousand right here we can go ahead and refresh the page and I can see that
I'm still seeing my chat app HDL file.
So all we've done is we've created these server outside of the Express library we're creating it ourself
and configuring it to use our Express app then we are starting it up using server dot lesson.
Now with this in place it's gonna be really easy to setup socket dot I.
Oh the first thing we're gonna do is load it in.
So right here a new constant I'll call this constant socket I owe and we'll go ahead and load in that
library requiring it socket dot I O.
Now down below we can create a new instance of socket dot I O to configure web sockets to work with
our server right here.
Let's go ahead and create a new constant a new constant called I O.
Once again this is a common name used.
You'll see this used in the socket I O documentation and this value is going to come from calling socket
I O as a function.
So when we require the library we get a function back and we call that function to actually configure
socket I O to work with a given server and we pass to that server.
Right here we have that in the server variable.
So this is why we had to do the refactoring socket.
I O expects it to be called with the raw HDTV server.
Now when express creates that behind the scenes we don't have access to it to pass it in right here.
That's why we've created it on our own.
We created it for the explicit purpose of being able to pass it in right there.
And here we go.
Now our server supports web sockets.
Now at this point in time it's not going to do anything too interesting but we can further configure
index dot and J.S. to actually work with the clients that connect to it and down below to get started.
Oh we're going to do is print a message to the terminal.
When a given client connects.
So right here we're going to do that using I O that is I O dot on and we're listening for a given event
to occur.
Now right here we provide the name of the event and a function to run when that event occurs.
In this case the event that we're going to start with is called connection connection is going to fire
whenever the socket Io server gets a new connection.
And right here we'll just go ahead and print a message console dot log new web socket connection.
Perfect.
Now with this in place let's go ahead and save index dot J S that's going to restart our server and
what we're going to do is head over to the browser and just refresh the page right here.
We should still see our chat app HDL rendering and if we head back to the Visual Studio code what do
we see.
We see nothing down below.
We're not getting our message so clearly at this point we have not connected to these server for whatever
reason as we're not seeing that connection message we're printing online 16 and this is true.
What we need to do is a load in the client side of the socket dot Io library.
So right here we're using it on the server which is a great start.
We're also going to use it on the client inside of our web application.
Now when we set up a socket I owe to work with a given server.
It also sets up a file to be served up that your clients can access and that's what we need to do.
So over here inside of our HDMI all we're going to setup a new script tag like we've done plenty of
times before and we're going to define these source attribute.
Now the script we're loading in it's not a script that we've created and it doesn't exist anywhere in
the public directory.
It's something that is served up because we've configured our server to work with socket dot I O right
here that is a forward slash socket dot I O forward slash socket dot I O dot J.
S this is the client side version of the library.
And when we load this in our client side JavaScript code will have access to all of the stuff from the
library it needs in order to set up that communication.
The next thing we need to do is create our own client side JavaScript file load that in and use what's
provided by this script right here.
So what we're gonna do is create in the public directory a new folder we're gonna call this folder something
like J asked to hold all of our J S files and we're going to create a single one right here.
I'm going to call that chat dot J S and in here we'll write some code in a few it's to actually connect
to the server using web sockets before we can though we want to make sure the script actually gets loaded
in.
So over inside of index not HDMI all that means we add another script tag down below.
We're going to provide the source attribute that is forward slash J S forward slash chat dot J S and
with this in place our new client side script is indeed going to run now because we've loaded in this
file this file has access to some stuff that it otherwise would not have access to.
And one of those is a function called i o we go ahead and call I O to connect to these server right
here.
This is all we need to put in the script now down below I can see that the server has restarted and
it's up on port three thousand with the changes made and saved to our two files in the public directory.
All I'm going to do is refresh the browser over here I'll give things a refresh.
We should still see our chat app message but this time over in Visual Studio code we should see new
web socket connection and that is exactly what we're getting.
And this is fantastic.
This means that our server is indeed setting up web sockets report correctly and it also means that
our client was able to connect to it but with this connection in place we're now able to facilitate
real time communication and that's exactly what we're going to start to do.
That's what we're going to start to do in the next lesson.
So let's take a quick moment to recap what we did in this lesson in index dot J.S. we setup support
for socket dot I O all we needed to do to get this done was to create a new socket I O instance passing
the server in and we can do a lot of things with socket I O on the server.
The only thing we've done so far is we've printed a message when a new client connects over in the browser.
We saw that because we've set up socket I O we have access to a client side version of the socket not
Io library provided to us.
And this client side library gives us access to some stuff we can use to facilitate this communication
and for the moment the only thing we've seen is that we get access to an IO function we can call to
connect.
We've proven that all of this works by seeing our message down below in the next lesson we'll learn
how to actually send data back and forth from server to client and client to server.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's jump right in to the next lesson.