In this lesson you're going to learn about event acknowledgements in socket.
Done.
Oh now as the name suggests an event acknowledgement allows the receiver of the event to acknowledge
that it received and processed the event now.
An example use case for this would be sending a location or sending a message the client sends the location
or the message off to the server but it's never quite sure that the server received it and actually
did something with it with an acknowledgement the client would get notified that the message or the
location was indeed delivered successfully.
So that's what we're going to focus on setting up and we'll start this process over inside a Visual
Studio code in chat dot J S.
Now for the moment what I'm gonna do is just paste in a couple of comments just to solidify this idea
one more time.
So if the server omits the event that means the client is the receiver the client can send back an acknowledgement
to the server allowing the server to know that the client processed it the same thing works in the other
direction.
If the client is emitting the event that means the server is receiving it and the server could send
an acknowledgment back.
Now obviously acknowledgements are optional since we haven't been using them so far so let's go ahead
and see how we would actually implement these into our project to get started.
We'll work with our send a message event which is emitted from the client and received by the server.
Now an acknowledgement is the client getting notified that the event was received and processed and
the code that's going to run is provided as the last argument to omit.
So we have our event name.
We have as many arguments for the data as we want to in this case.
It's just one it could be 0 it could be 6.
Then we provide a function as the final argument.
This is going to run when the event is acknowledged and we're going to do is use console dialog to say
something like the message was delivered perfect.
Now with this in place what we need to do is make a change to the server as well.
Right now the client is expecting this event to be acknowledged but it's never going to be acknowledged.
We fix that by making a very small change to the event listener.
So over in index dot J s what we do is we find the event listener for that event.
In this case it's right here and we set up another parameter for the callback function.
Right here we add a final one on called callback or something similar and we call this to acknowledge
the event right here.
I can call it at the bottom of the function after I've shared the message with everyone.
Now with this in place we have a basic acknowledgement set up over in the browser.
Let's test this out.
So what I'm going to do is refresh the browser and I will send a message.
This is a test.
I'll send it I can see the message down below.
And after it was delivered I have my little confirmation letting me know that my message was delivered
successfully.
Now when the server sends the acknowledgment back to the client it could also choose to provide some
data.
So as an example right here I could provide as many arguments to this function as I wanted to.
For now I could just say something like delivered and then over inside of chat not J.S. I would have
access to that argument.
So over here this function is now going to get called.
With that single argument.
I could call it something like message and I could use the message down below.
Right here what I'll do is just add it as the second argument to console dot loc.
Perfect.
I'll save all my files and make sure that shows up so over in the browser.
Once again just giving things a quick refresh.
I'll type test I'll click send I can see the message was delivered and I can see the message that the
server sent to the client as part of the acknowledgement.
And there we go.
Everything is working really well.
So once again an acknowledgement requires changes on the client and the server whoever is emitting the
event sets up a callback function.
Whoever is receiving the event receives a callback function that it needs to call.
And as we just explored if it wanted to it could optionally send data back and forth.
Now a great use case for acknowledgement could be something like validation.
So maybe for example I don't want to allow messages that contain profane language.
Now obviously that's up to the developer to determine whether or not they want to allow that but for
an example let's say we want to avoid that language.
There is actually an NPM module we can use to integrate this into our project.
If we head over to the browser you can google NPM bad hyphen words and this is the module we'll be using
bad words comes to pretty populated with a list of bad words and as the documentation below shows you
can add your own bad words to be excluded.
Now what we're going to do is reject any message that contains foul language so let's go ahead and start
by installing this library and see how we can use event acknowledgments to get this done.
So down below what I'm going to do is use control C to shut things down and then I'm going to install
that library NPM I followed by bad hyphen words at three point zero point zero from here.
We're gonna go ahead and run the installer once that's done and we'll start up our dev server once again
by using the up arrow key twice and hitting Enter.
And now we're going to integrate bad words into our project.
So first up we have to load that module in up top const uppercase f filter equals.
This is what comes back from requiring the bad words library if you want to learn more about what the
bad words library can do you can always check out the documentation then down below inside of that function.
We're going to go ahead and actually use it to check for profanity in this string a message.
So right here the first thing we have to do is initialize bad words.
So we're going to create a constant lowercase f filter and that is going to be a new instance of filter
and then we're going to use a method on there called is profane.
That's going to return either true or false and we'll use that in an if statement to determine what
we want to do right here.
If we are going to use a filter dot and we can see there are a few methods here I can add profane words
to filter I can clean the profanity in the message replacing the profane words with the actress symbol
I'm using is profane though to just check for profanity and right here I pass that message in.
Now once again we're gonna get true if it is profane and false otherwise.
So right here this code is only going to run if it is profane and what we're going to do is use return
to stop the function execution and I'm going to call the callback with an error message.
Something along the lines of profanity is not allowed.
Perfect.
Now with this in place down below we can go ahead and only omit the message when there is no profanity
and I'll still call the callback to acknowledge that I did send things off.
This time though I'm not going to provide any arguments so I provide a single string with an error message
when an error occurs.
Otherwise I provide nothing like I'm doing down below.
Now on the client we can go ahead and while you're right up to actually work with this information over
here what I'm going to do in chat dot Jay s is the following.
Right here.
I'm going to change the message parameter over to something a little more explicit like error and then
we're going to set up some code to run and we'll use a condition inside of here.
If there is an error we'll do one thing.
Otherwise we'll do something else.
So if there is an error I will stop the function execution and I'll print it.
Console log error if there is no error I can go ahead and print something like console dialog.
Message delivered perfect.
Now with this in place we should be able to test out our changes.
So what I'm going to do is save a chat dot J.S. over inside of the browser.
We're going to refresh our application and I'm going to send off a regular message.
This is a test I click send or hit enter.
I can see my message shows up and message delivered to Prince which is great.
Now I'll type hell in the box hit enter and down below I can see profanity is not allowed.
So that message was never sent out.
All I got back.
As the sender was an error.
No one else even knew I tried to send it.
So acknowledgments can do a lot for us when it comes to creating real time applications.
And now that you know how to use them you're gonna be setting up an acknowledgement for these send.
Location event as well down below I have some challenge comments outlining what I'd like you to do.
So right here I'll paste those in the goal setting up acknowledgement for send location.
Now since the event is being emitted from the client the first thing you're gonna want to do is set
up the acknowledgement function on the client.
Much like we did for send a message.
Then on the server you want to make sure that the server sends back the acknowledgement by calling that
callback.
Now in this case there's no need to call it with any arguments whatsoever.
You can just call it after the location has indeed been shared with all of those connected clients.
Now when the function on the client runs what do you want to do when the event is acknowledged.
You're just going to print something like location shared to the console then test your work.
Open up the application in two windows have a one person share the location you should see the location
show up for both Windows and the one who shared the location should have the acknowledgement message
as well.
Take some time to knock that out and when you're done come back and click play
how that go.
Let's get started by providing a function as the final argument to emit.
So right here I'm going to set that up.
That's step 1 step 2 is to make sure that the server actually sends back an acknowledgement for send
location so over in index.
And Jay asks We have to find send location and we have to set up that callback parameter right here
callback or something.
Similarly named now after we emit the message we're gonna go ahead and call the callback letting the
client know that the event has indeed been acknowledged.
Right here we can go ahead and save that as it's the only change we need to make to the server from
chat dot Jay S. we can move on to Step number three when the event is acknowledged we're gonna print
location shared.
So right here in that function we created console dialog printing location shared.
Excellent.
Now with this in place the only thing left to do is to test our work.
So what I'm going to do is go ahead and remove the challenge comments.
Make sure all of my files are saved and I'll head over to the browser right here.
I have my first window.
I'll also go ahead and create a second window cracking open the developer tools for that as well and
I'll navigate over to local host three thousand.
Now I'm going to send the location as this second to user I click the button in a second or two the
location should indeed show up and it does.
And the person who actually sent the location has the acknowledgement message right here.
Location shared is printing which is fantastic.
Now that we have this in place we're all done with acknowledgements acknowledgements are really useful
for real time applications.
It allows the event emitter to make sure that everything actually went as expected.
Now that we have this in place in the next lesson we're going to focus on tying acknowledgements and
socket dot o into the interface providing a clearer UI for users so they know what exactly is happening.
I'm excited to get to that.
So let's go ahead and jump right in to the next lesson.