In this lesson you're going to learn how to integrate time into the chat application.
So along with every single message that shows up in the browser you'll also see the time at which it
was sent.
So in this lesson we're going to focus on figuring out how to generate timestamps how to transfer them
between client and server and how to format them in a way that's useful for the users of our chat application.
Now to kick things off what I want to focus on is how we are going to generate timestamps.
We can actually do that using built in JavaScript functionality.
So in the console down below.
Let's take a look at the 12 or so characters necessary to get this done.
Now the first thing we need to do is create a new Date object.
So right here we can just go ahead and create a constant we can call it whatever we'd like for example
I could call it now and then we're going to generate a new date and to do that we use the new operator
with the date constructor function that is capital D date we call it providing no arguments as none
are necessary.
Now when we do this it's going to generate a new Date object that represents the current point in time
whenever we run the code it's going to store that in now and we can use now to work with that time.
So right here we've executed it storing a value in now and now we have access to all of the methods
that date provides.
If you pull up the MDA and documentation you can get a complete list of all of these.
Let's go ahead and walk through a couple.
So for example right here now dot to string.
This is going to show a string representation of that date.
In this case it was the date created a few seconds ago and all of this information is indeed accurate
for the current time and where I am in the world.
Now don't worry we're not going to show all of this information to the user in the chat app.
We'll be formatting it to just show them the information that would be useful.
Now another method we could use is now dot right here.
Get date.
This is one of many methods that allows you to extract individual parts of the date.
And in this case get date allows you to extract the day of the month right here 31 aligning.
There are other methods you can use to extract other pieces of that date such as the number of seconds
or hours.
The other method that we're going to use and the one we're actually going to integrate into our code
is called get time.
So let's take a quick moment to run that right here.
It is now dot get time.
I'm going to execute it.
And what do we get back.
We get back a really big number.
Now this value this number is a timestamp.
It is the representation of that point in time.
Up above it is the number of milliseconds since January 1st at midnight of the year nineteen seventy
that point in time is also known as the Unix epic.
So the number zero represents that point in time positive numbers are in the future from that point
in time and negative numbers go into the past.
So here I have a very large positive number because it has been quite a few years since 1970.
I would have a very large negative number if I was trying to get a timestamp for something like the
start of World War 1 as an example.
Now in this case we have the timestamp and timestamps are great for transferring between systems because
it is nothing more than a number.
And this number is universally understood by pretty much every programming language out there including
javascript.
So it's really easy to work with.
What we're going to do is use this exact same code on the server to generate timestamps numbers for
each and every message that the server sends to the client.
The client will then receive that message and it will be able to use all the message text like we have
above as well as the timestamp.
And we'll talk about how we can format that to make it look a bit nicer and a bit more useful for humans.
So let's get started by generating that timestamp on the server inside a Visual Studio code.
We'll be kicking things off in index dot J S now in index dot J.
S we're going to focus on the message event.
At first we'll be ignoring the location message event for now.
Now we admit the message event from four different places right here.
I admit it twice once to the user who's joining and once to everyone else down below I admit the message
event to send a user's message to all other connected users.
And finally at the bottom I hit a message when someone leaves the chat room.
Now in this case we have four different places where we need to set up the date and that's going to
require us to have a lot of duplicate code.
So the better solution would be to create a separate function that can get all of this done for us.
Now when it comes to omitting the message event we are going to need to provide more than just a single
value.
Now when we need to omit an event with more than a single value we have two options we can one provide
more arguments for example adding the timestamp over here as another argument to omit or we could choose
to just omit a single piece of data and object with everything on there as a property.
For example I could have a message property on the object to store this text and I could have a created
at property on there to store the timestamp.
And that's the approach that we're going to take.
So right here we're changing two things.
One we are going to send objects back instead of just sending back strings when we emit the message.
And we're also going to create a function that generates that object for us.
So we don't have to add these same code over and over again.
Let's go ahead and see what this is going to look like before we create it.
So right here for the welcome event I'm going to remove this string.
We're going to provide an object instead.
And this object will have a text property with that message.
Welcome.
Exactly like we had before.
We're also going to send back something like create it at setting up a new date right here using the.
Get time method to get the timestamp.
Now I could have stored this in a variable first and then used to get time.
That's what we did in the terminal.
But I could change the method on right here to get all of this done at once.
So in the end of the day this is the sort of thing we want to be sending from the server to the client.
Now once again we're going to create a function that generates this object for us.
So I don't have to type this out every single time I want to send a message from the server to the client.
I want to put all of this logic into a single function.
I can use and reuse.
So what I'm going to do is create a new file in the source directory.
Actually I'm going to create a new directory in the source directory.
I'll go ahead and call this something like utilize and in the utilize directory we'll make our new file.
And for this one I could call it something like messages dot J S.
This is going to be a pretty simple file which is focused on defining a few functions that are going
to generate those message objects.
Right now it's just text and created at but as we progressed through the section we'll be adding even
more data on for example eventually we'll have user names for our users and we'll need to transfer that
as well.
So let's go ahead and get started by defining our first function right here.
Let's create a new constants for our function call it something like generate message and we'll set
it up as an arrow function.
And there's not a whole lot to this one.
We're going to accept the message text in as the first and only parameter for the moment.
Others will come later on and then down below.
Oh we're going to do is return an object.
Now right here we are going to set up the properties we want to transfer.
Of course I do want to transfer the text so I will set that text property up getting its value from
the parameter value above and then I'll also set up created app or something similarly named.
And right here we're gonna use that exact same code.
We create a new date and we use get time to get the timestamp.
Now if we export that from this file other files like index dot J yes we'll be able to use it.
So module dot exports equals a new object since we will be adding other functions in later.
And right here generate.
Message is the particular thing we're trying to export right now.
So with this in place we can call generate message with our text instead of needing to generate the
object in line in index dot J S that's going to reduce the amount of duplicate code we have keeping
things nice and clean.
So from here let's go ahead and load that function in up above we need to require that file.
So I'll set up a require call that is dot forward slash utilize forward slash messages and we are going
to create a constant to grab that function.
Now we know that require is going to return that object that we export it right here.
I'll use destruction thing like we've done before to grab the one property off of there I want and store
it as a standalone variable in this case it is generate message perfect.
So now that we have this in place we can replace the object we created with a much simpler solution
instead of defining the whole object here.
We simply call generate message.
This generates the object and passes it in as the second argument to emit.
And remember we have to provide the text right here for this one that happened to be welcome now that
we have this in place.
Let's go ahead and actually adjust the client to get it to work with the new structure before the client
was expecting a single value to come back a string.
Now it's getting an object which means that things are broken.
If I refresh the browser what do we see.
I see that it's trying to represent that object as HDL which results in the following.
We need to go ahead and adjust that client side code.
So over in chat dot J S right here we are passing the entire object in as the property value for our
message.
We are going to set up the message property but instead we need to grab text off of this.
This right here the message parameter it's now an object.
So that means message dot text with this in place.
Things should be restored to their working order.
If I refresh the browser I would expect to see my welcome message and that's exactly what I'm getting.
In addition though I can see I'm also getting that created at timestamp which is excellent.
We can use that to display the time up above.
Now we only made that change for one of the four places where we emit the message event.
So let's take a quick moment to add it for the others.
For example right here we'll go ahead and cut this string out copying it to the clipboard then I'm going
to go ahead and call generate message passing that string in as the first and only argument and we'll
do something similar down below for sending the message to all connected users right here.
I'll remove the message variable I'll call generate message passing it in restoring order to the world.
And finally we have disconnect.
I'm gonna take this string.
Copy it to the clipboard and remove it from its current location.
I'll call generate message passing in the string once again.
And now every single time the server emits a message event it's emitting an object.
We use a single function to create that object so we know it's going to follow a nice standardized format.
That means over here in chat J.S. our code codes never going to break because message is always going
to be an object.
With this in place let's go ahead and integrate the timestamp into the template.
So in index dot HDL I'm gonna make a change to the message template up above right here before the message
we're gonna add a little bit of code.
What I'm gonna do is open and close another set of two curly braces and I'm going to reference something
like created app.
Now we're currently not passing that in but it's ok we'll just provide it right here later on in the
section when we focus on styling.
Our app will adjust where the date shows up but for now this is a great place to get started.
Then we'll have a space followed by a hyphen followed by another space and then the message.
So with this in place we can save index not HDL and all we need to do is make sure that this template
gets access to some piece of data named created at so over inside of chat dot J S right here we have
to add created add into the mix and I'm going to get it off of the message object.
There is a property on there called created at which is what we want access to.
Now with this current setup we're gonna have a number print in the browser.
That number is not useful for humans as it makes no sense whatsoever.
And that is where the moment library comes into place.
Javascript does provide infrastructure for working with dates and it's not very good when it comes to
formatting it does not give you an easy way to format your dates in a way that you might want.
For example maybe I want to say that something happened three hours ago based off of its timestamp.
Or maybe I want to extract just the month as the shorthand.
That would be Jan for January and fab for February.
So on and so forth java script doesn't give you anything good to get that done you'd end up writing
a bunch of code yourself.
And that's where the moment library comes into place it gives us all of the tools necessary to format.
Time now let's go ahead and pull up the documentation real quick.
You can find it over at moment J.
S dot com.
Here we are gonna head over to the documentation page and once again there are so many things that moment
can do.
We're only going to use a very small part of its feature set for example under manipulate you can learn
how to manipulate time adding or removing weeks or hours or seconds.
What we're going to focus on though out of all of these options is just display.
Our goal is to use moment to display time in a way that makes sense for our application and to do this
moment and provides a format method we can provide no arguments.
And it will find a nice default or we can provide a string this string is a pattern of tokens and those
tokens allow us to customize how the date shows up.
So for example down below we have tokens for month.
I have five different ways I can represent the month and I can see the example outputs over here.
So if I wanted to show Jan or desks excuse me T C for December.
That's not a real word.
I shouldn't have tried to pronounce it.
I would use three M's in my pattern those three ends would be replaced with the correct values.
There's values and tokens for other things as well if I keep scrolling down.
We have a.m. p.m. hour minute and second all of which we can use to get time showing up as we see fit.
So let's go ahead and actually use this format and method with some of these tokens to get our date
showing up correctly.
Right here what we're gonna do is remove the value we currently have for created at and we are going
to call the moment function that's provided by the moment library we loaded in.
Remember in index dot HDL you already grabbed that script tag when you grabbed the mustache library
a few videos ago.
Now we can go ahead and call it passing to it.
Our timestamp so right here that is message dot created at and then we can go ahead and call format.
Now as you mentioned you can call format with no arguments but it's probably not going to show you what
you want.
We can take a quick peek at what exactly we get by default.
It contains a bunch of information in a way that's not necessarily what we want.
Instead we're going to provide our own string pattern using just the tokens that we actually want to
have show up.
So there's no need to show the year or the month if those things don't make sense for your purposes.
And in our case that's true.
All I really want to show is the hour the minute and a.m. or p.m..
Now down below for our there are options for a 24 hour clock or a 12 hour clock.
So feel free to use a pattern that makes sense for where you are in the world.
For me what I'm going to do is use a single H that is the hour from 1 to 12:00 without a padding up
front two Hs adds that padding and making sure it's always two characters that's not something I need.
So right here over inside a format all I do is pass in a string and I type the letter H that character
or token will be replaced with the correct value.
What I'm going to do is save chat dot J S and test things out before we go any further over inside of
the browser.
I'll just give things a quick refresh to generate a new welcome message.
And right here I have 11 and that is correct for the hour.
It is eleven something a M. It's eleven fifty nine.
So almost 12.
Next up we're going to add a couple of other tokens into the mix.
I'm going to show the minute with two characters always so 0 0 instead of just 0 or 59.
They have great examples for all of the tokens.
So you know what you're going to get over here.
We're going to do just that showing the minute.
Now I'm going to put a colon between the hour and the minute and Colon is not a special token and tokens
that aren't special stay as they are.
So moments not going to do anything with that.
It'll show up as is between the correct hour and the correct minute.
Next up a space followed by either a.m. or p.m..
So over here we have a.m. or p.m. I have upper case A for upper case a.m. or p.m. and lower case A for
the lower case version.
Right here I'll stick with the lower case version.
So for me that's just a lower case a loop.
Let's put that inside of the string.
Perfect.
Now with this in place we have a great system for getting the time from the server to the client and
having the client format the time in a way that is useful for users of the application.
What I'm going to do is head back over to the browser.
By now it should be 12 something.
And if I refresh it I can see that it is 12:00 p.m..
Exactly.
Now I believe it's 12 0 1.
I'll give things a refresh.
And now I'm seeing that down below if I were to add other messages into the mix I would expect those
to have timestamps as well and that is exactly what we're seeing right here.
So now we have timestamps set up for our standard messages that we don't have anything like that set
up for our location based messages.
We'll focus on tackling that in the next lesson.
So stay tuned and I'll see you then.