In this lesson you're going to set up the join page for the chat application.
So we're going to allow users to provide their user name and the room they'd like to join.
They'll submit the form and then they'll be redirected over to that chat room.
So what we need to do is create a separate HDL file right here in the public directory.
We're going to create one called Chat dot HMO.
Now index dot HDL that's the home page and that's actually going to be the join page chat that HDL is
going to contain everything we have in the other file that means to get started.
We're gonna head over to index dot HDL.
We're gonna highlight everything in this file copying it to the clipboard and we're going to paste it
over in chat.
Dot HMO.
This file doesn't need to be changed any more.
We are just taking all of that chat code and moving it over here.
Now index down HDL is going to be the join page and we're going to get started by gutting everything
we're not going to need.
We're going to leave the head of the document exactly as it currently exists.
Down below for the body we're going to remove everything so we're removing our div with all of the chat
content we're removing all of our templates and we're removing every single script tag down below.
That's going to leave us with an empty body and we'll focus on building up the markup for the chat page.
So to get started let's go ahead and create a div.
This is going to have a class on it since we're still taking advantage of our styles right here.
That class is centered hyphen form.
And from there it will add another div right inside.
The reason for the divs is to just provide us with a nice layout which we'll see in a few moments right
here.
That is going to be a another div with the class centered form underscore underscore box.
Now inside of here we're gonna put the actual form content and I'll start off with a title tag using
an H1.
Right here I could say something like join or something similar.
Now with this in place let's go ahead and refresh our index dot HDL page just to make sure it's looking
good so far over here.
I'll give things a refresh.
No longer do we see our chat content instead I see my join forum.
Now from here we're actually going to add the form into the mix.
Right here we are going to set up the form with the following elements inside.
We'll start off with a label.
We're gonna use labels to describe the form fields.
And the first thing we'll ask the user for is their display name so I'll set the label equal to display
name and down below.
We're going to create the input where the user can type that name in.
Now we are going to set up some attributes for this input.
First up the type that will equal to text.
It's a simple text field where they can type anything they'd like.
Then we'll go ahead and give this a name.
I'm going to name it.
User name from there.
Just a couple more.
We're gonna set up placeholder to show some text in the input when nothing is typed.
I'll just match it up with the label.
So that would be display name
and lastly we're gonna go ahead and set required and no value is provided.
We just listed out.
This is gonna use a little HDMI L5 form validation to make sure a value is actually typed in.
Next up down below we'll be creating a another label for the other field.
This is the room name I can call this room and then we'll set up the input for that as well.
Very similar to what we have up above.
So the input type is indeed text.
We'll setup a name for this input something like room gets the job done right here.
I'm also going to set up a placeholder room followed by finally required.
Since you are gonna have to provide a value for that as well.
Now the last thing we need here is a button.
This button can have the text of something like join or submit or whatever you'd like.
Now this alone is gonna get everything rendered correctly.
The only problem is that it's not going to bring us over to the chat page when the user submits the
form to fix that.
We're going to set up the action attribute on our forum and we just provide forward slash chat dot HDMI
out the path to the page we want to redirect them.
Now we can go ahead and actually test things out so to get started we're going to refresh the home page
right here.
Local host three thousand and I see my form showing up and it looks really nice.
If I try to submit it.
I can see that I do have to fill out these fields so I'll pick a name something like Andrew and I'll
pick a room.
Let's go ahead and use something like South Philly and then I'll go ahead and click join and to join
that room with this username.
Now currently we don't have any code for actually doing that.
That's okay if we click the Join button though.
We should get redirected over to the chat page and you can see our form data as part of the query string
up above.
So now this page can extract that data and use it when connecting to socket dot I.
Oh and that's exactly what we'll end up working on.
So we have that joint page and we have our chat page and users can switch between them.
So at this point we do have the HDL for the page in place and that's where we're gonna stop for this
one.
We'll be continuing on working on this page and the chat dot HDL page actually using both the display
name and the room name when connecting to the server.
I'm excited to get to that.
It's where we're going to stop for this one so I'll see you in the next lesson.