Welcome to section 18.
The course is coming to a close but there is still this final section and there are still two really
important things that I want to cover in the next video.
The first thing I'm going to do is offer up some suggestions for features you can now add to our existing
applications based off of the skills you acquired in the class.
This is going to give you a few things to work on now that the course is over.
It's going to be really important that you continue to write code and build no J.S. applications in
order to keep your skills sharp in the final video.
The second thing we're gonna do is aim to answer a single question which is what should I learn next.
So I'll offer up a few different paths based off of your interests.
Let's go ahead and jump right in to the final section.