The course is officially over.
But if you've made it this far into the class you're probably wondering what you could learn next in
this video.
I'm going to offer up two suggestions for other courses you could take that would pair really well with
what you learned here.
Now in this case I'm recommending other classes I teach.
If you like my teaching style take those.
Otherwise there are plenty of other instructors teaching these same topics.
You can find the two topics I'm going to talk about over at Lynx dot Mead dot I O forward slash courses.
This is going to redirect you to my profile page on udemy and if we scroll down these two topics I want
to talk about our graph QoL and react.
So if you're interested in spending more time with backend development I would definitely recommend
checking out graph Kuo graph Q offers up an alternative to the traditional rest api and it comes with
a lot of nice features graph.
Q L scales really well it is super flexible allowing the client to request just the data it needs and
it also comes with support for subscriptions allowing you to create real time web applications as well.
So if you're interested in taking your knowledge of know J.S. to the next level that is definitely the
course I would recommend.
Now if you're looking to get a little better at creating the front end for applications I'd recommend
checking out react the react class is going to teach you what it takes to build complex web applications.
So in this class we built some basic web apps with just standard javascript features in that class.
You'll learn how to use the react library to build complex web apps with complex forms validation models
routing and more.
So these are my two recommendations.
If you want to spend more time and with the back end learn about graph.
Q Well if you want to pair no jackass with a front end technology I definitely recommend react.
Now there are other front end libraries similar to react such as angular and view that is v you e.
Those are fine tools as well but react is definitely my favorite of the bunch.
I wanted to come back just one last time to say thank you so much for taking the class.
I'm Andrew Meade and I hope you got a lot out of the course and I hope to see you in another class sometime
soon.