Welcome everyone to this section on conversational neural networks so compositional Neural Networks
are a specific architecture of neural networks that are extremely effective at dealing with image data.
In this lecture I just want to quickly review what we're going to be learning about in this section
of the course we're gonna start off by trying to understand the theory behind convolution of neural
networks and what makes them different than artificial neural networks.
We'll talk about image kernels and filters convolutions as well as pulling layers.
Once we understand the theory behind accomplished neural networks we'll go ahead and tackle two really
famous datasets.
The M this dataset learning how to apply convolution on neural networks to grayscale images and then
we'll move on to color images such as the Safa 10 dataset.
Essentially expanding it out to three color channels red green and blue.
Once you understand how to work of those basic datasets we'll expand to working with real image files
something you'll encounter in the real world.
How did the of pick files or PMG files etc.
So we'll also be using accomplished on your networks for analyzing things like images of malaria blood
cell classification.
So we'll have various images some blood cells will be infected with malaria others will not and we'll
build a compositional network that will actually be able to detect just based off an image whether or
not a blood cell has an infection.
After that we'll go ahead and test your new skills with a compilation on the URL that we're exercise
on a fashion image dataset.
OK let's get started by learning about the theory.
I'll see you there.