Hello everyone.
Welcome to this course.
As a quick introduction to the course we're going to have a course overview lecture and I ask you one
favor that you Please don't skip this lecture.
We're going to quickly cover just a lot of important topics to give you the best course experience possible
so in this lecture we'll talk about some useful tips for going through the course how to get help during
the course.
Advice on how to approach the course where to find the course notebooks and notes and how to use our
student chat channel so a couple of useful tips to use the video player settings to speed up or slow
down the videos.
All you need to do is look at the bottom bar of the video player and you should see either a little
gear icon or just a setting icon to actually speed up or slow down the videos for playback speed.
Also I would highly encourage you to make sure to view the videos in 10 ADP quality.
You can use the Udemy app to download videos of course lectures.
Also please make sure to make use of our current question and answer forums.
There's lots of previous discussion already available there free to check out now let's talk about getting
help during the course.
If you're experiencing issues with the Udemy platform then please email support at to me that com or
go to their support page and open up a new ticket.
These are issues like video playback issues.
If you experience blurry video or audio issues if you experienced choppy audio or things like getting
your certification or issues if your payment I don't control that you give me those.
So you can send them an email that support you to me that com also.
As far as getting help of the course before actually posting to our question and answer forums inside
the course please make sure that you are using our provided environment file and that you've tried running
or provided notebooks directly not just copying pace individual cells but running our entire notebook
often simple typos can cause errors and if you follow the two steps above that pretty much guarantees
that the notes should work because we have the right environment file for you.
Our notebooks will run with no errors.
If you're running them inside the provided environment file so if you ever get an error while you're
coding along the course please make sure to follow these two steps in order to fix any of those typos
other things you may want to do besides double checking against the course notebooks is if you're exploring
other technical things with tensor flow or programming usually quick Google search or stack overflow
search of your error code will bring right away.
The most relevant answer also I encourage you to search the CUNY forums in the course and you can also
check out the FAA queue lecture for general questions.
If you still haven't found the answer to your question with all those steps please submit a new question
in the community forums including details on what you've tried as well the screenshot of your error
or your code.
Please keep in mind that we cannot help with your personal deep learning projects outside of the course
material.
However if you do want to talk to somebody about your own personal work projects or fund projects involving
tensor flow or deep learning we have a discreet chat channel and it's a great place for you to share
your questions on your personal projects.
You can use the link and the automated welcome message to join our discourse server.
Upon enrolling in this course you should have received an automated welcome message.
It has all this information as well as a link and includes a link to a YouTube video describing how
to use and log into the chat server when you check your utility messages.
Please make sure to check all messages not just unread ones in order to actually see our welcome message
remember that the purpose of the chat channel is to connect students for other students technical questions
related to the course material are still best suited for.
Question Answer forums as far as approach in the course.
The best way to approach the course is to review the notebooks along with the video notebooks contain
code used in every lecture and are organized in the same order they appear in the course.
So upon downloading the zip file of the notebooks that goes with this course everything is essentially
in the exact same order organized by the same sections they see here in the unit.
Of course the videos usually contain explanatory concepts that can't be shown through code resource
links.
The notebooks can be found in the FIA queue lecture.
We provide all the notebooks used inside of this as a zip file.
There is no get hub link.
It's all organised for you as just a simple download zip file the resource folder is a little blue folder.
Next the lecture title will actually show you all this through video in our course setup lecture.
So again we discuss all this in detail in the setup and installation lecture so you can follow us with
the video.
All right.
That's it.
Thank you so much for enrolling and let's get started with your course setup.