Welcome everyone to this section on deployment.
Let's start with a quick overview of what this section is going to cover.
We're first going to start off in a Jupiter notebook environment or your Google collab environment and
we'll start off by analyzing the famous IRS data set which predicts a flower class and or using that
data sets we can focus more on creating a model and creating a deployment from that model instead of
the actual analysis of the data itself.
So we're going to start from scratch loading that data set create a model of that dataset and then we'll
show you how to export that model as well as export any additional components you need to go along with
that model.
For example if you used scaling in your model which we will use in this particular case we'll show you
not only how to export your model but also export your scalar that way when new data comes in to your
deployed model.
You can scale that data based off your historical scaling as the model expects and then we'll show you
really two main ways of deploying your model.
One is by creating a COBOL API so we'll call that API with postmen and then will show you how to programmatically
call the API through python and then we'll show you how to call the model through a simple flask web
application which is essentially just an extension of the fundamentals we build in the API lectures
and then we'll show you how to launch this full machine learning application to the web so that any
user can visit your web app type in whatever numbers they want and then your web application spits out
a prediction based off the save that model.
You train in the beginning.
All right.
So lots to cover here.
But first I want to make a couple of notes of what this section is not going to cover please note that
this course is not a web development course.
So if you've never deployed any web application and don't even know maybe what an API is then this section
is probably too advanced for you and you don't have a good use case yet for deploying a model if you're
not actually really familiar with the fundamentals of just what deployment means to begin with.
So this section keep in mind is going to assume some basic knowledge of APIs and web apps.
If you don't know what an API is or what a web application is please revisit this section after learning
a bit about those topics the entirety of what API is are and what Web applications are there really
outside the scope of this course which focuses on deep learning and tensor flow too.
So this course isn't designed to completely supplement an entire web development course.
Also please note that we cannot help you or consult for your homework or personal projects since you
wanted deployed to the Web.
Please keep in mind that we have far too many students and since each deployment case is fundamentally
unique to your own dataset and your own model we cannot personally consult for each individual student.
So if you are deploying your own personal projects and have questions on those please post those questions
toward discord chat channel.
Please do not post questions about your own homework projects or your own work project deployments to
the Q and A forums.
That's not what the CUNY forums is meant for.
Now if that being said the videos and more importantly the code that goes along this section of course
should be more than enough for you to actually use as scaffolding or skeleton code for you to attach
to your own data sets and your own projects.
So if you go through a section and really understand the core ideas of this section you should have
no problem expanding this to your own projects.
Okay so with that being said let's get started and I'll see you in the next lecture.