Hello everyone and welcome to this section of the course that focuses on just general machine learning
and in this particular lecture we're going to try to get an understanding of what is machine learning
so before we jump into neural networks tensor flow the caris API etc. It's a good idea to understand
a few fundamental general concepts regarding machine learning.
So in this section we're going to cover some important theory and concepts surrounding machine learning
so we'll be covering things like in this lecture what is machine learning as well as answering the question
what is deep learning.
Then we'll talk about in future lectures differences between supervised and unsupervised learning the
actual supervised learning process and then how do we actually evaluate performance and how do we evaluate
performance for different tasks.
If we're performing a regression task like trying to predict the price of a new house on the market
or performing a classification task such as trying to predict whether we have an image of a cat or a
dog there's different ways to evaluate how well our actual machine learning models are performing or
doing so we need to take that into account and then we'll also discuss things like overfishing.
So all of these concepts can apply to just general machine learning algorithms.
So it's part that we have a general understanding over a lot of these things before diving into things
like neural networks and deep learning so let's first briefly discuss what is machine learning machine
learning is a method of data analysis that automates analytical model building using algorithms that
it really learned from the data.
Machine learning allows computers to find hidden insights without being explicitly program ought to
look.
So typically a lot of times when we're trying to program something using Python for instance we have
to tell the program what to do.
In each case maybe with an if statement or an if l statement however with machine learning what we do
is we follow a general process and then allow the machine learning algorithm to figure out what the
best approach is dependent on the data.
So really ends up learning from the data and that is what automates the model building so was Machine
Learning used for well machine learning is used in a wide variety of topics and use cases everything
from fraud detection to web search results to credit scoring.
So if you're ever applying for a mortgage there's machine learning happening behind the scenes to see
if your credit worthy.
Or maybe you're traveling abroad and ease your credit card and you get a call indicating a possible
fraud on your credit card.
That's also machine learning attempting to detect fraudulent use cases.
Then there's things like recommendation engines.
So if you're shopping on something like Amazon.com or even viewing some online streaming video service
and it's recommending new videos or new movies or new TV shows to you.
Machine learning is used for that as well and things like e-mail spam filtering so the e-mails that
actually go into your spam folder that's using natural language processing to figure out what is the
actual spam email and then things like pattern and image recognition.
Now there's certain use cases where the only possible approach is to use deep learning.
So keep that in mind later on the course especially during things like convolution on neural networks
for image analysis.
We'll be learning techniques where the only way to actually conquer this task so to speak is by using
the capabilities of deep learning and neural networks so are these neural networks.
We're going to go into a lot more detail about how neural networks are constructed in the next section
of the course.
But for the basics Neural Networks are a way of modeling biological and you're on systems mathematically.
And these networks can then be used to solve tasks that many other types of algorithms can't.
So for example that image classification it's really hard for other machine learning algorithms to perform
well on things like image classification.
And this is the kind of task where neural networks perform very well.
So deep learning simply refers to neural networks with more than one hidden layer.
Now there are many different types of machine learning tasks and in the next section of the course we're
really going to be focusing on two specific types of machine learning tasks and those are supervised
learning tasks and then unsupervised learning tasks.
So we're gonna cover supervised learning and then briefly talk about unsupervised learning in the next
sexual course and we talk about things like classification and regression.
Those will fall under supervised learning so it's important understand the distinctions between these
two various topics.
And then as a final note sometimes students get confused between machine learning neural networks and
deep learning and what the differences are between them.
As a quick review machine learning those are just a general terms for those automated analytical models
neural networks is actually a specific type of machine learning architecture or algorithm that specifically
modeled after biological neurons and then deep learning.
Put simply is really just a neural network with more than one hidden layer.
And we'll discuss what that means and what a hidden layer actually is in the artificial neural network
section of the course.
Coming up next.
So let's go ahead and begin by learning about one of the most common machine learning tasks which is
supervised learning.
I'll see you in the next lecture.