Welcome back everyone.
In part three of the caris syntax basics.
We're gonna focus on the evaluation of our model recall that we have this test set that we can compare
our models to predictions to to evaluate how well our model is actually performing.
Let's head back to notebook and continue where we left off OK.
Here we are where we left off last time.
Now with this plot I can see my losses on the training set but what I really want to know is how well
will this model perform on data that it's never seen before and that data is our test data.
There's lots different ways we can evaluate.
So we're going to walk through a bunch of different methods and a lot of these will return back the
same results.
Some means caught error so we're going to go through the various methods of doing this.
One way to do this is by calling model dot evaluates and the weight model that evaluate works as you
pass in your test set X and Y.
So what I'm going to say is X test and Y test and I will say verbose is equal to zero.
So I don't see a bunch of output and if I run this will happens is it returns back your models loss
on the test set and why test.
So what this number actually represents is the metric loss that you decided on.
And if we take a look back at our model in our case that's mean squared error.
So what this means is on the test set that is data it's never seen before.
It's getting back to a mean squared error of twenty four point nine seven.
So we could do the same thing for our training set so we could say model that evaluate X train versus
Y train run that and we see the loss on our training set.
Keep in mind your values may look slightly different just because of the way the neural network works.
It starts off of random initialization.
So you may get numbers that are slightly different.
However after training on about 250 epochs you shouldn't be hovering somewhere between twenty four and
twenty six as your means squared error.
So what does this actually mean.
Well this is a way we can interpret our results to see how well the predictions are actually performing
and we'll show you and also grab root means squared error and mean absolute error.
So the way we can do that is get our actual true predictions and we do that by saying models that predict
now we're going to pass in our test to get test underscore predictions.
So what this does is we pass in our test features and have the model predict just based off those features
what it thinks the price should be.
So now here's a list of the prices that are predicted based off our next test set.
And in fact let's bring these together along with the true values for that test set.
That is the why test.
And then we can plot them out compare them against each other.
So what I'll do is the following I will create a data frame called pred underscored the F so my prediction
data frame and it's going to be equal to and in this case I will say that my test predictions are this
model that predict and I will turn those into a panda series by saying test predictions is equal to
PD that series Test underscore predictions.
And in this case I will need to reshape this to be 300 karma and that's just what matches up with the
dimensions that a pan this serious call expects.
So essentially after running this I still have those same test predictions but it's a pan this series
now instead of a nut pyrite which will allow me to do the following.
I can say my prediction data frame is equal to PD that data frame based off white test let's say the
columns here are just test true why.
So right now my prediction data frame just has the true value of y and what I'm going to do is say go
ahead and concatenate that with the true value of y comma with my test predictions.
And I know there's a lot of code here as well as a lot of braces brackets and parentheses.
So if you get an error somewhere.
Go ahead and check out our notebook and just run that directly and hear what I'm going to do is also
make sure that I'm joining these along axis equal to 1.
So along the columns after running that you should be able to see your prediction data frame which is
essentially looking like this we have test true y.
And here we get zero because we don't actually have a name for that.
So go ahead and say my columns are test true y and then my model predictions.
So now when I take a look at my predicted data frame I get this result.
So here I can directly see based off my test set what the true price value was and what my model predicted.
OK so what I can do is lots of things now.
I can actually plot these against each other.
So what I could do is say create a scatter plot based off this data and my prediction data frame and
then I'll also do the following I'll say X is equal to test true y and I plotted against these model
predictions.
So run that and we see this result.
So what does this actually mean.
Well let's imagine that my predictions were a perfect match for the true y prices.
That means I would expect a perfect straight line here because if my price was three hundred then my
prediction should also be three hundred.
Now notice we actually are quite close to a very straight fitting line which means this model is performing
very well and we can also grab metrics to essentially show that not just qualitatively through a plot
but quantitatively through the various regression methods that we talked about.
Recall back in the machinery lectures we had a whole discussion on regression evaluation.
So we talked about mean absolute error means squared error and then root mean square error.
So let's show you how you can actually grab those to do that.
I can say from S.K. learn that metrics import mean absolute error and mean squared error.
And if I want my mean absolute error then I just need to if I take a look at this compare my y true
to my Y predicted and luckily I've already organized that for myself in this data frame where I have
my test true y and I also have my model predictions.
So I run that and I get a mean absolute error of about 4 which is something you should begin initially
beginning or somewhere around 4 4 a mean absolute error.
So this means on average I'm about four dollars off from my price point.
Now the most common stupid question I get is how do I know if this is good or bad.
Well it really depends on your original data.
We take a look at our original data frame recall we have this price column let's go ahead and call dot
describe on this and we can see that the average price is around five hundred dollars with a minimum
of two hundred twenty three and a maximum of seven hundred and seventy four.
In our mean absolute error that is how on average how far off we are we are on average off by four dollars.
So if I take a look at the mean price that's less than 1 percent.
So that would mean that this is actually a pretty good mean absolute error.
Something indicated again by this plot right here that's almost a perfect straight line.
So this indicates that our model is performing very well at predicting the price of let's say this gemstone
based off these two features.
Now again the mean absolute error doesn't mean anything without the context of the label you're trying
to predict if the average price was one dollar in our mean absolute error was four dollars.
That means we're off by 400 percent and that's a very different story.
So you always have to take into account the mean values as well as the actual distribution of your label
when comparing it to your error such as mean absolute error and we can also calculate our mean square
error by performing the exact same thing.
So I can say it means great error.
Go ahead and copy and paste this and notice it's twenty four point nine seven which is essentially the
same thing we got at the very bottom here when we said model to evaluate on X test versus Y test which
makes sense because the original loss for the model was mean squared error.
So essentially what this model evaluate line does is exactly what this line does.
It just calculates the mean squared error for whatever you pass in the test set or the training set.
And if we wanted to get the root mean square there then all I would need to do is essentially take the
square root of this which is the same as taking something to the power of zero point five.
You could also say NDP thought rescue party if you imported some pie and then we get back the root mean
square error which is four point ninety nine.
So you can use that mean absolute error means squared error and root mean square.
However you see fit to evaluate your model's performance and finally I want to go over two last things
which is predicting on brand new data.
So let's imagine that we go out into the field and I pick out this gemstone from the ground and it has
these features.
Let's say I pick up this new Gemstone and pay attention to my dimensions here.
I have double braces so that it matches up with the original data and feature one is equal to 998 and
feature two is equal to a thousand.
And these are just made up features.
So I pick this new gem out of the ground and I want to ask my model which I prices at.
Well the one thing I have to remember is that my model is trained on these scaled features.
So what I have to first do is take my original scalar and transform new gem.
So now I have the scaled version of these features.
So let's go ahead and set new gem equal to the scaled version of new gem.
And now what I can do is simply take my model and predict the price of that new gem which in this case
should be somewhere around 420 dollars.
So that's how you would predict on a brand new set of data.
Keep in mind that's the exact same process you just ran on your test data set since your test data set
according to the model is essentially brand new data.
It's never seen before.
So the way you evaluate your test set is basically the exact same thing you would do for brand new data.
And finally if you're running a very complex model that took a lot of time to train you want to make
sure that you save that model and Caris makes it quite easy.
We simply say from tensor flow that carries that models import
Load model and then I take my current existing model and they save it as a HD F5 file so I can say some
string my gem model the H5 run that.
And now what I can do is use the Load model come in so later on I can say OK I'm in a new notebook and
I want to load up this model.
I SIMPLY RUN THIS import command of load model and I say later models equal to load model and then I
read in that model I saved my gem model that H5 and then you make it some morning there based off the
input shape you can totally ignore that warning it's OK but notice now I can treat this later model
just as I would any other model and then predict on new gem just as I did before and notice we get back
the exact same results.
So that's how you can both save a model and then load it later in the new file.
OK.
So we went over the very basics of terrorists.
Now we did this on a fake generated data.
Coming up next let's focus on a much more realistic dataset and really focus on the full workflow including
exploratory data analysis and feature engineering which is very crucial to becoming a good machine learning
practitioner.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.