Welcome back everyone.
Let's go ahead and test your new skills on recurrent neural networks through an exercise in this lecture.
We'll just do an overview of the exercise notebook and in the next lecture we'll go through solutions.
Let's get started.
All right.
Here I am at the exercise notebook.
This exercise should pretty much feel very similar to the previous lecture.
We're essentially asking you to given a time series and this time series kind of a fun one it's frozen
dessert production and it's from the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System again that Fred
dataset.
We want to figure out all the information on it.
You can click on this link but we keep track of the industrial production of ice cream and frozen desserts.
So clearly there is a seasonality to this.
And notice that the seasonality is based on the summer months because when it's hot outside you usually
want some ice cream.
So kind of a fun day to set the play around with here and come back to the exercise where you're going
to be doing is essentially the same series of steps that we did in the previous lecture.
So feel free to reference previous lecture although try your hardest to do this maybe not from memory
but from Google searching on your own and not referencing the code in the previous notebook precisely.
Instead try to see if you can think about it on your own.
See if you can figure out those loops on your own etc. They'll be really helpful for you.
But as always you can always reference our previous notebooks if need be.
So we ask you to read in the data and then go ahead and rename the column to make sure it's easy to
read plot out the data and then do the train test split you have a lot of flexibility here on figure
out the length of the data set but the test set should be at least the last 24 months of data.
Again you can always play around with this and make it less it's up to you.
You can take 18 months of data they don't want you to scale the data and then create the time series
generator object.
Create the model and again you have all the leeway you want.
As far as Alice time units you can see what we actually used here we use 100 Alice Tam units very similar
to the lecture then create a generator for the test set and validation set.
The main thing to note here and this where you actually may get a little bit of trouble is the length
for that test validation generator.
Recall that the batch length needs to make sense for the size of the test set.
So we mentioned that in the previous set of lectures and basically the main thing to note here is that
the length of your actual batch size it has to be less than the length of your test set because if you
have a batch length that's the exact same length as your test set you won't be able to grab that extra
forecasted all point into the future.
So if your test set for instance is one month and your batch length was one month you need the extra
month in order to forecast one month into the future.
So again make sure that your batch length is less than your test length.
OK.
So we discuss that in the previous lecture.
So go ahead review that if you have any trouble creating that validation generator then we want you
to create an early stopping callback.
Go ahead and fit that generator using the early stopping.
It should end around 10 epochs or so plot out the history.
So you'll see that it's pretty noise in the beginning but then starts to flatten out and then we want
you to evaluate on the test data.
So go ahead and get the prediction the predictions etc..
And in general you should be able to at least get a model that more or less shows the trend.
You may feel a little better a little worse in this due to the random initialization of the recurrent
neural network.
But your model should at least be able to tell that during the summer it tends to peak and then in the
winter it tends to go down.
If you got a model that got that general trend then you should be pretty good.
OK.
And then the last tasks and this is something we actually didn't show you how to do.
But I know you know how to do it based off what we learned throughout the entire course is calculate
your route means squared error on this actual data set.
So if you get stuck on this you can go ahead and check out the solutions but you should be able to do
it given everything we know about psychic learn test predictions et cetera.
OK so coming up next we're going to go ahead and go through solutions.
I'll see you there.