Welcome back everyone to part two on competition on your own that works on custom images.
In part two really we're going to focus on is this special object from tensor flow cares which is called
the image data generator.
What you're going to be able to do of this class is feed it in the directory over your actual image
files are and you'll be able to perform a bunch of manipulations on your images and then feed those
new images to your model.
Let's go ahead and explore this idea of manipulating images as well as flowing from a directory.
These new batches of files.
Let's head back to notebook where we left off last time.
All right.
Recall last time we basically read in the data and we figured out what are the average dimensions of
our images.
Because when we feed these images to the model we need to make sure they all have the same size.
So picking out the average dimensions is probably a good idea in our case it was conveniently around
130 by 130.
Next is image manipulation.
So keep in mind there's really just too much data for us to read in all this data at once.
These files are much much larger than the files we've been dealing with.
Recall Em this was on was basically twenty eight by twenty eight.
The Safa was 32 by 32.
And even that small expansion from twenty eight to twenty two color images a 32 by 32 was a huge expansion
in the amount of data.
So that's 28 times.
Twenty eight was seven hundred eighty four data points.
And when we went to Safa That was thirty two by thirty two times three one for each color channel.
That was three thousand seventy two our files are going to be even larger as we read them in they're
gonna be 130 times 130 times three.
So now we're dealing with fifty thousand seven hundred data points because of that we're not going to
be able to just feed in everything at once.
Instead we'll have to select batches of our images.
The other idea that we want the model to be able to overcome is the fact that it should be robust enough
to deal of images that are pretty different from images that it's seen before.
And when we can do that is by manipulating and performing transformations on our images things like
rotation resizing and scaling to begin this entire process we'll say from tensor flow that carries the
pre processing the image import and we're going to use the image data generator.
Go ahead and run that and then once that's imported I would encourage you to actually call help on this
object and take a low or just take a look at the documentation for this class.
There's definitely a lot going on here.
This is a huge class even has kind of full examples of how to do this.
But what I want you to do is just take a time to kind of read through this and see the different examples.
You can also read up about this on its online documentation page.
But what we're going to do is basically show you the main idea of what image that data generator is
doing.
So what I'll do is I'm going to create an instance of an image generator we'll say image Jen is equal
to and we will call our image data generator object.
If you do shift type here you can begin to see the various parameters and there are a ton of parameters
they can pass in here.
Everything from feature wise centering sample wise centering brightness range horizontal flipping vertical
flipping pre processing et cetera.
So there's lots of different things we can do here.
You should also recall that when we're dealing with the m this dataset we had sixty thousand images
and sixty thousand images is a ton of images.
And that was for a very simple file type essentially a very simple image.
It was only 28 by 28.
Right now we have half of that size over our entire dataset our entire dataset is less than 30000 images.
So we want to be able to do is to expand the amount of images without having to gather more data.
We can't just keep grabbing blood cells from people.
So what we can do instead is do things like take our current images and randomly rotate them so something
we can do say rotation underscore range and set this equal to the amount of degrees that we can randomly
rotate our images so we can do something like 20 degrees and for something like the blood cell which
is circular in nature you can possibly choose a lot larger than 20 degrees.
But here I'm just showing you examples the other things we can begin to edit are things like the width
shift range and this will shift the actual width of the picture by some maximum percentage.
So if we say zero point one that stands for randomly choose a value between 0 and 10 percent or 010
zero point one to shift the width of the image and we can do the same thing for the height.
We can randomly kind of stretch these out so we can say something like zero point one.
Now you may be wondering what are good values to choose here for things like rotation and shifting.
It all depends on the kind of images you're dealing with.
We're very lucky in our case that we're dealing with what are essentially blobs.
So we can expect that future images of red blood cells will kind of look like these blobs will be circular
in nature and they can kind of be stretched or squished in feature images.
So what we can do is pray choose a pretty larger values here for things like rotation with and shift.
If you're dealing something like facial data you don't want to be squeezing or rotating faces so much
that they're in unrealistic positions.
For example let's imagine you're making software for a video camera that will be trying its best to
detect whether or not the face of a person is in that image.
You probably don't want to rotate something 180 degrees because it's not useful for the camera to be
able to detect upside down faces unless someone is going to be walking upside down in that camera's
view.
So those kind of ideas can help you choose reasonable values for these random transformations.
OK.
The other thing we want to do is we want to reskill the image so we can reskill it by simply normalizing
it.
If we take a look at one of the sample images we have.
So let's take a look at let's say parasail.
So that was our image file there.
Let's take a look at the image.
Read of it and let's take a look at the max values here.
So in our case they're actually already standard and normalized for us.
But if they were not let's say they went from 0 to 255 then I'd have to reskill by saying one divided
by two fifty five.
In our case it looks like these images are already scaled for us.
So we don't need to normalize anything by the scale factor.
We can also check this on the uninfected cell that we had earlier.
So the uninfected cell let's make sure that's actually I believe this already in array from before.
So we already have the uninfected cell.
Let's take a look at it.
Check out its max value.
It also looks to be normalized.
So it looks like all the values fall between zero and something less than one which is exactly what
we want in our case.
So the reskill factor we don't need to worry about that.
But if you did want to reskill you would do something like 1 over 255 OK so in our case where we normalized
we didn't worry about that.
We can also do things like have a sheer range.
So sheer means cutting away part of the image and we can set that to maybe a maximum of 10 percent.
We can also zoom in on the image.
We have the option to randomly zoom in so we can say zoom range.
Zero point one.
We can also do horizontal and vertical flipping.
So for example I can say horizontal flip is equal to true.
So it will randomly allow for horizontal flipping and then I have to figure out Well how am I going
to fill in the missing data.
So one way of doing this is Phil mode of nearest.
So what I mean by that is if you're doing a transformation that essentially stretches out the image
how are you going to fill in that space.
Are you going to leave it blank through some just padding of zeros or are you going to take the nearest
pixel values to it and then stretch it out with those pixel values.
I would recommend choosing nearest.
OK.
So we have this image data generator.
And let's take a look at this uninfected cell again.
So recall uninfected cell is this array so I can say Pulte image show and I have this uninfected cell.
Let's see what happens if I take a look at randomly transforming this uninfected cell and it may not
be so obvious here because there's no point in the center.
So actually let's do this with the parrot image or the parasite cell.
So we come back up here make sure we grab the right object so we'll say PDT M. Reed parasol.
So scroll up.
Let's choose one actually has this point.
We'll make it a little easier to see the transformations so we're going to go ahead and say Keelty and
show em read parasol.
OK so I have this parasol in read.
Let's go ahead and set that to just be para underscore image is equal to m read parasol.
That way I can just simply display parasite image.
So I run that is basically the same idea.
So what I'm going to do it's take this poor image.
That's my array and I'm going to say the following.
Take my image generator object that I defined above and call a single random transformation.
So essentially do a bunch of random transformations on it based off the restrictions that I set up here.
So we already know this is what it normally looks like when we're actually feeding in the data to the
model.
We're not going to feed it this raw image.
Instead it will randomly transform the image.
So let's actually see the random transformation by St. peel team show.
Run that.
OK so here is now the randomize version of the image.
Notice that we got some stretch.
Kind of like columns sticking out of the cell.
And that's because through this random transformation it looks like it got stretched out and it filled
in those values with the nearest pixel value.
And then note it was also rotated makes a lot of sense to randomly rotate images here because their
cells that can be in any sort of rotational axis that they want.
They can be floating around in their sample so depending again on the actual type of images you're looking
at you're going to be playing around if these actual range values OK so now with the fact that we can
randomly transform these images I can essentially augment my dataset.
I'm no longer restricted to just this single image from the cell I can randomly transform this many
times over.
So if you keep running this you'll see more and more random transformations.
And this is a way of artificially expanding your image dataset.
Recall we had less than 30000 images but now I could do a random transformation on all those images
and immediately double the size of my dataset.
Maybe I could do five random transformations and I've gone from something like 20000 images to 100000
images.
So this is a really powerful tool that you have to keep in mind when you're dealing with kind of smaller
datasets and when it comes to compositional neural networks it takes thousands thousands images to get
something that performs really well.
That's why the m this dataset and that so far 10 data set were actually very large.
OK so how do we actually set up our directories to flow batches from a directory the way we do that
is we say image underscore gem that flow from directory and then you provide the path to your training
folder.
So recall that this train path variable if we come up here was the file path to sell images train.
So we'll say image can flow from directory train path.
And when you run that you'll notice it says OK I found this many images belonging to two classes.
How does it actually know that.
Well it's because in order to use flow from directory your files have to actually be organized in a
very specific way.
And we've laid that out for you in the notebook that corresponds with this lecture working of custom
images.
If you scroll down basically you'll see everything we've been doing so far keep going down until you
see this.
So in order to use Flo from directory you must organize the images in sub directories.
So this is an absolute requirement.
Otherwise the method won't work.
So when you're following along these instructions on your own data sets the directories have to be basically
like this.
You have to have your overall image data folder.
So recall that was our cell images folder and then you need for every class here.
So you have class 1 you'll go ahead and have an image.
Another image in that image of representations of class 1.
Then for class 2 you'll need another image in other image etc..
So essentially what happens is if we take a look at our original training paths so we can come back
to our notebook to play around with this.
Recall that our training path is right here.
Cell images train and inside of that.
If I say OS list directories I have one folder per class.
If we were dealing with a multi class classification problem for example let's say we were trying to
distinguish between images of birds dogs and cats.
Then I would need three folders here one for all the bird images one for all the dog images and then
one for all a cat images.
So you need a folder per class.
That is how this flow from directory immediately understood that there was two classes because there's
two folders here.
There's the parasite folder and the uninfected folder.
So that's how this works.
It must be in this sort of format and you would then have one folder for your training data and then
one folder for your test data.
Okay so in other we understand that.
Let's go ahead and see what it looks like for the image generation flow from the tests it would just
say image Gen flow from directory.
Check out the test path run that and you'll notice it found two thousand six hundred images belong to
two classes which makes sense because it was thirteen hundred images per class.
And again the test path has the exact same formatting.
It has two folders beneath it.
One for each class.
Okay so that's it for this lecture on being able to generate images from this image data generator class
object.
This is a super useful class and it basically does all the heavy lifting for you.
I would encourage you to spend time reading the online documentation for it to see what other options
there are.
But the main thing to note here and again a big part of this is understanding your file parts is making
sure your data is organized into this particular format of one folder per class or then every class
folder has many instances of that particular class so this would for example be all dogs all birds etc.
for each of those animal classes.
In our case we're just dealing with two classes coming up next.
We will create a model and then after that we'll talk about evaluating the model's performance.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.