OK now let's go ahead and start our feature engineering process as well as getting rid of features that
are not going to be useful to us.
So we're going to start working with this feature data and I always like to kind of review the data
frame itself.
So something we can drop right away is this idea this idea is some sort of unique idea.
There's no trend to it.
And if there is we probably don't really understand that based off this number itself.
So I will just say DLF is equal to DFT drop and then go ahead and drop that idea column and that's along
axis is equal to 1.
So we go ahead and just drop that idea column and the next thing you're going to do is check out the
date column.
So if we take a look at this date column right now it looks to be just some sort of string.
So we can convert it to a date time object by doing the following.
I can say the FDA is equal to PD to underscore date time and pass in the FDA.
And what this does is it's going to automatically convert this string to be a date time object and once
it's a date time object that means I can extract information such as the month or year automatically.
So I go ahead and run this.
And now if I take a look at my date column note the formatting is different and it now reports back
that it's a date time object which means I can begin to perform feature engineering off of this this
date time by itself may not be useful but I can extract the year component and the month component and
the way I can do that is through a couple of simple calls I can say the F year is equal to def date
and I can apply a function that actually extracts the year from this date time.
So if I have a date time object it's simply an attribute call to grab the year itself and I can do this
with a simple lambda expression by saying lambda date and then say date month if you're unfamiliar with
land expressions.
That's essentially shorthand for a function so to show you what I mean by that this land expression
would be the exact same thing as if I did this or create a function called the air extraction takes
in some date and then it returns back date that year date that month.
And in this case the should actually be a year in order to match up with what I'm calling the column
here.
So this land expression is the exact same thing as running this right here.
So recall that when built in Python you have this date time object and you can grab the attributes of
Year Month et cetera which is why we called PD to date time on the original string column and then this
land expression is essentially shorthand for that and I'm going to copy and paste this for month as
well and this is essentially feature engineering because these features were technically hidden inside
of the string date and now I'm creating new columns to try to extract or engineer more information off
my original features.
This is a very common step especially if timestamps.
So we'll go ahead and run this.
And now if I take a look at the head of my data frame I have this newly formatted Date Time column and
I'll scroll all the way to the right here and I should see my new year and month column and now I can
do some sort of exploratory data analysis to see if these are useful features in general.
So let's go in and see if there's any variation based off the month that this is selling it.
So maybe we price things higher if we believe they're going to go on market in December versus in March.
So I can do that by saying S.A. box plot and let's go ahead and see the distribution per month
and another way I could do this is through grouping by month and then doing it describe on the price
column as well which is essentially what a box spot does visually.
Now let's make this just a little larger.
We'll say Pulte figure fig size make this something like 10 by six.
Go ahead and run this and I can see the distributions here.
Now it's hard to tell just from this plot whether or not there is any significant distribution differences
between the month that you're going to sell this house at and what might be easier to do is just see
the numbers themselves.
So I could do the F group by column month here and then just see what's the average price per month.
So I'll take the mean after I do the group buy and then just explore the price and then here this maybe
will allow me to actually see or read the numbers myself to see if there's some sort of significant
difference between the months and if I want to see this visually.
I could also just call that plot and this would show me the behavior.
So it looks like maybe there's some sort of difference between the months if we actually see the total
y range.
It only goes from 5 million ish to around five and a half million ish.
So not a huge difference here in the price.
Excuse me actually five hundred ten thousand versus five hundred sixty thousand.
So not a huge range but it looks like there's some behavior differences there in the months themselves.
And we could do similar things for the year.
So if I wanted to explore the year this plot definitely makes sense because if you look back at King
County sales they're just increasing in price as time goes on and you expect that just naturally with
inflation unless there's some sort of a major housing event.
OK so we featured engineered year and month we'll go ahead.
Just keep them in there.
See if the model uses them or not and we'll drop out our date column will say EDF is equal to the drop
and we'll drop off that original date column since it's no longer useful to us since we featured engineered.
Now let's take a quick look again at what remaining columns we have.
We can either do this with the F columns or it can simply just check the head of my data frame to begin
exploring this.
A lot of these features actually make sense already the way they are.
The number of bedrooms bathrooms square foot living doesn't look like we have to do a lot of feature
engineering here and even the waterfront and view type categories.
Those are already in dummy variable form for us.
It's either a 0 or 1 something that we want to maybe take note of is this zip code column.
So there's the zip code is numerical and if we feed this directly into our model the model will assume
that it's some sort of continuous feature that somehow ZIP Code 9 8 1 7 8 is greater than 9 8 1 2 5
and this may or may not be the case that pending how the zip codes are actually mapped out on a real
map.
So this is where domain experience comes into play.
You'd have to either look up the maps yourself so you can do a quick google search and find some sort
of zip code mapping on top of King County and see if there actually is a relationship you could zoom
in here and see if there's a really shift between the numbers zip codes are assigned versus maybe their
latitude or longitude.
They can also do that through some sort of correlation plot but if you take a closer look at this there
doesn't seem to be a clear continuous distribution of these actual zip codes which means you would want
to start treating this as a categorical variable.
So again we'll come back to our notebook here and begin exploring this and see if it's actually viable
to keep it as some sort of category so we can say something like the F zip code and call value counts
on it and this will give us an idea of how many actual unique zip codes we have and what their distribution
is like across the dataset.
And it looks like we have 70 unique zip codes so it's probably too much to just call PD get dummies
on this and then have 70 categories of zip codes.
So we'll go ahead and for this particular case we will drop the zip code column because 70 categories
is just too much for us.
However what we could do is have a little bit of domain experience and domain knowledge maybe try to
categorize this based off what we know are expensive zip codes versus maybe less expensive zip codes
or we could do some sort of mapping or grouping to do zip codes in the south zip codes in the middle
and zip codes in north east and west etc. But this will take then a lot more manual work here.
And it also takes a lot more experience of what King County is actually like.
So again a big part of machine learning and data science is to contact someone with domain experience
and try to get those mappings and feature engineering in place.
But for use case there's 70 categories here.
We'll go ahead and just ignore them for now.
However in a more realistic situation you'd probably want to take the time to look at a map and start
mapping these out yourself manually.
So we'll say EDF is equal to D F drop and kind of for the sake of time really we'll drop the zip code
column
and then there's other things that can take a look at another one that may be kind of troublesome is
this year renovated.
You'll notice that right year renovated if we take a look at it the F year renovated let's do a value
count on that
most of the values are actually zero which essentially implies that it was not renovated.
So he's stuck in a zero there and then we have 2014 2013 etc..
Now there's different approaches we can take here.
As far as feature engineering is concerned one main issue here that we can tell is that zero is not
actually a year.
Instead it's basically an indication that the House was not renovated so it may make more sense to categorize
this as renovated or not renovated essentially turn all these years using a custom to apply function
into a kind of positive renovated call and then keep zero as just not renovated so we could do that
through an apply function.
However we can actually take advantage of the situation by thinking of it in the following fashion.
Notice that it's most likely the more recent the year of renovation.
Essentially the higher the value of this year renovated than the more likely that the House is going
to have a higher sale price.
And we can just think of that intuitively because the more recent the renovation the better.
And since 0 actually follows along with this correlation it's almost like the lowest year possible.
Then we should expect that to also have little value.
So in this case we're actually kind of lucky and due to the scaling from zero to the highest year higher
should correlate with more value and we can actually just keep this as is.
And that's essentially the kind of lucky situation we find ourselves in that the years happen to go
in a positive direction and the higher years tend to correlate with more value because the more recent
renovation just intuitively you expect that to have more value.
Now that won't always be the case for things that are years and then have zeros filled in.
But in our case we got kind of lucky here and that makes sense to just leave it in.
However you could perform more feature engineering off of this by categorizing it into renovated versus
not renovated.
Okay.
And then other things we can do is we can take a look here at something like the square feet in the
basement kind of a similar situation so I take us square feet and basement and do value counts on it.
You'll notice that in a similar situation it just has zero there for a lot of the entries and zero most
likely just means there is no basement there.
So they just put in the zero four square feet and basement.
Now we can see here again the values starting to go upwards etc. and these also basically make sense
as a continuous variable because we would expect that there is no basement.
It would have less value than having an extremely large basement.
So we can also keep this as is.
So a lot of times you'll have to make the decision in feature engineering if you want to make a continuous
variable categorical or just keep it as continuous and you have to really think carefully if it's valid
to keep it as continuous.
And for these two it's not a crazy assumption to keep them as continuous and leave these zeros as kind
of your bottom marker.
All right.
So that's it for a feature analysis and feature engineering section later on in your section exercise
you'll be doing a lot more feature engineering than what we've done here.
So keep that in mind feature engineering and exploratory data analysis is pretty much always a necessary
part of any good data science or machine learning project.
Coming up next.
We're then going to focus on doing our train test split and scaling and pre processing our data in order
to create our model to run off of it.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.