Hello everyone and welcome back.
We just finished our exercise our current neural networks with time series and the bonus.
I want to have a quick discussion on multivariate time series with Ellis team Recurrent Neural Networks
dizzy often requested topic from students.
So we'll go ahead and discuss it so we have this quick bonus notebook.
It actually comes after the exercise solution.
So we're going to quickly discuss how to use Ellis Tan's recurrent Real Networks to predict multivariate
time series.
Something to keep in mind though is that there's a few cons to using Ellis stamps for this approach.
So as with all neural networks the model is essentially a black box that makes it really difficult to
interpret what's the model actually doing internally.
In order to predict this multivariate time series and that's a problem that extends not just to multivariate
time series but using recurrent neural networks for time series in general it's essentially a black
box so you can't see what factors are important to the network especially for a deeper and larger network
that actually relay information to forecasting into the future.
Now the larger con is time series is actually very well studied field of mathematics and there's many
well studied alternatives that are actually simpler to use such as scream X or seasonal auto aggressive
integrated moving average exoplanets models and also via emacs or Varma X models.
So I would highly encourage people to check out those well studied models first and you can apply those
not just to multivariate time series but also single time series and they work very well and more importantly
they're very interpretable.
So I highly recommend they try those more conventional approaches before settling on Ellis tans or current
narrow networks for multivariate time series data or time series data in general while it can feel very
cool to be using state of the art recurrent annual that works for your time series forecasting again
the cost of not being able to interpret what's going on is a large enough con that you should really
fall back this well studied Rima based models.
OK.
Now fortunately let's say you actually do want to check out recurring your networks for your time series
data and you happen to have multivariate time series so there's actually only two real main changes
you have to do to essentially the notebooks that we've been working with and the general structure we've
been working with.
So for a multivariate time series the two main changes are the first as you may expect you need to change
the input shape in your Elyse Tam layer to now reflect that two dimensional structure.
You may recall previously we had a variable called an underscore feature and we were just saying that
equal to one since we just had a single variable or a single feature in our time series in order to
reflect a multivariate time series will simply change that to however many features we have in that
multivariate time series and then the second main change is that final dense layer.
Previously it was just one neuron because we were just forecasting a single value into the future for
a multivariate time series before forecasting multiple features into the future.
So within one neuron per feature or variable.
So let's go out and explore these changes since essentially everything else stays exactly the same.
We're not actually going to manually program through this bonus notebook.
Instead we'll just go ahead and walk through and point out where the two main changes happen to occur.
OK.
Let's open up that notebook and walk you through it.
Here we are underneath the Arnolds folder at the very end you should see bonus multivariate Arnon.
And if you don't see it make sure you've downloaded the latest version of our zip file.
Let's go ahead and open up that notebook and basically just walk through the major changes.
So we have a little warning here that basically tells you that you should definitely check out these
arraignment based models before jumping to Ellis team.
But let's imagine that you do have a multivariate time series and you do want to forecast these multiple
wearables into the future.
So we're working with here is a multivariate time series that essentially it's a data set that occurs
of recording every 10 minutes from a wireless sensor network.
So this wireless sensor network is actually recording a bunch of different features and it's every 10
minutes for 4.5 months.
As you can imagine recording something every 10 minutes for that much time four point five months.
It basically creates a huge dataset.
So later on in this notebook we're also going to take part of that dataset because we want to forecast
24 hours into the future.
You don't need 4.5 months of information a 10 minute intervals to learn that behavior.
So we'll go ahead.
We actually have here linked the original source of the dataset.
Let's zoom in a little bit.
Again we're not actually going to code this notebook out manually and so we'll just walk you through
it.
So let's get just a little bit of a better view.
I'm going to toggle the header here so we can really focus on the code.
So first thing first I did my imports and I read in my CSP file I said inferred they time format equal
true so we can actually infer here that not only is this date stamped but it's also has a timestamp.
And then we set the index column to the date there.
So if you run that line you should see something it looks like this.
We have this index called Date and their date time objects date time because not only are they they
can see it's every 10 minutes.
It's a recording of how many appliances are on the lights.
And then these various features and you can check out more information about various features in the
actual description and link here below.
So we have all this variable data that was recorded and what we want to do is theoretically at the end
on a forecast all these multiple variables together so we can see the information here.
Luckily I'm not missing any information.
So Nanos.
And then if you want you can explore the various features themselves.
So here we can see wind speed.
And here we can see appliances etc..
Notice it looks very noisy and the x axis overlaps because these are 10 minute increments for 4.5 months
so there's tons and tons of data points here.
Okay.
So clearly there's some sort of behavior because you can see here there's looks like there's empty spaces
so you can imagine things like occurring during night or occurring on the weekend that could change
some of these cases.
So what we do is we're going to do a train test split just as we did before.
But before that since we're only predicting 24 hours into the future so as noticed here says we just
don't predict 24 hours in the future we don't need three months of data.
So we're going to do is save a little bit of train time and we're just going to select the last month's
data.
So if we take a look at the head here it starts at 2016 01 eleven and then goes to 2016 may 27.
So 05 twenty seven let's just go ahead and say grab the entire month of May and we can do that with
LLC by saying starting at 2016 05 01 and then go all the way to the end of the colon.
So that just grabs essentially the month of May going for the first all the way to a twenty seven optionally
if you want you can use all the data but you'll save some train time by just grabbing that chunk of
the data.
So we may we went ahead and reset our data is that and what else we want to do is you'll notice that
it has really high precision but a lot of this is unnecessary.
So we can see here it has lots of zeros and for such high precision especially after we normalize the
data it's not gonna be helpful to the network.
Essentially it's going to be noise.
So we'll also do as we round off the data to either one decimal point or two decimal points it's really
up to you.
So here we went ahead and said data from the two and the next thing is to figure out well what's in
our batch sizes look like if there's 10 minute increments that this is being recorded.
We know there's 24 hours in a day.
And then there's 60 minutes per hour.
So by that then by 10:00 which means every one hundred and forty four rows is one day of information.
So you can imagine that if I wanted my test range to be two days.
So here we have this little variable that can play around with test days is to that I just multiply
that by 144 to get the actual amount of rows.
So here we have this little test index that represents how many rows back and have to reach in order
to have my test set at the end be equal to this many days.
So two times 144.
That means the last two hundred eighty eight rows represent those last two days of information.
So setting that as my test set what I can do is just to use this integer based location by saying starting
from the beginning colon all the way up to 1 not including negative test index essentially minus those
two hundred eighty eight rows.
As my training set and then the test set is starting from the end and going back negative two hundred
eighty eight rows colon all the way to the end.
So notice that minus sign in the indexing it won't work for you.
Try it the other way round.
OK so now we have our training set starting at May 1st going all the way to here May 25th and the test
set starting at May 25th just 10 minutes later and then going all the way to May 27.
Perfect.
Then we'll go ahead and scalar they do just as we did before.
We only do it on a training data.
We don't want to assume prior knowledge of this test set and then we transform both train and tests
to get the skilled versions the time series generator object.
This as we did before.
Very useful to us.
So important just as we did before and notice here I set my length to 144.
So I want to get that full daily cycle in the length.
So that's a logical choice that size that's still equal to one.
And so this essentially looks the same as before skill train skill train length and batch size.
The only thing in play around a fear really is the length and 144.
It's logical sense that's a full day's information for the batch.
So given one full day go ahead and tell me in the forecast what the next 10 minutes are going to look
like.
OK.
So we have the length of skill training set.
We know what the generator does.
However if you take a look at the first batch you'll notice that it's quite a bit larger because the
first batch is now essentially passing in every single column and you have a multivariate time series.
So these batches are a lot larger and a lot more complex but the same idea holds that given these last
one hundred and forty four data points for each of the feature columns show me and predict the next
10 minutes worth of data essentially one row into the future of all those variables.
So that's why why is so large it's one y per feature.
Because they multivariate data set.
OK.
So you can edit the length so that it makes sense for your time series.
Then we create the model suite that before.
And this is where the first change occurs.
We have this Ellis Tam layer here the input shape is going to be again defined by the length of that
batch comma.
And then scale train that shape of one.
So what is that shape of one.
Well if we take a look at the shape of scale the train currently it's three thousand five hundred sixty
five rows by twenty eight features twenty eight features.
That's just the number of columns we had in the original data frame.
So if you scroll all the way back up here and take a look at our original data frame and you take a
look at these 28 columns we're right now predicting each of these columns ten minutes into the future
step by step.
So this is what makes it multivariate is that instead of predicting for instance appliances into the
future we're predicting these 28 columns into the future.
So that is kind of main change.
Number one they have to take into account is when you created that model the shape here for this second
I mentioned the input shape has to reflect the amount of features you're considering.
And I've actually put it here as scaled train that shape index 1 because is now the generalized version
of any other data set.
So you could input your own multivariate data set.
Check out the shape and you still be able to use this code as a plug and play because as the generalized
version and same the second change here is the final prediction layer you should have one neuron per
feature.
So it should be the dense layer of skilled train again that shape one.
So if you wanted to you could hard code these as twenty eight.
But here we have the generalized versions and those are the two main changes you need to consider when
dealing with multivariate data.
And as mentioned in the lecture I would highly recommend you check out a Rima based models first because
they're interpret ability and they actually perform very well on multivariate datasets.
So you can check that out.
After that you get a summary of the model and you can also implement early stopping if you want just
a week before essentially nothing changes here.
It all looks exactly the same.
And then we just fit to that generator we to some epochs we can do early stopping we only train for
two epochs because as you can imagine dealing with a multivariate dataset you're training time is going
to go up quite a bit soon as here we only train for two epochs and it was still taking about eight minutes
per epoch more or less.
And if you only train for two epochs there's still plenty of room for improvement.
You can see both training validation the loss of training set and your validation that test set.
We're still going down.
So it's probably good train for a lot more epochs so early stopping was actually never hit.
So you can go ahead and play around that dataset and then train it for longer if you have the patience
for it or if you have some free time to just let your computer run and crunch those numbers then the
evaluation.
All of this code is essentially exactly the same as before.
The only things you need to consider here are when you're reshaping those evaluation batches.
It's one by length.
And then here it's against skill train that shape one.
So that's the main difference here.
Because now that first batch has to include those 28 feature columns.
So that's during the evaluation.
And then here you'll notice that we're essentially just going to set and features equal to scale train
that shape one for all our previous problems and no features we just hardcoded as one.
But here we want to make sure it equals to the same number of feature columns we had in the beginning
and then that loop is exactly the same.
And here we're just predicting for the test range because expand that number to forecast into the future
especially if you just retrained on everything.
So all this code pretty much exactly the same.
The main thing to keep in mind here is your number of features is going to be higher than just one.
And then here we have the test predictions scale tests.
And if you want you can inverse those transformations and begin to compare.
And here we have the real test data.
Versus our true predictions.
And consider if your predictions are a lot noisier and there's only room for improvement here.
Now again it really depends on the actual situation for how you would actually evaluate this model.
You could do mean squared error but recall that you have all these features so we could do is do a routine
squared error comparing for instance appliances versus the true appliances prediction and see how that
performed.
If you just are concerned about your routine squared error on appliances and your forecasting capability
on that particular feature.
But if you're forecasting on everything as a whole.
Maybe you want to do some sort of weighted average of your root mean square errors across all these
features.
It really depends on what features are important to predict which features are not that important and
also you'll notice that the scale here is different for all these so it probably make more sense to
start calculating that sort of error term on maybe the skilled version.
Again it really depends on the exact situation and your exact dataset on how you should be evaluating
these multivariate predictions.
OK.
But again the main differences here are during the forecasting section is edit the number of features
here and during the construction of the model to edit the number of features.
In this simple R9 layer to reflect the input shape and then one dense neuron or one neuron in the sense
layer per feature and those are essentially the main changes.
OK.
I hope that was helpful to you.
And as always again I would highly suggest checking out those Auriemma based models first before jumping
into this kind of black box of deep learning.
But this notebook is here for you.
In case you want ease it.
Thanks.
We'll see you at the next section of the course.