OK.
So here we are back in the notebook.
We have our model where we're going to do is say model DOT and we're going to do is say predict underscore
generator and we're going to pass in our test image generator and then let's go ahead and just call
this PR E.D. for predictions.
Go ahead and run that.
Keep in mind this usually takes a lot longer than a typical prediction because the generator has to
actually go into a computer read and open these image files and then feed them back into your model.
So if we take a look at the results here of pred we get what kind of looks a little strange but essentially
you'll notice there are values between 0 and 1.
So it actually doesn't return back the straight.
Class calls instead it returns back the probabilities so you knows that this last one for instance is
zero point nine seven.
So it's ninety seven percent sure it belongs to Class 1.
So we actually do is set predictions equal to pred greater than zero point five.
And what's nice about this is if you take a look your predictions now.
This is essentially just true and false statements so true and false statements are treated as zeros
and ones in the case of null pi.
So we can do this directly pass this in to our confusion matrix and classification report.
So again keep in mind that pred even though it looks for some of them to be just class calls like zero
on one they're actually a probability values.
So keep that in mind.
Okay.
And if we take a look at the length of red notice for the entire test set.
OK.
So we're gonna do here is simply say from S.K. learn not metrics import a classification report as well
as a confusion matrix run that.
And then let's go ahead and print a classification report comparing our correct answers which if you
want to get the actual classes you can say test image generator grab the actual classes and returns
back in array of those classes.
So that's our why test values pass those in and compare them to our predictions which recall was this
filtered version of the actual predicted probabilities.
So we'll grab our predictions here and put them in so we print our classification report and you should
be getting something around 90 percent maybe a little less.
But we can see our overall actually is eighty seven or pretty good precision recall across the board.
If one scores pretty close to 90 percent keep in mind the defaults are going to be 50 percent accuracy.
And the fact that this is saving a lot of time really helps.
And what's nice about this model is the fact that it's returning predicted probability is let's say
you wanted to implement this model in real life and actually have it aid doctors.
So far we're saying that if we're more than 50 percent sure that our prediction is infected go ahead
and label it as true it is infected.
Actually we have to look back here and check the so uninfected is actually one.
So the values go from 0 to 1 and unaffected is one which means if it's true that's a one we believe
it to be uninfected.
So what we're saying here is if we if we're saying with a probability of greater than 50 percent that
it's uninfected go ahead and just say that it's unaffected.
But really what this is going to do is serve as a model that assists a doctor so we can actually set
the threshold higher if we want to.
And this is where you can essentially make your own sort of precision recall tradeoff so you can maybe
say OK I only want to maybe alert the doctor if we're 80 percent sure or something like that and have
the doctor manually look at everything else.
So this is something you can definitely play around with.
And it's in poor aspect to consider in real life especially when we talk about things like what's more
important a type 1 error or a type 2 error or a false negative or a false positive.
And we discussed all that in the machine learning overview section of the course.
So keep that in mind.
This line right here even though kind of looks innocuous and just a very brief moment.
This is actually probably one of the most important lines in this entire project because it directly
determines your precision recall tradeoff rate.
OK so we have a classification report and we can also perform a confusion matrix if we want to we can
say confusion matrix pass in essentially this tuple right here.
Go ahead just copy paste that and we can see how many or where misclassified.
OK so once we actually take a look at that let's go ahead and show you how to predict on a single image
if we take a look at parasol.
This is a single image and I can actually show you that image by uploading from Kerry's pre processing
we can say from tensor flow dark hair stop pre processing import an image function and what's kind of
nice about this is there's this load image functionality that's actually built into tensor flow.
Previously we were using my part limb but we can actually do this with this parasol so we can say image
load image.
And it actually displays an image.
And if we check the type of what this returns it's returning back the special kind of pillow image file.
So keep that in mind.
Secondly not an array.
It's kind of specialized image file.
What we're gonna do here is what's nice about load image is not only can we provide the path but I can
also say what's my target size.
And in this case I can reshape by saying my target size is equal to that initial image shape I define
of 130 by 130 by three.
So we'll go ahead and say This is my image
and if we take a look at my image the notebook actually displays it.
So we think about this real world situation what's actually happening.
The doctor is going to essentially e-mail us this PMG file we'll go ahead and either train our model
or load up the model that already exists.
And so now we've got this email of this PMG file we'll load it with this command image that load image
will check what our target size was the image shape and we can always say if we want to model that summary
run that and we can kind of examine the model that we're already working with here and then what we're
going to do is we're going to read in this image and pass it to the model.
So how do we actually do this.
Well if we say image dot there is an I.M. g to array which actually transforms the specialized image
object to an array.
So I'll say my image array and now I have my original image which quite clearly looks like it's infected.
Given the design and now let's actually grab my image array and there we have it where we're gonna go
ahead and do is we're going to check the shape and notice it's 130 by 130 by three.
So what I'm going to do here is simply resize this along the zero dimension and I can do that several
ways I can do a reshape or what I can do is I can say NDP and it has this expand dimensions functionality
that basically says taken that current imagery and expand it so that it has a new image along axis is
equal to zero.
That very first item because really what I want this shape to look like is one image by 130 by 130 by
three color channels.
Because the model expects batches of images even if it's just one image it needs to know that it's a
batch of one image.
So let's go ahead and redefine that we'll say my image Ray is equal to this guy.
Now we check my image Ray check the shape of it.
It's one by 130 about one three by three.
Now it's ready for our model to predict we're predicting off a single image array not off a generator.
So now I can just say my imagery run model predict and it predicts it to be zero which recall if we
were to take a look at the class indices again we can do this off train image generator or test them
a generator called Class indices.
It believes this is a parasite cell and clearly it is in fact it was the first image we saw previously.
OK.
That's it for this project I hope you had a lot of fun and I hope now you explore your own image datasets
and start training it for your own classification problems.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next section of the course.