Welcome back everyone to part three of our Caris regression coda long project.
So we just in the previous lecture ended up training our model and fitting to that training set.
Now it's time to explore and evaluation on not just our test data but also being able to predict the
price of a new house given its features.
Let's get started.
OK here we are in the notebook where we left off last time we just finished training for those 400 epochs.
Well I'm going to do now is explore what my model history looks like now.
So recall we can get a history of those losses by saying model that history that history and it returns
back.
This dictionary however because we passed in the validation data tuple what I can now do is want to
convert this to a data frame I not just get my loss on my training set but I also get this other variable
called Val underscore loss and this is my loss on that test set.
That validation data and now I can directly compare the loss on training versus the lost on test or
validation in order to see if I'm over fitting to the training data on my model.
And the best way to do that is by simply plotting these.
So I will say losses is equal to that data frame and then I can say losses that plot and I can directly
compare the plot behavior of my blue training loss versus my orange validation loss.
And this is exactly the kind of signal we want where there is decrease in both the training loss and
the validation loss.
And then there is no increase so far in the validation set.
And actually what that means is technically we could have continued training.
Now you'll notice that towards the tail end we're actually not improving that much.
So after 400 epochs it looks like we're kind of hovering around this particular lost value and the decreasing
is happening much slower but because the validation loss is also going down that's an indicator that
we could continue training without over fitting to our training data.
If you saw this orange line began to spike after some of these epochs so it started to go up and up
and up.
That means your over fitting to the train data because now you have a much larger loss on your validation
data.
And later on in the lectures we'll see an example of that which will allow us to then actually implement
what's known as early stopping in this case.
This is pretty much the perfect behavior you want to see.
You want to see training loss and validation loss go down and then continue down together.
So there's no over fitting that we can see occurring here OK.
So now let's do some evaluation on our test data.
So what we can do is a variety of methods on this.
You can say from us can learn that metrics import and we can import things like the mean square error
the mean absolute error and we can also even if we want get an explain variance score.
So what we do here is we grab our predictions
by saying model that predict and we're gonna predict on the test set so we run that and now recall we
have our list of predictions and we're going to do is simply compare these to what we know are the correct
values so we can call mean squared error or mean absolute error we can do both and what we do is we
first pass in y true.
So recall that is why test and then we compare that to our predictions.
So our total means caught error here is this value is a very large value which kind of makes sense because
we're dealing with the prices of houses.
So we're Squaring those.
So it should be a large value.
This is really hard to interpret.
So what we can do is either get the root mean square error by taking the square root of this either
by running Ed pew or NDP square root.
This is our square root error or root means square or we can do is also get mean absolute error.
So I mean absolute error it's really easy to interpret because essentially just what is your average
absolute error across all your predictions.
So it can say why test versus predictions and it looks like our mean absolute error.
So on average we're off by about one hundred thousand dollars.
Now is that good or is that bad.
Again we have to take into account the actual data frame itself.
So we have to take into account our price column off the original data frame called describe on it and
see what kind of values we're actually dealing with.
So recall that the mean it looks like it's five point four times tend to the five.
So if we actually grab this and put it in here as a number we'll report back that the average price
of the house is around five hundred forty thousand dollars.
In our case our mean absolute error is about one hundred thousand dollars so that's not really that
great.
Or off by around 20 percent.
So not great.
Not horrible either.
We can also do is use and explain the variance score to try to get a deeper understanding of our evaluation
metrics here.
So I can use explain variance score and if you do shift time here they'll essentially explain what's
actually happening here.
So the best possible score is one point zero.
And what this does it tells you how much variance is being explained by your actual model.
You take a look at the online documentation for further examples of how this actually works and how
it actually is calculated.
But what we can do here is same as before has an R Y test values versus our predictions and we're getting
explained variance score of somewhere around zero point eight.
So in this case zero point seven nine.
So that's just merely OK.
Again it really depends on the context.
Do we have a previous model that actually performs better than this.
We also notice that technically we could still keep training and keep lowering this loss.
So maybe it's worth it to try to keep training on the training data since we technically haven't actually
reached over fitting on it quite yet due to our analysis here.
Well we can also compare is our predictions and we can plot them out against a perfect fit.
So recall that previously what we did we did a scatter plot of white test versus our predictions and
we can see the way they fit here.
And what I can do is make this a little larger so I can say Pulte figure thick size is equal to let's
say 12 by six in order to fit everything nicely.
Now in a perfect world this would be a straight line.
Now we can compare by saying PDT plot and I'm going to plot y test
against y test and I'll just say this is a red line by saying ah and now this red line represents the
best or the basically the perfect prediction line.
You'll notice that we're basically being punished here by these outliers.
So these really expensive houses were actually not good at predicting that price but we're pretty good
at predicting the prices of houses between zero and two million dollars is actually not so bad.
There's clearly a good fit here between our test and our predictions and that's essentially what explained
variance score is trying to report back to you in the form of a single number what may be worth it is
to retrain our model just on that bottom ninety nine percent of houses.
And so if we come up to a situation where our maybe sale price is over three million dollars we'll just
say sorry our model's not good enough for this and we'll only refit to that bottom 99 percent.
Again it really depends on the context and what questions you're trying to answer and what problems
you're trying to solve.
OK.
So finally let's show you how you would use your model to predict on a brand new house.
So let's take a look at our original data frame.
We'll go ahead and just pick the very first house here.
So let's say the F and what we'll do is we're gonna drop the price of this house.
So say drop the price along axis is equal to 1 and then just grab the very first house here.
So what this is.
These are only the features of a new house and market.
So let's say a new house is coming onto the market and you want to sell it in October 2014.
And you know these various features of the house you know how many betters it has you know how many
bathrooms it has et.
You know its condition whether or not it's waterfront et cetera.
So we have all these features for a new house coming onto the market.
Now the next step is to actually scale this single house data.
Recall that our model is trained on scaled versions of the features which means we can actually pass
in these features raw and instead what we need to do is say single house grab those values.
So now it's a nun pie array but the shape is actually off.
Notice there's only one set of braces or brackets there.
I need to reshape this to be negative one by 19 and you'll notice now that essentially adds that extra
set of brackets there which is the shape expected negative one just basically means keep those old dimensions
along the axes.
So now that I have it in the correct shape I should be able to say scalar that transform on this.
And now I have the skilled versions of everything and now we'll reset this to be our single house.
So now that I have my single house I'll say models that predict on my single house run this and now
I have the predicted price that this will sell out.
And if I take a look at the f then the very first item there just show one the true price.
It sold that was two hundred twenty one thousand dollars and I'm predicting it will sell a two hundred
eighty eight thousand dollars.
So it looks like we are kind of overshooting here and again that may be an issue when we're trying to
fit to these extreme values.
So an interesting next step to actually undertake would be to retrain your model by dropping out maybe
the top 1 or 2 percent of values and see if that can reduce your means squared error on your data set.
But for right now I would say we're pretty much done with this project.
We've been able to do a little bit of fixed engineering do a little bit of exploratory data analysis
create and train a model and then get back a relatively reasonable model in order to predict the prices
of houses.
It's not like we're predicting 2 billion dollars on a 200 grand house.
Instead we're relatively in the range of what a house could sell it.
And it looks like we're more or less explaining quite a bit of variance up to 80 percent of the variance
in the pricing.
Okay.
So that's it for this lecture coming up next.
We're going to begin to dive deeper into a lot of these topics based on things like batch sizes and
early stopping in our model.
And we'll do that by taking a look at classification tasks through tensor flow.
I'll see you at the next lecture.