Welcome back everyone to part two of our classification code along in part two we're going to create
the model and then show you how to help prevent over fitting of the model.
Let's head back to the notebook and continue where we left off last time OK.
I'm going to begin by importing tensor flow.
Actually we'll say from tensor flow
from tense flow that carries that model's import sequential.
Make sure you spell import right.
Run that and then we'll also say from tensor flow that Kerry's stock layers import and will first start
off using dense layers but we'll also add in dropout layers later on OK so let's create a very simple
model given what we know so far about creating models.
So right now in my training set I have four and twenty six rows.
So not a whole lot of rows and then 30 features.
So what I will do is I will create a sequential model and then I will add in a first layer of 30 neurons.
You can say units equal to 30 if you want and then the activation will just be a rectified linear unit.
And then we will repeat that except we'll go ahead and cut that in half.
So the next layer will go down to 15 and we'll keep things simple so that we have one last output layer.
And this is just going to be one neuron.
However the activation and this critical will be sigmoid because this is a binary classification problem.
So for a binary classification problem we want the last activation to be sigmoid.
Check out the theory lectures on this.
If you are a little fuzzy on why we're choosing that specific activation to have binary classification
one neuron outputting something between a 0 and 1 and that will decide what class this belongs to either
malignant or benign.
And then we will compile this we'll say model compile and we also have to make sure this last call is
correct.
This should be binary underscore cross entropy in order for it to work correctly.
And then the optimizer we have lots of different options here but we'll go ahead and just choose an
atom optimizer.
So we created our model and now it's time to train the model we'll say model that fit and we'll say
X is equal to x train why is equal to y.
Train and then epochs.
And I'm going to choose a really large number of epochs here.
So six hundred is probably way too many for its particular training.
But I want to specifically actually show you what it looks like when you're over fit to your training
data and to do that we're also gonna pass in our validation data.
So say validation data and we'll pass an X test and white test so go ahead and run this and this will
take a while because we're running it for so many epochs.
So I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done.
Training on the six hundred epochs.
So that's six hundred times through the entire training set.
So let me fast forward in time okay.
This is just finished training for the six hundred epochs.
We're going to do now is we'll go ahead and plot out the loss and remember you passed in our validation
data during the training.
So we'll be able to plot out both the training loss and the validation loss.
Recall that I can say model thought history that history and I can pass that into a pan this data frame
and we'll call that losses and then here's my losses I have the training loss and the validation loss.
Let's go ahead and plot this out and see what this looks like so here are my losses and this is a perfect
example of over fitting.
So what is the key characteristic here over fitting.
You'll notice in the beginning during the first couple of epochs both validation and training loss are
both decreasing.
That's good.
That means we haven't yet over 50 training data.
And as we go along we're decreasing loss in both the validation set and the training set.
However at a certain point in time notice that our training loss here in blue is still going down.
However our validation loss is beginning to increase.
That basically tells us that we're over fitting to our training dataset so we have a clear indication
here that we're training just for too many epochs.
Notice the validation list gets worse and worse after these epochs.
So we're going to do is we're going to see if we can use early stopping.
So we've obviously trained too much.
And we're going to do is show you how to use tensor flow cares callbacks to actually based on your validation
loss stop the training before it gets out of hand as shown here.
So I'm going to copy and paste our model again and this is kind of important in order to show this because
we don't want to keep training on the same model.
I want to recreate the model fresh so I will copy and paste these commands or scroll down.
Go ahead and basically redefine your model again and then let me show you how we can use callbacks.
And these are not the only callbacks we'll be using throughout the course.
This is our first instance of using one we'll say from tensor float dot care stop callbacks import and
the callback we'll be learning about right now is called early stopping and I would encourage you to
call help on early stopping to see the full details on it.
But basically what's happening here is we have to choose a metric to monitor in our case it will be
validation loss.
This orange metric right here.
So we're gonna be tracking that validation loss and then you can specify things like the minimum changed
required.
Also there's patients which is the number of epochs with no improvement after which training will be
stopped.
So it doesn't just do a hard stop the minute that validation loss goes up a little bit you can see that
throughout training there is a little bit of noise so maybe we want to wait a couple of epochs so we
can have that patient's parameter there as well and we'll have different modes of training.
So lots of different things you can explore here and you can even see the full example that's available
to you in the doc stream.
But let me show you how to use this early stopping and the early stopping has basically two steps.
One is to define the variable early stop is equal to early stopping so we do that actual call and in
our case we're going to be moderating monitoring validation loss
and then the mode that we're actually looking for is men.
So there's a couple of different modes here.
Go back up here and check them out.
Recall that the mode is basically what are you actually trying to do here.
Are you trying to minimize the thing you're monitoring.
Are you trying to maximize the thing you're monitoring etc. so you can imagine if our metric was accuracy
accuracy something you want to maximize.
If our metric is loss essentially the reverse of accuracy loss is something you want to minimize.
So keep that in mind.
And there's also this nice little auto string that basically the direction is automatically inferred
from the name of the Monitor quantity so ill infer it based off the string that usually almost always
works but just in case it doesn't.
I would recommend that you manually put in min or max.
It also lets you know that you know enough about the metric you're actually tracking to understand what
you should be doing for early stopping.
So in this case we're tracking our validation loss which is what we want to minimize because if we have
a loss of zero that means we have a perfect fit.
So we'll go in and say early stopping monitor validation loss try to minimize it.
And we'll also say for both is equal to 1.
Basically just have a little report back and then we'll set patients equal to twenty five.
That means we'll wait twenty five epochs even after we've kind of detected a stopping point because
of noise that could occur.
So we create this early stop variable and then upon calling model that fit and I'm going to copy the
same command we used before.
So up here we have our original model fit command.
Just go ahead and copy that.
So we'll go and copy the contents of that cell.
Make sure you've redefined the model again.
Otherwise you'll accidentally be training the old model.
So we just redefined the model again and I'm calling model that fit everything looks the same except
now I'm going to add in a couple more lines here we'll say callback parameter or callbacks is equal
to.
And you actually pass this in as a list even if it's just one and you pass in that early stop callback
so go ahead and run this.
And now it's going to happen is it's going to attempt to run on 600 epochs unless the early stop is
triggered.
And in this case note that the early stop was triggered and if you scroll down here it stopped training
after 81.
So it has that early stopping call.
So that's nice.
Now we know that 600 was too much.
What's also nice about this is you can now with early stomping to some arbitrarily large number of epochs
and then indicate that you want it to stop early with this callback.
So now you have to worry too much about choosing the correct number for epochs since callbacks with
early stop.
We'll take care of that for you automatically.
Let's now check out that model loss so we'll say model loss is equal to this pan this data frame call
on Model history the history and then we will say model loss plot.
Go ahead and run this.
And this is exactly the kind of plot that we want to see or loss and validation loss are both beginning
to go down and right as they begin to spread out.
That's probably were a good indication of where we should stop training.
So notice this flattening out.
That's OK behavior.
Well we want to prevent is validation lost beginning to increase and that's what was happening so early
stopped was triggered.
All right.
So the third thing we can do to try to help prevent overfishing is add in dropout layers.
So dropout layers will essentially turn off a percentage of neurons randomly.
So let's come back up here and I'm going to copy and paste my model again to make sure I don't accidentally
keep training my old model so there's my model again and what I'm going to do is I'm also you can do
this in the same cell or in the cell above it.
We will say from tensor flow that carries that layers import dropout with technically already than this
I just want to clarify that the drop out call comes from Carousel layers and you should have already
imported this before but go ahead just do it again.
And what we're going to do is after each of these two dense layers we will add in the drop out calls
a model dot add and then we say drop out and then the main parameter you choose will drop out.
You can do shift tab here and you'll notice that the main thing is basically raped and the rate is the
probability that you're going to randomly turn off the actual neurons.
So it's the fraction of which your randomly turning them off.
So if you put a zero that means your taking zero percent of the neurons and randomly turning them off
during training if you put a one here you typically would never do that.
But that basically means that 100 percent of the neurons are going to be turned off randomly for each
batch of training.
So is a really common value is somewhere between zero point two and zero point five.
And essentially that means is half the neurons during each batch essentially each batches one entire
epoch of training.
In our case because we haven't specified it that size half of those neurons in this layer of 30 are
going to be turned off.
So their weights and biases won't be getting updated.
So we'll go ahead and put that here as well.
And that means again about half of these neurons are going to be turned off randomly.
So it's not the same neurons each time it's a random sub selection of 50 percent of the neurons.
OK so that each neuron has essentially a 50 percent probability of being turned off during each batch.
So go ahead and rerun this.
So we read the fine our model and then we'll use this in combination with drop out so we can still retain
the same early stopping here but I'm going to copy and paste the contents of this model that fit.
We still have our early stopping and now we've added in these dropouts.
So both of these things should really help prevent overfishing.
We'll go ahead and run this and we should expect this to run on all 600 epochs.
So go ahead and just wait a little bit and eventually it should stop running.
Notice it did run for a little bit longer and that's actually good because it means it's still learning
even on those further epochs.
And that's due to the fact of these dropout layers.
So let's go ahead and analyze now these losses here will say moral loss is equal to PD data frame
model history and then we'll go ahead and plot this out.
And this is even better behavior in fact this is absolutely fantastic.
Note that the training loss and the validation loss are both quickly going down and they essentially
are flattening out at the same rate.
This is exactly the kind of behavior we want to see.
This is much improved over what we saw earlier.
Recall our original plot here where even at that set of epochs we were already clearly over fitting.
So no adding in the early stopping and adding those dropout layers has significantly increased performance.
So let's do now a full evaluation on our classes.
So recall that we're performing a classification task so we're predicting essentially either a zero
or one.
And the way this works of chorus is instead of saying models that predict we actually now say model
predict underscore classes we pass in our test dataset and it will end up showing you the classes it
predicts for the X test dataset and recall that even if you had some new tumor with all these features
it's still just predict classes.
A new data point is essentially the exact same thing as a test set so then we'll go in and say these
are our predictions and now let's go ahead and say from S.K. learn that metrics import and there's two
main things we import for a classification problem and that is a classification report and they confusion
matrix and definitely check out the machine learning theory lectures.
If you have any questions on things like accuracy precision recall or F1 score we've actually already
covered what those represent so we'll go in and print out our classification report and this takes in
white true.
In that case that's why test.
And we directly compare against predictions.
So go ahead and run that and we can see the results here.
So notice we're getting very good performance and we can check the performance by printing out our confusion
matrix showing the comparison of white test versus our predictions.
And that essentially shows that our network only misclassified one point in our test set.
Yours may be slightly different.
You may mis classify a few more specific sets especially if you're using a different random split than
us.
But overall overall you should have gotten better than zero point nine five.
Performance on precision and recall.
Okay.
So you can also then check out the accuracy here we're ninety nine percent accuracy and we're doing
fantastic on precision and recall and recall that here that accuracy is a good metric because we saw
that we had relatively balanced classes they were perfectly balanced but they weren't extremely unbalanced
either.
And that's what this count plot of the actual label was for.
All right.
So now we have more tools in our arsenal for deep learning.
We've understood now that we can add in dropout layers and we can also use early stopping to not have
to worry about the number of epochs that we're training for.
So lots and lots of different things we're going to keep adding to our toolkit to become better practitioners
of deep learning of tensor flow.
Okay.
Thanks.
And I'll see you at the next lecture.