Welcome back everyone.
It's time to test new skills with a project.
So you're going to be building a model that will attempt to predict whether or not someone will pay
back their loan based off historical information you have three options for this project either go completely
solo an exercise guide notebook or coat along with the solution lectures.
Let's quickly review your three options.
Your first option is to simply read the introduction in the exercise notebook and then proceed if your
own methods to build a predictive model.
You may even be able to build a predictive model that actually outperforms our guided solution.
So feel free that if you feel very confident with the material that we've already presented for you
to just take your own stab at the project and see what you can come up with.
The second option is to follow along with the exercise guide notebook.
So we've written out a notebook with step by step tasks for you to complete in order to guide you through
building a predictive model.
And then finally the third option is to simply code along with the solutions lecture so you can skip
the next overview lecture and simply treat this project as a large coda long project.
So you can cut along with us as we guide you through our solution video for the project.
Feel free to choose any of these three options depending on how comfortable you felt with the previous
material we've gone over.
Keep in mind this is a very large project and to reflect a realistic situation we actually spend a lot
of time performing feature engineering and preparing and analyzing our data for our model.
So let's explore the project guide notebook in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.