Welcome back everyone to generative adversarial networks.
In part one we're just going to briefly go over uploading our data now to save on train time or we're
actually going to be doing is working off the m this dataset.
A data set that we're very familiar with.
That way we can focus on how the generator and discriminator actually work instead of focusing on learning
about a new dataset.
But the other thing we're going to be doing is to save on training time and to really see how the generator
and discriminator work we're going to be filtering out the m this dataset to only select a single digit
so we'll select all the zeros for instance and then we can clearly see the generator be able to generate
images that look like a zero.
OK let's head over to the notebook and get started.
All right.
Here I am at the notebook I've already imported an umpire S&amp;P pandas as PD and map pup lived up pipeline
SPL T.
And let's load up our end this data set.
We can do this by saying from tensor flow dock carries that data sets import amnesty so this a data
set that already actually very familiar with.
So we'll go ahead and do is will simply use the tuple unpacking TO GRAB IT WE'LL GRAB THE X train y
train subset of those tuples and then the X test and white test and we run this with M this stop load
data.
OK so we load up our data.
Let's go ahead and use peel to show the display at one of these to the arrays let's go ahead and grab
that first image X strange zero and we can see it's a five.
Okay.
And recall that the actual y data is essentially just the actual number itself.
So we can see on y train the first one was the five corresponds to this image.
So what I want to do is want to filter out the data for two reasons.
One is to get a little bit of a smaller dataset for faster training and 2 so we can clearly understand
the generator is working or not.
So what I want you to do is choose one of these numbers to actually feed and generate data from.
So what I mean by that is for instance I'm going to select only zeros.
I can go ahead and follow along with me by saying X train where y train is equal to zeros.
So notice here I have white train and if I were to say where's white train equal to zeros then I get
this tuple of excuse me this num pi array of billions false true false false etc..
And so I'm going to use these actual boolean indices to then only gram those corresponding X train images
essentially allowing me to only grab the zero images and now if I take a look at only zeros dot shape.
Notice now I have around 6000 images the actual size of my full dataset recall is about ten times as
much sixty thousand images.
So we're dealing with a much smaller dataset.
And what's nice is now all of these numbers essentially look more or less the same.
So any of these for example loops not only train only zeros.
So any of these guys just go ahead and choose any random number between zero and five thousand nine
hundred twenty three.
And if you actually show it feel to team show they're all essentially these kind of zero looking things.
So they should be kind of looking like doughnuts or these rings which is kind of nice because that way
we can be able to tell if our generator is actually learning from our very particular data set.
So I would encourage you to choose a number and if you want you can choose zeros like us because it's
a very distinct shape.
We can see here that there's essentially no values on the outside.
Then we suddenly have our values as the string and then no values on the inside.
It's a very particular shape and it's gonna be hard for the generator to mistakenly make this from just
random noise.
So there's a very distinct shape.
So we'll be able tell whether or not our generator is learning from it.
OK so that's it for the data.
What we've done here is we just loaded up our data set and then only using the x train data set.
What we did is we filtered down and chose one particular number if you want to follow along exactly
if us go ahead and just choose zeros.
But what's fun about this is then you can change this white train to equal any number from the M this
digit dataset.
OK.
Coming up next we're going to focus on is actually creating the generator and the discriminator.
I'll see it there.