Hello everyone and welcome to this course installation and setup lecture in this lecture.
We're going to show you the two options for setting yourself up for the course.
The first is Google collab notebooks that are online.
And the second is a local installation Google offers a free service called Google collaborator notebooks
or Google collab for short.
They're free from Google and the only thing they require for you to do is to set up your Google account
such as a G.M. and was really nice about this is they also allow you to run on GP for free online as
well.
And while no installations are necessary you essentially just log in and the notebooks are ready for
you.
The internet is required to you're not gonna be able to run these notebooks offline.
You should also keep in mind that because they're free the free tier does have limited disk and RAM
space.
However for the projects we do in this course there should be enough disk and RAM.
The other option is to do a local installation which will also walk through in this lecture.
This requires however the installation of python and a few libraries.
Once you install Python through Anaconda and the libraries through a environments text file list that
we provide for you it no longer requires internet access beyond that and there are no memory limits
beyond your local hardware so we're going to first quickly show you how to access Google collab notebooks
online and upload files since that's the faster setup of the two.
Afterwards we'll walk through the entire local installation process.
OK let's start by showing you how to access Google collab notebooks online.
I'm going to head over to my browser now.
All right here I am in my browser a Google dot com.
Notice that I've already logged into my Gmail account.
You can see my little icon of change in the top right.
So you need to do is also log in to your G.M. account.
It can work on a free e-mail.
And the next step is to Google Search Google collab notebooks hit enter and the first link you should
see is collab.
That research does Google dot com.
And if you don't see that link go ahead and scroll down until you see it but otherwise you could just
manually type this your URL into your browser.
Go ahead and click that link and see if we're already logged into Google the first thing you should
see.
You won't see it.
This zoomed in but you'll see this little window open up and it has a couple options for you.
It has the examples tab which has example notebooks for you to follow such as an overview of collaborator
features a markdown guide et cetera.
So these are super useful things on how to access files how to grab data from Google storage such as
your sheets et cetera.
Then you have recent notebook so just notebooks that you've already played around with.
This may be empty for you.
It is your first time using Google collab.
You can also access your Google drives if you've uploaded files such as our notebooks so we provide
for you in this course to Google Drive.
You'll be able to instantly access them from Google Drive.
There's also GitHub so you can check out Get hub your URLs.
There is no github link for this course.
Instead what we do is we provide every everything for you as a zip file so as a supplemental resource
for this lecture all you need to do is just go ahead and download that zip file and then you can unzip
it locally and then upload the notebooks they want to play around with or upload all the notebooks at
once using this upload functionality.
So all you need to do is just choose the files after you've unzipped it are really common mistakes.
I've seen students do as they download our zip file and then they forget to unzip it so they get errors
when they upload.
You should unzip the file and then upload notebooks or data or upload it to your google drive.
OK.
So what we'll do here is we'll go ahead and use a new Python 3 notebook so we'll click on this.
There's an auto welcome notebook there.
And you'll notice here that we have a new notebook and for you it should be kind of untitled 1 or untitled
2 depending on how many times you've run this.
You can essentially now run code inside these cells.
And while it looks slightly different than base Jupiter which is what I used to film this course in
a local installation it's essentially the exact same thing.
You can type in Python code and then do shift enter and then it will run it will first connect and initialize
the notebook and it will show you how much RAM and disk space you have on the back end.
And depending on your Google account it may be less disk space so I actually pay for an expanded Google
account through Google suite.
So I have a little more gigabyte space there.
So notice here it says print yellow and I get to see the output directly below.
And what's really nice here is essentially all the libraries we use in this course are already installed
here for us.
So I can do something like imports and then for example I can import seaborne as S.A..
That's a visualization library we use later on the course.
And you can see it's actually already installed for you.
So pretty much the most basic and common data science and machine learning packages they're already
installed on Google collab just universally.
And if you ever need to install something yourself you can just do.
Exclamation point tip install and then whatever library you need to install and it'll install it for
you.
So the exclamation point is what tells the Google cloud notebook to actually run this as if it was a
command line installation the last thing I want to note here is depending on when you're watching this
Google collab has actually not transitioned into tensor flow to officially yet.
So if you do import sensor flow again this may change for you if you're watching this in the future.
So let's go ahead and importance flow SDF do shift enter here.
Notice that currently the default version of tensor flow will soon switch to tense float too.
So you'll notice right now that if I say check the version of tensor flows that's TFR underscore underscore
version underscore underscore and to shift enter currently the default is actually still one point one
five.
But in this course we're focusing on the future which is tensor flow too.
So how do you make sure that Google collab is actually using tensor flow to.
Well if you're watching this in the future and you run importance flow it's tough and you don't see
this output then it's already transition to the tenth floor.
So that's totally fine.
And you can check by running this command right here which is t after underscore underscore version
underscore underscore however let's say they still haven't switched the tense floor to and you want
to make sure it's using it then all you need to do is say percent sine tensor flow version.
Go ahead and just hit internal autocomplete for you space and type two point X run that.
And what's going to happen is it may say tense flows already loaded.
Please restart the runtime to change versions.
So I'll go ahead and do that.
I'll say runtime restart runtime.
Notice I'm restarting the runtime.
I'll hit yes and then what I'm going to do is before I actually import tensor flow I'll run this command.
So I'm actually going to first run my prints hello.
So another type prints hello new so we can see that I'm actually doing this.
So again I have hello new and then before you importance flow go ahead and type out this percent sign
tensor will underscore version space two point X run that and now when you import tensor flow as TAF
you've selected a tense flow to which is what we use in this course.
And so you should be ready to go.
So this may take a little longer.
But now when I run TFT underscore underscore version underscore underscore I'm at the latest 2.0 version.
OK so that's just a quick note.
If you've seen this in the future to go collab online notebooks may have already transitioned to tensor
flow too.
So just keep that in mind.
Now the last thing I want to show you is how to make sure you're using GP you in case you desire that
for more complex models and the way you do that is you simply say edit notebook settings click on notebook
settings.
Notice right now the runtime that should be Python 3 is what we use in this course.
And there's the option for hardware acceleration and there's more information here that will take you
to this link on et cetera on all the hardware resources.
However all you need to do is select here for a GP for graphical processing in it and you also have
the option to try to access a tip used which are tense flow processing units.
So we have our GP you go ahead and hit save.
And now it will go ahead and connect and it will reinitiate lies and now use GP on the back end.
OK so now we're using GP you and we have tons flow and essentially everything's ready to go.
Now we're going to do is walk you through a local installation if you're satisfied of using Google collab
online then go ahead and just skip the rest of this installation lecture.
OK let's continue on if a local installation Welcome everyone.
Let's go ahead and get you set up if you're following along a local installation if you'd decided to
just keep the Google collab installation from before you can go ahead and skip the rest of this lecture
just make sure to download the zip file with their notebooks that is included as a supplemental resource
in this lecture and this lecture we're going to do is we'll start off by downloading that zip file.
Then also download and install Anaconda showed you how to create the environment activate the environment
install any required libraries with our simpler requirements that text file and then we'll show you
how open an example Jupiter notebook.
OK let's get started.
OK.
So our first step and the local installation as well as just getting the notebooks themselves is as
you're watching this course you should notice that in the course content there's a little resource tab
over here on the right that allows you to download both a zip file and a requirement that text file
go ahead and download those two and make sure you remember exactly where you saved both of these files.
We'll need to know their exact location on your computer later on in this course.
So I would recommend either just saving directly to your desktop or to download a folder somewhere where
you're 100 percent sure you know their location.
Keep in mind you Timmy from time to time changes how you download supplemental resources.
So if you don't see it exactly like this over on the right hand side.
Go ahead and check out their support page on downloading supplemental resources because this has been
known to change from time to time.
I would recommend that if you don't see it the way I've presented it here.
Go ahead and go to this whole port page and check out the downloading supplemental resources.
OK so we're done with step 1 which is the download that zip file and that that text file and know exactly
where they're located on your computer.
I won't be able to answer the question of where they're located on your computer for you.
Next step is to download Anaconda.
So to download Anaconda I've come to go dot com and go ahead and search for Python Anaconda.
And if you want go ahead and add download hit enter.
And essentially what it should take you to is either Anaconda dot com or Anaconda com distribution.
So click on that that takes you to Anaconda and summer on this page.
Keep in mind this page does change its style from time to time.
There should be a download button.
So even if you're on the home page there should be a download button somewhere here.
Go in and search the page for the download from it's over here on the top right.
That will take you to the distribution page which we're already at.
We'll go ahead and hit download here.
And essentially it's the same thing as scrolling down you'll see that there's instructions for the three
versions of Anaconda one for Windows one for Mac OS and then one for Linux where you're going to do
is choose the one that's correct for your operating system.
Keep in mind doesn't by default select your operating system.
So I'm on windows.
I'll make sure to select windows and then we recommend that you download Python 3.
In fact that's essentially required for this course free to operate with Python 3.
And go ahead and choose either the 64 bit installer or the 32 bit if you're running a relatively modern
computer which would most likely be 64 bit.
So go ahead and click on that and that will begin the download process.
The other thing I want to mention is if you continue to scroll down there's documentation for installation.
So if you want a written step by step installation guide for any of these operating systems either Mac
OS or Linux simply click clear on documentation installation guide.
Just click read more.
And that takes you to docs the anaconda dot com slash Anaconda click where it says installation and
then it has full step by step instructions for not just Windows here but also for Mac OS on the graphical
install and for Linux.
So if you're operating on any of these systems you have step by step installation instructions officially
up to date from Anaconda themselves.
So I highly recommend they check that out.
Again it's just docks that Anaconda dot com slash Anaconda slash install.
OK.
You'll notice that my executable file is done downloading.
I'll go ahead and open it up and it will look something like this.
So welcome to Anaconda three 20 19.
Go ahead and click next.
Go ahead and accept the license agreement click.
I agree.
And then depending on what permissions you have you can download and install either just for you or
for all users.
However all users requires admin privileges on your computer then click next.
Go ahead and select the location that you want to install it.
I just choose the default.
And then the last thing I want to note here is if you intend to run con the commands at your command
line like we do when we set up our environment go ahead and add Anaconda to your path.
I know it says not recommended but I highly recommend they actually do add the path environment because
it will allow you to do con the commands directly from your command line.
So even though it says not recommended.
Go ahead and just select add an icon into my path.
OK then go ahead and click install I've already installed Anaconda so I'll fast forward until this is
done installing.
OK.
We're actually almost done.
The last thing to do is to open up our command line prompt create the environment activate the environment
and then install the libraries.
So for the command line prompt after installing Anaconda you should be able to search your computer
for Anaconda prompt.
This is for all operating systems and then be able to use the command line there.
If you're on Windows you should also be able to just type in CMT and you'll see your built in command
prompt.
However I do recommend that you use the anaconda prompt for this.
I would also recommend that you restart your computer before following the next couple of steps that
we're gonna show here.
So restart your computer and then go ahead and open up the command line prompt.
If you can't find any kind of prompt or CND Marquis and Linux users do have the option of just searching
for a terminal and you'll be able to operate at your command line that way you have those three options
and then we're going to do is show you how to create the environment.
So what I will do is after restarting my computer I'm going to open up my anaconda prompt.
Let's get started.
All right so what we're going to do is we're going to search our computer for Anaconda prompt and if
you don't see a pop up go ahead and just open up your regular command line tools such as command prompt
or Mac OS and Linux users can open up terminal but we should see here an icon the prompt I'm going to
go ahead and open it.
All right.
Upon launching Anaconda prompt you actually may see a message complaining something about your environment
or saying something like environment not activated using base environment etc..
You can go ahead and ignore those messages since we're going to be creating our own environment the
way we're going to create environment is by saying Conda space create space dash n space and then you're
going to choose an environment name it should be an environment name that you can easily remember.
For example I'll call my environment my T F E envy for my tensor flow environment and then we'll say
space and what I need to do is install this environment with a specific version of Python because the
latest version of tensor flow does not actually support the latest version of Python yet so we'll say
space python is equal to three point seven.
Make sure you type this command exactly as shown otherwise you'll get an error.
Go ahead and hit enter and what an icon is going to do for us is it's going to create a virtual environment
upon creating this virtual environment.
It will ask you to install some new packages will go ahead and say Y for yes.
And it's going to install in this case Python three point seven and then it will install any necessary
packages to make sure that's all set up upon finishing creating the environment.
It'll give us the option to activate the environment.
We only need to create the environment one single time.
However for activity in the environment if we ever want to use the environment then we need to activate
it.
So we activate multiple times but we only need to create one time so I will say Conda activates my T
F E envy and depending on your operating system it may say source activate.
So just follow the instructions that are reports back to you here.
So anytime I want to use my environment I'll simply type contour activate my TAF EMV hit enter and you
should notice somewhere parentheses that is reporting back that now you're using this my tensor flow
environment.
The next step is to recall where you actually saved the zip file and requirements that text file to
in my case.
I'll go ahead and open them up.
I save them to my downloads folder.
So notice here I'm underneath my downloads folder and I also remember to unzip this t f course notebooks
so that now I have this folder called T of course notebooks and I also have requirements that text.
So make sure that you remember exactly where you saved the zip file and the requirements that text file
and also make sure to unzip the file something to keep in mind especially for Windows users is that
you often have duplicate downloads and duplicate desktop folders especially if you're a one drive user
so often your computer will have a desktop for your one drive and a desktop for your local.
So just keep that in mind and triple check that you're in the correct location.
So I'm underneath downloads which is directly underneath if I take a look at this P.C. I can actually
click on one of these ticket properties and they'll give me the full file path which is C users Mossad
and then go to downloads so I'm going to change directory one further into downloads so I can be in
the same directory as this notebook.
So let me close that I'll come back to my anaconda prompt and say See the and in my case I'll go to
downloads.
They should be able to tab autocomplete this.
OK so now I'm in my downloads.
The next step is to actually install the required libraries.
And there's two steps for this.
One is to make sure that we have the PIP installer available to us.
And I can do this by typing out Conda install Pip hit enter and this will make sure that we're using
a pip installer that's connected to this environment.
It may already be installed for us so it may say something like all requested packages already installed.
Once that's done then we simply type out the following command.
We will say pip install space Dash are space requirements not text file and if you're in the same location
as the top text file you should be able to tab autocomplete this then enter.
And what this is going to do for us is going to automatically download the packages from the requirements
text file if you actually open up and take a look at the requirements on text file.
It's actually it's a very simple text file that you can easily edit and make any changes to if necessary.
So I'm going to bring it over just to show you what it looks like.
So while this is installing I want to show you that the requirements that text file is just eight lines
where essentially has a library name and then it's required version.
So for instance if you're watching this in the future and you want to update to a feature version of
pandas all you need to do is edit this to whatever version of pandas you want maybe by the time you're
watching this version of pandas point thirty is out to you just say zero point thirty.
Now in my case that's not the change that's been set.
So I'll go ahead and not do that change.
So you can edit this requirements out text file however you deem necessary.
But the main thing to know is we're essentially just installing the visualisation libraries psychic
learn and then tensor flow to as well as our own copy of Jupiter which is our main programming environment
for this course.
Let's head back to the anaconda prompt now that it's almost done installing all right now that that's
done installing.
The only thing left to do is at your command line.
Go ahead and call Jupiter notebook and hit enter.
And what should happen is you'll see a little output saying Hey we're running the notebook at one of
these local your L's.
So if you want you could manually copy and paste these.
However be careful not to use control seat copy because control C actually stops the server.
We should have seen though is your notebook environment would have automatically opened up in your Downloads
folder and after that you're going to do is essentially let me bring it up for you locate here in your
browser your ti of course notebooks.
Go ahead and enter them and you should see the files themselves.
So everything's essentially organized and the order we filmed it in.
So it corresponds to sections of the course.
You click on one of these and I have access to all the notebooks and you can easily create new notebooks
by simply saying new and then select python and I should be able to type import tensor flow as TAF shift
enter.
You've imported TAF and then we can always check the version by saying TAF underscore underscore the
go ahead just tab autocomplete for version hit enter and it should report back to you tensor flight
too.
OK.
That's it for the setup.
Just keep in mind that anytime you want to use the environment you'll need to activate it at the command
line.
You don't need to create it you just need to activate it.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.