Welcome everyone to our first lecture on the deployment series.
So to begin to actually deploy something we need to actually create a model.
So let's head over to first a Jupiter notebook and then we'll create a model there.
Let's get started.
OK.
Here I am at a fresh notebook.
I essentially want to start the process of deployment from the very beginning.
So the first thing you need is a data set and I'm going to run import as an important Empire's MP and
import pandas PD to get started and to use a data set they're all familiar with.
What I'm going to do is reading the iris dataset So recall that the iris dataset is one of these kind
of world famous data sets that everybody always starts off with in machine learning and it has a variety
of features about flowers and then the class they belong to.
So this is a supervised learning problem where we have these four measurements or these four features
and then a species of flower.
And so what I want to do is let's imagine in the future I have a researcher out in the field who picks
a new flower and then takes the simple length and width and then the pedal length and with measurements.
Eventually what I want them to be able to do is to log into a Web site enter those measurements and
have a deep learning model produce a species prediction result.
So that's kind of our final goal here.
But in order to do all this when you start with historical data.
So what's always important when you're deploying your model is think about your dataset as well as what
the final product should look like or what question you're trying to answer.
In our case we're trying to create a model that will given four features of a flower predict what actual
species of Iris flower it is.
So first we need to do is separate this out into features versus target.
So that means my X should be Iris.
I don't need to drop that species column and when he did drop a column so we say access is equal to
1 and now x is just all those features and then what I need to do here is similarly for y I just need
to do the opposite which is just grab the species column.
Okay.
So I have my X and Y and as I mentioned before typically X is capitalized because it's a two dimensional
matrix and Y is lower case because it's just a one day vector what I want to do is I want to now make
sure in order to do multi class classification if we take a look at why the unique values here are three
classes which means in order to actually perform multi class classification with the way we're going
to design our model essentially one neuron per class output.
What I want to do is somehow either one hand code this or use some sort of a dummy variable to convert
my actual y values one way I can do this quite easily is psychic learn so there's lots of different
ways you can do this but secular does have one way we can say from Eskil or in the pre processing import
label binary either run that import and then say encoder is equal to an instance of this label binaries
or.
And essentially what we can do say Y is equal to encoder that fit transform on Y.
And then if I take a look at what y looks like now it's essentially one hot encoded so I have so Tosa
and then Virginia and then Versa color here and later on we'll talk about how you would actually know
the orders there.
It's just the same orders as they're shown in what unique the Tosa versus color and Virginia and this
kind of a more official way to do that which is actually off the encoder itself.
So we'll show how to do that later on but right now we've essentially one high encoded y as needed.
Now it's time to do a trade test split as well a scalar data.
Hopefully this all seems very familiar so we'll say from scalar in that model selection import train
test split and also say from S.K. learned that let's make sure we spell that right from S.K. learn that
pre processing import min max scalar go ahead and run that.
And now we say train to split and I like to do this little shift tab trick to make sure I don't have
to type out too much scroll all the way down until you see that example here and let's go ahead and
grab this guy OK so we have our extreme accessed why train and why test.
Next thing you need to do.
Let me zoom out so we can see the whole thing here.
We just say X and Y.
Let's go ahead and choose the test size of 20 percent.
So zero point two.
And then to make sure you get the exact same brand the split I do.
Go ahead and say random state is equal to 1 0 1 you run that.
And now you've created or train test split.
Next step is to do scaling so we'll say scalar is equal to an instance of this min max scalar we take
our scalar and we fit it only on the training set.
We don't want to assume prior knowledge of our test set run that and now let's create our scaled X train
which is scalar thought transform on X train and now let's create a scaled version of our x test sets
scalar the transform on X test and you only need to scale your feature data loops.
Make sure we say no there.
Run that.
Okay so we have our skilled features.
And recall we only fit the training set.
So later on we have to do is what we're gonna have to actually save this scalar object in order to use
it for new incoming data.
So keep that in mind after this next step is to actually create the model we'll say from tensor flow
that Kerry's top models import sequential and then from tensor flow that carries that layers import
dense.
Let's go ahead and create a very simple model we'll say model is equal to sequential and let's add a
dense layer of four units with an activation function of rectified linear unit.
And here the input shape it's just 4 features and we're actually not going to worry about batches or
anything so just the input shape is for comma we don't need to worry about the other dimensions since
we're not dealing with any to the images and we're also not feeding and things batches so finally after
this we'll say a model and go ahead and edit Dantzler here and this is will be our last layer which
means a number of units should match the number of classes we have.
Recall we have three classes so total of Virginia converse color.
So units is equal to three and then the activation function here because it's a multi class classification
algorithm.
We need this to be soft Max okay.
And then finally we will compile this model and we can do this with the atom optimizer again you have
flexibility overall optimize you want to choose but what loss you should be choosing is categorical
cross entropy.
Now let's go ahead and also keep track of the accuracy and our metrics.
So instead of just loss we'll say accuracy OK and make sure this is just compile without an s to make
sure we don't commit any typos there run that and you should have a model created for you after this
it's time to train the model so nothing you so far will say from terrorists or tense flow that carries
that callbacks we'll go ahead and import early stopping that we don't need to worry about choosing the
right number of epochs.
Go ahead say early stop is equal to early stopping and we are actually going to use most of these defaults
like what we're going to monitor.
Minimum delta et cetera.
Last thing I want to do is I'll have patients be a little larger than 0 so this is a very simple problem.
We're just going to say patients is equal to 10.
That way we can really see that curve flatten out for a bit and now it's time to fit our model will
same model fit you pass an X which in this case is our scaled X train and that's corresponding y is
y train then we'll go ahead and choose just a very large number of epochs since we have that early stopping
mechanism to stop in cases over fitting we'll see epoxy the three hundred and then let's say our validation
data is equal to scaled x test and Y test and then finally we'll go ahead and set our callbacks so callbacks
is equal to early stop that we created earlier.
We'll go ahead and run this and now we can see it's training.
Training shouldn't take that long especially if the early stop.
Let's go ahead and scroll down here.
You may notice that it actually may take close to all the three hundred epochs.
If it's getting better and better performance you should get pretty high accuracy here.
So let's go ahead and then see how it performed on our actual data.
Let's grab first those metrics will say metrics is equal to PD data frame and we can say model history
that history run that.
Take a look.
Your metrics here can see loss accuracy value loss and about accuracy.
Let's go ahead and plot first loss against validation loss run that plot.
Okay so we can see here that both loss and validation loss were continuing to go down.
In fact we could train for even further.
You can see that it was still headed down.
And let's go ahead and check out our accuracy metrics so we track metrics and compare accuracy versus
validation accuracy.
Go ahead and plot these out run that and it looks like in the beginning we were over fitting a little
bit suddenly got a lower performance on accuracy but eventually the model learns what to do.
And it looks like it flatlined for quite a bit from epochs like 100 or 200 but eventually start to learn
a couple of those kind of edge cases till it was getting around 80 percent accuracy.
So if you're running the models just like we did you should have achieved somewhere between 70 to 80
percent accuracy and the worry if your validation accuracy is a little bit lower than ours.
We're getting a pretty good fit on this model.
Okay.
So last thing you can also do as a model dot evaluate just look at that raw metrics data and we can
pass in our scaled x test why test and then say verbose is equal to zero and then it will give you back
the final loss as well as the final accuracy.
So in our case we're getting 80 percent accuracy on a test set of this model.
This is the point in time where you would have to decide if those performance metrics are good enough
for you if we decide that our model is ready for deployment if we decide that 80 percent accuracy is
doable then let's go ahead and ready our model for deployment.
So how do we ready our model for deployment.
Well when I deploy my model I want to make sure that I use all available data.
So for the purposes of training and evaluation I do my train test split when it comes to the real world
for that researcher out in the field who's going to pick that new flower.
I want to make sure that I'm providing the best model possible by using all the data.
So what I'm going to do is the following we'll say epochs is equal to length of metric.
So we'll go ahead just run the same number of epochs recall that was three hundred and then I'm going
to say scaled X is equal to scalar and if I wanted to I could then do a fit transform now on all my
data.
X so notice I'm no longer doing train test split.
I've decided already that this performance is good enough for me.
80 percent accuracy.
So that wasn't the test set that test set recall is data that the model was not trained on.
It's just evaluating it as it goes along now to provide the best model possible.
I'm retraining on all my data so it's kind of a phase two.
And so far in all our lectures we've kind of just been stopping on this evaluation phase when it comes
to deployment.
We want to retrain in everything so that's why I'm doing a fit and the transform on all my X data for
my scaled X so go ahead and run that.
And now let's go ahead and create a new model will say sequential.
In fact that is going to essentially copy paste what we did before.
So scroll up here can go ahead and copy and paste what is already there for us.
Scroll down and now we have our model.
Go ahead and redefine your model and then we're going to fit our model to our scaled X data our y data
and epochs is equal to the previous number of epochs we chose which was three hundred.
Go ahead and fit that model.
Okay.
So once that model is done fitting for those 300 epochs we're now ready to figure out how to save the
model.
So scroll down here we can see if we kind of scroll towards the very bottom how well the models performing.
So it looks like it's getting 96 percent accuracy.
However keep in mind that's the accuracy on all the data that it's being trained on.
So it's not a true fair comparison to say your model is now in ninety six percent accurate it's ninety
six percent accurate when it gets to see all the data train on data and evaluate itself on all that
data the true accuracy measurement that you should be using is this 80 percent accuracy which is a much
fairer evaluation of this model.
So keep that in mind so we'll come down here and then we're going to do is there's two things you need
to save.
We need to save our model.
Luckily we already know how to do that.
So go ahead and say a model save and I'm going to save this as final IRS model dot H5.
Keep in mind this is all the same file name that we save for you but it's OK if you want to rewrite
it and then the next thing to do is save the scalar itself.
New incoming data will have to be scaled in the same way that the model expects it to do this.
Go ahead an import job lib or job library.
This is actually built into Python so you're into download anything to run that and then say job live
that dump and then the way this works is you pass in essentially the object that you want to persist
as an arbitrary python object and then the file name.
Essentially the file path that it's going to go into.
So I want to save my scalar object and I will say this as Iris underscore scalar in the extension it
should be scale if its P K L stands for a pickle file.
Go ahead and run that and I'll basically report back the string name of where it was saved.
OK so I saved this dot H5 file for my model.
And if you end up using scaling for your model you need to say that scalar as well.
Now let's see what this would look like.
If I want to predict on a new single flower so we'll say from tensor flow doctors that models go ahead
and import load model is essentially just to check that everything is working and then I'm going to
create two new objects one is my flower model a new variable which loads up the final Iris model and
I'm also going to say flower scalar and I'm going to say job live the load and I'm going to load up
the iris scalar object as well and now what I should be able to do is based off this model predict something.
So what we're gonna see in essentially part two of this continuation is how to use this new loaded model
and this new loaded scalar object and create a function that takes in this model takes in the scalar
and takes in an example Jason which is what our API is going to be working with when we actually deploy
our model and return back a prediction for the actual classes.
All right so I'll see you in the continuation of our deployment lecture series coming up next.