Welcome back everyone to this lecture on supervised learning supervised learning algorithms are trained
using labeled examples.
And that's a keyword label such as an input where the desired output is known.
That means within your dataset you're going to have some historical features with historical labels.
So you already have that information such as a segment of text could have a category label.
So you take a bunch of previous e-mails and someone has already gone by and classified them using the
correct label.
So they read the e-mail and classified it as spam versus legitimate or we have a bunch of movie reviews
and someone has already gone and labeled movie reviews either positive to the movie or negative to the
movie and then the idea would be for future text information such as a future e-mail using the historical
label data the network or machine learning algorithm could learn off the historical data in order to
predict for new data whether it belongs in the spam category or legitimate category or in the positive
category or negative category for these movie reviews so the way this works is for neural networks the
networks and receive a set of input data along with the corresponding correct outputs and then the algorithm
or network will learn by comparing its actual output with correct outputs to find errors and then it
will modify the model accordingly such as adjusting the weights and biased values in the network and
the worry about those two key terms.
We'll discuss those and a lot more detail when we talk about neuro network theory so supervised learning
is used in applications where historical data predicts likely future events and the machine learning
process for supervised learning.
Looks like this.
So let's go in and go through this step by step so the first thing to do is actually get data and depends
on what domain you're working in where this data actually comes from.
This can come from your customers or can come from collecting things into a database online or maybe
it's physical data and it comes from sensors et cetera.
So at some point the data has to actually be acquired once we actually acquire the data then we need
to clean and format the data so that our neural network can actually process it and often we'll do this
using a library called PANDAS then we split the data into training data and test data and we'll talk
about this particular step in a little more detail towards the end of this lecture.
But what we do here is we take some portion of our data maybe like 30 percent to be test data and then
the larger majority of data like 70 percent to be our training data and what we're going to do here
is we're going to use that specific training set on our network or model in order to fit a model to
that training data then we want to know how well our model actually performed.
So we then run that test data through the model and compare the model's prediction to the actual correct
label that the test date ahead because remember we actually know the correct label for that test data
so you can run that test data features through the model get our models predictions and compare it to
the right answer and then we can evaluate the model and then maybe you want to go back based off that
performance and adjust the model parameters maybe add more layers or more neurons to try to get a better
fit onto that test data.
And once we're satisfied of this we can then deploy the model to the real world now something to note
here is what we just showed was technically a simplified approach to supervised learning and it does
contain a key issue which we kind of touched upon during that test train split and the question arises
Is it fair to use that single split of the data into one test set and one training set to actually evaluate
your model's performance.
So when you actually test your model on the test data you'll get some sort of performance metric for
regression tax.
It could be something like a root mean square error for a classification task.
It could be something like the accuracy but is it actually fair to use the accuracy you get off the
test data as your model's final performance metric.
Since technically after all you were given the chance to update the model parameters again and again
after evaluating your results on that test set.
So how do we fix this conundrum.
Well to fix this issue the data especially in neural networks and deep learning it's often split actually
into three sets and we have training data validation data and then test data.
So we kind of introduce this in-between step of this validation.
And so what we end up doing is we have these three sets and we have the training data just as we did
before.
And this is used to train them on a parameters.
So the model gets to look at the features look at the correct output and then fit to this training data
and then the next step is our validation data which was kind of our test data from before.
And so what we do this validation data is after training on the training data we check the performance
on the validation data and maybe based off that performance we go back and adjust our models.
Maybe adding more neurons or adding more layers changing the actual architecture of the network et cetera.
And then you kind of repeat that process over and over again until you're satisfied.
If your model's performance on the validation data and now it comes time to evaluate the true performance
of your model.
So what do we do.
Well that's why we have that third split of test data.
That the model has never seen before and what you use that final test data set is to actually get some
final performance metric.
Now the key thing to note here is that once you run the model through the test data that's gonna be
the performance metric that you expect your model to actually perform with in the real world.
Since you're not going to go back and adjust your models weights or parameters or anything else.
Once you actually go onto that final test dataset you're technically not allowed to go back and adjust
the model in order to try to refine your performance on that final test dataset so you can think of
it this way.
You train on the training data to actually fit your model.
Then you use the validation data to see how your model performs and unseen data and then go back and
adjust your hyper parameters.
But when it comes time to actually kind of report to your boss how well will this model do in the real
world.
That's where your final test dataset comes into play and the test data set.
Once you actually pass through test data and you get that performance metric that's it.
You don't really get to go back and adjust the hyper parameters.
Otherwise you're kind of cheating yourself again and understanding the models real performance on truly
unseen data.
So what this means is after we see that result on the final test set we don't get to go back and adjust
any of those model parameters.
This final measure is what we labeled the true performance of the model to be on unseen data now in
this course.
In general we're going to simplify our data by just doing that single train test split.
While technically we could be doing another split to get both validation and a test set for the kind
of problems and exercises we're doing in this course since we're not really deploying a lot of these
models to the real world it's not a huge deal that we essentially just have a training set and a test
set and we skip the sort of like in-between validation set so we will simply train and then evaluate
on a test set and we'll leave the option to the students to go back and adjust the hyper parameters
and then after going through this entire course you're going to be able to easily perform another split
to get three data sets.
If you desire so you'll be able to easily create a training set a test set and a validation set if that's
what you want but just want to tell you in this course we'll keep things simple and just train on a
training set and then evaluate on a test set and we won't really go back into just hyper parameters
will kind of treat that test as the final.
And again you can always go back and add in more neurons or more layers or more hyper parameters to
your network they'll be really easy to do and we'll kind of leave that up to you as a student to decide
if you want to continue with that.
Okay let's go ahead and move on to discuss things like overfishing.
I'll see you at the next lecture.