Welcome everyone to our first lecture in the solutions for these project exercise questions.
We'll begin with the exploratory data analysis section.
Let's get started.
OK here I am at the exercise notebook and I start off by running the first couple of starter code cells.
So that's importing the data that allows us to run our feature information function as well as loading
in the actual data set that we'll be working with.
So it looks like that's all loaded up.
Next let's begin exploratory data analysis.
So as I mentioned before it's always a good idea especially of classification problems to do account
plot to explore the actual balancing of your labels.
So we'll say S.A. count plot and we'll say lone status
and say data is equal to the F.
So that's how you can create a count plot here.
And I would say this is an unbalanced or imbalanced problem.
Notice that we have a lot more entries of people that fully pay off their loans than we have people
that did not pay back.
And this is really common for things like classification problems that have to do with fraud or spam.
There's a lot less instances of fraud or spam than there are of legitimate actions such as a legitimate
email or a legitimate credit card purchase or a legitimate loan where it was fully paid off.
So that's something to keep in mind.
And what that means is we can expect to probably do very well in terms of accuracy but our precision
and recall are going to be the true metrics that we'll have to evaluate our model based off of.
And we should expect to perform that well on those particular metrics due to the fact that we have a
very imbalanced dataset here.
So next we want to create a histogram of the loan amount column lots of different ways we can do this
by the easiest way is to simply call a distribution plot on that column so we can call the F loan amount
here.
And since I just want the actual histogram I'll say Katie e is equal to False and if you just run that
that basically gives you the basics of the histogram then you can begin playing around with things like
the bins.
So if you wanted more beans you can increase the number of beans there and you can also play around
with things like size so you can always say Pulte figure fig size is equal to some tuple.
So usually for his grams you want them long but a little shorter.
So you get something that looks like this.
OK.
So lots different ways you can do that but essentially something to notice here is you see these spikes
happening at these even money amounts which kind of make sense.
So clearly these bean spikes are happening at something like an even ten thousand dollar alone instead
of a spike at some random value like eight thousand three hundred and thirty three.
So that's what these little spikes are essentially indicating that there are certain amounts that are
basically standard loans.
OK so let's go ahead and explore the correlation between the continuous feature variables so we can
easily do this by simply just saying the F and then calculating the correlation as such.
So just the simple method call we've seen this already a bunch of times throughout our lectures.
We've also seen a little bit of how we can visualize it.
So what we can visualize it is by calling S.A. heat map on this particular correlation and we can also
say annotation is equal to true.
So we have those actual links for you in case you're interested in those and I will go ahead and change
the color mapping to be see map there this just because for me that's always a little clearer.
So if you run this just by itself you'll get this kind of really shrunk down heat map so something can
do.
First off is expand on the size say Pulte figure.
And this should always go before your seaborne command say fig size and let's make this quite a bit
larger.
Something like twelve by seven.
You run that and it will be a lot more improved.
But something to note here is that depending on your version of that plot lib you'll notice that the
bottom and the top are actually kind of cut off here and you can check out the links we provided for
you for help with resizing.
So specifically this second one will actually talk about that little error and that's due to Matt polyp
not playing well Seabourn.
So the way you can edit that is by messing around with the Y limits.
So there's lots of different solutions.
So one way we show this in the solutions notebook ourselves is after we do the Seabourn call simply
say t y limb and they say go from 10 to 0 or something like that.
And that will stretch out the actual heat map.
OK.
So that's our heat map we can see the various relationships between the features and obviously you would
get a perfect correlation along the diagonal so moving along here we're going to see is you should have
noticed almost perfect correlation with this installment feature.
So if we come back up here.
Notice that the loan amount has a zero point nine five correlation with this installment.
So that's quite interesting.
So let's explore this feature further we want to make sure that we're not accidentally leaking data
from our features into our label.
So we always make sure that there's not a single feature that is a perfect predictor of the label because
that basically indicates that it's not really a feature it's probably just some duplicate information
that's very similar to the label.
So let's go ahead and print that out.
We'll say feature information on that installment so we go ahead and run this and the installment is
the monthly payment owed by the bar.
If the loan Originates.
So keyword being if and then we also say feature info on the loan amount
and this is the listed amount of the loan applied for by the bar.
So it pretty much makes sense that the installments and the actual loan amount would be extremely correlated
because they're essentially correlated by some sort of internal formula that this company uses which
kind of makes sense if you loan someone out one million dollars you would expect that following some
formula your payments your monthly payment instalments are going to be quite high and you'll probably
use that same formula even if you loan someone a thousand dollars and then those payments will be likely
correlated to be much less.
So they're clearly using some sort of formula that is just a direct function of the loan amount to figure
out what the installment should be.
And we can always just do a scatter plot to confirm this.
We can say S.A. scatter plot and we can view this high correlation.
So we see X installment Y is equal to loan amount and then data is equal to the.
So we run that and we'll be able to see these actual scatter plots.
And you can do things like turn off the marker edge make Alpha a little lighter et cetera.
OK so next we want to create a box plot showing the relationship between the loan status and the loan
amount.
So going to answer the question is there a relationship between maybe really expensive loans and not
being able to pay them off or very low amount loans and then fully paying those off.
So what we do is we simply say get a box plot
on our loan status as the x axis and then the y axis will be our loan amount and our data still remains
that data frame so this allows us to explore the relationship and in general it looks like that pretty
similar charged off loans.
On average you can see this box plot is slightly higher meaning that if our loan amount is higher we
have a slight increase in the likelihood of it being charged off which again intuitively makes sense
that it's harder to pay back larger loans than it is.
Smaller loans so they're extremely similar here.
So this isn't a key indicator of whether or not someone's going to pay off their loan.
The actual amount they take off but there is a slight relationship there that we can see from this box
plot and we can do this by just calculating summary statistics for the loan amount grouped by the loan
status.
So I can say the following I'll say the F group by loan status and then if I just grouped by loan status
and then ask for describe it will show me this for all the columns.
So notice here there's kind of a really large data frame when really all I'm interested in in this particular
case this is what the questions asking for is the loan amount and this essentially shows us the quantitative
numbers behind this box plot.
So if you ever get a case like this that the box plot is a little hard to read you can always compare
the averages here.
So you can see the charged off average price is a little higher than the fully paid loan.
OK.
So again all this is indicating is the averages of the loans for people that aren't able to pay them
back are slightly higher than the averages for people that do pay off their loans.
That's what's in the care of the box plot.
And if it's a little hard to read you can always just manually check this out.
So that's what these tests are trying to get you to realize next.
Let's go ahead and explore the great and so great columns that lending club attributes to the loans
and then the first question is what are the unique possible grades and sub grades.
This should be pretty straightforward.
You can just simply grab the grade column and then ask for unique off of this and you should be able
to do the same thing for the sub great column simply say unique and we can see right away that these
sub grades basically contain the information of the actual grade itself because it contains the letter
grade and then some sort of sub character.
And if we ever wanted information on what it represents we can only say ft info and then pass on something
like sub grade.
And it will report back the lending club assigned loan sub grade.
Okay.
So we scroll down here and we want to create account plot per grade and set the hue to the loan status
label.
And this way we can see if there is differentiation between fully paying off your loan or having it
be charged off based off your grade so we'll say S.A. count plot we'll say X is equal to grain.
Data is our data frame and here the hue.
We'll go ahead and have it be our lone status
we run that.
And here we can see the kind of a clear relationship.
But what's a little hard to tell here is the ordering of the actual grades.
So notice that we're starting with B and then going a c e d e f g.
So it would be nice.
And what we're gonna do in the next problem our next task is actually show you or have you figure out
how to reorder these x axis ticks.
But essentially what this is showing is the percentage of charged off loans looks like it's increasing
as the letter grade gets higher.
So it looks like the best customers are given a grade of a second best given a grade of B C D s etc.
and we can do this by actually comparing the ratios here so let's take a further look at this.
Let's actually do it by sub grade.
So we may need to actually resize to try to get this plot but what I'm going to first do is get a count
plot of these sub grades to see this distribution throughout the entire dataset.
How many a ones do we have.
How many a twos do we have etc..
And we can see from the answer it looks like the majorities are a B's and C's which kind of makes sense
because these are clearly the riskier loans because they're more likely to be charged off.
Based off what we've seen here on the overall grades notice that the fully paid versus charged off rates
almost look the same for someone in the G grade category.
So how do we actually show this count plot per sub grade.
Well we simply say S.A. that count plot and then we'll say X is equal to sub grade.
Recall there's an underscore there and then our data is equal to def.
Now if you just run this plot you'll get something that looks like this.
So the first thing you should fix is the size of this plot.
So do that by saying Pulte figure fig size is equal to that's going to make this told by four.
Okay.
So that takes care of the sizing.
However what I want to be able to do is reorder that x axis.
So if you do a little bit of research on the count plot in seaborne essentially just go to the seaborne
API or tutorial page and then look up count plot say it'll be here in the categorical plots.
You'll notice that there's actually an order parameter which is just the list of strings so that's the
order you wanted in.
Let's go ahead and figure that out.
So we're going to do here is we'll say our sub grade order desired is equal to will come back up here
and use what we did before where we printed out the actual unique sub grades.
So we'll copy that and then we'll just sort them using basic Python so base Python has this sort of
function and essentially what we're doing here is we resize the plot and now we have this list of the
sub grade order which is this sorted call of the unique sub grades.
And then I'll pass that in as my order here so I'll go and say so.
Great order.
Run that.
And now you should see everything ordered.
The last thing to note here is something I disliked is the color seemed to be too similar.
Between a one or the eight groups and the G groups to then I just chose a palette that basically doesn't
allow for that.
And in my case after exploring the documentation on a map plot lib I like to call warm so it can hear
the essentially better grades are bluer and the worse grades are redder.
OK so here we can see that it essentially looks like F and G so grades don't get paid back that often.
So you want to isolate those and recreate the count plot just for those upgrades.
You also notice that appear.
It also asked you to maybe feel free to play around the hue.
So on this second plot we just had the lone status hue so we can kind of compare that as well so you
can always do that by just coming up here and saying Hugh is equal to lone status and then you get that
plot.
So lots of information here that we can deem just from the visualization.
And clearly these worst grade categories.
It looks like the charged off rate is almost the same as the fully paid rate so it might be worth investigating
if it's even worth giving people loans.
If we're gonna grade them a G or an F and what we're gonna do here is we're essentially going to kind
of zoom in on that little section of the plot and the way we're gonna do that is simply the exact same
code but we're going to do a quick filter first using panties.
So I'm going to essentially copy and paste this code come back down here
paste it here and what I'll do here is say I just want f and g so I'll say F and G is equal to my data
frame where my data frame grade is equal to g pipe operator or were the grade is equal to F and then
I'll wrap these guys in parentheses to make sure I don't get an error
and then the rest of these lines of code where we have d f I'll just replace that with F and G so we'll
grab our sub great order there and we'll set our data there.
Okay so all we're doing is essentially subset in the data frame and then doing the exact same plots
as above so if we run that now we can see the fully paid status versus charge off status for these essentially
worse sub grades.
You'll notice that if you're graded G5 the likelihood is almost the same as fully paying off your loan
versus being charged off on the loan okay.
We have one more plot to create in order to create it we have to complete first this task which is create
a new column called loan repaid which will contain a one at the loan status was fully paid and a zero.
If it was charged off so right now our label column is such that it's strings and I want to change that.
So essentially map to a 1 and 0.
So lots of different ways we can do this but one way is to simply say my lone status.
Go ahead and map the fully paid and I can just copy these.
You can grab this source of a unique call.
But go ahead and map fully paid to be one and then map charged off to be zero and then we wanted you
to set this as a new column and we'll set this as a new column called Lone underscore repaid and this
will actually be the label column that we use when working of tensor flow.
So go ahead and run that and then you should be able to then view both of them.
So let's go ahead and show that.
So we have loan repaid comma loan status.
Just see those two and we can see that it worked.
So loan repaid.
It's a one if it's got fully paid.
It's a zero.
If it was charged off.
So now that allows us to complete our last visualization which we've actually already done in previous
lectures.
So it's technically a challenge task but there's a helpful link in case you need help.
And what we wanted to do is essentially do this plot that shows which numeric features have the highest
correlation with the actual label.
And we did this in our classification tasks or in our classification lectures before.
But let's go ahead and show you again how to do it.
First it actually calculate those correlations.
Next step is to only grab that loan repaid column after that.
What you can do is a plot kind equals bar and that gives you the very basics of what this plot is doing.
However one thing to notice is loan repaid is going to be included and it's not sorted.
So what we can do here is before we call plot we'll go ahead and say sought those values saw underscore
values.
You plot that out and you get the sorted version here.
However it makes sense that loan repaid is perfectly correlated for loan replace repaid.
So we will go ahead and drop loan repaid and I don't need to specify axes because this is actually now
a series from the correlation data frame run that.
And now you will get back the exact same plot here so you can see that interest rate has essentially
the highest negative correlation with whether or not someone's going to repay their loan which kind
of makes sense.
Maybe if you have a extremely high interest rate you're going to find it harder to pay off that loan.
OK.
So that concludes this.
First section of the exercise where we just explore the data and perform visualizations.
I would highly encourage you to not just do the visualizations here in the notebook but play around
the data yourself and see if you can answer any questions that you have.
Based off your domain knowledge and based off what features are interesting to you.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture where we continue with Section 2 on data pre processing.
I'll see you there.