Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to show you how you can use python codes create order encoders for the purpose
of dimensionality reduction we can use an auto encoder for dimensionality reduction by separating out
the auto encoder into two parts the encoder and the decoder so here we have the full auto encoder recall
the auto encoder.
The main idea is that we have the same number inputs as we do outputs and then inside of the auto encoder
we do a dimensionality reduction and then expand that backup.
So we end up doing is we separate this out into two parts in encoder and decoder where the idea of the
encoder is to take something that's highly dimensional and then encode it into a lower dimensional space.
And basically the decoder job is to expand back out that low dimensionality in order to make sure that
that hidden layer in the middle of the auto encoder is actually learning correctly what features are
important because if it's not able to learn correctly what combination of features is important then
you're going to have a really poor output.
So that's the job of the decoder.
So what we do is we train this all together until the hidden layer becomes really good at extracting
useful information and then the decoder can expand that backup.
Once you've trained the full auto encoder then we just grab the encoder section and now we have something
that can successfully reduce dimensionality.
So we train them together that when we actually want to use it for dimensionality reduction we only
need to grab the encoder part.
So this encoder cannot successfully reduce dimensionality of the original data by taking combinations
of the original features.
Now you may be asking what use cases does this actually have dimensionally reduction has a wide variety
of use cases.
It can be used for things like compressing your data set visualizing data in lower dimensions and most
importantly revealing hidden relationships that are not clearly seen in higher dimensions when we're
dealing with feature data that goes beyond three dimensions then it becomes very difficult to actually
visualize this and understand the relationship especially if you're performing something like a classification
tasks it may be quite useful to understand just how separated are these classes.
And if you're able to visualize this either in 3D or to the you may be able to get an understanding
of just how separable these classes are.
So for example here we have an example of dimensionality reduction where we're starting from three dimensions
we can see here that these two clusters are highly separable and we're actually able to visualize three
dimensions.
We can imagine that this could have been a case where we have eleven dimensions and so there's no way
of actually visualizing the classes themselves or all the features at once.
So what we could do is reduce that dimensions into either to these space or one d space or 3d space
for operating from something much higher and then see if we're actually able to separate those classes
or not just to get some intuition of how separable these two groups are.
OK so it's actually cut out this exact problem set.
I'm going to hop over to a notebook and get started.
All right here I am at a notebook I've already imported no pie pan this seaboard in map plot lib and
I'm going to do one more import that we actually haven't seen before which is from S.K. learn thought
datasets import make underscore blobs which is a really useful function for just quickly creating a
dataset.
So we're going to be just creating a dataset so you can get an idea of how an auto encoder can be used
for reduced dimensionality and then later on in your exercise you'll work with a real dataset to actually
apply this.
So let's create a dataset with this make blobs function and we're gonna call make blobs.
And if you want explorer make blobs in more detail the ship type here and see the various functionality
that is available for it.
So we're going to do just walk you through the main parameters we're going to be passing in.
First we're going to decide the end samples which is essentially how many rows do you want in your dataset.
So this case will last for three hundred rows and then we'll say N features and this where you can decide
how many features you actually want.
So I'm just going to create that first two features for this dataset and then we can decide on centres.
So how many clusters they actually want in this case.
I want to.
So we can think of this as a kind of binary dataset belonging to one of two clusters.
And then finally we can say cluster underscore standard deviation essentially how much noise is there
for these clusters.
All set that to just one point zero.
And then to make sure you get the exact same data set that I do.
Go ahead.
Is that your random state.
2 1 0 1.
Because this sets you're going to make 300 samples part of two clusters with just two features.
We go ahead and run that and then we can separate out our data because if we take a look at this data
object it's a tuple of two arrays or the first item is these X features and then the second item is
your actual labels.
So we take a look at this by this tuple unpacking.
We have this X feature data and then if we took a look at why we have the actual corresponding labels
either into cluster zero or cluster one remember that in this case we're actually worrying about any
sort of classification.
Instead we're going to see how to reduce the number of dimensions here.
Let's say they only created a two dimensional dataset.
What are going to do is add a third feature that is just noise.
So we're gonna say and P go ahead and put this into yourself and P random seed and go ahead and set
your scene to 1 0 1 and in the exact same cell seek at the same noise I do create Z noise and say P
random normal and say the size is equal to the length of X and then say Z noise and convert that noise
array into a series.
So all I did here is with these three lines I now have this series which is just a bunch of random noise
for every single row from zero to ninety nine but I'm going to do next is create a data frame called
features by saying PD data frame on X.
So if I take a look at my features right now I have 0 and 1 which is the original features created by
make blobs.
These two features actually have some sort of correlation or effect to separating out all these data
points into their respective clusters.
What I'm going to do is say features is equal to PD and I'm going to concatenate my original features
with that noisy series and then I'll say concatenate this a lot.
Access is equal to 1 and let's go ahead and just relabeled those columns to be equal to some x1 x2 and
then x.
So it is actually look like I say feature head and I see X1 X2 and X3 and I can actually perform a scatter
plot here by saying party scatter and let's go ahead and scatter plot X1 versus features x2 recall these
are our original features.
So they should be informative.
So here I see the two clusters.
There's clear separation here and I can actually specify what to colour them by by saying c is equal
to y which means just colour them by the zeros and ones.
So clearly in my original data I have these very clearly separated clusters.
What I can do is I can actually visualize this in three dimensions but again visualizing the extra noise
we added in as our third made up feature so we can say from NPL underscore toolkits that M plot 3D the
import axes 3 d.
Okay.
So we have NPL toolkits and plot 3D import axis 3D.
And then I'm going to create a three dimensional figure by saying figures equal to peel figure and I'm
actually then going to say axes physical to fit add underscore subplot and you can check out our auto
encoder notebook.
So if you actually go to the auto encoders notebook that this lecture is based upon you scroll down
here.
I blinked for you the actual information from the online documentation to don't think that I have this
scatter plot memorized.
Instead I just went ahead and referenced that link.
So keep that in mind.
That's how I know this code.
We're gonna say add some plot one 1 one and then most importantly we say projection is 3D and then I'm
going to call a scatter plot here X that scatter and will say scatter feature x 1 against feature x
2 against feature x 3 and then we'll go ahead and color that by the correct labels again.
So I run that and I see this nice three dimensional scatter.
Now what's really cool is if you're operating in the latest version of Jupiter you should be able to
say percent sine map plot lib space notebook run that cell and then rerun the plotting and you should
see that this is now an interactive plot that you can explore.
So notice here along this third dimension that we created here this kind of noisy one along the z axis
that is actually just straight noise.
Well we originally saw was the scatter that looked like this so if we looked at it straight on top.
Notice that we have these type clusters.
But this third dimension is kind of adding a lot of noise that actually does not separate out versus
yellow.
There's no separation between purple versus yellow.
In this third dimension of noise that we created there's clear separation of purple vs. Yellow.
Along these two original features.
So what we're going to explore is if we can create an auto encoder that can essentially try to filter
out which features are important and which are not.
And we would assume that it'll take information from X1 and X2 and it won't take information from x3
since x3 really does nothing to tell us about these two blobs since it's just noise.
Okay.
So if you want to kind of turn off this plot you can just come up here and then click this little off
button.
I'm Zune dense you can't see the whole thing but here we have now those two clusters X1 and X2 informative
features x3 essentially just noise.
It shouldn't be very informative especially for informing you on how separable these classes are.
So now let's explore creating an encoder and decoder going to come back down here and we'll say from
tensor flow not curious thought models import sequential.
And then from tensor flow thought curve stop layers import dense.
And then lastly when I want to show here is we're actually going to import stochastic gradient descent
as our optimizer and when we can do that the same from tensor flow that carries the optimizes import
s g d and what's nice about stochastic gradient descent is you can play a lot with the learning rate
of the stochastic gradient descent to try to help out your auto encoder.
Now in our particular case there's a very simple dataset so affecting the learning rate shouldn't really
make much of a difference but it's quite common in auto encoders to use something like stochastic gradient
descent and then play around with that learning rate and make it a little slower.
If you notice that hidden layer is having trouble understanding what features are important.
So how do we actually do this or we're gonna do is we're going to create an auto encoder that starts
off with the three inputs reduces it down to two neurons in the hidden layer and then expands it back
out to three neurons.
So we want to make sure that the input 3 matches the output and we're going to do this in two steps.
We'll first create an encoder and we defined this as its own separate model by saying coder is equal
to sequential and saying encoder ad and we add in a dense layer and we'll say units is equal to to specify
the activation function to be rectified linear unit and most importantly when you specify that are input
shape is equal to the original input shape which was 3.
So we're going from 3 as our input down to 2 dense units.
So that's our encoder and then we need to match a decoder to it.
So the decoder is going to be equal to again its own sequential model and then we'll say decoders equal
to excuse me decoder add panel will add dense layers.
And in this case the decoder ends with three units go ahead and use the same activation function rectified
linear unit but it's input shape is coming from the output of this encoder.
So we're going from 3 to 2 and then the input shape is going to be equal to that 2 and then it's going
to come out as three.
So that's what's happening here between the encoder and the decoder.
We start off with three features go down to two and then from that to as the input for the decoder we
expand back out to three.
So very simple auto encoder here to define the actual auto encoder will say it's simply a sequential
model and this is what's really nice about the care syntax is we just passed a list of encoder and decoder
and we've essentially combined them together.
So we're gonna do is we'll train the auto encoder together that way we can have the encoder learn the
best way to reduce from 3 to 2 in order to reproduce on the decoder side a similar output and then once
the auto encoder has learned this will separate out the encoder section of it in order to just go from
three to two.
So the last we need to do is compile our auto encoder so we'll say auto encoder compile and we'll go
ahead and say a loss is mean square error.
Since these are all continuous values and here's we can play around the atomizer if you really want
to you could just pass in the string code.
Adam but typically what's really nice is to play around a stochastic gradient descent and then play
around your learning rates.
So people just pass on one point five okay.
So we have our auto encoder completely setup last we need to do is actually scale our dataset.
We'll save from that scalar and pre processing just as we've done before import min max scalar.
And notice what I'm going to do here is since there's technically no right answer as far as how you
should reduce this dimensionality I'm just going to fit and transform on my entire dataset because I
don't really have a right answer to compare this to soc I have a correct version of this dataset in
two dimensions.
So we'll go out and say min max scalar and then say our scale data is equal to scalar.
And here I'll just call it transform on my entire feature dataset.
So this is what's making this so far different from the supervisory process because there was no trained
test split here because it doesn't really make sense for doing something where we don't actually know
the correct answer we're going from three dimensions onto two dimensions.
OK.
Finally let's go ahead and take our auto encoder and we're gonna fit this and we're gonna take our scale
data and then pass our scale data as well as both X and Y.
Here really.
And then we'll go and train us for five epochs this should be pretty fast because it's a very simple
dataset.
OK.
There we go just kind of a few microseconds per epoch and then we're gonna do is we'll say the encoded
2 dimensional version is equal to.
And notice here I'm just going to grab the encoder not the full auto encoder.
So just the encoder section which goes from three to two and I'll ask it to predict based off my scaled
data run that and now if we check out encoded two dimensional run this nation notice some behavior that
looks something like this.
So if we check out the shape of this it's taken from three hundred to three so if we take a look at
the original scaled data shape it's three hundred rows by three features and we have successfully reduced
that down to just two dimensions.
So let's see what that actually looks like.
I'm going to call peal t scatter and we'll call encoded two dimensions and say grab all the rows from
the first column and plot them against encoded two dimensions all the rows in the second column.
We go ahead and run that and you should see something that maybe looks something like this.
It may not be so noisy here you may actually just see two straight lines.
But note that we have this little group cluster and then kind of these points up above here.
Now the question is how well did this actually do at separating out the classes that we know to be the
underlying truth.
Well what I can do is turn this off here and say c is equal to y then actually color these run that
and you notice that it was able to separate this out and it got some of the noise here but it reduced
it back down to two dimensions where all the L points are down here and all the purple points are up
here.
So why would this be useful in a real world situation.
Well in a real world situation you dealing with high dimensional data so it may not just be three features
that it may be something like eleven features something that's just impossible to visualize as we did
before.
So appear when we actually visualize the two three dimensional clusters that we did appear we are pretty
lucky we can actually visualize this and there's no real need for dimensionality reduction what the
purpose of this which is to show you that we're going from 3 down to 2 that in a real world situation
you're going to be dealing with an extremely high dimensional data set something that's four or five
six ten et cetera something that's just impossible to visualize.
So what you would then do is train your auto encoder to go from something like 10 dimensions down to
three dimensions and then you'd be able to plot this out in a three dimensional space and you can imagine
if you plot it out in a three dimensional space and saw a clear separation by class because maybe you
just wanted to explore the data and see how intermingled these classes were and just general sense and
you saw that there was clear separation then you would know that these two classes are very distinct.
If after reducing it down to three dimensions or two dimensions there was a lot of crossover between
these two classes or multiple classes then you would know which classes are really similar to each other
and which classes are very separable from each other.
So this is just to reveal hidden insights visually that you wouldn't be able to see before and your
exercise is really going to focus on that and your exercise will give you a real dataset that has 17
dimensions and will be your job to actually reduce it down to either three dimensions or two dimensions
and see what components or what categories are highly separable from the other ones.
OK.
So all we did here is we created an auto encoder by separately creating our encoder first and then our
decoder.
Coming up next we're going to analyze how we can perform this same process but on even higher dimensional
data such as image data.
Recall a 28 by 28 image is going to have seven hundred eighty four feature points or seven hundred eighty
four pixels or dimensions.
So you're going to reduce that down.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the CUNY forums.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.