Welcome back everyone.
Now that we understand how image kernels and filters work.
Let's go ahead and see how they play a role in the convolution layer portion of a conversational neural
network.
Recall that running an artificial neural network that was just a fully connected feed forward neural
network for the endless dataset actually resulted in a network with relatively good accuracy.
However there are some issues with always using an end models for image data.
So if we were to always use artificial neural networks just normal fully connected networks for image
data we would end up with a huge amount of parameters.
Recall that when we actually checked the parameter count for our network on the end this dataset we
had over 100000 parameters.
And that was for tiny 28 by 20 images 28 by 28 pixel images are really small compared to your images
that you're used to a normal life.
For example you know that your resolution on just a normal monitor screen is probably like 10 ADP that's
10 80 pixels or 1080 pixels.
That's a lot larger than 28 by 28.
So if we try to scale an artificial neural network to just normal sized images you're going to end up
with not just 100000 parameters but a million parameters as a training time is going to take forever.
The other problem with an artificial neural network is recall that we had to flatten out the data before
actually feeding it into the network.
And if we flatten out the data we basically lose all two dimensional information.
And the other issue is an an and will actually only perform well where images are extremely similar.
And if you take a closer look at the end this dataset you'll notice that essentially all the numbers
are centered in the image.
We want our convolution on neural networks or just our networks in general to be able to recognize a
number regardless of where it is in the image.
In artificial neural network will actually not be able to do that.
If you were to take a 20 by 20 image of a handwritten digit but the digit was not centered maybe it
was starting all the way on the right and feed it into the artificial neural network we trained you
would actually not get good results.
And it's most likely that the network would not be able to understand what it was actually looking at.
So the M.A. data dataset is really special because all the numbers are perfectly centered in these really
small Twenty by 20 images and that's why the artificial neural network was actually able to perform
so well there.
But later on we'll see that this network won't generalize well to just normal sized images especially
when what we're looking for could be anywhere in the image.
So we have a lot of restrictions for the artificial neural network.
Now a CNN or convolution on your own network can use what's known as a convolution layer to help alleviate
a lot of these issues a convolution of layers created when we apply multiple image filters to the input
images the layer will then be trying to figure out the best filter weight values a CNN also helps reduce
parameters by focusing on local connectivity and we'll actually see an example of this localized connections.
So in a convolution on your own network specifically in this compositional air not all neurons will
be fully connected.
Instead neurons are only connected to a subset of local neurons in the next layer.
And these actually end up becoming the filters so let's understand this local connectivity and its connection
to filters by beginning with a very simplified one dimensional example and then later on we'll expand
this to two dimensional inputs for a grayscale image and then later on to a three dimensional tensor
input for a color image so here we have just a normal artificial neural network we see here on the left
hand side we have some sort of input and then it's fully connected to all the neurons in the next layer
and then that would continue on throughout the network so because this is fully connected.
There are lots parameters which we've already decided is gonna be a problem for really large images
or even just normal sized images because of training time to figure out all those parameters.
So how do we reduce these number of parameters well a conversational layer what it does is it focuses
on local connections.
Notice now that the neurons are only connected to a local neuron in the next layer they're not connected
to every other single neuron.
So here we have these localized connections and this is just being shown on one dimension.
Later on we'll expand this to two dimensions where we can see here that we actually have one filter.
So what's gonna happen is because of this essentially a all layer with a localized connection these
localized connections end up creating this filter and the network itself is going to figure out where
are the best weights for this filter and so what we could do is then maybe add another filter and as
you're training your compositional neural network you actually get to decide how many filters you want
to apply to this image and essentially have the network learn the best weights for the filter.
So previously we saw that really common filters such as a blur filter or an edge filter those weights
are already known.
But if you're working with maybe facial recognition data and you're trying to figure out well what filter
values are going to be really good at recognizing eyebrows you yourself are probably not going be able
to figure out those numbers but the convolution neural network will somewhere along the line probably
be able to figure out some filter which is good at recognizing some component of that face.
Keep in mind it's going to be difficult to actually open up so to speak the neural network and decide
what each filter is actually looking at on those face images.
But it's likely that the filters will begin to recognize higher and higher patterns related to a face
like eyebrows noses ears mouths et cetera and we'll talk about interpreting the filters of a network
and visualizing that later on in the course.
But here we can get an idea that through these localized connections in this compositional neural network
we can then have kind of a stack that no filters so that was a simple one dimensional example of convolution
but recall these grayscale images.
Those are two dimensional.
And we mentioned that we wanted to preserve the two dimensional relational information in the convolution
all layer and this is where our knowledge of those image filters or image kernels comes into play.
So let's expand this down to two dimensions.
And it's actually quite simple.
Here we have an input image.
It's a really simple image.
It's just three by four pixels.
And recall that since this is a grayscale image essentially each value falls somewhere between 0 and
1 or the pending how it's normalized between negative 1 and 1 or 0 and 255 is another really common
pixel value.
But the main idea here is these are pixels and they're technically just numbers or a matrix or feeding
in here.
So here's our input image kind of just this really really simple Y shape we're showing here with darker
zeros and lighter ones than what we're gonna do with this input image is recall that we have this filter
that we can essentially scan across the image and other things to remember is that if we wanted to we
could pad the image and we can also choose a stride length.
So we're going to do is here in two dimensions we're going to focus on localized connections using this
filter process and recall again that we can edit our stride size.
And so eventually what we end up doing here is we get these localized connections from these input images
or input features of these pixel values and connect them to only certain subsets of neurons in this
next layer.
And you'll notice that essentially what we're creating here is a filter and then it's it's up to the
network to figure out what weights that should be applied to this filter during training to correctly
classify the images.
And if you want you can always do this with another set of filters.
You can add on as many filters as you want here.
So you do the same scanning process again and again.
And here we have three filters on this input image but it's not uncommon to see a tens or hundreds of
filters depending on the complexity of what you're actually trying to classify as well as how many different
types of objects you're trying to classify so if we were kind to stack these filters together that's
what begins creating our conversational air.
It's essentially this stack of filters for the convolution all network to figure out the proper weights
in each of these filters only has localized connections because we understand how the image kernel is
involved across that image.
Now keep in mind that was an example for technically just a grayscale image.
But what about color images color images can be thought as three dimensional is consisting of red green
and blue color channels additive color mixing allows us to represent a wide variety of colors by simply
combining different amounts of red green and blue.
So you've probably already heard of RG G.B. color coding red green blue color coding and the idea behind
that is through some combination of red green and blue you can create any version of any color.
Now keep in mind there are limits to this are RG B can't produce every single color available but it
does produce a wide variety of colors that we can see on a human scale.
So you're not going to see things like ultraviolet or infrared but arguably does allow you to create
what's known here as this range of colors now.
Each color channel will have intensity values and you've probably already seen this.
If you've ever worked with representation of color pixels and other software of RG B sliders.
So here we have our sliders and essentially we choose some value between 0 and 255 or red green and
blue and you essentially mix them together as if there are paints and you get some sort of color out.
The main idea being is that these colors can essentially be represented as a mix between red green and
blue.
So what does that mean for our actual images.
So here we can see an example of breaking down a full color image into its color channels.
So for a single color image we have these actual three dimensions.
We have the height in the with something we're already familiar with.
But then for every single color channel that is one for red one for green and one for blue we're actually
going to have a separate array of pixels so this means when you actually read in an image and chicken
shape it's going to look something like this.
You'll have maybe twelve eighty by 720 by three.
So that means that the single image has told 80 pixel with 720 pixel height and then three color channels.
And keep in mind that each of these color channels is essentially if you were just to grab one of them
it looks like a grayscale image.
That's just values between zero and one or zero to fifty five or negative one and one they just represent
the intensity for that particular color.
So we can see here the intensity for red green and blue.
And then when you combine those intensities as we previously discussed here you end up creating mixes
of colors which produces this color image.
So again we think of this as the height the width and then three color channels.
And recall this is just for a single image.
So now a single image is actually this three dimensional tensor.
You should also keep in mind that the computer will actually know if a channel is red.
It just knows that there are now three Intensity channels.
So you should also keep that in mind in case your images happen to have different color encoding certain
programs will actually encode instead of red green blue.
They'll encode it as blue green red.
That won't really matter that much for our use case of the convolution on you're on networks because
the network doesn't really care what order the colors are being fed in.
It just cares that there's three Intensity channels.
Now the question arises.
We just saw how to perform a convolution on a one dimensional array that we saw had a performance on
a two dimensional array.
How do we perform a convolution on this color image since it's a three dimensional tensor.
So we actually end up with is a three dimensional filter with values for each color channel so essentially
this filter now has three dimensions to it.
We have the actual height and width of that filter shown as three by three.
But then we have an instance for each dimension for the color channels.
So there's one for the red one for the green and one for the blue and just as before we can have as
many filters as we want.
So we can create another filter.
And again this filter is three dimensional.
It has one little image kernel per color channel.
So one for red one for green on blue for blue.
And we can keep adding on these filters.
So we should now be thinking of these filters for these colored images as three dimensional.
And later on the course will actually expand from grayscale images and we'll move on to color images
so we can get an idea of working with this extra dimension of data now often come volitional layers
are fed into another compositional layer.
So it's not uncommon to see it come volitional layer being directly stacked and fed into another compositional
error and then stack them fed into another compositional layer.
And what's really cool about this is this allows a network to discover patterns within patterns usually
with more complexity for later compositional layers.
Now we've learned a lot so far and we have one final theory topic to cover before coding our own accomplish
on your own networks.
And that is the pooling layer also known as the down sampling or sub sampling layer.
Once you understand how the pulling layer works along with the compositional error then we have all
the pieces we need to actually create our own compositional neural network and then we'll revisit that
in this dataset problem.
So in the next lecture let's go in and discuss pulling layers.
I'll see you there.