Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to talk about indexing and selection in number pi specifically.
We'll first talk about grabbing a single element then expand this to grabbing a slice of elements.
Then we'll talk about broadcasting those selections indexing and selection in two dimensions.
And we'll talk about a very important topic called conditional selection which we will also see a lot
in pandas and dealing with data and data cleaning in general.
Let's head back to the notebook and get started.
All right.
In my notebook I've already gone ahead and imported some pie as MP next well I'm going to do is just
create a simple array by saying NDP arrange from zero to eleven for default step size of one.
So I have numbers 0 3 10.
Now let's imagine I wanted to just select a single value to do this.
I simply passed in the index just as I would select a single value from a normal Python list.
So if I just say 8 or grabs whatever is at index 8.
So there we have the value 8.
Let's imagine I wanted to get values in a range.
I can do that the exact same way I can do this with a normal Python list with a starting position a
colon and then an ending position which will go up to but not including.
So for example if I say 1 colon 5 it goes up to but not including 5 starting at 1.
So I got the numbers 1 2 3 4 if I want to start at the very beginning.
I can either say go from 0 up to not including five or I can admit that zero and say colon five which
will basically say start at the beginning and then go up to five.
So these two cells are essentially the same thing.
It's up to you whether or not you want to include that zero.
Similarly to go all the way to the end that is from a starting position.
You can say starting at index five colon and it will go all the way to the end.
This is nice because that way you don't need to actually know how long your array is to index all the
way to the end.
Now let's quickly discuss broadcasting empire raise differ from normal Python lists because of this
ability to broadcast with lists.
In normal Python you can only reassign parts of a list with new parts of the same shape and size and
then you would also need then possibly reassign this to a new variable.
However none Pi you can actually broadcast a single value across a larger set of values.
Let me show you what I mean by that.
Let's take a look at our original array.
The numbers 0 through 10 and then we're going to say here is grab all the numbers from 0 to 5 and set
that equal to 100.
You would not be able to do this with a normal Python list.
If you take a look at our array notice now it's been changed.
The values in the sections from 35 have this broadcasting reassignment.
So one hundred is been broadcasted across these values.
Let's go ahead and reset this by saying NPR range 0 to eleven.
The next thing I want to point out is actually slicing a section of an array and setting it to a new
variable will actually only act as a pointer to the original array.
So I'm going to say slice of array is equal to my array from 0 to 5.
So if I check out that slice of the array then I get 0 1 2 3 4 and if I take a look at my original array
it's been reset so that it's 0 through 10.
Now let's imagine I grab this slice of the array and I say just the colon to select everything and I
set that equal to ninety nine so now if I take a look at this slice of my array everything has been
set to ninety nine because I just set a colon here which basically means from beginning all the way
to the end.
Now what you think is going to happen with my original array.
Well if none pie that slice of the array was actually when you assigned it here as a rate 0 through
5 you're basically just pointing it to the original array which means this broadcasting operation has
actually affected the original array.
If you wanted to not have it affect the original array you would need to explicitly set a copy.
So you have to do something like this array copy is equal to whatever original array and then you call
the copy method off the original array.
And that way you can do any sorts of changes you want to this array copy such as grabbing everything
and setting the equal to 100 and if you take a look at my array copy that is now all one hundreds but
my original array hasn't been changed because of specifying that copy.
OK so we've talked about indexing and selection across just a one dimensional vector here.
We also talked about broadcasting next what I want to talk about quickly is indexing on to the arrays
or matrices and then we'll talk about conditional selection which is a very important topic to begin.
Let's go ahead and create a two dimensional array will say array 2 D is equal to N.P. array and here
what I'm going to do is simply kind of cast as quickly as the list by saying 5 10 15 as the first item
in this list.
Then we'll create another one twenty twenty five thirty and then finally thirty five forty and forty
five.
So no here what I essentially have here is a list of three lists and transform that into an umpire if
Perry and I'll be my two dimensional array.
So now if I take a look at array to the I have this.
So let's imagine that we actually wanted to just grab a single row.
Well indexing is basically going to work the exact same way in 2D except now you have a dimension for
the rows and a dimension for the columns.
The first one is the rows.
So if I say array to the DOT shape this returns back the number of rows first and then the number of
columns.
So index 0 we have number of rows the index one we have number of columns.
That distinction is going to be important later on when we cover pandas.
So let's imagine I wanted to just grab from array to the a single row then I can pass in an index.
So for example 0 and I'll return back that very first row at index 0.
If I wanted to grab the last row.
Well for example that's an index too because we're starting at 0.
So that returns thirty five forty forty five.
Now let's imagine I want to grab a single element value from somewhere in one of these rows.
Well notice now I had this array so I can index off that rule.
So let's imagine I want to twenty five.
Well that's a row one and then I could either index off of it with two bracket notation to then also
say one to get twenty five or what's more common is to just put this in the same set of brackets separated
by a comma.
So one one says at row one column one.
So let's go ahead and pick another number just to make sure we understand like 15 that's in row 0 at
column 2.
We run that and then we get back 15.
Now we can also do the same thing except expand this to slicing.
For example let's say we wanted a slice of this little square of 10 15 along with 25 30.
The way we could do that is simply by thinking of what rows we wanted first.
So I want rows 0 1 up to but not including at index 2.
So I can say for my rows go ahead and give me colon to which if we think about this returns back rows
0 and 1.
So up to not including two.
Now let's imagine I only wanted 10 and 15 25 and 30 from that I could then say comma and say something
like starting at column one or column index one which is ten twenty five.
Go ahead and colon go all the way to the end.
And we can see how we could grab that little subsection of our matrix not to worry too much if you get
confused by this sort of double notation we really won't see this that often with real data sets we
feel data sets the rows stand for data points and the columns typically stand for features so it's unlikely
we need to do some sort of double subset typically we're either subsidising just on rows or on columns.
It's quite unusual to do something like this but you should be aware of that sort of notation in case
it does come up.
Finally the much more common type of selection we'll be doing is called conditional selection for this.
We'll go ahead and show you an example we'll say NPR range one to eleven.
And here's my array.
One two three all the way to 10.
Now what I can do is I can actually broadcast a condition or a comparison off of this so I can ask for
where's my array greater than the number four.
So I run that and this returns back a numb pie array of boolean values where the index location matches
up with the original data to those that says false false false false and then once it gets to five it's
only becomes true true true.
So what I could do is showing you this in multiple steps.
I could say my boolean array is equal to array greater than 4 run that now I have this boolean array
and I could use this to filter so I could pass that in to my original array run that and now it will
only return back the index locations of this boolean array which happens to be true which is 5 6 7 8
9 10.
Since these are all greater than 4 So again the steps here I did was have some sort of original array.
Do a comparison operator which gives you back this boolean array which you can then use to filter out
your original array.
Now I separated this out into multiple steps but theoretically we can actually have to do this reassignment.
So typically what we see is this sort of notation.
We take our array and then we ask for some sort of comparison such as Array greater than 4.
Run that and then we see here 5 6 7 8 9 10.
So this is the sort of thing we're gonna be seeing quite often especially when we move on to pandas
and pandas will later learn we'll give us the ability to then do something like multiple comparisons.
So for right now we just need to understand this basic idea that it can perform a comparison within
my array and then pass that as my conditional selection filter.
Later on we'll discover more complex ways in order to do this for even more functionality.
But for right now we've discovered how we can actually index and select off one dimensional arrays.
We've talked about broadcasting and we talked about indexing and selection on two dimensional rays.
And finally this important topic of conditional selection.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.