Welcome back everyone to this lecture on Seabourn seaborne is a visualization library built using map
plot lib that focuses on creating standard statistical plots with a simple one line function call in
a works especially well with the panel's data frame.
This comes at the cost of less customization options than pure map plot lib.
So keep in mind you're not going to be able to customize every seaborne plot exactly how you see fit
through straight seaborne parameter calls.
Sometimes you'll have to reach in to map pup lib to actually work with the plot for further customizations
so as I mentioned you can still affect plot attributes created and Seabourn by adding pure matte plot
lib the pipe plot calls for more information on the full depth of the seaborne library you can visit
the official online documentation at seaborne the PI data the org.
For now let's head over to a Jupiter notebook and show the very basics of how to create the school plots
with the seaborne library.
Let's jump to a notebook now.
OK here we are at this Jupiter notebook to begin working with Seabourn.
What we first need is a data set.
So if you actually look under the visualization Crash Course folder and then open up Seabourn basics.
The notebook that corresponds of this lecture.
We have a full rundown on the data we're going to be using.
And we're actually going to be using a medical data set that has a bunch of information about patients
and then whether or not they had the presence of heart disease.
So we can see here we have their age years their sex male or female chest pain type cholesterol levels
et cetera.
So if you want information on what all these columns represent the information is right here for you.
But keep in mind this data is located under our overall data folder.
You're gonna make sure to read that incorrectly and then you should be able to read in that data frame.
Pay careful close attention to your actual full file path when reading it in.
So I'm going to say my data frame is equal to PD read CSB and I'm going to since I'm located in the
exact same location as the actual Seabourn basics notebook have to go out one generation to data and
this file's called Heart that CSP to begin working to see more than we import seaborne as S and S So
let's discuss just a few of the basic plot types.
There's a distribution plot which is essentially a histogram.
And if we call S.A. that this plot we can call it on a single column and it will show you the distribution
of the data.
So if I say DFA age this will show me the actual distribution of the overall H data.
It has both a kernel density estimation which is this line essentially estimating what a probability
function would look like for this data and then it has a histogram if you want to turn off this case
the E line where you can do is say Katie is equal to False run that and then here we see our actual
essentially histogram and histogram is essentially just a count per bin.
So I can see here that have these what look like columns.
Well each of these is actually a bin and the y axis is defined by how many counts fall for the left
side and right side of that bin.
So for example here on this kind of really tall bend the tallest bend there is.
It looks like there's about a little over 60 count and that means that for this range in the bin.
So looks like ages maybe something like 58 up to 60.
There happens to be around 60 people there.
Now for what.
I can't affect the bins by saying no beans is equal to maybe I only want to beans.
In which case if I run that now I just have two beans which essentially goes from a little less than
30 to kind of midway around maybe fifty four and the count there is somewhere between one hundred and
one twenty five points.
So obviously depending on the size here dataset you can affect this number of beans which in turn affects
the actual with the beans.
Now keep in mind if you start asking for too many beans for example let's make this something like beans
is equal to 50.
You'll end up with lots of empty spots because there happens to be no data points for that particular
bean OK now if you do want to change the size of this plot.
Well you can do is make a call right before this seaborne using map plot line by saying PDT that figure
which essentially calls the underlying figure that seaborne is working with and then say fig size is
equal to.
And then you pass in a tuple of how large you want the figure.
So I can say something like 12 by eight.
And the story sizes too tall by eight inches and we can kind of stretch it out if we want to.
So for example if I made this three by 15 you can see how that stretched out.
So this three representing kind of along the x axis is 50 representing the Y.
Okay.
So other things we can do here.
Let me turn this back into a more normal looking plot just say eight by eight.
Other things I can do here.
In fact we can make it a little smaller eight by four so other things I can do here are set the color
so I can set color strings.
Just we mentioned before so I can say something like the color is red and I can also play around the
bin size if you do ship type here and expand on this it will show you the various other things you can
do such as different fittings for the KDE e different labels et cetera.
But keep in mind most of this is designed to be just very simple calls.
In fact you'll notice that the X label or the label for the x axis was automatically determined from
the name of the data frames column.
So now let's go ahead and show you a counter plot since we'll be doing that as well if I take a look
at the head of my data frame again here maybe I'm interested in the account of the label.
Essentially the target whether or not they have presence of heart disease per sex male or female.
So I can say S.A. count plot state that I want the X to be equal to the sex feature and then say my
data is equal to the state of frame def run that.
And essentially what this does this is essentially a group by whatever you have on the x axis for a
count call.
So this shows you the counts for in this case x is equal to sex.
So how many males you haven't dataset versus how many females then we can do this same thing for the
target which is really important actually later on in machine learning.
We'll see that.
It's usually a good if you have balanced classes.
So here I have roughly the same amount of zero targets as I have one targets.
Then we can do other things like CPE which if you go back to the actual notebook you can look this up
and see that it's like chest pain type.
So there's actually various types of chest pains and we can see the count for that as well.
Now maybe you're interested in the types of chest pains not just the count but count per six.
So it's really cool about Seabourn is you can add this hue call and add another categorical feature
such as sex and it will then divvy this up not just by the pain type in their chest but by the hue.
So I'll show you.
For both male and female.
Per C.P. OK now the last thing I want to show you is that you can actually affect the palate here.
So if you don't like these colors you can say palate is equal to and then you can pass in a string code
that corresponds to the color mappings that are available in map plot lib.
And if you take a look again at our notebook and scroll down we discuss this right here where we essentially
provide you a link to all the color mappings so you can add colors based on the color maps sometimes
certain color maps don't make sense for every dataset you want to be careful.
For example here it looks like we're dealing with categorical data so it might make sense to deal with
category based color mappings.
So if you come over here to choosing color maps and map lib as you mentioned Seabourn is built directly
off the map plot lib.
Simply scroll down here.
Here it sees all the code.
But this is actually the colors that we can use.
So there's sequential color maps there's two types of sequential color maps there's diverging color
maps that go from one color and diverge into what is kind of like an opposite color.
There's cyclic color mappings.
There's qualitative color maps.
These would probably be good choices for things like categories and then they're just miscellaneous
color mappings.
So here are all the string codes that correspond to those as well.
And you're free to choose whatever you want.
So we'll come back to Seabourn basics and recall for a lot of these seaborne commands you affect that
by choosing palette.
All right.
The next plot type I want to share with you is known as a box plot.
And I'm going to quickly explain what the box plot is in our Seabourn basics notebook.
We have this little image here of a single box plot.
So if you were to know what the box plot is go ahead and kind of fast forward for this part.
But I'm going to quickly explain the basics of what this is trying to display visually with the box
plot attempts to do is show you the distribution and specifically the distribution across different
categorical features.
So here we see just a single box plot which shows just a single distribution.
And what this does is it splits up the data into four equal parts.
So here we have these different percentiles and we have right here in the middle.
This what's known as the inter quartile range.
The data points between Q1 and Q3 were Q1 is the 25th percentile in Q3 is the seventy fifth percentile.
So essentially what that means is the middle 50 percent of all points.
So if you had one hundred data points then the middle 50 points are in between somewhere in this box.
This line in the middle the box then splits up all the points and half.
So 50 percent of the points on one side of the median and then the other 50 percent of the points on
the other side of the median then we have these minimum and maximum values which are calculated with
the inter quartile range.
So these are often known as box and whisker plots because we have these whiskers extending off of that
middle 50 percent and this minimum is established as key one minus one point five times this entire
quartile range and then we decide that anything outside that particular minimum or maximum based off
the inter quartile range are going to be outliers.
So then we just label those as points.
OK so let's build our own box plots and see why they can be useful and head back to our notebook that
we've been working with.
What I'm going to do is call S.A. thought box plot
and let's set the x axis to sex and then I want to see the distribution of H across this category.
So again for box plots the Y should be a continuous feature the X should be a categorical one and then
we just need to say data is equal to def and I can see the distribution of the ages across sex 0 and
sex 1.
So here we can see that it looks like sex 1 on average tends to be a little younger than sex 0.
Now what I can also do is start kind of comparing other things.
Maybe I want to compare the actual target against categorical zeros and ones against a feature.
So one of the features could be if we look back a seaborne basics and come up here there's this maximum
heart rate achieved feature.
So let's go ahead and kind of copy that one in we'll come back here and set that as our y z and run
this.
And now we can compare the maximum heart rates achieved for people with the presence of heart disease
versus not having it.
And it looks like there's kind of something different here between them especially between the averages
of them.
OK then maybe I want to add a hue here to see how this is affected by sex and what I can do is say Hugh
is equal to sex and now I can see not just the heart rate per target category but the heart rate per
target category per sex.
So now I have these four box distributions that I can play around with.
And if you want to see more examples of this you can definitely check out the Seabourn documentation.
I want to show you two more things which are scatter plots and then a pair plot which essentially a
scatter plot for your entire data frame.
So let's show you what a scatter plot looks like.
You should already pretty much be familiar scatter plots if you have some interest in machine learning.
But essentially what this does is you pass in some feature along the x axis and some feature along the
y axis.
So I'm studying some sort of beats per minute feature and then stay our data run that.
And here you can see a scatter plot.
So essentially for each data point we just grab these two values and put a point on the map.
So what I can also do is start adding in hues to color points differently based off a category.
Again maybe I can choose sex for this and then I can also do a start playing around the palette so maybe
I want these to be colored differently I can say palette is equal to dark two for instance and then
I can see these results.
So if you're colorblind you may want to play around the palette until you can distinguish the points
correctly and you should also be keeping people that are colorblind in mind when you're performing visualizations
that are dependent on color.
And finally we can do is we can also change the size of these points based off a feature.
So for example I can say size is equal to H and you'll you'll notice that the larger the point is the
older that particular person is.
So as we begin to play around with these visualizations we can actually display a lot of feature dimensions
on a to the plot.
So here we're actually showing not just this beats per minute versus this cholesterol feature but we're
showing also the sex and the age.
So lots of information here on what is actually just a simple scatter plot.
So very useful.
And then last thing I want to show you is something called a pair plot.
Often when you're dealing with a smaller dataset such as the IRS data set.
So let me load that in.
We'll say IRS equal to PD read CSP and then we'll say data Iris that CSB so the iris dataset is probably
something you are familiar with.
Essentially it shows you four features of flower pedals and simple lengths and widths and then the species
of flower.
It actually is what you can do here is you can call S.A. dot pair plot and then you just pass in either
an entire data frame or a subset of data frame columns run that.
And what Seabourn will automatically do for you is the following pair plot.
And what this does is it creates a histogram of each of these features along the diagonal here and then
performs a scatter plot for each comparison.
And you should know that for some of these essentially along a diagonal you should get duplicates.
So for instance here we can see pedal width versus pedal length and it looks like there's a strong relationship
there.
And if you keep going across the diagonal you'll notice the exact same plot pedal with versus pedal
lengths.
So it should essentially be mirrored across this diagonal.
Now there's lots of different options here.
You can play around with.
You can start adding cues.
So for example you can say Give me the Hugh Herr species of flower run that and then you'll see the
actual change the histogram to be K.D. essentially kernel density estimation plots or distributions
of these actual features per species.
So this is a really nice way to quickly get an understanding of all your data but you should keep in
mind that the larger your data frame especially on number of rows and number of columns the larger this
pair plots going to be and it's gonna be harder to interpret and it's gonna take seaborne longer to
actually develop it.
So don't just run pair plot on huge data frames otherwise your duper notebook will be stuck all day
waiting to render this giant plot that may not be useful to you instead maybe try to select subsections
of the plot based on some sort of analysis of the data frame beforehand and keep in mind you can always
just perform your own histogram or on distribution plots or your own scatter plots for any combination
of features you're interested in.
OK thanks.
And coming up next we're going to set you loose on some exercise to test your new Seabourn my pop live
skills.
I'll see you there.