Welcome back everyone.
In part three we're going to work on setting up our training batches so we're going to be using the
built in TAF data set object.
And again we'll be using the from tensor slices method.
We actually already saw how to do this in the MLP lecture series.
So let's go ahead and do a quick review and set up our batches for our again and head over back to the
notebook.
All right.
I'm back at the notebook where I left off last time.
First thing we need to do is when setting up our batches we to decide on a batch size.
So I will go ahead and choose a relatively small batch size since we're dealing with technically image
data but only if a dense network will slow down our learning training time a little bit and choose a
smaller batch size.
If you want training to go faster you can choose a larger batch size.
Okay.
And then I will say my dataset is equal to only Zero's object that we made before.
And the reason I'm setting it up this way is so you can optionally try to run something like my data
is equal to x train.
But for now we'll just operate on zeros that way we can really tell if our generator is actually generating
numbers such as zero or not.
Okay.
Next they're going to do is set up our data set so to do this we simply say data set is equal to TAF
dot data dot data set and then we call from tensor underscore slices and then we pass in my data and
then we're gonna do here is we call shuffle even though it doesn't matter too much since it's already
kind of just random zeros.
You should always shuffle just in case it's an order.
And then we're going to do here is choose a buffer size the buffer size is just so it doesn't load everything
up into memory we set a limit in case we're dealing for really large data set.
And usually we just choose a thousand.
So we'll go ahead and run that and then we're going to do is if you want to just confirm the type of
this object it is a data set and that's a shuffled data sets are actually going to shuffle it and then
we're gonna do here is will say data set is equal to data set and we'll start setting up the batches
for it by sending dot batch and then you pass in the batch size that you wanted and then we say drop
remainder is equal to true recall from the actual MLP lecture series that drop remainder just means
if those last few items is less than your batch size we'll go ahead and just drop those.
So if I take a look at the size of my batch it's thirty two and then if I take a look at my dataset
the shape of it is five thousand nine hundred twenty three.
So that means 30 to if we try to divide this up into batches of 32 we get a little bit of leftover we
get a hundred eighty five clean batches with some images left over.
And so all drop remainder does is it drops that last remainder.
So we get one hundred eighty five clean batches each of thirty two and for our dataset one hundred and
eighty five batches should be more than enough for at most going to drop just 32 images and out of almost
6000.
That's essentially inconsequential.
So we can go ahead and feel safe dropping that remainder.
And then what we can do here is call pre fetch 1 and then we'll just train this for one epoch after
one epoch.
We should be able to see it start generating zeros.
OK so we set up everything for our batch training now it's time to actually create our training loop.
So if we take a look at the Gan object we created it's this sequential model and I can actually call
layers off of this and essentially get back a list of two sequential models because recall when we created
our again it's essentially just a sequential of the generator and discriminator which ends up being
this concatenated list of the generator and discriminator which means if I call the first item off of
this I can see my first sequential model and then I can call layers off of this and then I see the actual
layers here of that first sequential model and then I can do the same for the second one which is the
discriminator and I can see my discriminator here.
So notice my generator starts off dense and then reshapes everything.
And what I can also do is then start calling things off like a summary of my generator model versus
a summary of my discriminator model.
And this is all just to show you that I can access the generator model by itself or the discriminator
model by itself by just calling off of these actual layers since the layers of the scan are sequential
models themselves.
So that's all I really want to show here with this dot layers because I'm going to do is I'm actually
going to grab the separate components before we actually start the loop by saying generator comma discriminator
equals again and I'm essentially impacting that list of layers.
So I'll go ahead and this is all now going to go in a single cell but have Gan about layers here and
I'm grabbing the generator component from it and the discriminator component and we can see that layers
itself.
I could just call the actual models itself.
All right.
So our training loop is going to be a little different here than we usually do.
Typically we just fit.
But since we're operating with essentially two distinct phases we need to do a say for epoch in range
epochs.
In this case we're just training for one after one epoch we should be able to actually see results that
basically make sense and we're going to do is print ourselves a little message just to make sure we're
running we'll see currently on epoch and then we'll print out epoch we'll do plus one that we don't
start to epoch 0 and so we'll keep eyes a little counter so I's equal to zero in our case.
Essentially just run once and then for every batch in our dataset what we're going to do here is we'll
say I is equal to I plus 1
so we able to run and then we'll say if I model hundred is equal to zero.
Essentially we've done a hundred batches.
We're gonna print out a little message.
This is now so we can track on the current batch so we'll say it's actually put a little tab here just
for spacing we'll say currently on batch number and then we'll input I and then I can actually calculate
how many batches by saying of lengths of my data and then just do classic division.
So to forward slashes divided by batch size this is just for kind of printing out what we're currently
on and let's make sure we spell that right.
There we go.
OK.
So again all I'm doing here is I'm just using eyes a tracker to essentially count what batch I'm on
in every 100 batches.
I'll go ahead and print something out to tell me what batch I'm currently on.
Otherwise we actually won't see any information while this is training so we can print out that I'm
currently on some epoch and then print out what batch I'm currently on.
And if you scroll up again recall that we should be having a hundred eighty five batches.
OK.
So now we set this up in two phases during the training to make sure we close that off.
Go ahead and enter here.
So outside of this if statement I'm going to start off by the discriminator phase.
OK.
So first I need to create some random noise so it's ATF random normal noise and the shape of this noise
should be equal to the batch size by the coatings size we chose earlier recall coating sizes essentially
that latent layer that is at the very beginning of the what is essentially almost like a decoder that
the generator is operating as OK.
So we have that random noise and then what we're gonna do is we'll generate some numbers based off just
noise input.
So this is technically the discriminator training phase but in order to discriminate between real images
versus fake images we have to actually produce some images.
So the generator what it's going to do on this very first run is it's going to try to generate images.
So that is what's happening here.
All the generator gets to see is this random noise and then given that we're gonna noise see if based
off this model shape of going from 100 it's 150 784 and then reshaping it's 20 to twenty eight what
is going to do is can you actually produce an image you can imagine that the very first images that
it's gonna produce are just gonna be absolute noise.
So it generates some images.
Next we want to do is we want to concatenate generated images along with real images.
So what we'll do here is we'll say X fake versus real so we have our fake generated images and our real
images from our dataset.
So the way we're going to do this is if a little bit of sensor flow commands they look pretty similar
to some panels and then like code that we have Comcast which is concatenate.
And what I want to do is I need a pass and a list of what I actually want to concatenate together.
I want to concatenate together my fake images.
Those are the ones that the generator is generating on the very first pass this should be horrible but
hopefully over time they get better.
And then what I need to do is I need to actually grab my current x batch and to make sure this works
as far as data types action to cast the data type to be float 32 bit.
So we'll say F D types cast and I take in my X batch and cast it to float 32 bit and then we can cat.
Nate this along axis is equal to zero.
Okay so all we're doing here is I have these fake generated images and then I have my real images from
X batch which I'm casting to float 32 that way later on I don't get errors if you don't cast to float
through to some versions of tense flow.
Also the penny on your operating system will show errors that it can't concatenate things that are a
different data types.
Okay so we can get those guys together.
Now I have my fake versus real then what I need to do is I need to actually set the target label for
them.
Essentially what is the Y for the discriminator.
So the distributor is going to take TAF constant while we're gonna have the following we'll say zero
point zero times the batch size.
Notice that this is a list so you might recall that if you take a list of a single item and multiply
it by some number it essentially just expands that list.
So I'll show you a quick example of that in case you're not familiar.
This is just basic python but let's imagine I have that zero point zero times it by ten.
The result is here 10 of these.
Okay so that's what I'm doing here I'm just taking all these zeroes times that batch size and then what
I'm going to do is I'll then go ahead and say plus and that is these are just Python lists.
These are num pi res.
I'm not actually adding zero plus one here.
I'm just taking my list of zeros and then I'm essentially joining it or concatenated along with.
Here we have one point zero times the batch size
OK so what does this actually look like when it's all said and done.
Let's go ahead and grab it here grab these guys and then let's paste this here and see what we actually
get.
So if I run this I essentially get a bunch of zeros first and then a bunch of ones.
So does that actually make sense.
Well we come back here we'll see that it does because the zeros should be zero.
Not true for the generated images.
The ones should be true for the actual real images from the X batch dataset and we have to make sure.
This little
cursor there should be right here.
There we go.
So it's essentially a list of single list zeros and a list of single ones so let me copy and paste them.
That's why we actually didn't get those brackets correctly.
Pace set in.
Run that again.
And just to show you what it looks like.
So this is essentially what we're using as our labels.
So all these zeros correspond to that first batch of generated images.
It's zero.
They're not real.
And then ones here correspond to the real images the ones that we actually know are true zeros written
by human eyes ones.
And that is going to be joined up with this ex fake versus real.
So we have those labels now.
Next we need to do is in order to get rid of a curse morning we say discriminator not trainable.
We actually do want the discriminator to be trained here.
We'll say it's equal to true recall that previously we said it was false and that was basically to let
the gang compile.
So if you have discriminated that trainable is equal to False here that's only false for this compiling
it doesn't mean you can never train discriminator again.
So that's why we have to essentially reset it as OK.
Now it's time to train the discriminator.
So we said that the true.
And then we say take my discriminator and then train on batch on that X fake versus real.
And then the why is that why when we just created.
So this was actually pretty straightforward for this commuter train phase.
All we're doing is we start off with some random noise given that random noise to the generator and
telling the generator.
Given this random noise produced some images.
So it's really interesting here is the generator never actually sees any real M digits images.
All it gets to see here is noise being fed into it and then increases generated images.
We get those fake images these generated images and concatenate them together with the real images from
our current ex batch which recall we're getting from that data set object that created before.
Next we need to actually create labels for these and we know the first ones do talk talking carbonation
are all the fake images.
So we say those will all be zeros since they're not real.
And then we assign one labels to all the ones that are real and you do this regardless of how many classes
you have because they're called discriminator.
All it's trying to do is say what is real versus what is fake.
And then we have screaming that trainable is equal to true and then we're gonna go ahead and train on
that batch and now all that's left to do is to train the generator.
So for this we create some random noise again we'll just say TAF thought random that normal for random
normal noise and then we'll say shape is equal to the batch size by whatever the encoding size you want
in here.
So it will say coding size.
So there's a random noise again.
Go ahead.
Just Label this as train generator so there's the random noise and then after that what we're going
to do is we actually in this phase.
What's happening here is a generator.
It's going to start by producing fake images and then discriminator again tries to guess whether these
images are fake or real.
However in phase two is actually happening here.
We want to discriminate or to believe that these fake images are real.
So what we end up doing is we set those targets all equal to one.
So what we do here is we say why two is equal to TMF dot constant and we have this one point zero times
the size of the batch.
So say at one point zero and make sure we have princes here.
So one point zero times batch size parentheses close that off and then to avoid an error we say set
discriminator is actually really to avoid a point a warning not an error.
What happens is Caris if you put your trainable is true and then say trainable is false.
Chris would essentially warn you.
Are you sure you want to do this because you compiled it with a false versus true or vice versa.
So that's why we're actually doing this.
These two lines are technically to avoid these warnings.
So we have discriminator now trainable sequel to false and then we end up taking the entire game we
call train on batches or train on batch and we pass in the noise versus Y 2.
So eventually hopefully what's gonna happen is at the end of all this training.
Once these epochal loops are done running we can just take our again and then say based off some noise
go ahead and give me some sort of generated output.
OK so we'll go ahead and zoom out and we can see the entire process here.
Again all we're doing is in Phase 1 we feed in that Gaussian noise the generator produces fake images
and we're completing that batch by concatenate in an equal number of those real images and we set the
target accordingly where zero corresponds with those fake generated images and then one corresponds
to those real images from the batch.
OK then we train the discriminator on that batch and then essentially in Phase 2 what we're doing is
we feed the Gan itself some Gaussian noise it's generator will start by producing fake images then this
criminal will try to guess whether or not these images are fake or real.
And again we want in this phase 2.
We want that discriminate to believe that the fake images are real.
So we set the Y two targets to one.
All right.
So let's go ahead and run this.
This is just running for one epoch but as you run this what you should see is our little batch indicator.
And if you want you can set the smaller so instead of 100 go ahead and report on every 10 batches or
something like that but we'll go ahead and just let this run.
I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done running.
All right.
So this is just finished training for me.
Now it's time to actually see if the generator components of the pan can produce something that more
or less looks like a zero.
So when you first need to do is ask for some noise we'll say noise is equal to T F random normal shape
is equal to and then however many fake images you want to go out and ask for a 10 fake images by the
encoding size so we run that and if we take a look at our noise space is just 10 by hundred were called
the encoding size was one hundred and licious show what this noise actually looks like.
So that's all it is it's just noise.
So given this series of noise essentially 10 of these series of 100 noise points passes into the generator
to get some images will say images is equal to the generator being fed in that noise and now if I take
a look at the shape of my images it's ten by twenty eight by twenty eight.
So I have ten twenty eight by twenty images.
Let's grab the first one see what it looks like so notice has a lot of zeros which makes sense but kind
of in the middle hopefully starts to actually label some data.
So let's say Keelty M show and see what this visibly looks like.
So you run that and you get something that more or less should have some sort of circular shape.
And if you're getting just something that's very very noisy or totally blank.
Go ahead and restart your colonel and train for a couple of epochs.
Sometimes it's dependent on your hardware and if you're really just getting a lot of noise or just really
bad results.
Try downloading our notebook and running our notebook directly.
We've actually added a little bit of code to set some random seeds for you in our notebook to make sure
you get some good results.
So what we did here is notice this does kind of look like a doughnut so clearly it's learning some kind
of zero.
Now you should also notice with your model it's highly likely you'll encounter this error known as mode
collapse.
That was the first image it generated.
Let's take a look at the second one.
Image number one.
Notice that it essentially looks exactly the same.
And out of this batch of 10 images you'll notice they all look either exactly the same or extremely
similar.
You can see that maybe the values are slightly different.
So if I take a look at this little green point that little green point exists here.
But the actual value is slightly different.
This one's a little brighter and you can take a look at maybe here.
These bottom points they are in the same coordination or formation but these happen to have slightly
different values so they are technically different arrays but they look almost exactly the same.
And this is extremely common with generative adversarial networks.
And this is known as mode collapse.
So it's actually happening here.
Well what happens is the generators outputs are becoming less diverse.
And so what's actually happening is the generator basically figured out that it could produce one single
image that would always fool the discriminator and that single image was essentially something that
looks like this.
So the generator is starting to think so to speak.
Why would it tried to bother to learn other types of zeroes when it figured out the type of zero that
can fool the discriminator.
So it gets cut and this feedback loop of consistently producing the same image and then sometimes this
can oscillate as a discriminator gets smart this image suddenly a generator collapses back down to noise
and then thinks of another zero it can generate et cetera and it's almost like this cycle of noise versus
a single zero noise versus a single zero where that single zero is the image it figured out that could
fool discriminator.
So there's this kind of weird oscillation that can occur due to this mode collapse.
Now this is essentially a state of the art as far as trying to figure out how we can prevent mode collapse.
There's a couple of different ways that people can go about it and I've linked a couple of research
papers where researchers are actually trying to do things like propose new cost functions or different
techniques to stabilize training or avoid this mode collapse.
So things are actually trying to do is maybe techniques like experienced replay which actually consists
of storing the images produced by the generator at each iteration into what they call a replay buffer
and then it gradually drops those older generator images that way discriminator gets a C newer stuff
and you don't get this kind of repeat image that the generator understands it feels discriminator And
the thing to notice here is we actually used a completely dense network to produce to the images it
might make more sense to try to create a convolution volitional network based game.
And these are known as Deep convolution all Ganz or DC Ganz.
So we're gonna do is in the next series of lectures essentially going to edit our network.
So instead of using dense layers since we're dealing with to the image information let's see if we can
use convolution volitional layers.
OK.
Hope you found this project really interesting.
Again we're dealing with state of the art stuff here and it's highly likely that we're not to be able
to produce perfect zeros.
But if you were able to produce something that is at least circular in shape then you know your generator
has at least attempted to learn something from the images of zeros.
And what's really cool is it never even got to see the images.
All it gets to see is noise.
I'll see you in the next room of lectures where you begin to discuss deep convolution Ganz.