Welcome back everyone to finish off this section.
We're going to have a couple of exercise questions involving the data visualization skills we just went
over.
Let's head over to the notebook and go over the tasks.
All right.
Here I am at the visualization exercise notebook.
And if you check out the data we're gonna be dealing with a classic dataset that basically contains
the prices and then some other attributes of about 54000 diamonds.
So it's a really great dataset.
And here's the different columns that are available and inside the exercise notebook.
We actually already run the imports and data for you.
So all you need to do is just run these first few cells to actually do your imports and read in the
file so you don't need to worry about finding out where the actual data is.
We set that up for you.
Just go ahead and run these first cells.
Then once you've done that we have some tasks for you to complete.
Keep in mind in order not to overwrite the actual expected output visualization you should code in this
cell and not overwrite anything in this cell.
So keep that in mind you should only be coding in the cells that say code here.
First we're going to have you create a scatter plot of this price versus carrot as shown below.
And then you'll notice that basically there's an issue with this plot in that the marker edge is making
it hard to actually read this plot.
So then we want you to use the alpha parameter an edge color parameter to deal with that overlapping
issue and get something that looks a little more like this.
Keep in mind there's going to be some task requirements that we didn't specifically go over in the lectures.
A big part of becoming good at using these visualization libraries is being able to do either a quick
Google search or search the online documentation or search stack overflow to figure out how to solve
a common task.
So keep that in mind you may need to actually google or search around the online documentation to figure
out the parameter calls.
However there's pretty heavy hints within the tasks itself next we want you to figure out how to make
that previous plot larger so that it looks something like this then we want you to create a histogram
of the price column as shown below.
Notice there's no kernel density estimation plot on top of this.
It's just the histogram then we want you to create a count plot of the instances per cut type as shown
here.
And then we want you to figure out how to make a box plot of those cut types and then we have kind of
a final challenge which is to see if you can figure out how to change the ordering of the box plot.
So you'll notice here in this ordering on the default box plot it goes ideal premium.
Good.
Very good and fair.
It would be nicer if we could have this in an order that goes from worst to best.
So fair.
Ideal.
Good cup.
Very good and then premium.
So we want you to do is figure out is there an actual parameter call that allow you to order this and
you'll notice that we changed up the palette for this box plot as well.
Okay.
So those are all the tasks.
Best of luck and if you get stuck.
Feel free to look at the next lecture or go over the solutions.
I'll see you there.