Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to be talking about nut pie operations.
We'll discuss various arithmetic operations as well as some universal array functions and summary statistics
you can use of nut pi.
These sort of operations will easily extend to pandas as well.
Let's get started.
All right.
Now I've already imported umpires MP.
The next thing going to do is set array equal to NDP arrange zero to 10 and let's check out this classic
three.
Now let's quickly talk about arithmetic between arrays as well as Earth missing between a scalar with
an array.
If I were to take this array and say plus five what's going to happen is number I will perform this
operation on an element by element basis.
So it will take every number in that array and simply add a fight to it.
And the same goes for any major functions so for example array minus two etc..
It all happens on an element by element basis.
Now the same thing happens when we take an array and do an operation against another tree.
Keep in mind these arrays have to be the same shape in order for this to work.
So if I were to take my original array and add it to itself I've essentially doubled every number in
the array.
And keep in mind what's gonna happen is I can do this for any sort of operation multiplication division
et cetera.
So if subtraction everything goes to zero something I want to point out is num pi is a little bit special
in the way it deals with divisions by 0 4 with something like a division error.
So what actually happens is you get a warning instead of a full error.
For example if we take a look at my original array I have zero as one of the options.
So if I were to say my array divided by itself I can end up getting at the very first indexed location
zero divided by zero.
Technically mathematically speaking this isn't really actually makes sense but if I run this notice
num pint will still output a result.
However it will give you a warning that some sort of invalid value was encountered during division.
So what it does here is it replaces zero with or zero divided by zero.
With this Nan or not a number.
What's also interesting is if I were to try to do one divided by zero in normal python I would get a
zero division error division by zero.
However if this occurs within num pi.
So if I do one divided by an array essentially taking the reciprocal of every number in this right at
the very first element I would get one divided by zero.
So normal Python won't let you do that but if you have num pt. what's going to happen is it will also
report back again a warning divided by zero encountered in true divide that has a sort of placeholder
with divided by zero.
By saying this infinity.
So keep in mind if you have zero being divided by something such as Zero will end up getting not a number.
If you have some sort of element or scalar being divided by zero then we'll have this place holder of
infinity there.
The main thing to notice here is that num pi won't give you back a full error.
It will only give you back warnings and it will still actually output a result.
This could be dangerous because often we would expect our program to crash or have an error when not
pi will kind of keep chugging along replacing this with either NAND or infinities.
It's just something to keep in mind.
Now pi also comes off many universal array functions.
So we saw the basic ones that are built into python like arithmetic and division.
But there's other things that we can easily call on every element in disarray.
For example I could say MP security for the square root.
And we can see here we've taken the square root of every number in that array and I can do things also
like trigonometric functions.
So take the sign of every number that array or take the log of every number in that array.
And same thing here we start getting errors if we try to take the log of zero since mathematically it
doesn't really make sense.
Again we just get a warning.
We don't actually get a full error.
OK.
So something to keep in mind there's a lot of universal array functions that are available to us in
number pi.
And if you go to the lecture notebook for this particular lecture we link you to this documentation
page with if you start scrolling down you'll have a list at the bottom of all the different math operations
trigonometric functions comparison functions et cetera that are available to you in num pi as universal
functions.
So we can essentially just do N.P. and then do some sort of call here.
So that link is available to you.
However we won't really be using too many extravagant nut pie.
Universal function calls.
We will be using a lot our summary statistics on arrays.
We're often dealing with really large datasets and we want to perform some summary stats in order to
get an idea of just the general intuition behind the dataset so we can do this.
If I took up my original array I can call things such as some which we've seen before that actually
just sums up every element in this array but there's other ones such as mean which takes the average
or I can also call things like Max.
Now there's other things like the variance and standard deviation which we'll discuss further especially
when dealing with real data sets.
But keep in mind there's already all built into nut pie.
So we don't actually need to calculate those out ourselves.
The main thing I want to point out here is that there's the components of axes logic.
So right now we've been doing everything across this one dimensional array so make sense that if we
some things up or take the mean it takes all the elements into account but let's go ahead and create
a two dimensional array so I can do this by saying something like and p a range and then what I'm going
to call here is let's say 0 through twenty five and if I run that I get these twenty five elements so
I can reshape this to be five by five and then to get back this two dimensional array let's go in and
say array to the is equal to any pure range which means the shape of this two dimensional array is five
by five.
Now I could call something like some on this and it will sum up all those numbers but let's imagine
actually want to ticket the sum of maybe all the rows or all the columns.
How do we actually do this.
Well you'll notice that some actually takes in an axes parameter which means you can actually specify
whether you want to perform this operation across the rows or across the columns.
Keyword being a cross.
So what I'm going to do here is say array to the dot some and I'll say axis is equal to zero.
And the result here is 50 55 60 65 70.
So recall when I say great to the shape the elements at index 0 is the rows so rows is represented by
axis equal to zero which means if I were to say that sum and x is equal to zero it means perform this
operation across the rows which gives us this result which is technically the sum of the columns.
So that can be a little confusing for beginners.
The fact that by saying axis is equal to zero it means perform the operation across the rows.
Similarly I can say array to d that sum and see axes equal to 1 run that and they'll perform the operation
across the index one of shape which is the columns so performs separation across the columns.
So keep that in mind X is equal to zero says perform this operation across the rows axis equal to 1
says perform this operation across the columns that cannot be confusing for beginners because they kind
of expect the results here to be switched but the keyword remember is the operation across OK so that's
it for this lecture we'll be using these sort of method calls and Earth method calls later on in the
course I'll see you at the next lecture.