Welcome back everyone.
Here we are where we left off last time in part one of our theta friends lectures.
We learned how to actually grab information from the data frame based off a column location or Arrow
location or both.
Now what we're going to do is learn how to grab information off a data frame based off a certain condition.
Here we have our original data frame with columns WXYZ and rows A through E.
Now let's imagine I wanted to maybe grab the subset of the data frame where we only had positive values.
Well what way we can do this is by asking where is the data frame greater than zero.
Essentially performing a comparison operation across the entire data frame.
What happens is we get a data frame back.
However this is now a data frame of boolean values where we get true where the condition is true.
So we have a positive number or false where the condition is false.
So we have negative numbers there.
If we were to use this as a filtering condition basically passing it into the data frame as a condition
what happens is pandas removes all the values that happen to be false.
So we get these not a numbers or basically missing data then what we can do is later on learn about
how to work with missing data and remove those values or fill them in or something else now.
Typically these columns in our data sets are going to represent features and we're going to want to
filter based off of those features.
So for example we take a look at our original data frame.
I have data frame with the columns.
They'll be X Y and Z.
Let's imagine I wanted to filter out my entire data frame based off conditions occurring in x.
So I wanted to grab where X happened to be greater than zero.
If we take a look at this it gives us back a series where we have the index values ABC the E and the
corresponding boolean as they happen to correspond with the statement.
So you can see the X is negative on B and D so we get a false there.
And what we do is we can take this condition and essentially broadcast it across the entire data frame
based off these index locations.
So what it ends up doing is it only returns back the true rows.
So we should only get back roads a C an E if we take this condition and pass that into our data frame.
And this is very very common with pandas.
We're gonna be doing this sort of thing all the time.
So if there's one thing you get out of this section is understanding conditional selection of pandas.
We go ahead and run this here.
We get back the data frame results where X was greater than zero.
Now keep in mind we can also now work off of this data frame.
So since this itself is a data frame I can perform operations such as grabbing a single column like
the W column off of this and I get back here the W column off of the data frame where x is greater than
zero and I can do all sorts of things just as they would any normal data frame like Graham.
The very first integer location row which would be these values here.
So keep that in mind that it's really common to see pandas operations stacked on top of each other in
one giant long line.
Now I can actually select with multiple conditions here we're selecting on the singular condition of
X being greater than zero.
But what I can do is have two conditions maybe I want where DFW is greater than zero and where d if
y is greater than one.
So how do we actually combine these conditions of Kansas.
Well there's a couple of steps.
The first step is to write out the conditions you want to search for.
So here I have my first condition where W is greater than zero.
And my second condition where y is greater than one.
Step number two which beginners often forget is to wrap each of these in parentheses.
Then once they're wrapped in parentheses you have to decide if you want the actual filtering to be done
with the end operator or the or operator.
So the end operator is an ampersand which essentially shift seven on the keyboard.
So here we can see that I'm asking for results to be returned back where both of these happened to be
true.
So this is an end if I want it to be returned back where either of them happens to be true I can use
this pipe operator where the or operator let's go ahead and stick with Ampersand because that's usually
the more common of the two that we're using and then we pass this entire thing into the data frame.
And if you're a beginner with pandas and you see this giant line of code it can be pretty confusing
at first but just break it down into its key components and it will begin to make sense.
All we're doing is we're asking where DFW is greater than zero wrap that in parentheses and we also
want the condition where DFW Y is greater than one to be true we take both of those connect them with
either the ampersand for and for both conditions to be true or a pipe operator for either condition
to be true and then pass that into our theta frame if we were to use the pipe operator.
Well it looks like all the values in the data frame satisfy either this condition or this condition.
However only these happen to satisfy both of these conditions and this is the exact kind of thing we're
gonna be seeing all the time with pandas.
Now a couple of more index details I want to go over is how to reset the index in case you have a named
index.
But you want to reset it to integer values.
We take a look at our data frame.
Let's imagine that here I have this named index.
But let's imagine actually wanted it as a column itself.
What it can do is say reset underscore index run that and it will actually create a new column for me
called index with these old index values and the new index notified here in bold are just integer values
0 1 2 et cetera.
Keep in mind this is not permanent unless you actually assign it that way.
So what I want to show you now is how we can take a column that exists already and set that as our index.
So I'm going to create a list called New I.A. for new index and what I'm gonna do here is pass in some
states.
Keep in mind is going to have to have the exact same length as the number of rows we currently have
in our data frame in order for this to work.
So we'll go ahead to say California New York Wyoming Oregon and then Colorado.
So we have our new index list and what I'm going to do is assign this as in your column by calling the
column as if it already exists and then setting it equal to this new index.
So here we have our data frame recall that we actually didn't make this resetting permanent if we wanted
to make it permanent.
We'd say def is equal to DFT reset index into the reassignment that way but right now I still want that
old index.
So let's imagine here that I actually didn't like this labeled index.
It wasn't useful to me so I didn't want to save it.
And instead I wanted the states column to be the index.
What I can do is instead of resetting my index I call def set index and then pass in the column.
I want to set it to such a states.
And then when I run that it gets rid of your current index.
Keep in mind it won't save it to another column if you just call the index.
It'll completely remove it and then I'll take your old column here states and turn it into an index
something that confuses students is they think the words states here is actually a column name that's
actually not true.
And it's denoted by the spacing.
Notice that w x y z are on their own line and then a line below it.
We see states basically what this indicates is that states is the name of this index.
The only columns we currently have here are w x y z.
Keep in mind if I say just set index.
This effect is not permanent unless actually do the reassignment.
So if I want the reassignment to occur I can say D F is equal to DFS set index run that and then I get
back the state of frame permanently changed.
That states is the name of the index to confirm that WXYZ are the columns.
I can say the FDR columns and here I only see they'll be X Y Z.
Notice I don't see states because states is just the name of that index.
Now that I've said it by default indices usually don't have names which is why you see everything here
on the same line finally.
There is a couple of data frame summaries that are really useful such as DFT top describe which essentially
just gives back a bunch of numerical information so provide summary statistics for each column such
as the count each of these has five.
The mean the standard deviation the minimum value for each column the maximum value and then the percentiles.
So the fiftieth percentile.
That's essentially same thing as the median.
Essentially saying 50 percent of all points are below this number 50 percent are above it.
The other ones that are useful are def the info telling you how many not Nulls and the data types and
if you just want the data types you can also say DFT D types.
OK that's it for this lecture.
Makes you review that notebook carefully because conditional selection by pan this data frames is something
going to be using all the time throughout the course.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.