Welcome back everyone to the auto encoders exercise so the purpose of this exercise is to really answer
the following question.
Given a data set of average eating habits between countries in the United Kingdom does any particular
country stand out as different from the others.
So keep in mind this particular question doesn't entail any specific discussion of dimensionality reduction.
In fact this question could possibly just be answered by taking a close look at the raw data itself.
And we're going to actually explore that throughout the exercise.
But we'll first try to answer the sort of question by visualizing the data and then we'll see how dimensionality
reduction can help us figure out which country is the standout.
So let's head over to the exercise notebook and explain where you're going to be doing OK.
Here we are at the exercise notebook to begin.
You're first going to run these imports and then read in the CSB file by running this command.
And essentially what this is.
It's a table of the average consumption of 17 different types of food in grams per person per week for
every country in the United Kingdom.
And so you'll notice that while the table after your reading data shows some interesting variations
the overall differences are actually not clear because what we have here are 17 different categories
across four countries England Wales Scotland and Northern Ireland.
So what's going to occur here is from a normal just person perspective you're not actually going to
yield to take a look at this table and instantly figure out which country or which set of countries
is very different from the others.
So next logical choice is to try to visualize this and maybe decide to choose a heat map.
So we'll go ahead and have you transform or transpose the data frame to look like this where the countries
are the actual rows and then create a heat map that looks like this.
So this is one approach to answering this question and you'll see that this heat map still doesn't really
quite answer the question of which country is extremely different from the others.
So in that case you may want to try to perform dimensionality reduction because really the hard part
here is that we are dealing with 17 different categories of food across four different countries.
So that's almost 80 different little cells here that we have to look at.
So instead of we're going to do is see if we can create an auto encoder that goes from seventeen to
eight to four to two and then back out from that two to four eight to 17 and you have flexibility over
what hidden layer neurons you want to choose but then you'll combine the encoder and decoder create
the auto encoder and eventually we should be able to do is after training on a set number of epochs
then you should get something that looks kind of like this.
Essentially what we did when we first discussed our encoders for dimensionality reduction and after
plotting this out you should notice that Northern Ireland is quite different than the other three countries.
Keep in mind you will most likely not get this exact plot especially if you use a different type of
auto encoder.
So we should notice is some differentiation between Northern Ireland versus the other three countries
and it does have that actually happened like this.
It could be that Northern Ireland maybe centred around zero and the other three countries are not centred
around zero.
OK so go ahead and take a look at this and follow along.
The exercise coming up next we're going to work through an example solution.
We'll see whether.