Welcome everyone to the final part of our next generation project in this part.
We're going to load up the model but we'll only load the weights that way when we build the model.
We can actually build it to accept a batch size of one and then we'll create a function that can generate
text.
Given the model let's get started and continue where we left off last time.
All right.
In order to actually load up our model or load up your model that you just trained First off make sure
you've saved your model.
So if you decided to actually train your own model go ahead and save it and then the next step to load
it up.
So has a batch size of one create a new model we'll say create model and then pass in everything we
pass them before vocab size in bed size as in bed dimensions and then Ana neurons but finally for batch
size say batch size is equal to one.
So you'll create a model of batch size equal to one and then same model load weights and then pass in
the actual file that you saved or our file which was Shakespeare underscored again that H5.
And then after that we'll say model build and we'll build it passing in the input shape and the input
shape stems from TAF tensor shape and then we'll say one by none so running these three lines of code
here of creating a new instance of the model or batch size equal to 1 and instead of actually loading
up the full model we will say load weights and then we will build out the model with that particular
shape size.
Okay so now when I say model summary same models before but notice instead of 120 as the batch size
it expects just one.
So that means I can create a function that will be able to generate text.
So the way it's going to work is will say these f generate TEXT function it's going to take in the model
it's going to take in some starting seed and then it will take a Jen size argument essentially how many
characters you want to generate.
Go ahead and generate 500 characters by default.
And then we'll also specify a temperature argument.
They can play around with.
We'll set it to a default of one point zero.
So the basic idea behind this function is to take in some seed text format it so that it's in the correct
shape for a network and then loop the sequence as we keep adding our own predicted characters very similar
to the work we did in our time series problem but for current year on networks.
So we'll do here it will say the number to generate is equal to the size this is the number of characters
that generate and then we're gonna start by vector rising the starting seed text.
So the start seed will actually be a rostering that the user can pass then.
So in order to do the actual evaluation we'll say input evaluation is equal to character to index s
for s in start seed.
Essentially for every character will go ahead and transform it to an index and then we'll have a list
of those and then we want to expand this to match the batch format shape.
So say INPUT eval is equal to T F expand dimensions we will say INPUT eval
comma zero so it expands the dimensions so that it's in the correct shape and then we're gonna create
finally an empty list called text generated which is going to hold our resulting generated text.
Then finally we can specify a temperature so we can say temperature is equal to temp and the temperature
is of value can play around with.
You can make it lower or higher depending on basically how random or more surprising you want the results
to be.
So we'll show you in a second in our loop how that actually comes into play when generating the predictions
for right now we'll go ahead and reset the state to the model.
So same model reset states
and then we're going to do here is say for i in range the number to generate
will first generate some predictions.
So we'll say predictions is equal to model and pass in that input excel that we just created and then
we'll say predictions and we'll remove the batch shape I mentioned we can do this by simply saying TAF
squeeze predictions zero it's almost essentially reversing the TAF shaping we used earlier that is to
say this to expand dimensions so the opposite of squeezing them and then we want to use a categorical
distribution to select the next character.
So make sure we spell predictions right here.
Perfect.
Then we'll say offer this predictions is equal to predictions divided by temperature and then we'll
say the predicted index or predicted I.D. is equal to just as we did before.
TMF random the categorical predictions we only need one of these characters will say samples as one.
And then finally because of the format does return then we'll do a little bit of indexing by saying
negative 1 0 2 num pi is essentially just indexing formatting so we get the actual single idea which
means then our input eval will say TMF will expand the dimensions back out so we'll see expand dimensions
notice the braces there to predicted Ida comma zero and then we'll transform this back to the character
letter by saying Tex generated
that append index to character of the predicted Ida
once that's all done we'll go ahead and make sure you check your indentation here will return start
seed plus and then we'll join all the items together we'll say join the tax generated list all right.
So let's go ahead and make sure we understand this.
We take in the model the starting seed strain the number of characters we want to generate as well as
the temperature then we assign some variables here number to generate as well as the temperature and
then we're going to get our input evaluation essentially transform that string back into the index locations
we'll expand this dimension.
So it's in the right shape for our model we'll reset the states and then for Iron Range number generators
or for each of these characters we'll get a prediction we'll do squeezing essentially undo this expand
dimensions in order to actually grab the predictions.
These are what these two lines are doing we can affect the actual probability those distributions based
off a temperature you can play around of that value one point zero.
Essentially the base essentially no adjustment since dividing by 1 is the same as leaving at the same
we get predicted I.D. to random categorical it's actually grabbing it a little bit of indexing here
it's converted to some PI so we get that single digit expand that back out so you can get the input
eval shift it forward by your predictive text and then we get this text generated and we start appending
it.
Okay so let's run this make sure we then commit any typos and we'll go ahead and say print generate
text pass in our model go ahead and pass in anything that seems like it should belong in a play by William
Shakespeare such as Juliet in all caps and then let's go ahead and say Our Jen size is equal to 1000
characters run that and this should take a little bit of time but eventually you should see something
that hopefully looks Shakespearean in its output OK so here is what it came up with you can see Juliet
and then excellent start going in all caps but again it's doing this character by character they can
see King Richard how now mistress does the Mona help me pluck over the proud.
No doubt us and you can see some of these are actually just kind of made up words but other ones actually
make a lot of sense.
So you notice it's doing a couple of typos here but on a character by character basis it's pretty amazing
that it's able to start labeling scenes and after a scene as label it tells what characters are entering
and then it really learned the structure of you have some character name in all caps and then what they
say then another character name in all caps and then what they say et cetera.
So pretty amazing work that just on a character by character basis is able to learn the structure of
Shakespeare.
OK definitely check out the rest of the resource links for more examples of this sort of recurrent neural
network architecture being used to generate results.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next section.