Welcome back everyone.
As we begin to finish up this section on pandas we're going to take a little bit of time to discuss
some useful operations.
So in this lecture we're gonna go over a few but very very useful operations that didn't fit into the
previous lectures.
Let's get started.
All right here I am at the Jupiter notebook.
I've gone ahead and just copied and pasted the first cell from the operations notebook.
So if you're here under pen this Crash Course you can go ahead and open up the operations notebook and
essentially just copy and paste this content of the first cell.
Once you've done that it should return back.
This DLF one or data frame one that gives us this K1 column call 1 and call 2.
We have just ABC and k 1 and call 1 we have one hundred two hundred etc. notice there's a repeat here
with three hundred and in call two.
You'll notice that states and again repeats and you can notice here that rose 2 and 3 are actually exactly
the same.
So first let's show you how to get information on unique values.
Let's imagine you wanted to figure out if a data frame was maybe thousands of rows.
What the actual unique values were.
So here we can easily see that in column 2 we have the states New York California Washington and Arkansas
and Nevada.
But for a very large data frame we're not compelled to visualize everything or read everything.
So I can say DFA one call two and I can ask for unique as a method call and return back any unique values
so that if I do that for k 1 the unique values are ABC.
I can also just ask for and unique which it turns back the length of that list.
The actual number of uniques so I could do the same thing for a call 2 and see I have five unique states.
OK finally if we wanted to get a count of all these I can say value counts and it returns back the actual
counts per unique entry.
This is essentially doing a group by on this column with a dot count aggregation method.
I can also drop the duplicates so I can say D F 1 and I can call the drop duplicates method.
Here I just had autocomplete that open in close parentheses I notice it's gonna to drop the second duplicate.
So once it has an entry that is unique such as B 300 Washington every other entry that is exactly the
same as that gets dropped.
So it's going to end up keeping the very first instance and notice it jumps from two to four because
I went ahead and dropped this three which was a duplicate if there was another row further along.
There was also a duplicate it would drop that one as well.
Next I want to show you how to create new columns with operations and functions specifically with the
Apply Operator.
So we already know that if I want to create a new column I can do something like this.
I can say the F one reference the new column and then say based off some old column like call 1 Go ahead
and multiply those values by 10.
And then if I take a look at the f one I have this new column which is column 1 multiplied by 10.
However what if I actually want to do something a lot more complex and just.
Times it by ten or just add two other columns.
I can actually use something known as D dot apply method to apply any functionality I want to every
value in a column.
So step number one is to actually define the function that will operate on every row entry in a column.
For example let's imagine I wanted to grab the first letter here and set that as a new column first.
I'm going to define a function called grab first letter.
So this function takes in some state string and then it returns back the very first item in that state
string.
So if I were to call a grab first letter on NY it should return back.
And now let's imagine that I wanted to use this function and create a new column based off this function
being applied to every value in column 2 what I can do then is say def 1 and maybe I say call 2 here
and I call the DOT apply method and I pass in that function grab first letter.
The important thing to note here is I just pass in the raw function.
I do not add in parentheses to call it.
Instead I will leave that to pan this to call across the entire column.
So if I run that this returns back the first letter of all those states which I if I wanted to I could
then assign that to some new column like first letter is equal to column 2 with the grab first letter
being applied to it.
So then when I call the f 1 notice my column 2 is still in its original state.
However I have this new first letter column based off applying this function to every item.
Now these functions can be as complex as you want as long as it can accept the items in each row.
So you should watch out for some data type issues that sometimes occur.
But let me show you a slightly more complex function so we'll call this complex letter.
Same deal it takes an estate however maybe it has some if statement check so it says hey if the state
first letter is equal to W. then I want you to return Washington else go ahead and just return an error
notice.
I should be returning everything I should not be printing any sort of statement out in these apply to
functions so the next I can say the F one column two here.
Go ahead and apply this complex letters run it in here I can see error error Washington Washington error
error.
You can imagine now that you have a lot of flexibility over what you can do with your own custom functions
applied to a column you should now be able to theoretically create any sort of column you want as long
as I can think of a function that can be applied to every item in the actual column.
Keep in mind you want to watch out for data type errors.
So for example clearly this complex letter function expects a string.
If I were to try to apply it to column 1 here which is numerical and run it I would get a type error
and it would immediately report back hey this integer object is not something that subscript all meaning
I can't go ahead and index off an integer.
So keep that in mind if you get this type error.
Check your function very carefully and then also check to make sure the column is in the correct data
type and other thing I want to show you to quickly create new columns is mapping.
So often you want to map different names to current values in your actual data frame.
So if I take a look at the f one let's take a look at the K 1 column.
It's right now.
A's B's and C's but maybe actually wanted to map D to be one twos and threes instead.
What I do is I define some sort of mapping dictionary so I can say my map is equal to and here I'm going
to define a dictionary that takes an A and sets it to one takes in a b sets it to two and then takes
an A C and sets it to three.
So there's my mapping dictionary then all I need to do is grab the corresponding column and map my map
to it and here it can see the results.
So now I can maybe reassign this to be something like numbers is equal to the F one K K1 maps to my
map.
And then if I take a look at my data frame I see these numbers.
Keep in mind the way the map should work is that the keys should be the existing values in the column.
You want to map this to those values in that dictionary should then be the new result.
So kind of pay attention closely to the ordering here.
8 to 1 be the 2 seat the 3.
And then you just call dot map on this.
Finally I want to show you how to locate the index positions of Max and Min values as well as sometimes
get column and index names.
So we have this giant data free now.
The f 1 let's imagine I wanted to grab the max value of column 1.
Well I know I can do that easily by saying def 1 max and in fact I can be more specific by just saying
Call 1 and it returns back 500 as the max if I actually wanted to figure out the location of that Max.
All I need to do is say Ida X Max.
And it returns back the integer based location in my case since that happens to be the index.
It's the same for minimum.
If I call Ida x min it returns back zero since the minimum actually happened at the very first index
location.
So you can use Ida x men or write the X Max to figure out the actual index for the men in the max for
column names and index names you've actually already seen this before but just in case you don't remember
to grab all the columns use DFA and columns.
No it's an attribute you do not add parentheses you just have it like this.
And what's useful about this is sometimes there's weird spacing in the strings or capitalizations a
little strange.
This shows you exactly what the string calls should be in actually to call those columns then we can
use maybe reassign them.
So if you really wanted to you could say something like the F one that columns is equal to.
And if I wanted to I could say C1 C to make sure these are strings C three see for C5 and this should
it match up to the exact length of the current amount of columns I have and now I have reassign the
columns.
Keep in mind this effect is permanent so you always want to be careful when reassigning those column
names for ordering the data frame.
I can always say the F1 call sort values and then choose what I want to sort fi.
So maybe I want to sort by C3 so I run that and I notice C3 is alphabetical.
Then I could also call ascending or descending.
So if we expand on this you'll notice it says ascending is equal to true.
I could just make that ascending equal to False and then I'll start at Washington and go all the way
down.
Notice what's really cool here is your index still keeps the same label so you can still identify it
based off that index.
There's just two more things left I want to show you which has to do with concatenated data frames and
creating what are called dummy variable features which is something we'll see later on when dealing
with the machine learning part of this course.
So I'm going to copy and paste the cell here that's located under concatenated data frames and this
is typically what our data structure is going to look like.
We're gonna have some multitude of features such as feature a and feature B and then maybe we'll have
our predictions or our labels.
So here we can see our predictions.
Here we have predictions of the class zeros and ones.
Let's imagine that I wanted to join these two data frames back together.
Well what I can do is say PD dot concatenate and I pass in a list of the data frames I want to join
back together.
Essentially concatenate or glue them together.
So I would say features and then predictions.
Now one thing to keep in mind here is you have this axes argument which by default is zero which that
means join them along the rows.
So you'll notice that there's this little warning that pops up because you have these issues of these
null values.
So this join them together but it didn't join them along the right axis.
It took the first data frame and then took the second one and put it on the bottom.
What I should probably do is join them along the columns say x equal to one run that.
And that gives me the correct result that I was expecting.
So if you want to join these like so long columns you'll passin a list into PD dot com cat and then
say x equal to 1 and then maybe you assign this to some new data frame or overwrite an existing data
frame.
Finally to create dummy variables if we take a look at D F 1 we have these categories of a B's and C's
in C 1 so I can see see one here have those categories often in machine learning you need to do what's
known as one hot encoding and the way we can do that is called PD dot get dummies and then call D of
1 C 1 and essentially what this does is it returns back as many columns as there are categories in that
particular column and then it provides a 1 if the category matches up and a 0.
If it did not so we can see the pattern here.
2 ones on A's then 2 ones on B's and then 2 ones on C's.
We're gonna talk a lot more detail about why this is useful for machine learning but right now I just
want to get you introduced to the actual function call which is PD dot get dummies.
All right so we talked about a lot here.
The most important thing I would say for this lecture is that you get a lot of practice using this apply
functionality.
It's a super powerful tool of pandas and essentially lets you create any columns and your only limitation
is what you can think of.
For a python function which is quite flexible.
All right.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.