Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to discuss data input and output with pandas so throughout the course we're
going to be reading our datasets from CSB files.
But real world data can come from a variety of places.
And fortunately pandas has a very robust I O toolset that we can use.
Let's see a few of them in action and then we'll explore the rest of the documentation for them since
there's quite a wide variety of data sources that pandas can read from.
But here we're just really going to focus on reading from C.S. V's since that's what we use in the course.
Let's head over to a Jupiter notebook and get started.
All right here I am at the Jupiter notebook.
I've already imported umpires and pee and pandas as PD.
I want to quickly note that inside our pandas Crash Course folder if you open up our data input and
output notebook which is what this lecture is based off of you can scroll down here and we have a link
to the user guide.
So really this user guide on input output.
That's part of the official online documentation is the best resource.
And if you go to that link it basically has the various format types that pandas can read in from and
the actual reading call and the writer call.
So for example let's imagine you're dealing with a Jason File and you want to know how do I read into
Jason File.
Well he's just come to this Io tool page and then click in here where it says read underscore Jason.
And that basically gives you the information of the parameters you can call why you're reading in a
Jason File so how to accept that and the format of the Jason string et cetera.
So you can scroll down and check out all the various parameters.
So this basically informs you of how to read in various data types.
And it's not just reading but it's also the output.
So if you wanted to read in that files Jason but maybe save it to some excel file you can just read
here to excel click on that and then I'll inform you how to write Excel files to disk.
So it has a lot of information there and a lot of examples as well.
So really the number one resource for you to check out for pan this input and output is this page to
a link to in the actual notebook.
And we have this table copied for you for quick and easy access so we're going to first start off by
learning and how to read in a CSP file since really that's what we're going to be working with throughout
the rest of the course.
So a key part of this is understanding file paths.
So we reading in a CSB file.
So for example here in pan this crash course I have some CSP files here for us to read in.
Now what we need to make sure is that we understand the location of our notebook or our python script
relative to the CSP file that we're trying to read.
So you really have two options.
One is to say PD the read CSB and then as a string just passing the CSB file.
So for example I know there's a CSB file here called example that CSB and I should be able to tab autocomplete
to confirm that it's there.
So I run that and that automatically reads in the example that CSP file but let's say somewhere else
on my computer I have some other file so somewhere else on my computer I say some file that CSP what's
going to happen is it's going to get a file not found error because right now if I just pass in the
string like this pan this assumes that this dot CSP file is in the same location as either this notebook
or if you're running this as a dot pi file as the dot pi script.
So in this case you'll get back something that says file not found error.
So this also happens if you accidentally misspell the file.
So if you said for whatever reason examples that CSP and ran that you would also get that file not found
there.
So if you're getting a file not found error there's essentially a couple of ways to fix this.
One is to make sure that the file is in the exact same location as your notebook to see where your notebook
is located.
You can type P WD inside a cell and then run it and this will actually report back the file path that
you're currently in.
So again inside a Jupiter notebook you can type P WD which stands for print working directory and then
that will report back.
We're located so you could then move this some file that CSP to this folder and then just call it as
such and then it would work again.
The other option which is probably the recommended one is to actually pass in the full file path of
the file that's located somewhere else on your computer.
So that would look like this.
I would say PD that read CSB and then for example purposes.
Let's imagine I want the full file path of example that CSP.
I would essentially copy paste its file path from here and then add one more and then say.
Example dot CSP.
So keep in mind this command here that includes the full file path.
This will work no matter where this notebook or where your dot pi script is located on your computer
so you can always pass in the full file path.
And the reason we have these double back spaces is because in windows the backspace or excuse me the
backslash usually refers to as an escape character so the double back slashes essentially indicates
that we're not going to escape this.
If you're working on a Mac OS or Linux based system you may have forward slashes there essentially just
follow whatever formatting TWD returns.
But if I run this no I get back the exact same result so I can either move the CSB file or provide the
full file path to confirm what files are available to you and your current location inside you open
up but you can type L S essentially for list run that and this will return back a list of all the files
in your current location.
Here I can see in my various notebooks and then at the bottom I can see the CSP files available for
me.
So keep that in mind.
It's a really common question I get from students of the file not found error either move the CSP file
to are currently located or pass in the full file path.
Okay so we just learned how to read in data from a CSP file often especially after performing your own
data analysis on a dataset you want to save your results.
So the way this works is you have some data frame so we read in that data frame then we're gonna do
as we say to CSB and as a string you can again provide a full file path if you want to save it somewhere
else on your computer or if you want to save it to this current directory you would choose the name
your file such as output that CSP and if you do not want to save the actual index here.
So for example by default if this is a numeric index I can say index equal to False and that will not
save the index.
However maybe this index happens to be something important like the name states then in that case I
would want index to be true.
So let's go ahead and see an example of what happens if I save index to be true here.
Recall that the very first column here currently is a 0 4 8 12.
So if I say go ahead and save that index then if I try reading it in again P the read CSB and I read
in that output that CSB notice it automatically saves that index as some unnamed colon 0 column so 0
1 2 3 and then adds an additional index.
Now what I can do is take a look at the options here under read CSB.
There's lots of different parameters and you can even specify if the particular index column should
be referred to from the CSP file itself.
So keep that in mind if you actually save the index you can always refer to something as the index or
you can reset the index drop columns et cetera.
You have all your tool sets available to impact this.
So that's reading from a C as we file and writing to a C C file and frankly speaking if you understand
how to run read CSP using pandas you're pretty much good to go for the rest of this course but show
you just for example just a couple of other options.
A panda is also has the ability to read tables off each HTML and keep in mind this will only work if
your firewall is not blocking this Web site.
So if you're on a corporate network this may be blocked but I'm going to go to this Web site from the
FDIC that has a list of all the failed banks.
Now typically if you see a table on a Web site for a thought estimate file if you take a look at this
page source by saying view page source or control plus you and you scroll down here the way HDMI out
works to render tables is there's actually a particular tag that each team only uses and you can kind
of zoom in here and see that there's these table tags.
So we have the column names institution city state etc. and then we have the various entries with pandas
attempts to do is it attempts to read all the tables present on this HCM El page and we can do that
by saying my tables is equal to PD that read each HTML and then I'm going to pass in that each team
El again you can copy and paste this from our actual notebook but I run that and keep in mind if you
get an error here saying something like Alex smells like install they're beautiful soups not installed
you may need to manually install those but they do come with the environment that we provide.
However if it says something like El excel not found or HDMI 5 Live not found.
Go ahead and install those and we mentioned how to install them interaction with notebook as well.
So if you scroll down here we mentioned that you may need to install these if you're not using the virtual
environment that we provide for you.
Now if you're getting an SSL error on this particular command it means your firewalls blocking you and
there's not much I can do from my end to help you if your personal firewall.
You'll just have to figure out a way to disable it but essentially what happens is pain this creates
this list of tables.
So if we actually check the type that's returned here it is a list which means it attempts to find every
single table on that page and saves it as a data frame.
And if we took a take a look at the very first entry in tables it's actually a data frame that matches
up with the tables that were on that each team our site.
So I can see bank name City National Bank of New Jersey New work et cetera which in my case happened
to be the very first entry on this actual table on this Web site.
So keep in mind you can read from a variety of sources a really common one as well is reading from Eskew
all so you can see here on read Eskew all.
This one's a little hard to show an example of because it often depends on providing a password to your
secret table.
But there's some really nice cookbook examples you can click here on this link to cookbook examples
for cookbook sequel and then there's some other nice links here on reading from databases we've sequel
and then Eskew all documentation and it actually links you to some really great Stack Overflow posts
on how to read from for example an Oracle database my sequel database etc. So lots of great links and
I would highly recommend that if you ever have a question on how to read in from particular source you
reference this online documentation since it's always going to be the most recent up to date resource
for you.
So the takeaway from this lecture really for the rest of this course is just keep in mind that we're
really going to be using this read CSP capability throughout the course PD that read CSP and then to
make sure you understand this file path and how to read in your current file path or how to provide
a full file path.
All right.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.