Welcome back everyone.
Previously we just saw how to run a simple recurrent neural network on our sine wave theta.
Let's go ahead and check out how the performance compares to using Ellis teams.
We also saw that it can take a long time to train these recurrent neural networks as we saw up here.
And we also know that it could get noisy as we train for more more epochs.
So let's introduce how we can use early stopping in conjunction with the fact that we're fitting to
a generator because passing in the validation data in our case we need to pass it in in the same batch
shape as a generator is doing so essentially to create two generators one for our training data and
one for our validation or test data to do this we'll start off by setting up our early stopping just
as before we'll say from tensor flow Dr. Harris that callbacks import early stopping and we'll create
an early stop variable just before by saying early stopping in our case we're going to also going to
monitor that validation loss and we can decide on a patients basically how many epochs are you going
to keep waiting until this early stop actually takes to effect and for recurring neural networks.
I would recommend a higher patients and just patients equals zero because they can get pretty noisy
sometimes.
So it's really nice to wait a couple more epochs just to make sure that we're not in a noisy territory
and then going back down with our loss.
Okay so there's are early stopping mechanism.
Now we need to do is create a validation generator.
So I will say validation generator is equal to and I'm going to use the same time series generator as
before except this time it's our scale test data that's the source of the X in our scale test data that's
the source of the Y and then I need to define length equal to length and then batch size is also equal
to 1.
Now pay attention to what happens when I try to just run this as is I will get an error and this is
a really common error especially for beginners.
So they set everything up just that with the training generator and they think well what's actually
going on here.
Well here's the problem right now our validation set is essentially looking at the exact same length
as the entirety of our test set.
So what needs to happen is this scaled test dataset must be greater than the length chosen for our batches.
And that's essentially a sacrifice we have to make in order to actually run this validation generator.
And the reason again we're getting this error is because right now it's trying to essentially follow
this protocol and it's going to be disallowed.
You can't have your start index plus the length of your training batch equal to 50 when our end index
is essentially 1 short of it because our length of the batch is the exact same size as our test set
which doesn't make sense we're essentially missing that future singular y point.
So what we'll have to do is also redefine our original generator to have a shorter length.
So we're going to have to and you can do this in another cell in the same cell but we're going to say
length it can't be the same size or scale test data.
So previously our scale test data that was going to be a length of 50 we'll go ahead and shorten it
by one to make sure everything's OK so now we'll say generator.
And this is now our training generator is a time series generator passing our skilled training data
as a source of our X and Y and then length is equal to length and the batch size is one.
And now that the length of our batches is shorter than our scale test set we should be OK and essentially
what the validation generator is going to do is going to keep testing on that test range as we actually
predict.
So now what it can do is take forty nine points and predict.
Point number 50 and keep that in mind that technically we're actually just checking the accuracy of
one of these points because of how close our test data is to our length.
If we had it as 50 that wouldn't make sense for the validation set because our validation set is only
50 long.
We will need that fifty first point to actually check against which is why we were getting that error.
So again make sure that if you start creating these validation generators the length here of this batch
has to be at least one shorter than your test data.
Otherwise you'll be missing that predicted point.
OK.
So now that that's ready to go we have our generators in place.
Let's go ahead and create our models.
So I'm going to just copy paste the same model we created before I mean comet out these previous test
predictions and scale data will come back here grab our model so I will copy this scroll all the way
down here paste it in and we're we're going to do here is the only thing we need to do is during our
first step we need to add in the fact that we're producing a validation generator.
The other thing we're going to do is that of a simple Arnon call we'll call else team we'll go ahead
and run that and then we'll say model fit generator and then say generator.
And in this case you can make epochs pretty large because we're working on this validation generator
that we can say our validation data is equal to this validation generator which is nice and then we
just have to make sure to add in that callback that we just defined by saying callbacks is equal to
and in the list we just pass an early stop and then we'll go ahead and run this.
So we set it for 20 epochs hopefully doesn't need to train for actually 20 epochs.
I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done training.
OK.
So I finished training this they only had a train for six epochs.
Let's go ahead and run our evaluation on the test set just as we did before and we can use the exact
same code for this.
So we'll come up here reset our test predictions go ahead and copy this come back down here evaluate
the test predictions for that range and the other thing we're also going to do is make sure that we
do the inverse transform for our test predictions.
So I'm going to run this just before and essentially I just copy these three lines from our notebook.
But it's the exact same mindset that before we'll say true predictions is equal to the inverse transparent
this test predictions.
I'm going to overwrite my current test predictions to be true predictions but we can do is go ahead
and call this Ellis time predictions is equal to true predictions and then we'll run this and we'll
have three columns.
And tonight I can see the predictions from my normal aren't in the predictions from the Ellis team here
in green.
And we can see that the green tends to be performing really quite well towards the end although it's
overshooting here in the middle.
And that is also kind of an artifact of the fact that we're essentially really just focusing on that
last and prediction point which makes sense given the way that we're using a batch length of forty nine
and our test set was 50.
So it actually might be better to either increase the test data and keep the length of 49 or 50 or keep
the test data at 50 and then lower the actual length of that batch size so here are all our comparisons
against the actual data itself.
And now let's go ahead and see how it works if we were to forecast this into the future.
So let's imagine that I want to actually forecast this beyond 50.
Recall that our original data frame if I plot the data out it only goes up to 50.
So let's see how we can forecast essentially a sine wave or something similar to it beyond that X is
equal to 50.
So what we should be doing here is I should be retraining on all my data.
So I'm going to essentially copy and paste a couple of commands from the notebook.
So this is all stuff we've seen before.
I will scale all my data so fit transform on all my data because now I'm forecasting into the future
and what I have to decide here is that I have to look either at this orange line or the screen line
and decide you know what I'm satisfied with this performance.
Let's go ahead and retrain and everything and forecast into the future.
So this is me scaling everything so we have our full scale data and then we're going to do is we'll
go ahead and create our generator.
So we'll do this off the scaled full data now.
Go ahead and create that generator and then we'll use the same model as before.
So let's read the fine our model again.
We'll go ahead and say models equal to sequential.
Grab this guy come back down here.
Define our model.
And then finally let's go ahead and fit our model to the generator.
So say model the fit generator and we'll say fit it to the generator and then previously it took if
you look on the Ellis Tam data set here it took six epochs.
Let's just go ahead and train for six epochs was the epochs is equal to six.
Go ahead and run that and I'm going to fast forward in time until that's done training.
OK.
This is done training.
So what I'm going to do is come back and use our same loop that we did earlier so we'll paste it here.
Except now I'm not predicting on my test range.
Instead I'm going to forecast.
And here I get to decide how many spaces do I want to forecast into the future.
So for i in range what am I actually going to forecast.
So let's go ahead and forecast.
Let's say twenty five points into the future and then what I'm going to do is instead of calling these
test predictions these are really just forecasts and there's no way I can evaluate these truly because
my original data set doesn't have anything to compare these values to.
So we'll go ahead and run this.
And now I have my forecast.
So I have my original data frame and I need to take my forecast inverse it or invert the transformation.
So let's say the forecast is equal to scalar dot inverse transform on my forecast and now that the forecast
is inverted all I need to do is take my forecast and get an index for it that corresponds to the points
that it was actually forecasting for.
So I know that my original data frame if I take a look at it it ends at fifty point zero which means
with a step size of point one here my very first x points or X index for my forecasting should be at
fifty point one.
So how do we actually see that.
Well I'll just create a forecast index.
Using that logic I'll say my forecast index is equal to NPR range starting at fifty point one.
Go to in this case I have to think how many points that I actually predict into the future so if I do
a little math here I know I predicted twenty five points into the future with a step size of zero point
one.
So that's going to be a total of 2.5 added to this guy.
So that should be 50 to point six swaps.
There we go.
So that should be my X range with a step size of zero point one.
So that's my forecast index.
So let's make sure that we'll check the length of my forecast index and it's twenty five points which
is the exact same length as my forecast.
There just a little bit of math there to make sure those X's line up with my predicted y values and
then we're going to do so simply plot it will say Keelty dot plot plot my original data it's index versus
sine here.
So that's my original data.
And on the same plot we'll say PDT plot plot my forecast index versus my forecast.
And there you have it.
We can see those twenty five points.
And the reason you see a big gap here from this point to this point is because these are two separate
essentially series.
So there's no line that automatically connects them here.
However what you could do is bind these together using PD dot concatenation or contact and then it would
just be one continuous data frame.
All right.
So that's it.
We were successfully able to compare against a test set but also show you how to forecast into the future.
Coming up next we're going to do is we are going to show you how to run all of this on a real time series
data set.
OK thanks.
And I'll see you there.