Hello everyone and welcome to the data visualization project.
Now that you learned but geez you put two and done some basic plot two exercises it's time to take all
of that knowledge and use it to do a data visualization project.
Let's go ahead and hop to data visualization project notebook.
All right here we are at the notebook and this notebook is under the training exercises folder under
capstone and data.
This projects.
And then there's a folder called Data visualization project and this actual notebook is called assignment
for G.G. plot too.
I want to make a little statement here.
This is an optional assignment.
You don't have to do this data visualization project completely.
It's a pretty complicated project because we are recreating a complex real visualization from the Economist
.
But go ahead and go as far as you want in the plot to data visualization project and then the next lecture
I have a full solutions walkthrough for the entire project.
Basically we're we're going to be doing is if you click on this link in the notebook it'll take you
to a link in the Economist magazine where this visualization is I go ahead and click on that tab.
They'll take me to this article and this article just talks about the correlation between corruption
and development in countries.
And it's from the year 2011 and it has the state of visualization in it where you have a Corruption
Perceptions Index on the x axis and a human development index on the y axis and then notice it's basically
a scatterplot with some sort of trend that fit line.
If you go back to the assignment.
Basically this assignment just takes you step by step through what she have to do on this project.
You can go ahead and access the data in this folder.
It's the Economist underscore assignment underscored data that C S V and it's in the same folder as
this actual notebook.
And then you just go ahead and step by step slowly reproduce the figures shown in the notebook which
will lead you to actually recreating something that looks really similar at the end to the economists
.
You notice here we have some labels there's too many labels and then we reduce the amount of labels
etc. make it a little nicer white theme at a scale to it and just continue on until we get something
that looks more or less like the final visualization.
A quick note to keep in mind this notebook because it's an HDMI format some of the actual figures may
be too compressed and hopefully when you actually perform these operations in our studio they'll look
a lot better.
Just keep that in mind.
OK.
Hope you have fun with this project.
Again it's optional and you can go either as far as little as you want throughout the state of visualization
project or if you just want to browse the solutions walk through video.
Feel free to do so.
I hope you enjoy it.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture video