Hello everyone.
Welcome to the advanced our programming section of this course and this section of the course we're
going to be going over some unique are functions and features that you can use to your advantage when
you're programming with our.
We've already gone over the basics of programming.
And if you already have experience programming you could have just read the notebooks for that particular
section for this section of the course.
Even if you already have experience programming in other languages you should still check out the videos
or at least go through the notebooks because everything we're going to be discussing is pretty unique
to our.
We're going to talk about built in our features the Apply function math functions of our regular expressions
with our.
And then how to do of date and time stamp information with our.
All right.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.
To get started