Hello everyone and welcome to the programming basics section of this course in this section of the course
.
We're going to start understanding how to program with our using things such as logical operators if
else else's statements conditional statements while loops for loops and how to create functions and
are.
If you're already familiar programming in another language what's probably the best course of action
for you is to actually visit the notebooks first for each lecture and then see if you actually need
to review any of the material or if you just need it to quickly learn the syntax from the note.
In a lot of the lectures and the section of the course I will take the beginning of the lecture to quickly
explain the syntax for experienced programmers and then I will slowly go step by step through the actual
concept for people that are never programmed before you have two training exercises in the section of
the course.
So best of luck with them.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture