Hello and welcome to the science machine learning boot camp with our course.
My name is Jose Protea and I teach thousands of students on to me about programming in science and I'm
super excited to teach you all you need to know about data science machine learning with our data scientist
who's been recently ranked as the number one job by Glassdoor that due to not only the incredible salaries
for data science positions but also the chance to solve some of the world's most interesting problems
.
This course is uniquely designed to be suitable for both experienced developers seeking to make that
jump to data scientists or complete beginners don't understand data science and machine learning from
the ground up in this course we cover our programming data visualization and machine learning.
Let's go ahead and take a quick look at just a few of the things you'll be learning in this course once
we're guiding you through the environment set up.
You'll start off by learning the basics of programming including working on vectors matrices and data
frames.
Then we'll learn how to create amazing data visualizations with our Which will lead to a data capstone
project
that will move onto machine learning where through the course of over a dozen machine learning porfolio
projects he will teach you a variety of machine learning algorithms including topics such as linear
regression logistic regression in the more advanced topics such as decision trees in random force and
support vector machines will also include a variety of advanced machine learning topics such as data
mining Twitter for trending topics and create in a word cloud from those topics leave and cover reinforcement
learning such as neural nets all in our all along the way will test your knowledge.
There are programming exercises capstone projects and over a dozen machine learning portfolio projects
.
This course includes over 100 comprehensive video lectures with an explanatory code notebook for every
single lecture we can learn in whatever way works best for you.
You'll also get access to our community forums with thousands of friendly students and I are happy to
help answer any questions you post.
This course also comes of a certificate of completion which you can post on your LinkedIn profile.
You can try this course completely risk free a 30 day money back guarantee.
If you are completely satisfied in your first 30 days you can get a full refund.
I'll even let you keep the over 100 notebooks just so thank you for trying out the course.
So what are you waiting for.
Become a data scientist and improve your career by enrolling today.