Hello everyone and welcome to an introduction to k means clustering in this lecture.
We're going to discuss that k means clustering algorithm which will allow us to cluster and label data
in an unsupervised machine learning algorithm.
You want to fool mathematics behind this algorithm.
Go ahead and read Chapter 10 of an introduction.
Just learning k means clustering is an unsupervised learning algorithm meaning it takes an unlabeled
data it's going to attempt to group similar clusters together in your data.
So what is the typical clustering problem look like.
Well a few examples may be things like clustering similar documents together clustering customers based
off of their features trying to perform market segmentation or even trying to identify similar physical
groups.
The overall goal is to divide data into distinct groups such that observations within each group are
similar.
Here you can see a diagram of unlabelled training data and k means clustering trying to attempt to cluster
that data into five distinct clock colored clusters here.
How does the algorithm actually work.
Well you first choose a number of clusters K and we'll discuss how to choose k later on then you randomly
assign each point in your data to a specific cluster then until the clusters stop changing you repeat
the following steps for each cluster you're going to compute the cluster centroid by taking the mean
vector of points in the cluster.
Then you assign each data point to the cluster for which the centroid is the closest.
Let's go ahead and take a look at the state of visualization or this plotted out visualization of k
means clustering algorithm.
You first start off of just the observations that's shown on the top left then in top center we have
Step 1 of the algorithm.
Each observation is randomly assigned to a cluster in the top right of step 2 A The cluster centroid
are then computed.
These are shown as large colored disks.
Initially these centroid are almost completely overlapping because the initial cluster assignments were
chosen at random in the bottom left and step to be each observation is assigned to the nearest centroid
in the bottom center.
Step two is once again perform.
You can see that we've led to new cluster centroid and we basically keep repeating these steps until
there's no new clusters meaning data points aren't being reassigned to a new cluster centroid at the
bottom right.
We have the results obtained after about 10 iterations.
Let's discuss choosing a k value as we just saw to perform Kamins clustering.
We as it decide how many clusters we expect in the data.
The problem of selecting K isn't actually that simple.
There's no easy answer for choosing a best case value.
However one way to try to do it is using something known as the elbow method.
First of all you compute the sum of squared error otherwise known as s s e.
For some values of k for example 2 4 6 8 etc..
The sum of squared errors is defined as the sum of the squared distance between each member of the cluster
and its centroid.
If you plot K against the SS e you will see that the error decreases as K gets larger.
This is because in the number of clusters increases they should be smaller.
So distortion is also smaller.
The idea of the Elbel method is to choose the K at which the s s e decreases abruptly.
This produces an elbow effect in the graph as you can see in the following picture.
Here we can see an example of the plotted out Eldo method on the X horizontal axis.
We have the K value which stands for the number of clusters we choose for.
The algorithm on the y axis you have the within groups sum of squares you want to try to choose a K
where you won't get that much more information by increasing the number of clusters.
Many are not going to significantly decrease the within groups sum of squared error by increasing number
of clusters.
And that's why this is called the elbow method.
As you can see an elbow occurring around the number let's say six to seven clusters.
That means that's a good number to choose for your clusters.
Again there's no correct value.
So you want to use your domain experience or domain knowledge in whatever field you're working with
in order to try to choose a correct or reasonable value.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and begin to explore an example.
Then you'll have a project to test your own understanding of the Kamins algorithm.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.