Hello everyone and we'll get to your first machine learning project the linear regression project or
this specific project or what we're going to be doing is focusing a lot more on exploratory data analysis
versus actually building a model as you progress through all the machine learning projects.
We'll focus more on building the model and training and testing sets versus exploratory data analysis
.
But for now we'll start off slowly and check out exploring the data that you've never seen before using
G-G plot two.
And then finally at the end building the model let's go ahead and walk through the notebooks how to
get the data and everything you'll be doing throughout the machine learning project.
All right so here I am at this notebook here to have it open in the browser where you can open it however
you want.
This actual linear regression project notebook is labeled m l Dasch linear regression project and it's
under the machine learning project folder which is under the training exercises folder.
So if you're looking for this notebook go to training exercises machine learning projects and then select
an L linear regression project.
Don't select the solutions version of this lecture until after you've attempted it.
This is what the linear regression project looks like for this project.
We're going to be doing is exploring the bike sharing the man Kaggle challenge.
We won't be somebody any of these results of the competition but feel free to explore.
Kaggle or some people call it Kaggle.
A little more in depth.
If you ever heard of this go ahead and click on the link here in the notebook and it will take you to
the actual competition page.
If you're wondering what haggler Cagle is you can just go ahead and click here.
Good.
How about calm and Cavalier's basically a data science competition Web site.
It's pretty interesting.
I'm going to give you a brief rundown of what it is because we're actually going to be using some data
sets from this Web site later on in other machine learning in projects.
Do you go ahead and click on competitions from the main home page.
You'll notice there's a bunch of active competitions and the basic premise here is that companies such
as State Farm or Facebook or Airbnb etc. will post their data sets and will also post a particular question
they're trying to solve.
So for instance here we have State Farm distracted driver detection.
If you click on that link will take you to this page and essentially they'll have a bunch of data and
some sort of task they want you to perform here they want you to figure out if you can use computer
vision to spot distracted drivers.
If you do well on this competition and are a top performer there's actually monetary prizes associated
with some of these competitions.
In this case the top performing team will win $65000 if they have a top performing result that State
Farm approves of.
That's the monetary reason people would want to actually participate in these active competitions.
There's other competitions that will lead to possible jobs.
You notice here there's Facebook five predicting check ins you click on that link it'll take you to
this competition which is I trying to identify the correct place for check ins.
If you do well in this machine learning competition Facebook will actually offer you an interview to
come to work on Facebook which is pretty cool.
Finally if you're just looking to get started there are the knowledge competitions and these knowledge
competitions are just for the sake of knowledge and practicing.
This is the kind of competition we're entering for our very first machine learning project and it's
the bike sharing demand.
Like I mentioned before we're actually going to enter submit data we'll just be playing around this
data set.
You can download it here from the Web site or just use the BikeShare CAC file that's included with the
repository of notes you keep scrolling down here.
What you'll end up noticing is that there's a bikeshare that CC file and you'll eventually just use
rethought CXXVI to read it as a data frame.
All the information of what's actually going on in the BikeShare file as far as what the columns stand
for and what they represent is all here in the notebook.
So for instance if you're confused as to what the season numbers stand for you would just come to notebook
and understand that one is spring to a summer of fall for winter etc. then you're just going to go to
this notebook and try to figure out the tasks in bold go ahead and work through them.
First he'll check the head of the DMF then you try to figure out what is the target we're trying to
predict.
You can check the cagily or Kaggle link if you're confused on that.
Essentially you would just click here read through this and realize that you must predict the total
counts of bikes rented during each hour covered by the set.
OK.
And if you know here we have a county column that's essentially or trying to predict using linear regression
then and this is the main focus of this project is the exploratory data analysis.
I want you to try to recreate some plots.
Don't worry about getting too fancy of the colors of the themes.
These are fancier plots with scale colors and custom themes to them.
Just try to get the basic plot down and then have fun and explore as you plot further.
If you really like data visualization if you don't actually like data visualization too much just get
the basic plot working you want you to create a scatterplot of count versus 10.
Then you can go ahead and move on and you'll want to plot count versus date time and you'll actually
have to convert that date time column into posek C-T formatting before plotting.
So go ahead and do that.
And here is a nicer plot with some color scale variation to try to indicate temperature versus actual
dates.
And from this exploratory data analysis which will end up realizing is that there's a seasonality to
the data.
And this is discussed more in these solutions video walk there and you'll realize that there are some
pros and some definite cons to using linear regression.
And in fact linear regression will end up not being such a super great algorithm given the seasonality
of the data then you'll be asked what's the correlation between 10 and count.
He'll explore the season data a little more by recreating this box but like I mentioned before I worry
too much about the colors of the theme.
Just try to get the basic box plot working then you'll do a little bit of feature engineering trying
to create in our column from the date time column and then you create a scatterplot of count versus
our with some additional options free to check out.
Again don't worry about getting this plot looking exactly like the solutions without checking out the
solutions first.
But just try to get the basics working then you'll create the same plot for non-working days.
So what we have here is a plot for the bike usage with colored by temperature but also by the hour of
the day on the x axis for our work days which means a lot of people are leaving on their bike in the
morning and then leaving on their bike when it's time to go home at 5 p.m. and maybe some lunch breaks
in between.
This for non-working days on the weekend you can see there's like this gradual rise during the middle
of the afternoon and it dies off slowly.
Finally after all that you'll build your model and the here you'll just use the Elham function that
we showed in the lectures to actually build out your model.
You'll get the summary of the model and you keep working through this.
Then you'll ASP's to be you'll be asked to use the model try to predict counts of bike rentals.
You'll continue on.
Create another model that uses other features to predict.
Then get a summary of the model.
Read through it and eventually what you'll end up discovering is that due to the time series nature
of the data actually splitting the data randomly into training and test sets doesn't really make sense
because since it's a time series data what you actually want to do is split the data using test as future
data and train as past data.
Previously we used C.A. tools to do a random split.
Here you would want to do a non-random split.
This is an optional assignment for this machine learning project to try to create this train test split
but we don't actually go into it too much since we're just starting off machine learning.
Later on we'll discover other data sets that are better for training and test split and will come back
to this and try to realize if we can use something that's not linear regression to make a better model
to fit this data.
All right.
That's a brief overview of what you're going to be doing.
Go ahead and get started the machine learning project.
I hope you enjoy it.
Take your time have fun with it and go as far as Long far along as you want to.
In this state a machine learning project.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture