Hello everyone and welcome to the function exercises solution's walk through video in this lecture.
We're going to be doing is walking through and explaining the solutions for the R function exercises
.
Let's go ahead and get started by jumping into our studio.
OK so here we are our studio.
I'm going to go ahead and get started by going to the first exercise question.
So in the actual exercises the first two examples were done for you.
So let's go ahead and jump to our first function which was create a function that will return the product
of two integers.
So this one's actually pretty simple we start off by just naming your function we'll call it pro-the
and assigning it with the key word.
Function well needs taken two arguments or two parameters will be number one and number two curly brackets
.
And this is where the code is actually going to be executed.
So we're going to say return on say return number one times number two and we can go ahead and test
it just by calling.
We'll say Prince Prod. will they will say three and four.
Go ahead and run the source.
We get 12 out check in one more time 120.
It looks like everything's working well.
All right.
Well that was pretty straightforward for you.
So let's go ahead move on to exercise too.
All right.
So the second exercise was to create a function that accepts two arguments an integer and the vector
integers.
It returns true if the integers present in the vector.
Otherwise it returns false and also a quick note to make sure you pay careful attention to your placement
of the return line in your function.
Let's go ahead clear the cons. expand our script a little more and begin to build out this function
.
First thing I want to say is the actual name of the function we'll call it name check for checking if
the number is inside of that vector and the caller function keyword.
And then we accept two arguments we'll say and U-M number for the number we're looking for and v for
the vector we're checking.
So basically we are just checking if that number is in the vector.
So we have to do is use a for loop to go through the vector and then check if the item or element we're
checking in that vector at that moment in time is equal to the number we're looking for.
So say for that said E L E for elements.
So for every elements in the vector if
the element really is equal to.
Now we turn true.
All right so what are we doing with this little for loop we're saying for every element in the vector
.
If the element is equality with the number then we just return true.
If none of this actually happens what we want to do is return false meaning if this elf's statement
never actually occurs will return false.
So at this curly bracket read outside of it are going to say return false.
So let's go in and run this and check to make sure it makes sense.
So say check 2 and then pasan of vector 1 to 3.
So this should return true.
We run it looks like I forgot to print the actual results.
Now let's run this and we return true.
Let's go ahead and get rid of the to make sure slow returns now should return false actually false.
So looks like the checks are working correctly.
Let's break it down so we can actually explain what's happening here.
So we say function nomine vector for every element in V.
If the element is equal to return true we have to be careful with as mentioned the last line is where
we actually put this return false statement.
So we want a place to return false statement.
Outside of this entire for loop and the way this function is actually going to work is if this condition
becomes true we immediately return true.
And that essentially just finishes the function once the function returns something.
It won't continue on.
What that means is if this for loop completely goes without returning anything then we return false
meaning there was no element that matched our number.
OK it's good to move on to exercise number three.
OK.
Exercise 3 was to create a function that accepts two arguments an integer and a vector of integers.
It returns the count of the number of occurrences of the integer in the input vector.
So it's pretty similar to the exercise we just did except now we're going to count the number of occurrences
.
So we're going to say this function is called Number underscore counts have the keyword function.
Same inputs as last time a number and a vector.
In this case what we want to do is count the number of occurrences.
So we'll start off with counts is.
And then we're going to go and say Is this for we'll say Elly in the so every element in that vector
if just like last time the element is equal to.
Now we're going to add 1 to our count.
So we're just going to say counts and reassign it to count plus 1.
And then finally after that entire four loop is done running will just return the value of the count
.
So let's go ahead and make sure this all works out by saying Prince name counts El pass in.
Let's say two and a vector will go in and pass a vector that has two 3 times in it.
So if you run the source we get three perfect.
Let's go ahead and remove one of these twos with one.
Make sure it doesn't actually get counted to looks good.
Let's make sure if we have no instances of that number it returns zero.
And there it is.
Let's quickly break the saddle one more time.
We're saying no count was name or a function function accepts a variable and u m which is going to be
the number and a vector v we count to start off as 0.
Then we go iterate through that vector and then we check every every element in that vector.
If the element at that particular instance in the vector is equal to the number we're looking for we
add once the counts and then finally after we run this entire for loop and we can check that by selecting
one of the curly brackets.
Notice will automatically highlight the curly bracket that it's linked to.
So once this for loops done completely we just return count meaning where there was no instance of that
number count stays at zero.
So we just returned 0.
Otherwise we actually just keep adding to counts.
Right.
Let's go ahead and move on to next exercise.
All right exercise 4 is a little trickier.
We want to ship bars of aluminum.
We're going to do is create a function that accepts an integer representing the requests that kilograms
of aluminum for the package to be shipped to fulfill these orders.
We have two types of bars.
One is a small bar with one kilogram of aluminum and the other one is a big bar with five kilograms
of aluminum each.
We want to return the least number of bars needed.
So it will return false if the required load cannot be created with the bars.
So for example 0.5 kilograms can't be created with those bars.
We won't worry too much about that return false requirement.
We'll worry more about the actual structure of fulfilling for the number of bars.
So a couple of the examples let's say the load required was six kilograms.
So that will require a minimum of two bars.
We can have one five kilogram bar and then 1 1 kilogram bar.
Then for instance the load is 17 kilograms acquires a minimum of five bars so we can have three five
kilogram bars and then two 1 kilogram bars you could have also filled out the six kilogram load using
six small bars.
But that's not the best way to do this if we're trying to minimize the number of bars.
So we have to figure out is a couple of things for the logic of our code and then I didn't write it
in some comment form.
We want to figure out how many five kilogram bars can we use because we want to maximize the amount
of five kilogram bars before we start filling in the rest of the gap with one kilogram bars and then
we want to say well how many 1 kilogram bars do we need to essentially fill that gap.
So how can we actually figure this out.
Well we can use the Mada capabilities or modular capabilities to figure out how many times 5 goes into
the kilogram package number.
So we really want to answer is how many times does five go into required load number.
Once we figure that out we'll know that the remainder
will be the number of 1 kilogram bars.
So let's go ahead and try to code this out.
So again I wouldn't say bar underscore count is the name function pasand function and we'll go in except
pack as the argument.
So pack represents that is the kilogram load to fill up.
Let's call it to start by just grabbing the remainder of how much the one kilogram bar number we're
going to need.
So we can say the amounts of one's
So that's the amount of one kilogram bars we need is going to be equal to the actual load modified.
So what that ends up returning is the remainder.
So for instance we're going to show you the cons. If I say 15 modified I get zero.
So that makes sense because if our package load was 15 kilograms I would only need three five kilogram
bars and I wouldn't need to fill in with any one kilogram bars.
Let's go in and say our package is 16 kilograms so we can already just tell by looking at this.
We should pack this with three five kilogram bars or three large bars and then fill in that gap with
one bar.
And the way we can figure out that gap is just by using that model function says it give us it gives
us the remainder.
So I want to go ahead and assign that to the amount of ones we need.
And then I just need to figure out the amount of we'll go in and say fives we need.
So the amount of fives is just going to be the total package minus the amount of once
divided then by five kilograms.
So what does that actually represent.
Well we'll know that the amount of ones is going to be the remainder.
So we're looking for that gap to fill and then we want the amount of five kilogram bars we can take
the entire load subtract that gap that we essentially already filled up and then divide it by 5 kilograms
.
Since every large bar in take five kilograms of weight and then we just return as our final answer.
So we're returning the amount of bars will return amount of ones plus the amounts of fives.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and test this make sure it works out.
So if I say Bahrke count 17 let's go in and print out the result.
Read the source we get five bars.
All right.
And that's really all there is for this particular function.
The main trick to this is figuring out this sort of logic that you can use this modular function or
maade function are really statements to percentage science to get the remainder value.
Go ahead and look at the arithmetic lecture in case you're a little rusty on this.
Let's go to and jump to exercise 5.
All right exercise five for exercise five.
We want to create a function that accepts three integer values and returns their sum.
However there's a caveat to this if an integer values evenly divisible by three then it won't count
towards the sum.
And we want to return 0 if all numbers are evenly divisible by three and there's a hint here you may
want to use the append function.
So there's lots of ways we can solve this problem.
I'll try to use the pen function along the vector to split out this function into as many steps possible
so it's really clear what we're doing along as we go.
So I want to create a function called summer instead of just saying SU M because I don't want to overwrite
the SU function that's built into our then we'll call function and we accept three integer values.
I'll go ahead to label them a B and C and then what I'm going to do is start off by creating our output
as a vector 0 and then as we go along what I'm going to do is check for a b and see if they're evenly
divisible by three.
I won't put them into this out vector.
If they are not evenly divisible by 3 then I will put them in.
And then finally one of them is just return the sum of that output vector.
So some outs.
So let's go ahead now and use if statements to check all of these integers.
So I may say if a mod 3 is not equal to zero
meaning it's not evenly divisible by 3 then I know it's going to count.
So then I'm going to go ahead and append this to our vectors and when I say a out.
So if in case you aren't familiar of a pen you can always just go to the council type and help append
search for it and it'll basically just tell you how it works.
So with adding elements to a vector and is shown example here again.
First argument is the vector to be modified and then values to be added to that vector.
Really easy.
OK so we have a.
And you can also reverse this order if you want outcome a.
And then we'll go ahead and say if and then we just essentially copy and paste this for the rest of
our two values.
So I'm going to go in and do that and then I'll change this to B and B and then C and C.
And then finally I return to some about what's actually happening here.
Again I created this initial vector with just eight values zero.
And then I'm going along for a b and c checking if to evenly divisible by three.
If they're not evenly divisible by three then they can go to the sum.
And so I append them to or out doctor and I do that for a b and c and then I just return the final Some
of that vector.
So let's go ahead and check this out.
So go ahead and call Prince summer and I'm going to pasan let's say 7 2 and 3.
So this should print out free run source 9 because we're adding 7 we're adding two but we're not going
to add three and same if I change this to 9 for instance.
It just so I output 9 because nines evenly divisible by three.
And if I have let's say 1 on 6 1 that should output 2 because 6 evenly divisible by three.
So it's not going to go to the final output.
All right.
And that's one method you could use for this function just going along using if statements to check
all of them appending it to a vector and then finally summing the output vector.
Let's go ahead to move on to the next function exercise.
All right so here we are at our final exercise which is a classic one to create a functional return
true with IMPA integers prime or otherwise return false.
There's lots of ways to solve this one Gronau we won't worry too much about certain edge cases like
checking negative numbers.
They can feel free to add a bunch if statements to check for that kind of thing.
Right now we're just going to be worried about the basic logic of this function.
So let's go ahead and start by creating a function called Prime check and the function just takes in
a number.
And what we're going to go ahead and do is the first thing we're going to check is if the number is
equal to 2 since if the number is equal to 2 2 is a prime number.
So we will immediately return true if that's not the case.
You can also start putting if statements for checking if it's a negative number or returning false etc.
.
We'll go ahead and just skip forward to actually cycling through numbers to check if it's a prime number
So a prime number is only divisible by itself or 1.
Meaning that if we were to say for x in two colon to numb minus one.
So let's think about what the statement actually is creating this creating a vector of integers that
goes from two all the way to the number right before the input number so minus one.
We know that if the input number maade x is equal to zero it means it's evenly divisible by a number
that is not either 1 or itself.
And in this case we want to return false.
It's not a prime number if that's the case.
Otherwise if we go through this entire four loop and that's not the case we can return true.
All right and that's the basic naive method of checking for a prime.
There's other more sophisticated methods of doing this.
And you can check out the links in these solutions note book and the explanations of solutions in a
book or some other more sophisticated ways of checking for prime numbers.
But this is the most basic way of doing this.
As long as you can get this then you're good to go.
So again we just have some checks at the beginning to check if it's a legit prime number or at least
an option to be checking for a prime number.
We just cycle from to all the way to right before the prime number if the number is divisible by one
of those numbers evenly equal to zeros all return false on prime number.
Let's go in and check to make sure this works we'll say prime.
Check our Passons 7.
Let's go in and print the results of this run that looks like 7 is true and we know 7 is a prime number
.
What if we do.
It's false.
That makes sense.
Basically any even number should return false.
So if we say this.
So this is false it's also not a prime number.
We'll have to check it on line.
But I believe it.
Let's do let's do a number that we know for instance ninety nine is divisible by 3 and 33.
So that's also false etc..
Right.
And that's basically how you can solve the prime check function in the most simple Knabe way.
Like I mentioned go ahead and check the solutions in that book if you want more info on other ways of
going about it.
OK.
Hopefully you are able to succeed in this functions exercise.
If not take your time.
This is probably the most programmatically intensive portion of this course as far as the way to think
in a logical procedure of a program created its functions for a lot of the course.
We actually won't be touching on this sort of thinking because data frames will do a lot of the stuff
automatically for us.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see it in its lecture