Hello everyone and welcome to the Arithmetike with our lecturer.
It's going to be a relatively short lecture just showing how to do basic mathematics with our let's
go ahead and jump to our studio.
All right so here we are our studio and we're going to be just doing really basic math.
We're just going to be using the console so don't worry about writing in our script for this unless
you want to keep a history of what we've done.
So go ahead and push the con. ups we can see it.
And let me go ahead and just show you how to do some basic arithmetic with our first off just edition
addition can be done with just a plus sign.
And then you can almost These are just as a simple calculator which is basically going to be doing for
this lesson.
Go ahead and click enter to run that and you have one plus two is three.
Again just the number and another number.
Cetera.
And you can do this with floating point numbers as well.
So that's numbers of a decimal in them.
You can see that the decimals are added up just as you would expect subtraction.
As you might have guessed it's just going to be a minus sign.
So do five minus three to notice that you're probably going to want to try your best to use spacing
for readability.
So here I would say five minus three is more readable in the second iteration than the first one.
First one kind of looks like just five space.
Negative three which is technically the same thing.
The way are is going to read it but you always want to make your code as readable as possible for division
.
Just going to be a slash.
So that's one divided by two 0.5 and the vision is going to perform what's known as true division.
So Ill perform division.
And keep in mind the decimals.
So the remainders etc. all right for exponents or to the power of you can use a little carrot symbol
.
So that's above the 6 on a keyboard.
So two to the power of three is eight.
And do say four it's the power for 256 etc..
All right well one other note is that order of operations is followed in are as you would just expect
to be.
So for example if I said a hundred times two plus 50 divided by two and put those together I get 225
.
So order of operations is followed.
Meaning I'm going to do 100 times to first to get 200 than 50 divided by two.
Since division is the next one up which is 25 and then 200 plus 25 is 225 if I want to actually specify
particular orders of operations I can use parentheses.
So for example I could say something like 100 times and with parentheses designate that I wanted to
actually add 2 plus 50 first and then divide right to accepter.
OK so everything's working probably as you would expect it to.
Just basic arithmetic.
The last operation I want to show is the motter modular operation which basically just returns the remainder
of a division.
So for example if I say five divided by two I want to get two point five.
So that means that two times two is four and I have a remainder of 1 right.
So by about about 2 is 2.5 if I actually want to get the remainder.
I can use the modulo operation which in R is two sets of percentage signs.
So that can be read as 5 2 and the remainder is 1.
And all this is doing is just returning in the remainder of a division.
So for example if I say 10 maade something like 8 I'll get two since a can only go into 10 once with
a remainder of two.
Since eight plus two is equal to 10.
So that's just going to give you the remainder in a division.
This is really useful later on for checking if numbers are even or odd or third divisible by a certain
number.
Cetera.
OK.
Hopefully those are all pretty straightforward.
You can just review this lecture or the notes for this lecture in case you ever want to reference what
the actual symbols or operations are for arithmetic.
OK that's it in the next lecture We'll talk about some basic data types in here.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture