Hello everyone and welcome to lecture and built in our features this lecture talk about a lot of the
built in features and functions in our how we can use to work with data structures.
Let's go out and jump to our studio and see how they work.
All right so here our studio and the features are functions we're going to be going over our SE Q to
create a sequence the sort function which will allow us to vector Rev which will reverse elements in
an object that's here to show us the structure of an object and append which will allow us to merge
objects together.
Let's go to get started with the first one.
CQ first sequence Swit sequence allows us to generate some sort of regular sequence and taken three
arguments.
You'll go ahead and start with where you want to start.
So let's say zero then you'll put in where you want it and it's going to say 100.
And then the third argument by is going to be your step size so we'll say by two actually it's going
to make this 10 so we don't get a huge output.
And now you'll notice we get the same thing as if we had written zero call and 10 except we're going
by 2.
This will allow us to generate sequences from a starting point and an endpoint really easily and jumping
by a certain numeric amount.
So another example will sequence 0 to 100.
In this case we'll say by 10 and now I can see I'm going from zero all the way to 100 and I'm jumping
by 10.
This kind of thing is really useful if in case you want to get for instance all the even numbers from
0 to 24.
So to do that I would say my starting point which is zero.
My ending point which is 24 and I would say by two and I've got all the numbers from 0 to 24 that's
as a cue it's really useful for creating sequences you want to learn more about it.
You can always just say help as CQ and through that line and I'll tell you more about how to generate
regular sequences and some more examples and details throughout the documentation.
OK.
So that's the basic usage of creating a sequence.
Let's go ahead and clear the console and talk about sort which will allow us to sort a vector.
Imagine I had the vector V and I'm going to put in some unsorted random numbers here so go at 1 4 7
2 13 3 and 11.
So I have my vector it's good on display at these kind of random numbers.
If I say sorts the I'll get an interesting output back I will get the sorted version of this vector
and I will get it in ascending order if I want to get it in descending order I can say sort the with
an additional argument decreasing equals false sees me decreasing equals true.
So false is the default.
If I say decreasing then I will sort it in a descending order.
That's really all there is to sort as far as sorting a vector.
If your vector is a vector of characters it's going to make C-v equal to a vector of characters for
instance b comma D.
A face shows C-v BDA face sort.
See the it will sort them in alphabetical order.
Now if one of these happens to be capitalized so we'll go in and say see BT A and I'll go ahead and
pasan a capital C in r.
As far as the sorting parameters it will go ahead and treat a capital C same as a lowercase c.
So for instance say it added additional capital a here and say sort C.v.
Ill put in the lower case first and then the capital first.
In other languages sometimes all capitals are sorted first and then the lower cases here are more or
less treat them equally in the sorting process.
So keep that in mind as you sort on a vector of characters.
All right.
That's it for sort.
Now let's talk about RMV which will reverse the elements of an object going to go ahead to re-assign
V to just be numbers one through ten if I call Ari V which is for reverse on that Dr. V I just get the
reversed output.
That's really all there is to it.
Es TR we've actually used quite a bit but it will show the structure of an object.
So first if I call on a simple object like a vector it will tell me that its integer vector has 10 elements
1 through 10 for a call on something a little more complex such as the built in data frame empty cars
.
It will show you observations of 11 variables meaning I have 32 rows of 11 columns.
Ill tell me what the kind of data types are in that column.
So for example the MPG column is a numeric data type and here are the first few numbers of that column
structure is really useful.
And so a summary summary especially is useful for data frames.
And again we've actually seen this in the past and it shows you Siskel summary of the various columns
.
Finally let's go over append which will allow us to merge objects together which works on vectors and
lists.
I'm going to quickly create a new vector will say it's 1 through 10 and I'm going to create a vector
the two which will be let's go and say 35 to 40.
So these went through 10 to 35 through 40.
If I wanted to merge these objects together I can just use append and passing those two objects as arguments
separated by a comma and as a result I get in return the appended version of those two vectors.
It also works on lists but it's the exact same thing you just pass in one list and another list you
put them together and append those lists.
OK that's really all there is to it for a append a few more things I want to show you that are useful
features in our is checking the data type and converting the data type of objects and our.
Let's talk about checking the data type Mi-Go to clear this.
We're checking data type and we're going to use is dot for that.
Notice there's a lot of outputs there.
So we're going to say vector is C one two three.
I can use the is dot notation to check if an object or a variable name is of a certain class or a data
type in our notice.
Our studio gives me a large dropdown of the various data types objects functions etc. that are available
to me in our.
So for instance I can say is vector pass in V.
Now we'll get a logical indicating whether or not that object is a vector.
So it's true it is a vector.
Maybe I want to check is data frame on V.
I will get a false sense of a vector not a data frame.
If I check is data frame on empty cars all get true.
And since empty cars actually is a data frame.
So the basic notation to remember is is dot.
And then you'll get a nice dropdown of all the various things you can check it check if it's a list
.
It's a matrix.
If it's an array there's any hazier data frame etc..
So that's the basic structure of checking for a data type.
Now you can use the as dot notation to try to convert it to another data type.
So for instance I have my vector v which is one to three I can say as dots and I get again a bunch of
results here but I'm going to say as Dot list.
Now what this is going to try to do is construct a list out of whatever you pass in as an argument.
So if I say as list for V notice I can output a list and it's in essentially iterate through each element
in the vector and convert it into an item in a list.
I can also say something like as Matrix pass in that vector it will convert it into a to then missional
matrix with one column and three rows.
That's really useful if you're trying to quickly cast or convert data types from one to another.
That's going to be the as dots and then whatever data type you want to try to convert it to the is that
is a method for checking the data type as that is a method for converting the data type.
OK so that's it for the lecture.
Again I hope you found that useful.
There are some really useful built in data functions that we went over including making a sequence reversing
sorting checking the structure and appending merging objects together.
And then this is that as are also going to be really useful is that is especially useful when you're
debugging your code.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.