Hello everyone.
Welcome to the decision trees and ran them for us with our lecture this lecture.
We're going to learn how to implement decision trees and run the course with our on an example dataset
.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to get started.
All right so here we are at our studio.
We're going to go ahead and do is install the our parts package that we're going to need in order to
create this trees in random force.
So go ahead and type in install the packages our parts are going to go ahead and jump to the finished
downloaded installation of this.
OK what's the our part library.
We're going to be able to build a decision tree model we're going to go ahead and show you the our part
library and the function when we go in and clear this console.
If you call Library our parts it will then allow you to use the r part function and call help on it
.
The our part function is what's going to allow us to build a recursive partitioning and regression tree
This is just a fancy way of saying good decision tree.
This our per function is we're going to be using to pass in the formula and pass in the data.
Like we've been doing before.
For other models let's go ahead and continue.
Hopefully you take the time to just browse through the documentation for our part.
But we're going to go ahead and run through the example that's in the note book for this lecture.
Let me go ahead and clear this.
We're going to be using the chi whosis data frame which has 81 rows and four columns.
Let me go ahead and shoot the structure of it.
It's built into our.
That way you can just go ahead and call psychosis.
And you'll notice that it has an age number and start the closest feature is the actual label indicating
whether proposed This is absent or present in catharsis is a type of deformation of the spine.
Then you have a page which indicates the age of the children in months.
So don't worry they're not 158 years old 158 months old.
These are relatively young people.
And then the number in the case the number of vertebrae involved because this is a deformation of the
spine.
And then the star is the number of the first or top most vertebrae operated on.
Let's go ahead and check out the head of this data frame
that we will notice we have absent and present the actual label the age in months of this child.
The number again of vertebrae involved and then start which indicates the number or of the first top
most vertebrate operated on.
And basically this dataset the way it came about is this is data on children.
They've all had a corrective spinal surgery and the label is whether the condition was present or absent
after the surgery.
And that's why we have the starts which in the case the number of the first or top most vertebrae that
the operation was started on let's go in and continue by just building a tree model off of this data
.
Everything's already correct.
They're all in integers and we have our label as a factor.
We can just simply call our model.
I'm going to make a variable called tree and call our parts in order to build that tree.
And then I pass in the formula in this case I want to predict the Infosys notice it's a capital K.
Now I want to predict Infosys absent or present off of all the features but tilde period comma I pass in
mephitic class because this is a classification.
And then I can go ahead and say data equals and here's why I passen lower case i Phasis the actual data
frame.
And now there's actually lots of functions you can use to examine your tree model.
Let me go ahead and jump to the notebook for this lecture to show you just a few of the examples.
All right here's the notebook and you have access to this.
There are lots of functions you can use to examine your model.
You can plot the cross-validation results.
You can just print the results you can actually plot the decision tree or label the decision tree plots
and you can even plot the approximate R-squared relative error for different splits and that creates
two watts.
However that's only appropriate for the Nova method where you try to do some sort of regression at time
series indels.
Let's go ahead and explore a few of these.
I'm going to go back to our studio right behind this.
I'm going to go ahead and print C.P. which will display ECP table for this and you just pasand the actual
model be called Tree.
Right.
And this is a classification tree.
It reports back to me that you use the variables actually used in the tree construction.
This case we used age and start the root node air meaning right off the bat.
What is our error when we do that initial split.
It's about 20 percent and then it gives you some more error information a lot of times you'll actually
just want to visualize your tree and you can actually plot out your tree.
You can say plots your tree or whatever the site it's called Decision Tree model and I'm going to put
in uniform is equal to true and Main is just the main title.
Go ahead and say Hi Folks this tree.
Go ahead and click enter and you'll notice you'll get an error if your margins are too large.
You're going to want to expand this first and then call the line
and notice if you just call plot.
You actually won't see anything which you have to do after that is called text as well
and the text function is going to add text to this going to and pass in tree Kessin used.
And as true and pass in all true and this just puts in labels into that decision tree.
There it is.
And the reason I did this in multiple steps was just to show you a few of the issues if you just call
plot and text off of that tree.
Couple of issues are you already need to have the plot window expanded then you need to plot the tree
and plot the text separately.
There's actually a much nicer library for this and it's just the our parts the plot library let me go
ahead and show you how to install it.
You can just go ahead and say install the packages.
And as a string say our parts dot plots and this is a much nicer library her plotting out this decision
trees going to go ahead and jump to the finished download.
There it is.
And let's go ahead and call Library our parts the plots and now we're going to do is just call the p
r p function and the PR P function is our part up plots way of plotting a decision tree and then just
passing your model is going to be a much nicer plot than what we've seen before and we can zoom in on
this.
And now this is really intuitive to interpret what's really cool about this.
It will show you what it split on and what the actual split criteria was and then what the classes fill
under this can get really awesome when you have a lot more features.
But just keep in mind if you have a ton of features this could get complicated.
But again a much nicer way of plotting these decision trees.
Instead of using the double plot and then text method you can just call the our part up plot library
and then call p r p on the tree.
That model we just built to get this much nicer plot.
That's what I highly recommend doing there want to plot out or visualize her decision trees.
Let's go ahead and move on to random force.
Remember that ran the Chloris improve predictive accuracy by generating a large number of bootstrap
trees based on random samples of variables classifying a case using history in the New Forest and the
sighting a final predicted outcome by combining the results across all of the trees and in classification
it's a majority vote of the trees.
Well we need to do is go ahead and install the random forest library or package go ahead and say install
the packages and then type in random capital F. forest and this is the package we're going to be using
for random forest.
All right.
Again go ahead and install that and then what you're going to do is just like the tree model we built
.
You can call ran the force.
Let's go ahead and say our F model ran the forest model then just call random forest let's make sure
we actually call the library ran the forest first.
OK.
Now it's called Let's actually start that again.
Our model ran them for us.
There's our function and this is going to take just like your tree then to take the formula.
Now this should be a capital K because it's the actual column name filled dots.
And then we're going to put in the data I Phasis that's the data frame.
And now let's go ahead and just print out the model and this will basically give us an estimate of the
error rates.
Let me go ahead and clear this and call it one more time.
Print R.F. model
in something I want to point out is that if you actually look at the documentation for random force
function you'll notice a list of arguments but also a list of values that are held inside a random force
.
That means there's a lot of components that you can actually grab out of this ran of course model since
this random force model is essentially just a list of components.
For example you want to grab the model put in the dollar sign and there's all these items in the list
call type predicted we can call predicted in a report back for each of these values would it actually
predict it when it ran the random forest.
The other information for instance a number of trees grown you can call your model or model and type
in and tree and it will tell you it grew it with 500 trees which is the default value of trees you can
possibly lower your error or misclassification rate by adding more trees but at a certain point adding
more trees is not going to help you a good way of deciding that it's like plotting out your number of
trees versus your misclassification rate and you can even do things like call the confusion matrix offer
your model.
And again this is just for the training data that it was trained on.
All right go ahead and explore all the different components that are inside the rain forest.
More likely in real life scenarios.
You're going to be using random force instead of just single decision trees.
Just because a random force is such a powerful algorithm and it's so easy to use implements Plus it's
really nice for distributed computing because you can just distribute some of the trees to one server
or some of the trees to another server and they're all in the pivot of each other.
That we don't need to communicate to each other until the aggregate the actual votes.
All right.
That's it for performing decision trees and ran them force in our hope those useful to go ahead and
check up the notes.
If you want more information on random force and the trees coming up next is your machine learning project
.
We're going to practice all of this.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture