Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture guide to using the plier.
This lecture will cover how to install the player as well as installing a data set and then we'll go
over various functions we can use with the player.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and get started.
OK so here we are our studio and the first thing we need to do is actually install the the player package
.
So then the player package actually one of the most popular packages for our.
And the way to install is just by saying install bot packages and it quotes inside the parentheses.
You're right.
D p l y r.
Go ahead and click enter.
And it should install for you.
I'm going to go ahead and fast forward to the end of the installation.
All right.
Looks like everything's successfully unpacked everything's checked.
We have a downloaded binary package great again.
All you have to say is install that packages the player.
Go ahead and put that appear.
OK you want to reference it later.
It's also in the notes.
Let me go and clear the console and next thing I want to do is actually install some package data.
So I'm going to go out and say install packages again and I'm going to specify N.Y.C. flights 13.
And this package is basically just a large dataset of a bunch of flights from 2013.
So I'm going to go out and click enter here in Sulla packages and again I'll go ahead.
Fast forward to the finished downloading and installation.
All right so he finished installing everything going to go ahead and copy and paste this line in case
you want to reference it later.
Again this is also in the notes.
So we installed the player package and we installed the dataset.
We're going to play around with this N.Y.C. flights 13.
Let me go ahead and do a control alt.
Clear the console and I'm going to get a call.
Library the player and tell me what it's attaching and I will go ahead and say library and why see flights
13.
Something to note here is when you say library the player.
You'll notice it says the falling objects are masked and that's these two functions filter and lag.
And the reason these two are masked as well as intersects set if set equal in union is because basically
the player is going to have its own filter function and its own lag object or intersect object that's
going to overwrite the default filter for our.
So just keep that in mind.
And I'm going to go ahead and clear this and just keep in mind that we had to call library the player
and library NYC flights 13.
So now that we have those two libraries called Let's actually take a look at this example data that
we just installed with NYC flights 13.
OK.
Since I previously called Library NYC flights 13 I can actually call flights and that will result in
a built in data frame.
What I'm going to do instead is just call head of flights so we can see what it looks like.
If you combine flights is quite a large data frame so you probably will want to call head or tail of
it.
All right.
So what does this actually look like.
We have a year column a month Day column and then some other columns just on flight information.
This flight information includes stuff like departure time schedule departure time the delay.
So the difference between your scheduled and your actual departure time same suffer arrival the carrier
.
So what airline they were on and a bunch of other variables actually aren't shown here since the state
of frame's too large Shusha everything such as flight the hour.
How long it would take the minute how long that it's a tail number origin destination etc..
So lots of information we can play with in this flight's data frame and that's the reason we're going
to be using it.
You want to get a better idea of what flights looks like it can go ahead and call summary on it and
this will show you a summary statistical summary of all the columns in that data frame.
Again we have some time information some departure and arrival information.
The caregiver information origin the situation air time distance etc..
OK.
So now that we get a feeling of what our data looks like.
Let's go ahead and learn how to use the player.
So if the player we're going to focus on a few key functions that allow us to easily manipulate our
data we're going to get a copy and paste them from the notes here.
So we have filter and slice arrange select and rename distinct mutate and transmute summerize and then
sample and sample frac.
Let's go ahead and work our way through all of these built in functions with supplier again you're only
going to be able to use these functions after you call library the player either in your script or in
the con..
Otherwise you may be using normal built in functions of our such as a normal filter which is why the
normal filter is actually masked now.
And we're going to be using the pliers filter whenever we call a filter because we imported library
to plier.
OK.
Let's go ahead and move on and actually show you how filter works.
So filter allows you to select a subset of rows in a data frame.
Previously we have been using the subset function in order to do this but it's actually a lot easier
to use filter the player.
So I'm actually going to just say filter and the first argument pass in is your data.
In this case it's flights.
And then you go ahead and just in column names.
And what the conditional statement you want to filter by.
So for instance I want a filter flights to happened in November so I'll say month equals equals 11.
And notice I put two equal signs because I'm checking for equality and let's say also want day to be
equal to the third.
So flights happened on November 3rd and let's go ahead and say carrier is equal to the character string
capital capitally for American Airlines.
And that's how filter works.
I'm going to go ahead and call ahead on this.
So they don't want the entire data to show up.
At least the inter filter data frame.
I just want the first filtered six rows and see what that looks like.
So again all we're actually doing here with filter is selecting a subset of rows in a data frame.
The first argument is the name of the data frame and the second and subsequent arguments or the expressions
or conditions that are filtering that data frame.
So here we select that all flights from American Airlines that occurred on November 3rd and you just
separate your conditional statements with a comma in between.
So hopefully you realize that this looks a lot easier to read versus a subset call.
Now a subset call is actually really similar but you would have to add a lot of logical operators such
as.
And statements in order to do this you could have also used fragen notation to do this sort of filtering
.
But again it also would have been a little more complex.
I'll go ahead and copy from the notes what the bracket notation for the similar commands would look
like.
So it would look like this.
And when we went in run this just to show you that it's the same output.
Well what's the difference here.
So with the player package we're able to just say philtre pass in my data and then separated by a bunch
of commas whatever the conditions I want to filter on are here using bracket notation.
I had to keep calling the data frame and the column using that dollar sign notation using some sort
of conditional statement and then logical operators to basically glue all of these together and then
finally a comma in order to call all the columns for these rows.
So this can get really messy if you want to filter on a bunch of columns while filter still always keeps
a clean readable syntax.
And this is the whole basic idea of the plier.
It makes these sort of operations easier and cleaner to read.
Let's go out and continue with the next function which is slice slice is going to allow us to select
rows by position 1 or go ahead and clear the con..
So filter allows us to filter out based on conditions slice will just return rows by position.
So you say slice passing your data this case its flights and then you just go ahead and pass in what
rows you want.
So for instance if I want the first 10 rows you pass in a vector of the slice of rows you want.
So there are then my first 10 rows and that's really the basics of slice just allows you store select
rows by position using the plier slice function.
OK.
And again you can check the notes in case you want a reference to all of these functions or you can
just say help the player and I'll also bring you a bunch of these helpful hints.
Now let's talk about the arr. function with the player arr. works really similarly to filter except
that instead of filtering or selecting rows it orders the rows.
It takes a data frame and a set of column names or more complicated expressions to order by.
If you provide more than one column name each additional column is going to be used to break ties in
the values of the preceding columns.
Let me go in and show an example of what I mean by that.
So again I'm only calling ahead because I just want the first six rows.
Otherwise the state of frame has so many rows it's going to be a huge output.
So I'm just going to call ahead on stuff.
OK.
So a range really similar syntax to filter except now instead of filtering we're going to order stuff
first argument.
As always you just pass in your data and now you just pass in the columns you want to order by.
So for instance I want to order by year then month then day and then let's go ahead and say error time
and if we see the output we see that well since every row in this data set or a data frame has 2013
for the year.
That's our first year notice months are all one's days are all ones and if we go to air time which is
right here we get order or excuse me that's actually arrival time.
Time is over here.
Not being shown.
So let's go ahead instead of saying.
Ordered by airtime will order by arrival times.
It's a little more clear.
Let's go in and show that we actually see the results.
OK.
Here it's really clear that we're ordering an ascending order 3 6 8 16 20 21 et cetera.
So again we just take a range pass in our data in this case flights and then the order that we want
to sort stuff by.
So I want to first order by year then order it by the month then by the day.
Then the arrival time and that's all there is to it.
If you want one of these columns to be in descending order you can just pass in the DSC function to
arrange in descending order.
So imagine I wanted to say arrange it by the year the month in the day but instead of sending arrival
time I want descending arrival time I just pass in D E S C for descending and pass that around that
column that I want to make descending.
And now we can see arrival time is in descending Ceasars of four hundred hours 23 58 etc. So that's
it for arr. we learned about filter slice and arrange.
Next one up we want to learn about is select going to go ahead and clear this data frame in order to
fit time limits.
We'll continue this in part to