Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on histograms and this lecture we're going to learn how to
create histograms with our.
And the G-G plot 2 package.
We're going to first start off with installing Gigia plot to will also install a dataset with related
the Gilia plot to called a cheesy plot to movies dataset.
And before we actually start coding anything I'm going to show you a great cheat sheet resource that
our studio provides for you for work and of G-G plot 2.
OK.
I'm super excited to show you all this.
So let's go ahead and jump to our studio.
OK so here we are our studio.
Let's go ahead and start off by installing the packages we need.
You're going to need to install G-G plot 2.
So the start off will just go to Head and in the console you can say installed packages in quotes.
Go ahead and pass G-G plot 2.
That should take a little while to dollar install so I'm going to go ahead and fast forward and jump
to when it's done installing.
Gonna go ahead jump now.
OK so it's finished installing.
Second thing we're going to need to do is go ahead and just copy and paste the slide and common to appear
in the script in case you need to reference it.
It's also in the notes.
Second thing I want to say is installed up packages and I'm going to go ahead and say cheesy plot to
movies
and that's going to go ahead and install the data set that we're gonna be working with.
Right.
That one's done.
Going to go ahead and copy and paste it as a comment appear in the scripts.
You can go ahead and positivity references if you need it.
OK so before we get started on actually coding out a histogram what I want to show you is jump to my
browser or your favorite browser real quick and find a cheat sheet that's going to be super useful for
working of cheesy plot too.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to the browser now.
OK so I'm here in my browser and I went ahead and google searched our studio.
Geez you plot cheat sheet.
So I'm zoomed in right now on the results.
But if you just google our studio use you plot cheat sheet the first link here should be the Ju-Ju plot
to cheat sheet developed by our studio.
So not that our studio developed just a plot to but that they created this cheat sheet.
Although Hadley Wickham does actually work for our studio.
So keep that in mind.
Anyway as we go ahead and jump to the cheat sheet we have a wonderful PTF cheat sheet to work with as
far as the different varieties of plots we can make with cheesy plot too.
And it gives you a couple of nice formulas to follow as far as creating your plots.
We won't have enough time to go over every single one of these plot types but we will go over enough
plot types where you can eventually just reference's cheat sheet or even the documentation or plot types
that you're looking for and know immediately how to create them.
OK so first thing we're going to do is a histogram.
So if we look throughout this cheat sheet right here we can see that we have a histogram method.
So if I go ahead and zoom in a bit Lotusphere center screen we have Jiya underscore histogram.
So our data and æsthetics layers are going to be really similar almost every single time.
We'll either have an X or an X and Y depending on what kind of plot we want to create.
But then after that we're really going to have to decide on is what kind of geometry layer we want.
And in this case you're probably reference's cheat.
Or the documentation and find the geometry layer that you're looking for.
And they have a nice little mini visualization here so you can reference like oh yes I want a histogram
since I'm looking for some sort of frequency plot.
OK.
Let's go ahead and jump back to our studio again.
Mix it down his cheat sheet and reference it and I'm going to go ahead jump back to our studio and let's
start plotting our history.
OK we made it back to our studio.
First thing we're going to do is call in the libraries and when I need G.G. plot too.
And then for the dataset I'm going to need a library to plot two movies.
Again there's no quotes it's recalling a library here.
Just keep that in mind first layer that we're going to create in our grammar of graphics philosophy
is the data layer and then the aesthetics layer.
So data and aesthetics is what we're going to look for right now.
So we start off by saying G-G plot and then the first thing we're going to do is pass in our data.
Now our data is going to be movies.
Movies is a data frame that comes with this Ju-Ju plot.
Two movies can go ahead and just put movies there or you can assign movies to ADF or some different
variable and pass in the variable here.
In this case we're just going to say movies nor for this to work you have to install and call it the
DZIEDZIC plot to movies dataset.
Next thing you want to do is aesthetics.
Now the syntax for aesthetics is a little strange because you're not adding it as a new layer.
You're actually putting it into the initial plot function.
So just keep that in mind and aesthetics is going to be whether you want X Y and what variables you
want for x and y.
So in order to get an idea of what we actually want to put in as aesthetics what I'm going to go ahead
to do in the console call column names on my movies dataset just so I can get an idea of the movie's
lips.
And the first thing I have to do like I mentioned before is actually call cheesy plot to movies.
The reason I have to call in the cancels because actually I haven't read the script yet.
OK.
So I call that now let's try that again.
All right.
So calling all the column names off of movies.
I have the title of a movie the year the length rating et cetera.
Let's go ahead and call head of movies.
Take a look at this.
So notice I have the title of the movie Sacha's $1000 touchdown or something.
Twenty one day once a month the center a climax show I have years that they came out the length of the
movie budgets a movie in this case a lot of these have Knolles.
They're the rating of a movie might be an interesting one for histogram.
So you can see kind of the frequency of ratings.
So I have my ratings column.
Let's go ahead and build the histogram off of the ratings column then go ahead and clear the console
so we can continue working.
So this case I'll say X equals rating.
I won't pass it.
Why.
Because if histograms were just going to plot out the frequency of a single feature or variable or column
in our data frame and in order to really put the idea of the layers of the grammar of graphics to good
use I'm going to assign this to P.L. variable.
So I have my state unaesthetic Slayer and then going to add in my geometries layer
geometry and then that layer will be P.L. plus G.
Underscore.
And if he just type GM underscore our studio is going to show you all your options for geometries.
There are a ton of options here.
So usually you have to either in your help search for Gian and you'll get a result that looks like this
.
And you can go ahead and check out descriptions of each of these geometry layers or you can reference
that cheat sheet that I showed you earlier it's good jump to it real quick.
So here's a cheat sheet I showed earlier and what you would do is kind of look around and say OK I have
one variable that I'm trying to plot.
It's a continuous variable because it's a rating.
So the ratings go from let's say zero to 10 continuously.
And I want to create a histogram.
So then I want to create a plot that looks like this and you figure out oh I need to do Jiya underscore
histogram.
Don't worry if you don't totally understand that yet as we go over more and more of these examples you'll
start to get really familiar as far as using this cheat sheet or the documentation to figure out what
geometry layer to call.
OK.
So we decided we'll call a GM underscore histogram as our geometry layer.
Let's jump back to our studio here our studio.
I'm going to go ahead and call a histogram.
I won't pass any additional arguments in the history.
For now let's go ahead and run the source here and if we go ahead and go to plot's you'll notice nothing
actually comes out.
Reason for that being that you have to actually print out whatever you actually want to plot.
In this case I want to say.
Plus GM histogram print that out is going to run source again.
And now we actually do get the plot.
So this is what the very basics of a histogram look like.
We have a continuous one variable plot that goes from zero to 10 and we have a histogram which is just
the counts so essentially showing the frequency of these ratings so we have maybe around 2000 ish counts
of I don't know seven point six ish ratings.
So the most common rating is around a six.
Now we can see that the least common orating are either zeros or it tends to make sense you don't have
perfect movies you don't have that many super awful movies.
Now we can begin to add arguments into our geometry layer in order to customize our plot.
So if we take a quick peek again at that cheat sheet or jump to it now we see we have additional arguments
such as been with.
Sorry about that.
We had been with equals five.
Maybe that's default etc that we can use x y Alpha color fill line type size weight etc. So we're going
to go ahead and do is play around with some of these extra geometry arguments and see how they affect
our plot.
Let's go in and jump back to our studio.
Notice in our studio when we actually printed out this plot we got a little statement here that sets
that been using Ben's equals 30 pick better value with bin with.
Now what that basically means is you can edit the width of these bins if you want to get more granular
information on these counts.
So we're going to go ahead and do just that.
I'm going to add the argument been with and we know that's an argument because we checked out that cheat
sheet and let's go ahead and say 0.1.
So that means I want every been in my plot.
So you have a width of 0.1 units and the unit in this case is rating.
Now let's go ahead and run the source and I can see I have a lot more Bins.
So now my information is actually clear.
Then last time last time we had 30 bins.
Now I can get a little more granular on that information of the history I'm going to get a better picture
of what's actually going on.
We can also begin to add things such as color and fill arguments into our geometry layer.
So let's go ahead and try doing that.
We had it been with.
If I say color equals I can pass in a string of basic colors.
So for instance I can say color equals red.
Let's go ahead and run that source.
And now you'll notice if you can make it out that each of the outside lines of this histogram is colored
red.
If you actually want to affect the fill color of this histogram you'll have to pass in fill.
So let's go ahead and add that in.
We might go to another line here.
So we'll say fill equals.
Let's go ahead and say pink and then make sure we have enough parentheses go ahead and run this.
And now we have a red outline for our color and our fill is pink.
So there's tons of arguments and keep adding to this geometry layer.
I'll show you one more common one.
And that's Alpha what the alpha argument allows us to do.
So all the way here on the right.
But what it allows us to do is set the transparency of our plotted data.
So if I set our foot equal to zero that means it's fully transparent.
So you see there's no more fill there.
If I set it to 1 which is essentially the default that means it's totally opaque.
So I can't make out the lines those grid lines behind the plot.
So actually I want to try to make out those grid lines.
I'll say something like 0.4 and now I can kind of both see the fill and the grid lines so that's Alpha
for transparency.
So these are going to be really common arguments with a histogram you'll probably specify the bin with
the color fill and then maybe some sort of transparency.
Now let's talk about adding labels.
So adding some more layers.
I'm going to go ahead and do is assign all of this to peel too.
So we have a geometry layer and then I'm going to say that line is getting kind of long.
I'll start adding stuff to appeal to for printing purposes.
So we get peeled to add in them to go ahead and add labels to this plot.
So right now the labels are defaulted to count and rading count because it's counting the number of
times each of these ratings show up.
And this rating is just because that was the name of the column.
We said X equals rating but let's say we actually wanted to set our own x labels and y labels maybe
even titles.
The arguments are going to add and this kind of goes with the coordinates or facets kind of layer.
We're going to say X L A B parentheses and then pass in a string of whatever you want the X label to
be.
So this case let's go ahead of person move the rating.
And then for y label it's going to be really similar are you going to say plus y L.A. B.
And then we're going to go ahead and say
well just say count to the capital C since that's essentially still what it is.
And now it's a sign all of this to P.L. three.
And then Prince P.L. three.
And the reason of doing all these assignments is just so you can easily read this.
So have data and aesthetics.
We go ahead and play around for geometry till we get something that looks nice to us and then we go
ahead and add X labels and y labels.
Let's try running the source see what it looks like.
I have an error.
Looks like I accidentally added a parentheses here.
Let me go in and remove that.
OK.
Now let's run from source.
There we go.
So if you can make it out here this access has been changed to a movie rating and the y axis is capital
C count.
Now just to show that it's really clear we'll go at it say my counts case.
It's too small c can probably see if I add two words there.
Run it.
Now I can see we have my counts.
OK we have a nice plot we have our own x label or on y label.
Let's just add a title to this plot.
So maybe you want an overall title appear on top of the plot the way you can do that is by adding G-G
title and then just passing a string.
I'll go ahead and just put in all caps.
My title run the source here.
And once the source is done running we can see my title has popped up in this new plot.
You can go ahead and go back and forth between your old plots by clicking on these arrows.
So just keep that in mind.
Finally let me go ahead and show you how you can actually save these plots.
So once you have a plot that you like you go ahead and click here on export and you can save this image
save us PDAF or copy to the clipboard.
This means if you are working with maybe some Excel data you just imported into our one to make a nice
custom plot in R and then maybe paste it back into a Word document or an Excel document.
You can either save it as an image save as a PDA or actually just straight copy to your clipboard and
then paste it into whatever document you're working in.
So you have some three options that are really nice free to work with and you can go ahead and clean
up your history of plots by clicking on this room here.
All right so what have we learned so far.
We learn how to create a basic plot which you plot the ever data and esthetics layer.
Then we have our geometry layer.
Again how do we find that geometry layer.
Well you can either reference the documentation or you can search that cheat sheet that I showed you
earlier.
We added some additional arguments to play around of her geometry layer including things such as color
fill Alpha for transparency and then we went ahead and added some x labels of X lab a y label y lab
and then a title of G-G title.
All right before we completely finished this lecture I just want to show you in advance æsthetics technique
that you can actually apply to the geometry layer in order to fill out your histogram based on the counts
or occurrence number of your y axis.
In this case.
So don't worry if you don't fully understand the syntax.
But I just want to see what's possible of cheesy plot and how cool it is going to go and come back here
to my geometer score histogram and I'm going to add h e s is going to affect the fill of the geometry
layer so I'll say æsthetics fill dot dot count dot dot and this kind of a special way to fill out the
color of your histogram based on the counts of the histogram.
So let's go ahead and run this from the source.
Now you'll notice that as my count gets higher here my blue color becomes lighter and as the count is
lower the blue color becomes darker.
So that's kind of a more advanced technique.
Don't worry if you don't fully understand this we'll go over these more advanced aesthetic techniques
later but hopefully you can see now just how powerful G-G plot is to make some really cool looking plots
.
OK this advanced technique is also in the notes in case you want to reference the code for it.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture