Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on data frame's selection and indexing.
And this lecture we're going to learn how to grab data out of our data frame.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to see how to do this.
All right.
So here our studio and I'm going to go ahead and just move the environment tabs and the file tabs to
the side so we can focus on the scripting and console.
Notice I'm going to be using the same data we used in a previous lecture.
This weather data of the days the temperature and the rain to go ahead and pass this as ADF going to
go ahead and run the source.
And now on a call if it's going to reveal that data frame.
Let's go ahead and learn how we can use this bracket notation we're familiar with to actually grab information
from a data frame when we were learning about Matrix indexing and selection of elements from a matrix
.
We learned that we could just say something like Matt.
And then the Rose who want it and the columns he wanted were actually going to be able to do the same
thing with data frames.
So imagine that we wanted everything from the first row.
We would just input row number one comma and then blank in the killing.
All the columns from the first row and that would actually return.
Likewise the first row of our data frame and notice how the labels of the columns are kept in the results
.
They can also do the same thing to get everything from the first column.
So I can say something like blank comma 1 instead of that square bracket notation and slow return the
days notice that the levels are included here.
Now something to note here is that one of the main points of using data frames is actually being able
to label your columns and your rows by some sort of character or string names such as days temp or rain
.
We're going to be able to actually index using those names instead of having to remember which column
numbers are which row numbers you want.
Let's go ahead and show how we can do this.
Going to go ahead and clear this.
We have our data frame.
Let's go ahead and select all range values from the rain column.
I can say Blinkx comma and then input the string rain instead of inputting the number three for the
third index column and that's going to return all the values of the rain call.
For example let's say I wanted to get the first five rows for days and temps.
Well I can say D-F if I want the first five rows That's actually all the rows in this case going to
go ahead in the use slicing notation here.
One colon five comma and then I want the columns days and temp.
So I want all five row values for the columns days and temp.
I can go ahead and pass and a vector is in the combined function with days and temp inside of it.
And there you have that subsection of the data frame with just those two columns.
We also have the ability to just grab all the values of a particular column.
Now we can do this in a couple of ways.
One way we can do this is by using the dollar sign notation.
So you put the name of your data frame a dollar sign and then the name of the column.
And you'll notice that our studio actually provides little clips for the column names.
So I can just go ahead and say days will return all the values for days.
The dollar sign and I begin to get the other column name option's temp etc..
We can also use bracket notation to do the same thing.
I can put India off and then just pass in a string of the column I want.
Notice how this is different though.
If I use the bracket notation I'm actually getting the data returns in a data frame format.
So I keep this index notation with the column days and the row number values if I use the dollar sign
format actually getting back a vector.
So keep that in mind when you're using this notation to callback columns completely.
All right.
Let's go ahead and learn how we can use the subset function to grab a subset of values from our data
Freyne based off some condition.
For example imagine I wanted to grab the days where it rained.
That means we want to grab the days where rain is equal to true but use a subset condition to do that
you put in subset you pass in your data frame source.
So in our case it's día.
Then you pass in the subset argument and you go ahead and pasand some sort of condition statement that
these conditions statements pretty much always use comparison operators.
And we want our condition to be rain is equal to true.
Notice that rain doesn't actually have to be a character string.
You can just put in range without any quotes and that's because subset knows that you're going to be
referring to column names in the court and subset.
If we go ahead and do that we get back a data frame where the values of rain was equal to true again
.
Notice how the condition uses some sort of comparison operator in the above case it was the equality
operator.
Equals equals.
Let's go ahead and show another example where we grab days where the temperature was greater than 23
degrees.
Again I say subset pass in my data frame source put in subset as my argument and then put in some sort
of condition.
This case I want temp column to be greater than 23 so return all instances where that's true.
And there you have it.
It's rows 4 and 5 and it's returned as a data frame.
OK finally let's learn about ordering a data from we can sort the order of our data frame by using the
order function you pass in the column you want to sort by into the order function.
Then you use that vector to select from the data frame.
Let's go ahead and see an example of this.
I'm going to make a variable called sorted temp.
I'm going to go ahead and call the order function and then Pessin ZF.
Let's go ahead and pasand DFA temp in if I call sort of temp.
All right.
Notice how I get back the index notation for the temp vector.
Basically what this means is it's the sorted temperatures by index.
So temperature 21 should be sorted first if you're going to sort them from least to greatest.
Then it goes twenty two point two and the remaining three were already in order.
Let me go ahead and show you how you can use this sort of vector to actually sort your data frame.
You would just go DMF pass in sort of temp comma and this will go ahead and sort your data frame by
those temperature values and you can notice now how these rows values were connected to sort of temp
.
When we think of what's actually going on here we're essentially just asking for the index elements
in that order and by default it's ascending.
You can also pass a negative sign to do a descending order.
Let me go ahead and show you how we can do that.
All say sending 10 order that a negative term.
Take a look at the ascending temp.
Now it's 5 4 3 1 2.
And when we pass that into our data frame the sending temp column or comics Scuse me because all the
columns.
Now we get a descending temperature again with this sort of notation.
All you're doing is you're basically just asking.
Give me back the rows of the data frame in this order 5 4 3 1 2 because you use the order function to
sort by temperature.
You also could have done this exact operation instead of using the bracket notation here by using the
dollar sign notation to show you a quick example that.
Let's go ahead and just say the sending temp order E-F.
Tim I will go ahead and put a negative sign up front that is sending and then we'll actually get the
same thing when we call for the sending as the data frame.
All right that's it for the basics of selection and indexing of a data frame in the next lecture.
We're going to be doing a complete overview of the various operations and capabilities of a data frame
.
Remember for the next lecture there's an entire notebook ready for you to reference almost as a cheat
sheet for use in data frames.
The next lecture is actually going to be one of the most fundamental lectures as far as learning how
to use data frames with our.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture