Hello everyone and welcome to the guide to our studio in this lecture which is going to be giving you
a tour of the various functionalities that our studio will provide when you're programming in our programming
language.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio now.
All right.
So here we are our studio.
And you'll notice we have various panes or windows open within our studio.
We have the console here on the left and we also in an environment and a history tab.
Sometimes the environment is also known as a workspace tap.
And here on the bottom right we have some files in this tab.
So let's go ahead and just explain these various windows and screens and show you what they do.
You may see some R code throughout this tour of our studio or if you don't fully understand it we'll
teach you all about our programming later on in the course.
Right now we're just giving you a basic feel for how to use our studio here on the left.
We have the cons..
So the council is where we can type direct commands and see output.
So we've actually already used this in the installation video.
We'll go ahead and show another example that can do something like Prince.
And you'll noticed you'll get a lot of helpful pop ups show up in our studio.
So as you begin to type functions that exist in our our studio that will automatically pop up suggestions
or auto complete code for you.
So here it pops up some information about the print function.
So go ahead and says something like print's it's arguments etc..
So we're going to do is do an open parentheses again you'll notice our studio automatically adds closing
parentheses in a file type in a single quote.
It automatically adds the closing quote and we'll just go ahead and say our studio is nice.
I'll click enter and since is a con..
I have directly typed the command and I see the output directly.
Now let's explore this environment tab right here.
So this is going to show all the active objects in my environment.
So what that means is I.
As I assign various variables values so I'll have a bunch of variable names and they'll have different
associated values to them or objects or data structures.
This tab is going to go ahead keep track of that.
So for example let's go ahead and start of a variable called a in a sign at the number 2.
Don't worry about this syntax will go over it in much more detail later on.
Basically here I'm just assigning to the variable a.
I go ahead and click enter and now in my global environment I can see that I have some value.
And it has been assigned to.
All right.
So here at the bottom right I have a file's tab so the spiles tab shows all the files and folders in
your default workspace as if you're just on either a PC or Mac window.
Also if you end up using plotting in our studio you can click here on the plot's tab and your plot's
will show up here.
The next tab which is the package's tab will list a series of packages or add ons needed to run a certain
process will get into packages much later on in the course.
So don't worry about them right now.
Here you have the help tab which is really useful if you have some sort of internet connection or a
downloaded the are resources or manuals needed.
You'll always find all the help you need throughout this helped including great resources for learning
.
Are are learning more about our studio.
OK so let's go ahead and explore the workspace a little more.
So again I have this environment tab which is going to store any object value or functions that I create
during my R session.
So in the example below I already created a variable A and assigned the number to just an integer.
But for example if I do let's go ahead and make a vector called the.
And don't worry about the syntax here and just showing this for example purposes I create a new object
.
In this case it's a vector.
And here I see more information about the different values I have existing in my environments.
You'll notice that right next to this environment tab.
I have a history tab and the history tab keeps a record of all your previous commands.
And this really helps when testing or running various processes.
Here you can either save the whole list or you can select commands you want and then send them to in
our script to keep track of your work when you're using our studio.
It's more likely that you're going to want to actually select a particular working that rectory here
.
I've already selected a working directory for this.
Our code will let me go ahead and show you how you could change a working directory if you wanted to
change your working directory for this particular session.
You just go to this session and this top tab and then go to set working directory and then you can choose
directory here.
A window will pop up and then you can go ahead and choose the directory you want to go ahead and Slik
cancels.
Since I'm already at the folder I want to be in so again go into session set working directory choose
their victory will allow you to change the working directory.
But you can also set a default or can directory that's directory that's going to default to every time
you open our studio.
You can do that under the Tools tab so you can go to Tools go to Options or global options and then
here you'll get a little options window pop up and then which you can do is go ahead and select a default
working directory and then you can go ahead and click Browse and choose the folder.
Make sheet click apply and then click OK.
If you ever want to figure out what directory you're in there's two ways to do this.
You can either just go ahead and check here under the files tab the directory or under.
It'll show you the path.
Or you can click here in the console and type G E T W D.
Close parentheses and that will get the working directory which is what.
There'll be the stands for if you click enter it'll show up as a response.
And there's my working there victory.
If you want to set your working directory or change or working directory directly from the console you
can actually use set W.D. parentheses and then type in the directory of wherever you want to set.
So you would just type in here the file path to whatever new directory you want.
I will go ahead and run that since I'm already at the directory I want and I already did it using our
studios graphical user interface.
Now when you're developing in our program or in our script usually you're not going to just input a
bunch of functions or commands directly into the console which you're going to be doing is working with
an R script.
So an R script is where are you going to basically keep a record of your work and be able to run multiple
commands all at once.
Now what you can do in order to start a new script is click here on this little icon and then go ahead
and select our scripts later on we'll discuss things such as are marked down and shiny webapps.
But let's keep it simple for now and go ahead and select our scripts.
Now you can see we have four windows.
This is what you'll almost always be using when you're dealing with our studio.
So you have the console window the workspace or global environment that history window over here on
the top right.
You have the files plot's packages isn't help when though here at the bottom right.
And here the top left you have your scripts here.
My script is currently untitled so our script is we're going to basically keep a record of your work
and be able to run a bunch of our commands all at once.
So maybe if you're coming in from another language such as Python you can think of this is just a dot
PI file.
All right.
Let's go ahead and see an example of using in our script to run some commands.
So I'm going to go ahead and type out some R code.
We'll just go ahead and use simple print statements saying the say print first line and then I'm going
to go ahead on the second line of code here and go ahead and say print.
Second line.
All right.
So here we have my our script.
Notice right now it's untile and not saved.
I go ahead and click this floppy disk icon.
It will save it and it will have to name it's going to go ahead and say this is Demo click Save it automatically
put the extension demo.
Are here for you.
So I have my script all ready to go.
You'll notice here I have a run which is going to run the current line or selection and then I also
have source which sources the contents of the active documents and in between those I have a rerun the
previous code but.
So let's go ahead and explore each of these buttons does.
If I select here I can go ahead and highlight or just have my cursor on the first line.
So print first line.
If I go ahead and click run.
Notice I just get here on my console which displays the output print first line.
It didn't run everything in the script.
And again if I have my cursor or if I highlight select the entire second line and then click run.
It's just going to execute where the cursor was on that line.
So it's only going to do one line at a time here.
So that's what the run button does.
It runs that either the entire selection you have.
So if you highlighted a bunch stuff will run it or just the current line.
Now if we go ahead and click here on the source you'll notice we get everything output.
So this is basically going to run the entire source script.
And in this case you can see here on the console we have first line second line and you'll notice here
that the command was source and then it just relays the entire path to that dot our code.
All right.
So those are the basics of our studio writing our scripts and using the history in environments windows
in our studio.
As we begin to learn more about the our programming language we'll explore our studios other capabilities
in more detail later on.
The last thing I want to discuss is setting up customizing the appearance of our studio.
So right now you'll notice the fonts pretty small.
So when I'm teaching everyone in this course what I'm going to do is actually make the font larger and
I'm going to go ahead and make the background dark instead of white.
So let me go ahead and show you how to do that.
You can just go to Tools Global Options and Global Options is the window where you're going to be able
to change pane layouts Appearance's packages etcetera.
So there's a lot of options here.
And if you just click on appearance here you'll have the option to choose your editor font and your
font size how much you want to zoom in.
And there's some example code here and I'll show you what it looks like.
So I'm going to go ahead and select the font to be a little bit larger.
And if you go ahead and select Ed. themes you can change the color themes for you.
So go in and select the theme that you like the best.
I'm going to go ahead and select mano Kai.
It's really similar to Sublime Text Editor if you're familiar with that text editor software and if
you want you can also play around with the font.
I'm going to go ahead and keep the default.
So let's go ahead and apply that make this a little larger at 16 apply select OK and you can see I have
changed the appearance of my scripts and my cons..
So choose whatever is most readable for you what you like the best.
Obviously that's personal preference.
All right.
That's it for this lecture.
Hopefully that was a nice little tour an overview of what you can do.
Our studio and how to use our studio.
So it's going to be our main development environment where we're learning how to program with our.
Don't worry we didn't understand all the art commands or our code that I showed in this lecture.
We're going to be covering all of that later on when we actually learn how to program it.
This lecture was just for showing and exploring the art studio development environments.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture