Hello everyone else can support vector machines project solutions part 2 video lecture in part one of
this lecture series.
We went ahead and got the data turned the features that were categorical into categorical data features
using the factor function and then we went ahead and explored the data of G-G plot 2.
Let's go ahead and move on to part 2 where we actually train and build our model ship to our studio
.
To get started.
OK here we are at our studio.
Let's go ahead and see that we've read the CAC data and that actually converted the columns into categorical
data.
The ones that needed to be categorical.
Now we can actually start building our support vector machine model.
The first step in doing this is to split our data to training and testing sets.
I'm going to go ahead and call the CAA tools library to do this.
I will set the seed to 101.
You don't have to do this but if you want your results to be just like mine you should go ahead and
do that then we will create the sample split you passin a column of your data frame.
I always like passing in the column or trying to predict.
And then you pass in your split ratio which in this case is going to be 0.7.
And then let's go ahead and make 70 percent of our data training data by taking the subset of loans
or sample is equal to true.
And then the tests will be the subset of loans where the sample is equal to false.
That's our train test split then we're actually going to train the support vector machine.
We do that by calling the e 1 0 7 1 library and then we just say model is going to be support vector
machine we pass in the formula.
We're trying to predict the not fully paid column based off of every other feature.
And then we'll indicate that we want this data to be our training data.
Then after that we'll go ahead and print a summary of the model.
Let's go ahead and run this.
Just a quick note.
Depending on the how fast you computer how much RAM you have and your CPQ these support vector machines
steps may take a while especially in the tuning phase.
So just keep that in mind here.
We've ran our model and it looks like we're using a cost of one and a gamma of zero point zero or 1
7.
Let's go ahead and see how well our model did by actually getting predicted values off of it.
We're going to clear the cons. I'm going to say predicted values I will call my predict function I pass
in my model and then I pass in my test data and I'm only going to pass in the test data that doesn't
have a label and that's going to be the columns one through 13 of your test data.
Then I just call a table on my predictive values
comma and then the actual not fully paid column.
The thing I was trying to predict.
All right if you did your same sample split with set seed 101 you got a table that looks something like
this.
And that's actually just really bad results.
Basically your model is predicting that everything was 0 for not fully paid meaning everyone fully paid
off their loan.
What we having an issue with here is that we're using the wrong cost and gamma parameter values.
This is where tuning the model is going to come into play.
We're going to need to use the tune function to test out different cost and gamma values in the previous
lecture not part one but the lecture for SVM with our we went ahead and showed you how to tune the model
.
Let's go ahead and do that.
All right.
To begin tuning our model we're going to go ahead and use the tune function.
I'm going to make a variable called tuned results called the tune function and I'll show you another
way you can actually use the tune function in the previous lecture with our and how do you support vector
machines.
We saw that we could put in train the X put in the features and that person train that y and put in
the labels.
You can also put in train the X and just person a formula.
That means I can say not fully paid cild dot and that's the formula for prediction and if you do that
then you know after actually passing training.
Why.
Which is kind of nice use whatever method you prefer.
I prefer the formula method since it's similar to how we actually train our models and the passenger
training data.
When we go in the case that I want the kernel to be the radio kernel
it then I will go ahead and search for ranges and then ranges is going to take a list of vector values
for the other parameters.
In this case we're looking at cost and gamma says this can take such a long time.
The pending on the speed of your computer.
I'm going to go ahead and just test two different costs values.
We'll go ahead and say 100 and 200 or something like that you can actually just put a good range.
We'll go ahead and just test this against gamma values and in this case I'm actually just going to test
against one game of values or point one.
You can go ahead and put in as many values here as you want.
Just keep in mind the more values you put in for this grid search of tuning the longer it will take
especially if you have a slower computer.
Then we will go ahead and print the summary of our tuned results.
Let's go ahead and run this.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to this tuned results and tune function grid search completing.
All right.
Looks like our tuning is done and went ahead and jumped.
This took a like about five to 10 minutes on my computer and I have a pretty fast computer so keep that
in mind.
If you have a slower one and you put in more values here it would still take a while.
Looks like our best performers were cost of 100 and a gamma of 0.1.
We're still getting about a 20 percent error rate which isn't so great.
Well let's go ahead and do a new tune into model with this cost.
And this gamma value is going to go ahead and copy these results so I can reference them you know put
them here in our script.
Let's go ahead and clear the council now and go ahead and say tune's model SVM going to go ahead and
pass in my formula.
Not fully paid.
Say that my data is equal to my training data.
And then I'm going to set my costs equal to 100 and my gamma equal to zero point 1
want to run that support vector machine and train it on my training data with those specific costs and
gamma parameters.
Once that's done you can go ahead and call a summary of our SVM and we can also start predicting new
values with this tune into model.
Right.
So let's go ahead and actually try to predict new values using this model.
We're going to go ahead and say tuned predictions is equal to predict where a person might tune's model
.
And then my test data.
And in this case I just want the actual feature columns not the label column.
And then once that's done I can call it table off my tune predictions versus the actual label which
was not fully paid column.
All right.
And it looks like we are now no longer classifying everyone as the 0 for the not fully paid column.
We're actually beginning to classify some of the ones correctly.
This still isn't such a great model but you can go ahead and calculate accuracy recant precision for
this model here that's been tuned.
If you really want to start getting a much better model support vector machines you'd have to tune for
a much larger array of cost and gamma combinations.
However that comes at the cost of just waiting a long time to test those various combinations through
your grid search.
All right let's go ahead and quickly review everything we've done and the second part.
We went ahead and did a train test split using C-8 tools.
We just said sample that split on the not fully paid column.
Took 70 percent of it said it as a training data 30 percent as our test data.
We called the e 1 0 7 1 library.
We went ahead and we first just trained the model without specifying the gamma and cause we just use
the default.
And when we reprinted that original summary of our model it was quite bad.
We were basically labeling everything in the not fully paid column as zero.
Then we used to we are a grid search to actually search and combine various values for cost and gamma
.
Once we did that we took the summary of the tuned results and reported back that out of the various
combinations we tried.
We basically tried to combos one hundred and 0.1 200 and 0.1 that the cost of one hundred and Gamme
of 0.1 were the best out of those two.
And then they went ahead and created a new model with those specific parameters that can take a while
depending on how many costs and gamma values you put in.
This is usually something you want to try to sync with going out to lunch or taking a coffee break though
where you set your tuning and grid search ready to go and you go out have lunch and come back an hour
later and the results are done for you.
All right.
I hope you enjoyed that project.
I will see it next lecture