Hello everyone and welcome to the conditional statements training exercise.
We've already learned about logical operators and if else and elses statements.
This conditional statements training exercise is here to test your knowledge of the previous lecture
.
Let's go ahead and jump to notebook and get a brief overview of the training exercise.
All right here I am at the conditional statements exercises notebook book this note book is Under the
training exercises folder and it's called conditional statements exercises for these exercises you're
going to use what you just learned.
But if else if else statements to answer the questions.
This first exercise is an example that's done for you.
In order for you to understand the format So for example if the question is write a script that prints
hello it's a variable x is equal to 1.
What you'll go ahead and do is set some variable and assign one to it and then for example using an
if statement.
We can check if X has equality with one equals equal sign.
We'll go ahead and say prints hello and then hello is printed because we set one to X..
You can go ahead and check make sure this actually works by setting X equal to 2 and then if you run
this statement you shouldn't actually see any printed.
Hello output.
All right.
This is a relatively short assignment.
There's only 4 exercise problems but hopefully it's pretty straightforward given what you just learned
.
The next lecture has a solutions walkthrough for these four exercises.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture