Hello everyone and welcome to the art data types lecture and this lecture.
We're just going to discuss some basic data types and our let's go ahead and get started by going to
our studio.
OK so here we are in our studio and let's go ahead and discuss some of the basic data types.
The first data type is the numeric data type and the numeric data type consists of decimal otherwise
known as floating point values.
So for example 2.2 is a numeric and I can assign something like a
2.2.
So this floating point numbers are part of the numeric class in R and integers which are natural or
whole numbers such as 5 or 7 are also part of the numeric class.
So you have this overall numeric class and then you have decimals or floating point values and integers
so those both fall under numeric class.
The next one we have is the logical and the logical class consists of boolean values which is true or
false.
So an R These are written in all caps.
So true or false or which you can also do is just in capital letters right t or death.
So for example I can't assign a CBT.
And you'll notice here it says a true.
So that's a capital T.
If I do a lowercase ill get confused and think that you're referring to lowercase t is some sort of
function.
So just keep that in mind.
It should always be either just a capital true or a capital C and likewise a capital F or capital false
so false in all caps.
And those are known as logicals.
OK so we've discussed numerics which are thus more floating point values or whole numbers.
Now we have logicals which are true or false.
And then we also have characters which are also known as strings.
So texture string values are known as characters and are.
And you can use quotation marks either double or single quotes to make a character string.
Let me go in and show you how we can do that.
So if I have something like hello and we've actually seen this sort of character string before we were
printing them out.
Hello world.
There's my strain.
I notice in the output you'll see double quotes here.
That doesn't mean anything it just means that this is a string.
Ok so you can use either single quotes or double quotes for strings.
Let me go ahead and show simple example.
We'll say is hello and then we'll also in double quotes we can say hello.
I encourage you to use double quotes because that's more common by convention but you can feel fine
using single quotes Assos work as well.
But again I would encourage the use of double quotes.
OK so let's say you have some sort of variable here we have variables A and B and you want to know what
data type they or you can use the class function to check the data type variable.
Later on we're going to learn a lot more about functions that had a constructor own functions buffering
.
Now you can think of a function as just having a name.
And here you can start seeing our studios built in help.
So our position is the simple generic function mechanism and it's going to be used to basically return
whatever data type class A variable is.
So for example we have a and we know it's hello.
So if I pass a into this class function so the function is the name and then to print CS and you add
an arguments inside of the predecease it's going to return what class it is.
So this is a character class and it's going to be the same for B also at character class so those text
string values are known as character classes and we can go ahead and check the classes of other things
so let's say 12 that's a numeric and we can check the class of 3 2.2.
That's also numeric.
So even though a 12 is an integer and 3 2.2 is a floating point or decimal number those both fall under
the numeric data type class.
And then finally we can go ahead and affirm that true is a logical and these are also sometimes known
as boolean values and we can do the same for f which stands for false.
MEMBER It's capital F and that's also logical.
OK so those are just some of the basic data types and are later on we're going to use these basic data
types to build on top of them as building blocks as we learn more about data structures in our.
And one of the most common ones we're going to learn about next is called the vector.
OK.
So you should have gone out of this lecture.
It's just how to check data type classes using the class function here and the three main data types
that we're concerned with right now.
The basic ones which are numerics which consists of decimals and integers.
Logicals which are those boolean true and false values and then characters which are those text and
string values.
Ok that's it for this lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next one.