Hello everyone and welcome to the conditional statements exorcized solutions walk through this lecture
we're going to be going over the solutions and programming them out or the conditional statements exercises
.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to get started right so here we are our studio.
The first example script was already done for you is just a very simple script to print Hello it's x
is equal to 1.
It looked something like this.
I just copy and paste in the notes but let's go ahead and move on to the exercise problems later on
we're going to learn about functions which is going to make organizing this type of code a lot easier
because here it's copied and pasted.
The first exercise which was to write a script that will print even numbers some sort of character string
if the variable x is an even number.
Otherwise print not even.
So let's go ahead and just assign some variable x and we'll play around a bit later on the check this
but to check if that number is even.
We have to know if we divide it by two is the remainder 0.
And the way you can check that is in this modulo capability.
So this conditional statement right here if X divided by two remainders equals zero then I can go ahead
imprints even number.
Let's go ahead and say even.
Else I want to print.
Not even.
And there we have it.
So let's go in and run.
This looks like two is even.
That's good.
Now let's go ahead and put in 13 Juno's odd.
Not even.
All right.
So pretty basic exercise to Kita this one's for isn't a trick.
Was just remembering that you can have this.
Essentially my capability to get remainders out you can go ahead and review the arithmetic lecture you
a refresher on that.
Moving along to exercise number two.
And to go ahead and clear this all right.
So jumping to exercise to want to write a script that will print is a matrix variable x is the matrix
.
Otherwise prints not a matrix.
And in case you need some hints you may want to check out.
Help is that matrix.
So I want to go ahead and just go quickly over these is dot methods work centrally if you want to check
if something is of a particular class you can say is dots and then notice our studio has a bunch of
dropdown options here in this menu.
You can say is dots and any sort of data structure or data type you want so you can say is that logical
pass in either the variable you're checking or that actual name of the variable So for instance is logical
true that returns true.
Passen an integer such as 12 will return false.
So that's the way you can use the method to check if something is a data structure or a data type that
you're looking for.
Sissons actually then quite straightforward.
I'm going to go ahead and make a matrix.
One quick way to do this just by creating an empty Matrix like so.
And then we'll go ahead and say if is dot matrix Has an x.
And notice that these is dot methods always return some sort of logical value.
So I can just leave this as my conditional statement.
So this is going to return true or false.
And then I'm going to go ahead and say print is Matrix else I'll just go ahead and print not a matrix
.
Whoops.
There you go.
So this should printout is a matrix.
Perfect.
And if I say X to be something else maybe a character string such as GWV.
Now if you run this we get not a matrix so that all worked out trick for this one.
It's just discovering how these methods work.
Next one is exercise three.
Let's go ahead and jump to it.
All right exercise 3 was to create a script that given a numeric vector x for length 3 it will print
out the elements in order from high to low and you must use if.
Else if and else statements for your logic.
So in other words you can just use a quicksort function the point of this script was just to get you
used to using a bunch of IF or else if statements in order.
So usually you would never actually program something that looks like this but this is just to get you
really comfortable with using if else and these other conditional statements.
So let's go ahead and start off with this is because again going to be kind of long and you usually
won't actually type something like this but this is just for practice.
So we want to do is systematically check which elements are going to be the first second and third highest
elements.
So essentially what I want to do is at the end of this mean going right at the very end of the script
I'm gonna say prints no going to use the paste function to paste together three variables first second
and third.
And what these variables stand for that we haven't actually created yet or a sign that we will is the
first Greatest the second greatest in the third greatest So the highest second highest third highest
.
Let's go ahead and start assigning these so we'll start by just comparing the first two elements.
And then we use indexing brackets to do this.
So I'm going to compare X-1 versus x 2.
So if x is greater than x 2 I'm going to assign first to be x 1 and then second to be x 2.
Else I'm going to do the exact opposite.
I'm going to go out and copy this save some time paste here but then just switch the numbers.
All right.
So that's assigning first and second.
And then we've got to start bringing in third.
Two it's.
So that's that script.
Taking care of the first two numbers.
And now we just need to compare the order with the third number.
So essentially if this was this would already be done if we just had a vector of two numbers.
So let's go ahead and add in our third number so when we say if the third number is greater than first
and the third number is greater than the second one and then go ahead and do is do assignments like
this on going to re-assign.
What's the third argument or th i.
To be second re-assigning second to be first and then re-assign first place to be that third element
.
So basically what this is saying is if that third element was greater than the first at one and greater
than the second one then basically shift everything over so that the third element is the first one
.
And then I'm going to have an ELSE IF statement which will be if the third element is less than the
first one ends if the third element is less than the second one.
The ones we already kind of ordered up then I already know the third element is going to be the smallest
one.
So I will reassign it to
x 3.
So that's essentially last place.
So I want to go ahead and put in some comments here before we finish up.
So this one is first and second place for these two.
This one is going to be if the third element's was.
We'll go ahead and say largest This is for third element was the smallest And if that's not the case
we'll then I know it's right in the middle since there is only three of them and I'm going to go ahead
and take care of that with just a simple S L statement and shift that third output to be actually second
and then second to be that third element.
So I know this is a little maybe confusing as far as the terminology here.
So you may want to just use a B and C instead.
If this T H I S C C F I R A variable choice for the names is a little confusing but hopefully the logic
here is pretty solid.
Basically what you're doing is just organizing the first two elements in first and second place and
then you just seeing where the third element should go.
Should it be the first one since is the largest.
Should it be the last one if it's the smallest or otherwise it goes in the middle.
Let's go ahead and run this.
Make sure it all worked out.
It looks like it worked out so I put in three 7 1 and an output 73 one perfect greatest the smallest
.
Go ahead and check out the notebook.
You want to reference this code again.
I'm going to go ahead and move on.
Exercise for exercise for jumping to it.
We wanted to write a script that uses if else if else statements to print the max elements and a numeric
vector with three elements.
All right.
Let's go ahead and see how we can do that.
Sorry no my input is going to be some sort of numeric elements.
We'll go ahead and say 10:21 and I want to find the max elements and I'm going to use if.
Else if an L statements so you could just use the built in max function but that would kind of kill
the whole purpose of this exercise.
So in this case I'm going to start off of an IF statement checking for this logic.
I'm going to say if the first elements is greater than the second one and if my first element is greater
than my third one go ahead and just print out the first element since that's the largest one.
So if the first element is bigger than the second one and the third one that I know is the largest.
So this should feel kind of similar to what we just did earlier and then say.
Else if.
If the second element is greater than the third one
printouts that element sent in the second one is the greatest.
Otherwise go ahead and print out that very last third element.
So why do I not have to check any more for the first element you may be wondering in this if statement
.
Well the reason for that is because I already checked that against both the second and third element
in that very first IF statement.
So it's essentially been clear and basically clearing each of those elements as they go along.
I clear the first number to check if it's the largest.
Then I clear the second number to check it.
If it's the largest And then finally if neither the first or second were the largest by default.
I know the third one has to be the largest.
Let's go ahead and run this it looks if we get 20 so that's good.
Let's go in and mess around the order of these Let's put one 2 three points up three.
Now let's put the largest in the middle we'll say one 100 two and it prints out 100.
So looks like the scripts are working and eased.
L if else if and else in order to do that in real life you would just see something like max of X. OK
.
Hopefully that was good practice as far as using if else and elses statements.
That's really the point of this exercise.
So usually you won't be writing such crazy scripts like this.
As far as arranging or checking max of elements in a vector.
But the idea of if else if an else is pretty important for programming in general.
So hopefully this was a good exercise to just give you a nice solid foundation in those concepts.
Okay.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture