Hello everyone and welcome to the regular expressions lecture in this lecture.
We're going to learn how to use OUR to search for patterns and tech strings or vectors.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio get started.
OK so here we are Studia and we're going to discuss how we can use regular expressions.
No question are familiar of the term regular expressions regular expressions basically just covered
the idea of pattern searching typically in a string or sometimes a vector of strings.
For now we're going to learn about two useful functions.
The first one is going to be Grapel G R E P L and the second one is going to be grep G R E P And they
basically just stand for general regular expressions so g r.
P.
OK.
Now let's go ahead and get started with an example.
I'm going to say a text.
Just some variable is equal to a string and I'll say hi there.
Do you know who you are voting for questionmark.
So now I have my text just a string and I want to be able to search for either certain terms or patterns
in my strings so I have two options.
This grep L or Grapel and then grette the difference between the two is one will return a logical grep
L for logical and the other one will return an index.
Let's go ahead and show you how we can use these sort of Grethel which is the simpler to what grep els
are going to do is it's going to take in an argument and the first argument is going to take in is the
term or pattern you're searching for.
So let's say I'm searching for the word voting or the pattern voting just that string and then the second
argument you're going to pass is the actual thing you want to search this case I want to search text
that object.
Let's go ahead and see this in a research.
True.
So that means that the pattern or term voting is inside of the text.
Let's go out and try another example.
Let's say a search for dog in text I get a false meaning.
That term dog or pattern dog is not inside that text.
And finally let's go and say crap logical or grep.
Well we'll go in and say do space you pasand text and it returns true because that little pattern do
space you is in inside of the text and that's the basic way we can pattern search.
True or false.
At least using grep L and using R.
Now let's you want to know where those actual terms were.
For instance imagine we have the vector V of character string.
So what's going to make them simple letters.
Let's say a b c d and I'll go ahead and add another D.
So I'm going to go and clear this.
And show me a vector v.
So the vector 5 characters.
If I search using grep L for the pattern B inside of my vector I actually get a vector back.
Notice that says false true false false false.
So it will return the index true wherever it actually found the pattern which is really useful.
Now another thing you might be interested in is finding out the actual index of where it is true that's
where that normal G RFP function comes into play.
The passing of the pattern we're looking for this case be the object we want to search the and then
no return the index where it occurs.
So B occurs at index 2.
So 1 2 years or B if it shows up multiple times for instance the letter D or pattern D so at multiple
times that vector will return all the index locations where that pattern occurred.
And that's really all there is to using grep L and grep in our studio or an our general again G R E
P L or return a boolean value indicating if it's the pattern you're searching for is in that text or
not.
So for example is hello in the text Hello world that returns true while grep will return index locations
.
So for example I'm searching for the term a in some vector that has b comma a get back index location
to insist that the second index.
For now that's all we'll discuss about regular expressions.
If you're interested in further use cases for grep or grep Well you can just go ahead and say help pass
grep enter and there's a nice piece of documentation concerning pattern matching and replacement.
So you go ahead and check this out.
In case you're already familiar of regular expressions and are trying to do a particular task in are
using regular expressions.
OK thanks everyone.
Now I'll see at the next lecture.