Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on to variable plotting with cheesy plot too.
And this lecture will show some examples of how you can compare two variables from the same dataset
.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and see how this is done.
OK so here we are our studio and the first thing I want to do is go ahead and call library Geez you
plot too and also call library to bring up the movie status that we were talking about earlier.
Cheesy plot two movies and let's go ahead and show you a couple of examples of how we can do two variable
Claudian with G.G. plot two.
First we'll go ahead and start off with our data layer.
So say G-G plot pass in movies since that's going to be the data set we're working with for data frame
are working with and then we'll have an æsthetics layer inside of that G-G plot call will say x is equal
to year and Y is equal to the rating column.
Let's go ahead and save that as a variable P L and then the geometry you're going to first explore is
the two d been chart.
So the to the bench or is g underscore been to D.
Let's go ahead and just check out what this looks like on its own.
So we'll go ahead and print out
this to the chart.
OK so taking a look at this plot we have a 2D bencher and basically what this means is we have two variables
on the x axis we have year in on the y axis we have rating.
And then this is almost serving as a bit of a heat map where the color indicates high or low counts
of ratings.
So that means not the actual rating value but the number of occurrences.
So the general trend we can see here is that there were lots of ratings between 5.0 and 7.00 in the
later years around what say 1990 or year 2000 ish whatever you can see this hotspot.
If we wanted to go ahead and change this color from the default Blues what we can go ahead and do is
add a scale field gradient argument to this.
So let's go in and do that.
We'll go ahead and call this Piel 2.
And after Geum underscore beento will say scale fill gradients and then for the scale fill gradient
what we can do is add high and low values so we can say high is equal to red although and say low is
equal to what you see green.
You can go ahead and choose that are values you want and let's make sure the prince sees our balance
.
This is getting a little unwieldy.
We'll go ahead and say this is pilt too.
So we assign this data set x and geometry it's appeal to and then we say Piel 2 plus this scale Phil.
I'll go ahead and then print this out.
So I'm printing that out.
We can go ahead and see probably in a much clearer picture where those high count values are for particular
ratings.
So that's the way you can affect the scale fill gradient of your to the bin charts and you can also
control the bin sizes in a GM underscore beento geometry or to the benchmark type which you can go ahead
and do is pasan a been with arguments and that accepts a vector.
So they use a combined function c and to show you an example.
Go ahead and pass in 3:01 as a vector.
And notice we end up getting a different ratio or different Ben size.
Here let me go in and make this sort of green will say blue.
So it's a little easier to see.
Hopefully as far as a change in size but that was due to the been with argument that we just added to
that geometry layer by default the been with are just one one.
So you can mess around and play with that in case you want to affect the bin sizes in case you don't
want just to the band with rectangular bins.
But you can end up doing is a hex plot which is really similar to this to the plot except it uses hexagons
instead of just rectangles.
So sort of saying in this geometry layer GM underscore been to the what you're saying is Jiya underscore
X and we can go ahead to leave everything else the same.
And if you get this error package hecks been required for stat then hex which you'll need to do is install
hex been as a package.
So I'm going to go ahead and show you how to do that.
You'll need a say install packages and pass in x been in quotes then it will install a package.
Download it for you.
And now you should be able to apply this Jiya underscore hex for some installations of our.
This will automatically be installed for you see may not need to do this line but I'll go ahead and
just copy and paste it here.
In case you need a reference later.
So again you may need to say install the packages hex men for line number seven in this case.
Actually call this geometer Estcourt hex.
Let me go ahead and clear the console and run this again.
And now we have a nice hex spend plot.
So if we go ahead and zoom in on this we can see the shapes of the hex bin.
Sometimes it may get messed up on this zoom in but usually that clears up when you actually export it
to an image or PDA.
So just keep that in mind.
Sometimes the graphics won't display the same in our studio as they will when you export it.
Just because there may be too many hexagons for it to properly display.
Finally the last to the variable plot.
I want to show you is the GM density to the.
Which is just to the density plot.
So that command if we go ahead and just show that basic one.
I'll go ahead and get rid of the scale filt gradients will so Geum underscore density to the let's go
ahead and run that
and you'll get an output that looks something like this.
If you go ahead and zoom in on it you can see that this is just a to the density plot with year on the
x axis and rating on the y axis so it's coherent close.
This zoom and that's really all there is to to the variable plotting.
If you're interested in some more options as far as plotting two variables against each other you can
go ahead and check out the cheat sheet we mentioned earlier in the section of the course so it didn't
jump too quickly now.
And here we are at this cheat sheet so you can check out again two variables.
If they're continuous by various distributions these are essentially the ones we just showed right now
.
If we go in and zoom in go to the right.
These are the different types of plots you can use for two variables and we essentially just showed
that to the bin plots the to the density plots and the hexagon plots.
All right so that's it for this lecture.
Hopefully by now you feel comfortable using the different layers and going to this cheat sheet and seeing
what options you have.
All right that's it for this lecture.
Thanks I'll see you at the next one.