Hello everyone and welcome to the our data frame's training exercise lecture and this lecture will just
get a brief overview of the training exercise for the art data frames section of this course.
Let's go ahead and jump to the data frame exercise notebook now.
All right here we are at the our data frame's exercises notebook for this exercise we're just going
to be testing your basic knowledge of data frames.
You'll go head to just follow the exercise instructions that are in bold here below.
For instance this first exercise you're shown the state of frame right here consisting of three rows
and three columns.
And I want you to recreate this following data frame by creating vectors and then using the data that
frame function and passing in those factors in the correct manner then you'll go ahead and just keep
performing other exercises to test your knowledge of data frames.
OK that's it for this state of frame exercise.
Go ahead and try it out.
Best of luck.
And then the next lecture will have a solutions through for this exercise.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture