Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on vector operations.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and learn how to work with actors and some basic operations.
OK so here we are our studio and what we're going to do is just perform some basic arithmetic with vectors
and do some other operations just to show you how they work within our.
So are going to go ahead and start off by creating two vectors.
The first one is just going to be a numeric vector one to three.
So use the combined function that see when to go ahead and aim at v1.
And then I will assign the two.
We're just going to say this once.
Five six seven.
OK.
So I have my two vectors.
Let's just go ahead and go over some basic arithmetic.
So for basic arithmetic what you'll be doing is an element by element operation.
And so what that means to say something like the one plus the two it's going to perform the operation
element by element.
So you can see here that 6 is 5 plus 1 8 to 6 plus 2 and tennis 3 plus 7.
And it's going to be the same for subtraction.
So I could say something like V-1 minus 2.
Notice I just get all negative force I could do against the two might be one positive force.
I can also multiply vectors element by element basis.
So the one times to Elby five times one six times two etc..
You can also do subtraction which I showed earlier as well as division.
So I could do the one divided by the two.
And that's going to perform element by element division.
Now let's move on to learn about some useful built in functions that are that we can use along with
vectors.
So as we've seen before with functions you basically have the name of your function some parentheses
and then you have some input.
So let's say you wanted to sum up all the elements in an American actor you can use the built in some
function.
So that will be su M and then you can just pass in your vector.
This case we have the one in all returned the sum for you.
And if you wanted to you could actually assign the output to some sort of variable.
So we could make a variable called let's say some of the C and A that as some one looks enter.
And now if we call some of that we get that six.
So that's a useful builtin function.
And now we're just going to show you a couple of more easeful built in functions for vector operations
.
So we've learned about some common function.
You can also do things like check the mean of the vector loops the one they'll return the mean you can
also do things like standard deviation.
You can find the maximum elements in a vector as well as the minimum elements in a vector and you can
do that or as built in operations in the last one I want to show you quickly is the ticket the product
of all the elements in the vector which is Parodi which just returns all the product the product of
all the elements in the vector.
So one times two times story is short for V-2 as well to 10.
So that's five times six steps seven.
All right.
So that's definitely not all the functions that are available that are built into our.
There's just some that are going to be using over and over again don't worry too much about memorizing
them now.
They'll come up often throughout the course if you want a reference for all the functions that are available
.
You can go to the link Crann that are Dasch project or org slash doc slash contrib slash shorts ref
card that PDA.
This link is also available to you in the notes for this lecture or you can just google search for our
reference card and this link should be in one of the top results.
Again you can look up any sort of our built in functions reference and there's tons of cheat sheets
online which are just nice reference cards for all the built in functions as we go throughout the course
we'll be using the most common ones over and over again.
So you probably will have to reference them too often.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.