Hi, welcome back.
In this chapter, we'll cover
the UX design process.
This is an iterative process in which we try
to understand the user, question assumptions
and redefine problems.
To find alternative strategies and
create innovative solutions.
The framework we use for this is called
design thinking.
You will learn how to understand and define
the needs of your users, how to generate lots
of ideas, and how to test those ideas by:
Observational research.
This helps to build empathy and define needs.
Visual sense-making.
To make insights tangible and visualize relationships
Rapid prototyping.
A fast and cost-effective way to test your
ideas.
Some of the world's leading brands, such as
Apple and Google, have adopted the
design thinking approach.
Design thinking is a different way of thinking,
in which the people affected by a solution
are central.
This leads to a deep understanding of those
people and the problem space.
Design thinking brings together what is desirable
from a human point of view with what is feasible
and viable.
Desirability means:
What is the solution your customer really needs?
Feasibility means: What is technically possible
within the foreseeable future?
Viability means: What is likely to become part of
a sustainable business model?
You can see design thinking as an innovative
way to solve problems.
It is extremely helpful in addressing problems
that are ill-defined or unknown by re-framing
the problem in a human-centric way.
At the same time, it is also a practical approach
to solving problems.
It focuses on developing many potential solutions
that are prototyped and validated to get it
right the first time.
It involves ongoing experimentation.
Design thinking is therefore not just a process,
it is a toolbox.
Design thinking is not new.
Throughout history, many designers have applied
a human-centric design process to create
meaningful and effective solutions.
Despite this, design has traditionally been
an afterthought in the business world, often
applied only to improve the aesthetics of
a product.
However, this has led companies to develop
products that do not meet the real needs of
their customers.
That's why forward-thinking companies have
moved their designers from the end of the
product development process to the beginning.
This people-oriented design approach proved
to be a differentiator and design thinking
was born.
To be able to apply this approach in large
organizations, it had to be standardized.
Herbert Simon sketched one of the first formal
models of this process in 1969 and it still
forms the basis of all design thinking process
models used today.
However, the specific term "design thinking"
was not coined until the 1990s by
David Kelley and Tim Brown.
They summarized methods and ideas that had
been around for years into one concept,
which has brought design thinking
to the business world.
“Design thinking is a human-centered approach
to innovation that draws from the designer’s
toolkit to integrate the needs of people,
the possibilities of technology, and the requirements
for business success.”
Today, there are many variants of the design
thinking process in use, and while they can
have different numbers of stages, ranging
from three to seven, they are all based on
the same principles as in Simon's 1969 model.
For this course, we will focus on the Norman
Nielsen Group's design thinking model, founded
by the pioneers of user experience:
Jakob Nielsen and Don Norman.
The model follows six phases: empathize, define,
ideate, prototype, test, and implement.
Let's go through the steps.
The first stage of the design thinking process
is to understand the problem you are trying
to solve, the users, and their needs.
This means consulting experts to better understand
the problem space and talking with users to
understand the human needs involved.
Your first step is therefore always research
to develop knowledge about what your users
do, say, think and feel.
Empathy is crucial for a
human-centered design process.
As well as immersing yourself in the physical
environment so that you can gain a deeper
personal understanding of the issues involved.
Empathy enables design thinkers to set aside
their own assumptions about the world to understand
users and their needs.
During the define stage, you combine all this
research and observe where your users' problems are.
You will analyze and synthesize your observations
to define the core issues you have identified
so far.
The next step is to define it as a problem
statement in a human-centered way.
By looking at your users' needs, their problems,
and your insights.
Organize all your observations and draw parallels
between your users' current experiences.
Identify unmet user needs.
Is there for example a common pain point across
many different users?
This will help you and your team members gather
ideas as you progress to the third stage:
Ideate
You have now gained insight into your users
from the empathy phase and you have defined
a human-centered problem statement.
During the third phase of the design thinking
process, you are ready to generate ideas in
ideation sessions.
Brainstorm a range of crazy, creative ideas
that address unmet user needs.
Give yourself and your team total freedom.
No idea is too far-fetched and quantity takes
precedence over quality.
Sketch out many different ideas.
Then share these with each other so that you
build on each other's ideas.
In the prototype phase, you will create representations
for a subset of your ideas.
The goal is to understand which parts of your
ideas work and which don't, with some inexpensive,
scaled-down versions.
This gives you insight into the impact and
feasibility of your ideas.
They can be shared and tested within the team
itself or on a small group of people outside
the design team.
This is an experimental phase and the aim
is to find the best possible solution to each
of the problems identified during the first
three phases.
So make your ideas tangible.
If it's a new landing page, draw a wireframe
and get feedback internally.
Change it based on feedback, quickly prototype
it again and share it with another group of people.
In the test phase, you return to your user
for feedback on your prototype.
Ask yourself, "Does this solution meet the
needs of users?" and 'Has it improved how
they feel, think, or perform their tasks?'
Because design thinking is an iterative process,
the results generated during the testing phase
are often used to redefine a solution.
At the end of this phase, the UX team will
have a better idea of how real users would
behave, think and feel
when they use your product.
This is the most important part of design
thinking, but it is often forgotten.
However impactful design thinking can be for
an organization, it only leads to real innovation
if the vision is actually implemented.
This sixth step is therefore crucial.
At this stage, it is time to put the vision
into effect.
To make sure your solution sees the light
of day and touches the lives of your end-users.
It is important to note that these six phases
are not always consecutive.
Design thinking is an iterative and
non-linear process.
The framework is there to simplify things,
but it’s the mindset and principles behind it
that really matter.
It should be treated more like a guide than
a manual.
They do not have to follow a specific order,
but can even occur in parallel and be repeated
several times.
New insights often make you jump back and
forth between phases.
For example:
After testing with your users, you can get
new ideas.
Or you have to go back and redefine the problem
or do new user research.
What else do you need to know about the user?
What new use cases have emerged from the prototype
that you haven't explored before?
A UX team continuously uses the results to
improve their initial assumptions.
It provides new insights so you can see alternative
solutions that may not have been available
with your previous level of understanding.
Let's zoom out for a bit for a better understanding.
You can place the 6 phases: empathize, define,
ideate, prototype, test and implement
in a general flow of understanding,
exploration, and materialization.
To simplify the process, we have represented
it as a linear process.
But in reality it is not.
This illustration shows you that it is a perpetual
loop in which you continually gain new insights
and improve the user experience.
And that is where the real power of design
thinking lies.
Each stage is intended to be iterative and
cyclical, as opposed to a strictly linear process.
So don't think of it as a step-by-step recipe
for success.
Instead, use it as a toolbox to support you
when and where you need it.
Be a master chef, not a line cook: take the
recipe as a framework, adjust as needed, and
adapt it to fit your needs.
Design thinking, as you have noticed,
is a powerful framework.
Let's summarize the benefits and why you should
use design thinking:
Design thinking puts people first and tests
assumptions and ideas with real users.
It immediately makes insights visual
It targets the right problem before going
into implementation mode.
It stimulates innovation by exploring multiple
avenues for the same problem.
It uses collective expertise and unleashes
creative energy in the team
Design thinking is often referred to as "outside
the box thinking" because it offers new ways
of thinking over the more general
problem-solving methods.
It combines a user-oriented perspective with
rational and analytical research with the
aim of creating innovative solutions.
Design thinking may look intimidating, but
it's not necessarily a lengthy process.
As design thinking requires a user-centered
approach, the amount of discovery you need
to do depends on how much or how little you
know about the problem and user at hand.
It's good to know that, despite the name,
design thinking is not exclusive to designers.
It is a design methodology that provides a
solution-focused approach to problem-solving
that can be used by anyone and belongs at
every level of business.
Let’s recap what we’ve
discussed this lesson.
Design thinking is a different way of thinking,
in which the people involved in a solution
are central.
This leads to a deep understanding of those
people and the problem space.
Design thinking brings together what is desirable
from a human point of view, with what is feasible
and viable.
In other words:
What is the solution your customer really
needs?
What is technically possible
within the foreseeable future?
What is likely to become part of a sustainable
business model?
The model follows six phases: empathize, define,
ideate, prototype, test and implement.
It is important to note that these six phases
are not always consecutive.
Design thinking is an iterative
and non-linear process.
They do not have to follow a specific order,
but can even occur in parallel and be repeated
several times.
So don't see it as a step-by-step recipe for
success.
Adjust it if necessary and adapt it to your
needs.
Join me in the next lesson where I will discuss
the first step of this process.
You learn to understand the problem
you are trying to solve, the users
and their needs.