Have you ever used a website or app that frustrated
you so much that you wanted to throw your
device out the window?
Then you know what it means
to encounter a bad user experience.
Almost everything you do in life is
a user experience.
The mobile payment for your takeaway coffee.
Or the reservation you make at your favorite restaurant.
Your friend's photo you like on Instagram
The car you drive.
The navigation you use to find your way
Or the Uber that you order
They are all a user experience.
Or in short UX.
Hi! Welcome to Learn UX Today.
My name is Ruben and I have been working as
a UX designer for over 20 years.
In this course I share some personal insights
and stories about my experience in the industry.
During this course, you will gain a thorough
understanding of the UX principles that come
together to create a user experience when
using a product or service.
Along the way, you'll learn the value UX provides
and which aspects to consider when designing
great user experiences.
Let's have a look at what you can
expect in the upcoming lessons.
In the first chapter, I'm going to give you
an introduction to UX.
I will explain what UX really is, the factors
that influence the user experience.
How the profession came to be,
the input needed for a good experience,
the different disciplines, and more.
In the second chapter,
we cover the UX design process.
In six lessons I guide you through every step
of the design thinking framework.
This is an iterative process in which we try
to understand the user, question assumptions,
and redefine problems to find alternative
strategies and innovative solutions.
In the final chapter, I'll talk about the
fundamentals that fall under the broad spectrum of UX
We cover usability, accessibility, user research,
cognitive psychology, information architecture,
content strategy, interaction design,
and visual design.
But first, let's start by explaining what
UX really is.
Simply put, UX stands for user experience.
It refers to any interaction someone has with
a product or a service.
It takes into account every element that makes up
this experience, how it makes them
feel, and how easy it is to accomplish
their desired tasks.
This could be anything.
From how a physical product lies in your hand
to how easy an online checkout process is.
It can be about all kinds of products
and services.
In general, however, the term user experience
design is used for digital products such as
websites, apps, and other digital interfaces.
Good UX ensures that customers use and enjoy
the experiences you designed.
Essential for creating
customer loyalty and goodwill.
A UX designer, therefore, puts the user at
the center of all considerations so that the
final experience delivers interactions that
are intuitive, useful, and enjoyable.
And that's essentially what
a good user experience is all about.
The top three questions every
UX professional should ask are:
Does the site or app provide
value to the user?
In other words, is it useful?
Does the user find it easy to use and navigate?
Is it usable?
Does the user like using the site or app?
Is it desirable?
If the answer to all the above is yes, then
you are on the right track.
Because user experience is such
an evolving concept.
It is difficult to provide a comprehensive
definition of the term 'user experience'.
The most used definition in the industry is
that of Don Norman, the pioneer, and inventor
of the term "user experience".
“User experience encompasses all aspects
of the end-users interaction with the company,
its services, and its products.”
As Norman points out, user experience is an
umbrella term that covers many different areas.
From interaction design to content design.
And it has interfaces with fields from
architecture to psychology.
This illustration can be very overwhelming,
but to think that you have to be an expert
in all these circles is of course absurd.
So don't see this as the only roadmap for
the entire UX design industry, but as an assumption
about why it's so complicated
to get good UX.
It's good to know which areas impact
the userexperience so you know
what tools are available to you.
The first requirement for a good user experience
is to meet the customer's needs.
And this goes way beyond giving
customers what they want.
Ideally, the user experience is designed to
avoid frustration and delays.
It’s seamless and effortless.
And the user understands what to do and how
to get where they want to go.
It's also good to know that everything has
a user experience.
It's not your job to create the user experience.
It's your job to make it a good one.
User experience is such a popular term in
today's digital industry
that everyone uses it freely.
Although building a product with an enjoyable
user experience sounds easy, is this where
most people are wrong.
So before we dive deep into the world of UX,
we need to debunk a persistent misconception.
We tend to assume that people who will use
the products we've designed are just like us.
When non-UX professionals speak of what they
believe is a better user experience
they often refer to their own experience.
While they only have one example of someone
using the interface… themselves.
And this is dangerous thinking.
The real people who use your product every
day are not like you, even if you are one
of them.
Your needs, problems and understanding of
the experience are not the same.
That's why it's important to always keep one
thing in mind...
“You are not the user” has become one
of the mantras of user experience
and for good reason.
We all make assumptions.
It's a very human, natural thing to do.
But, you can't learn anything about users
if you work with your own assumptions.
UX professionals always start with the fact
that they are different from their users.
Otherwise, we'll make generalizations based
on that one example...
our own experience.
Assuming you are your user is natural and
it is a misconception that is ingrained in
the human mind.
It's called the false consensus effect.
The false-consensus effect refers to people’s
tendency to assume that others share their
beliefs and will behave similarly
in a given context.
Only people who are very different from them
would make different choices.
So what can you do to overcome this?
First, acknowledge this bias
so that you are aware of it.
Second, talk to the people that
you're designing a product for.
And by this I mean real users, not your colleagues.
Know who your users are and test how they
respond to your designs by seeing them use
those designs.
When you do user research, you can provide
your users with the best solutions because
you have discovered exactly what they need.
So don't make assumptions.
Later in this course, you'll learn all about
researching user motivations and needs.
Now that we've got that out of the way.
What skills and qualities do you need to be
a good UX professional?
In other words, what does it mean to do UX?
A UX role can vary widely from organization
to organization, but they always demand that
they be the user advocate and put the needs
of the users at the center of all design efforts.
Whether you are a UX designer, UX writer,
or researcher.
The commonality between all UX roles is a
strong focus on users.
It involves a process very similar to doing
science.
You do research to understand the users and
the problem space.
You make ideas to solve the needs of the users
and the business, and you build and check
those solutions in the real world to see whether
they work.
I will show you in detail how this design
process works in chapter 2.
No standard background or path is leading
to a career in UX.
This course is hopefully your first step.
UX designers come from all walks of life such
as visual design, marketing, psychology, and
interaction design.
So what skills do you need to become a
UX designer or researcher?
UX professionals are strategic thinkers with
a conceptual approach to problem-solving.
They love the challenge of diving into data.
They understand the importance of every piece
of information and no means are therefore
left untouched during the research phase.
They know that the UX strategy is only as
strong as the data and research.
The best UX professionals typically share
certain qualities and attributes, including:
An ability to think both creatively and analytically.
A user-first mentality
Interest in technology
and how people interact with it
Strong problem-solving skills.
Strong communication and presentation skills.
The ability to articulate and discuss your
design decisions with clients and stakeholders.
Commercial awareness.
Understand business metrics and how your designs
contribute to performance.
Flexibility and adaptability
So much for the first lesson.
Let's recap what we've covered.
I started by explaining what UX really is.
Simply put, UX stands for user experience.
It refers to any interaction someone has with
a product or service.
It takes into account every element that is
part of this experience, how it makes them
feel, and how easy it is to accomplish their
desired tasks.
A UX designer puts the user at the center
of all considerations so that the final experience
delivers interactions that are intuitive,
useful, and enjoyable.
The first requirement for a good user experience
is to meet the user’s needs.
And it’s important to keep in mind that
you are not that user.
We all make assumptions.
It's a very human, natural thing to do.
But, you can't learn anything about users
if you work with your own assumptions.
UX professionals always start with the fact
that they are different from their users.
They are strategic thinkers with a conceptual
approach to problem-solving.
Before we dive deeper into the world of UX,
it's good to go back in time to see how the
UX field came to be.
And how companies have designed their products
with the needs of their users in mind.
I'll tell you all about it in the next lesson.