In this lesson, we'll discuss the early stages
of a design process.
But before investing time in a design thinking
process, most teams start with discovery.
A discovery is a stage prior to the UX design
process and always starts with a broad objective.
Because once teams have already decided which
product to build, it is no longer a discovery.
The discovery phase seamlessly transitions
into the empathize and define phase.
The first phases of the design thinking process.
The double diamond model introduced by the
UK Design Council illustrates this process
and you can see how it contains the same phases
as the first four steps of the design thinking process.
This model shows the two different problem-solving
approaches and shows the contrast between
the divergent thinking and the convergent
thinking approach.
A discovery starts broad and requires team
members to explore the problem space
in many different ways.
Divergent thinking allows you to generate
ideas and develop multiple solutions to a problem.
Convergent thinking is the opposite of divergent
thinking and focuses on achieving one well-defined
solution to a problem.
This happens in the define phase, which we
will discuss in the next lesson.
The steps ensure that we do not jump into
creating solutions prematurely, or with biases
and assumptions.
Through this approach, the team focuses on
the issues that will have the greatest impact
on that outcome.
Well-executed discoveries ensure that any
solutions proposed later are desirable to users,
viable for the organization, and achievable
with the available technology.
What to do during the discovery phase?
Discoveries are best made with multidisciplinary teams.
Depending on the size of the problem and the
activities, the number of people involved
and the type of roles can vary.
There are many different types of activities that can be
performed, but these are the most common ones.
With exploratory research you learn new things
about a domain and generate new, open insights.
By conducting this research, you will learn
more about the problem space.
Commonly used research methods include user
interviews, diary studies, focus groups, and
field studies with a representative group
of users.
We’ll discuss more about conducting user
research in chapter 3.
Stakeholders often have unique knowledge,
insight and data about internal processes
behind the scenes and about the users who
interact with them.
Stakeholder interviews provide an additional
layer of insight that helps the team understand
the magnitude of the problem and also the
feasibility of subsequent solutions.
During the discovery, the team works with
stakeholders to understand the overarching
business goals and desired outcomes and get
answers to questions like:
"what do we want to achieve?"
or 'what does success look like?'
Workshops align team members and stakeholders
and are a useful tactic for discovery.
The type of workshop is very dependent on
the problem.
Some workshops that are commonly used in discovery
are a kickoff workshop at the beginning to
create alignment, problem-framing workshops,
or service-blueprinting workshops.
At the end of the discovery, the team has
a detailed understanding of the problem.
And the results it should pursue.
The end of a discovery can also be a
decision not to proceed with the project.
For example, if there is no user need.
The discovery phase transitions into the first
phase of the design thinking process: 'empathize'.
It is the first step towards thoughtfully
designed products that prove that the designers
built with a compassionate eye for their users.
Understanding the user is arguably the most
crucial step in UX methodology.
Without a good understanding of the user,
the solutions you create have a high chance
of failing.
But this can be a deceptively challenging
process.
Many companies think they know a lot about
their target customers, but the UX process
requires you to understand users at a level
of detail often overlooked by marketing managers
or business owners.
Empathy is the ability to understand other
people's feelings.
It's about becoming aware of what other people
are feeling and sharing their emotions.
It serves as a way to connect yourself and
another.
When you say "put yourself in someone else's
shoes," you are referring to empathy.
Empathy is often confused with sympathy.
While empathy involves sharing another person's
feelings or emotions by putting yourself in
their position.
Sympathy is about showing concern or compassion
for someone else.
In this phase, design teams conduct research
to gain personal insight into the needs of
their users.
It is important to set your own assumptions
aside, and to gain insight into the world
of the users by observing and consulting them.
Only in this way can you really understand
the experiences, motivations and problems
of users.
Empathy is therefore a crucial skill for increasing
user satisfaction.
Simply put, empathy allows designers to better
understand users, because you can relate to
them and their emotions.
So to empathize is to research.
You need to become completely objective before
you can see through the eyes of your users
and interpret their points of view.
To do this you have a range of options.
The first option is interviewing users.
The most fundamental user research method
for the UX design process is the
one-on-oneuser interview.
It is important to ask open questions and
not guiding questions.
Also, try to listen unbiased instead of focusing
on points that confirm your beliefs.
A second option is to observe or shadow real
users.
You observe these users while they try to
solve an issue with your design.
Even more effective is observing users in
their natural environment.
This often yields additional insights beyond
what is revealed in a standard user interview.
Video journals and diary studies.
With this method you ask users to record or
write down their own experiences
in approaching a problem.
These may capture their pain points more accurately.
Another option is online surveys.
If you are redesigning an existing website,
polling current users for their feedback provides
great insight on what works and what doesn't.
And the last option is immerse.
This means put yourself in the shoes of your
customer and try out your own product in a
real situation.
Or that of the competition.
It's great for building contextual knowledge
and empathy.
These are just a few methods.
We'll discuss more methods in
our user research lesson in chapter 3.
To understand people and connect with their
experiences and problems, you need to be an
empathetic observer.
How do you do that?
Empathy in research is not something that
can be taken for granted, but it is a skill
that can be cultivated.
As you approach your research,
you’ll need to:
Let go of your ego.
In other words, it's not about you.
To understand and empathize with your users,
you need to let go of your assumptions and
biases.
Instead, focus on your users' thoughts,
feelings, and experiences.
Embrace humility.
You may be an expert in your field, but that
doesn't mean you know everything.
Practice humility while observing your users
and learning about their experiences.
Be open to the fact that
you can learn from them.
Be humble enough to accept new perspectives.
And consider solutions you would not have
thought of on your own.
Actively listen.
Good listeners put aside their assumptions.
Don't interrupt or discourage your users.
Instead, let them finish their thoughts so
that you can understand their perspective
and experience.
In the next phase of the design thinking process,
you will synthesize the results and define
the problem.
One tool to help you record your lessons from
this stage is to create an empathy map.
An empathy map is a visualization of the
attitude and behavior of the users.
It helps teams to have a shared
understanding of user needs.
In doing so, it also reveals any holes in
the existing user data.
As their name suggests, empathy maps simply
help us build empathy with our end users.
Once created, it should act as a source of
truth throughout the project, protecting it
from bias or baseless assumptions.
Traditional empathy maps are split into
4 quadrants: say, think, do and feel with the
user in the middle.
The Says quadrant contains what the user says
out loud in an interview or other survey.
Ideally, it should contain direct quotes
from research.
The Thinks quadrant captures what the user
thinks throughout the experience.
What is important to the user?
What keeps the user busy?
Pay special attention to what users think,
but may not be willing to say.
Why are they hesitant to share?
Are they insecure, self-conscious,
polite or afraid?
The Does quadrant contains the actions that
the user takes.
What does the user physically
do from the survey?
How does the user work?
The Feels quadrant is about the emotional
state of the user.
Ask yourself: what worries the user?
What does the user get excited about?
What does the user think of the experience?
So how do you create a valid and actionable
empathy map?
Start by drawing this diagram on a whiteboard
or in a digital tool.
Gather the research you will be using.
Empathy mapping is a qualitative method, so
you need qualitative input such as user interviews,
field studies, diary studies
or qualitative surveys.
Based on the research, each team member writes
what strikes them, and adds it to the corresponding
quadrant on the whiteboard.
For instance, in the says quadrant you can
find quotes like:
“I don’t understand what to do from here.”
“This is too expensive.”
“I was expecting something different.”
The Thinks quadrant captures what the user
thinks throughout the experience.
For example,
“This product seems confusing.”
“Or this looks good”
“Do they think I’m stupid?”
“I wonder if there’s a better alternative.”
In The Does quadrant you put actions that
the user takes.
Such as
Refreshes the page
Search for an alternative
Walks away from product
And the Feels quadrant is about the emotional
state of the user.
Overwhelmed: too many options
Impatient: pages load too slowly
Worried: they are doing something wrong
When everyone is ready, the team collectively
go through the stickies on the board and group
similar notes that belong to the same quadrant.
The activity of clustering facilitates discussion
and alignment.
Which outliers are there?
Which themes recurred in all quadrants?
Which themes exist in only one quadrant?
What gaps are there in our understanding?
You may see inconsistencies, ambiguities or
overlaps between notes in the quadrants.
For example, apparently positive actions but
also negative quotes
that come from the same user.
These are important signals to look out for
as they can be very valuable in learning more
about the user.
If you don't have anything to put in a particular
quadrant, it's a strong signal that you need
more user research before moving forward with
the design process.
Keep empathy maps "alive" by reviewing and
adapting them as you do more research.
The information from the empathy map, also
helps you to create or update your personas
and customer journey maps.
As we discussed in chapter 1, in the lesson
about UX inputs.
To create these types of maps you must do
user research.
Otherwise these are not based on anything
and have no value.
You’ll learn more on doing
research in chapter 3.
Empathy requires practice, but as you cultivate
empathy in your design thinking, you’ll
be a more effective UX professional.
Let’s recap what we’ve discussed
in this lesson.
I started by showing you the double diamond
model which shows the contrast between the
divergent thinking and the convergent thinking
approach.
Through this approach, teams focus on the
issues that will have the greatest impact..
Discoveries are best made with multidisciplinary
teams.
We discussed some common activities that you
can do with your team during a discovery phase.
The discovery phase transitions into the first
phase of the design thinking process: 'empathize'.
Empathy is the ability to understand other
people's feelings.
To put yourself in the shoes of the user.
To empathize is to research.
You need to become completely objective before
you can see through the eyes of your users
and understand their points of view.
To do this I have shown you a range of options.
Empathy in research is not something that
can be taken for granted, but it is a skill
that can be cultivated.
I gave you three tips to do this.
At last I have shown you how to create an
empathy map, to help you record your lessons
from this stage.
Once you have a good idea of who your users
are and, most importantly, their wants, needs,
and pain-points, you’re ready to turn this
empathy into an actionable problem statement.
Which I will show you in the next lesson.