Once you've empathized with your users.
You can move on to the second phase of the
Design Thinking process: the define phase.
Here you get a clear picture of exactly what
problem you are trying to solve for the user.
You then work this out into a meaningful problem
statement that will function as your northern
lights during the design process.
This is perhaps the most challenging part
of the Design Thinking process.
It requires you to synthesize your observations
about your users from the first stage.
The relationship between the empathize and
define stages is best described in terms of
analysis and synthesis.
In the first phase, we used analysis to break
down everything we observed and discovered
about our users into smaller,
easier-to-understand components.
For example by creating an empathy map.
In the definition phase, we piece these
components back together to create
a detailed overall picture.
We organize, interpret and give meaning to
the data we have collected to formulate a problem.
This is called synthesizing.
A problem statement identifies the gap between
the current state and the desired state of
a process or product.
You can see the user problem as an unmet need.
By designing a solution that meets this need,
you can satisfy the user and ensure a pleasant
user experience.
A problem statement frames this need in a
way that is feasible.
It gives a clear description of the problem
you want to tackle, with the user at the center
at all times.
Without a well-defined problem statement,
it is difficult to know what you want to achieve.
It is also difficult to explain to stakeholders
and team members exactly what you are trying
to achieve.
A meaningful, actionable problem statement
will therefore steer you in the right direction
during the ideation process.
Here are some tips that will help you create
a meaningful problem statement:
Focus on the user: The problem statement should
be about the people you are trying to help.
Not about technology, product specifications
or business goals.
Concentrate on the user's perspective.
Keep it broad: A good problem statement should
not focus too narrowly on a specific implementation.
It prevents you from exploring areas that
may offer unexpected value or new insights.
A good problem definition therefore leaves
room for innovation and creative freedom.
Make it manageable: On the other hand, don't
try to address too many user needs in one
problem statement.
It then becomes too overwhelming,
while it also has to give direction.
So give it sufficient constraints to make
the project manageable.
So how do you define a problem statement?
There are four steps you can follow.
One of the first steps in defining a problem
statement is to organize your findings from
the empathize stage.
A popular method is to collect all observations
and findings in one place to create a collage
of experiences, thoughts, insights and stories.
They call this: Space saturation and group.
The term "saturate" describes the way the
team covers the space with their collective
images, notes, observations, data, experiences,
interviews, thoughts, insights, and stories
to create a wall of information to support
the problem-defining process.
Second, you group these findings to explore
which themes and patterns emerge.
It is then possible to connect the dots and
to develop new and deeper insights that help
define the problem and develop possible solutions.
In other words: go from analysis to synthesis.
The best way to get to the heart of the problem
is to look at it from multiple angles.
By answering a few basic questions, you can
formulate a better definition of your problem.
With all your findings from the empathy phase
in one place, ask yourself the following four
questions: who, what, where, and why?
Who is experiencing the problem?
Start by defining your target user, their
needs and motivations, and how they interact
with your product.
What's the problem?
What are the pain points that emerged in the
empathy phase?
What task is the user trying to accomplish
and what is standing in the way?
Where is the problem?
What space, situation or context is the user
in when confronted with this problem?
Physical or digital?
Are other people involved?
This will give you a better understanding
of the context.
Why is it important to solve this problem?
This question is perhaps the most in-depth
of all four questions.
You will be asked what it would mean for your
user if the problem were solved.
Another question-based strategy is the five
whys technique that can help you get to the
root of the problem.
It involves asking a first question and then
asking "why" for each subsequent answer.
Once you've identified the root cause, you'll
have something to focus on.
Take as an example a working professional
who wants to eat healthy, but has difficulty
with it.
With the five whys you can find out the cause
of the problem.
The first question could be:
Why isn't he eating healthy?
- He orders takeaway every day.
Why does he order takeout every day?
- The refrigerator is empty.
Why is the fridge empty?
- He hasn't been grocery shopping for a while.
Why hasn’t he been grocery shopping?
- He does not have time to go to the supermarket.
Why doesn't he have time?
- He works long hours and is exhausted.
The root cause why our user isn’t eating
healthy is a lack of time.
So you now know that your solution should
focus on efficiency and convenience.
A great format for writing a meaningful and
useful problem statement is a Point Of View.
It defines who your user is, what their needs
are, and any surprising elements or insights
you've gathered from your research.
You articulate a POV by combining these three
elements: the user, their needs
and your insights.
An example might be easier.
If we continue with the example of our busy
professional who likes to eat healthy.
Then you could define the problem statement
as follows:
“Busy working professionals need an easy,
time-efficient way to eat healthy because
they often work long hours and don’t have
time go grocery shopping and prepare their meals"
In the define phase, you start with "Why"
to find out how to solve a design challenge.
By asking this several times you get to the
heart of the problem.
You can now work backwards from that abstract
statement by asking 'how' for each statement.
This is called the Why-How Laddering technique.
You can now start using your problem statement
by asking a specific question
that starts with: "How might we?"
These are questions that have the potential
to trigger ideation sessions such as brainstorms
and should allow you to come up with many
possible solutions.
Your ‘How Might We’ questions help you
move from the define phase to the next phase
in design thinking, the ideation phase, where
you look for specific innovative solutions.
For example:
How might we make preparing meals easier?
How might we best present healthy options?
How might we make grocery shopping faster?
At the end of the define phase you have converted
your findings from the empathy phase into
a meaningful problem statement.
Let me summarize what we covered in this lesson.
In the define phase we organize and give meaning
to the data we have collected to formulate
a problem.
This is called synthesizing.
A problem statement identifies the gap between
the current state and the desired state of
a process or product.
I showed you some tips to help you create
a meaningful problem statement.
And the steps you need to
follow to define one.
The best way to get to the heart of the problem
is to look at it from multiple angles.
By answering a few basic questions, you can
formulate a better definition of your problem.
Like asking yourself the following four questions:
who, what, where, and why?
Another question-based strategy is the five
whys technique that can help you get to the
root of the problem.
It involves asking a first question and then
asking "why" for each subsequent answer.
Once you've identified the root cause, you'll
have something to focus on.
A great format for writing a meaningful and
useful problem statement is a Point Of View.
It defines who your user is, what their needs
are, and any surprising elements or insights
you've gathered from your research.
Finally, I showed you the why-how laddering
technique.
To help you move from the define phase to
the ideation phase,
With your problem statement at hand, you are
ready to move on to the ideation phase and
generate as many solutions as possible.
Join me in the next lesson,
where we'll cover this phase.
Often the most exciting stage in the
Design Thinking process.