In this lesson, we are going to cover the
factors that influence user experience.
When we talk about UX, the term user interface
design or UI for short will come up.
But, it is good to realize that despite being
often used mixed together, UI and UX are two
different things.
Although the user interface of a product is
of course an important part of the user experience.
It's not the same.
It is a subset of UX.
Like UX is a broader part of the total customer
experience and service design.
They are all sides of the same coin.
UI focuses on how a product's surfaces
look and function.
UX focuses on what the end-user encounters.
Customer experience or CX for short encompasses
all interactions a person has with the brand.
While service design at the end of the spectrum
focuses on how the internal parts of the organization
are aligned to deliver that experience.
To explain the difference between UX and UI
more clearly.
UI refers to the actual interface of a product.
The visual design of the screens through which
a user navigates on, for example, an app or website.
UI designers handle all the visual and interactive
elements of a product interface.
Which includes everything from typography
and color palettes to animations, transitions,
fonts, colors, all these sorts of things.
They don't necessarily have to create the
blueprint for the product or understand exactly
what the user needs
or the business goals are.
That is the role of the UX designer: research
these goals and bring them together to what
the product could be.
Take, for example, a travel website where
you can book an overnight stay.
Even if the UI for finding accommodation is
perfect, the UX will be bad for a user looking
for a private hotel room in Amsterdam,
if the underlying database only contains
bunk beds in hostels in the UK.
Both UX and UI designers focus on usability
and improving the user experience.
UX and UI go hand in hand and product interface
design has a huge impact
on the overall user experience.
But UX professionals don't just focus
on creating useful products.
All too often UX is confused with usability,
which describes how easy a product is to use.
While it's true that UX started out as a usability
discipline, UX has evolved into
much more than usability.
It also focuses on other aspects
of the user experience.
We must also distinguish between UX and usability.
Usability is a quality attribute that assesses
how easy user interfaces are to use.
The word "usability" also refers to methods
for improving ease of use
during the design process.
By this definition, usability is a quality
feature of the user interface.
A very important aspect of UX, but the total
user experience is an even broader concept.
A UX designer is concerned with the entire
process of acquiring and integrating a product.
It is a story that begins before the product
is even in the hands of the user.
Products that provide a great user experience,
such as the iPhone, are designed not only
with the use of the product in mind.
But also with the entire process of acquiring,
owning, and even troubleshooting it.
So usability and user interface are important
aspects, but UX design covers many other areas
as well.
In the first lesson, I showed you the three
fundamental aspects of a good user experience
that are well known in the industry.
A good user experience must deliver
on three promises
Is it useful?
Does the site or app provide
value to the user?
Is it usable?
Does the user find it easy to use and navigate?
And is it desirable?
Does the user enjoy using the site or app?
Peter Morville, a UX pioneer who has written
several bestsellers and advises many
Fortune 500 companies on UX,
has expanded this model even further.
According to him, seven factors influence
the user experience.
Morville ranked the seven factors in the "User
Experience Honeycomb", which became a famous
tool for understanding UX design.
As you can see, this model includes the
3 basic requirements of UX that we discussed
earlier but has been expanded to include
four other key components.
Let's take a closer look at each factor and
what it means for the overall user experience.
We'll start with the one we mentioned earlier.
Usability has to do with how easy a product
is to use.
With functionality that is intuitive.
For example, a car without a steering wheel
is not very useful.
At least for now, until everyone
has a self-driving car.
Poor usability is often associated with the
very first generation of a product.
With the introduction of the personal computer,
with mouse and graphical interface, it became
usable for ordinary people.
The Macintosh wasn't the first computer, but
it was the first, at least in a UX sense,
to be useful to everyday people.
Or what about the first generation of MP3
players, which have lost their market share
to the more convenient iPod.
We'll talk more about usability in
Chapter 3.
If a product is of no use to anyone, why would
you want to market it?
Sounds logical, right?
If it has no purpose, it is unlikely to compete
for attention alongside a market
full of useful products.
The experience should be useful in every way
and should provide content, features, or functions
that meet the general user needs.
For example, an e-commerce website might include
the ability to see if a specific product is
in stock or not, a very useful feature.
It is worth noting that "useful" is in the
eyes of the beholder.
Things can be considered "useful" if they
provide non-practical benefits.
For example, playing a video game might be
useless to you, but it can be super helpful
for a teen to let off steam after
a busy day at college.
Good UX designs enable experiences that are
desirable or even delightful.
Thus, the solution not only offers useful
features that are easy to use.
But also in a way that appeals to the user,
for example with great visual design, content and copy.
Desirability is reflected in the design through
branding, image, identity, aesthetics, and
emotional design.
The more attractive a product is, the more
likely the user who owns it will tell about
it and arouse desire in other users.
When a user buys a product online, it should
be so engaging and enjoyable that users are
likely to come back again.
Or share the positive experience with others
with their family and friends.
Findable refers to the idea that the product
should be easy to find.
If you can't find it, you won't buy it.
Time is precious to most people.
Findability is therefore essential for the
user experience of many products.
Imagine you are reading a newspaper and all
the stories were placed in random order.
Instead of being organized into sections like
sports, entertainment, or business.
You would find reading the newspaper a very
frustrating experience.
Findability is essential for the user experience
of many products.
Credibility refers to the user's ability to
trust the product provided by you.
Today's users don't give you a second chance
to fool them.
They can and will leave your website or app
in seconds unless you give them a reason to stay.
Especially if there are enough alternatives.
It is impossible to provide a user experience
if the user thinks that the creator of the
product is a lying clown with bad intentions.
Worse, they will also share this negative
experience with others.
For example, by leaving a negative review
to warn potential customers.
Unfortunately, accessibility is often forgotten
or an afterthought when creating user experiences.
Accessibility is about providing an experience
that is accessible to all users.
So also for people who are hard of hearing,
who have learning problems, movement disorders,
or who are visually impaired.
Designing for accessibility is often seen
by companies as a waste of money.
The reason for this is the persistent misconception
that people with disabilities are a small
part of the population.
According to research from the United States,
at least 19% of people had a disability.
This number is likely to be higher in less
developed countries.
That's one in five people who may not be able
to use your product if it's inaccessible.
It's also worth remembering that when you
design for accessibility, you often create
products that are easier for everyone to use.
Not just people with disabilities.
Finally, accessible design is now a legal
requirement in many jurisdictions, such as
the EU.
Failure to provide accessibility in designs
can lead to fines.
So don't neglect accessibility in the
user experience.
Later in this course, we will therefore devote
an entire chapter to accessibility.
Finally, the product must deliver value.
It must deliver value to the company that
creates it and to the user who buys or uses it.
Without value, a product's initial success
is likely to be undermined eventually.
Designers should keep in mind that value is
one of the most important influences on
purchasing decisions.
This brings us to the end of this lesson.
Let's recap what we learned in this lesson.
I showed you that UX and UI
are two different things.
It is a subset of UX.
Like UX is a broader part of the total customer
experience and service design.
They are all sides of the same coin.
We also discussed that UX is too often
confused with usability.
While it's true that UX started out as a usability
discipline, UX has evolved into much more
than usability.
It also focuses on other aspects
of the user experience.
So the success of a product depends on more
than usability.
Products that are also useful, findable, accessible,
credible, valuable, and desirable are much
more likely to succeed.
These are the 7 factors that influence the
user experience.
Join me in the next lesson where I cover what
input is needed for a good user experience.