If you've done some reading about UX,
you've probably come across the
term information architecture.
Or simply: IA.
Information architecture is one of
the most fundamental components within UX.
In this lesson, we'll cover the basics of information
architecture and the main things you need to know.
What is it? Information architecture is how you
organize and present your content to the user.
So that they can find everything
they need without great effort.
You can find it in websites, apps, and other
digital products, but also in the physicalworld.
Such as libraries, museums, and shops.
A well-structured information architecture
makes it easier for visitors to find what they
need and use it to achieve their goals.
Trustme, it's not always easy.
As you'll soondiscover, there's a lot to think about.
As consumers, we are used to
finding exactly what we need,where we expect it.
And what happens if we don'tfind it?
We give up in a few seconds and move on.
Disorganized content makes navigation difficult.
Users can get lost and irritated.
Eventhe most beautiful design fails withoutthe right IA.
Your user experience is only
as strong as your information architecture.
Famed UX designer, Jared Spool, once said:
“Gooddesign becomes invisible when it's done right.
It's when it's done poorly that we notice it.”
The same goes for IA. If everything is in order,
it becomes invisible. If a user experience has a
weak underlying information architecture, the
overarching user experience is bound to fail.
A good IA is the foundation of any user
experience. If something is easy to find,
it is usually no coincidence. It's the
result of extensive user research and testing.
Let's look at common methodologies
and how to follow a good process.
According to Peter Morville and Louis Rosenfeld.
The authors of the leading book:
Information Architecture
for the World Wide Web
a website's IA needs to address
different user needs.
They distinguish 4 main types of needs:
Known-item seeking: Users will come to the website
to search for something desirable and known.
Exploratory seeking: Users will come to the
website looking for inspiration.
They’re lookingfor something desirable
but not sure what exactly.
Exhaustive research: Users are in the process
of extensive research. They want to
find as much information as possible.
Re-finding: A user needs a desired
item again and is trying to find it.
When thinking about information architecture
it’simportant to think about the different users
andhow they will
navigate, search, or use filters.
Think of an e-commerce website. If you’re looking
for a new dress for a party, you might want to
filter by style and by color. But if you’re aftera gift,
you might want to see some curated giftideas.
If you know exactly what you want, you want
the option to quickly find it without browsing.
A good information architecture has a
major impact on the user experience.
The faster the users reach their final
destination, the greater their satisfaction.
So, we must never forget that knowing the
users and their information-seeking behavior
is the key to success. Once we know the
needs of our users, we can focus on the
architectural components to built.
The main components of IA are:
Organization Schemes and Structures:
Howyou categorize and structure information.
Labeling Systems: How you represent information.
Navigation Systems: How users browse
ormove through information.
Search Systems: How users look for information
When building the information architecture,
there are many things to consider besides
organizing the information in a logical way.
Depending on the size of a website or app, it can
be a complex task requiring ongoing maintenance.
An expert in this field for over 20 years,
Dan Brown developed eight principles
that help build or test a good information
architecture. Let's go through them one by one.
The principle of objects means that content
should be treated as a living, breathing thing.
It has life cycles, behaviors, and attributes.
Identifying the application's content is as
crucial as identifying the behavior of the
content when the user interacts with it.
For example, a text and an image gallery
are two different types of objects.
Each with a different content,
structure, and user interaction.
You could think of all pages that are
text as the same content type, but
there's plenty of variety here too. For example,
take a recipe as a content type, with ingredients,
quantities, a cooking process, an image of
the dish being prepared, nutritional value,etc.
Still mostly text, but very different
from, say, a product page or a news article.
The principle of choices is simple: Keep the
number of choices small. Less is more.
Users can become overwhelmed and even paralyzed with
indecision if you give them too many choices.
Create pages that provide users
with meaningful choices, where
the available choices are task-oriented
and therefore relevant to the user.
A shorter list of navigation links
will be used more than a long list
of navigation links. Keep the choices
users have to make as few as possible.
Only display enough information to help
people understand what kind of information
they will find if they dig deeper. Humans
can only process so much information at once.
Rather than submit everything to them at once,
limit the content to what they absolutely need.
Like this example of an accordion,
which helps users understand what kind of
information is hidden when they dig deeper.
Or an icon with some brief information about
the page you find when you click on it.
The idea is to present information in layers.
Also, keep in mind that each layer of information
is part of a larger content story that
the end-user can understand and follow.
Show examples when describing the content of
the categories, to show users what they will
be able to access. This concept is based on the
psychology behind how the human brain categorizes
items to process information faster and better.
Especially if some category options don't speak
for themselves. Images are particularly helpful
for this. As you can see in these examples.
Not all users will enter your
site on the homepage. Assume that
the majority of users will even use a
different access point than the home page.
You, therefore, want to make sure that each
page in itself gives your end-user an idea of
where they are and what they can do next.
With useful information and navigationaids.
Breadcrumbs, for example, are a very useful
tool for this. They immediately let the user know
where and how deep they are in the website. As you
can see in these examples from Apple and Google.
This principle is based on providing easy
ways to find information on your website.
Provide users with different ways to browse
the site's content. Using top-level search
and menus are two ways to do this. Some
users may want to browse the hierarchy,
so make sure your information architecture
meets their needs. As you can see in this
example on the Apple website. You can find pages
via the menu bar at the top, the search function,
or the links in the footer
at the bottom of the page.
Keep the navigation aids consistent.
Make sure menus cover the same areas
and don't mix topics or confuse the user.
A good strategy is to have different menus for
different types of information whenever possible.
As we have shown in the Apple example,
the footer has a different navigation
strategy than the main menu options.
Assume that the content on the website will grow.
The growth principle speaks for
designing with the future in mind.
Assume that the content you have today is a small
part of the content you will have tomorrow.
Make sure the website is scalable.
The contentyou start with is only a small
part of the content you get.
So your site needs to be scalable. Give it room
to grow and develop organically and by addition.
We live in a world where people want instant
gratification. This, coupled with an abundance
of information and choice, means you really need
to deliver the right content at the right time.
If the process of finding
information is too complicated
or too slow, the user will simply exit
the process and move on.
Investing timein developing an effective
informationarchitecture yields many benefits.
Happy users. Poor information architecture
always leadsto poor usability.
A good information architecture
ensures that users can easily and quickly find the
most used and most useful content and features
within an experience. That an experience behaves
the way a user expects it to behave. Which
leads to greater customer satisfaction.
More profit.
Lost business is one of the most obvious
consequences of poor customer-centric IA. After
all, if users can't find the products they want,
they won't be able to buy them. They will usually
find a competitor who solves their problem.
While a good IA can actually
reduce costs. Two examples.
When the information architecture makes it easy
for users to find what they are looking for,
the cost of live help will drop significantly
Organizing the data and content
of the website affects usability,
conversions, and ranking. Ranking places the
website higher in the search results, usability
makes the website user-friendly and a seamless
flow leads to a higher conversion rate.
This meansthat significantly less money needs to be spent
on paid advertising to achieve the same results.
Defining an effective information architecture
brings efficiency to the UX design process.
Paying attention to the basics requires less effort for
the design. It also makes it easier and cheaper to
maintain the experience. Since IA breaks down
the experience into reusable components and
helps separate form and function. Good IA helps
reduce the cost of updating the experience by
allowing updates to specific reusable components
of the system rather than to each page.
So as you can see, the costs of poor
IA can quickly add up. What processes
does a business employ to ensure they don’t
waste money or miss out on potential revenue?
So now that you know the importance of IA, what
are the key information architecture processes?
First. Define the business goals.
You can ask yourself two questions:
Why do you want to do it and
what do youwant to achieve with it?
Goals fall into categories such as
making more money,
reducingcosts, or helping people
make better decisions.
Two. Define the user's goals.
The firststep to understanding how to design a
robust architecture is to understand your
users. What are these users going to do
on the website or app?
What are their goals?
Who are the people who will be using the website?
Follow UX practices: conduct user interviews,
create personas, scenarios, and so on.
Analyze competitors and their
information architecture.
Where do they show information?
What information is a common denominator?
Is the website easy to navigate?
Whatmakes it good and what makes it bad?
And define content. If a website already has
content, review it first and decide what to keep
and what to remove. If it's a complex site, focus
on the important parts and higher levels first.
The content structure depends on several
factors. First of all, IA experts take into
account the specific needs of the target audience,
because IA puts user satisfaction as a priority.
The structure also depends on the type
of product and the offers companies have.
For example, if we compare a
shopping website and a blog
we see two absolutely different structures.
The content is therefore leading.
Content is the heart of the website and should
be taken seriously from the start of the project.
Build your website around
content, not the other way around.
Creating the IA can be done in three steps:
Group and label the content.
Define navigation and create
a site map and wireframes.
User testing.
Step 1: Group and label the content.
Once you have a list of all
content, prioritize it and group.
When identifying what content is a high priority
for the experience. The primary criteria should
be what content is most important to users.
The card sorting exercise can help with this.
Many corporate websites make the mistake
of using departments as a way to organize
content in an experience. Always view the
experience from the user's point of view.
Don't make blind guesses when prioritizing
and categorizing your content. If you're not
sure what type of content is most important to
users there's an easy solution: ask your users.
Use for example card-sorting techniques
to help you group the content.
We already talked about this a bit in the
chapter on research. Card sorting is a
participatory design technique, which we use
to determine how users group different items
into different categories. In the end, group
names can be refined into a menu and sitemap.
It's a simple concept.
You write topics, pages,or features on cards
and then ask the user tocategorize them.
Card sorting is invaluable
in figuring out how to structure something.
An important step towards creating an
intuitive information architecture.
Card sorting is a research technique
that makes it easy and affordable to find
patterns in the way users organize content.
These patterns are called the mental model of
the user. The relationships they create between
cards will teach you which ideas or functions
are most related in the minds of the users.
Card sorting is not the ultimate technique to find
the perfect IA of a website, it's merely a tool
to understand the existing content and its flaws,
or the potential strengths of future content on awebsite.
You need probably around 15 participants
to get good results and spot patterns.
The words or phrases you write on the cards depend
on what you're trying to learn from your users.
For example, if you want to know if
the way your website is organized is
easy to understand, you can write
down the different pages of your
website and ask users to sort them into
categories that make sense to them.
This is an open card sorting session that
generates new ideas and category names.
In contrast, in a closed card sort, you
provide participants with a predefined
set of categories and ask them to sort
the items into the available categories.
You can perform a card sorting session using
physical index cards or a digital tool.
After conducting this research
and defining the content,
the next step is to analyze the data. And make
decisions about where information is located.
This is done in close collaboration with the
content strategist or copywriter in your team.
Let's first look at groups or the categories
into which the information is divided.
There are three main organizational structures:
hierarchical, sequential, and matrix.
In hierarchical structures, also called tree
structures, there is a top-down approach.
Many users are familiar with
structuring information in hierarchies.
Users start with broader categories of
information. Then progress through the structure
to find narrower, more detailed information.
Sequential structures require users to go step
by step and follow a specific path through
the content. Sequential structures assume
that there is an optimal ordering of content.
Anexample of this type of structure is when a user
tries to buy something. Also, this online course
you're taking right now is a sequential structure.
A matrix structure allows users to define their
own path as content is linked in different ways.
For example, one user may choose to navigate
through a range of content based on date.
While another user navigates by subject.
Wikipedia is a great example of the matrix model.
When structuring content it is important to decide
how you gonna group similar types of content
or pieces of information.
This is what we calltaxonomies.
For example, a clothing store
mayconsider multiple taxonomies.
One based on fabrictype, another based on clothing,
and another basedon color.
You can label a shirt with cotton, or
nylon, as well as a shirt or top and white.
That way, a shopper with the mental model “I need a new
shirt” could easily find this white cotton shirt.
Labeling, or what we call pages and links on a
site, ensures that our navigation and hierarchy
are properly titled, which plays a big role
in whether users can find that information.
Step 2: Define navigation and
create site map &amp; wireframes.
Information architecture is
not visible to the visitors but
forms a backbone of the website. You can
represent it in a diagram called a sitemap.
This illustrates the grouping of related
content and the hierarchical structure ofa website.
How do the pages within the websiterelate to each other
and what dependencies existbetween them?
To create a sitemap, you need
to have content that is grouped and labeled.
Creating a sitemap seems like a simple task.
However, there is much more to creating a solidsitemap
than listing all the available pages and
linking them together to form the website content.
The sitemap consists of a hierarchical
structure with global navigation displayed
in the first level of this structure.
All pageswithin the website should flow
logically fromthe main navigation.
From the first level of the
hierarchical structure, the content is structured
in a second and possibly third level.
Don't makethe hierarchical structure too deep,
as the usercan quickly get lost and not find content.
In general, your sitemap will either be very flat.
With more sections in the menu and fewer
clicks needed to get to the bottom.
Or yoursitemap will be deep menus,
but more clicks toget to where you are.
Sites with many products such as Amazone,
often need deep architecture.
Otherwise, the menus will be ridiculous.
Sites like YouTube, which only users and
videos interact with, tend to be flatter.
While a sitemap can show possible
navigation paths between two parts
of a site, it usually cannot show
every possible navigation path.
Please note that the sitemap is a
general representation of the experience,
not a definitive blueprint of every aspect or
detail of how the ultimate experience will behave.
For some UX designers, wireframes are the best
way to represent the connections between differentscreens.
Wireframes visualize a user path or flow,
as well as page layouts, information hierarchy,
and even interactions. Even though they look
simple, that doesn't mean you made them easy.
Good wireframes take time. Every little piece has
to be carefully planned and placed on a specificpage.
Every page needs a link to get there.
Wireframes are 90% thinking and 10% drawing.
Anyone, regardless of his or her drawing ability,
can sketch a wireframe to explore
possible solutions to design problems.
Take it step by step and use common components
to create fast, messy, yet useful wireframes.
Unless you're creating a very complex site witha lot of
different content, you don't need an expensive tool.
Most are too complicated, most of the time.
You can just use Figma, Sketch, or even
Keynote and Powerpoint to create them. The easiest
is with pencil and paper, or even a whiteboard.
A wireframe primarily focuses on the information,
interface, and navigation of the experience.
All major components of an experience should
be reflected in the wireframe of your page.
Use simple shapes instead of real images,
copy or text, and label them.
Messy is fine. They are wireframes,
not the Mona Lisa.
Step 3: User testing
There are a number of ways to test whether
the information architecture works,
depending on the design stage and goals.
Tree testing is a quantitative research
method that allows you to test the hierarchy
and findability of topics in an app or website.
During tree testing, only the text version of
the site is given to the participants, who
are asked to complete a series of tasks.
For instance, add a banana to your shopping cart.
Tree tests show us whether the names
of the categories are understandable.
Whether they convey the content correctly.
If the content is categorized in auser-oriented way.
Whether the titlesare distinguishable from each other.
And whether the information is easy to find.
You can use cart sorting when defining
the IA, but you can also use it later on
to test the new website architecture.
This time you use the closed variant.
Where the category names are already defined.
Click tests are a quick and easy way
to testwireframes.
It shows us which navigationelements are used
and which are overlooked oravoided.
The test provides participants with a
static wireframe, before asking questions such as
Where would you click to launch a
specific action to another page?
The places on the screen where a user clicks
is recorded for post-test analysis, with
the first place they select being the most common
measurement, often referred to as first-clicktesting.
The generated results can take the
visual form of a heatmap, clickmap, or a darkmap.
Usability testing is used to determine how
and why users use a website or a product.
It is one of the qualitative testing techniques.
We described this method in detail in one
of the lessons before, so check out the UX
research lesson again for more information.
In summary, we can say that information
architecture is a core part of user experiences.
Efficient IA helps users navigate
content and find everything they need.
Let'ssummarize what we discussed
during this lesson.
Information architecture is how you organize
andpresent your content to the user.
So that they canfind everything they need
without great effort.
A website's IA needs to address
four different user needs.
Known-item seeking: Users will come to the website
to search for something desirable and known.
Exploratory seeking: Users will come to the
website looking for inspiration.
They’re lookingfor something desirable
but not sure what exactly.
Exhaustive research: Users are in the
processof extensive research.
They want tofind as much
information as possible.
Re-finding: A user needs a desired
item again and is trying to find it.
The main components of IA are:
Organization Schemes and Structures:
How you categorize and structure information.
Labeling Systems:
How you represent information.
Navigation Systems:
How users browse or move through information.
Search Systems:
How users look for information.
Dan Brown developed eight principles that help
build or test a good information architecture.
1. The principle of objects
This principle means that content should
be treated as a living, breathing thing.
2. The principle of choices
The principle of choices is simple: Keep
the number of choices small. Less is more.
3. The principle of disclosure
Only display enough information to
help people understand what kind
of information they will find if they dig deeper.
4. The principle of exemplars
Shows examples when describing
the content of the categories,
to show users what they will be able to access.
5. The principle of front doors
Not all users will enter your
site on the homepage. Assume that
the majority of users will even use a
different access point than the home page.
6. The principle of multiple classifications
This principle is based on providing
easy ways to find information on yourwebsite.
Provide users with different
ways to browse the site's content.
7. The principle of focused navigation
Keep the navigation aids consistent.
Make sure menus cover the same areas
and don't mix topics or confuse the users.
8. The principle of growth
Assume that the content on the website will grow.
The growth principle speaks for
designing with the future in mind.
Investing time in developing effective
information architecture, therefore, yields
many benefits like happy users, more
profit, cost reduction, and efficiency
To start the process
Define the business goals.
Define the user's goals.
Analyze competitors.
Define content.
Creating the IA can be done in three steps:
Group and label the content.
Define navigation and create site map.
User testing.
As you can see, a well-structured
information architecture
makes it easier for visitors to find what
they need. Content is therefore central to
every user experience. That's what our next
lesson on content strategy is all about.