One of the best ways to understand if an idea
will work is to do some form of prototyping.
Prototyping offers the opportunity to bring ideas
to life through a low-cost and scaled-down version
of a product. To then test the feasibility
and investigate how users think about it.
Simply put, a prototype is a
scaled-down version of your product;
a simulation or sample version that
allows you to test your ideas and
designs before investing time and money
in the actual development of the product.
Prototypes come in all shapes and sizes,
ranging from simple paper models to
fully functional, interactive digital prototypes.
For example, when developing software,
a design team can create a number of
paper prototypes. When you design an
app, you can create a digital prototype.
Or when developing tangible
devices, such as the computer mouse,
designers can use 3D printing technology
to create a low-cost prototype.
Tim Brown, CEO of international design
and innovation company IDEO, said it best:
“They slow us down to speed us up. By taking
the time to prototype our ideas, we avoid
costly mistakes such as becoming too complex too
early and sticking with a weak idea for too long.”
Prototyping is an extremely valuable
step in the design thinking process.
Prototypes can help you to:
Test whether there is a market for your
idea. If an idea or design is doomed to fail,
you'd rather find out early on before
spending time and money developing it.
Identify any usability issues or design
flaws, before they go out into the world
and into the hands of your users. Does the
design work as you intended? Does it solve
the user's problem exactly as planned?
Is it user-friendly and intuitive?
Prototyping also helps you
make informed design decisions.
Can't decide where to put a certain button on your
app's home screen? Are you hesitating between two
different layouts for your website? Test out a few
prototype versions and see which one works best.
Testing a tangible product. No matter how thorough
your UX research is, many people find it difficult
to really conceptualize a product until they
have it in front of them. Prototypes allow you to
iterate, refine, rework, and make improvements
until you have a market-ready product.
There are different types of prototypes. They
can vary in shape, interactivity and fidelity.
Shape means: is it a hand drawn prototype,
a digital prototype or maybe
a physical 3d printed version?
Interactivity means how functional
is the prototype? Can the user click
or interact with it, or is it read-only?
How detailed and polished is the prototype?
Fidelity describes how similar the prototype is
to the final product. Whether it is an accurate
representation of the final product, or more of
a basic model at an early stage. Prototyping
methods can be divided into two categories:
low-fidelity and high-fidelity prototyping.
Here's an example of what a single app prototype
would look like from low- to high-fidelity.
While hi-fi prototypes can help the design team
gain valuable insights into how the product will
be received when distributed, the production
of hi-fi prototypes can be time-consuming and
have the potential to significantly slow
down a project if changes need to be made.
So how do you know if you should use
a low- or high-fidelity prototype?
It all depends on what you
want to achieve with it.
Low-fidelity prototyping involves the use of basic
models or samples of the product being tested.
Low-fidelity prototypes can be either models that
are cheap and easy to make, or simply stories or
visualizations of them. Low-fidelity prototypes
are ideal if you want to quickly test broad
concepts. They are fast, inexpensive and
highly collaborative. They do not require
advanced design skills, so people of different
expertise can easily be involved. As a rule,
low-fidelity prototypes keep content and
image to a minimum, presenting only the most
important elements as basic shapes to convey
visual hierarchy. Low-fi prototypes are also
limited in terms of interactivity, so it's not
possible to transfer animations or transitions.
The most common low-fidelity
prototyping techniques are
paper prototyping and clickable wireframes.
You can make prototypes with nothing more than
pen and paper. They are best used in the very
early stages of the design process. When you need
to quickly explore a variety of broader ideas or
concepts. You simply draw different screens of
a digital product interface on sheets of paper.
You can even simulate interactivity
during testing by moving the screens
or sheets of paper, based on how the user
navigates through the paper prototype.
Clickable wireframes can also be
used as low-fidelity prototypes.
Clickable wireframes, like paper prototypes, are
a bare-bones representation of the final product.
They can be created with dedicated wireframing
software, or even with a presentation tool like
PowerPoint or Keynote. Unlike a paper prototype,
it also offers a degree of interactivity.
You can simulate the journey a user goes through
by including hyperlinks that lead to another wireframe.
Another advantage is that they can
be adjusted quickly and easily. Unlike a paper
prototype where you have to redraw the entire
screen if you want to make changes. Still,
low-fidelity wireframes are also best suited for
prototyping in the early stages of the project.
The advantages of low-fidelity prototyping are:
Perfect to validate ideas and concepts
Fast and cheap.
Possible to make changes on the
fly and test new iterations.
Get a general picture of the product
with minimal time and effort.
Available to everyone. You
don't need visual designskills.
It stimulates and fosters design thinking.
The disadvantages of low-fidelity prototyping are:
They are limited. You cannot
convey visually complex interfaces,
nor a high degree of interactivity.
An inherent lack of realism. The
applicability of results generated
by testing simple early versions
of a product may not be valid.
Depending on your product,
the production of low-fi prototypes may
not be suitable for your intended users.
Such prototypes often deprive the user of
control, as they generally have to communicate
in basic ways and therefore do not provide a
complete picture of the final user experience.
You move on to hi-fi prototypes once you have
a good idea of what you're going to build.
High-fidelity prototypes even look like a real
app or website and work like the final product,
which is useful when it comes to user testing.
The user feels like they are interacting with
a live product, so you can expect them to
behave naturally and thus provide meaningful
feedback. You can also use hi-fi prototypes
to show colleagues and stakeholders exactly
what the end product should look like. Of course,
high-fidelity prototypes are more expensive and
time-consuming to produce than their
low-fidelity equivalents, but still many
times cheaper than actually making the product.
The advantages of high-fidelity prototyping are:
Stakeholders see their vision
realized immediately and
can judge how well it meets their
expectations, wishes and needs.
User testing with high-fi prototypes
will enable the evaluators to
collect information with
a high degree of validity.
The closer the prototype is to the finished
product, the more confident the design team
will have in how people will react to,
interact with, and perceive the design.
The disadvantages of
high-fidelity prototyping are:
They take longer to produce
than low-fi prototypes.
Making changes to prototypes can take a
long time, delaying the entire project.
More expensive to make
Test users are more likely to focus on and comment on
superficial features, as opposed to the content
They can only be made by designers with
knowledge of prototype software and
who are specialized in UI or visual design
So you need special knowledge
to be able to make prototypes.
It is not something that we will go
into in detail in this training. But,
if you want to delve into this further,
you will find some good tutorials below
this video that will help you in the most
used software: Sketch, Figma and Adobe XD.
Due to the pros and cons of low-fi and
high-fi prototyping, Low-fi prototyping is
the usual option during the early
stages of a Design Thinking project.
While high-fi prototyping is
used during the later stages,
when the test questions are more sophisticated.
Now that we know exactly what prototyping
is, why it is so valuable and what kind
of prototypes we can use during the design
process, here are some tips to get you started:
Set concrete goals. Have a clear idea of ​​what
you want to achieve with your prototype. Remember
what you're testing for. In other words, what do
you want to learn when you test your prototype?
All prototypes must have a central test
problem. Don't lose sight of that issue, but
at the same time don't become so tied down
to it that you lose sight of other lessons.
Build with the user in mind: Test the prototype
against your expected user behavior and user
needs. Then learn from the gaps in expectations
and realities and improve your ideas.
Choose the right kind of prototype. Before
prototyping, consider what stage you are at
in the design process, as well as
the time and resources available.
Low-fidelity prototypes make
sense in the early stages, but
you'll want to move to high-fidelity prototypes
as you get closer to shipping your product.
Don't spend too much time. Prototyping
is all about speed; the longer you spend
building your prototype, the more you can
become emotionally attached to your idea,
hindering your ability to
objectively assess its merits.
Use the right tools. When it comes
to high-fidelity prototypes, you
are most likely creating digital prototypes
using specialized software. Some of the most
popular prototyping tools on the market include
Sketch, Figma and Adobe XD. Below this video is a
comprehensive list of prototyping tools, including
links to external tutorials on how to use them.
After this lesson, I hope you will agree
that prototyping is an extremely valuable
step in the design thinking process. Let's
summarize what we've covered in this lesson.
Prototyping offers the opportunity to bring ideas
to life through a low-cost and scaled-down version
of a product. To then test the feasibility
and investigate how users think about it.
Prototypes come in all shapes and sizes,
ranging from simple paper models to fully
functional, interactive digital prototypes.
Prototypes can help you to:
Test whether there is a market for your idea.
Identify any usability issues or design flaws,
before they go out into the world
and into the hands of your users.
It also helps you make informed design decisions.
Testing a tangible product.
There are different types of prototypes. They
can vary in shape, interactivity and fidelity.
So how do you know if you should use
a low- or high-fidelity prototype? It
all depends on what you want to achieve with it.
Due to the pros and cons of
low-fi and high-fi prototyping,
Low-fi prototyping is the usual option during
the early stages of a Design Thinking project.
While high-fi prototyping is
used during the later stages,
when the test questions are more sophisticated.
I've shown you the pros and cons of each
method to help you decide and ​​some tips
and best practices to get you started.
Prototyping and testing go hand in hand,
so once you've created a prototype, you need to
present it to real users. Continuous prototyping
helps you make informed design decisions. Building
your way to an intuitive, easy-to-use product
that your users will love. This brings us to the
next stage: testing. See you in the next lesson.