One of the many UX myths
is that it's just a fad.
But in reality, the value of UX design is
enormous.
Not only for the end user, but also for the
business or the brand behind the user experience.
So why is UX so important?
A good UX process increases a project's chances
of success when it eventually comes to market
or it can play an important role in helping
to achieve business goals and generate revenue.
UX has a direct impact on the user.
An ineffective UX almost always translates
into a user leaving the experience unsatisfied,
while a strong and compelling UX builds trust
and respect for a brand.
Designing first-class user experiences is
therefore absolutely essential to ensure
customer satisfaction and build brand loyalty.
After all, only when a product or service
is problem-free and enjoyable does a user return.
As a result, companies that prioritize UX
receive several benefits, including increased
brand awareness, higher financial returns,
and improved customer satisfaction.
Let’s look at examples where good UX can
have a significant business impact.
Design-driven companies have a strong competitive
advantage.
Because they have the ability to understand
the unique needs, mindsets, and behaviors
of their customers.
According to a study by the Design Management
Institute, design-driven companies consistently
outperformed the S&amp;P 500
over a 10-year period by 219%.
In addition, a study commissioned by Adobe
found that design thinking provides a measurable
competitive advantage in business.
Design-driven companies reported a 41% higher
market share, 50% more loyal customers, and
46% overall competitive advantage.
The better the experience with a product or
service, the more likely customers will continue
to use and recommend it.
It’s becoming an increasing factor in overall
customer loyalty.
Retain current customers by providing them
with a meaningful experience and sustaining
their relationship with the brand.
By focusing on the users and what is relevant
to them, they can stay satisfied when engaging
with a brand.
When a user is happy with a brand, they will
engage with it again and again, and even refer
it to their friends and families.
The biggest impact is revenue.
Clarity and consistency in UX help users move
quickly and efficiently through for example
an online checkout process.
For major online stores like Amazon, a marginal
improvement in the UX of the checkout process
can make up the difference in
millions of dollars in sales.
UX can also help sell more products
efficiently and effectively.
For example, in an online store, if the UX
is easy for a customer, the overall sales process
improves because the user has a purchasing
experience that is simple, enjoyable, and intuitive.
Or how about improving the user experience
through cross-selling, wish lists, recommendations,
and other functionalities that increase ease
of use, as well as extra revenue for the company.
UX can also save a lot of
unnecessary costs for a company.
First, cost savings can come from fewer errors
in applications and interaction experiences.
By taking the time upfront to build user-friendly
experiences, they won't have to be reworked
in the future.
Second.
By putting the user at the center of the design
process, UX ensures that user needs are met.
Beforehand, rather than at the end of the
development process, which happens often enough,
you can determine the most critical functionality
to build into your interface through user
research and testing.
You no longer have to worry about developing
redundant functions that a user would never use.
A third example is to reduce
customer support costs.
By providing the user with the necessary,
useful information, such as faqs, manuals,
videos, and the like, you can already answer
many questions that would otherwise have to
be handled by a customer service representative.
Or you can reduce returns because users feel
they can't use the product or service effectively.
The better the UX on a website, the more likely
users are to spend more time on the site and
return at a later date.
More traffic and time spent on the site or
app has a direct correlation with rankings
in search engines such as Google.
And the higher the ranking, the more additional
traffic will visit the site.
In short, better experiences mean more customers.
And finally, the better the UX, the better
the overall impression of the brand.
A bad experience leads to a bad brand perception.
UX is not something that many users notice
unless it is bad or broken.
In those cases, users will definitely notice
the experience.
The user may leave angry or decide not to
return.
Or even worse, talk about the negative experience
with others or leave a bad review.
So bad UX can be extremely costly
and damaging to a business.
A good user experience, on the other hand,
leads to positive brand impressions and
a higher brand value in the long term.
When users find what they need, they gain
confidence in a company and its ability to
deliver on its brand promises.
When a user feels a website is credible and
understands their needs, they are more likely
to trust the brand and continue to buy a product.
As you can see, the value of UX is enormous.
In summary, the areas where good UX can have
a positive business impact include:
Competitive advantage,
customer satisfaction and loyalty.
Revenue
Cost reduction
Increase traffic
Brand expression
Please join me in the last lesson of this chapter
where I will cover the 8 disciplines of UX.