Content strategy is an important discipline within
UX. A solid content strategy framework
ensures a high-quality, relevant UX for the user.
But before discussing the role of content
strategy, it is important to first define what
we mean by 'content'.
What is it exactly?
Simply put, content = information.
Whenever information is created and delivered
to people, in whatever form, it is content.
Long text, short text, single words, audio,
video, infographics, chatbots, and so on.
Content is central to any user experience.
So why is content important?
The answeris quite simple.
It is impossible to design a
great user experience for bad content.
In fact,user experiences without content would be
meaningless and useless artifacts.
Imagine yourfavorite app without any content.
Would you stilluse it?
Would it even be possible? Probably not.
Content provides users with the information
they need to achieve their goals.
You often see companies investing heavily in the
design of the interaction and visual experience.
And not fill that experience
with useful and relevant content.
It is often seen as an afterthought and is
not considered until everything is ready.
Whereas if the content does not meet the needs of
your users they may not return to your experience.
If you're passionate about
creating better user experiences,
you can't help but care about delivering
useful, actionable, and engaging content.
Content strategists or UX writers are responsible
for the content design and strategy in a company.
It is a discipline in itself.
And the field is very wide.
In this lesson, we'll cover the essentials of
content strategy and the basics you need to know.
Content strategy can be defined
as guiding the creation, delivery,
and governance of useful and usable content.
A strategy helps you identify what already
exists, what needs to come, and most importantly,
why it needs to be created. It is a user-centric
practice that empowers organizations to make
strategic decisions based on user empathy.
So what is a content strategy all about?
Content strategy connects your organization's
content efforts with business goals anduser needs.
Everything you do related to
content must conform to those requirements.
You can divide content strategy into
four areas. They are defined by the
Brain Traffic team as the components of the
content strategy. This Content Quad is the
most widely used and respected visualization
of content strategy. The work of a content
strategist usually falls into one of two
groups: content design or system design.
In the top half you will find content design.
Content design is the process of using data
and evidence to give audiences the content they
need when they need it, and in a way they expect.
A term coined by Sarah Richards of
Content Design London.
The two areas offocus that intersect in content design
areeditorial strategy and experience design.
Editorial elements such as
voice and tone, audiences,
and brand guidelines represent the quadrant on
the left. You try to answer questions such as:
What is our editorial mission?
Who are our target groups?
What is our position?
What is our voice and tone?
What brand and language
standards do we need to meet?
Where and when will you deliver the content?
Experience elements such as user needs, customer
journeys, and content layout make up the rightpart.
Effective content design requires you to
know your audience. Their needs, preferences,
and expectations. When you balance these
with the business goals, it produces useful,
actionable content that people will love.
Experience design answers questions such as:
Who are your end-users?
What are the needs and preferences of our users?
What are our customers' journeys?
What does our content ecosystem look like?
What formats will our content take?
How will design patterns shape
our content on mobile and beyond?
At the bottom we find systems design.
Systemsdesign is the process of defining the
architecture, modules, interfaces, and
data for a system to satisfy specifiedrequirements.
To maintain theintegrity of content
over time and to enable us to
create, deliver, and manage content to consistent
standards and meaningful results.
The two areas offocus that intersect in content system design
are content structure and process design.
Structure also called content engineering
represents the left side.
It's about howcontent is organized, such as tags and
categories. Depending on the field,
this can go as far as browsing a web page to
personalization and artificial intelligence.
Structure focuses on the following considerations:
How do we organize content
so that users can find it?
Which tags are the most intuitive for users?
How are we going to categorize
content for efficient management?
How are we going to structure
our content for future reuse?
What are the requirements for
personalization or dynamic delivery?
The last quadrant, process, looks at the content
lifecycle, governance, and content measurements.
Process design answers the following questions:
How will content progress through its lifecycle?
What tools will we use to create,
deliver, and maintain content?
Who is responsible and liable for the content?
Who should be consulted
and informed along the way?
What standards and metrics will we use to measure
the quality and performance of our content?
How and when do we take care
of our existing content?
These four quadrants are all design features
that all have an impact on your content product.
As you can see, content strategy is a
mix of editorial work, experience design,
and system design. The content strategy
works to connect the dots between them.
As you've seen in this quadrant,
content strategy is a very broad area.
The methodologies that make up the work
also vary widely. It's impossible to cover
them all in this short amount of time, but
let's highlight some of the most important.
Common methodologies are omnichannel publishing,
marketing, branding, and information architecture.
Omni-Channel Publishing is one of them.
A content strategist can be a publisher,
responsible for considering
omnichannel publishing needs.
This is different from multichannel
or cross-channel. Multichannel refers
to delivering content and considering the
consumer experience on more than one channel.
Omnichannel is about understanding and optimizing
the entire journey across all channels.
It's vital that the experiences consumers share
with your brand feel consistent and unified.
Some form of content is present at every point in
the consumer's journey, and it plays a huge role
in making that unified experience a reality.
A well-designed experience encourages greater
consumer engagement and provides valuable
content across all relevant touchpoints.
While content strategy focuses on the content
that creates an experience, rather than how that
experience can be marketed. There is a lot of
overlap with areas of work such as marketing.
Marketing and content strategies
depend on each other to be successful.
They often build each other
up into a cohesive strategy.
The same goes for branding. When a content
strategist focuses on creating a message or
providing guidelines that evoke a specific voice,
they use branding techniques. Brands are visual,
represented in logos and color palettes, but
also verbally, in language and style of speech.
Content Strategy borrows and learns from
Information Architecture to prioritize
content and help users find the information
they need, in the places they expect to find it.
You have probably already seen some
overlap with the previous lesson.
Both should consider things like current
state content, taxonomies, content models,
cross-platform requirements, and so on.
But an IA is rarely responsible for editorial,
workflow, or governance components of content
planning and development. This is more
the work field of the content strategist.
The duties of a content strategist include
conducting content audits, CMS research, content
mapping, creating voice and tone guidelines,
and of course developing content strategies.
Right from the start, from the Discovery phase,
a content strategist is involved in a UX project.
Their work is unique inthat it continues almost to the
end of theproject. Unlike a researcher, UI designer,
or developer, who might own one stage of
the project and then move on to other work.
Producing compelling and sustainable content means
understanding and following the content lifecycle.
Content strategist Erin Scime notes that there
are five stages in the content lifecycle:
Audit, strategy, plan, create and maintain.
The first step includes objective analysis and
evaluation of the content environment, competitive
analysis, stakeholder interviews, and more.
Content audits can take many forms, but they
usually start with an inventory. For example
in a spreadsheet. The steps for completing an
audit are similar to the steps for creating an
inventory. In fact, the exercise is often
done simultaneously with the inventory.
Even if you don't have an existing experience from
which to define a new one, you still have content.
By rating these, you can
determine what new content
will support your goals for the future experience.
The inventory is a catalog of all the content used
in a project. Content strategists use this tool to
determine the quantitative value of the content.
The inventory also helps determine what types
of content there are, how they are labeled and
organized, and what type of structure is needed
to support each. It also helps determine what
is needed in the future solution and where each
piece of content should be within the experience.
How complex or in-depth depends a lot on
the size and type of products a company has.
The best choice for a content inventory
documenting tool is a spreadsheet program
such as Microsoft Excel, Numbers
from Apple, or Google's variant.
The audit is then the qualitative analysis
of the inventory. It supplements the
content inventory with extra information to
assess the quality of the existing content.
This tool will help you visualize
how much content you have and itsquality.
It captures any issues, gaps,
and strengths of the existing content.
It provides an easy reference when planning
your information architecture. Or to identify
opportunities and untapped areas to
consider in an omnichannel strategy.
If you're redesigning an existing website or app,
evaluating its content can help you decide which
content should not be included in the redesign
because it's no longer valid or duplicates othercontent.
It will also help you decide what content
you want to promote more because it is popular.
There are many types of content audits and
the correct execution depends on the purpose.
A content audit can be compared to competitor
sites for a competitive audit, or it can be
turned into a content evaluation, where the
strategist rates each page against specific goals.
The content inspector can then be reused
as a report of prioritized pages to create,
edit, retire, or migrate to a new
CMS, all depending on the project.
Stakeholder interviews reveal the needs
and requirements of your internal users.
Start by listing all the stakeholders
involved with the content. Such as the content
contributors, legal department, SEO specialists,
brand managers, marketing managers, and so on.
The purpose of the interviews is to bring to
light issues in the current state, including the
content itself, the way the content is published,
and any other issues that affect the content.
You should also use the interview
as an opportunity to gather content
requirements for the future state experience.
After this step you can start designing the
Content Strategy. And this requires many differenttasks.
Content strategy is not a discipline in
which only one or two core activities are carriedout.
This means, for example, determining
current territories of ownership, taxonomy,
the content production workflow, sourcing
plan, voice and brand definition, and so on.
There are many different types of
tasks included in content strategy,
and they depend largely on
the solution you are creating.
Given the breadth of this topic, we'll focus
on the most important content strategy tasks.
The first is identifying which content
types are needed for your experience,
called content mapping. This information is
collected through stakeholder interviews,
personas and user journeys, and user research
and insights. By reviewing the audit, inventory,
and recommendations, a range of content types
can be formalized. A content strategist often
works with an information architect to ensure that
the content types are reflected in the new design.
Second is understanding how to label and
organize content and creating a content model.
Content mapping is the process of identifying
the types of content while content modeling
adds definition and structure. For each area
of ​​the experience, extract a content rule and
capture it in a tool called a content model.
Another important aspect is voice and tone
guidelines. Whether the end product is a marketing
website, app, or other digital interfaces,
the end-user expects certain things. One of
those things is consistency. If one writer
uses formal writing and another is more casual,
the voice will feel inconsistent and awkward.
Voice and tone guidelines can be as simple as
outlining the general feel of the language,
or as specific as identifying key
vocabulary terms and branding language.
Usually, these guidelines outline the goals
of the product and any market research that
influences the decisions and connects the
brand voice with visual brand elements.
Next is planning. This includes staffing
recommendations, a communication plan,
a content migration plan, and recommendations
for the content management system.
A content management system is an
application designed to house all the content that
appears on a site or application. A well-known
example is WordPress or Shopify for webshops.
For most teams, the best CMS depends a lot on
their goals and the capabilities of their team.
For example, a team without a developer needs a
CMS that can be managed with little
to no additional code, like Webflow.
An organization that relies
heavily on user surveys wants
a CMS that easily integrates forms. A
content strategist may be responsible
for gathering these various requirements
and narrowing the field of viable CMSs.
Creating in the content lifecycle
includes writing content,
asset production, governance model, search
engine optimization, and quality assurance.
Content creation is the step in the process
where content is actually created. In the case
of copy writing, it is what an author
writes. In the case of video, it can
involve several steps including storyboarding,
scripting, shooting, editing, and finalization.
Images may require a different set of steps.
This type of content requires very different
sub-steps within the creation process. So each
of these content types has a unique life cycle.
Finally, maintain. This includes scheduling
periodic audits. Recommend a governance model that
maintains the quality of the experience. Set goals
for success measures that you can measure through
analytics and user research. It also means giving
advice to the client, which completes the circle.
This was a small glimpse into the diverse and
important field of work of a content strategist.
Let's recap what we discussed in this lesson.
I started by explaining what content is.
Simply put, content = information.
Content is central to any user experience.
It provides users with the information
they need to achieve their goals.
Content strategy can be defined
as guiding the creation, delivery,
and governance of useful and usable content.
You can divide content strategy into four areas.
The work of a content strategist
usually falls into one of two groups:
content design or systems design.
Content design is the process of using data and
evidence to give audiences the content they need,
when they need it, and in a way
they expect. The two areas of
focus that intersect in content design are
editorial strategy and experience design.
At the bottom, we find systems
design. The two areas of focus
that intersect in content system design
are content structure and process design.
Content strategy is a mix of editorial work,
experience design, and system design. The content
strategy works to connect the dots between them.
Next, we've discussed Common Methodologies like:
Omni-Channel Publishing
Marketing &amp; branding
Information Architecture
Producing compelling and sustainable content means
understanding and following the content lifecycle.
I showed you the five stages
in the content lifecycle.
Audit and Analysis
Strategy
Plan
Create
Maintain
Content is essential for gooduser
interaction with a product.
The dialoguebetween a system
and a person using it.
We'llgo into more detail about this in the next lesson
on interaction design. See you there.