The umbrella term user experience encompasses
many different broad activities.
In this section, we'll highlight these components
to help you better understand what makes up UX
In chapter 3, we take a better look at each
of these areas.
UX can be divided into 8 main disciplines:
User Research
Content strategy
Information architecture
Visual design
Cognitive psychology
Interaction design
Usability evaluation
Accessibility evaluation
Let’s start with user research.
User research is the most important first
step a UX designer takes.
It is a crucial part of the human-centric
design process.
Much of what a UX professional does during
their work day depends on the desired mix
of UX design and UX research.
Some companies have specific design and research
functions, although many functions are often
a combination of both.
UX research is the process of gaining valuable
insights and understanding of users' behaviors,
needs, and pain points using various observation
techniques and feedback methodologies.
The goal is to provide context and perspectives
to make informed decisions
and build user-centric products.
Research should take place at every stage
of the design process, from early interviews
and field studies to prototype testing and
post-launch monitoring.
As such, UX research involves continuous questioning
and evidence gathering.
A process whereby findings and insights from
the study of people are used to create
intuitive human-centered experiences.
There are four key benefits of integrating
UX research throughout
the product and development process.
One of the main benefits of incorporating
UX research into the design and product development
process is that it helps you understand user
behavior and thereby make better and more
informed decisions.
Second, it removes bias from the
user experience design process.
Confirmation bias is the tendency to give
attention and value to information that confirms
one's ideas, beliefs, or hypotheses.
In general, people tend to seek, and remember
information in a way that supports their personal
ideas, while paying less attention to information
that contradicts those ideas.
Doing thorough user research prevents this.
Third, user research allows you to test and
validate concepts early on, without waiting
for launch day to collect feedback.
When it comes to testing and validating design
ideas, usability testing with users early
in the process allows you to test everything
from a low-fidelity mock-up
to high-fidelity prototypes.
Finally, a key benefit of UX research is that
you work with solutions that deliver real
value to customers and are intuitive to use.
This allows you to successfully
market your products.
UX research plays a vital role in helping
product marketing managers understand customer
needs and effectively communicate product
value to the market.
The next discipline is about content strategy.
A content strategy is a plan for creating,
delivering, and managing content.
High-quality content is a core component of
successful design.
UX writers and designers need to review and
create clear content that people find useful.
The content for the experience is an important
part of defining the user's overall experience.
Content strategy determines how, why, where
and when content goes into an experience.
It can refer to any type of information that
has been captured, such as text, video, images,
or other pieces of information.
All content within an experience must have
a purpose and make sense to help a user complete
a task.
With content strategy comes information architecture,
or IA for short.
Content should be organized in such a way
that it is understandable, findable, and meaningful.
Information architecture is the practice of
organizing information and content in a meaningful
and accessible way.
It helps users understand their location within
a design, what to expect, and to navigate
through a product.
It informs many parts of UX design including
the content, interface, and interactions,
making it one of the most fundamental components
of good UX design.
To determine the IA of a particular product,
information architects consider the relationship
between different sets of content.
They also pay close attention to the copy
used, making sure it is consistent.
And the visual priority of page elements,
where things are on the screen.
Information architecture is usually brought
to life through a wireframe during the design process.
A blueprint of a web page or an app.
Often these also include technological and
functional requirements, which help determine
how the experience will change when a user
interacts with them.
UX designers also need to think about how
the product they design behaves.
This is what Interaction design focuses on.
It looks at how the user interacts with a system.
It takes into account all interactive elements
such as buttons, transitions, animations,
and so on.
The field of interaction design is growing
as the type of interaction
with digital products increases.
For example, most smartphones enable touchscreen
interactions, which has opened up new models
of interaction design, including touch, swipe,
and pinch, that didn't exist
with the computer before.
Interaction design helps define the journey
a user goes through to accomplish a task.
What types of interaction should the website
or app contain so that all of the user's needs
are met?
Interaction designers strive for intuitive
designs that allow the user to perform core
tasks and actions effortlessly.
Visual design is obviously an important discipline.
Anybody who pays a professional to
create an interface wants it to look good.
But a beautiful website with difficult or
unintuitive navigation won't impress anyone.
The visual aspects of each user's experience
are the most visible components of the solution.
Visual design not only helps to ensure that
a solution is aesthetically pleasing
but it also ensures that the solution
follows brand consistency.
In addition, visual design helps a user process
all the content on any screen
adding greatly to the usability of an experience.
It is important that as a UX designer you
are not guided by your personal preference
or taste.
As a UX designer, your definition of "design"
will be much less artistic
than that of many designers.
It doesn't matter if you 'like' it, but do
your users think it looks good?
Do they trust it right away?
In UX it's about how the design works, and
it's something you can prove.
It's not a matter of style.
To design for people,
you also need to understand people.
The way people acquire, process, and store
information in their brain is what
cognitive psychology focuses on.
When designing products, we spend a lot of
time on different research methods to understand
the behavior, habits, and needs of our users.
But there are some general patterns that we
see in most people.
This branch of psychology examines a wide
variety of mental processes, including perception,
thinking, memory, attention, language, problem-solving,
and learning.
As with the other disciplines, this is a very
broad subject and a field in its own right.
In the lesson on cognitive psychology in chapter 3,
I take you through some principles and
examples that are good to know when working
on user experiences.
Usability is one of the most important components
that make for an enjoyable user experience.
Usability evaluation is about measuring the
quality of this user experience.
It rates how easy user interfaces are to use.
Usability is an area of ​​research and
testing that primarily ensures that any digital
solution works, and is easy to use and intuitive.
Usability refers to how well the experience
performs against users' interactions with it.
For example, you test whether the experience
is clear and intuitive for users, or whether
active concentration is required to fulfill
basic functions or needs.
You check whether the website or app is constructed
in such a way that it is understandable for
a user.
Are there navigation paths that don't lead
to a user's task completion, dead links, buttons
that don't work, or links that take users
to features they didn't expect?
What about cognitive overload?
Are you asking the user to process too much
information or fill in too many functions
or fields?
Or have you designed a user flow that might
be too complex to understand?
The most important measures of usability are
clarity, consistency, and ease of use.
So if you build an experience that's clear,
concise, and easy to use, there's a good chance
your solution will be effective and
keep your users happy.
And last, but certainly not least, is the
accessibility evaluation.
Measuring the quality of a product to be accessed
irrespective of personal abilities
or device properties.
A UX designer ensures that all users can access
and interact with a service or system,
regardless of their personal capabilities.
Accessibility testing is the practice of making
your web and mobile apps usable by as many
people as possible.
It makes them accessible to people with disabilities,
such as the visually impaired, hearing impaired,
and other physical or cognitive impairments.
Accessibility evaluation is not a simple test
if the interface passes or fails.
Instead, it's a holistic assessment of the
content, design, and code against a range
of the most common impairments, aiming to
highlight the areas users are most likely
to find challenging.
Disability is complicated.
That's why in chapter 3 we take a closer look
at accessibility and designing for a wide
range of people.
As you have seen, UX is a very versatile field.
While these are the core disciplines of UX,
they are by no means the only ones.
Depending on the industry you work in, you
can add things like service design
or behavioral design, product design, psychology,
and so on.
With the UX disciplines, we are almost at
the end of this chapter.
But before we get into the next one, let's
recap what you learned and the most important
things to remember.
UX research is the process of gaining valuable
insights and understanding of users' behaviors,
needs, and pain points.
It should take place at every stage of the
design process.
To make informed decisions and build user-centric
products.
Content strategy determines how, why, where
and when content goes into an experience.
All content within an experience must have
a purpose and make sense to help a user complete
a task.
Information architecture is the practice of
organizing information and content in a meaningful
and accessible way.
It helps users understand their location within
a design, what to expect, and to navigate
through a product.
Interaction design looks at how the user interacts
with a system.
Taking into account all interactive elements
such as buttons, page transitions, animations
and so on.
Visual design not only helps to ensure that
a solution is aesthetically pleasing, but
it should help a user process all the content
on any screen, adding greatly to the usability
of an experience.
To design for people, you also need to understand
people.The way people acquire, process, and
store information in their brains is what
cognitive psychology focuses on.
Usability evaluation is about measuring the
quality of the user experience when interacting
with a product or system.
It rates how easy user interfaces are to use.
And last, but certainly not least, is the
accessibility evaluation.
A UX designer ensures that all users can access
and interact with a service or system, regardless
of their personal capabilities.
You now have a better understanding of the
basics of user experience.
Join me in the next chapter where I will walk
you through the UX design process.