In this lesson, we are going to focus on
interaction design.
An important part in the broad field
of user experience.
But what exactly is it?
Let's start with this famous quote
from Steve Jobs.
He said: “Design is not just how it looks
and feels.
Design is how it works.”
And this is exactly what interaction design
is about.
Interaction designers focus on the user and
their interaction with a product.
Think of it as a conversation.
Interaction design is the creation of a dialogue
between a system and a person using it.
Interaction design has its origins in web
design, but has grown into its own domain.
Interaction designers are responsible for
creating every element on the screen that
a user can swipe, click, tap, or type.
In short, the interactions of an experience.
Everything from a button to a link to a form
field is part of interaction design.
The 5 dimensions of interaction design is
a useful model to understand
what interaction design is about.
Gillian Crampton Smith, an interaction design
academic, first introduced this concept.
According to this model interaction design
pays attention to five dimensions.
Words, visual representations, physical objects or
space, time, and behavior.
Let’s take a look at this application form.
The first dimension is words.
You may think that writing puts one word before
another, but there's a lot that goes into
choosing your words.
Words should be easy to understand.
Written in such a way that they easily transfer
information to the end-user.
Words, especially those used in interactions,
such as button labels, should be meaningful
and easy to understand.
They need to pass information to users without
overwhelming them with too much detail.
Visual representations are graphical elements
that users interact with.
Such as images and icons.
Basically, anything that isn't text.
They usually complement the words used to
convey information to users.
Users need to be able to interact with them
seamlessly and use only their intuition.
Physical objects refer to the hardware that
a user interacts with.
For example, a laptop, with a mouse or touchpad.
Or a smartphone, with the user's fingers.
Second, within which physical space the user
does that.
For example, is the user standing on a crowded
train while using his smartphone?
Or is he surfing the website at a desk in
the office?
These all affect the interaction between the
user and the product.
Time is the time the user spends interacting
with the first three dimensions.
For example, can users track their progress?
Or resume their interaction sometime later?
Motion and sound play a vital role in providing
visual and audio feedback about user interactions.
It helps users understand changes in an interface.
The fifth dimension 'behavior' was added by
senior interaction designer Kevin Silver.
How do the previous four elements work together
to influence a user's interaction with a product?
Behavior includes both action and reaction.
They are the emotions and reactions that the
user has when interacting with the system.
The behavioral dimension looks at emotional
feedback from users and forms new recommendations
based on feedback to improve the user experience.
Before we delve deeper into the main principles
of interaction design, it is good to explain
the concept of mental models.
Let's start with a definition.
A mental model is an explanation of one's
thought process about how something works
in the real world.
It is a representation of the surrounding
world, the relationships between its different
parts, and a person's intuitive perception
of his own actions and their consequences.
It's an umbrella term for any kind of concept,
framework, or worldview that you carry around
in your head.
Mental models play an important role in interaction
design.
As users take actions based on their mental
models.
Users often form their mental models based
on interactions with existing apps and websites.
Basically, they expect functionality to be
consistent with past experiences.
If you can understand your users' mental models,
you can simulate these models in your designs
to make them more usable and intuitive.
But you can only do this successfully if you
really understand the users' mental models.
Too often designers base their ideas on their
own mental models.
This in turn leads to a user interface failure.
Where the user does not find their mental
model and remains confused and frustrated.
They are likely to go somewhere else where
the environment is aligned with their mental model.
To better understand interaction design, it
is good to look at some important principles.
Bruce Toganazzini, a recognized expert in
human-computer interactions, has created a
widely used set of principles.
There are too many to cover in one lesson.
Some also overlap with topics we've discussed
earlier, such as usability, cognitive
psychology, or visual design.
So I'll highlight the most important ones.
At the bottom of this video, you will find
a link to the full list.
The first element is that of anticipation.
One of Bruce's principles here is "Bring the
user all the information and tools needed
for each step of the process".
This means that systems must try to respond
to the wishes and needs of the user.
Information must be visible.
Don't expect users to leave the current screen
to search for the necessary information on
their own.
If it's on the screen, but users can't find
it, it might as well not be there.
Anticipation requires designers to have a
deep understanding of the user's mental model
to predict what will be needed.
It also requires usability testing to ensure
it achieves its purpose.
Autonomy means that users remain in control.
Users learn and quickly gain a sense of mastery
when "in charge".
Enable users to make their own decisions,
even those that are less efficient.
Taking that kind of control away can leave
users frustrated and angry.
This means, for example, that users can decide
for themselves what kind of device they want
to use.
How they want their desktop to look.
Even if it’s messy.
Or what apps they want to use.
To give users autonomy, they need enough information.
Up-to-date and accurate system status information
is therefore essential.
This is information that users need to respond
to changing circumstances.
Users don't have to search for status information.
One look at the interface should be enough
to understand the state of the system.
Accuracy and honesty are important here.
For example, if software indicates that an
update is required.
If a progress indicator shows that it takes
about five minutes to complete the task, but
is actually an hour,
a user is feeling lied to.
After all, the user could not predict when
he would be able to use the software again.
Such a user does not feel autonomous.
Next is consistency.
The following four principles avoid disrupting
the areas of consistency that matter most
to the user.
Changing the interpretation of a user's usual
action is one of the worst things you can
do to a user.
Consistency is therefore an important principle
in interaction design.
According to the first principle, the importance
of maintaining strict consistency varies from
level to level.
Like consistency at the highest level, where
you're talking about maintaining the look
and feel of a product or service.
To consistency in small visible and invisible
structures.
For example, think of icons, symbols, buttons,
scroll bars, and so on.
The latter is much more important than consistency
in look and feel.
Users should not have to spend time figuring
out how to scroll or print.
Changes that need a user to unlearn an unconscious
action and learn a new one are extremely frustrating
for users.
So it's important to be consistent when things
work the same.
But it's also important to be inconsistent
when things work differently.
Make objects or pages that have been modified
look different.
If someone comes across an unfamiliar page
on an updated website or in a revised app,
they try to figure out what's different.
If there is no such signal, they will use
the page exactly as they always have.
Which will not work.
Over time, strive for continuity, not consistency.
Products evolve.
For example, a new version of an app will
not be identical to the previous one.
Consistency then makes way for continuity.
Whereby there is a thread that weaves through
different products and releases guiding the users.
But the most important consistency is
consistency with user expectations.
If users expect it to work any other way,
it is doomed to fail.
If your way doesn't offer a clear advantage,
always follow with what your users expect.
So consider carefully which features you make
visible and which you hide depending on the use.
For example, use active discovery to lead
people into more advanced functions.
In its ideal form, your system realizes
that they need it now and offers it to them.
Controls and other objects necessary for the
successful use of the software must be visibly
accessible at all times.
Exceptions can be made on small screens where
it is impractical to display items that are
not currently needed.
Simplicity is certainly important for easy
interactions.
But, hiding functionality to create the illusion
of simplicity is not.
This undermines the user's efficiency.
To figure out what information to communicate,
it's important to run repeated usability tests.
See if they can locate, identify, learn, and
use the tools they need to perform the tasks
you expect your users to do.
If they can't, iterate on the design until
they can.
Provide explorable interfaces.
A single-use application for performing an
unknown task requires a much more direct interface
than a regular-use interface for experts.
The earlier your users are in the experience
curve, the more you need to guide them.
Stable visuals not only allow people to navigate
quickly, they also act as reliable landmarks.
Something as simple as a company logo on every
page allows the user to escape back to the
homepage and feel safe.
Always offer a way out.
Users should never feel trapped in a maze.
They must have a clear path.
Recognizable interfaces also mean that unwanted
actions are reversible.
Next up is Fitts' law.
Fitts' law states that the amount of time
it takes a person to move a pointer, such
as a mouse cursor, to a target area is a function
of the distance to the target divided by the
size of the target.
So the longer the distance and the smaller
the target, the longer it takes.
According to his law, fast movements and small
targets result in greater error rates.
Because of the trade-off between speed and
accuracy.
We use it to assess the appropriate size of
interactive elements.
Based on the context of use and to highlight
potential design usability issues.
Use large objects for important functions.
Use small objects for secondary functions.
While this law may seem obvious at first glance,
it is one of the most neglected principles
in design.
For example, this law affected the convention
to make interactive buttons large.
Especially on touch devices, smaller buttons
are more difficult and time-consuming to click.
According to Fitts' law, standard interface
elements such as the right-click pop-up menu
or short drop-down menus have had resounding
success.
They minimized the user's travel distance
with a mouse when selecting an option.
Reducing time and increasing productivity
as a result.
Human interface objects play an important
role in interaction design.
They are quite well known in graphical user
interfaces.
Examples include folders, documents, email,
buttons, menus, and the recycle bin.
They appear in the user interface and can
refer to the object of an object-oriented program.
Objects on the human interface can be seen,
heard, felt, or otherwise perceived.
They are manipulated in a standard way.
For example, buttons are pressed, sliders
are dragged, and so on.
Human interface objects have default resulting
behavior.
If you drop a document in a trash can, it
will not be deleted, but stored in the trash.
Selecting "Empty Trash" is necessary to actually
delete it.
If placing a document on your delete document
icon immediately and permanently destroys it
don't make it look like a trash can.
This does not correspond to the expectations
about previously found objects.
It is therefore important not to confuse or
weaken such expectations.
Not only is it confusing for your users, but
it is also harmful to any other developer
who uses the trash can icon correctly.
Latency is the delay between a user's action
and a web application's response to that action.
Latency can often be hidden from users through
multitasking techniques.
Allow them to continue with their work
while transmission takes place in the background.
For example, modern web browsers can prefetch
data.
Reducing dead time when the user reaches the
end of a task and has to wait for the next
page to appear.
You can see this, for example, with Netflix
or Youtube videos.
If you can't prevent this, you should notify
users when they experience delays.
And make it faster to start with.
Cut every element of the application that
does not help.
Be ruthless.
Good usability is a fundamental need for interaction
design.
Things like efficiency, error rate, or learnability
have a direct impact on usability.
Ideally, products would have no learning curve.
But in practice, all applications and services,
no matter how simple, will have a learning curve.
Learnability and usability are not mutually
exclusive.
First, determine what is important.
Are you working on a product or service that
will be used only once or rarely?
Or is it a product or service that will be
used a lot?
If it is a one-off, the answer is obvious:
learnability.
If someone is going to use this every day
for the rest of their life, the answer is
equally clear: usability.
What helps in learning is the use of metaphors.
Good metaphors generate in the minds of the
users a strong set of connections to real-world
experiences.
This gives users a quick idea of ​​the
possibilities of the system.
Most metaphors evoke the familiar, but can
also give it a new twist.
For example, an electronic newspaper resembles
a traditional newspaper.
But hyperlinks allow users to quickly dive
into articles.
Which is impossible with the paper counterpart.
There is no need to literally copy an object
from the real world.
Also called skeuomorphism.
In the first versions of the iPhone, the entire
interface was based on this.
Unnecessarily limiting the functionality of
a software counterpart, to perfect the imitation
can also reduce usability.
The inverse of skeuomorphism is an abstraction,
a prominent feature of so-called flat design.
A fashion that took hold in 2013 and turned
once well-understood icons and other elements
into sometimes meaningless abstractions.
It is therefore important to find the right
balance when using a metaphor.
A metaphor is meant to empower your user.
But, there are times when it can hold back
your design.
Many of our browser-based products live in
a stateless environment.
So it's good to maintain the status if possible.
Our systems need to 'know'.
For instance, whether this is the user's first
time entering the system.
Where the user was when they left off in the
last session.
Or the progress they've made since then.
Amazon.com is a good example.
Their suggestions on what we would like to
discover and buy are the result of their understanding
of our full history on their site.
They know what expensive items we've come
back to repeatedly in the past.
Which pages we have visited.
And what would pair well with what we've recently
purchased based on like-minded individuals.
Status information should be saved to the
server when users log out.
Users should be able to log out of work, go
home, and pick up exactly where they left off.
Just like with this online course.
As you have noticed, interaction design is
a very versatile field.
It contains way more than we can cover in one
lesson, and it continues to evolve along with
technology.
Let's recap what we covered in this lesson.
Interaction designers focus on the interaction
between a system and a person using it.
Interaction designers are responsible for
creating every element on the screen that
a user can swipe, click, tap, or type.
In short, the interactions of an experience.
Everything from a button to a link to a form
field is part of interaction design.
Interaction design pays attention to five
dimensions: words, visual representations,
physical objects or space, time, and behavior.
We discussed mental models.
A mental model is an explanation of one's
thought process about how something works
in the real world.
Mental models play an important role in interaction
design.
As users take actions based on their mental
models.
We have covered some important principles
for interaction design.
Anticipation.
This means that systems must try to respond
to the wishes and needs of the user.
Autonomy means that users are in control.
Users quickly learn and gain a sense of mastery
when "the boss".
Consistency.
Changing the interpretation of a user's usual
action is one of the worst things you can
do to a user.
Consistency is therefore an important principle
in interaction design.
Discoverability.
Consider which features you make visible and
which you hide depending on the use.
Provide explorable interfaces.
A single-use application for performing an
unknown task requires a much more direct interface
than a regular-use interface for experts.
Fitt's law.
So the longer the distance and the smaller
the target, the longer it takes.
According to his law, fast moves and small
targets lead to larger error rates.
Latency reduction.
Latency is the delay between a user's action
and a web application's response to that action.
Latency can often be hidden from users through
multitasking techniques.
Learnability.
Ideally, products should have no learning
curve.
But in practice, all applications and services,
no matter how simple, will have a learning curve.
What helps in learning is the use of metaphors.
Good metaphors generate in the minds of the
users a strong set of connections to real-world
experiences.
And last track the user's state.
Many of our browser-based products live in
a stateless environment.
So it's good to keep the status if possible.
Join me in the last lesson of this course,
where we dive into the world of visual design.