Users' first impressions usually form within
seconds.
If users don't like what they see, they will
leave.
If they have to stop and think about a design,
they won't trust or use it.
Visual design is therefore an essential part
of the user experience.
Visual design stems from the field
of graphic design.
It focuses on aesthetics and usability.
With graphics, typography, space, layout,
color, and more.
But it's about more than aesthetics.
Visual design is all about making an interactive
user experience engaging.
And involves much more than just adding colors
to a wireframe.
The purpose of this lesson is not to make
you a visual designer.
It covers the basics of the visual design
process within a UX project.
Learning these foundations will also help
you collaborate better with the visual designers
on your team.
So let's dive into the world of visual design.
We are going to discuss elements and principles.
Elements are things you use to design an interface.
The building blocks.
Principles are the rules you must follow to
design a good interface.
The building methods.
Lines connect two points and are useful for
defining shapes and dividing space.
They can range from straight to curved.
They can be dotted, broken, horizontal, vertical,
or diagonal.
Thick, or thin.
Typography refers to which fonts are chosen,
their size, alignment, color, and spacing.
It improves readability and should reflect
the content
Shapes are defined by boundaries such as lines
or colors to create self-contained areas.
These can be organic or geometric, such as
squares, triangles, or circles.
Form is when an element is three-dimensional
and encloses volume.
It includes height, width, and depth.
You create form by combining two or more shapes.
It can be further enhanced by using different
tones, textures, and colors.
Size refers to the actual dimensions of an
element.
You can use scale to emphasize an element
or area.
Value is how light or dark an element looks.
You use value to create a pattern, draw attention,
emphasize an element or create the illusion
of depth.
For example with shadows and highlights.
Texture refers to how a surface feels or how
an element looks.
They are used to create a more three-dimensional
look.
For example, you can create texture by adding
a pattern.
Depending on how a texture is applied, it
can be used strategically to attract or deter
attention.
Space is the area around or between elements
in the design.
Related elements are placed together to show
unity.
Including space in a design helps reduce noise
and improve readability.
And is an important part of a layout strategy.
Color is used to evoke emotions, distinguish
items, create depth, emphasize and organize information.
But color is not just color.
It’s a very powerful and influential tool
in user interface design.
Let's look at the different aspects of color
in more detail.
First, a short introduction to how colors
work.
Light contains all colors of the color spectrum.
Each color represents a different wavelength
of light.
And each object absorbs different wavelengths
of color.
In this example, the tomato absorbs all wavelengths
of light from the sun.
Except for the wavelength which is the color
of the object.
In this case red.
If an object does not absorb any of the light
wavelengths but instead reflects it.
The object will appear white.
If an object absorbs all light wavelengths,
all colors will disappear.
The object will appear black.
The foundation of color theory is based on
the color wheel, a circular diagram of 12 colors.
The wheel was developed in 1966 by the well-known
English scientist Sir Isaac Newton.
It consists of primary and secondary colors.
The primary colors are red, yellow, and blue.
The secondary colors are a mix of two primary
colors.
Together they create green, orange, and purple,
as shown in the following image.
Tertiary colors are created by mixing primary
and secondary colors.
The color wheel can be divided into two main
sections: warm colors and cool colors.
Warm colors are energetic and consist of red,
yellow, orange, or a mixture of these colors.
While cool colors are calm and consist of
blue, green, and purple, or a mixture of these color.
When designing the user interface of a website,
it is important to use a good balance between
warm and cool colors in your design.
White, black and gray are considered neutral
colors and do not fall into the warm or cool category.
It is good to know that color does not have
the same effect on everyone.
Age, gender, and culture are all factors that
affect how people perceive color.
Colors can even have conflicting meanings
in different contexts, countries, or cultures.
So if you’re working with a specific target
market it is important to do user research.
It is normal to look at a color and subconsciously
judge it.
If a person sees a red light and perceives
it as a danger, the person will take action
to avoid the situation.
A person's decisions are automatically influenced
by color.
Color can even lead a person to buy one product
over another.
Color also plays an important role in accessibility.
Which we discussed in the lesson before.
Certain color combinations are also hard on
the eyes.
When lines or text of different colors are
projected or printed, the depth of the lines
may differ.
One color may pop out, while another may appear
sunken.
As you can see in this visual illusion whereby
the impression of depth is conveyed.
The effect is strongest with red and blue,
and red and green.
These color combinations can be difficult
and exhausting to look at or read.
These were the design elements.
The other important aspect to consider are
the visual design principles.
They tell us how the design elements we discussed
go together, to create user-friendly interfaces.
A successful visual design applies the following
principles:
Balance
Unity
Contrast
Scale
Hierarchy
And Gestalt principles
The principle of balance refers to the even
distribution of elements within a design composition.
As with weight balancing, the design would
feel a bit unbalanced if you had one small
design element and one large design element
facing each other.
The area occupied by the design element matters
in creating balance.
Not the number of elements.
This does not necessarily mean that there
is always symmetry.
Balance can be symmetrical.
The elements are symmetrically
distributed along the central imaginary axis.
This is silent and static.
Asymmetrical means that the elements are distributed
asymmetrically along the central axis.
This is dynamic and captivating.
It creates a sense of energy and movement.
Unity brings harmony between page elements
so that they seem to belong together.
Elements look united when you stress their
similarities.
Even if they are not exactly the same.
Visual design must strike a balance between
unity and variety to avoid a boring or overwhelming design.
Contrast is a common principle that makes
certain parts of a design stand out.
You can do this by emphasizing differences
in size, color, direction, or other features.
Contrast is especially important if you want
to show that elements have different functions
or belong in different categories.
The principle of contrast is often applied
through color.
For example, red is often used in UI designs
to signify deletion.
The contrasting color indicates that one red
element is different from the rest.
It's good to know that not all users perceive
contrast in the same way.
It's a perception.
Contrast sensitivity in humans refers to the
ability to detect subtle differences in shade
and patterns.
This changes throughout our lives as we get
older.
It can also be affected by various health
conditions or medications.
So be careful when using contrast to make
sure it still meets accessibility standards.
A few examples:
This image is from a test for color vision
deficiency.
Do you see a number?
And what number do you see?
If you can see the number 74, you have normal
color vision, but this is only one part of the test.
If you can see 21, you may have a red-green
color vision deficiency.
Research has shown that even people with normal
color vision experience a decline in their
contrast perception and color sensitivity
as they age.
This means that not all users perceive contrast
in the same way.
Contrast can also be affected by contextual
factors, such as the context of nearby colors
and other features of a design or image.
For example, take a look at this image.
Which of the two boxes is darker?
A or B?
The truth is that tile A and tile B are identical.
Yet one is often experienced as lighter than
the other.
This illusion works because of the way our
brains process information about contrast
and shadows.
To determine the color of objects, we use
relative color and shading.
You can also see it in this optical illusion.
In this example, the same colored object is
seen as a lighter or darker gray, depending
on the background color, while both circles
are actually the exact same shade of gray.
Scale identifies a range of sizes.
It shows how each item compares to the other
based on size.
Applying this principle, the most important
elements in a design are greater than the
less important ones.
The reason behind this principle is simple:
if something is big, it's more likely to be noticed.
Make sure to emphasize the most important
aspect of your design by making them the largest.
When the scaling principle is used correctly
and the right elements are emphasized, users
will easily parse the interface and know how
to use it.
The next principle is visual hierarchy.
To understand this take a look at this image.
Funny, right?
Chances are you have read
the text in this order.
This is due to the visual hierarchy.
The principle of visual hierarchy refers to
guiding the eye on the page.
So that it pays attention to different design
elements in the order of their importance.
By adjusting various properties of these elements.
Such as their relative size, color, or grouping.
The way you organize information has a major
impact on how users experience the product.
A layout with a good visual hierarchy will
be easily understood by your users.
If you're having a hard time determining where
to look on a page, it's more than likely that
the layout doesn't have a clear visual hierarchy.
That's why it's so important that your designs
have a clear visual hierarchy.
This allows you to control how your experience
is delivered to the user.
Finally, there are the Gestalt principles.
Established by German psychologists in the
early twentieth century.
And are an essential part of visual design.
These principles describe how your brain handles
visual information.
Our brains are built to see structure and
patterns so that we can better understand
the environment we live in.
Gestalt theory is based on the idea that the
human brain will try to simplify complex designs
made up of many elements.
You can use these principles to determine
how users interpret your design.
There are six individual principles commonly
associated with gestalt theory:
Similarity
Continuation
Closure
Proximity
Figure/ground and
symmetry &amp; order
The first Gestalt principle is similarity.
It's in human nature to group similar things
together.
The squares here are all equally spaced and
the same size.
But our brains automatically group them by
color even when there's no reason to.
Similar elements are grouped regardless of
their proximity to each other.
Similarity is used to connect elements that
should not be next to each other in a design.
In UX design, using similarity makes it clear
to your users which items are similar.
With the aim of helping them to learn the
interface faster.
For example, a list of features that use repeating
design elements.
Like an icon with a few lines of text as you
can see in this example from Airbnb.
The equality principle makes it easier to
browse.
Of course, you can also make things different
if you want to make them stand out.
That's why call-to-action buttons are often
designed in a different color.
So that they draw the visitor's attention
to the desired action.
The law of continuity states that the human
eye will follow the smoothest path when viewing lines.
Regardless of how the lines are actually drawn.
This continuation can be a valuable resource
when the goal is to direct a visitor's gaze
in a particular direction.
In this example, the eye tends to follow the
straight line from one end of this figure
to the other.
And the curved line from top to bottom.
Even if the lines change color halfway through.
Since the eye naturally follows a line, placing
items in a sequence in a line will draw the
eye from one item to another.
Closure is the idea that your brain fills
in the missing parts of a design or image
to create a whole.
Look at these examples.
Your brain sees a triangle, a square, and
a star.
While there aren't any.
Closure is used quite often in logo design,
such as the one for the World Wildlife Fund.
Large parts of the outline for the panda are
missing.
But your brain has no problem filling in the
missing parts to see the whole animal.
Another example is when you show a partial
image that fades from the user's screen.
To let them know that there is more to find
if they swipe left or right.
Without a partial image, the brain doesn't
immediately get that there may be more to see.
Now the user knows they can scroll or swipe
to see more.
The distance between two objects creates the
feeling that those objects may or may not
be related.
That distance is called proximity.
We group elements that are closer together.
And separate them from the elements that are
further apart.
So when you cluster individual elements into
one area or group in your design.
Users will recognize it as one entity that
stands out from everything else on the screen.
The opposite is of course also true.
Placing space between elements allows you
to add separation.
Even if their other characteristics are the
same.
Take, for example, this group of circles.
The only thing that distinguishes the group
on the left from the one on the right is the
distance.
And yet your brain interprets the picture
on the right as three different groups.
In UX design, proximity is usually used to
let users group certain things without using
things as hard boundaries.
By placing similar things closer together,
with space between each group, the viewer
will immediately pick up on the organization
and structure you want them to see.
The figure-ground principle states that people
instinctively perceive objects as in the foreground
or in the background.
When people use a website or mobile app, one
of the first things they do on a screen is
determine which is the figure and which is
the ground.
Your brain will distinguish between the objects
it considers to be in the foreground of an
image, the figure.
And the background, the area on which the
figures rest.
In general, your brain will interpret the
larger area of ​​an image as the ground
and the smaller area as the figure.
Where it gets interesting is when the foreground
and background actually contain two different
images.
Like the figure you’re looking at right
now, also known as Rubin's Vase.
What do you see?
Two faces or a vase?
In this famous illusion, developed by the
Danish psychologist Edgar Rubin, the viewer
is presented with two interpretations of the
form: two faces or a vase.
An excellent example of the figure/ground
principle.
Another example is this logo for the
Pittsburgh Zoo.
What do you see?
Some people will immediately notice the tree
and birds.
While others will see the gorilla and lion
staring at each other.
In UX design, the figure/ground principle
can be very useful when you want to emphasize
a focal point.
Especially when it's active or in use.
For example when a modal window pops up and
the rest of the site fades into the background.
When you use figure/ground correctly, you
help users with their tasks and reduce their
cognitive load.
The law of symmetry and order is also known
as prägnanz, the German word for 'good figure'.
What this principle says is that your brain
will perceive ambiguous shapes in the simplest
possible way.
For example, a monochrome version of the Olympic
logo is seen as a series of overlapping circles.
Rather than a collection of curved lines.
Here's another great example of this gestalt
design principle.
Your brain will interpret the image on the
left as a rectangle, circle, and triangle.
Even if the outlines of each are incomplete,
as these are simpler shapes than the general image.
So much for the introduction to visual design.
Let's summarize what we discussed in this
lesson.
We started by distinguishing elements and
principles.
Elements are things you use to design an interface.
The building blocks.
For example, lines, shapes, space, value,
size, texture, typography, and color.
We looked at the different aspects of color
and found that color doesn't have the same
effect on everyone.
Age, gender, and culture are all factors that
affect how people perceive color.
Next, we covered principles.
The rules to follow to design a good interface.
The building methods.
First, there is balance.
The kind of balance you use in your visualization
depends on what you want to convey.
Symmetry, for example, is silent and static.
While asymmetry gives a sense of energy and
movement.
Unity brings harmony between page elements
so that they seem to belong together.
Contrast is a common principle that makes
certain parts of a design stand out.
You do this by emphasizing differences in
size, color, direction, or other characteristics.
Scale identifies a range of sizes.
It shows how each item compares to the other
based on size
The principle of visual hierarchy refers to
guiding the eye on the page.
By adjusting different properties of these
elements.
Such as their relative size, color, or grouping.
Finally, we discussed the Gestalt theory.
Based on the idea that the human brain will
try to simplify complex designs made up of
many elements.
You can use these principles to determine
how users interpret your design.
And with this we come to the end of this course.
Thank you so much for purchasing and taking
this course.
I hope you found it helpful and I look forward
to your feedback.
Below this video, you will find
a link to leave a review and rate this course.
You would greatly help me and future students
if you do this.
On the homepage, you can now also download
your personal certificate.
As proof that you have successfully completed
this course.
Thanks again and hope to see you next time.