[Autogenerated] serverless functions provide a number of
benefits over fully hosted applications.
Rather than paying for an application that's constantly running and available,
you only pay for individual requests to a function and in fact,
on AWS.
The 1st 1 million requests each month are free,
along with a generous amount of compute time.
Serverless functions air also stateless,
meaning that you can run many instances of the same function
without worrying about conflicting state.
Across those instances,
most of the management of serverless function is
taken care of by the function host,
leaving you to focus on the logic that you care about AWS.
Lambda functions are individual server lis functions.
You write just the function code and deploy to AWS,
and the Lambda Service manages the rest.
But we're not going to break up our A.
P I methods into individual Lambda functions,
instead will build our A P I into an AWS serve Earless application and
used the service application model to connect especially designed lamb to
function with our A s p dot net application,
this lambda function will sit in front of our A P.
I respond to requests for the individual methods and route those
requests to the appropriate method in our a p I,
even though the A p I will always be available.
Because of this, we won't be paying for the A P I to be continuously running.
You'll only pay for each request to the Lambda function,
including the time it takes to process the request.
What's also interesting here is that we won't be
coating up a new Lambda function.
We're just working with what's already familiar.
Sp dot net core AWS is serverless application model,
or Sam will create a special type of lambda function that will be designed to be the entry point to my a s p dot net core a guy.