[Autogenerated] AWS has a variety of container services that
coordinate to provide you the right sized solution.
You can store your doctor images on AWS and choose from two orchestrators.
All containers run in E C two instances,
and no matter what workflow you choose,
the container instances are managed by AWS.
But the various options do give you different levels of control.
And AWS also has tools to make the deployment and management much easier.
Elastic beanstalk is one option which you're already familiar with,
and in this scenario you can think of that as a platform as a service option.
The other is called fargate, which takes care of even more tasks,
and you can think of fargate as a container as a service option.
E C.
R or Elastic Container Registry is the A.
W s service that stores your docker images and partners with other services.
When it's time to create containers,
PCs or elastic container service is Amazon's proprietary container orchestrator,
E.
K s,
which is elastic coup Bernetti service is for those who want to
use kubernetes as their container orchestrator.
You can just deploy your container directly into easy to instances,
and if you want to be responsible for controlling the EEC to itself.
You can take that path,
or you can leverage elastic beanstalk to take care of all
of that devil hoppsy stuff for you.
One thing to be aware of is that if you do want to use
elastic beanstalk to deploy to containers,
you'll need to do that from the console.
That particular path isn't supported in the AWS toolkit for Visual Studio.
Fargate is a service that fully takes care of deploying and
managing your containers in either E C S or E.
K s, so you don't have to be responsible for managing the orchestration at all.
It deploys and provision containers and their servers and manages thumb for you.
And it's a server lis option.
So that's also beneficial when it's time to think about the fees for compute time and Fargate is what will be using