[Autogenerated] and now I'm ready to debug in the local container.
It starts up really quickly,
and I'm already at a break point that I set in the startup file.
I just wanted to show you that the containerized AB is still
able to read the A S P Net core secrets.
Here.
You can see that the DB user secret was available and has been set to
the builders user I d property and I'll let the d burger continue and
the output from the controller get method all the authors and books
from the database and scrolling down to verify that it's the database
that's on AWS.
Not my local Deby,
because there's April ______ book again with the coming soon note in the title.
I also want to point out the URL noticed that it's local host
Port 32 7 82 The container is exposing its internal port 80 on
Port 32 7 82 of the host machine.
In other words,
my computer's port 32 7 82 That port number is controlled
by the doctor tools in visual studio,
and it won't necessarily always be that port if I open
up the dashboard of Docker desktop.
You can also see the running container,
and it shows again that it's exposed on Port 32 7 82 I won't bother
drilling into the details about the container, though, and now we can move on to publishing this as a container on AWS.