[Autogenerated] the last task and the transformation is just clean up any
code that's related to that s three proxy controller.
That's in some of the files we copied over.
It doesn't hurt to leave it there.
But if you use this project as a reference point in the future,
that extra code could cause unneeded confusion.
Why not just aim for clean code here?
I'll start with a serverless template file since it's already open.
And keep in mind that you do need to be really diligent about grabbing
the correct sets of races and commas when doing this,
or you'll really muck up.
The Jason Visual studio can help you see which braces
are paired by selecting opening brace,
and then it will highlight the closing brace.
Or, if you collapse a section,
then you can be sure to get the full thing when you delete it.
The first chunk ago is this section called Parameters,
and that's all about the S three proxy.
So we'll delete that,
and the same goes for the section called Conditions Inside of the A S P.
Net core function section.
There's a subsection that we can also get rid of,
and that's the one called Environment.
And again, be sure you get the comma that's right before events.
The next section you can believe is called Bucket,
and you'll want to get rid of the common that's above this section because
there's no more subsections that air following and finally,
inside the outputs section weaken believe this
section called S three Bucket Proxy.
And again, don't forget the comma that precedes this section.
Now the Serverless template class is much cleaner and a lot easier to read,
and we can do the same for the Lambda Tools file.
That's the one that has the deployment settings,
and I bet you can already see what needs to go.
It's the S three prefix property and the template parameters property.
And since template parameters was at the end,
don't forget to delete that leftover comma that was before it.
So that's all the changes we need to make.
We pop it over some files we copied over code.
We fixed a name space.
We Addison policies or function would have correct permissions,
and we got rid of all of the extraneous settings related to that sample controller in the template generated project