[Autogenerated] The solution to this problem is to connect the
function to the data bases VPC in the toolkit window.
It very clearly tells you that if your function accesses,
resource is in a vpc that you need to make this connection,
and it gives you a much more efficient way to achieve this.
Then, if you were going through the console,
you start by selecting one or more sub nets from the
VPC that you want to connect to.
And since this is just a demo and I don't care about high availability,
I'll just choose one.
It's important that the sub net is a public sub net,
and all of these happen to be.
That's the default When the VPC and its default sub nets get created.
This map to public I p column doesn't mean that the sub net is public,
though that's for something else.
So don't rely on that for your selection,
because I selected a sub net from the plural site RTs Vpc.
The security group dropped down is now on Lee,
showing me security groups from that same vpc.
And here's where we need to remind you all the way back near the very
beginning of this course when I asked the toolkit to create my RTs instance in
a new custom VPC instead of creating in my default VPC.
And because of that, I've had to do extra security steps throughout the course,
and that's the case here to none of the security groups.
In my custom,
VPC have the correct inbound permissions that I need for my function.
The default security group of the default VPC would be set up correctly and
I'm going to use the default security group of this VPC.
But I'll have to make some changes to it.
And since this change takes a few minutes,
I'll go ahead and apply the changes and we can take care of the security group.
While this is processing,
we can see the security groups right in the AWS
Explorer start in the VPC section,
then opened the security groups for the VP sees and here's the one
I'm using the default security group for the plural site RTs vpc
notice that it's on Lee Inbound rule is the one we added for the Far
Gate Containers load balancer.
I recognized the I D and you may recall, adding that in the previous module.
Although you can add inbound rules right here in the tool kit,
I want to add a special type.
It's called a self referencing role, and I can't do that in the tool kit,
so that means we have to go back to the console for that task.
But I wanted to go back to the console anyway,
so you could see what's going on with a function update from the services.
Choose Lambda.
You'll see a list of all the functions and then drill into our
function on the top of the function page.
There's a big blue bar telling us that that function is still being updated.
Scroll down until you see the VPC section.
Before I started doing this change,
this section would have been mostly empty and it would
have said there's no VPC connection.
But now it shows the details about the choices I made the VPC,
the Sub Net and Security group,
and you can click on the hyperlink for the security group to get Teoh.
Its details.
We've done this before,
will select the inbound rules for the security group and
then click the Edit Inbound Rules Button.
Then add rule.
What we're going to do is add a self referencing rule which essentially
says that any resource assigned to the security group can talkto any
other resource assigned to the same group.
To do this, select all traffic for the type and then enter the i.
D of this same security group.
So filtering on SG Dash 08 and there it iss.
So choose that and then scroll down to save rules.
And what's nice is the rules get applied right away.
So that means when AWS is finished setting up that
connection between the function and the VPC,
everything with respect to that security group will be set up correctly.
Okay, let's go check the status again in the console.
And yes, the function has been successfully updated.
There is still one more step to complete, but I want to drive that lesson home.
Let's go back to the weather forecast controller of the
function now that it's been updated now,
the weather forecast isn't coming up and neither is the authors controller.
The weather forecast was working before we connected the VPC controller. What happened here