[Autogenerated] AWS history goes back to 2002 when Amazon
offered a variety of cloud services.
Then in 2006 they brought these various offerings together
under the umbrella of Amazon Web services.
AWS provides platforms and AP eyes on demand with pay.
As you go billing, you pay only for the services you use,
and in many cases you're only paying for the time that they're actually in use.
Not for while they're sitting around waiting to to some work AWS is
available for and widely used by individuals,
companies and governments.
I do want to be clear that I will only be focusing on A W s
support for dotnet development in this course,
and I won't be making comparisons to the other cloud providers.
Beginning with dot net core .net became a cross platform
framework and dot net core runs on Windows,
Mac OS and Lennox.
So essentially you can run dot net anywhere.
AWS enables you to deploy and run don and applications directly on AWS is
various services as well as in containers and on virtual machines.
And with these capabilities,
AWS has built all kinds of support dedicated to dotnet developers.
The dot net on AWS team consists of dedicated engineers,
developer advocates, AP eyes and these tool kits for a visual studio,
V S code and jetbrains products that have already mentioned.
Another important illustration of A W s commitment to dot net is
that they're a sponsor of the DOT net foundation.
And when taking this step, they wrote,
AWS has a long standing commitment to dot net,
with a decade of experience running Microsoft Windows and Dot net on AWS.
Joining the DOT Net foundation is a natural step for us to
further invest and participate in this community,
so they're very proud of being part of the dot net foundation.
The services and tooling for dot net on AWS are all directed towards
enabling developers to build modern dot net applications.
I've been programming for over 30 years,
so that word modern does carry some weight.
What do we mean by modern applications?
And what is AWS mean by that?
Leveraging the cloud?
Modern software can take advantage of services that take care
of the overhead of managing infrastructures,
so it allows US developers to focus on our code and,
more importantly, our business logic.
By doing this, we can get our software to market more quickly and more reliably.
And because these modern practices have us building smaller,
more encapsulated pieces of logic,
it also allows teams to be more innovative in their tasks
without impacting the work done by other teams.
One last thing I want to be sure you're aware of with AWS is that you can
create an account and use many of its services for free.
Some of them are always for a summer free for a period of time,
and others have monthly usage caps.
Because of the possibility of going over these usage caps,
you will need to use a credit card to create the count in the resource is list.
At the end of this module,
I'll leave a link to this handy page that provides some
guidance around avoiding the thing we fear accidental O verges that would lead to unexpected charges