[Autogenerated] the toolkit for visual studio has been around for a while.
The latest version installs in Visual Studio 2017 and 2019.
It's also notable that there is a get hub repository for the tool kit,
but it's not for the tool kits code.
If this is, this is the place where you can raise issues with the tool kit,
you can install the toolkit right from Visual Studio's manage extensions.
As with any extension,
you'll have to close visual studio for the extension to install.
So I've already restarted visual studio.
After installing,
you'll find the AWS explore under the View menu and on
the first time you open this explorer,
or for as long as you haven't set up any credentials yet.
The getting started with AWS Toolkit window will also open up This one no
provides guidance for creating an identity and access management,
or I am user.
Your AWS account, also referred to as a root account,
is for the overall management of your account and for the billing.
But you'll do the actual work of creating and
interacting with services with an I am user,
and you can have a great number of I AM users under your account.
The instructions provide a link to the I Am user's page in the AWS
console and describes the configurations you should use.
It also helps you get this credentials onto your computer so
that the toolkit can use them as well.
So let's walk through that process.
I'll start by clicking the link to the I Am user's page.
You will need to be logged into your AWS account
before you can create a new user.
And if you haven't created an account yet,
you'll get a number of prompts to make sure that you're able to do that.
I already had some users from some previous work I've done.
But if yours is a brand new account,
then of course your I am users list will be empty.
Notice that on the header of the page you can see my Amazon account name,
and also there's a drop down for regions which is set to global and in fact,
global is the only option for I am user,
so I don't have to worry about that.
But I thought I would mention it because, of course I clicked on it.
So click add user and then I'll give the new user name
and I'm calling mine Julie Plural site.
Then, as for the guidance on that getting started page,
the next thing to do is to select programmatic access.
This will give a P eyes s decays and other development tools
like visual studio access to services.
Then go to the next page where you'll select permissions and you
can assign a user policy to the I am user again.
As per that getting started page, you can select an existing AWS policy,
so I'll click that.
And then there's a list of every single built in policy
because this I am account is on lee for demo purposes and
won't be used in real application.
You can just select the very 1st 1 administrator access that gives
the I am user wide open access to the services.
The getting started page suggests this or a power user policy.
If you prefer the 2nd 1 you can filter on Power User
and the last one on that list.
Power User access will also work for our purposes,
but I'm just gonna leave mine with the administrator,
access the next pages to assign tags and I'm just going to skip that.
Then you get a chance to review your settings and finally
click the create user button to finalize the new I am user
on the confirmation page.
There's a button to download a C S V file,
and you need that that contains the credentials that
you can import into visual studio.
Now that I've downloaded the CSB file, I'm done with the AWS console,
and I'll close that and return to visual studio.
The bottom of the getting started page has a form for
providing thes I am credentials,
and you can just click the import from C S V file button and select the
credentials file that you downloaded two important official studio.
Before we save enclosed, I want you to see one more thing here.
Back at the top.
There's a warning that the tool will collect analytics and by default,
a check box that you acknowledged it.
Unfortunately, this is opt out instead of opt in.
But if you prefer not provide this information for some reason,
you can opt out in the tool kits.
Options settings.
Finally,
saving close will save the new default profile that's
tied to the imported I am credentials,
and now the AWS explorers shows that it's using that default profile.
You can see the list of all services that the toolkit connects to on AWS.
Also notice that it's defaulting to the U S East region.
So when you expand any of these service notes,
it will only show the services in the region that selected in
the next module out of all of these services,
we'll be focusing on the R.
D s service. RTs stands for relational database service.