[Autogenerated] switching are apt to use a database in the RTs instance
could simply be a matter of changing the connection string,
except for the fact that we've got credentials to include,
and we don't want to expose them.
So let's walk through getting that done.
First, I'll grab the server address from the tool kits view of DB instances,
just like I did earlier.
Remember, that's by right clicking on the DB instance,
and then you can copy the address.
Now I'll go into the APP settings Jason filed to change the connection string.
First, I want to keep the local d B string around,
and I'll just rename it to books Connection local.
At some point,
you might want to always use the local DB when in development and then Onley
use RTs at run time so you could just put the local DB Connection string into
the APP settings development dot Jason file.
I'm not gonna bother with that path.
So create a new version of the Books Connection String and here's the
server and then I just add the database name again.
But I'm not putting the credentials in here.
What I'll need to do is stuff that credentials into the
connection string right before I pass it into the DB context
and I'll come back to that in a minute, since I don't want a hard code.
Their credentials and I also don't want to accidentally
share them along with source code.
I'll take advantage of a s p dot net user secrets that
will store them on my computer and as P.
Net core will know how to read them.
I'll walk you through that.
In case you haven't taken advantage of that before,
right click on the project and choose manage user secrets
that will open up a file called Secrets.
Jason.
That visual studio will store somewhere else on my computer.
Then I'll just create a little Jason document with property names and values,
and you can use whatever you want for the property names
I'm using DB Password and Devi User.
I'm not putting my real password in here quite yet,
so I'll just leave that password.
My super secret password, for now and my user name,
as you've seen already, is Julie A S P net course configuration ap.
I knows how to read from that secrets file as one of its sources.
Now I'm back and start up,
and I'll build up the connection string with a
connection String builder Object First, I'll have it.
Read the books,
database property from APP settings and the connection String Builder
Class has properties for password and user i D.
So I can set those two configuration __ password and configuration DB User.
Now the connection string builder has all the pieces it needs,
and I'll set my connection variable to its connection string property.
I'll stick a break point here and debug the app so you can
see that it's reading the secrets first.
Here's the builder object,
and it already has the connection string from apps settings.
And if I debug into the configuration object,
it shows that there are six different sources or providers.
One of them is upsetting.
Another is app settings.
Development secrets is next,
then environment variables and then info coming in from the command line.
Any properties from the later providers will override
matching properties in the earlier ones.
Finally, when the connection string has been put together,
you can see that the user i D and password from the
secrets have now been included.
I'm going to stop there, though,
and go back and replace that temporary password with my real password.
Then I'll go through and run this again.
And even though I know it's working, we're still getting an error.
That's because we haven't created the database yet,
so I'll use E F core migrations to create the database
in the RTs DB instance this time, like it did before,
Migrations will read the connection information from the startup
file and be able to connect to the instance.
I'll run update database again, and when it's finished,
I'll refresh the RDS instance in the sequel Server Object Explorer.
And now you can see the new book database and inside there
the authors and books tables and remember that the
migrations also seated the data.
Now I'll run the APP again, and there's the author data in the browser.
How do we know that this is really the RDS database and not my local one?
Remember that I added April spray to the local DB, and she's not in here now.
Will flip over to postmen again at her and her book into the RTs
database using the post method of the controller.
But I'll make one small change so we can tell the difference between the
database that's on AWS and the local DB on my computer.
I'll just add coming soon to the book title.
So back to the browser, I'll refresh the page and there's the new data.
So now my APP is properly interacting with the database in the AWS cloud,
and it's time to publish the up so it too, is running on AWS.