[Autogenerated] before moving on.
I want to be sure you see the AWS tool kits for visual
studio code and JETBRAINS Rider in case this is where
you'll be doing your development.
This will just be a quick peek,
since this course will focus on using the toolkit for visual studio.
Both of these ideas are cross platform.
So just for fun,
I'll show them to you on my Mac book instead of in
Windows in visual studio code.
You can get the AWS toolkit from the extensions tab,
and there are a lot of extensions when I filter on AWS.
But happily, the tool kits on top of that list,
this tool kit is focused on services related to building serverless functions,
so all that's currently available on the Explorer are notes for cloud formation,
Lambda Schema AS and step functions.
There are also a lot of commands available.
Here's the beginning of the list of AWS commands in the command palette.
The toolkit to install for Jetbrains.
Rider is in fact, a toolkit that installs in tow.
A number of jetbrains i d es.
You can find it by going to the plug in settings for the I.
D.
then filter on AWS.
And there it is, the AWS Toolkit.
After installing it, the AWS Explorer will be available in the I d.
And in addition to the nodes we saw in the V s Code Toolkit,
there are also notes for managing elastic container services.
That's E C S and S three, which is a W s simple storage service.
Get it?
Three s is simple storage service.
So s three. Very clever.