[Autogenerated] and we're Beck.
Now that the database instance has been created,
the tool kit shows that it's available with a little
green dot instead of yellow one.
And the only thing the log shows is that the instance was
created and what time it was created.
I've enabled all of the possible columns in the grid using
this show hide function and one of the pieces of info Here is
the end point of the database.
That's what we'll use as the server name when it's time to connect,
there's a context menu associated with the instance,
and you can get to it from the grid or by clicking on the instance in the AWS.
Explorer will look at the 1st 1 Add two server Explorer shortly,
but I want to focus now on the modify DB instance option that lets
you change some of the facets of the DB instance.
But not all of the things you can set up when you create it.
The details you can effect here are the amount of storage,
the master password for the instance, the parameter and security groups,
which are more advancing.
What we care about for this course and on the next page.
You can change your mind about the automated backups and sister
maintenance if you want the last pages just to review again,
and I'm not going to change anything here so I'll just close this window.
I think the most common mistake you might make when creating the
database instance at least the one I made numerous times is missing
that public accessibility check box.
You can't fix that in the tool kits, modify instance options.
So let's go to the console to take a quick look at what's there in the console.
The list of the instances also shows Theophile ability and some
other high level info about the database usage.
And in case you're wondering,
I did verify that the instance was working and
accessible before jumping in here.
So that's why it's already showing some activity.
If you drill into the database instance,
there's a lot more information,
the kind of details you'd want to see for managing a database server,
things like monitoring and logs.
Another common thing you might want to change is what I P
addresses are allowed to access the database that's managed by
the security group that was created for the VPC that AWS
created for hosting the database.
Instance.
And you can drill into that from the security section of this page.
There's a security group, and I'll click on it.
And on the details for the security group,
there's info about inbound and outbound rules.
If I click on inbound rules,
you can see that the toolkit set up a sequel server rule with the
default Port 14 33 allowing my I p address access,
by the way, because I didn't know what this was.
That slash 32 after the I P address is referred to as a cider block.
That's C I.
D E.
R.
And the cider block code 32 means that Onley this I p address.
Here's a nice explanation of that.
From Stack Overflow.
You'll find a link to this page in this modules.
Resource is, if you got a dynamic I p address,
you might need to come in here and edit the rules to change that.
I p Address Changing aspects of the instance itself means
that you need to modify the instance and everything you
specified before you can modify here,
including if I scroll down the public accessibility.
And again, I've mistakenly forgot to mark that check box a few times,
So I've had to come here and update the instance.
One other important point to be aware of is that by default,
any changes you apply and save here won't be made until the next
scheduled maintenance window for the instance.
And on that second page, you can schedule your changes to happen immediately,
and that's perfectly fine for testing.
But if you're working with the production database,
you'll need to be more careful,
and you'd also need to learn a lot more about RTs anyway. Again, I'm not making any changes, so I'll just click cancel here.