[Autogenerated] I'm just about ready to redeploy the application,
but I do want to test it out still in visual studio to make sure it's working.
And I can do that,
thanks to the fact that I pointed the APP settings
development filed to my tool kits profile.
I do want to be sure you're 100% confident that the user and
password aren't coming from the US Peanuts secrets,
but truly coming from AWS.
So the first thing I'll do is open the secrets and change the property.
Name of the password from DB password to DB Password X so and
configurations looking for D B password.
It won't see that,
and there are no more DB password properties anywhere in
this application or on my computer.
A W S will be the only source for that property.
I've got a break point in my startup class at the point that my code is reading
the configurations so we can take a look at what it's found.
And when I drill into configuration notice that it now has seven providers.
Previously, there were only six and noticed the last provider here.
It's the new one.
The systems manager configuration provider.
That's from the AWS extension,
and it's populated with all the parameters that start with the plural site path,
as I configured it to do in the program class.
And here are the two properties Phoebe password in DB User.
And again, I've just masked the password value here,
even if I hadn't modified the DB password property name in the
Secret Start Jason file because the systems manager provider
comes later than the Secret start.
Jason Provider, the systems manager, will override any matching property names,
whether they're in the secrets or any of the other earlier
providers when they continue running the APP.
Here's the authors controller output in my browser,
and when I scroll down I see that special bit of data
that I created in the RDS database by adding the words
coming soon to the book's title.
So I know that everything's flowing through properly.
The settings that I added to app settings development.
Jason allowed visual Studio to use the Tool Kits profile,
which has theater procreate permissions to access the
systems manager and the parameter store.
That file won't get packaged up with the application when I deploy it,
though,
and we know that the EEC two instance that hosts the application does have
permission to access the VPC that hosts the RTs database.
So when we deploy the up, all of that should work seamlessly.
Remember, the problem wasn't those permissions?
It was that we didn't have the credentials those secrets
available anywhere on AWS before a deploy.
I'm just gonna go back to the secrets and fix that password property
name so that it doesn't trip me up in the future when I'm to bugging or
just running the application for my computer.
It shouldn't matter, really,
because the systems manager configuration will take care of it.
But it's just not a good idea to leave garbage code in your code base.
Now it's time to republish the APP again,
and this will be just like the last time I republished it.
Remember, when choosing to deploy to an existing environment,
you have to select the environment, not just the application name,
before the next button will be available with click on,
there are no other settings to change, so I'll go ahead and deploy,
and again this process will zip up the application assets,
upload them to S three and then Beanstalk can grab the
application from there and install it onto the E.
C.
Two instance.
When it's done,
I'll go ahead and click the URL link and again chose because it's my habit.
All first, validate that.
The a P I itself is working by hitting the weather
forecast controller and it ISS.
So now it's on to the author's controller from the deployed app.
That's on AWS now.
And there's the correct output.
The data from my RTs database.
So the deployed app is reading my database credentials
from the Systems Manager parameter store,
then connecting to the VPC where my database lives and then using
the connection string and those credentials toe executed query on
the database by way of entity framework And when it came to
setting up the environments.
And all the resource is that the publish APP needs
grabbing the application assets, publishing them onto the E.
C. Two instance, elastic beanstalk is what took care of all of those things for me.