[Autogenerated] it was important for you to see this problem as
well as the little bit of trouble shooting will do to get some
information about what's going on.
And, of course, the resolution back in the Tool Kits environment status window.
I'll go to the Logs tab and click on the button for snapshot logs to get
the toolkit to pull down the logs from the server.
And when the log files there,
I can open it up and show you where in the log you can see where the problem is.
I've scrolled down to the dot net core section of the logs,
and I'm definitely familiar with reading those,
and I can see the problem here.
The log shows you that the sequel Connection String Builder,
failed because there was no password.
It was no.
The weather forecast controller doesn't care about the database,
but let's look back at the startup file where this is happening.
While we weren't trying to trigger the authors controller,
this code isn't related to a particular controller,
but it's in the start up of the a P I itself before we
even try to get to a controller.
This code is running Where's the password?
It's on my computer in that secret stock Jason file.
It didn't get deployed to the EEC two instance with the APP,
and that's part of the point of the S peanut core secrets manager.
It's on Lee local, but the deployed up also needs credentials.
We do have a few options for securely storing credentials on
AWS and SP dot net Core would be able to read them along with
the other configuration providers.
That, however, is a lesson for the next module.
But I do want you to see the A p I working.
So what will do for now?
And I will try to avoid my desire to remind you 50 times in
the next few minutes that this is ah, hack,
which is on Lee for the goal of letting you see this ap I working.
It's just temporary, and here's what Will dio.
I'll copy the DB password in DB User data from Secrets Jason
into the upsetting start Jason File APP settings does get
deployed with the application, so S P Net course configuration will be able to read these parameters