Know everyone and welcome to the section of this section we're going to cover a very famous library.
We'll call it number pi.
It's very very powerful library that we can use to do a lot of algebraic operations and we will help
us a lot when we deal with race multidimensionality as well.
OK.
Let's get started.
So in this book we're going to cover the pie basics.
We're going to cover how can we do built in methods and functions.
How can your penis shape length and type of umpire race.
How can we perform reshaping how can we get let's see the minimum and maximum of elements within an
array have together indices how to do mathematical operations how to perform indexing slicing and selection
as well that a lot of content in here.
We're going to be a lot of fun.
All right.
Let's get started.
So first how can we imported pie.
Okay the first step how can we install to software so to insist on one pie on the in the command window
which is going to right.
Kinda miss Tom non-pay any should have an umpire install and then the first step that you need to import
some pie before you actually run any code.
Right.
In what we do in general.
And it looks really weird you know when you look at it for the first time.
Well you should it as import imported nump II.
The common standard is SNP which kind of as a shortcut so you can use.
MP You know through our the code basically.
So when you run this cell to tell you okay now we imported an umpire basically if you don't see any
error then you're a good.
And then the first step is let's see how can we find a list.
We actually covered how can we find a list before you actually just write the square brackets and you
list whatever numbers you have.
So we will listed five 3 10 for X for instance and we call it my list and actually let it go and view
the list.
So now we have a list as call 5 3 and 10.
All right.
Perfect.
The next step is what if he wanted to create a nump high energy from that list.
Right.
So we can do that by COLLING.
Basically the function or the methods you n.p. Dot array and then you open in parentheses and then you
pass along your list which is.
All right and then you pass that along to Y.
So when you run this you know and then you run y they'll tell you okay now you have an array which has
an umpire array that has basically then ellens the same elements of the list which is our 5 3 and 10.
When you try to check the type of y.
Actually if you're done type Y though you're Cain.
Yeah it's nump high and it's basically umpiring.
All right.
OK great.
That's how you define it one dimensional array.
What if I wanted to define a two dimensional array.
All right.
That's actually pretty easy to what you could do.
Then again you can define MP dot array or in parentheses here and then within a square brackets you
can specify the rows so I'm specifying the first store within the matrix.
We're going to be one and two and then you write comma and then you specify the next elements are going
to be C and four or eight.
And that would create basically your numbi Matrix.
Let's stran it.
And if you're on the Matrix I'll tell you.
Now we have an array multidimensional array that's let's say two by two and there will be 1 in 2 3 and
4 which are the same.
And when they specify that you are right that's pretty much how can you like initialize an array single
dimension or add multidimensional arrays perfect.
So let's see how can we use pi and its power to actually develop.
You know when initialize whatever metrics we want it let's assume that one of the finality in every
single or multiple single dimensional array.
And you wanted to initialised let's say with random numbers you don't need to actually go and write
any functions for random.
You can actually do it again within non-price very easy.
You can hear if you can specify n.p. but random dot rent makes sense for random and then here you specify
10 or eight.
If you run it that will give you simply 10 numbers here.
Elements that are not random basically there are uniformly distributed which is simply put the number
from between zero on one that has a uniform distribution.
What if I wanted to let's say the fine 10 by 10 let's say matrix.
You can call it MP dot random the trend and then you specify the dimensions of your of your matrix.
Let's run on it and they will tell you okay.
Now you created a 10 by 10 matrix that has that has a lot of random numbers in here again uniformly
distribute it.
Or what if you wanted to create again random numbers.
But the are normally distributed they have a normal distribution.
How can you do that instead of frightening trend which is uniform distributed.
You can make it more this distributed by adding rent n which send for more.
OK this is pretty much the same thing you run it's okay.
Again you need the number as you can again create here.
If you wanted to create a integers you can specify that way by calling rent int which end for an end
integer or.
You run it.
You will see that basically this function returns just one single number which has one single integer
random integer between 1 and 10.
All right and that's basically X that you got what he wanted.
For example let's say visionary five numbers.
You get anxious perform a syntex if you want to do this.
You can quote it again.
MP they'll trend them the trend integer.
Here you specify the range do you need the number between 1 and 10.
Okay.
And you need actually five numbers.
That's why you specify how many numbers you're looking for.
Let's run it and you give it X simply has five numbers which is our randomly again random integers because
he used Trent int he it already.
Again it's a little bit little bit different so first you specify the window.
What's my range you're going to be specifying she has pathfinding the number between 1 and 10.
N they need 5 of them or 8.
He did specify if I achieve this.
Let's see.
To make it 15 for example if I run it then I have 15 numbers that again range from 1 to 10.
What if I wanted to make let's say from 1 to 100.
I can run it they'll tell you in those who numbers are way way larger.
That means because you are looking for integers that between 100 but again you're looking for thin numbers
are perfect.
Okay so what if I wanted to let's say to define read the numbers again using the A range.
Actually we call that before we used it before but we were going to use it within the nump II library.
Yes fine.
MP The range from 1 till 50.
If you run it they'll tell you okay now you actually specify the e.u. you specify kind of you know numbers
that have this sequence 1 2 3 4 and so on up until 49.
Right.
OK.
Let's run the next line again here if you'd answer that one that would tell you okay now we have n.p.
the range again 1 50 n with the step 4 which is a little bit different than wanting to be confused but
this is a little bit different we use a range compare to their end int he They're actually calling Okay
now I need to read the numbers again a range.
Okay so you have a kind of a sequence but we're going to do a defined number for one till 50 with a
step forward.
Okay.
So he specify the step.
So if he lets qualifies as specified one you would see that actually using a one step one two three
four.
And so one if they make this let's say two then you would see that actually skipping the numbers are
going 1 3 because you skipped two three to five is skipped four and so on so forth.
If we change to one make it let's say three.
If you run it then you skipped every three numbers.
If you make it 5 which is their original syntex we had then you have 1 6 11 and so on and so forth.
What if I wanted to create a matrix and that meter x has a unique diagonal which means I need the matrix
with all these are your primary voters.
But the day agonal only has once.
It's actually pretty common in most programming languages even in matlare for example.
And here in London there's none pie we specify the.
I basically only specify npe that I have five.
Then if you run it that will create a matrix that meetings had tons of zeros zeros everywhere except
that they added an element which is only once.
Alright.
And that's how you actually use y or.
Sorry I in the PI package right.
Okay what if I wanted to let's say create an array was all the.
So we get to big heavy.
Very handy when you go into some profiler project.
You can just specify MP ones and then you specify the dimensions.
How many ones do you need if you run it.
They'll tell you OK now you created 5 array or five elements that all ones get.
What if I want to find a matrix again so finding one dimension specified dimensions within brain disease
you would be finding n.p. Dot ones and between pretend it's easier to pacify a 5 and 5.
That simply creates my metrics that has all once and then me just has the mentions of 5 and 5 or X..
Let's change this for example make it let's say 15 instead of 15.
Then you will come up with 15 elements has on once he if you change this let's say to 15 and 15 if you
run it then you come up with them.
The larger matrix that has 15 and 15 15 by 15 ones perfect.
What if I wanted to make or create an array with all zeros or a matrix that of zeroes.
Again you can do it with mump high or n.p. zeros and off 5.
If you Granites they will tell you OK we have all zeros.
Again if you make it that say 50 then you create an array with of all zeros.
Okay perfect.
So now we know pretty much just to summarize again.
Now we know how can we define PI every.
How can we define non-pay me to X which is going to be very useful.
Again when when we moved to the practical part of the course and now we want to get know some We're
going to apply some methods and some functions that she'll put in some more information about an umpire
reason matrices.