Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to learn how to take beta from the users using the input function.
So let's take a look.
Let's assume that he wanted to for example prompt the users to enter their name.
Okay.
And then afterwards I'm going to print to the users say hello and then followed by the name that they
use had just entered.
Let's take a look again.
User get how to get user input along with the print function.
They are extremely important because the enables you to actually enter act with a user which as you
know makes your code way more handy and way more actually practical.
It's the kulluk.
So what it could do here going to say okay let's assume name equals two.
And what I could do.
I'm going to use the input.
Okay.
And open prentice's.
And here it double quotes and say OK what's let's say What's your name for example.
Right.
So what is going to happen here which is very powerful that you're asking the user input basically value
first going to prompt data to the user.
This kind of a command is kind of a mix.
You're printing something on the screen at the same time or expecting beta to be fed and whatever they
do at any fed from the user.
We're going to be put into the variable me which is very interesting.
Let's take a look.
So I actually will on this.
You will see that you know here's the cell becomes have an asterisk so stick means that kind of them
which is very important that the code is stuck which means it's swathing for the use of inputs something.
So what we have here is that what's your name which is what you guys draw applauded here.
And then here the kind of the python is just waiting for you guys to enter a value here.
So going to say for example whatever they're going to see right for example you know has any case.
And you have to press enter and when you once you press enter you will see that basically here it doesn't
become asterisk anymore which means the cell has been executed successfully.
And now if I could look at a name on it you would see that there is value of Ryan which had the you
know look they're very they're actually entered as as an input which is really powerful.
Let's assume that he wanted to kind of have a more interesting example.
Let's assume they're going to.
The users to enter their name and then followed by their age afterwards and then enter the address to
okay and they're going to print to them.
Okay.
My name is you know your name is whatever you are or whatever is old and you're live at that specific
address.
OK let's take a look.
So what I could do he is going to say okay meme define any baby name equates to I'm going to because
I'm asking the user to input the value of getting the input.
Again function here.
Open prentice's again double quotes and say okay enter your name.
Right looks good to me.
The next step will ask the user to improve the H.
And say okay age equals 2 again input and then open parentheses open double quotes and then wilkie into
until you age gimmick that kind of thing or maybe a little bit more pretty.
Here just add two columns here.
Okay.
And then afterwards mean ask the user to input their ads Signus the key address equals to input or print
parentheses double quotes enter your address.
Looks good.
Looks great right.
Columns as well.
Looks great.
It's actually let's run it and let's test that first so you know run it until you're name and say let's
say right for example let's say in AIDS you call college whatever.
Again 23 whatever and do you adjust to say okay for example like Toronto for example.
Canada.
Whatever.
Okay.
I'm going to run it and then you'll see that everything went ran perfectly.
So the cell has brain and now I have Neame agent and this has the everyone is nicolaides check if we're
playing name maybe there is rain in there.
If I do the address and if I run it down it's.
Toronto Canada looks great.
Perfect.
It's what it could do here.
And I wanted to print to the user that basically your name is whatever your age is whatever and you'll
live at that specific address.
OK.
Let's take a look and say okay print open prentice's.
I'm going to say that because I'm going to say okay.
Your name is open to any brackets.
OK.
You are whatever year old Kate.
Again comma and say okay you will live X.
And then curly brackets and then you can pass along all of that using this format method.
If you get it of course after the after the double quotes here you're going to say OK you format right
open parentheses right and then pass along everything in order to say.
Meme I'm going to say age I'm going to pass along the address.
Okay.
I hope everything looks good.
Let's try let's try it again.
And to name Ryan again 23 again and then enter the address let's say.
Again Toronto Canada run it and then after the input there you'll see okay your name is Ryan.
You are 23 years old.
You live at four of them.
But Toronto looks great to me.
Well that's exactly what we're expecting.
So now we know how can we use this to improve value.
How can we take data from the U.S. and have conjecture printed as well to the user.
Okay perfect.
Let's take a look at another example.
Let's add you know creates couple of new Will new cells here.
Let's assume that I wanted to ask the users to enter an integer to integer values and then print the
sum to the user.
Okay let's take a look.
So I'm going to say okay I'm going to instead of having a string I can ask you is it okay to a equals
two.
Okay I'm going to use input or I open parentheses.
I'm going as the user.
Great interview.
No.
Okay.
For example.
Right.
And then you should enter a number and that number should be fed here in a string.
OK.
In a vat the value.
And then you ask you okay one more time going to copy paste.
And then I go here.
Call is be an orgasm is to enter another number.
OK.
And what I could do here.
I'm going to say okay print open parentheses open double quotes.
I'm going to say give some of let's say A and B is.
Open again curly brackets come here.
They say God for a Mets.
Okay.
And here I'm going to pass along them in order to A and then B.
And he had a have two options either to actually perform let's say the summation previously and you
say okay.
See for example equals two a plus b.
I can do that and can pass along.
Here the value of c and then simply say okay the sum let's say of two plus three is let's say five.
That's what I was expecting.
Okay.
Let's take a look.
Let's Jonathan see what's going to happen if I went on it and there are no it's going to take three.
Press enter enter another number in minutes let's say to enter and then you come up with that surprise
that the surprises.
Yes.
All that looks great.
The sum of three and two is this is the problem what happens here is that you simply want it liquid
Python did here is that just it concatenates simply this ching's.
Well do you mean by that simply it just shows three followed by two.
It didn't actually perform the summation.
OK.
So why is that OK.
That's actually very important because here we need to differentiate between string and integer values.
So let's take a look.
So what we have done here is that when I ask the users to enter a number.
OK.
The user Yes the user entered three.
But if we take a look at let's say the type of a.
And if we're on it you would come up.
That's not an integer.
It's actually a string which means think of it as kind of you know it's a character OK again within
and covers things so far.
But this is not a number.
This is not a value that you can actually use to add to perform mathematical operation on it.
Similarly put Similarly if you do type let's say B and you run it you come up with again with this string
two.
And that's why he went to put a plan B.
It just d dealt with them as kind of strings not as numbers.
OK.
Well how can we actually overcome this.
We to overcome this by using or by converting the values that the user are going to be inputting here
from the strain's to integers.
Okay let's take a look.
So what I could do here is is going to copy these to be exact same going to copy them here and what
I could do here is simply going to convert from string to integer.
Let's take a look what I could do again think the value of a.
Or a.
So going to say okay int.
When it do end open parentheses pass along the value of a.
Okay then what I could do.
You're going to pass along this again.
Call it a underscore it's.
Which means.
Now I can convert from a string to integer value.
Let's take a look.
So if I actually run this all right.
OK.
Before look in before running this I want to confuse you what I could do what I did here is let's copy
that code men do it separately here.
I just took the value of a and convert it to integer.
Let's run this and if I get the type of a underscore it is not found on it you'll come up with a value
of integers which means that simply now a is not a string anymore.
If I actually take a look at it there's actually you see that we converted the value of three which
was a string value of three.
But now that has a type of integer.
Then you can do mathematical operation on it.
All right.
OK.
Go Heat again.
So again I want to confuse you.
We until the number we put in in a is a string.
Now let's take a converted from a string into an integer.
Now looks good.
Now I'm going to take on another number which is B which is again still string have to do the conversion
for me as well go Duby underscored int equals to n s bracket B or 8 and then go do the mathematical
operation not an even B.
Well actual ain't right plus b.
It's great.
And that will generate the value of c and that's it.
That's pretty much all what I need to do.
Then you're going to perform the actual operation.
Some of them up and then you should be printing valuev see which is supposed to mean the actual true
summation values.
Let's try this.
Let's run it.
This is 3 percentage 2.
If you're on it you'll come up actually was what are you expecting.
The sum of 3 and 2 is 5 in a Instead of actually 3.
Could get the weighted order just next to 2 which makes complete sense.
Let's try it again.
Let's Destino let's say for example the value of 10 and value of 20.
And if you some of the summation 30 looks great that's all expecting and that's pretty much all what
we have for this section.
Again you guys are getting closer to mastering python.
Keep it up eureka's enjoy that session and see you in the next section.