Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and the PBS lecture.
We're able to do some data visualization and what if I've been able to use Word Cloud to actually visualize
you know the kind of all the important words in here in any text.
That was kind of our mini challenge and we're able as well to use our reviews Colin and actually visualize
some information in here regarding our dataset which is Amazon reviews dataset.
And this lectures I'm going to show you how can we perform some data cleaning or some feature engineering
again.
And in this course we're not going to be focusing mainly on machine learning.
We're going to have obviously a section on machine learning.
But here the objective is just we're going to walk you through how can you just do maybe some data manipulations
and just get it ready just do some data cleaning and we'll see how can we make it ready for to be to
be processed afterwards.
But this is not the objective.
The objective is just to review the data view it and maybe do some visualization as well.
All right.
So let's see how can we do that.
So first let's make sure that you have psychic learn installed on your computer.
The next step is to say okay from scalar dot feature extraction dot text we're going to import something
called Count vector laser.
OK.
So what's going to happen here is when I wanted to do it I wanted to see for example how many times
let's say the word love has been mentioned in the reviews.
How many times let's say the word quality have been mentioned the reviews.
These are very important words or very important keywords that might like might affect us kind of you
know as a product manager for instance in a company or as like a decision maker you need to know what
people are talking about especially we are dealing let's say with big data like this that's not big
you know that big but it's but it's a lot of information so we need to kind of you know kind of do some
feature engineering and do what we call it count victimizers.
In a nutshell what we need to do they need to convert all these reviews which is a bunch of words into
a bunch of numbers indicating how many times let's say the word love has been mentioned how many times
or what quality how many times the word let's say awesome has been mentioned and so on.
So let's say how can we do that.
What we could do we can say okay we're going to instantiate so now we imported the class.
So let's go ahead and essentially hit an object out of our class.
So going to say Victor riser equals to count Victor riser.
So instantiated an object and then afterwards we're going to say OK let's do vector riser which is our
object.
We can say dot fit underscore transform and you're going to pass along here simply what I'm looking
for.
They wanted to pass along my the F Alexa which is simply go up.
This is simply what I'm looking for right.
I wanted to translate my verified the views into the count victories of words.
So let's go down.
And here we go.
So I could do and say Okay let's go here and paste this.
So I can say okay vector risers actually.
My apologies this supposed effect vector riser.
This is a vector could apply fit transform and that should simply transform our reviews.
Actually it is simple and pretty straight forward into what we call it here.
I call it Alexa on the score count vector riser vector riser
get shift enters.
Looks good.
And here we go.
Let's take a look at Count victimizers.
Copy paste and let's do that shape.
Entered.
And that's what we're getting.
So it's actually powerful because now we simply transformed our 31 50 views.
OK.
Three thousand one hundred and fifty views into a matrix in a way.
What an array per say.
What's what the Matrix says.
OK.
So we have see 150.
However we have for almost 4000 columns.
So the matrix has you know like 320 150 views which is equivalent to the how many views do we have.
But it has almost 4000 columns which indicates how many words do we have.
OK.
So simply put I'm going to show you the mathematics right now.
But the overall idea is that we what we did is that we took simply this if these reviews you know and
we convert all these reviews verified reviews into just a bunch of zeros and ones and a bunch of numbers
basically say let's go ahead and actually visualize a mistake in print.
And I wanted to print Alexa count down Victor riser and we're going to do.
Going to say Okay let's take it and convert it to array so I can actually view it shift enter.
And here we go.
So simply we have kind of a metric matrix and that matrix has a bunch of numbers indicating Okay like
how many times let's say the word let's say Love has been repeated how many times a word let's say happy
has been repeated.
If you guys are not you know like following still let's take a look at how many words are there.
So what we could do are going to say OK print and I'm going to say OK let's show me the vector either
and I will say it gets feature names shift enter.
And here we go.
This is simply every single word that have been repeated somehow within the reviews which is incredible.
So apparently there is like you know like apparently OK this is like word Apple there is appliance.
People are talking maybe about like audibles about like audio audiobook for example.
These are all the words and these words actually constitute of the columns.
So all the columns in there the 4000 ones are simply consisting of all these words in here which is
incredible OK.
So what you could do is let's say go here scroll down every single words you sign for a find for example
there is let's say the word love the word looks.
Well let's say loose you know longevity.
What is this they love without an E.
You know love.
He is loved.
You know a lover loves loving.
That's good that's every single word has been contained within the reviews.
Which is again incredible.
All right.
OK.
So the question is what I'm going to do with this.
You know what's the point.
So let's see how can we do this.
What we could do.
I mean I say OK let's grab our Alexa Cohen victimizer and let's actually do something pretty kind of
fun with it so I'm gonna do.
Who's going to take Alexa.
Count victimizers to array which is what I had here.
Copy it and it's basic.
Here OK.
And what I could do.
I'm going to say OK let's take this which is basically again the matrix that has a bunch of zeros and
one that's actually view it again just view it matrix a bunch of zeros not zeros and ones.
My apologies it is a numbers.
So let's say for example actually get a plot like one of these rows to give you an idea of what what
do I mean.
So I'm gonna say again I think this and simply put it in words on the score count underscore array.
I just called it this way.
You can call it whatever ketchup.
Enter.
Looks good.
And what it could do.
I'm gonna say OK maybe go into word underscore count on the score array and maybe grab for me.
Let's say the first review so I'm going to take a zero comma and all.
Which means I need to grab all zero that means the first row.
Right.
And all I need to get all columns.
OK let's actually view this.
You'll find that simply here we have a bunch of zeros and numbers to write.
OK.
So let's maybe visualize it.
Let's maybe view it.
So let's see how can we do that.
We gonna say okay T dot plots and we could simply take this and plot it here.
So let's make shift enter.
And here we go.
It's amazing.
So you'll find that simply here there is all the words are zero or every single word which is four thousand
ones all of them are zero.
However there are three spikes in here of count one which means I have three words in here.
The question is what these words are.
All right.
So maybe we can go ahead and grab that review with that specific index when I say ADF on the score.
Alexa let's go ahead and to verify the reviews verify the views and let's maybe grab our zero which
is our first index right this ship enter.
And here we go.
So here basically love my echo has been translated into love my echo which is incredible.
Maybe grab let's say index number one which is my second view enter.
You'll find that there is.
Love it.
Which is has been translated into one word and one word.
OK.
Maybe grab it say three.
Loved it.
Oh my apologies.
This should be three 2.
Right.
So we're applying three and three so that's what we're getting.
So you guys can see here.
You will find that we have the word count.
Race is I love.
I have had a lot of fun with my thing my four year old learns the dinosaurs all this stuff I've been
translated into like all these like you know different peaks in that showing indicating because every
single location and he had every single number has a word meaning there is a meaning behind it.
Right.
Which is translated into one of these words in here.
All right.
Okay maybe one more time describe maybe five and maybe five.
Okay.
Again you'll have tons of words in here.
Maybe let's go up and take a look at our the F reviews and maybe grab it.
Easy one is simple want to make sure they actually understand this correctly.
Let's assume they're going to go here and maybe grab like I need to show you guys an easier one
so this one for example that's actually a very good example.
This is called Love love love right.
Which is single word but has been repeated three times.
Right.
OK.
So let's go ahead and actually do it.
So let's go ahead here which is 15.
Let's go ahead and get the word 13 and get here the word 13.
The actual review along with the convict tries.
And here we go.
Amazing.
So this is this is the index of the word love which is around let's say twenty two hundred or something.
And here you will find the count has been three which mean the word has been repeated three times which
is great too.
All right.
OK.
And that's all what it is when it comes to applying the count victories either.
Let's go ahead and actually do one more kind of analysis before we conclude our project.
So what could do against the ADF underscore Alexa and Hill could pass along our lines.
What we going to do we're going to create a new kind of features within our data frame that has a lens
into it.
You're gonna see ADF on.
Alexa.
And what I could do I could say okay verified the views
and I could say Doc apply and I can pass along the length simply.
All right.
So simply we're going to do going to say OK let's go ahead count how many words in here within our verify
their views and added in a new data frame new element in the frames called defense.
Let's take a look maybe at the f on the score Alexa that heads enter.
And here we go.
So now we have the ratings.
Now we have the dates.
Now we have the variations.
Now we have the verify the view's feedback and lends to indicating actually how many characters were
there not words my apologies.
So loved it for example here there is l o v e d space I.T. exclamation mark 9.
Here we have one hundred and nine feet 1 5 1 7 2.
Why are we doing this.
We're actually doing this because that might add some important information for us.
Maybe for example you know like people who write more more length or more words maybe they are a little
bit more bitter.
Maybe they have they are not that happy.
So something along these lines.
So we can extract more information regarding the length of the reviews.
OK.
Obviously if someone is not happy you're are not going to say you know for example I have one word for
instance maybe.
For example.
OK so most of the time people actually don't like the product.
We're just going to say you know what.
Like I hated or something I'm going to say like write an essay or something.
Right.
People actually do write reviews that much unless they actually hate the product.
So we could do we're going to say okay maybe go ahead and show me a histogram of the lines in a sec
ADF on the screen Alexa and let's go ahead and show me the lengths GTA H dot histogram and maybe I can
pass along our bins equal to let's say a hundred ships enter it we go.
So now I have my histogram and he gets can see here you find that there is an actual.
Somebody who actually wrote 800 characters which is crazy.
Someone actually wrote just my apologies.
Someone actually wrote wrote here zero characters.
OK.
So or maybe one very small number of characters maybe like a smiley face or something.
And he is somebody actually wrote almost like fourteen hundred maybe fifteen hundred characters which
is insane.
So let's see who who did this who maybe let's go ahead and obtain that's a minimum.
Characters equals to the F underscore.
Alexa let's go to our verified reviews and what we could do.
Going to say that men let's attain the minimum value.
So that's the minimum.
And let's take a look at the at the actual Let's go ahead.
If Alexa.
And let's go into the f on the squad Alex again and I need to go within the lance data frame right and
compare it if it's equal to the men car so here this is the minimum number of characters.
So I wanted to say okay.
Go ahead to our data frame to the lens bring to me please what is.
Which one has the many main characters in there.
Which has the minimum number of words right.
And what I could do as well.
I'm going to say okay what I need to extract out of it.
I need to extract my verified reviews the score reviews and I need to obtain if you guys recall from
previously I lock 0 to just obtain for me what's in it.
So please shift enter.
It's actually telling me there is an error in here.
It's to make sure.
So what we're saying.
ADF Alexa DFL excel at and Lentz is equal to the men car which is this variable here.
OK.
So actually I My apologies here what I wanted to do I wanted to attain the minimum out of the lens.
Right.
We're not we don't want to get the verified the views we actually want to go to the lens column to go
up.
These are the lens column right.
What I wanted to obtain and I just I wanted to obtain the lens of thin the minimum value.
What's the main and what's the max.
So actually it's go here seeing this GBH.
And here we go.
So simply someone actually just wrote like a smiley face with a heart in it.
OK.
That's like one the minimum review that has been made.
Maybe let's go ahead and obtain the max.
We're going to take control V.
We're going to see this.
Call it Max car.
And we're going to call it Max.
And here we're going to say when was the max car occurred shift enter.
And here we go.
Wow.
So you find that there is incredible piece of technology.
I love this right center of my living room.
Actual surprise because this is a good review.
So actually someone actually the perfect or good review with which is great.
You know that means he actually wrote the view and he's happy with it.
You know like he did send for me and my floor lamp just perfect.
Highly recommended by buy in Ecuador from my bedroom now which is just just incredible.
All right.
OK.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
I hope you guys enjoy the entire project again one last challenge.
What you guys wanted to do is to maybe go here and try to obtain the reviews.
That has a number of characters equal one hundred.
So what I wanted to do when the number number of characters was equal to one hundred and maybe number
of characters equals to 150.
And I wanted to obtain these reviews I want to see like them if they are not.
Maybe pick any number close to it maybe 1 to 1 or maybe hear like let's say 151 or 152 or something.
Please go ahead pause a video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
I ask you has to do is to simply go ahead and obtain simply this and try to obtain or give me how many.
What is the review that has let's say a hundred characters in it or maybe has 150 characters number
of characters.
So simply put instead of getting the maximum what I could do I'm going to say OK maybe set this to 100
and that's it.
Shift enter.
And here we go.
Great for my office.
I use this daily in many ways to include spelling for me and background music looks good.
Maybe grab one one to shift enter.
Got this.
Amazon Prime within pro works great being lazy OK.
That's pretty much all what it is.
All right.
I hope you guys enjoy this project.
I hope you find it helpful and useful.
Let's recap what we have done so far.
So if you go up here you will find that we just went through and we did a lot of analysis actually to
our Amazon review dataset.
So we're able to load the data so we know how to deal with data frames now able to visualize some information
within the data we're able to obtain some kind of somebody using info and using describe method to just
give us kind of a summary of the data we're able as well to visualize the data using you know seaboard
libraries that scroll down we're able to kind of group the reviews into positive and negative reviews
and we're able as well to actually a lot of information we're able to use count plot seaborne count
plot to plot how many reviews are positive how many reviews were negative we're able to as well do some
count plot to review the ratings how many reviews were five star rating or not we did some histogram
analysis we did as well some analysis here to show the different variations along with the ratings and
we're able to do some work cloud as well which is really powerful we're able to actually convert the
entire kind of reviews column into just one string and simply apply the word cloud to it.
We got something like this was really amazing.
And then afterwards we're able to do some data cleaning and feature engineering by just counting how
many words have been repeated in if in each single single review and attain that specific metrics along
with a matrix of words then we're able to let's say if you the actual review and if you how many words
have been repeated in each one of them and we're able as well to obtain the lengths of how many characters
were contained within the reviews and add that column in here in our data frame and to do some histogram
analysis entertain the least review which is just one character and the maximum as well which is the
entire paragraph here and we're able to go as well through a mini challenge to walk you through the
if you wanted to get you know specific length of or how many characters do we have.
All right that's all we have for this project I hope you guys enjoyed it and I'll see you guys in future
projects.