Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I hope you guys were able to figure it out.
You know at least a couple of the questions that you guys had before if not that's fine that's built
you know like all the solutions together.
OK.
So I'm asking you to do for the first question is to write a code that takes a speed inputs from a user
in kilometres per hour converts it into miles per hour and then print both speeds on the screen something
like.
That's what I'm expecting to see basically.
Right.
So let's take a look.
It's going to do here.
Don't find a variable in a kilometre column but to put our whole key in MH You can call it whatever
they're going to say OK it equals two.
And then as the user to input data is going to say input.
OK.
And I'm going to as the user to enter speed.
Right.
In kilometres per hour.
All right.
And because Hilo have kind of column that I'm asking to do list at column as well.
Right.
Looks great.
One important element here if you as a member of that user input whatever value this number will be
is changing.
Correct.
In order to do the conversion if you guys remember from the string to Integer I have two cast basically
whatever the data that I'm getting here.
Okay.
And convert it to integer.
You can as well you can obviously take the colombus butt out and convert it as well afterwards but you
can do it in one shot to see.
It's open parentheses and come here and close the parentheses.
That's it.
So whatever string value that we're going to be fed here we're going to be converted into integer afterwards
and be put into colombus put out which is great.
Next step is to say okay I need mph would be equal to basically the equation that we have done before.
Point 6 to 1 4 right.
Multiply that by the K H which is the value that will take before.
Please make sure that all the letters are in lower case so you won't have any issues afterwards.
OK.
Now you have done the quad version.
That's great.
Well you could do it afterwards if you want just to print the data on the screen.
I need to print Speen in Columbus but our equals to whatever you can do that.
OK let's take a look.
So going to say cannot say okay print open parentheses OK.
Open again.
Quality of scale speed in kilometres per hour right.
Are those good and a C equals two.
Because there is an equal right.
And what I could do here.
I'm going to say okay comma.
I'm going to print kilometres per hour which is my value here that I have you but I need to pin the
units so basically this what I'm going to be expecting to see here.
What I need to do they need to see a case space as well.
I'm going to put here kilometres per hour.
Upper case which is not going to be printed afterwards after the number.
Okay.
Looks great.
When to do we are going to copy this.
I'm going to make it again here.
Print speed in miles per hour and miles per hour equals 2 again mph which is the very we have before.
M p h right.
I'm going to specify mph mph.
Right okay it looks good to me.
Let's run it let's test it with a different number.
Let's run that's a.p. the economics but our.
Let's say it's 50 for example this time.
Run it.
Okay so speed in kilometres per hour equals to 50 kilometres but our richest input data looks great
to me.
This is a free show right here speedin miles per hour is around 31 miles per hour.
Which is again pretty.
Looks good to me as well.
OK.
That's pretty much all what I wanted to do.
I hope you guys were able to figure that out.
OK.
Perfect.
The next question that we have is that I ask you to print the calendar for this month.
Just because whatever money you have.
OK.
And I wanted to print the calendar using simply this okay to import the module calendar and then here's
how you're gonna use calendar month.
Pass along whatever number of the year.
Okay.
And pass along the month here OK.
Again this kind of an extended research I haven't covered before but again you know.
Please be prepared to go ahead read the documentation and make sure you're actually familiar with whatever
comment because you.
Be flexible moving forward to do whatever is called on your own.
Now just stick to the Course.
Ok this article looks frivolous imports calendar.
Its first step.
Second step.
Going to say okay you're equal to let's say 20 16 for example.
I'm going to go on.
And let's say for example last month's going to say for example March or thirty or whatever.
Three here.
Well I would do afterwards.
I'm going to say okay I want it to print.
That's what I wanted to do and I want it to print.
Here's what a listed here bouquet is a faded calendar.
But months and they open prentice's if they pass along they hear and again pass along the months then
that will helping to simply print whatever you and whatever you think using the calendar.
Basically modu that we imported here.
OK.
Let's give it a shot.
If we're on it that's all we actually get.
It's actually in March 2014 and that's basically the calendar for March 2013.
Just perfect.
OK.
That's pretty much again very easy.
We have a couple of the before.
But again I want you to practice searching like module's on your own.
OK.
All right the next example is I'm asking you to instead of actually feeling this.
Actually the months of assembly use to improve the year end the month.
Okay.
Again it should be very straightforward.
Just got a copy.
Basically what we have here.
I'm going to copy the exact same here.
And just a couple of changes.
Here's what I want to do instead of four years to in 2016 and months equals thirty three.
What I wanted to do with I actually ask the users to input the data for me when I say OK and then I
say OK we're going to see more of this are going to use input.
I think as a member input or in parentheses open double quotes and they say OK enter right here and
here.
And actually giving kind of an example as well to the user and say okay for example you entered the
year I'm going to tell you Okay I for example E for example you know double.
Colin I'm going to say 2019 For instance I'm going to do Colin here.
And it's a for example create space.
Looks good to me.
Please don't forget that whatever going to be fed he'll going to come as a string.
You need to do the conversion into an integer.
Again do not cast it as an opening in parentheses and close the parentheses here.
Cake looks good to me.
I'M GOING TO THE EXACT SAME THING.
SAME THING.
Integer open and then input.
Or print.
Right.
I'm sorry.
Input.
Open.
I'm going to say again here.
Right and when asking.
Enter months and then will give them an example of how to in a month.
E n and tell him K for example.
It would be 0 3.
Colin and that's it.
All right so once he was into the year of the month all these variables were going to be fed here and
there are going to be printed on the street.
Alright that's they can look around it.
They took it into a year in the middle of say 2015.
Anthea let's say less like a month or eight run it and then actually it's August of 2015.
And that's actually my calendar as well.
Huge.
Very interesting.
All right.
Sounds great.
And that's we're going to conclude the lecture here and then the next lecture going to continue along
and finish of the coding exercise.
I hope you have enjoyed it and see you in the next election.