Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's keep going.
So this
Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited because we're getting closer to predict our price for the avocado.
OK.
So in the previous lecture we discussed how can we view the data.
So we actually been able to view the data versus different regions with youth as well the sales or the
number of you know number of of elements that we have per years.
And we also created our own data frame which is specifically made to fit our profit operation.
So we only took these two columns which is date and average price.
And we put that into the average offguard or profit data free.
All right.
OK.
Sounds great.
Let's take a look at all gonna do here.
So what we gonna do here.
We are going to rename our columns.
So we're gonna go ahead to our avocado.
I'm going to tell you exactly why right now and go to avocado underscored profits on the score data
frame.
OK.
I'm going to do renaming so I'm going to rename our columns
I'm gonna rename them from date.
I'm gonna call it D Yes.
My apologies.
This need to be date.
This need to be d s OK.
And then we're going to rename as well the average price we're going to call it Y.
Average price.
And that will should we call it y right.
And then we're going to take that and put it in our data frame again.
So basically we're just gonna go ahead and rename our data frame again.
So what's the point.
Why are we doing this.
So in order for the up for the order for the profit to actually operate.
OK.
These two columns has to have that name.
So the date has to have the s name and average price has to have wining that's it.
Once we do that they're going to be very easy afterwards to actually feed the data into the profit prediction
function.
So let's run it looks good.
Let's take a look at it again the data frame.
And here we go.
That's our the data frame and that's our y data frame.
Looks great.
All right.
So let's take a look at how can we actually train our model.
Let's see.
So what we could do here.
I'm going to instantiate the prophet object so we're going to instantiate an object in let's say m m
equals prophet.
OK.
So basically what we did that we imported our class before which is f here we had import profits.
Right.
So here we instantiate that an object out of this.
All right.
So let's take a look at how can we actually perform the prediction.
So what we did here have just instantiated an object called M what we could do.
It's actually very very simple because the m dot fits.
And we're going to pass along our data frame avocado on the score profits and underscore data frame.
That's it.
That's actually pretty simple.
So let's run it let's run it.
So take a little while
so basically what we're doing here.
You know we're just trying to train kind of a model to try to predict the future in a way.
OK.
Again it's taking a little while to actually run and after after that.
Looks good.
That's done.
You know we don't need to actually take a look at what's happening in the background there's a lot of
mathematics.
Obviously it's not that simple it's actually really very complex.
But the overall idea here is just to try from an application perspective is how can we use it.
OK.
So let's go ahead and actually forecast the future.
Let's forecast forecasts the futures.
Let's go ahead and see how can we do that.
So what we could do here we could
go ahead and use our train.
So basically m here contain all the training.
So we use the input input data which is date and time.
Right.
And we use that to train kind of a model.
And then we can take that model and make predictions.
So going to say OK let's predict the future.
So the future equals to m dot we can use a method called m make on the score future underscore data
from thing and then it can pass along.
How long do we need.
Our our future going to be so heat I'm trying to predict in the future one year ahead is going to take
a period going to be 365 days a year I'm predicting in the future I want to see what do what do you
see in the future.
What we could do afterwards I'm going to say OK let's do two.
Here we created the future and then we can say OK our forecasts equals to m DOT predicts apologies predict
and we can pass along our future.
That's it.
That's right.
That's
sticking liberal while.
All right.
So now we're good.
Let's take a look at the forecast.
If we take a look at the forecast now put on it that's pretty much it.
So we find these two columns of the input which D.S. basically that's our input and you will find that
there is a lot of columns in here.
OK.
There's tons of information.
So simply put what what the profit function is doing is just giving you kind of the trend.
OK.
What are we expecting.
You know in the future what's going to happen moving forward if you scroll down here you would find
something really interesting.
You'll find that there's 20 19 appear even though the data or it was already like you know until March
of 2018 so you'd find that basically we what happened is the appended new columns in here for the future.
They are looking one year ahead.
OK.
And they're giving you a trend.
They're giving you what's the price you know expected in the future.
It seems that the price actually going down I'm going to watch it again and plot it right now and see.
And the beauty about it then giving you kind of as well like a bound to get there.
OK.
That's my trend.
That's my expected value and that's my why hat lower.
And that's my white hat up upper.
That's the expectation.
That's the bound.
And actually when we plot it it will show us the balance as well.
Let's take a look and see how can we do that.
So if we go here we say OK let's plots figure equals to end of plots.
So we're going to plot what's contained within the M..
But I wanted to simply plug the forecast OK which is simply our data that we have here.
There's a number that's forecast and I'm going to pass along our X label.
I'm going to be equal to our date.
And I want to pass along my Y label which is equal to our price.
All right.
Let's take a look.
Beautiful.
That's incredible.
Okay.
Like even though it might be like you know actually it's actually very very accurate because now this
is a data that we have.
That's the data we have got up until you know March of 2013 per say.
And that's the expectation for the future.
Just looking into the future and trying to like you know like predict what's going to happen in the
future.
So you guys can see here.
This is the trend.
So the expectation is actually the price we're going to go down and it's giving you like kind of a bounce.
You know maybe the price maybe it will be between these two bounds per say but that's the trend.
You know that's kind of you know the prediction.
So you can make predictions into the future.
Obviously it's like you know it's it's very complex to actually understand what's happening in the background
but the overall idea is just trying to look back and trying to find trends within the data and that's
how they are trying to predict the future in a way using that profit thing.
All right.
What we could do as well.
We can view as one other figures within a circle it's a figure equals to m dot plots.
And it can plot components second circuit components
and I can use the forecast as well which contains all my data but I get some that and that's pretty
much it.
It's amazing.
So here is showing you the trend.
So that's our column here.
If you remember that was attending here.
So it's showing you simply what's what's the expectation.
So it shows that's the price this the data provided.
Right.
All right.
So that's the expectations that all that data is provided.
So they're predicting basically the trend we're going to be something like this.
And with that with these bounds in mind and here the yearly.
So you'll find that this is basically over the entire year.
That's kind of the that's kind of the trend.
You know like it seems like in January you know the price goes a little bit down maybe the lows legs
are low they go up up up the peak around October timeframe.
OK.
Well people you know maybe around fall timeframe with the crave avocados for example and then the price
goes down by January timeframe or like during wintertime.
All right.
OK.
That's great.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
Let's recap recap what we have done so far is that we were able to actually train our model using applying
the fit method on our end and then we're gonna.
We started to make predictions in the future and we extended basically the data provided into the future
by looking at 2019.
And here we were able to plot the data as well and to look as well into the future.
Check out the trends and check as well the yearly trend over the entirety and that's pretty much over
half of this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoy it and see you in the next lecture.