Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to walk you through the questions for the list.
OK.
So please try to attempt to solve them.
If not that's not a problem.
We're going to have a detailed video explanations of other solutions simply in the next event.
All right.
Let's get started.
So here we actually have around.
We have eight questions.
OK.
And the first question that we have here is that I give you a list that has names equal to Sierra Chanel
and Mike Ryan wholy Alex of Rob and asking you to print first second and last elements in the list.
That's what I wanted to do to sprint.
You know like Sarah Chanel and Prince Harry.
Okay.
I hope that will be.
Please step forward.
Your next question I'm asking you to again giving you the green much you seem pleased.
I'm asking you to print all elements in the list.
Print Chanel metaldyne which is simply here for these elements.
They print the first three elements which is these the elements print the last three elements which
is here.
And Skip each other element.
Again we didn't cover that.
Simply I want to print it say ceara and then skip Chanel pretty much skip orionis slipped into holy
and so on.
We did a cover that again there's kind of you know one in an extended research that you need to do if
you can do it that's fine we can Willow.
We're going to walk you through it in these solutions sections.
All right.
The next question is I wanted to print sallie's.
SARAH Sally Jo and then print Ali for example with two different ways.
Okay.
Like cream.
The last element here in two different ways.
Again this kind of exercise for nested list which is a list.
All right.
Inside Inside the big list here that we have here again we have couple of a couple of examples before
in the concept lecture and you guys would find it that's true for the next question that we have.
I wanted to print the length of the list and add your name to the list which is kind of you know we
do kind of exteriorly search using the append here method.
So simply I have my list here and I'm asking you to print the length of the list.
We cover that.
That's easy.
Add your name to the list.
I want you here the end to just add your name on top of it.
OK so I have to use the pen here method somehow.
Again this is kind of a more of an externally research just for you guys to you know practice a little
bit.
How can you actually go ahead and look for additional concepts that are not covered within the lecture.
OK question number five is we want you to remove the name Peter.
So here we have I wanted to remove this knee from the list using two different methods.
Again this is kind of you know an extended search.
I wanted to use the Remove method.
Any medium we use as well delete or to Dell.
OK so just how can you actually delete a specific element within your list.
There's a lot of the research here and this exercise no problem no worry.
Again the objective is for you guys to practice as much as you can using stuff or topics that are not
covered within the lecture.
The next exercise I wanted to be sordid elements in a list and be versed on elements to go from maximum
to minimum.
So I'm giving you here a list I want you to sort it.
OK.
So I need to apply again kind of a sort method printed.
And I want you to again reverse it so make it you know it's going from minimum to Max.
I want to go from Maximin.
All right.
Question 7 I wanted to create a new list that contained the last elements in the nested list.
So simply put I want I wanted to do it they want you to print the last elements Only with chocolate
on the OK potatoes and protein bar right.
Try to figure out here there's no it's in the least Shiria we covered that in the in our election.
And the last exercise that I want you to create a list of with five of your closest friends and sort
them at phonetically.
So you need to just create the list whatever names you have of your closest friends and sort them in
and out for better or right.
And that's pretty much all what I have with this lecture.
Good luck.
I hope you guys we're going to enjoy that.
And if not again if you get stuck Don't worry.
We're going to have detailed explanations in the solutions lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
See you in the next hour.