Hello everyone.
Welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
I'm going to walk you through the exercises questions for dictionaries and bullion's the cake.
So they're going to be tons of fun I hope because we're going to have lots of fun doing doing the the
exercise of sport.
So just let me walk you through it really quick.
So here's the first question I'm asking you to create a dictionary we see of your favourite friends
and their respective age and print of the age of the second name you choose.
Just print whatever names along with our age.
And that's pretty much what we wanted to do.
Just got kind of you know quick exercise to test your skills on how we define a dictionary.
Right the next question is I'm asking you to create a dictionary.
We see you or your favourite friends and their respective hourly wage let's say twenty five dollars
three dollars whatever an up the average of all their salaries.
OK.
So this question is I'm asking you to update the previous dictionary with two of your next favourite
friends.
So now I need five friends and their respective senators as well and the average of all the salaries
of you know how can you add elements to an existing dictionary.
We've done that before.
Question for asking to write a code that multiplies all the elements in the following dictionaries so
we have this four specific dictionary and I wanted to multiply all elements in here to question five
for each of the students lists below.
Calculate the average mark for the midterm and final exams for each of the students.
So for all the midterm and final exam I wanted to calculate the average of that K and put the average
in a separate dictionary along with the student I.D. so simply I need to create another dictionary that
has a student I.D. along with the average of these two numbers.
Again this dude in a D.
And again and the average of these two numbers which is the midterm and final exam.
That's it get.
Question 6.
I'm asking you to repeat the previous exercise.
But the average in the new dictionary ok line with average as a key.
So I wanted to simply add another key value pair that has the average as a key and the actual value
as the add the value of the pick.
All right.
So Question 7 I'm asking two square each element in the following dictionary.
So basically take all that diction and try to square each elements in there.
Again please bear in mind that you know here we are within a couple of days before we here find that
there is a dictionary that has instead of having just single value.
Well having a list simply in in the position of the values are not just a single number.
We have a list which is kind of a little bit unique.
What I'm asking you to square each element in the following dictionary are in question 8.
I've asked you to create a list of all keys and a list of all values and the total sum of all values
of all this.
Again that should be pretty simple and pretty straight forward.
OK.
Question number 9.
I'm asking you to obtain the length of the following dictionary and so its elements.
How can you look in the lengths and how can you sort the elements within the dictionary.
Right.
OK great.
Question number number 10.
I'm asking you to filter out values that are greater than or equal to 30.
Okay so simply here have key value pairs and I'm asking you to filter basically through the values here
and only pick the number at a greater than it equates to 30 which is simply these values right 30 and
50.
Again we didn't cover that.
You know so so far you know what kind of advance.
That's why I listed it as advanced or kele to be covered in the future.
Again I'm going to walk you through it quick and you know and again if he didn't figure that out that's
fine.
We're going to walk you through it in the solution Section 4.
Question number 11 I'm asking you to basically tell me without running the code.
What will this go generate.
So here we have a couple of lines.
It's kind of testing you know your abilities on booleans which is how to generally true or false.
Alright that's pretty much all what we have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Best of luck and see you in the solutions.