Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited because in this section we're going to have tons of exercises related to functions
filters and lambda expressions.
All right let's get started.
So this lecture I'm just gonna walk you through the list of questions.
And again as you have done before be the next lectures we're going to have detailed explanations and
video explanations to solve all these questions.
Please make her make sure to just make an attempt to solve maybe a couple of questions in here.
And if you get stuck Don't worry we're gonna have tons of you know like solutions afterwards after this
lecture by the way.
All right let's get started.
So first I'm asking you to write a function that takes a variable and squared it.
So let's say if I send number three it will become 9 percent four become 16 then I'm asking you to test
the function by taking an input from a user.
So basically run the function as well not just write it to call the function to.
So for example I'm asking the user to let's say enter number number we use it into five and then the
squared a five.
We're going to be 25.
All right.
The next question is I'm asking you to write a function that takes two variables from the user.
So I'm asking you basically you going to enter let's say the first integer and then I'm asking the user
let's say to insert insert another integer and then I'm gonna send these two integers to a function
and that function should return to the summation.
And she was totally the multiplication as well.
All right.
Question number three am asking to write a function that takes a variable and return its factorial.
Because remember factorial let's say four is four times three times two times one.
Victoria let's say 10 is ten times nine eight seven and so on.
Question number four I'm asking to develop a script whose items are squares of the original list.
For example if I sent you for example one two three four five.
Here again I return the items we're going to be one for 916 and so on which is basically the square
of the first initial list right.
So question number five I'm asking you to write a function that squares a variable.
Okay that's the function and then I want you to test it.
Okay.
Using a list of integer numbers ranging from minus 20 to 20.
Okay so for example you're just gonna write define a function on its own that just squares a variable
that's you know that's separate and then you're going to test it using the list.
Okay.
Think of it as kind of you know the mapping if you as a member of the map function or the map keyword
along with a lambda expression again we can use it here to write our function.
All right.
Question number six I'm asking to write a three function that tick the radius of a circle and retain
the diameter area circumference and test the function using an input from a user as well.
Please make sure that this is not just one function.
I want you to write three functions all of them take the radius and return the diameter area and set
conference.
Question number seven I want you to write a code that takes a range from a user which is upper and lower
bounds and return a list of positive and even numbers only.
So I'm asking you to simply going to let's say the user insert let's say minus 30 to 50 and the user
will return a list of positive and even numbers so the numbers have to be positive and even like these.
All right.
So there is you know a bunch of if conditions in there along with you know the function as well.
Okay.
All right.
Question number 8 am asking to use the filter and lambda expressions to write a code that takes a list
of numbers below which is these numbers and return even numbers only.
So I wanted to return only even numbers so 622 120 and two hundred and two twenty.
Question number nine write a function that takes to an umpire matrices and return the addition subtraction
transpose product and dot product.
So he is simply undefined the two arrays and I wanted to do all these equations all these operations
on the actual matrices.
Okay I can write them in a function.
The lot of you know kind of practicing on how to multiply arrays.
I thought that would be very useful for you guys especially if you get to insert and put that into kind
of a function so kind of you know learning how to do multiplication with matrices how to perform different
operations.
And that's pretty much all the expected results that I wanted to see.
Okay.
There was maybe a little bit of research external issues because we didn't cover like matrices extensively
in this in the past.
Question number 10.
I wanted to write a function that takes two values from a user.
Some of them up if no values.
This is very simple right.
The key here.
If no values are provided.
Assume a default values of 3 and 5.
If guys remember we can set kind of a default values when we write the functions.
So that's the objective here is for us to exercise this part.
Question number eleven I wanted to write a script that will prompt a user for a range which is min max
value and returns a number that are divisible by 4 but are not multiple of 3.
So for example the user will enter let's say range from 2 from 30 to 200 and then he will get a return.
Basically these numbers the numbers that are divisible by 4 but are not multiples of 3.
We actually have we have pretty much the same example before in previous previous lectures but this
is just we can write it in a function if we wanted to and we can write in so many different other ways
or expressions of doing it to write the next or the last question.
I'm asking you to write a function.
OK define sorry and define in English to French translator function that takes an input from the user
and return the translation.
Right.
So here I selected for example five words you can select whatever word you want and what we wanted to
do is simply create kind of a dictionary.
You know from English to French.
Okay the dictionary can I think a war a word for instance and then we're gonna return the translation.
Just kind of you know more practicing functions and practicing a little bit of like you know dictionary
if you guys remember diction as before and that's pretty much the objective of this question.
All right.
Best of luck.
I hope you guys are going to figure it out maybe like a couple of questions.
If not then what about it next actually going to have detailed video explanations of all these questions.
All right stay tuned and best of luck.