All right.
Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's keep going and let's say hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's get started.
And let's start solving the questions for functions and filters and lambda expressions.
Let's go ahead.
So write a function that takes a variable squared it and test the function by taking an input from a
user.
OK.
So let's say can we write the function to say OK.
Define.
Def squared you can call it whatever you want.
And this functionally I think a variable X and we'll get a simpler return x times x.
Right.
That's basically the function really simple.
Let's run it.
Okay.
Nothing happened obviously because he didn't call the function yet.
Let's take an input from the users.
Going to say okay that's a equals to
int and we're going to take an input from the user and the user are going to enter let's say enter a
number.
So we can ask the user to enter number and answer in a and then we're gonna do here we're going to take
a print and I want it to print let's say the square of something is something and we're going to use
the format because I remember format to pass along our variable a.
Okay.
Which is the value that the user has entered along with the call for the function.
And that's the beauty about it.
Now actually right here the function call.
So this line we're just going to go here.
Call the function and we have to send it an argument right.
So we get a call okay I'm going gonna call the function with its name.
If you guys remember we're just gonna get the exact same stuff here.
Copy it from here pasted.
So called the function with its name.
And I'm going to pass along the variable.
All right.
That's it.
Let's run that's enter a number let's say four.
And that's what we're getting the square to 416.
Looks good.
Let's run it again and number let's say 10.
The square of ten is hundred one more time square of let's say five is twenty five.
Perfect all right.
The next question is I'm asking you to write a function that takes two variables and obtain the summation
and multiplication then test the function by taking an input from a user.
I'm asking you to repeat it using lambda expression.
So basically I'm asking for two solutions in here.
All right let's do this.
Let's see the first solution ask you to define to say we can call it whatever I'm going to hit I'm going
to call it some multiply I'm going to pass along two variables X and Y Okay.
And the function going to return some equals to let's call it actually summation to avoid any desert
keywords when I say X plus Y.
Right.
And I'm going to call it let's say multiply and there will be X times Y.
Looks good.
All right.
And the function simply should return right.
So I need to return back to the main I need to return back these two summation and they need to return
back.
Multiply
all right.
Okay let's run.
That looks good.
And let's call the function.
So simply here I wanted to get two variables from the user right.
So I mean I need to get the first integer so I can take a equals to cast as an integer.
When I say okay input I mean ask Okay enter any integer.
OK.
And it's copy that again and let's put it here and let's call it B.
Right.
And yes it can enter let's say another integer right.
So these are going to enter into these two and now to the fun part.
Now to the actual call for the function so to call the function.
OK.
So we'll get a call this function so multiply again I'm going to call it again with its name right.
So I need to get the exact same stuff here.
Call it here right.
So going to call it and pass along the variables A and B right.
OK.
The function would work somehow and the function would return simply to parameters would get a return
let's call them whatever again information multiplication is called a different name.
Right.
And call it let's say a result of some.
And we're going to return as a result underscore multiply
o kay.
And let's go ahead and actually printed in The Secret print.
I'm going to say OK multiplication sorry multiplication
equals two and then curly brackets right.
Then going add K addition equals to curly bracket AGAIN.
RIGHT.
GONNA TAKE A DOT format right and I'm gonna pass along these two parameters simply results and the result
summation and result multiply actually to make sure we're in the same order so we need to do result
multiply first and then the solid result submission.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
Let's go ahead and run it.
So let's run this one first looks good.
Let's run this one for a second sorry and so forth and then enter another integer.
Let's say five looks good.
And let's run that very well.
The multiplication is 20.
Which is four times five is 20.
And then addition is nine.
All right let's run one more time let's say 10 and let's say 50 and let's run that that well multiplication
five hundred and summation is 60.
Looks perfect.
All right.
OK.
My next question here I am asking you to actually repeat the exact same question but using the lambda
expression.
All right.
So I'm not going to go ahead and repeat those.
I just wanted to repeat repeat the function part.
So what I could do using the land expression.
OK.
We could actually do know say OK I wanted to use lambda because remember lambda and then I write my
inputs.
So the lambda we're gonna take let's say two variables x and y and it's going to return back x plus
y because remember that was kind of how we write using that expression right.
But we need to put that somewhere.
I'm going to take a summation equals to this again.
Think of it read it that way lambda expression takes two variables x and y and that's column.
And that would be the feedback that would be the outcome which is x plus y and that would be back in
the summation.
Let's do the same.
Put it here.
And that would be X instead of plus going to be a multiplication and that would be going to call it
multiply.
Right let's run it.
K looks good.
So no problems.
And let's actually go ahead here and copy this.
Pretty much the same mistake in print multiplication addition.
But here that format here I actually need to call it with its name right.
So I'm going to call summation and I'm going to pass along simply whatever very values I wanted to write
whatever numbers they wanted to see they wanted to let's say send a for example in B which is the inputs
I'm getting from the user and result some I'm going to pass along as well a and b apologies that's a
and b.
All right.
So I'm sorry.
That's summation.
We'll call this right.
And here we have multiply all that multiply.
So that'll be my multiply and I'm going to be a and b.
All right let's test it.
So it's Sharon shift enter on that and on that and that's what we're getting we're getting multiplication
equal sixty addition equals four or five hundred.
Actually they're reversed right.
So let's go back and make this multiply and let's make this summation.
All right let's do it again.
And that's what we're getting it.
Multiplication five hundred and additions is sixty.
Let's test it again.
So please just I don't want you to be confused again.
These are kind of two solutions right.
So I'm going to insert two new cells into insert that put it here and maybe enters into let's say I
call it lambda.
OK.
And go here make it mark down and maybe add a hash tag.
Here's just to show you that is just you know the sequence.
Second Solution.
That's a different solution.
Right.
That's it.
Let's shift it.
Let's run it again.
Let's set to values.
Let's say 20 and let's say 40 and run the lambda expressions go he'll run it and that's all getting
we're getting eight hundred and sixty looks perfect.
All right.
The next question is I'm asking to write a function that takes a variable and return its factorial.
So if you remember from the factorial is let's say for three to four is four times three times two times
one.
So basically the stopping condition is one.
Right.
Well let's see how can we do that.
So what we could do is a little bit tricky but let's say I'm going to do they're going to say OK define
quality factorial and the function I'm going to take just one variable x.
Right.
And what we're going to say here.
I'm going to say OK let's return right I'm going to do here going to take a return x.
So since factorial is let's have a total of four is four times three and then you know it seems like
the idea of running a factorial and this again is a little bit tricky is you know like factorial let's
say a 5 equals to five times the factorial of four.
Right.
Think of it this way like you wanted to call the factorial several times in a way.
OK but every time I'm going to call the factorial again but you gonna subtract one from the original
number.
Let's take a look.
Okay.
Return x multiplied by and that's the tricky part.
We're actually going to call the exact same function again which is really look strange about two here
we're just going to pass along minus one instead.
All right.
Looks looks crazy but you know let's see what's happening here.
So I'm going to say okay factorial can take number four.
Go here the function return four times factorial again of Four minus one which is three right.
So again I go back.
Call the function again.
OK so the return we're going to call the function back again.
You know we're going to keep doing this.
It's crazy again.
Right.
So keep doing this right until you actually stop.
This has to be a stopping condition somehow.
So the stopping condition can be OK if for example you found x the number is zero.
So if he found that he actually reached you know like the end.
OK.
So can I return one.
All right.
That's it.
So once that's pretty much it.
So what we're going to do here going to keep repeating.
You know like doing that factorial thing until you actually subtract the finger each one right.
So one minus one.
We're going to be zero.
It's going to call the function with zero.
Go here.
If X equals to zero that's true.
So I'm going to return one.
So the function here is going to return one in here.
But you already have the entire result.
Right.
So that would be the entire results return it back to the mean again.
Looks crazy but let's test it.
So let's run it.
Okay looks good right.
No errors which is good but obviously it might be looking all like garbage at the end.
Let's test it's going to say okay x equals two let's call it the different variables call X equals to
eight equals two.
It's going to say okay
we're going to say here's input and let's say for example enter number right.
Let's close.
That looks good.
And I'm going to say Okay print we're going to say factorial of something is something right.
And I'm going to say dot format because remember I'm going to pass along the variable a.
And again we're going to call the function factorial and pass along the parameter a That's it.
Let's test it.
So let's run it along for.
Going to turn back 24 which is four times three times two times one.
Right.
Amazing.
Let's run it again with maybe simpler numbers.
Let's end should three.
That would be the answer is six Why.
Because three times two times one which it's six and the one more time it's done for example 10 return
the crazy number you know 3 6 8 8 0 k looks good.
All right.
That's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And when next lecture I'm going to keep going.
And please stay tuned.
Keep solving the rest of the questions.
See you guys in the next lecture.