Hello everyone and welcome to this section and this section we're going to give you a brief introduction
of penders and then going to see how can we use penders Within Python this simply is what we call a
play called The the excel within python.
You can use it to deal with tables you can use it.
It's extremely powerful and we let we know I'm going to cover tons of examples here in this section.
So in this section we're going to start with a pen there's basics and then we're going to see how can
we access elements use the indexing.
How can we get let's say see is the file how can we appeal.
H.t. Emails beta How do pandas or politicians apply function sorting and ordering an concatenating concatenating
emerging as one.
All right.
Let's get started.
So first how can we up imported penders to do can import pend there's a speedy you can again there's
kind of the tradition that we do as again are very similar to important umpires.
MP You've done that and then there's a first step is the loading and then right now what are you going
to do with there one going to define let's say toolis first lists that compares the actual values that
we're looking for.
So let's assume that I'm looking for let's say fruits and vegetables fine my list equals two square
brackets he has one final key what a melon or engine Apple.
And then here I can actually specify within the penders leader frame or C it isn't going to tell you
exactly what they mean by this.
You can you just perspire a label you can specify a label for each of the elements.
So I'm going to specify a list.
Again another list and quality label equals to fruit.
Number one will stick in one string fruit.
Number two.
And number three.
Okay.
Let's on those two.
So now I have again my list which is again of all then and then I have a label which is simply hair
on fruit one two and three if they update the type.
Obviously we're going into two lists because you know you just haven't done much any penders anymore.
So what we could do.
You can define all quality pandas seeders spend this here is simply put you can store dealer you can.
It's kind of a data type that you can use.
They can actually stored elements in store as well labels for it.
Okay.
And then you can access these elements using the labels.
I'm going to tell you what they mean by that.
So in order to define is as again in pennies we're getting to see it is indeed a free Think of series
as you know just one dimensional column for example in Excel.
Think of a data frame as a two dimensional or a multidimensional table with an X out.
That's what it is.
It's very simple again.
So if you wanted to create pen this series out of the list what you could do with it can okay.
PD because we import penders a speedy dot series and then here you specify what's your data what information
you're looking for.
And what's the label or what index you're looking for.
So you could do it it comes off like a dealer equals to my list which is basically one of melon or and
Apple common and there's a spike index equals to a label which is this my colony here.
OK.
That will be my label.
That's we're going to be exercising my values and my elements.
And then you create it simply your X which is your data offering.
Okay so you create your seeders.
So simply put Now you have fruit one two and three you have watermelon autism and pi.
OK.
That's how you simply create the seedless.
Right.
The next step is we know we're not going to be using see it as extensively has been offering which is
a multidimensional and that's what we need.
We need to see how can we and can we use it.
So it's assumed that we wanted to for example define it in a frame or a penders in a frame.
And then call the data frame and then open he had parentheses here.
OK.
And then what I'm going to do you specify it I need employee idea that has let's say 1 1 1 2 2 2 3 3
3 and then comma.
Then ISPs fight employee meme which is a cause let's say chanels to Mitch and then he will specify it
say the celery and then use bespoke it's only 5 3 9 and 3 8 and he does have experience of three four
and nine.
If you run this and you plug the data frame then you can actually get something very similar to an Excel
table.
And that's what we've got here.
We got actually the first one which has the kind of the the tail which is employee I.D. And here you
have all the values you have one to and see which is you list that you can simply write it as kind of
a dictionary see a list a key and key and value.
If you go to a call where the key value period is when we defined dictionary you can actually define
it as one of the same fans in the same fashion he does.
But quite simply name you can write whatever you want.
He had celery you can specify and use of experience.
And that's how you come up with kind of you know like an Excel table Percy.
Once you have a pen there's a frame that it would be very powerful and very easy to exit or pin information
and do tons of tons of stuff with it as if you're you know dealing dealing in Excel you get quality.
I wanted let's say to show the head of show the first section you can call d.f. or did a frame dot head
because here you call it a frame sdf.
So now you can actually obtain our pile of dozens of methods to it and go get d.f. head and only two
they are going to open the first two rows.
What if on opening in the tail which is simply the last elements within a frame.
Okay d.f..
Teal one day out your key.
Is the last element within here which is simply the last element in it.
For one of the C D F tail two that will generate the last two rows and so on.
But I'll give d.f. head a lever there as is.
Then you will open pretty much the first couple of the first couple of rows as the head of the the different
alright.
OK.
So how can we actually access elements using indexing.
You can access elements within a day in a frame as follows.
Let's assume again I'm going to define my exact same data from my listicle what a minute or it is an
apple label fruit 1 2 and 3.
Again if I wanted to find a seeders going to call Wikipedia dotsie it is going to call it my data and
my index and undies that will do any X and then no one can access different values or different elements
in the video frame using its label.
So if I want to for example to an apple I can call it with its label which is fruit three which are
the label they have here for the apple.
If I write X and then it open.
Basically my square brackets here.
And then I can list what's my label is.
Okay then look it up.
Apple took this fruit number two then hung it up in the audience and sorts of our own.
Okay so now basically I going to work to have a quick overview.
No we can we know how can we define penders seeders and penders the error free using lists from a list.
From it the dictionary as one.
OK and how can actually x different elements within a be different are x.
What if I wanted for example to read C as he did.
And you get to read all the C is weedeater within it every hour.
So let's assume that we have a simple file and you guys are going to have access to that firehouse in
the course package.
So in order to read the data from the quality of the key PD dot read underscored C as V and then specify
the name of the file.
You don't see as V and then you get a lot in differing d.f. if you run this and if you plot the d.f.
then you would come up with basically all the elements that you had in your separate file.
Again it's loaded as if ignored Silicon excel format is very simple very powerful.
What if I want.
For example let's say you.
You can write again within a c v by Colin D F dot to underscore C is V.
And then you specify Okay the vva the file the name of the fight opportunity he'd call a simple update.
And if you don't know all this then then then you actually wrote data.
These exim data into this is very simple opport.
OK.
So let's assume that he wanted to a.
For example tables or a paper of data from a web page from each email for example.
So I guess you can see here have had this website called Canadian house housing prices showing let's
say Canadians see these average house prices for April 2018 and you can see there are two tables in
here.
What if I wanted to spin these two cables and load them within python in a day a offering.
You can actually do do they're using the Dot Dot believe H to amount and then you can specify the name
of the website you're looking for.
Okay.
If you on this then you would see that you actually took it successfully and then you can see within
the daily frame Yeah because they have two tables to connect to the first table by d.f. square brackets
0.
You can run there.
They'll tell you OK.
That's my first table and there's a table that you can see here gay Heaven coover Ahead of Ontario Calgary
Ottawa.
And we have all the average prices and here they have the 12 months.
Months change she'd have a fourteen point three percent increase which is you know kind of insane.
That's why you know the average house pricing vehicle which is crazy.
And then here if I want to talk in the next table I can up in d.f. Square America one that will open
again the House.
House prices changes which is my second table.
As you can see here for the Canadian this galien cities and there's getting in provinces.
OK it sounds great.
Now we can actually see any you use pen there's a frame deal to load data within from each meal.
A CML dealer website.
Next step is what if I wanted to perform some operations on delivery so it's assumed again I'm going
to find I paid a fee.
I would find that before again you know for kind of from a dictionary persay.
Yeah.
Define employee I.D..
Have all these employee numbers employee names.
These are all the names they have.
I hate to have my salary which is all the senators who have years of experience.
And then I can call d.f. and that's again my frame here.
What I could do is they can actually perform some penders operations by picking specific elements kind
of applying it if condition to select.
For example what if I won it let's say the role was that has no experience at then only graded them
would equal to three.
So I'm looking for this.
I'm looking for this and I'm looking for this straight.
I want to skip this B.S. so I could do that.
You can specify Okay I need my data free which is my d.f. you open square brackets.
And then I could do they can write you if condition hit pretty much okay.
What I'm looking for is I'm looking for the data frame with column years of experience this way.
D.f. square brackets years of experience.
And then this was folky.
The elements are greater than or equal to 3.
These are the elements I'm looking for.
If you run that then you will see you actually skipped that row here and you only came up with the first
three rows which makes complete sense.
What if I wanted to let's say delete a certain column for example as I wanted to delete let's say the
f employee.
I'm not I'm not interested in it you can actually call a Dell or a delete d.f. Square Beckett in plumy
idea.
If you run that then you're OK.
Then you actually got rid of this column.
Then you have an employee name.
You have the salary and you have years of experience.