Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited because now we're actually getting closer to finish the exercises for functions filters
lambda expressions.
It's really has been kind of a long you know like journey going through all these exercises and going
through the previous exercises as well.
Let's keep going.
So you know I ask you to write a function that takes two values from the user.
OK.
That's actually from a user.
Right.
And some of them up.
And if no values are provided assume a default values of three and 5.
So the actual summation is easy.
But I wanted two guys to remember how to do default values within the function.
So can we do that when I say could define summation.
I'm going to say OK X and Y.
Right.
I'm going to say OK.
Return x plus y.
All right.
Looks easy.
Do.
Going to say okay let's call that function summation.
I'm gonna pass along let's say values of five and seven on that and what we get is twelve.
Okay that's that's easy so far.
So what if for example you know I wanted to let's say call summation without sending any arguments.
If I do this for example I don't send any arguments.
Let's run that then.
Well I don't know I don't know what what you're doing right now because there are no default values.
So in order to set a default values what you could do here and say Okay X equals to four for example
he asked actually for three and five x equals three and Y equals to five.
So when you do this that means you are setting kind of default values.
That means if you run it again you'll get 12.
Right.
Because you actually sent the arguments.
So again if you sent arguments these arguments were going to win obviously but if you don't send anything
all right the default values will going to be we're going to be set.
So let's try it again and again.
And now it's eight.
Why.
Because we didn't send anything.
So you know the assumed OK.
Let's let's take the default values they take 3 and 5 as our default values.
All right.
That was pretty easy question.
Eleven I'm asked to write a script that would prompt the user for a range min max value I mean return
numbers that are divisible by four.
But I'm not multiples of three.
OK let's do it.
So how can we do that.
All right.
That's defined so going to say Min minimum very.
That's again kind of you know like revision review for you guys for the for loops and for if conditions.
Right.
So going to take a minimum let's call it an X score X let's say it's going to say input and we could
enter a mean number right or lower bound I can copy that copy put it here and send that to Max I'm going
to say enter a max number.
All right looks good.
What I could do here is you're going to say okay define my numbers right.
I'm going to set it to simply blank here.
I'm going to say okay.
For i in range between men on the score X and Max on the score x.
Right.
Because remember I'm going to say okay if you found that the number you got is divided by four and the
remainder basically was zero.
That means it's divisible by four.
And if you found that number if you take the numbers you divided by three.
Right.
I'm asking you if they are not divided the multiples of three.
If I divided by three and the remainder was not equal to zero.
Right.
What I could do I'm going to take.
OK let's go ahead and append that number to the actual number satisfies my requirements that append
an append simply my string of pi.
Right.
OK looks good.
And then afterwards I can go ahead here and simply print my numbers.
The idea here is to actually write all that in an a function format.
Let's actually run it without a function first.
All right.
Let's test it.
So if we run its end to the main number let's say for example 10 or 20 for his innocence maximum number
let's say 40.
And that's what we're getting we're getting the numbers 20 so number 20 actually was divisible by four.
Right.
Number twenty eight is divisible by four.
That's right.
So it was divisible by four.
So it satisfies all the requirements for the first one.
And it's not divisible by three.
Right.
So which makes sense.
All these numbers excuse me are not divisible by three.
All right looks good.
What we could do here the objective is to simply write that in a formal function so going to safely
define and what you could do that you can say let's say the number we call it let's say filters filter
numbers.
OK.
And actually it's called that filter numbers.
And that's pretty much my function here.
I'm going to tab TAB TAB TAB TAB TAB.
And you can print it here.
So that would be basically our function.
That's the overall idea.
All right.
OK.
Looks good.
Question number 12.
And the last one I'm asking is to find an English to French translator or a dictionary that takes an
input from the user and return the translation.
All right.
So let's see how can we do this.
So let's ask you to write the function.
So going to take it define and hit I called it dictionary.
I'm going to call it English to French.
And I'm going to pass along.
This function we're just gonna take a war a word that we're gonna be in English right and get translated
into French.
All right.
So what I could do here I'm going to say OK let's the function simply we're going to go and we're going
to return because remember that's a dictionary right.
That takes an English word could translate to French.
So the function is simply in return English underscore french I can simply call that dictionary right
and they can simply pass along here my word.
Hopefully that word we're going to be perfect rats are going to be happy for example of success or studying
or whatever.
Right.
And that's pretty much it that I can simply ask the user to input parameters so music Ward equals to
say input and I wanted to keep it as a string not to cast it as an integer.
Enter award in English in English.
And all right.
And what I could do.
Gonna see a print.
And they need to print simply the translation I'm gonna call my function in here I'm gonna pass along
my word in here which is the user has just entered all right let's test it let's run it let's run it
looks good let's run it into word in English let's assume that the customer or the user is actually
very perfect like you know he's very like he knows this.
These are the only five words we have so going to see a success it will tell me well that's the translation
is this translation.
Let's run it again through one word let's say love then well more as you know as the full French translation
of love.
All right.
What did they use it is you know like crazy for example decided Okay let's enter a new world.
It doesn't know that all these five words are you know like the only words that we have let's say insert
let's say like any word let's say and so I'm smiling for example smile and say well enter you know I
don't know what smiles because the smile is not contained here.
So what we could do here is we make that code better.
I'm going to say okay here we're going to do try.
All right so we're going to try this right.
What I'm going to say except
if you find any key error.
So basically if you find any error what we're going to say going to return to the user I'm going to
tell him the dictionary
does not contain this word.
Something like that and we're going to be my return back to the mean.
All right let's test it.
So let's run it let's run it and let's assume again I'm going to answer a smile or tell you well instead
of having that error signal we can actually or the error message which is not looks less scary we can
actually do with addiction does not contain this word.
Right.
What if you wanted for example to make it even a little bit better.
And for instance try to make it you know kind of not case sensitive.
So for example if the user let's say insert love which is the first letter was uppercase instead of
having all of it lowercase so if you do that to tell you well addiction does not contain this word.
However the addiction contained the word but just you know it's uppercase you know and worst case sensitive.
Right.
What we could do here we can say OK.
Dot lower.
And that should solve it.
That means whatever the input we're going to be the user going to be inputting we are actually going
to convert it to lowercase.
So he can compare it you know kind of apples to apples.
Let's run it let's run it.
Let's say the user entered all of them a love.
Well we get still the translations to the more.
That means we translated We went for first from uppercase to lowercase and then we have done the translation
afterwards.
All right.
Congratulations.
Now we finished the exercises for the functions filters on land expressions.
I hope you guys enjoy the lecture and see you in the next lecture.