Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I hope you guys were able to figure out at least maybe the first three questions that we have here.
So let's get started.
So here I am asking you what will this code generate.
OK so here I am asking is Python equals to Python and all of them here please note that all of them
here uppercase here we have the only the first letters uppercase and all of them here are lowercase.
So simply all letters have to match in order to generate true.
So that means here this is false.
Right OK.
The next question I'm asking is print is Python equals to python.
Well both of them looks good.
So here we are two you asking is Python not equals to python.
Well python is actually equal to python.
All of them they are exactly matching.
So I'm asking they are not equal.
Well that was false.
Right here I am saying is 15 not equals to 10.
Well that's true.
This statement is actually true because 15 is actually not equal to 10.
All right let's run that.
And that's what we got here.
False to false true.
Looks great.
All right.
OK.
Let's get good.
Keep going.
Let's go ahead to the next question that we are asking what will this code generate.
So let's assume that again we don't know what's happening here.
Let's see how can we analyze this statement.
It's going to say OK is hello not equal to Hello.
This is this First we have to analyze them one by one right.
I'm saying OK.
Hello.
Not equal to Hello.
Well that was true statement.
Right.
OK.
Because here not all of them are are the same.
Not all of them are uppercase for instance.
Mercifully end is six greater than two.
Well that was true.
It's five equals to five.
Well that was true as well.
So here they have two and true and true then the outcome should be true.
All right.
The next question I'm asking is print.
Hello.
Not equals to Hello.
Well is Hello.
This one not equals two.
Hello.
Well this statement is actually true.
Right and I'm saying or well they actually don't need to continue anymore.
Okay.
Why.
Because if one statement of one only is true.
That's it.
You know then the outcome or anything.
So here if I said let's say anything.
Okay.
Wherever Whatever value the output will be true and no matter what.
All right.
So basically both of them are true.
Let's run this through.
Let's run this.
The outcome is true.
All right.
Looks great.
Let's go ahead and check the third question here.
I'm saying OK what will this code generate.
Here I have X equals 20 y equals to 30.
And I wanted to see two print is X equals Y X not equal Y and so on.
So first is X equals to Y.
Well this statement is false.
Here I am saying is X not equals 2 y.
Well the statement is true right.
Is X which is 20 is 20 greater than 30.
Well that was false.
If is 20 less than 30.
Well this is true.
Is X equals to Y.
That was false right.
Please make sure to add the hash tag here.
So yes it is x equals two Y.
Well that was false and then or is X not equals 2 I am saying is X not equal to y.
Well that was true.
So if I say 0 or 1 the outcome will be true.
Right.
The outcome will be one.
I am saying is X equals to Y is 20 equals to 30.
Well the answer is false.
And I'm saying end is X not equals 2 y which is true.
Same the outcome should be 1.
Think of it again as multiplication multiply okay is one multiplied by a zero mystery multiplied by
1.
The outcome should be zero which is to be false.
All right let's double check.
So if we check that we'll see the case.
OK.
That is false.
False True True False True and then true and false.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
OK.
So.
So now we're able to.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the these first three questions yourself as well.
I hope you guys enjoyed that lecture and in the next lecture we to keep going with questions for up
till 10.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in the next lecture.