Know everyone and welcome to this section and this section we're going to do a lot of kind of fun activities.
We're going to see how can we visualize our data using meth plot lib.
Okay.
So first of all before I dig into the basic plodding techniques we're using meth plot lib this one to
go to that link first which is you know kind of the library the fundamental gotlib and you would see
that you can do tons of plotting exercises here.
It's an extremely powerful library that you can use within our Python and you can literally plot whatever
you want.
You can do really fascinating plots and all the codes are pretty much available for you.
You don't need to go when you're not becoming an expert you know in programming you can actually do
here you have an example for you find a job like for example like a heart for instance if you want to
do like a box plot if you want to do for example histogram if you want to do his to Glenn demos if you
do an error bar plots if you want a plot for example a different interpolations contour.
There are tons of you know like beautiful images and beautiful stuff that you can do here using their
plotly if you for examples.
Again that's just tons of dozens of examples that you can go and do it.
Obviously can cover all this because that would give me latenight least like 50 hours to go.
So they're all going to take a look at you know a couple of key key examples.
So there's you know wonderful examples to check the buyer bought a demo they can open it you will see
that you know how can this basically they're called if you copy the code and simply run it within the
GOP to modbook you will get the exact same results which is amazing.
Then you can apply to your data is very very easy and very simple.
So let's take a look at some practical examples.
Let's assume that a wanted for example to plotless say a sine wave.
Okay.
So I'm going to do an important maths plotly dot PI plot S P L T which is kind of the standard.
Again we imported an umpire in P We import Pand there's as PD We import their plotly the pilot has penalty
on this.
Then you imported it.
Now now we are good then you can use it here we important umpires MP and then what we're going to do
here.
I'm going to simply create an x and y.
So I need to create kind of artificial data and create an X simply by defining it that a pie array that
are evenly sample data at Stepney interval of point two seconds are going to go from zero to 10 with
the sepik interval of point two.
And that would be the value of X actually let's copy this let's create to win 8.
Let's do this and let's run this.
That would show us X action it's plot x 2.
Then you created x.
That's pretty much my X X as I'm going to create OK is zero point two point four point six and so on
and so forth.
Up until nine point eight or eight.
So what I wanted to do they wanted to I apply that specific function.
So on target or the sign of X and put them to Y.
So why equals to MP which is I've done that before dark side.
Ex Okay.
And in order to perform the plotting.
Actually let's separate that to unit X McReady in your cell.
Do this.
There will be the y value.
So now you have the y equals to sign X if you want to view Y.
Let's go and view why that would show us the values of why should only have the input which is our independent
variable.
And here you have a dependent variable which is my y axis.
OK the problem is that there looks very dry.
Looks very difficult to actually visualize it so what we need to do that we need to visualize should
plot it within the ship.
That's the beauty of of metalocalypse.
You can simply do plot P L T dot plot and you specify you x any specified way.
That's it as simple as that.
Then what you could do.
They can specify the label if you want to put let's say something on the x axis do X.
Describe what that signal is.
If it's time if its distance if it's whatever you can specify the date on the y axis and then you can
add the title as well to the grab.
Let's take a look.
If you do this.
That will give me perfect.
Now give me actually my input which is my x axis.
I'm going to show my y axis and he were going to show the data that a wanted or or the string that it
wants to display on the x axis each time I want to do here on the y axis sure it's sine wave and here
showed my tail my first plotting exercise on it.
OK.
Obviously what you could do I'm going to show you as well that later you can increase or change the
thickness you can change colours.
You can change you know and can do like really pretty graphs out of here and show you how can you do
that in the next section.
All right.
So we could do here.
We Let's see if one of you x.
That's my value of x.
So let's assume that we wanted to plot scatterplot which is simply I wanted to let's say create random
values for x around the values for Y.
And then when I plug them together okay it's not like like the irregular plot that we had before he
had passed the sign we just plodded like so several like go away points in a space so what would you
do here.
You know the final key n.p. around them to rent.
Okay.
For normal anomalies to data.
You'd have six hundred points that's for X here and the fine why again why your end.
MP The trend of the trend.
Six hundred and I again can use P.A. Keda and specify X and Y and here what it could do we begin to
create a figure and specifies whether the size of my finger can provide let's say fig size equals 2
7 and 7.
So if I do that that will generate simply my figured he'd want to make a little smaller.
Then because pacifies give four let's say four different one that will make it a little bit smaller
and you can make it obviously way bigger to 14 and put you're going to be crazy going be crazy big.
So how can you the size of the figure and plot scatterplot on it.
What if her wanted let's say to plot multiple curves or on the same on the same plot on the same figure
you can do that as well by plotting you know X value Y value common x value Y value common x value y
value and that's going to be on the same plot which is very powerful.
So again important point as MP.
Now partly of the pipeline does appear P.A. we have them there before and then humidifying MP to arrange
0 5.2 that will create again evenly distributed data with point to second sampling interval and he to
an engine in a Circuit City plot here.
Let's assume that one of the plotted say the V8 variable will itself so TNT.
I want to specify if say t n square N T and T CUPE for example.
And what I could do as well.
They can actually change is whether the the style of the of the of the curve of the deal.
So what I can do here and that's where the ON THESE We are elements come into play.
So let's assume that if wanted for example the first curve to be red so we specify R for red.
Then he has specified blue for B for Blue n g for green.
OK.
You can specify the line which says well he'd have the line with the 1 5 for instance.
You can also specify the actual style of that of the line.
So he defined one for example to have desch So to specify the style which is desch.
He just was fired say.
So going to be S10 for a square and here is that you know like hat stents for tilings.
If I had done this that would come up with this beautiful kind of graph.
As you can see you so have my linear line and then I have my square and then have my cube and you guys
can see that's dash.
These are squared and these kind of triangles go it an obvious and I'm going to have an entire section
just as explored.
Not all of these different combinations.
How can we change the width and can we change.
Let's say the columns and so on and so forth.
OK it's if I change the line with make let's say 15 on that you'll see the line begins way secured for
the last four for mainly 4.
For all the data.
If you go back here and it's it make it go back to 5.
He can change simply.
All this is going to show you how can we change him and create more beautiful growth than this.