Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's keep going.
Let's solve.
Question for you.
I'm asking Given that input dictionary which is key 120 key 233 550.
OK here I I'm asking you to write a code to select a dictionary elements that are greater than or equal
to 30.
So he was just going to obtain try to obtain the value here of the first element within the dictionary
and see the R equals to a greater than or equal to 30 or not.
OK.
And simply opt in that value and put it somewhere else here.
I just added a quick quick note here we haven't covered for loops yet we haven't covered how to do you
know a repeated operation yet.
Sheila I just wanted to do it manually anyway.
All right.
Let's see how can we do this.
Let's try a quick sample first.
All right.
So let's see how can we actually obtain the value within the dictionary if you guys remember from previous
lectures that in order to obtain let's say the number of the value of 20 here associated with that key
one we're going to call the dictionary with its name going to say OK input underscore dictionary.
OK.
And open square brackets and we're going to say OK I need the value associated to the key one.
All right.
First you need to run this to compute shift enter then run this shift enter and you come up with a value
of 20.
Okay.
When obtain let's say the second value I'm going to say okay instead of to make it make it so that one
to get to run it and you've come up with a value of 30 which is the value associated to that key here
let's try to obtain the third value.
So it will come up with a value of 50.
All right.
Looks great.
Okay let's go back to key.
So I want to do here is that we wanted to simply want to compare the value of only open the parameters
that are only greater than 30 right.
So simply I need to write an if condition I'm going to say okay if wherever value they're going to be
obtaining here right.
If this value is greater than or equal to 30 column right enter.
I need to obtain that value and prove it.
Put it somewhere else.
Okay.
And place it in a list right.
Which means here.
I need to create a new list right.
So I'm to simply go here and create a new list I'm going to call it let's say out okay for instance
and I'm going to initialize it as let's say empty.
So this is kind of an empty list.
Okay.
So what I wanted to do here I'm going to say OK I wanted to if the input dictionary of key one simply
if 20 is greater than 30 I'm gonna say okay out right Dot I'm going to use the append method.
Right.
And I'm going to say OK let's optimize that value which is input dictionary of key 1 which is the value
here.
And that sets appended basically take that value and append it just kind of stick it or add it to our
output list here.
All right.
Let's run this.
If we run it and if we take a look let's say it out.
And if we just shift enter you will come up with basically an empty array.
Okay.
Why why is that.
Simply put because 20 is actually not greater than or equal to 30.
And that's why the even if we on this condition the body of the F hasn't been satisfied hasn't been
rain yet.
Right.
OK so that looks good.
So this is the first step.
Again a here on what I'm going to do we're going to do everything manually OK.
This is kind of a very basic preliminary way of writing a code.
But here the idea is to try to teach you how to learn together how can we perform and if else condition
in a very simple format.
All right.
Let's do it again.
Let's repeat the exact same if condition but we're going to do a repeat it to all all of them right.
So I need three of them right.
One for key one.
One for Key two.
And if it's right out in key two and put it here I'm going to say okay let's go compare key three and
compare two key three looks good.
All right let's run it.
Shift enter.
Let's try it.
And that's what we are expecting.
We're actually expecting because 30 is actually equal to 30.
Right.
So this condition has been satisfied.
So we actually obtained the parameter and appended to our output list here.
So that's why you're seeing the value of 30.
And here's it since key three which is 50 was actually greater than or equal to 30.
The condition has been satisfied.
So we actually performed around the actual body of the if condition and we appended the value which
is 50 to the our output list and that's it.
That's pretty much how can we solve this question.
All right I hope you guys were able to figure that out.
Let's keep going.
Let's see.
Question five here.
I'm saying okay write a code that ticks a number from a user and compare it to a randomly generated
randomly generated.
So here this My apologies generated.
Okay.
No.
And simply state which one is larger or smaller.
All right.
So let's see how can we do this.
So there's actually speedy and I say advanced but a little bit like you know like there is lot of information
in here.
So what I'm going to do here I'm going to say OK I need to take data from the user.
When I say okay user which is a variable we're going to be obtaining from the user.
I'm going to get input and I'm going to say ask the user enter a number.
Okay let's say between 1 and 100.
OK.
All right.
Please bear in mind that the input we're going return the string right.
But in order because we wanted to perform comparison at some point make sure to cast it into an integer.
So whatever we're going to be getting here we're going to actually converted two into an integer.
Right.
And put it in the user here.
Let's run that and after you enter number between one 100 lists let's say say 20 plus enter and nothing
happened.
If you take it if you go ahead and check the user you will find the value of 20 which is what we have
just entered.
Looks great.
The next part is I wanted to compare that value to a randomly generated number which means I have to
use the random generator.
Right.
So to do that I'm going to say okay import gonna import random okay.
I am going to say OK let's use for example whatever value I'm going to call it let's say comparison.
OK.
Which is the random generated number.
OK equal to random dot Rand.
And so Rand ends and I pass along a number between 1 and 100 OK.
Let's run that.
Let's take a look at comp if we run it.
You will come up with the number 20 as well.
Let's run it again.
You'll come up with number 68.
One more time you come up with number 12 which is simply you are generating random numbers between 1
and 100.
All right.
That's perfect.
Now we have two variables.
We have the user which is the value that has been fed or input by the user.
And we have a random generator number called comp comparison.
And now we're actually ready to use our if else condition.
All right.
Let's see how can we do this math.
OK.
So what we need to do here we're going to say let's assume that we wanted to perform the if condition.
Going to say OK if you found the user value was greater than the comp value OK we are going to print
to the user let's say going to say OK the value you entered the value entered is greater than the randomly
randomly generated value all right.
OK.
Looks great here.
I'm saying OK.
Else if you found the user value was equal to the comparison value we're going to see Okay print and
we're going to say here.
Let's say value entered is equal to the randomly generated value.
All right.
OK.
Looks great.
And then the else which is the last one I'm going to say Okay print.
If it's not equal and if it's not greater then then obviously it's less then what is smaller then let's
do that going to say Okay print sorry print value entered is less or smaller than to make it consistent
with greater here and this is smaller than the random the generated value.
All right.
Looks great looks perfect.
Let's run that.
So when we're done it may tell you OK well values in the region enter the smaller than the random generated
number.
Why.
Because here you are comparing the 20 compared to 47 in this case.
Right.
So since 20 was actually smaller than 47 we only executed this on the right.
OK.
What we could do here to make a little of the code a little bit may makes sense.
We can actually print both values before going into the if condition we seeking every time going to
go ahead print.
And I'm going to say OK value view entered value entered is going to open curly brackets.
I'm going to say end randomly generated value is you know open another curly bracket.
And here I'm going to say if you guys remember a kid dot formats and we're going to pass along our user
value and our comp value which is simply here our comparison value our random integrated value is going
to be printed here.
And this is the user input.
We're going to be printed here.
If we read that again we're telling you okay your value you entered was 20 and the random generated
value was forty seven.
By comparing these two together the value entered which is 20 was actually smaller than the randomly
generated value.
Right.
It's make sure that that code actually works again.
Let's try it again.
Let's enter any value to say OK let's say 90 for instance let's enter.
Let's keep running.
So the value is 90 generate the random number the number is 36.
And let's run this one to Daniel will you.
OK value entered is 90 and generated value 36.
The value entered is actually greater than the randomly generated event which makes complete sense.
All right you guys can test that code like you know like hundreds of times if you want to just to make
sure that the code works.
And that's pretty much all what I have for the section.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And in the next section going to keep going and continue solving the rest of the problems.
See you guys in the next lecture.