Hello everyone and welcome to this section and this lecture.
We're going to keep going and solve questions 6 7 and hopefully 8.
If we if we can.
So I'm asking you to write a code that takes a number and indicates if it's positive negative or zero.
All right.
So it could do me to say okay x equals two.
We're going to take an input from the user which is whatever input I mean to say okay please.
Okay.
My apologies please enter a number.
And please bear in mind that that value has to be casted into an integer format.
If you're on that let's take it into number let's say 30 and we got the 30 number here and then we have
to compare if x is less than zero.
We're going to do something.
I'm going to say Okay print.
Well number is negative.
Right okay.
I say okay.
Else if if x is greater than zero going to say Okay print say number is positive.
Right.
And the last one I'm going to say else if these two condition not satisfied.
Well print the number is zero all right.
So here I entered 30 right.
Let's run that's going to say well the number is positive.
Okay let's try one more time.
Let's say for example enter zero and press enter and let's run that's but me well the number is zero.
Okay so one more time I mean to say for example minus 40.
Let's run it and let's try it again here.
Tell me okay.
Well the number is negative.
All right.
Perfect.
Let's keep going.
So question seven.
I'm asking you to write a script that will prompt the user for an input and check if the number is divisible
by five.
But not a multiple of seven.
OK it might sound a little bit confusing but it's actually pretty pretty straightforward.
Let's enter an integer or enter number or whatever and say okay I equals two ends and I say input apologies
inputs and we're going to say enter and number between 1 and 100.
Okay let's run that looks good.
Let's run it to 40 and list the check.
I make sure that actually makes sense.
I equals.
He looks good.
And let's write the condition here.
We're going to say OK here we wanted to see if the number is divisible by five.
If you remember to compare it to do this mosaic.
If and then I have to condition that I have to satisfy because here they have divisible by five but
not a multiple of seven.
So kind of I have two conditions two conditions this and this.
Right.
And if that condition is satisfied I can have dinner right the condition yet I say Okay print let's
say for example number satisfies satisfies the requirements.
And we're going to say OK for example let's say the number is actually divisible by five and not multiple
multiple of 7 which is the requirement.
Okay I am going to say okay.
Else if their condition is not satisfied I'm going to say okay for example print when I say no.
Does not satisfy the requirements requirements get and you can write for example numbers divisible by
five not divisible by seven.
Here too if you wanted to write.
That's the easy part.
Let's go ahead to that little bit tough than to say okay how can we check if the number is divisible
by five or not.
Well if you take the number if you divide it by five and got the remainder right.
If you divide by five and the remainder which is what you obtain is a member that mod here that basically
divide by five.
They take the number divided by five and obtain the remainder and see if that remainder was equals equals
to zero.
That means the number has been successfully used to be divisible by five.
So to save divide twenty five by five.
Well the remainder to zero.
That means Why.
Because that means 25 is actually divisible by five which is the first element here.
When I say end right here I wanted to say but not a multiple of 7 which means if I divided the number
if I divided it by seven and obtain the remainder right then I mean there should not be equal to zero.
I know it's still a bit confusing OK but that's pretty much how can you say it's not a multiple of 7.
That means that number let's say for example if the number is let's say 14 for instance OK.
Number 14 if I divide 14 by seven.
OK that means that the number is that I mean there is no remainder right.
The caution is to show that I mean there is zero.
That mean this condition is not satisfied.
Why could that mean number 14 is actually a multiple of seven right.
OK.
Any other number let's say four let's say 12 for example.
That's not a multiple of seven.
And so on so forth.
And that's it.
Let's run it.
So actually let's run it one more time so I can say okay let's enter number.
You know I'm asking to enter number say for example number 30 for instance let's run and let's run that
number 30 and let's run this.
Tell me.
OK.
Number satisfy the requirements which means the number is divisible by five.
And not a multiple of seven.
Well let's take a look.
So I enter number 30.
OK so number 30 if I divide 30 by five.
Well 30 is divisible by five.
Because you know the answer is six.
Right.
So I mean the remainder is zero.
However if you'd like 30 by seven actually.
There is a remainder right.
So that means a number is not a multiple of seven is not divisible by seven.
Right.
So number satisfy the requirement.
Let's run it one more time and let's enter for example 35 one at one more time one more time.
They mean well no it does not satisfy the requirements.
OK.
Why is that.
Because 35 is actually divisible by five.
Right.
So that I mean that is actually zero.
Let me that among number is divisible by five.
OK but thirty five is actually a multiple of seven.
Why.
Because if you divide 35 by seven you actually get an answer out of it.
Right.
And that's a very important concept.
That's pretty much what we're looking for here.
And that's why this condition has been false when we use the number 35.
You guys can test it pretty much on whatever values afterwards.
And that's pretty much conclude section question number seven.
All right.
OK.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lectures.
In the next lecture going to keep going and solve questions eight through 10 please stay tuned and see
you guys in the next lecture.