Let's take a look at that additionals plots.
Let's see how can we plot histograms or box plots so I could do here.
Let's assume that we have a bunch of variables so we have let's say a list that has 21 22 23.
And I wanted to plot a histogram histogram shows simply the frequency how many we get define basically
different bins.
Anybody specify how many how many numbers fall within these different individual bins.
So yes you can do that then.
First was specifying the number of bins.
So a number of beans he is five.
And here we did clot that hest for histogram he was specific Okay the X which is the variables and I'm
looking for specify the number of bints which qualify.
And then here you specify let's say the face column.
Let's strand that.
And that would generate this.
So simply put it you don't need to actually go and do the mathematics for us.
Just map plucked live you know end of the or the packages or the models that we have can do that for
us.
Okay so here you specify again because you have five bins and you simply counted how many numbers fall
between this is year 20.
You plug them and so on and so forth.
OK.
All right.
What if I wanted to change let's say the number of beans or chemical let's say 15.
You look at this you'll see that that's how the how can change the number of beans if you can make this
for example from red to let's say blue.
You can do it too.
You can make a blue.
You can again do tons of stuff with it.
Again it's pretty simple.
What you could do as well.
They can plot all of the box plots OK embossed plots.
You're just going to create kind of all I can ask for should data.
So I'm going to say OK I have data that has a mean mean mean distribution of 20.
And you have a standard deviation signal three and you're going to generate the data that has that mean
which is 20 sender deviation is what we call the dispersion from me.
How have disproved the data is the larger the standard deviation the more dispersed my data.
So the mean is 20 and they have all kind of the dispersion or extended deviation is around three around
me.
So we generate a simply random values here.
That kind of ground that mean and send elevation can create the green beans of 30.
And in the UP of the histogram some in a plot histogram of X number of bins.
And I'm going to show the face colours.
And again call the y label n the.
And the title to.
If you're not that that one shouldn't generate and my histograms you would see that histogram Because
you specified Rent N which is normally distributed of ten thousand semples.
That's why you get.
You get simply friend and enemy distributed data which makes sense.
The mean is 20 because the mean of the data is actually tending to make sense.
And you have a standard deviation sigma of three which really must make make sense to array.
And that's pretty much what we what we've got here.
So you have a number of bins of 30.
You plot a histogram and that's how can you kind of plot histogram as well.
This just kind of one other example of of a hue.
Yes well he has specified the tidal.
And that's what we've got here for the tidal Gates is find the new 20 and send their version of of three.
Right.
Let's take a look at another type of plot which is what we call it kind of a bot plot.
Let's see what we what we have this.
If you run this would come up with basically this kind of kind of graph.
How can we get that.
So let's assume that we have angry create kind of a sèvres of some nucleate let's say dealer 1 which
is MP.
The trend them look normal normally is to build a 120 10 n 2000 so any 2000 dealer sets and they need
one.
The base of the mean is 120 and that's why you see the the platzman 120 Senden deviation of pretty much
10 what you could do here.
And again these are the arguments get me there send a deviation and then on the distribution end the
number of values desired.
How many semples how many data sets you're looking for.
You create again another data that has mean of 60 that's where you would see when you plotted it means
60.
You have a standard deviation of 30 that's what you're getting here.
And 2000 semples too.
Again people telling them that normal 70 20 and 2000 45 and that's 40 and 5 and 2000 if you create or
you concatenate all that data in one list and then you can plot it using basically the box plots if
you get you create a figure as we've done before and then Figg dot EB subplots OK.
You can assure him of that line you need it.
And then what you could do here and create an axes because he you specified one one one you simply first
subplot that has just one finger an image basically.
And here is spy X's DOD box plot.
That's where you actually pass along the data and we'll do the wasp plot for you.
And that's the box plot you ask.
You guys can see here it's really very simple.
Again if you let's say change this to let's make it two hundred.
And if you run it you'll see the data has been the meat has been shifted.
If you change that send a deviation to let's make it 20 you would see that basically that windu here
should increase rate.
If you run it you will see that actually increase because the standard deviation pretty much increase.
Okay.
And if you to take a look at what do you mean by basically in these this graph.
So simply here you plug kind of the middle of the median here.
You plot the Q1 and Q3 that's what you're getting here which is kind of one sigma.
And that's one of the standard deviation you can see and simply put this three sigma.
So Hugh what you're plodding here these two what we call a thief three quarter of percentile.
And that's all we're getting here and all these diets all these points outside.
That's what we call an outlier okay again.
Unless you're doing you know extensive statistics you're not going to be using the the book's plot.
He doesn't want to give you an idea of how powerful we can use map of lip on it.
The next figures in its image are going to be plodding we have a lot lots of plots.
So what we're going to do we're going to see the plotting.
Okay.
So what we're going to do is get import axes Cedi.
Okay full of 3D plodding and it's assumed that it wanted to plot let's say X versus Y versus Z.
Let's see how can we apply kind of a surface.
It's really interesting and very kind of beautiful to plot a way you could do this and say okay I'm
going to create a figure of plot figure and specify the size you and then he's going to create an axis
basically.
And what we're going to do here are going to create these the deed and wanted to plot and he can specify
these cataloguing equality.
And when I plot axes Well xii's you can call it whatever dots care and pass along my values my the dealer
then wanted to plot you know going to best along X Y and Z.
And he going to specify the collar angle as specify the Micro's too.
And you can specify the labels as well.
That's blood that's and that's what we're getting.
Pretty interesting.
So you can actually view the data in a 3D format which is zeni powerful too.
All right.
If you wanted to change for example that blue and make it let's say red.
Mean then didn't see the markers.
No I did not make it.
Just keep it to keep it as it is and it's a safer that me change the size and make it let's say 10 by
10 and it's plug that.
That's what I get and give a little bit smaller and the dust becomes becomes stripped away.
What if I wanted for example to plot say well look at the way it's free.
Okay.
It's tough to explain it before actually viewing it.
So let's run the Alpha and the code and can explain it after it.
So if you're on the call do you come up with this what we call it a wire wire.
Wondering which side of you are plugged in the dealer in a 3-d format but has the kind of a white and
that is really pretty and through that kind of you know like I had to have like plot you know like go
for a presentation or something it's really powerful too.
And then here you have a plot the 3D 3D and I'm going to do specify the figures size specify the subplots
and I'm going to do here and say okay axes Cedi dot get test data point or fire.
That's just to get the data.
OK.
That's going to offer some test data.
If you have your data you can simply specific it that's my X That's my why there's Maisie an order to
call or deploy the wireframe you can use the Xs dot plot underscore the wireframe and then you can specify
Okay this Pipettes along with X Y and Z.
And here you go specify the stridency stride.
Let's assume that I make it let's say from 20 make it to hundreds for example and plot it.
You'll see that simply here it becomes a little bit smaller as you can see here.
If you make it let's say go back to 20 and that's what we're getting a little bit more details if you
make it let's see the seas try to make it a hundred.
You get again.
You will see that we dropped lots of lines in here.
Again that's kind of you know we can use depending on the dealer that you are plotting.
And that's where we going to using the plot underscore why free or it's.
One more one more plots let's actually plotted first and then go back and see what it would mean actually
to come up with these you know kind of pretty pretty graphs.
So in order to do that you need to create what we called the mesh grid.
Okay.
So in order to do it you need to define again X get you to the final why you wanted to create a mesh
grid out of ex-wife.
It's kind of like creating a grid in it each of the intersection of this grid a plot something in the
z direction.
So here we specify the key.
We're going to call a range of x and y.
We create n.p. from nump by mesh Dritte that would create our mesh see have no x and y that's kind of
a mesh.
And then he can plot whatever you want in the z direction here.
The actual plotting the sign of the square root.
X squared plus Y Square again it's kind of you know it's it's contained within the Python library map
gotlib library but you can do tons of activities just look you know look at it look up messengered and
Python you can you can do what one does with a concealer dozens of pretty graphs just give you kind
of an example.
Again it would be only going to be using vison actually in this actual course.
This one I'll give you an idea of how powerful these librans could be.
So here you can see a x and y npe The mesh grids.
You create the mesh.
And here you create you specify the function that you wanted to plot in the zede rection and then you
specify again you want to plot X's dot plot surface.
That's what you're going to get X Y and see and he to specify the coloured map.
You ran it again.
That's what we're going to get.
Pretty pretty interesting.
And the final plot they were going to be showing is were collop pipeline.
If you wanted to create kind of a pipeline showing a different kind of kind of portions within the pie.
OK.
It's kind of it's very valuable in when you're running for example different presentations or kind of
you know like a somebody of a it is very helpful except different values 2055.
This kind of a percentage.
Okay so then it's some up to 100.
Did you have different colours green red yellow.
How do you suppose the final got explode.
We wanted to for example emphasize specific let's say pie within the pipeline.
Know make it let's say stand out I'm going to say what do you mean by that.
And here you have lithic a couple of countries.
Egypt United States Canada China Europe that's kind of the labels.
And what you could do they can create the pipeline out of it.
You can see the pie.
You can specify the values some of the values.
That's kind of how you divide your pie.
You can find the colours which is what we have.
You specify the labels which is you know kind of the country's going to be plodding and explored if
you wanted to have nor certain section are going to be coming out of it.
Let's say on it and that's what gets political.
Countries that seem pretty much tidal that we have here.
And that's what we got here.
So these are the different percentage associated with the counties you have 20 to say for example Egypt
three percent for example for Europe.
That's what we're getting here.
And because we selected explodes for the last one.
That's where you see Europe coming out of it.
If you want to make this for example point five that would show that you are actually supporting you
know the empire you stipulated the United States is the second one here.
You separated it you make it look kind of you know out of the out of the room or emphasize emphasis.
I put more emphasis on it.
That's pretty much how can you plot your pie.
I.
And that's pretty much what I have for this section.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in the next section.