Welcome everyone to this quick lecture we're going to give an overview of the curriculum for this course.
So we're going to go over the curriculum that way you can decide what section you want to jump in.
The sections are modular so you can either go through the course from the beginning all the way to the
end or you can just jump into whatever point you feel most interested in.
So let's start off with the basic overview of the course.
We start off with three sections that are non-technical sections that talk a little bit more about a
high level overview of what it's like to start the day to science interview process a little bit more
information about data science careers in general.
So the first section is just the data science career overview there we talk about things like Why choose
a career in data science the interdisciplinary aspect the data science different positions and titles
that are in data science fields as well as thoughts on higher education and it's value to those positions.
They will continue on to the interview preparation section to a science interview preparation.
That section is actually still not technical.
What it involves is talking about what technical tools you should know what theory should know things
about machine learning different software that may be useful to you and how to know when you're ready
to begin the interview process in general.
After that we have our last section that's not technical which is just an overview of what to expect
for the data science interview process.
These are things like how to prepare your resume what the interview pipeline is like how to land interviews
and if everything goes well how you negotiate offers.
After that we have the main part of this course which is the interview questions and solutions or answers
to them.
So that actually has several sections to it and that's really the bulk of this course.
So the interview questions and answers we have tons of topics for you we have questions on probability
theory statistics product analysis and business metrics working of data.
Q Well coding questions machine learning and design of experiments.
Now keep in mind certain sections are very technical and they're either right or wrong answers to things
like probability theory statistics work and if they do a fescue Well there are going to be kind of the
questions that there's only really one correct way to get back a correct answer for other things like
product analysis and business metrics or design of experiments.
There are going to be much more freeflow questions so we'll discuss kind of a higher level overview
how you can approach those type of questions.
But keep in mind a lot of those questions don't have one particular right answer the way a math question
like one plus one equals two is instead a lot of times in the interview process for a data scientist.
You'll be presented with just kind of a basic product idea and then you'll be asked to come of some
metrics some experiment design some models ideas etc. on how do we evaluate that new product or business
idea.
So some of these questions are a little more open.
Some of them are going to be a little more close to try to reflect the rerolled situation of what to
expect in a data science interview.
So that's really the bulk of the Course here.
Now I want to be clear about what this course is not.
This course is not an overview that's going to actually teach you probability coding statistics or machine
learning.
Instead we're really only providing questions and solutions for those topics.
Now we do provide a lot of great resources that if you want to review those topics and learn more about
them like probability and statistics we're machine learning will have plenty of links you to check out.
But the Course itself cannot teach the entirety of data science in just one course I do have other courses
that are really great fits for learning about coding or machine learning or probability or statistics
and we'll also link those as well so you can expect tons of resources tons of leaks as you go through
this course.
But I want to be clear this course is definitely not going to be able to teach you all of this.
Instead of really only provide the questions the solutions for those topics expect you to learn them
elsewhere.
OK.
Let's get started.
I'll see at the next lecture.