Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to briefly discuss why you may want to choose a career in data science.
Data science is a field where you can create huge impacts by leveraging some key fundamental ideas from
mathematics and coding and being able to extract key insights from data to help build a better future
is really one of the most fulfilling careers you can have.
Now often people only associate data science with large tech companies like Amazon Google or Facebook.
But almost every industry can gain a substantial advantage with data science and you'll begin to notice
that even companies like Wal-Mart or industries like pharming or dairy they all really need data scientists
to help give them the advantage.
Now there's also many positions that relate to these ideas in this field that aren't particularly called
data scientist and we'll discuss that later on in a lot more detail.
Now besides the cool aspects of being able to leverage data to gain key insights There's also the great
benefits salary wise and compensation wise that come with a data science career.
Now according to Forbes jobs requiring machine learning skills or paying an average of $140000 and that's
a national average for areas of higher cost of living it goes up much more than that.
Now advertised data scientist jobs pay an average of a hundred or five thousand and advertised data
engineering jobs pay an average of 170000.
So you can see here you're getting really great salary compensation.
Not to mention a lot of the benefits like health care or stock options that also come with these sort
of career paths.
Now annual demand for the fast growing new rules of data scientist data developers and data engineers
are going to reach nearly 700000 openings by 2020.
So there's also a huge demand and there's a huge job market for this career path.
And by 2020 the number of jobs for all U.S. data professionals is going to increase by 364 thousand
openings to 2 million 720000.
According to IBM.
So the top reasons for a data science career is that the work is fulfilling and interesting.
There's really interesting technical topics if you're interested in learning about machine learning
you can learn bleeding edge scientific techniques to in order to gain insights from that data.
It's also in really high demand has great pay and benefits and simply it's just awesome.
OK.
Let's go ahead and continue our discussion on data science and how it's interdisciplinary.