Welcome everyone to this lecture on theory knowledge we've already discussed the technical tools of
the trade such as programming languages and software tools but general knowledge of the core concepts
about data science and the mathematics behind it are actually even more important than the software
tools used.
Let's cover some of the key concepts you should know when applying sort and begin by discussing some
of the more basic methodical topics you should understand and keep in mind.
Few people are complete experts in all of these.
You're going to constantly be learning more on the job as well.
You should just have a general understanding of the basics of these topics.
So some of the mathematical topics you should have an understanding of when applied to data science
positions are things like calculus linear algebra probability theory as well as statistics such as a
typical inference and distributions and also descriptive statistics things like means of standard deviations.
Now there are specific mathematical topics that you may need to know depending on what position or what
company are playing to.
So social network companies such as LinkedIn or Facebook really want to check they have a good understanding
of graph and network analysis.
Sometimes those topics aren't so important for other companies.
Companies that do things such as heavy advertisement testing or AB testing on Web sites are once you
are going to test your knowledge base in statistics and AB testing in general.
So definitely check out the research links for great online resources for these topics.
And as a reminder again few people are an expert in all of these topics they the science is definitely
an interdisciplinary field.
You just have a general understanding enough so that you can know where to look things up when you need
to dive into these individual topics deeper.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.