Welcome back everyone in this lecture we're going to discuss software engineering knowledge and we should
be aware of so coding and programming are going to be a major part of your day to day activities as
a data scientist and in a lot of data science rules.
So let's go ahead and discuss what you may encounter during an interview so during an interview depending
on what kind of company it is you may be asked questions on algorithms and data structures.
Now algorithm and data structure questions are typically associated with something as a general software
engineer role and there's already lost courses and books that discuss the best way to prepare for those
interviews.
That's in a state of science is still relatively new for a lot of companies and they're just starting
to build out their teams a lot of times they don't interview data scientist positions as they should
based on probability statistics or machine learning or just basic coding.
Instead they treat it more almost like a general software engineer position.
As far as the interview process is concerned so be aware that depending on the company you may be asked
questions that are concerned with algorithms and data structures things that you don't typically concern
yourself with as a data scientist but you may be asked these questions in an interview anyways.
Then there's also questions based on Eskew and databases.
Now these are really common data science questions.
And if you're applying for a science position it's highly likely that you're going to be asked just
a general knowledge question to test whether or not you know as school or sequel.
Don't worry too much about the different syntax or flavors of sequel things like My sequel postgresql
sequel or Microsoft's sequel server.
That's not really that important.
What's important is that you understand the fundamentals of.
Q Well because regardless of what position you're in it's very likely that the way you interact with
your data warehouse is going to be through some sort of a query or structured query language.
Now again the pinning on the position if you end up dealing with a larger big data sets you may need
to have some knowledge about Sparc and distributed computing.
Spark is definitely one of the higher players here distributor computing.
But then there's also languages or frameworks like Hadoop that you should be aware of as well.
Again that is really more specific to each individual job postings so just keep an awareness of that.
Then you also need to know things like data visualization products or services so maybe they're working
a particular service like plot Li or Tablo and they want your expertise in visualizing data using that
particular software tool.
That's another thing that you'll check the job posting for.
OK.
So again interview focus on this knowledge really depends a lot on the company and position.
So you'll need to be able to connect the job posting with what skills you should learn.
So now you should have a clear understanding of the various fields of knowledge that you'll need to
be familiar with as you venture onto your data science career.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.