Welcome everyone to the probability theory interview questions section of the course.
Let's work through some example interview questions that relate to probability theory in one way or
another and often these questions when you're being asked in an interview setting either use coins or
dice rolls to test your knowledge of some sort of key points of probability theory.
Keep in mind that these are sometimes some of the most difficult interview questions.
They're also often used during the technical screening phase and based on my own experiences as well
as the recruiters I've talked to here in Bay Area tech companies you'll often hear in a data scientist
technical screening phase.
So that's after your initial phone call but before your onsite interview some sort of probability theory
question.
And in my own experience when I was interviewing at Facebook and Google I've been asked questions and
we're actually going to see those questions later on in this course.
So let's go ahead and get some practice with basic probability theory interview questions.
I'll see you at the next lecture.