Welcome to interview question number four for probability theory.
All right this question is a little more involved.
So let's take it slowly and explain the entire situation.
Let's imagine that you have two jars.
So there's a table sitting with two empty jars on top of it.
Then you have 50 red marbles and 50 blue marbles.
So someone hands you a bag with 50 red marbles in another bag with 50 blue marbles and it's up to you
to place all the marbles into the jars in whatever distribution you want such that when you blindly
or randomly pick one marble out of one jar you maximize the chances that the marble you ended up choosing
was red.
So let's actually break this down a little bit to fully analyze the situation.
So again you're given 50 blue marbles and 50 red marbles and there's two jars on this table.
So it's up to you to distribute the marbles into the jars however you want.
The rule is you have to place all the marbles in a jar so you they a marble has to be inside a jar so
you can place them however you prefer.
And then what's going to happen is when you Bliley pick your first going to randomly pick a jar.
So to give you a hint the odds of any jar being picked is 50 percent right because we're randomly choosing
between two jars and the next step is that you randomly stick your hand in that jar and pick out a marble.
So the question is what's the best way to distribute these collection of 100 marbles 50 below 50 read
between the two jars to maximize your chance of choosing red.
OK.
If you have any questions on this one because it's a little bit more complicated of a setup.
Please feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I'll see you at the solutions.