Welcome to probability question number six.
And the solution for it.
So just to go over the question real quick again.
You're given a fair coin.
On average how many flips would you need to get two heads in a row really similar to the first question
and our probability set.
Our specifically only wanting two heads two tails won't cut it either.
So is actually lots of ways to solve this.
A general solving for any number of heads in a row is more challenging.
But since we only care about two heads in a row specifically it's going to be a little easier.
If you want more resources on the general solve for kind of the nth toss of two heads in a row you can
check out the guidebook for resource links.
But for now we'll focus on the actual probability question that was asked.
So keep in mind our falling method is not generalized.
It only works for two heads in a row.
So we'll go ahead and say let the expected number of coin flips be defined by the term X..
So in the case analysis is going to go as follows.
If the first flip is it tails the already wasted 1 flip because you're looking for specifically two
heads in a row.
And we know the probability of this event occurring of the first flip being tails is one half and the
total number of flips required is going to be X plus 1 because he basically just wasted a flip.
So the first flip is a heads and then the second flip is a tails.
Then you just wasted two flips because that tails basically blocks that first flip of heads from being
used and the probability of this event occurring is one fourth and the total number of flips required.
Now after this is going to be X plus two
if the first flip is ahead and the second flip is also heads then you're actually done.
So the probability of this event occurring is 1 2 or 4.
So the total number required for this particular event was to.
Adding these all up into the expectation equation allows us to do this sum.
You get 1 1/2 times expl one plus one fourth times x plus two plus one fourth times two.
And for this result we're getting two heads in a row we end up seeing the expect the number of flips
is going to be equal to six.
And if you're a little hazy on the expectation equation make sure to check the guidebook for resources.
They'll explain it to you.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.