Welcomes the solution for the seconds to stick's interview question.
So this question was about that quantum messaging system and you had a probability of 0.8 success in
any attempt to send the message through and you want.
Luckily having seven successes and 10 attempts and the hint was to look at a binomial distribution and
a binomial distribution is a very common distribution to be tested on in an interview setting.
So you definitely want to have this formula memorized going to show later on if you're in an interview.
He should also be aware of if you're ever in a situation where the question being asked gives you a
probability of either success or failure.
You trying to figure out something happening and a certain number of attempts the binomial distribution
is typically going to be a really good way to tackle that sort of interview question.
So keep that in mind in case you ever hear those key words of probability of success probability of
failure or attempts OK.
So let's briefly discover what a binomial experiment actually is.
So by no the experiment is one that possesses the following properties.
One experiment consists of and repeated trials so that works for us because we have and repeated messages.
Number two each trial results in an outcome that may be classified as a success or failure.
That's also true for our case.
And then 3 the probability of success denoted by P remains constant from trial to trial and repeated
trials are independent.
That's actually noted in the phrasing of the problem if we go back here in the probability of success
and any attempt to send the message through.
So that's basically telling you that the messages are probability of success is independent of the previous
message.
So the number of successes acts in end trials of a binomial experiment is called by no middle random
variable.
And basically what we're getting at here is this binomial probability distribution actually has an equation
that you can use for the probability of X being equal to k.
Has that formula right there.
And that's going to be for that little and overcame princes.
That's simply just the combination formula.
Where and is the number of things to choose from.
And you're going to choose k of them.
So there's no repetition.
Or does it matter for combinations and it's equal to this formula.
Right here and factorial over K factorial times and minus k factorial and then P remember the probability
of success.
And you can think of one minus p as a probability of failure.
So that means if we're playing this and the probability of success is P equal 0.8.
So that means Q which is equal to one minus three.
Q Is the probability of failure is equal to 0.2.
So now we're looking for the probability of that random variable x equal to 7.
So we have seven successes and that's going to be the combination ten seven times 0.8 to the power seven
times probability of failure 0.2.
The power of ten minus seven.
And if you calculate that all out you get 0.01 3 3 and hopefully the interviewer doesn't actually require
you to get out a calculator and actually calculate this out.
They're really just looking for that second line and seeing that you understand how you can convert
that word problem to the binomial distribution.
OK.
So if you do that by no is tradition formula that should have been a very straightforward problem.
If you need a refresher on that go ahead and check the links in the guidebook.
There are some great resources there for you.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.