Welcome back.
For question number four.
In these statistics interview section.
So this question has a little bit of setup.
It first begins with a new medical test for a virus being created.
Now over the entire population 1 percent of the population has the virus.
With this medical test.
Ninety nine percent of sick people with the virus will test positive.
That is they test positive indicating that they have the virus.
So ninety nine percent of people who actually have the virus and are sick with it test positive using
this new medical test.
Ninety nine percent of healthy individuals test negative for the virus.
Now here's the question.
If you grab the patient not knowing whether or not they had a virus and you administered this new medical
test and they tested positive what is the probability that they have the virus.
Given what you know so far.
So you know that overall 1 percent of the population has the virus.
Ninety nine percent of sick people have the virus test positive and 99 percent of healthy individuals
test negative for the virus.
So if you took a patient and they happened to test positive what is the actual probability that they
have the virus.
This is a very common question.
So best of luck and make sure you understand the solution for it.
If you weren't able to get it on your first try I'll see the solution.