Welcome everyone to the solution for Interview Question number four in the statistics section of course.
So again for this question you have this new medical test and this is a really common type of interview
question especially to test your understanding of statistics and things like accuracy precision and
recall and how to judge a experiment or the results of an experiment correctly.
So you'll often see if is a medical test but be aware there's other kinds of ways to frame this question.
At the end of the day you're trying to figure out some probability.
In our case we were trying to figure out the probability if a patient had tested positive that they
actually have the virus.
So just yet another question or we can use Bayes Rule.
Again very popular interview questions so let's walk through the steps how we would do this actual question.
So we know the probability of being sick in the population is 0.01.
And we also know that 99 percent of sick patients test positive meaning the probability of testing positive
given that you're sick is going to be equal to zero point ninety nine.
We also know that ninety nine percent of healthy patients test negative.
So the probability of testing negative.
If you're not sick it's going to be point nine as well.
But we want to solve for is the probability of being sick.
Given that you tested positive so using Bayes rule we can frame this in the following manner.
The probability of being sick given that you tested positive is equal to the probability of being sick
multiplied by the probability of testing positive.
Given that you were sick divided by the probability of testing positive.
Now we can actually calculate some of these things that we need particularly the probability of testing
positive.
We know the probability of testing positive is going to be the same as will say of testing positive
when they are sick.
Multiplied by the probability that you were sick plus the probability of testing positive given that
you were Nasik times the probability of being not sick basically adding up the populations of sick and
not sick and that people tested positive with them.
So if you do the math there that ends up being well to 0.01 9 8.
So if you plug that in back to the previous base rules that we had over here we already knew the probability
of being sick as well as a probability of testing positive given that you were sick.
We just figured out the probability of testing positive.
So that means we have probability of being sick.
Given that you tested positive is equal to 0.5.
And the idea behind a lot of these questions is so that you realize that even though it seemed like
it was 99 percent accurate we can see here that even this person who tested positive only has a half
chance of being actually sick.
OK.
Go ahead and check out the resources in the guidebook.
There's a really common type of interview question.
So make sure you understand really well how this is actually working.
Essentially just make sure you know Bayes Rule or base theorem.
Very well thanks.
And we'll see you at the next lecture.