Hello everyone and welcome to interview question number two for sequel.
And the solution for it.
So the question was was wrong this query here we can see we're selecting two columns idea and trial
date from the payments table and we're seeing grouped by ID.
So it's the actual issue.
Well there's no aggregate function on the trial date column.
There needs to be some sort of aggregate function on a column that's not in the GROUP BY statement.
Otherwise it doesn't really make sense what to return as far as a sequel statement is concerned.
And the other thing to think about that makes this even more obvious is that typically you're actually
going to be grouping by the date column instead of having it as another column because there aren't
a whole lot of ways where you can sort of aggregate data together especially if they're individual time
stamps.
So just keep that in mind.
You always need to either have an aggregate function on the columns you're calling when you're using
a GROUP BY statement or the column itself that needs to be inside the GROUP BY statement.
OK.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.