Welcome everyone to the solution for a sequel interview question number five.
So for this again we're considering these two tables below the Employees table in the manager's table.
He needed to write a query that retrieves all employees that have no manager.
And luckily since we're looking for employees that have no manager we actually don't even really need
to consider the managers table.
We can do this without a joint.
So the way we do that is we just say select name from employees where managed by is null.
Keep in mind certain sequel engines like my sequel post-crisis sequel Oracle databases Microsoft SQL
Server.
Sometimes there is slight variations or differences in how they approach actually calling a null value
from a column.
Sometimes it's not always just a keyboard a no.
Many times it is.
But keep in mind if the job posting is asking for a specific syntax of Eskew Well go ahead and double
check to make sure that you know what keywords like null are for that particular Eskew or engine.
In our case if you're just wipe Orting this should be totally fine.
Select name from employees were managed by is nil.
OK.
Hope you enjoyed that.
I'll see you at the next lecture.