Welcome everyone to the machine learning interview questions section of the course this series of practice
questions will focus on your general knowledge of some machine learning algorithms.
Now we're going to mainly be asking you about your understanding of different machine learning algorithms
a little more from a theory perspective.
Now the best way to approach these sort of questions is to white board them out.
That is to try to explain out loud as you're also writing down some key notes.
That way when you're actually in an interview setting you can talk out loud and also write on a white
board.
So use a white board or a piece of paper helping you to convey your understanding to whoever may be
listening.
We're going to ask about the following algorithms linear regression logistic regression.
This is treason trees and ran the force entry methods in general as well as nave Beys support vector
machines and just general questions on model evaluation and training.
So if you're unfamiliar if some of these topics or wants to review some of these topics go ahead and
do that first before heading out to the questions.
OK.
We'll see you at the questions.