Welcome everyone to the solution for machine learning question number three.
So this question was asking how does a decision tree decide on its splits so what is the criteria for
a split point.
So in general decision tree can use the information game side on the splitting points or the splitting
criteria.
And that also involves using entropy.
So let's give a brief overview of how this works and if you want more information that's more detail
than this brief overview.
You can check out the resources in the guidebook.
So the decision tree is built in a top down fashion where we have that root node at the top and then
it branches down to other nodes.
But the question that we're trying to answer here is how do you choose which attributes to split at
each node.
And the answer is to find the feature that best splits the target class into the purest possible children
notes.
So this measure of purity is called the information and it represents the expected amount of information
that would be needed to specify whether a new instance should be classified 0 or 1 or in this case whatever
Clora classification you're doing.
Maybe you're classifying things since I'm male or female cats or dogs.
Cetera.
So we want to find the amount that this information is represented the expected amount information that
we need to specify that sort of classification given whatever example ended up reaching that node So
entropy on the other hand is a measure of impurity.
So it's basically the opposite of the information.
And it's defined for a binary class with values a B as the following.
The probability of a Times the log probability of a minus probability belonging to b times the log probability
of B.
And if you plot this out eventually you get a curve that looks something like this.
So what ends up happening is you compare the entropy before and after the split and from that you can
measure information gain or basically how much information gains how much information is being gained
by doing the split using that particular feature.
And so this information gain can be calculated as the entropy before the split minus the entropy after
the split.
So overall we are trying to do is figure out what splitting point is going to separate these inputs
best into their two classes.
That's the overall idea of information gain information gain and entropy basically give you the mathematics
of how you can do that formally.
There's also other things like GINI index as far as other splitting criteria you could use and you can
check out the resources in the Guidebook for more information on those.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.