Welcome back for the solution for machine learning question number nine.
So this question I was just asking you to describe the differences between accuracy precision and recall.
So let's go ahead and imagine the results of a model where we have an actual class and then the class
that our model predicted and we'll end up getting some true positives some true negatives false positives
and false negatives.
And also keep in mind sometimes these columns are switched so the diagonals go the other way.
For what we're explaining here it's not really important so let's start off with the most common metric
which is accuracy for classification and accuracy.
Intuitively it's really simple to understand.
It's just simply a ratio of correctly predicted observations to the total number of observations.
Accuracy is a useful measure but really only when you have a symmetric dataset where values a false
positive and false negatives are almost the same.
That doesn't always happen so therefore he should also be considering precision and recall to more formally
describe what accuracy is.
It's the sum of the number of true positives and number of true negatives divided by the total number
of observations so that will be true positives false positives false negatives and true negatives.
So again how many did you get right out of everything precision is the ratio of correctly predicted
positive observations.
So the total predictive of positive observations and the question that this metric is trying to answer
is Of all the points that labeled as positive.
How many were actually positive.
That's precision and formely can describe that as the number of true positives divided by the number
of true positives plus the number of false positives.
Then finally we have recall which is also sometimes known as sensitivity and it's the ratio of correctly
predicted positive observations to all the observations in the actual class.
So that's going to be equal to formally speaking true positives divided by true positives plus false
negatives.
All right.
So those are the basics behind accuracy precision and recall it's a really good idea for you to practice
drawing this diagram and practice the actual formulas and explanations for accuracy precision recall.
Those are really common metrics especially in binary classification situations and you should understand
them well.
And what each of them is trying to answer.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.