Welcome back for the solution for machine learning Question Number 10 says questions asking what metrics
can be used to evaluate a regression task.
So there's lots of different metrics.
Let's go through some of them.
There's mean absolute error.
So this is the mean of the absolute values of the error so we have why and why.
Basically taking the difference between the true value versus the value predicted.
You take the absolute value of that and then you sum them all up and divide by how many points to where
essentially taking the average.
So this is not the most common metric but it is the most basic metric.
Basically on average how often you.
So there's then the mean square error.
And the reason this one is popular because it's the mean of squared errors.
It basically punishes you for having larger errors because you're going to be squaring the difference
between your predicted values and those true values.
So that means if you have a larger error when it gets squared then you're going to have a really larger.
So that's means squared error.
And again you're taking some of these dividing it by the number of points that were available.
There is a problem with this one though and it's the fact that even though you have the advantage that
you're punishing larger errors you are no longer in the same units as whatever the continuous value
you are trying to predict was.
So then we finally come up with root mean squared error and it's the same as the mean square there.
Except now we're taking the root the square root of it.
That way we still have the same units at the end of the day in the same category of whatever the label
happens to be.
So these are definitely three are some of the most common metrics root mean square error probably being
the most common out of three of these because it takes advantage of the fact that you are punishing
for larger errors.
And at the end of the day you still have the same units as whatever your label was in.
There's other metrics to consider things like R-squared value and adjust that R-squared value.
You can check out the resource links in the guide book if you want more information on the various metrics
for regression tasks.
But definitely you want to be able to know these three and also be able to explain the differences between
them and the advantages and how we kind of build up to root mean squared air.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.