Welcome everyone to the coding interview questions section of the course this series of practice questions
is really going to test your knowledge on just a few popular coding questions.
There's a few key questions that are really popular for whatever reason in interview settings either
at the take home phase at the screening phase or at the onsite phase.
So we're going to go ahead and let you practice on those these questions and actually rely on knowledge
of statistics or machine learning but focus instead on just solving general problems with code.
And depending on the company's experience of hiring data scientists the interview could potentially
really focus heavily on these types of questions.
And what I mean by that is sometimes smaller companies they've only had experience hiring software engineers.
So what ends up happening is their interview structure isn't changed for a data science position and
so they end up interviewing you as if you're coming on for a software engineer role.
So the interview questions are really heavily focused on coding data structures and algorithms.
So if you start facing those type of interviews maybe or even going into certain interviews for a Data
Engineer and they really focus a lot more on coding you may want to study data structures and algorithms
for more preparation.
OK let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.