Welcome to coding interview question number one for this question you're going to be given an array
of integers both positive and negative.
That's a big point here.
And your task is to write a program that can find the largest continuous sum some you just need to return
the total sum amount not the actual sequence of numbers that were part of that sum.
So let me go in and give you a few clarifying examples so you can understand what I mean by the term
largest continuous sum and keep in mind the integers are both positive and negative here.
So let's take a look at this first example given in array 7 8 9 they're all positive.
So if everything in the array is positive it makes sense that the largest continuous sum is going to
be everything in the array.
So you're going to say seven plus eight plus nine.
And that gives you 24.
So all your program has to do is given the array 79 returned the number 24.
Now let's take a look at this second array.
We can see we have two negative numbers on the tail and they're both at the beginning at the end.
So still the largest continuous sum is going to be seventy nine.
We're going to ignore the negative numbers.
And so that's why you're not going be able to just always sum up the array because that negative numbers
could hurt you.
So again the answer here is 24.
Now let's take a look at a little more complicated example here the negative number somewhere in the
middle.
So the largest continuous sum that we can see and what I mean by continuous are numbers basically a
subset of the array in a row.
And it looks like the largest subset of the Saray for the sum is going to be number nine.
Number two put together.
So that gives you 11.
If we ended up including the two in the three we'd have to include the negative 10 and that wouldn't
be worth including And they are the positive two and positive three because negative 10 would basically
cancel them out and also have negative five on top of that.
So third one the answer is 11.
Take a look at this fourth one.
Hopefully by now you get the point.
We can see here that even if we include the negative 10 we can offset it by including the 2 and 11.
So now it actually makes sense to include everything in the array.
We don't have to just stop at negative 10.
So we end up doing is say two plus 11 when a sample size plus two is equal to 14.
So given that fourth rate your output 14 and then for the fifth array you can see here the answer is
actually a single number 12 because it doesn't make sense to add in any other numbers.
And then the other sort of fashion given this array.
OK.
So best of luck on this question.
If you have any questions on it please feel free to post the cuneiform.
So hopefully now you understand what I mean by large continuous sum.
Just what subset of this array will give you the largest sum.
I'll see you at the solutions.