Welcome everyone.
The solution for the first coding interview question so as a reminder you're going to be given an array
of integers that could be both positive and negative and you need to write a program that can find a
large continuous sum.
And then we show you some examples of what large continuous sum and.
So how do we actually do this.
Well the algorithm is we start summing up the numbers and store them in occurrence some variable and
after adding each element what we do is we check whether the current sum is larger than the maximum
sum encountered so far.
If it is we're going to update the maximum sum so have the maximum sum variable and as long as the current
sum is positive we keep adding the numbers when the current sum becomes negative.
We start with a new current sum because a negative current sum will only decrease the sum of a future
sequence and note that we don't reset the current sum to zero because the array can contain all negative
integers.
Then the result would end that just being the largest negative number OK.
Let's go ahead and code this out in Python and kind of build this out step by step.
I think it makes a little more sense in code than just written out in words.
So let's hop to a Jupiter note book.
Or you can use any editor you want and let's go the Python to begin with by creating a function here.
Call it large continuous sum for large continuous sum and it takes in some array.
A R R can be a list or anything.
So the first thing you do is check for a little edge case and often your interviewer is going to ask
you to check for edge cases even after you come up with a reasonable solution.
So one edge case is the C is the array length is zero.
So if it is we're pretty much over.
So I'll say if the length of the array is equal to zero.
Go ahead and return 0.
Ok if that's not the case then we actually have to get to work here.
So what we're going to do here.
Is We're going to set the maximum sum so far equal to the first item in the array.
The first number in the array.
We're also going to set the current sum equal to the first item in the array.
And then we're going to do the following.
We'll say for every number in that array and we're actually going to skip the very first number so indexing
starts at zero in Python.
So I'll saying skipping that first number going all the way to the end so starting at index 1 colon
that means all the way to the end.
So for pretty much every other element in the array we're going to do is we'll do the following.
We're going to set the current some equal to the max of the current Some plus the number we're on versus
the number.
So what's actually happening here is the following.
We're basically saying the current sum and this Max function what it does is you passen two arguments
here.
Current some plus the number or just the number itself and it's going to return back what the max value
of these is.
So basically set the current sum to the higher these two values.
So once we know that we're going to end up doing is then we're going to say that the maximum is equal
to the max of the current sum versus the maximum.
So we set the max as the higher between the current sum and the current max.
So again just to explain here or doing is we start summing up the numbers and store them in the current
Some variables.
That's what we're doing here.
So you start off right at the gate with that current some variable.
And then after adding each element which is or doing here plus numb.
So we're kind of continuously going along this current some after adding each of these elements we're
going to check the current sum if it's larger than the maximum sum encountered so far after we do that
which is what we did right here.
If it is so if current Some happens to be larger than we're going to update Max some if Max maxim is
still larger we'll go ahead and keep it the max function is going to automatically for us.
And as long as the current sum is positive we're going to essentially just keep adding on numbers when
the current sum becomes negative which is what may happen if you have negative numbers there in the
starting of a new current sum.
And because a negative current sum will only decrease the sum of a future sequence and note that we
don't need to reset the current sum to zero because the array can contain all negative integers.
If that ends up happening you basically find the largest negative number and what I mean by a large
negative number is the one that's closest to zero.
And that's basically how it works.
Let's go ahead and run that and check this out.
We'll see large continuous passen an array was passen 1 2 3 and see what it returns looks.
Let's go in and say actually we forgot to return the maximum here.
So at the very bottom of this let's go ahead and say print the max sum the run that looks like Maxim
is 6.
That makes sense.
Let's go ahead and put in a really big negative number here.
And I notice it's only five because now it's only adding two and three.
Let's put in another negative number here and now it's only three.
And let's start off with a really large number.
One hundred and photostats 100.
If we put in another larger number here we should get 110 because it's worth getting that negative 10
to grab that 20.
So really basic algorithm but you have to kind of think about it and what's really saving us here is
this idea of comparing that current some kind of going along and adding it and then grabbing that maxim.
If this is confusing for you what I would actually recommend is adding print statements here so you
can print out the following.
Can print out current Some as you go along and you can print out the number as you go along and maybe
some other keywords so you can kind of get an idea what's being printed out but basically kind of allows
you to go along and see how the algorithm is working.
So if these two lines confuse you because basically just the two line algorithm here definitely use
print statements to help you out there.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.