Welcome everyone to the solution for question number four in the coding interview section.
So for this question you have to consider an array of non-negative integers.
That's kind of important here.
And the second is shuffled and you have to figure out which number is missing from the shuffle the array.
So one two three four five.
In this case we didn't really shuffle it to make it more obvious but here we have two is missing from
the second array.
So you can solve this problem multiple ways.
And there's many possible solutions so I'm sure you two straightforward approaches.
These are not the only two approaches but these are the two most straightforward ones since we know
that all numbers are non-negative.
Well we can do is we can simply sum up both of the arrays.
Check the difference and then you have your missing element right there.
Another approach is to sort both of the arrays and then just go through them sequentially until you
don't have a match.
So let's go ahead and show you how to code up the solutions finder and it takes in two arrays.
The second one has been shuffled and it's missing an element.
So we can do is sort D-Rays and technically speaking you don't actually need to sort the first one Bullecourt
sort.
And there's lots of different sort functions we'll just call the default ones and then once we sort
the two arrays what we'll do is we'll check and compare the elements in the sorted arrays.
Lots of ways to do this but one way is to zip them together.
So let me show you an example here.
Going to insert a cell below real quick.
So if I were to say I have array one will say a 1 is 1 2 3 and B 1 is 10 20 30.
In python we can use zip here with a 1 and b one.
And if we pass that as a list then you can see we have now a list of tuples basically pairing them up
based off their index position.
So that's what we're going to do here.
We're going to save for number one comma number two in zip and we'll say array 1 3 2 if number one is
not equal to number 2 then we're just going to return number two because that's where or excuse me number
one because that's the missing element in number 2.
And then if that's not the case we never actually hit that then we're going to return the very last
element from away.
A great one will return one index that negative one.
OK so let's go ahead and estus.
We'll say finder one two one two three four five and then let's go ahead and take up the four.
So I'll say 1 3 to 5 and we run this.
We get back four.
So that's one way to do it.
Another way to do it would actually take the sum and then subtract them so we can say the finder array
1 or 2 and then we're going to do here.
Let me scroll down real quick is do the following.
We can say some of array one minus some overate 2.
And then we can actually just return that result.
We'll say return this.
And now we run the same thing again.
In fact we can just run it again up here.
So if I run that top Salin it's like is back for again.
So both of these totally valid methods of solving this problem.
OK.
Hope those useful to you.
I'll see you at the next lecture.