[Autogenerated] everything we've seen so far about Springwood actuator
and Micro Meter is not specific to spring integration.
You can use these features in any spring good application.
Since this is spring integration course,
it's interesting to see what metrics bring
integration specifically makes available.
I still have the application running,
so let's take a look at the Springwood actuator metrics and point again.
You will see that there are few metrics with names that start with spring,
not integration.
These are metrics that spring integration automatically AD DS
for the components in our integration flow.
First, there are spring,
not integration sources spring dot integration dot handlers and spring,
not integration channels.
These three are actually not very interesting.
The only thing that these three metrics report are
the number off message sources, handlers and channels.
For example, if we look at the spring dot integration or channels metric we can,
see that there are four message channels.
The metric that is much more interesting is spring, not integration, not send.
This metric is a micro meter timer, so it contains count,
Total Time and Max measurements about messages that have been
sent to message channels and message handlers.
It also provides a number of text that we can use to view the
statistics off specific handles or channels and to distinguish between
successful processing off messages and failures.
For example,
let's zoom in on the registration Request channel by adding
a query parameter to select on the tag name with the Value
Registration Request Channel.
Here,
we can see that 1000 messages have been sent to this channel on how
long the processing of all these sent calls took.
Next.
Let's take a look at the Registration event channel,
which is where the registration service center registration events.
After successfully saving a registration in the database.
As you see, there were less than 1000 registration events.
That's because some registrations have failed.
The low generator test submits 1000 registrations with
random names and email addresses.
Sometimes it will generate the same name and email address multiple times.
And since the database requires email addresses,
to be unique registration will fail.
If the email address is a duplicate,
take a look at the scent metrics for the service activator.
You can see that 1000 messages have been sent to the service
activator in total by adding the result,
tech with the value, success or failure.
You can see how many off those messages it has processed
successfully on how many have failed because the services,
through an exception,
note that the metrics show us how many registrations have been
processed successfully and how many have failed.
But they don't tell us which ones have failed Metrics.
Are meant to provide statistical data about what the
application is doing and are not the right tool to get detail
information about specific failures.
For that kind of information, you should use logging or tracing.
We'll get back to that in the last model of these course,
where we're going to look at techniques for analyzying failures and debugging.
Besides the spring, not integration,
dot center metric spring integration also provides the spring,
not integration.
Don't receive metric.
The scent metric provides statistics about the scent
calls or message channels and handlers,
while the receive metric provides statistics on receive calls
on possible channels and message sources.
We don't see this metric in our demo application because all the channels
that we are using our published subscribe channels instead of possible
channels on we also don't have any message sources in our integration flow
just to remind you a message sources a component that can be pulled to produce messages from some source