[Autogenerated] spring integration enables us to write software
consisting of loosely coupled components,
which has a lot of advantages.
But one thing that loose coupling and Asian colonel is
messaging make a bit more complicated is debugging.
Fortunately,
spring integration provides us with tools to help us analyze the flow off
messages and inspect what's happening in this module.
We'll take a look at these tools.
First, we're going to work with the wiretap and message store patterns.
Our first explain the main idea off these enterprise integration patterns
and how they are implemented in spring integration.
And then we'll do a demo where real store messages in a Mongo DB database.
Then we'll take a look at the message history pattern,
and you'll learn how it can help you to analyze what has happened to a
message as it has passed through the integration flow. Those error three topics for this module