[Autogenerated] one off.
The standard features off Java is these JavaScript engines API.
Let's quickly review the main concepts off this API so that you're
prepared to understand how spring integration support it.
There are three main parts to the architecture of J M X.
The first part is instrumentation.
To be able to manage components inside your running application.
You'll need to instrument them.
That means you'll have to AD FS NetBeans classes to your application
that access the components you want to manage.
We'll take a closer look at and beans in a moment.
The second part is the Ambien server.
The M being server manages these AM beans.
You will have to register your ambience in the Ambien
server to make them accessible by J.
M.
X.
The third part is a communications connector.
This connector makes the M being server that's running in your
application accessible to external tools.
The standard connector that's provided with the Java Virtual
machine is based on Jaffa Remote method invocation.
But it's possible to use a different connector,
which works using some other network protocol.
When you have these parts running in your application,
you can use a management tool to access and control the and beans.
The jvm includes a simple tool named Jay console,
which will be using for our demos.
Let's take a closer look at and beans and I m being consists off a
regular Java interface and a class that implements that interface that
provide a number off attributes and operations.
An attribute is a value that might be read and
written by a gather and center method.
On operation is any arbitrary method that performs some action on the and being,
and beans are registered in the Ambien server using an object name.
J M X Object names have a specific format.
They consist off a domain,
followed by a column and then a set of properties
in the form off key value pairs.
There are no fixed rules about the domain or properties that you should
use for the object names off your M beans so you can choose anything that
makes sense for your particular application.
Finally,
and beans can produce JPA max notifications to signal state changes or errors.
A management tool can present these notifications to a system administrator,
similar to the alerts that we saw in the demo with Influx to be and Grafana
J M X is a standard part off the Java virtual machine,
and the JVM provides a number off and beans itself.
These platform and beans provide information about
things such as the just in time compiler, garbage collection, memory management and threats.