[Autogenerated] as I just mentioned in the overview Spring Integration is an
implementation off the enterprise integration patterns.
Let's take a quick look at enterprise integration patterns and
how they are implemented in spring integration.
The enterprise integration patterns are a collection off 65 design patterns
that were originally described in a book with the same name published in
2000 and three by Gregor Hope and Bobby Wolf.
These design patterns specifically deal with integration problems.
The word integration refers to integrating components and
external systems into a complete application.
Let's review the main concepts, since it's about messaging.
The first concept to understand is, of course, the message.
A message is a unit of data that is transmitted from a center to
one or more receivers fire a messaging system.
A message consists off to parts, a payload and headers.
The payload is the actual content off the message.
What the meaning off the content is, and how it is structured and formatted,
is specific to the application.
When you design an application that uses messaging,
then you decide yourself what kind of data to use for the payload of messages.
The headers off a message contained metadata which is used by
the messaging system for different functions.
For example, to attach a unique identify error or time stamp to a message,
or to keep track off where the message should be delivered,
this model of a message will look familiar if you know
anything about HTTP requests and responses.
These are also messages that consists off headers and the body or payload.
The next main concept is the message channel.
A Message General is a component that knows how to transport
messages from a center to one or more receivers.
There are different types off message generals.
One main distinction is point to point channels
versus published subscribe channels.
A point to Point Channel delivers messages from the
center to exactly one receiver,
whereas a published subscribed channel delivers messages to multiple receivers.
Another distinction is subscribe double channels versus possible channels.
This difference has to do with which party takes Thean
initiative to deliver messages to the receiver.
With the subscribe double channel,
the messaging system will take the initiative and call the receiver.
When a message is available and with a possible channel,
it's up to the receiver to ask the messaging system.
If there is a message available for processing.
When you design a spring integration application,
you will need to be aware off the different types off message
channels so that you can choose these appropriate once.
The next main concept is the message and point a message.
And point is the part of the code that connects a center
or receiver to the messaging system.
This is a rather abstract and general idea.
There are many different kinds of message and points described by
more specific enterprise integration patterns.
There are, for example, channel adapters,
gateways, servers, activators and a few other ones.
The last two concepts that I want to mention here.
Our message, transformation and message routing.
In some situations,
dissenter sends messages in a different format than what the receiver expects.
For example,
a center might send JSON messages while the receiver expects them to be in XML.
A message translator is an example of a message transformer that
can be used for converting between formats.
There are other types of message transformers.
For example,
a content and richer is a message transformer that AD DS
data from some other source to messages.
The Enterprise Integration Patterns book describes a
few more message transformers.
Another main function of the messaging system is message routing.
A message router is a component that decides where to send messages next,
so that they are routed to the appropriate receiver.
Routing can be done based on different criteria,
for example, based on the headers or content of messages.
More specific types, off message routers are message filters,
splitters and aggregators.
That was a very quick recap off the core concepts off
enterprise immigration patterns.
Spring integration provides implementations off all these concepts
and all the other enterprise integration patterns,
which you can use in your spring based applications to
connect components inside your application,
as well as to connect your application to many
different kinds off external systems.
It provides, for example, classes to work with messages,
different implementations,
off message channels and a collection off channel and actors and
gateways that you can use to connect to message brokers,
web services, databases, FTP service and a lot more off course.
It also provides implementations off different kinds,
off message transformers and routers.
If you want to know more about enterprise integration patterns,
you can, of course, by the book.
You can also find details about most of the patterns on the books
website www dot enterprise integration patterns dot com.
You can find more information on spring integration,
including the reference documentation and API
documentation on the spring website at spring. DLL io slash projects slash spring dash integration