[Autogenerated] when you need to understand what's happening with the
messages in your spring integration application,
you want to be able to inspect messages that passed through the
channels at certain points in the integration flow.
The wiretap and message store patterns will help you do that In
the Enterprise Integration Patterns book.
Each pattern is introduced by stating a question that the pattern answers.
The question for the wiretap pattern is the following.
How do you inspect messages that travel on a point to point channel?
Inspecting messages on the publish Subscribed channel is no
difficult because the published subscribed channel delivers
messages that are sent to it to multiple receivers,
so you could just add another receiver to the channel That,
for example, writes the content of messages to the debug blog.
This is, however,
not so easy for a point to point channel because they
delivers messages only to a single receiver.
A wiretap enables you to listen in on the messages that are passing
through a point to point channel in spring integration.
This is implemented as a channel interceptor on the point to
point channel that you want to monitor.
You can configure a wiretap that will send copies off
the messages to Secondary Channel,
where you can process them further in the demo that
we're going to work within a minute, you'll see how this works in practice.
One thing you can do and you want to inspect messages is to
write a content of messages to the debug blog,
as I mentioned.
But sometimes it will be more convenient if you can
store the messages in the database,
especially if you're dealing with large numbers off messages.
You can then use distort messages for analytics and reporting
the Enterprise Integration Patterns Book describes the message
store pennant for this purpose,
and that's how we're going to use it in our upcoming demo as well.
The question that the enterprise integration patterns book poses
for the message store pattern is how do we report against message
information without disturbing the loosely coupled and transient
nature off a messaging system?
But Spring Integration uses the idea off storing messages in
a database for a more general purpose, not just for debugging or analytics.
There are a number of spring integration components that
have the ability to buffer messages.
For example,
Possible channels such as cute channel need to keep messages in a queue
until the receiver makes a received goal by default.
These components keep the messages in non persistent memory.
When the application is stopped,
the messages are lost by configuring a message store on
a component that buffers messages.
You can have its store messages persistently.
Spring integration provides a number off different message story
implementations for storing messages in a relational database using J.
D.
B C.
And for storing messages in mongo DB reddish or gem fire.
Finally,
I have to note that there are some limitations that you have to be aware
off when you are using a persistent message store.
When messages are stored into a persistent message store,
they have to be serialized into whatever form is
necessary for the message store you're using.
And these, she realized when they are retrieved again.
That will only work.
If the Henderson payload of the messages only contain objects that
can be serialized and deserialize correctly,
you might need to convert values before storing them,
and after retrieving them from a message store, we will encounter audition the demo as well