[Autogenerated] Let's see how we can use a wiretap and a message
store in practice to store messages that we receive on the
registration Request channel in the database.
In this demo will first at a wiretap to the Registration Request channel,
which will send a copy off the incoming messages to with the back Channel.
Then we'll configure a message store on the debug channel that will store the
messages in a Mongo DB database where we can inspect them.
Open example.
Project number seven in your IDE.
Let's first at the wiretap.
Look up the definition off the registration request General in
the Spring Integration XML configuration file.
A wiretap in spring integration is the type off channel interceptor,
so we can add it to the Registration Request channel by adding an in
interceptors element in which we put in wiretap element.
We have to add one attribute,
which tells the wiretap where to send a copy off the messages to Let's
send the messages to a channel named D Back Channel.
We'll have to define that channel as well.
So now we have a wiretap on the Registration Request Channel,
which sends a copy off all incoming registration
request messages to the D Back channel.
The next step is to configure a message store on this channel so that
the messages are stored in a Mongo DB database.
To do that, we first have to set up Mongo DB.
Let's first get Mongol to be running in Docker.
This is just a ZZ is running other software in
Docker with the following command.
We can create and started Docker Container with Mongo DB.
Now let's go back to the application to use the Mongo DB Message store will
first have to add the dependency on spring integration.
Mongo db This spring integration module contains the Mongo DB message
store implementation and will automatically pull in other dependencies
that are necessary for accessing mongo DB.
Since this is a spring boot application,
we don't have to do a lot of configuration for Mongo
to be in the Application properties file.
We have to add just one line to tell it where to find
Mongol to be and what database name to use.
We'll have it used a database named Globomantics,
which will be created automatically if it doesn't yet exist.
Now we're ready to set up the Mongo DB message store we'll have to
define a message Group store Spring Bean for It,
which will do in the main application class Globomantics service application.
The message store implementation class that will want to use here
is glass of Mongo DB Channel Message store,
so we'll create a new instance of it.
In the being method,
we have to pass three arguments to the constructor first are among
Go DB factory and a mapping mongo converter.
Now we need to get these objects from somewhere, of course.
Fortunately,
this is not complicated because these objects are created
automatically by spring boot auto configuration,
so we can just inject them in the bean method and use them.
The third argument will pass to the constructor off Mongo DB
Channel Message store is the name off the collection in Mongo
db Why we wanted to store messages.
Let's call it registrations.
We're not completely done here yet.
Remember that at the end of the last clip,
I explained that there are some limitations that you have to take into
account when storing messages into a persistent message store.
You have to make sure that any objects that may appear in the
headers or payload off messages can be stored and retrieved
from the message store correctly.
In this case, there are two types of objects that may cause problems.
Message headers in registration messages will contain or cough spring framework.
HTTP dot media type objects that cannot be stored directly
on our own class at any registration that's used as the
payload of registration messages.
Contains an offset daytime field that mongo DB gone Tantalus Well,
To handle this, we need to add and register some custom converters.
We can do this by providing a mongo custom conversions.
Bean.
The converters I've used here are included with the example project as well.
I won't show them in detail, but they're just very simple.
Converters that convert media type and offset daytime
objects into strings and vice versa.
Side note.
Spring integration actually has another mongo DB message store
implementation in class Mongo DB Message store instead of the class
Mongo DB Channel message store that refused here.
That seems to be an older implementation that works in a
slightly different way and also the way you have to
configure custom converters is different.
It won't recognize the converters defined in our mongo custom conversions bean.
I recommend that you use mongo db General Message store
unless you have a special reason to use Mongo.
DB Message store.
End of shy note.
Now we have our message store,
and the last thing to do is to use it for the debug channel.
Let's go back to the XML configuration file again.
We'll make the debug channel acute channel by adding an inter
que element to it to make its store messages.
In mongo db,
we pointed to the message store we've defined by
setting the message store attribute.
Now we're ready to run the demo.
We have mongo DB running and also make sure that greenmail is running.
Then start up the services off the demo application.
Before we shoot in some registration messages,
it's worth mentioning that the wiretap can also be controlled.
Fire J M X.
By default, the wiretap is running, which we can see via JPA console.
But it's also possible to stop it so via J.
M.
X or via the control bus.
We can switch the wiretap on and off as needed.
Note that it's always started automatically when the application is started.
Unfortunately,
the wiretap does not have an auto started property
like we saw in an earlier demo,
where we add that the email retry components so that we can have
it turned off after starting the application.
Let's now start the low generator test to get some messages into this system.
We can now take a look at the messages in mongo db to do this,
run the following command,
which will start the Mongo shell in the Docker container by Mongo.
DB, is running in the Mongo Shell.
The command show DVS shows us what database is exist.
We want to take a look at the Globomantics database,
so let's center use Globomantics to make it the current database.
The command show collections tells us that there's one collection
named Registrations with D B that registrations count.
We can see how many documents there are in the collection,
and now we can, of course, to queries to see the contents.
For example, let's try DevOps load registrations,
not find, which will show us the first few documents.
As you can see,
the documents correspond to the messages that the wiretaps
saw on the Registration Request channel,
including the headers, that payload and some other fields. You can get out of the Mongol shell by typing exit