[Autogenerated] As you know,
the way that components communicate with each other in spring
integration is fire messages on message channels.
Spring integration provides many channel adapters and gateways to
connect other systems to the messaging infrastructure.
So it's probably not a surprise that for working with J M X,
there is also a set of channel adapters and gateways.
We can group these spring integration J M X components into
three groups for working with J M X operations,
attributes and notifications.
I'll first give you a quick overview, and then we'll do a demo again,
where we will use some of them.
First, the components for Working with J.
Maxx operations.
These are the operation invoking channel a matter on the
operation invoking Outbound Gateway.
These error both message handlers that can receive messages
from a message channel and then called J M X operations based
on the messages that they receive.
The difference between the channel adapter and the gateway is
the same as the difference between channel adapters and gateways
in general inch ping integration,
which is that the channel that there is one way so it doesn't produce a
response message while the gateway can produce a response message containing
the result off the call to the J M X operation,
which can be sent to another message General Next Starter
Components for Working with J M X attributes.
These are the Attributes polling channel adapter and
the tree polling channel adapter.
Both of these components are message sources that you have to attach a poll
are two to produce messages to be sent to a message general.
That way you can, for example,
read the value of a J M X attributes at regular intervals.
The attribute polling channel adaptor reached the value of one specific J.
Maxx attribute,
while the tree polling adapter can read more data from J M X at once,
it reached the attributes off part of the tree off ambience and
put all that information into a single message.
Finally, there are components for working with J M X notifications.
The notification publishing channel Adaptor is a message hander that receives
messages from a channel and produces JPA Max notifications.
The notification listening channel adaptor does Thea a Pa's it.
It listens for J.
Maxx notifications and produces messages that it sends to a message General.
That's the quick overview offspring Integration J MX components to
quickly summarize them for working with J M X operations.
We have the operation invoking channel adaptor and operation invoking
Outbound Gateway for working with J M X attributes.
We have the attribute polling channel adapter and the tree
polling channel adapter and for working with J.
Maxx notifications,
we have to notification publishing channel adaptor and a
notification listening channel adapter. Let's now see how we can use them in practice.