[Autogenerated] Let's now continue with this demo by using
the spring integration JPA MX components.
Our first goal is to get a J.
Maxx notification when the number off errors while
sending email goes over a threshold.
You can imagine that in a real world scenario,
you would want to signal a system administrator.
Went too many Errors occur.
We'll use to spring integration J M X components for this first,
an attribute polling channel adapter,
which will pull the Q size attribute off the outgoing mail
error channel to publish the J M X notification will use a
notification publishing channel adapter.
Let's at the attribute polling channel adapter Well,
given an IDE, and we have to set the J.
Maxx object name off the um being that we wanted to inspect and,
of course, the name off the specific attributes off the Ambien.
We wanted to look at the Q size attributes off the M being that's
associated with the outgoing mail error channel.
We can find the exact object name for that Ambien by
looking it up using JPA console.
The attribute Polling General adaptor will read the value
of the attribute package it into a spring integration
message and send it on a message.
General,
let's define a channel named outgoing mail error que sais channel
and make it a published subscribed channel.
Finally, we'll need to define a polar for the channel adapter.
Let's add a polar with a fixed rate that will fire
once every 10,000 milliseconds.
So every 10 seconds,
the channel adaptor will read the Q size off the outgoing meal error channel and
send a message to the outgoing meal error que sais channel.
Next, we'll add the Notification Publishing Channel adapter,
which will publish JPA Max Notification when there are
more than 10 errors on the Cube.
We'll put this channel adaptor in a chain along with a few
other components to pre process messages.
Let's add a chain that listens to the outgoing mail error accuse access channel.
The messages that appear on the input Q of this chain
have a simple number as the payload,
which is the number off messages on the Q as read from the JM excuse size.
Attribute by the Attributes Falling Channel adapter.
Since we're only interested in these messages when the
number off arrows gets too high,
the first component that will add to the chain is a filter that only let's
messages through when the number is greater than 10.
Next.
For the messages that get through the filter,
we want to prepare a J M X notification.
Let's add a transformer with an expression to
compose a notification message text.
And finally,
we will at the Notification Publishing Channel adapter on this general adapter,
we have to set an object name and we'll set the default notification type.
We can choose any object name we like here.
Let's set it to something that makes sense so we can find it in JPA
console before we run the demo replication again.
Let's add one more spring integration J M X component.
When the mail server is down and too many errors occur,
it makes sense to pose the whole registration service so that
it won't accept any more registrations,
which would all fail because there is a problem.
To achieve this,
we'll add an operation invoking channel adapter which will stop the
very first component in our integration flow.
Which is these HTTP inbound channel adapter.
The operation invoking channel adaptor will invoke to stop
operation on the HTTP inbound channel adapter.
When there are more than 50 error messages on the outgoing mail error channel,
we'll add another chain that listens on the
outgoing meal error que sais channel, just like in the previous chain,
will add a filter as the first component.
This one will only let messages through when the number is greater than 50.
After the filter will put the operation invoking channel adapter,
we'll have to specify the Ambien object name and the name
off the operation that we want to invoke.
We can again find the name off the Ambien and the operation with Jay console.
We've configured T HTTP inbound channel adaptor in the beginning off
the integration flow so that our response with HTTP status code 202
accepted when it's working normally.
When this channel adaptor is stopped by invoking the stop operation via J M X,
it will still listen for HTTP requests,
But it will respond with status code 503 services unavailable.
Let's run the demo again and see it all in action.
First,
make sure that Green Mill is running and then start the
services off the demo application.
Let's also start JPA console again and connect to the
Globomantics sure is application well again.
Ignore the warning that the J M X connection is insecure.
For this demo.
Go to the Ambien step.
You will see that in the tree on the left,
there is now an item named Conduct Globomantics.
Start registration, under which you can find outgoing mail errors,
which has a notifications item.
When you click on it, you will get a list of notifications on the right,
which is currently empty.
Click on the subscribe button at the bottom to make jae console.
Receive notifications from this Ambien.
Next, let's see it working.
Start the low generated test again when it's running and the services
processing registrations Stop the green Mill Docker container again.
After a while, when there are more than 10 email sending errors,
you will see notifications appearing JPA console and after a
while when more than 50 errors have occurred,
the low generated EST will fail because the operation invoking Channel
adaptor has stopped the HDP inbound channel adapter,
and the service has started to return status code 503 instead
of Status Co 202 that the test expects.
Fortunately, we now have tools to fix the errors.
Let's first start green meal again.
Then let's go to the outgoing mill.
Retry component using JPA console and trigger, it starts operation.
Now we can see that the number off errors on the
outgoing mail error channel is dropping.
As these emails are being processed,
we can also resume the HTTP inbound channel adapter by looking it up
in JAE console and triggering its start operation.
Now everything is back to normal and the service can
accept registration requests again.
If you want to learn more and practice with this than feel free
to experiment with the code of this example,
one thing you could try is adding another notification publishing
channel adapter that will put out a J M X notification when the HDP
inbound channel adaptor is stopped.
That seems like an important event that you might want to warn a system administrator about