[Autogenerated] in this module,
you've learned about a few useful tools that spring integration
provides for analyzying and debugging integration flows.
We've looked at the wiretap and message store patterns,
which we've used in a demo where restored the incoming
registration messages in a Mongo DB database.
Even though the Enterprise Integration Patterns book describes the
message store pattern as a way for reporting on messages,
spring integration uses it in a more general way as the backing
store for components that can buffer messages.
We also looked at how you can enable message history,
which will cause all messages to have a history had at it.
This will show exactly which path a message has
taken through the integration flow, which is often very useful information for analyzying problems.