[Autogenerated] Now we are at the end of this course about monitoring system
management and debugging offspring integration applications.
Before we finish, let me summarize what you've learned in this course.
We started with a short recap off enterprise integration
patterns and spring integration messages,
message channels, message endpoints, message transformation and message routing.
I explained the prerequsites and where this course fits in
with other courses in Pluralsight Library.
We took a moment to set up the software you needed to
follow along with the examples, and I introduced you to the demo application.
The first major topic that we discussed was how to monitor and
gather metrics for spring integration applications.
You've learned about spring Bootstrap, actuator and micro meter.
We did a demo with Influx DB and Grafana to show you how
you can gather metrics in the Time series database and
visualized them in the dashboard.
Next, we focused on managing and controlling spring integration applications.
You learn that spring integration provides a number of components that form a
bridge between the G M X and spring integration worlds.
You also learn about the control,
bus pattern and spring integrations implementation off it and how you can shut
down in spring integration application in a controlled way.
Finally,
you've learned about the tools that are useful for analyzying
and debugging spring integration applications.
This is the end of the course.
I hope that you are found it interesting and useful and that it
has inspired you to build great software. And I wish you success with using Splain integration in your own projects.