[Autogenerated] you are now ready to dive in, but let's do a quick summary.
First,
I refresh your mind about the most important enterprise integration patterns.
Concepts, which are messages, message channels,
endpoints, transformation and routing.
Spring integration provides implementations off these concepts,
which are ready for you to use in your own spring based applications.
For this course,
I expect that your Javad developer and that you are already
familiar with the core spring framework and that you also know the
basics offspring integration to follow.
Along with the examples, you'll need a few tools.
Obviously, A J D K, A.
Java IDE and Maven and Docker will be convenient for
running software like greenmail.
I showed you the demo application that will start out with,
and you should be able to run it on your own machine.
Now,
the first major subject that will work on is adding
features for monitoring and metrics. Let's see what that is all about in the next module