[Autogenerated] Let's do a quick them out to see how we can use
the spring integration Control was component.
Open up example.
Project number six in your E.
What we start with is the same code as what we ended within the previous demo.
Now let's add a control bus component.
It's really easy to do this.
We just have to add an into control bus element to our
spring integration XML configuration file.
Let's give the component and IDE and we have to specify the input
general from which it will receive messages.
An output general is optional and is necessary only if you
want to send the result of expressions evaluated by the
control bus somewhere in this case, let's also at an output channel off course.
We also have to define these two channels within channel elements.
Now to be able to use his control bus.
We have to have some way to access it to keep these demo simple.
I'm going to add an HTTP inbound gateway that's connected to the
input and output channels off the control bus.
This gateway will listen for HTTP post requests on the path slash control.
It will simply pass the body off requests as a string to the control bus.
Let's start up the services and see how we can access the control bus.
We can do that using any tool that consent HTTP requests
such aske URL Using a command like this,
we can send the spring expression language expression to
to control bus which it will execute.
Here we error calling.
The method is running on the bean registration requests General adapter,
which is the HTTP inbound channel adapter that receives registration requests.
When we execute, this command will get a very short response with the text.
True, which is the return value of the method goal.
Similarly, we can stop the service by calling to stop method.
Since this is a Voight method, we will just get a message.
No reply received within time out.
But it definitely has called the method.
If we now use the first command again to check if the
services running we got falsy off course.
We can start it again by running the start method.
Before we finish with this demo,
I should warn you that the control was component is a
powerful instrument that has Thea Bility to control many
components in your application.
Therefore, you should be very careful when you use it in this demo.
We simply exposed it to the outside world using an HTTP inbound gateway.
But this is definitely not safe and is not something you
should do in any production ready application.
If you want to use this in your own application, think very carefully about security.