[Autogenerated] in a spring integration application,
you typically have an integration flow,
with many components working together to process messages.
One subject that we haven't paid attention to yet is how to
stop the application in a controlled way.
Think about our demo application when the application is in use,
and we shut it down by immediately stopping the process.
There might be registrations which have only been processed halfway,
for example.
The ticket might just have been saved in the database,
but we haven't yet sent the confirmation email and call to billing system to
prevent having to deal with partially processed registrations.
It would be better if we could shut down the application by having it stop
accepting new registrations and finish the registrations that are
currently in progress before stopping the process.
Spring integration has a special method that we can call for this.
If we use JPA console to look at the ambience in the running applications,
then under the item or code spring framework,
integration off monitor, we can find the integration and being exporter.
This is the spring integration component that's responsible
for making all the other spring integration components
visible via jm X as and beans.
The integration and being exporter provides a number off operations,
and the one we are interested in here is to stop active
in When you invoke this operation,
it will stop the components in the application in a controlled way.
This happens in a series off steps.
First,
it will call the before shutdown method off any beans in the
application contacts that implement the interface.
Orderly Shutdown capable.
If you need to do anything special when shutting down the
application in your own components,
then you can have some implement this interface.
Next.
It stops all active message channels,
message sources and inbound message producers.
Active message generals Our message generals that have lifecycle
methods such as start and Stop and examples are channels backed by a
message broker that are accessed via J.
M S or AM Q B.
The point of this step is to stop messages coming in from external systems.
Then, in the next step,
the method wage for an amount of time which you can pass in
as a parameter for finishing the processing of messages that
are currently in the system.
Finally,
it calls these after shutdown method off beans in the application contacts
that implement the interface orderly shutdown capable.
After this, the process itself will still be running,
but all components will have stopped, no new messages will be accepted and the process can safely be stopped.