[Autogenerated] we're at the end of this model about managing and
controlling spring integration applications.
Let's summarize what you've learned in this module.
We started with a quick overview of J.
M X, the Jaffa Management extensions to use J M X.
You instrument your code by writing and beans,
which you register in an Ambien server and beans have
attributes and operations and can publish notifications with
the management tools such as JPA console.
You can read and write these attributes,
invoke operations and receive notifications.
Next we looked at how spring integration supports J M X.
There are a number of components that bridge the gap
between JM X and spring integration.
We did a demo in which we improved the error
detection and handling for sending email.
We added a retry mechanism that can be activated.
Fire J M X.
We used an attribute polling channel adapter to monitor
the number of messages on the error,
a Q and A notification publishing channel adapter to publish a J M X
notification when there are more than 10 error messages on the Cube.
We also added an operation invoking channel adapter to stop the service
when there are more than 50 error messages on the Cube.
Next we looked at the control bus enterprise integration pattern.
The main idea off the control bus pattern is to use the
messaging infrastructure that's used for application messages
for system management messages as well.
Spring integrations implementation off this pattern is to
control bus component that interprets messages as spring
expression language expressions,
which you can use to call lifecycle message of
components and other management methods.
Finally,
we looked at how we can shut down components in a controlled way
so that processing off messages is finished properly before the
application is really shut down.
There's more to learn.
In the next module,
you're going to learn about techniques for analyzying and debugging spring integration applications.