Hello and welcome back to the course on
Tableau and finally Tableau 10 is out
and today we're looking at the features
are in this whole section. We're looking
at the new features of Tableau 10, now
Tableau 10 has lots of great and
outstanding features of change the
colors, of added font, so you can optimize
your dashboards to different devices,
there's support for android devices. Lots
of new features and powerful techniques
have been introduced.
However, in my view they are three main
new features that are super ultra
powerful and those three others are
going to focus on inside this section of
course we're going to talk about many
more but these three other ones that I
would like to make sure that your
hundred-percent comfortable with and
that after completing this section you
can honestly put them into your data
sets Arsenal because those are the
three that will make the difference that
will put you ahead of the competition,
that will make you shine make you more
valuable than somebody else who also
knows Tableau because you're going to be
ahead of the game, you are going to know
how to use these features very well and
also you, this whole challenge that we're
doing in this section is going to be
based on these features. We're going to be
using these three features to solve the
challenge along with the other features.
Alright so let's talk about them; What
are the three main features? Number one,
you can build your own custom
territories in Tableau 10, very very
incredibly powerful if you worked with
massive maps in Tableau 10 and kind of
like odd type of weird maps, then you
will know exactly I'm talking about previously,
you'd have to do some geo hacking, I had
to do that once it will it's not fun
you have to actually go and play around with
certain files and create these joke
customers, joke coded files, upload them
into Tableau and literally hack Tableau.
You had to hack Tableau, to get these
maps in there so that you could create
things like this different regions like
this that don't actually exist, that are
only specific to your challenge.
Previously was very very painful and
tedious, now this
this is not right, now it's much easier
to do and we will find out in this
section of course how to. I hope you're
excited about that it will be a great
tool to have,
moreover we will look at two separate
methods of creating custom maps custom
territories in Tableau. Yeah, that's right
we'll look at two methods so, I just want
two different methods how to create
custom territories in Tableau 10, very very
powerful feature, will definitely come in
handy if you work with maps and Tableau.
Alright feature number two, uncover
patterns in your data with Tableau
10's clustering feature. So another
ultra useful technique, so this we've got
some examples here they're just creating
some clusters over there, that's clusters
on a map then there's just some clusters
inside on scatter plots combined with the
maps. So it's a powerful technique. It
allows you to understand how your
data is grouped and identify groups
in your data that aren't just
visually evidence. So we'll see that in
this section, we'll see when we can
visually identify a group and then
Tableau will confirm that for us and then
we'll refine our clustering and we will
challenge Tableau to create clusters from
more data than we can see and it will
do that for us and you will see some
very powerful insights from that very
good technique to have at you're just
by your side to use at any point time
because it's a great advantage because
previously to in order to run clustering
analysis or create clusters you would
have to attach tools like r2 analysis or
maybe create the clusters elsewhere and
then import them into Tableau. Now
they've incorporated this methodology
inside Tableau, so it's as easy as
everything else just drag-and-drop and
you have a ultra-sophisticated tool that
is working for you in the background and
it's just giving you the results which you
can use right away in your analysis. We'll
see how powerful that is inside this
section as well.
Alright, so I hope you're very excited
about that already so we've got two super
powerful tools. We've looked at maps and
now we've looked at clustering and now
we've got another tool in the third
realm in the space of data connections,
integrate your data with cross-
database joins in Tableau 10. Yes, we can
finally do it.
Remember back in the day, well back in
the day before Tableau 10, you couldn't
connect a data sets from different
sources. So for instance, if you had a
data set from a excel file and a SQL
database, the only way to combine them
would be to create a blend and same
thing goes for excel and csv for example
and lots of examples. Here they've got
SQL and MySQL and before you'd have to
create a blend in order to combine those
data sets and now they've changed it now
you can actually combine data sets from
different data sources no problem, of
course there's still some restrictions
but they're very specific. They are only
some data's basis that you can
connect with but for most applications
we there is now a connection that you
can create joins, not just blend. You can
create joins it before you start your
analysis even if your data is coming
from different data sources. If you've
worked on some projects, where data does
come from different sources, you will
know and appreciate how useful this new
feature will be to you. So I'm
super-excited about this one as well.
It's a big step forward for Tableau, it
has been a long time coming and it's
finally here. We can create cross
database joins. So, there we go those are
the three main features that will be
focusing on, those are the three most
powerful features that you have to know
about to leverage the full power of
Tableau 10 and we will cover them off
very thoroughly inside this section of
the course and you'll be entirely
comfortable by the end of it and
moreover we will solve a real business
challenge for a start-up inside this
section of the course using these
techniques and some other ones of
Tableau 10. Super excited about this. It's
going to be fun, can't wait to see you on
the first tutorial and until next time,
happy analyzing.