Hello and welcome back to the course on
Tableau. In today's tutorial we're going
to recap on what we learned in this
section, I felt that we learned quite a
few new techniques and that would be
very handy for us to have this recap
tutorial so you can always return back
to it and just check what exactly we
learned and I see where you can find the
right knowledge that you might be
needing in your analytics or data
science career, but before we do recap I
would like to ask you for a quick favor
I would really appreciate if you could
rate at this course and maybe even leave
a written review for it, to rate the
course, all you have to do is click the button
up at the top which says rate the course
and then if you have some time I would
really appreciate a quick written
review. This would really help me out and
moreover help the other students that
are considering this course to
understand whether this course is worth
their while or not. So even if you
received some value from this course
already, even if you haven't seen the
whole course entirely but you feel that
you received some value leave a note and
let us know what you thought of the
course. And now moving on with our show,
so what did we learn in this section.
Well in this section, we learned quite a
lot of things. In this section we learned
first of all how to create custom
territories by groups, so that was the
first way we learn how to create custom
territories and was a very direct
approach where you select that
geographical objects that you want in
your custom territory directly on the
map and then you just to create a group
from them and that allows you to create
that custom territory.
The second approach was how to create
custom territories by geographic roles.
So this was more of a process based
approach where you have some steps that
you need to perform so you go into your variable
that you want to use as your custom
territory and then you select, you create
a geographic role for it using another
variable that's present in your data set.
Also a very handy approach, both of them
are very powerful. They achieve the same
result but they just different
methodologies so depends on what your
situation is and exactly what type of
analysis you're performing. You
choose one of the other. Then we talked about
how to use highlighters in Tableau so
highlighters are kind of like filters
but they're not actually filter. So they
are a way to highlight data on your
charts without interfering with
the chart itself. Without changing the colors,
Without changing the shapes or sizes or
anything, you can very subtly add a
highlighter to perform some quick
analytics right on the chart. So that
this is more of a data investigation,
data interrogation type of technique where
you can very quickly highlight the
different categories that you're after.
Then we talked about how to perform
clustering analysis in Tableau and here
in tableau is actually underlined
because in older versions of Tableau, you
would need to link a tool such as for
instance are the programming language of
R, in order to perform this clustering
analysis. Now finally this clusterring
analysis is available directly in
Tableau and as you can see it is a very
very powerful feature which allows you
to very quickly derive insights from
your data based on some sort of
variables that you want to be included
in that clustering analytics. Then we
also looked at how to use domain
knowledge to add external data sets into
your analysis as you recall we were
talking about a startup that deals with
people and specifically deals with
helping out them with their laundry. So
therefore we thought that a good idea
would be to add population into the mix
and see how that affects our analytics
and the insights that we can drive and
in order to do that we had to create a
cross database join which is also
another powerful feature you can create
these joints across different sorts of
databases or datasets for example excel,
SQL and csv files, mySQL lots of
different databases and data sets. Of
course there are some restrictions and
hopefully the Tableau team will keep
creating a more and more possibilities
for us in that sense, but already you can
perform a lot of different joins even
across different databases which is a
great thing to have.
Then we talked about how to combine a
regression modeling and
clustering also a very powerful
technique when you combine these two
approaches to analytics as we can see we
derive some very powerful instance and
we were able to solve the business
challenge at hand. And finally we talked
about how to save clusters for further
analytics, so once you've created the
clusters it is always very handy to have
them as a group on your dimensions shelf
so you can always later bring it into
your analysis and see how those clusters
or how those categories that you've
created through the clusters affect the
other insights that you're driving from
your analytics and hopefully you enjoyed
this section of the course. Please don't
forget to leave a review I would really
appreciate if you could do this for me
today and I look forward to seeing you
next time.
Until then, happy analyzing.