Hello and welcome back to the course on
Tableau. In today's tutorial, we're
starting a brand new challenge which
will be solving in this section of the
course.
Alright, so let's look at the brief.
Alright, you are a data scientists
working for a laundry pick-up services
startup called "We wash, You sleep".
This is a relatively small company and
they cannot compete with the big players
in major cities. The company's strategy
is to build a vast network in this
smaller cities. So we wash, you sleep
already had a strong presence in a
140 locations and recently opened
stores in 10 new cities.
Additionally, the company has two
separate sales region so some just some
additional information on top of
everything else. You have been assigned
two analytics tasks. Number one identify
which of the two sales regions is
performing better, i.e. outperforms the
other in two of the three metrics:
average revenue per city, average
marketing spend per city less is better
obviously, and average ROMI, ROMI stands
for return on marketing investment per
city and that is revenue divide by marketing
spent and challenge number two or
analytics task number two, identify which
of the 10 new locations have the best
potential for the company to invest more
funds into marketing.
Alright so, let's talk about this for a
second before we proceed to the data sets.
So this company we wash you sleep, is a
startup, one of the startups where or
companies where they come to your house,
and you give them the laundry they take away
they wash it and they come back on the
next day, so basically it's all done. You
can even be done in the morning if you
needed very urgently usually takes like
a day or two and they bring back your
laundry and that's it. So you don't even
have to have a washing machine, don't
have to have a dryer.
It's a convenient service so I've used
one of those when I was in the US,
traveling. Very convenient, and I know
there's some in large cities like I use
one in San Francisco.
I don't know about the smaller cities, so
what this company is doing is obviously
as a start-up, you can't compete with big
companies like that that are established
in the market. You can, but it's tough but
their strategy bit different. So, speaking
of strategies, this strategy what
they could be aiming towards, they would
create this network in the smaller
cities and the cities' aren't that small.
They're like 100,000, 200,000,
300,000 people in population so they
will create a network in those cities
and then when the bigger companies,
because it is kind of a new industry,
where the bigger companies expand into
the smaller cities, what this company
could do is they could potentially look
should be acquired. To some, so that
is a valid strategy for a company as
well to create a network in smaller
cities. So when the big company comes
there, instead of doing everything from
scratch they can just buy this smaller
company and rebranded it and so that could
be the reason while, why they're
doing this or maybe there could be other
reasons. So basically this is what's
happening so they're in a 140
locations,  they're expanding to 10 new cities
and now they have two separate sales,
what is what are they called, two separate sales
regions and they're competing with each
other so that's also the strategy where
you split your company to two and to two
geographies and then they have to
compete with each other so they which
one outperforms the other, gets like
bonuses and stuff like that, so that's an
important thing so that's they want to
find out, some metrics there and number
two is this is probably the more
important part of the challenge in the
10 new cities, they want to know which
ones are best positioned to get that
additional marketing funding so if you
put that marked funding into marketing and
then you get more return on your investment.
So that's what we're going to be
researching in part two.
Alright so that's the challenge,
hopefully it all makes sense pretty
exciting and where do we get the data
set?
Well to get the data set, we need a
browser and as usual we need to go to
www.superdatascience.com/tableau. Scroll down here,
you'll find section 8: What's new in
Tableau 10?
So, in this section we've got startup
expansion, excel file and US cities
population csv file. Let's have a look at
them.
So here's the startup expansion file and
in this file, what we have is the store
ID or should probably say
location ID or city ID. This is where the
150 stores or 150 cities where
the company works that's those are the
ideas just basically row ID in this data set.
City is the actual city where the
company's operating, state of that city.
It's actually quite important column
because for many reasons, but also
because sometimes you might get cities
that you don't know which state they're
in because there they might be a city or
several cities with that name in the
U.S. so it's also have always important
to look at city and state. It's like kind of
like month and year right, so you might
know which month but you don't know
which year, so that might be a problem.
So it's always important to know the
exact geography or be specific and we'll
see an example that in this section, then
the sales region so as you can see
they're divided by regions so they
basically divided by states. Some states are in
the region two, some states are in region
one. Right now it's called quite
ambiguous, you can't really tell how it
looks on the map but once we create the
map you'll it will seem pretty
interesting how they've divided into two
sales regions and next we've got a new
expansion so, is this a new city or not?
Basically they're all except for the
bottom 10 which makes sense right so
they got added at the bottom and then
we've got the marketing spend, how much
was invested in the market and
revenue and so by the way in this
specific challenge, it is interesting how or
something to note is that ROMI, return
on marketing investment is calculated
revenue divided by marketing spend sometimes ROMI,
this matrix calculate as profit divided by
marketing spend. So be careful like
depends on the situation, depends on the
definition in this case its revenue
divided marketing spend. And then we've
got another file US cities' population, so
basically it's a file with the
population of the top three hundred US
cities. There are actually more than 300
years cities up to here. A quick hint, all
of our cities the ones we're looking at
these ones here they're actually part of
this top 300 so they're, they're in here
and we will have the population
information on those cities from
here so that's you don't need to worry
about that. As long as we have this file,
we'll have the population will be using
column 2015 estimates, so there's
2010 actual census data 2015 is an
estimate but we'll be working with this
because it's more recent and then
there's some additional information but
that's just an example when you have
additional information that you won't be
using in your analysis, although based on
those things you learn in this section
of the course, you can definitely
experiment with this additional
information and see if that might
somehow fix your cluster analysis and
stuff like that. So that's also just that
just some extra data in case you want
to play around.
Alright so there we go, that's what we
have for the section we've got two data
files and we have our challenge for this
part of the course. It's going to be a
very exciting tutorial, we're going to
talk about some cool analytics so this first part
is going to be all about geographies and
mapping. The second part is going to
delve into some more advanced stuff,
going to talk about clustering and we
also going to about trends or building
for costs are actually recruit like
models regression models on top of
clustering and then we'll also talk
about cross started joins and a few
other things. So exciting challenge ahead
exciting section ahead, I look forward
to seeing you on the tutorials
throughout this section and until next
time, happy analyzing.