Hello and welcome back and today we're
talking about types of joins. Now joins
are operations that are performed on
tables in relational databases. So you
would perform them in SQL, microsoft SQL
and Oracle in Mysql in many different
platforms where the data is stored
in a structured format. So let's have a
look at some joins and understand how
exactly they work. To start off with
let's assume that we have two tables,
table A and table B, and in our example
table A will have the following rows.
It's got three columns, customer, gender &amp;
age and is basically a table that is
describing our customers. So we've got
five customers Adam, Benjamin, Jack, Nick and
Susan. We've got their genders listed and
their ages. Now if we go to table B, it's
a table of employees of a certain store
of our store basically so it's got the
employee name, the title and the wage
and so what we're going to try and do is
we're going to try and find out which of
our customers are also our employees. So
basically where, where do we have
matching rows in these two tables? And
how we're going to do that? Well
basically if we look at the tables, we can
see right away that Jack and Susan both
appear in the customer and in the
employee tables. So how do we do this
from an SQL perspective for basically
from a joining perspective?
Well if we start off with an inner join
then let's have a look at how it will
work. An inner join will take the two
tables and it will look at only their
intersect. So basically if join in our
tables on customer equals employee then
and it's an inner join then the
remaining rows will only be the matching
rows, so in this case Jack is matched
with Jack and Susan is matched with
Susan because we're just looking at the
customer column on the left table and at
the employee column in the right table.
So once that matching is done,
the rest of the rows which haven't
matched are discarded and the remaining
table looks like this. So it only has
those rows that match and kind of glues
them together and that's it. That's what
the result of an inner join on these
two tables would look like.
Now let's have a look at a left join so
there's a few different types of joins
but now we're going to proceed to the
next week all the left outer join and
ensure it can also be called the left
join so a left join basically says that
the primary table is the one on the left,
once again we're joining on the first
column of the first table. Customer
equals to the first column of second
table which is employee and since the
left table is a primary one rows cannot
be discarded from the left table. Rows
will only be discarded from the
non-primary table, so here Jack is
matched with Jack, Susan's matched with Susan
again and then the rest of the rows in
the second table are discarded because
they didn't have a match. And so the
resulting table will look like this.
Where there was a match, the rows are
glued together and where there was no
match the associated columns are left
blank or some in SQL basically those
columns will be nolde, so let's just keep
them blank for now. That's how left join
works and basically the main idea here
is that the table on the left of the join
is considered to be the primary table
and therefore rows cannot be discarded
from the table. Now let's have a look at
the right join, the right joint works in
a very similar way but on this in this
case the table on the right is the
primary table. So once again Jack is
matched to Jack, Susan is matched to
Susan and the rest of the rows in the
left table are discarded because it is
the secondary table, it's not the primary.
Rows in the primary table on the other
hand cannot be discarded so the final
result here is a table which looks like
this. Once again the two sets of columns
have been glued together and where there
was no match on the left, the values in
the columns are left blank or nolde and
finally let's have a look at a full
outer join.
So in a full outer join we're looking at
the union of the two tables or,
probably unions not the right word. We're
looking at
all of the rows in the two tables and
that's why you see this
those two circles in the Venn diagram up
the top fully yellow and that means that
we cannot discard or the join will not
discard any of the rows in any of the
two tables.
Once again we're looking for matches so
Jack is matched with Jack, Susan is
matched with Susan and then what happens
is no rows are discarded and the tables are
glued together and that is what the
final result looks like. So on the right,
there's blank spaces where there was no
match to the table on the left, and on
the left there's black spaces where
there was no match to the table on the
right. So once again I'll just go back to
the previous slide and here you'll see
the two table separately and now off to
the join, this is what the final table
will look like.
So that's how full outer join works and
now let's just quickly recap on the
types of joins that we discussed. So we
had a look at four different joins, the
inner join which only looks at the
matching rows, the left join which keeps
the left tabe.. the table on the left as
the primary temple, the right joint which
keeps the table on the right as the
primary table and the full join or the
full outer join which does not discard
any rows from any of the tables. So in
your work you're probably going to be
using inner joins and left joins mostly
and that is because right joins are
rarely used simply because a right join
is the same as a left join just the
tables you just have to switch the
tables around so put the one on the
right on the left and the one that was
on the left on the right and you'll get
a left join once again. So most of the
time I personally use inner joins and
left joints sometimes you'll rarely find
that people do require full joins for
the task at hand.
So those were the type of joins and
that brings us to the conclusion of
today's tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next
time.