Hello and welcome back to the course on
Tableau and in today's tutorial we will
discuss how your data should look
like when you're importing it into
Tableau. Now, we've already touched on
this topic briefly before but i think it
will be a worthwhile exercise for us to
discuss this once again and recap on the
conclusion that we came up with that
time. So to start off with, I'm going to
bring up a spreadsheet with some data. So
here you have a spreadsheet that might
look familiar because we did talk about
it previously in the course, but this is
a spreadsheet that tells us about
unemployment rates or long-term
unemployment rates for different months
of the years. Starting 2005 and so on with
the different genders, so for men and for
women and for the different age groups.
So 16 to 19 years old, 20 to 24 and so on.
And so this data does look like
visually appealing to the human eye and
here we can quickly derive insights if
we need to we can scroll further along
and find the right year that we or your
month that we're looking at and we right
all right we know that the left column
is men, the right column is women and
we know which how to select the right
age group just because they're nicely
highlighted here. Also the inspiration
has some header information up at the
top. It's got some additional information
down the bottom, sometimes you might find
that spreadsheets like this will have totals
at the bottom as well like we can add
that right now. So here you've got the
total and let's just drag that along so
we'll call that total. So this is
not uncommon when there's a total at the
bottom of the spreadsheet might be
highlighted in a different color as well.
So maybe like a blue or something
that, and to as humans we can understand
and comprehend this information quite
easily but on the other side, the other
hand it's not the best format for
machines. So let's have a look at another
format that might be,
that you might be used to. So here is
another spreadsheet with the same
information and it's got the age groups,
the period and here the men and women are
split into two separate columns and so
for that period for that age group you can
understand right away
what does unemployment for men, what does
unemployment for for women and once again they
might be a total here as well. So we'll
just copy that down and as you can see
this information is presented in an
appealing way to the human eye but it is
not what machines are used to. It's not
what Tableau is used to. When you're
importing this information and for
instance this information is best
presented in the following way if you
are to put into Tableau and that format
is this where you've got two separate
columns for every type of dimension that
you have, for instance the age which is
split into certain bands here, the
gender is a separate dimension and then
you've got the period, so period of time the month
that you're looking at and then finally
you've got the measure for which is
aggregated at the lowest level of
granularity that you have. So when you
take the age, the gender and the period into
account. You've got that value over here.
So it's basically just columns of data,
rather than some visually appealing
formatted data which we had here and
here. So what you need to make sure when
you're importing data in Tableau is that
it is formatted as close to this is
possible. Ideally it has to look like this and
that means that you need to take out all
these headers any possible margins that
your data has you have to kind of
unpivot the views and put all of these
these months into a column and give that
column name called month or a time period and
put the genders into a column.
Also, you need going to get rid of the totals
because you don't need the totals in
Tableau. You can get them in Tableau if
you need them and here what they're only,
all they're doing is they're good for
visual analysis but they will confuse
you if you bring them into Tableau that
might
cause discrepancies in your data.
Also sometimes, you might find that
data instruction a way that if
a value in the commons repeated then
there is no value there. So for instance
it could be like this and so that
basically means that all of these are
January, all of these are February and March.
Well for Tableau, to understand this data
you also need to once again fill in the
blank spaces of your data and you
can all do all of this in Excel if you need
to. However the good news is in the
starting from Tableau 9, Tableau has
some advanced features in its data
import functionality which will help you
do a lot of these things in Tableau and
actually it allows you to do a lot of these
automatically and so that's what we'll
be looking at in the next tutorial. We'll
be talking about the data
interpreter and I look forward to seeing
you next time.
Until then, Happy Analyzing!