Hello.
Welcome back to the course on Tableau.
In today's tutorial we're going to solve the first part of the challenge and we'll identify which of
the two regions is outperforming the other.
Specifically we will talk about measuring these three or assessing these three metrics and plotting
them on a map.
And in order to solve this challenge we're going to learn how to create custom geographical regions
or custom territories in tableau.
So give me a fun tutorial.
Let's get straight to it.
All right.
Here is Tableau and let's open up our data set which is an Excel file so there it is startup expansion.
And if you have a look here you'll see that indeed this is our file at the bottom of 150 rows and ten
of them are the new locations or the new cities where the company opened up recently.
All right.
So let's proceed to solving the spiral challenge.
How are we going to visualize our different sales regions.
Well first of all let's create a map will drag state onto the blank area and we will change this to
a field map.
As you can see here and now we've got the states where the company does operate.
So you can see that they don't operate everywhere in the U.S. but in no problem the majority of states
they are present.
Now how do we even for ourselves identify how these states are broken up into those two sales regions
so how do we know which states belong to sales region one and which states belong sales region two.
Well the fastest way is to just take sales region and put it into color and then we go we can see that
there are two sales regions which are kind of like competing for performers which are trying to grow
faster and obviously it's it's a way to structure a company or a startup to split it into two pirates
and then see kind of put them against each other so that they strive for the better growth and things
like that.
So that's great.
And now how do we assess those metrics.
So for example one of the metrics that we're assessing is the average revenue per city.
How do we how you measure that or how to assess it.
Well let's give it a try.
We'll take revenue and put it onto label.
Now we will change this label very quickly so we'll click here click in side to form and liberal maybe
make it a 14.
So now you can see the some of the revenue for every state.
Now we can quickly change it to measure some sunless change to average snow you can see the average
revenue per state.
So what does that mean.
Well for example in Texas you can see that it's is thirty seven thousand six hundred eighty one so that's
the average of all the revenues in the state of Texas for all the cities in the state of Texas.
So if you go to the top you'll see that in Texas we've got at least two cities.
So there's Midland there's Denton and probably some more cities in Texas.
And so they all have their revenue and what we see seeing here is the average of all the cities in Texas.
But what we are actually after is the average revenue for all the cities in sales Region 1 and the average
on the revenue for all the cities in sales Region 2.
So actually we don't want the grouping the aggregation that just occurred and even if we take the averages
of these averages that's not exactly what we're after.
We just want Tableau to recognize this orange territory as a separate geographical object and then aggregate
in that object and then also recognize the blue territories or territory as one geographical object
and group or aggregate all of the cities inside of that territory and aggregate over them as well.
So we just want to numbers not that many numbers.
So how would we go about doing this.
Well this is where we start talking about creating our custom territories.
So basically we want table to recognize is a custom territory and this is a custom church.
And then tableau there are two ways for creating custom territories.
Today we'll look at approach number one.
All right.
So how would we do it.
Well it's actually pretty simple.
Were you engineered to use a group.
Now I know we haven't spoken about groups in this course and groups are a topic that we cover off in
the advanced class on Tableau but nevertheless we're going to need them now so I'm going to give you
a quick preview of groups and you'll see how you can use them to solve this challenge and if you're
interested in further developing a knowledge then you can always learn more about the groups in the
advanced course.
All right.
So what we're going to do is I'm going to hold on control and select all of the states that we want
to put into one of these regions.
So there there are.
And now we're going to just either hold our mouse over these one of them and you'll see that we've got
some options here and grouping is actually this option here which looks like a a little staple or something
like that.
And the other option is if you're right click and you slide group and you just in case we select all
dimensions.
So now we've created a group.
You can see the group on the left.
There it is sales regions and states so that's how the group was created.
That's what's included.
And if you right click it and select edit group you'll see that it has two parts to it.
Now I'm not going to go into detail about groups this is not part of what we're focusing on right now.
We actually just want to understand the custom territories.
So not in order to create the custom territory from here.
There's just one more step left.
All you have to do is take state out of your possession from here and voila as you can see now tableau
has created two custom territories.
So I'm just gonna move this over here and you can see that this is one huge custom territory which is
sales region number two and this is sales agent and once you can see that even it's not even though
it's not contiguous.
So it's like broken down into three bits.
Trouble is recognizing it as a separate territory which is a very very powerful thing to have and then
you have the average already has been calculated.
Now if you want to restore the previous color is very simple just click edit color select here orange
slice your blue click Okay.
There they are.
And so now you can see that that is our average revenue.
So right now out of these two custom territories this custom territory is performing better.
So a region one is outperforming region 2.
Now we have to check the other two metrics as well.
So let's put marketing spend in here as well we'll see average.
By the way here here's a quick tip.
So instead of sort of doing this instead of dragging the label or the object the measure into the label
and then selecting from the dropdown measure average what you can do to speed up the process is right
click when you're about to drag instead of left clicking right click drag it into label and right away
you're given this window where you can select has a pretty cool shortcut.
So it will allows you to save a bit of time on that one step and narrow it right away which to the average
marketing spend.
And finally.
So let's let's actually also put in the sales region into the label and what does the other thing are
we wanted the roaming rates.
So we wanted the return on marketing investment which is revenue divided by marketing spend let's create
a calculated field that's going to be Romi and marketing spend or revenue divided by marketing spend
click.
Okay.
Romi put that into the label as well.
Or again less is the shortcut right click put the label average Romi and let's just tidy up this label
a bit.
We're going to take sales region and put it at the top and then get rid of this and then we'll say average
revenue average marketing spend.
And finally average for Romi and all of these should be centered.
OK.
So let's click.
Okay.
So there you can see right away we've got some stats already region to average revenue 38 Region 1.
Average revenue 40.
So Region 1 is ahead in that sense then in terms of marketing spend got to two thousand in Region 2
and in Region 1 We've got two thousand eight hundred eighty nine.
So in this sense region one is ahead as well because average marketing spend that less it is the better.
And finally average Romi the more the better in Region 1 it's a bit better because it's 14 dollars revenue
per dollar marketing spend in a region to it's only thirteen point four.
All right.
So that is how we come up with these of course you can tidy these up a little bit so that so they look
a bit better.
So you can always change the font and size and for example let's just click on the label and here you
can change this to let's say at 12.
Probably would be better and bold and something that so very looks better than of course getting rid
of these zeros you can also round your average marketing span so apply some calculations.
But we're not going to focus on that the main focus was today's will was to hard to create this custom
territory.
And so we discussed the method for custom territories through creating a group.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and it is a very very powerful feature that you can use in your mapping
techniques.
So definitely keep it in mind.
And I look forward to see you next time.
Until then Happy coding.