Hello and welcome back to the course on Tableau.
In today's tutorial we will connect our special and PDA data and also take care of some data integrity
and data completeness.
Now in the previous tutorial we connected to each of the data sources individually but we need to join
them together to get the additional information relating to the crime statistics onto the map.
So we'll use a join for that.
Now we've already done most of the work on our crime stats on our PDA.
So let's delete everything else so we can delete this sheet over here.
And if we go into our data source we can also just go to New York parks and public spaces and just close
the data source just to keep our workbook nice and tidy.
Now we can also go back again and just rename our data source as well and we can call those New York
crime stats with geometry a nice long name but at least we know which one it is and what we can do now
is just follow there or redo the steps from their previous lecture where maybe connected to the spatial
form.
Now this case we won't go to data on new data source.
We want to use the same data source and just add another connection.
So we adding another connection by taking spatial fall and selecting our shape file.
Now immediately tableau will see that we want to join these two together and seeing as it can find a
field which to join on it allows us to select what we want to do.
So we're going to do an INNER JOIN because we want all the fields from both datasets that join together
so and how we'll be joined these do.
So we know we've got the park name on the PBF side and now on the far side we know the name is gold
or the field name with the park name in there.
He scored 91 1.
So once we've selected that tableau populates it for us and we can just close our joint.
Now that seems that that was just way too easy but we've done all the hard work before.
But let's just quickly check also the data integrity and data completeness and I cannot stress enough
that when working with open source data just to make sure especially when combining two data sources
on a net feel like a name that something hasn't gone wrong you haven't created additional records or
duplicate entries and some of the records that you wanted to show especially when using the enjoy is
actually you know from our PDA side is actually in there.
So first thing we'll check is just the number of records once again or the number of incidents and we
know previously we had 109.
Now we have 104.
So something has gone wrong.
So what will be checked.
There's two things we will look for.
Firstly we'll look at duplicates if any duplicates have been created even though the number of records
is less.
It's always good to check the duplicates because if there were records that were dropped the duplicates
can actually make up for that.
And we'll also look with them for records that did enjoin properly.
So first how we start off with us is we can take the name 3 1 1 which is from our spatial fault but
that into rows and take the park name into rows as well.
And now we can see with the number of incidents which we don't want by the way we actually want the
number of records because we want to see is for between the PD F and these sorry between the PD F on
this side and the spatial fall and that side.
Are there any duplicate records.
Do we have records for doing that and is more than one and we can just actually sort on that and immediately
we see and there are quite a range of those.
So how do we go about this.
Now we need to deliver on this project and we don't have time now to investigate this.
So what we will do is we will look at how we can exclude these discuss them with outline or look for
alternative data but for the purposes of this story that we will just now exclude this because we don't
have access to change the spatial data but what we can also look at is that some of these do not actually
have a number of incidents so you remember from our video file that there were records that had zero
incidents.
So what we could do is we can just take the incidents put that into filter and filter all of the zeroes
out just to see you know in terms of what actually there the problem is.
So if we do that we see there's only two records that had incidents that creates duplicate injuries
on there.
So what we will do for now is we can just take these two we'll just select both of them and we'll just
service or select them up again pest control see and put them into an Excel document just to make sure
that we keep track of what we are.
And let me just open that up.
What we are excluding or putting on the parking lot to take care of after we finish the visualization
and that will take care of our duplicate entries.
So now we are also concerned about anything that hasn't joined.
So let's go back to our data source change our joint type 2 and left joint.
Now that would take all of the entries if you remember correctly from the previous section or previous
tutorials we will take all of the entries here from our media fall and only the joining ones on the
spatial fall and this will allow us to have a look at any entries in here that had actually incidents
more than zero that did not join to a special file correct.
And that could be due to a number of different reasons and the spelling might be incorrect or a name
change could have taken place or any other inconsistencies.
But let's have a look at our sheet one.
So again we want.
OK so we know we need to be filtering for incident zero.
We are counting the number of records in there and let's just actually again sort this.
Now that we've made the change is sorted once again.
Now what do we see.
There are indeed parks and you remember these box are from your PD a file and these parks do not have
a corresponding entry in your spatial file which means that these do actually have incidents connected
to them but they are not being able to show on the graph on the map which means then that our data will
not be complete.
So just as while we check this and again we can just highlight these.
We can just highlight all of these.
Just copy them and put them in an Excel document because as we know we will we will just for now at
least ignore these and keep them on the list to discuss with outlined separately or look for alternative
solution.
And that's basically the ones they live in that we will be using.
So we'll just copy that.
And now if we go back into tableau we can join go back to our data source change our drawing to an inner
join once again.
And now we just need to exclude those.
Now we know we will do this at the data source filter and we actually already excluded the data source
filter while on the net source full of the total.
If you remember correctly from earlier and now we can just use this custom value list option over here
to paste what we have just copied into the list and it would exclude these ones.
In addition as well.
And then we're just gonna.
Okay.
And our number of entries are joined up.
And if we now look at any problems you can see all the numbers have disappeared and we only have one
record for each of them.
So this is exactly what we have done.
Not the best solution because we do want to show all of them but we'll put it on the parking lot for
now to investigate.
Once we've completed the visualization now we can just clean up our data source so we know there's any
certain fields you want to keep so we can hide the first three and we can rename this name 3 1 1 to
give it a more descriptive name and we will just cool this park name then we will continue in hiding
more of these fields.
We really don't need it right now.
And we'll go up to burrow.
We want to keep burrow so immune to give a proper name and let's just call this the city burrow.
All right then continue hiding and I think the only field we still need is the geometry so we can just
select all of them by holding down shift and click hide.
I guess this is already second nature to you so if I am skipping a few steps luckily you already looked
at the previous tutorials.
All right.
So.
And that's in essence what we were looking for.
We've got the park name from obviously from both that are sources the city borough the geometry which
we spoke about and the borough from our PDA fault as well as the incidents.
In actual fact we can hide also.
The borough from our PDA fault.
We will use it from the actual from the city generated information.
Okay.
So that is then our data ready and prepped for our visualization.
So let's quickly clear that what we've created and just put the geometry on there to see what we'll
deal with.
And that is exactly it.
You can see we don't have central Park.
Central Park wasn't in our crime statistics so obviously doing in adjoining to remove them and it will
remove all of the problematic ones which we've identified but at least we know our data is complete
for what our purposes are today.
Now in the next material we will finally get to creating that awesome visualization and putting everything
together.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.