Hello this is Carol.
And welcome back to the course and tableaux in today's editorial we will learn how to navigate Tableau
and we'll get to play around two.
So here you can see where we left off last time we had just connected to our office supplies that CSP
dinosaurs.
So let's move on to the tableau workspace.
Here you can see at the bottom a typical sheet one.
Let's look on that.
And right away we're presented with the tableau working area and it may seem a bit overwhelming at first
but that's exactly why in the previous section we had this quick agile run through where we very rapidly
created a map and it was quite intuitive wasn't it.
So that's exactly what we'll talk about today how easy it is to navigate this workspace in front of
us.
So the two main areas here are the data connection on the left or the Data tab on the left and the working
area on the right.
So this is where you will be creating things masterpieces.
So let's talk about the Data tab on the left first.
The data is always broken down into two sections dimensions and measures.
And there's a very distinct difference between them and it's important to understand.
So dimensions and measures are roles different to different roles that any data element can take.
And normally what tableau does is enmeshed in two measures it puts any kind of miracle values and into
dimensions.
It puts all the categorical and kind of qualitative Don.
So that's the default setting for Tableau and you're easily able to drag them around.
So if you're not happy with something being a measure you want you can put in two dimensions like like
that for instance.
As easy as that but we will do that right now.
So I just put controls that there to undo an action.
That's the standard Windows key to cancel something.
So the other way to think about dimensions and measures is dimensions are independent variables and
measures are dependent variables.
So for instance you have here we have unit units.
So how many units of a certain item were sold.
And here we have region.
So we can find out how many units in each region were sold.
So region will be the independent variable and units will be the dependent variable because will be
grouped by region and based on that definition which is the correct definition things might be you might
you might require to move things around from dimensions into measures and measures dimensions but we
won't focus on that right now because tableau usually guesses it quite correctly.
OK.
So what do we have here as well at the top we've got the normal ribbon for Windows so file basic you
can save your file open and you file data you can collect connect to new data sources here are worksheets.
So this is considered a worksheet.
What we're going to be creating now is going to be a worksheet.
And we will get to work with these elements a bit more in the future dashboards.
We are not talking about dashboards right now it will come further down in this course.
A dashboard is a combination of worksheets story a story can be a combination of worksheets and dashboards
and we will get to weave stories as well that's a relatively new feature for tableau analysis.
It just basically specifies how you want to do your analysis on the current sheet that you're working
with.
We will be working off this tab a little bit in the future map.
We'll work with this when we get to maps and basically formats.
There are other ways to access formatting and we'll be doing that in the course server.
We won't be looking at server right now and window help.
These are just auxiliary functions.
So then what are we going to look at now is basically we won't talk about this right away because we
will get to know this ribbon as we progress the course.
But right now I'd like to focus on the main work area where we will be creating a worksheet.
So here the main elements are columns and rows.
So most of your worksheets will be created by deciding what goes into columns what goes into rows and
then what goes into these other elements like what decides color what the size of your shapes what decides
what text is attached to shapes the level of detail we will talk about aggregation more for the course
and any tool tips that you want to apply.
So the easiest way to explore is probably to explore by doing so let's drag a few things onto this worksheet.
I would assume let's start perhaps with region.
So just drag it into the middle here.
And so we've put one dimension in and let's put another dimension let's say units and right away you
can see that by dragging those two in tableau has decided to put region automatically into rows and
your units into some them.
So it's aggregate them by region and it's put them into label.
And so here you can see that now you can tell right away how many units were sold sold in each region.
So now we can we can just drag and drop here.
So if we're not happy with having units here we can put them into columns and right away we have a bar
chart.
And now we can expand this a bit and then reduces a bit.
Now we can see by region we can also see how many units have been sold.
And you can also see that there is a tool to popping up every time you hover over or one of the bars.
Now there's a very handy tool in tableau which is called show me here.
So I encourage you to play around with it.
I don't normally use it in my work because I already know what I want.
Most of the time but it gives you kind of suggestions and quick shortcuts to different things.
So let's look at a pie chart for instance here.
Now we can see a pie chart instead of our market and now if we want to increase the size of its more
usually these pie charts so poor so we'll drag it like that.
And if we're still not happy if the sizes but annoy here size Just click that and you'll see how it
grows.
Well that's a bit too much.
So what does this show us.
It shows us what region by color has what proportion of the total sales in units.
Once again we're just playing around now where there's no intention of what.
For what we're doing we're just exploring tableau.
So here you can see Central East and West.
And yeah it's it's a pretty cool pie chart but let's see what else we have.
So we can do a bubble chart right away.
Tableau puts everything in the right positions for us.
As you can see there's nothing in columns and nothing in rows.
Everything has been put in here.
Tableau has selected circles for us from this dropdown that's created this bubble chart.
So what else.
And then we can look at a tree chart tree map.
That's what is called treatment.
So here.
So it's like a bubble chart but it's a bit different because it's got boxes instead of instead of circles.
And here once again the relative size of the box the area of the box is directly correlated to the number
of units sold in that region.
You can just keep clicking around and you'll see different versions of the dashboard that or the worksheet
that tableau is suggesting for you and maybe you might be happy with one of them.
But we won't rely on that and we will create our own version in the next story.
So before we finish up I just want to show you that in this show me box some of the things are great
out and that's because you need certain elements of data to create these for instance to create an area
chart you need at least one data so zero or more dimensions one or more measures and at least one day.
So we don't have a date in our worksheet right now.
Tableau concrete an area chart for us so if you want to add a day to just drag a date in here and now
it's highlighted and now we can create a area chart.
But once again we'll get to area charts line charts and all these other things for a done the course
today we're just exploring tableau.
So I look forward to seeing the next material.
And until then happy analyzing.