Hello, this is Carol, and welcome back to the course and Tablo.
And today we will get to start solving the problem that we have at hand.
Who gets a bonus?
So we left off here last that we were just playing right out of Tablo.
I hope you had a chance to explore further the different buttons and tools of table has to offer, because
the more you play around with it, the better you get at it.
And it happens very quickly because Tablo is very, very intuitive.
And that's just we're talking just about the navigation.
So, you know, basically where to look for what right now.
I'll show you another cool feature is clear the dashboard.
So we don't want any of this.
And so there's a button over here, the red one clear sheet.
And so we're just going to click that and boyah.
Everything is gone.
By the way, if you're using the Mac or a MacBook, um, some of these layouts might be a bit different.
So just kind of follow along and you will be able to find where they are.
But just bear in mind that they might not be in the same exact place as I'm showing.
OK, so let's start answering the question where we know that we can create Barchas this create a bar
chart for the representatives and see what they've sold.
So we want representatives to be kind of in the columns.
So there they are, our salespeople.
And let's see how many units each one of these represents have sold, has sold.
There we go.
So we can see that Richard has sold the most units, which is great.
And how about we break it down by region so we know that we have three bonuses, one for every single
one of one for the best representative in each region, and like this, we can't really tell who's the
best in each of the regions.
We could just tell who's the best overall.
So what we're going to do is we're going to take region and we're going to drag it into columns, but
we're going to put it before representative.
So as you can see, I'm doing here and I'm just going to let go.
And what does that do?
Well, it gives us a kind of another level on top of our representatives.
So first, the chart is broken down by regions so that you can see that here.
So I'm just going to make this a bit smaller so I can zoom in.
So here you can see that the chart is broken down central, east and west.
And then inside every region is broken down into by representative.
And so that way we can easily tell who's the best in sales in each of the regions.
So here it's Alex, here it's Richard.
Here's James.
And so now another cool feature.
You can order these bars by their size.
So if you see this little button here, so when you come roll over the axis, this this little one here.
So if you click that.
Automatically, they're sorted by side, so you can see how it drops off and you'd think that this answers
our question, but in reality, no, it doesn't, because units is actually the number of items that
has been sold.
But as we know, our representatives are actually measured based on the dollar value of their sales.
And so we need to find out the dollar value.
But as far as you can see here, there's no actual dollar value, total dollar value of sales.
We know that.
And it's really, really easy to find it or to see that because all of our numbers are kept in measures.
So we don't even have to look here.
We can see here that we only have units and we only have unit price and we have some of these other
fields which we will talk about further down the course.
But like the ones from our data, our units and unit price, and there's no total dollar value.
And that means that we have to create that total dollar value.
How do we do that?
Well, it's quite easy.
You just have to multiply the number of units the representative representative had sold by the total
unit price for those units.
So if I click our daughter here, I go to view data.
You can see here that when, for instance, Nick sold Binder's, he sold twenty nine binder's at the
price of one dollar ninety nine cents each.
So the total revenue from that sale would be twenty nine times one point ninety nine dollars, making
it somewhere around fifty dollars for that sale.
So we need to calculate that multiplied value and apparently it's not president database or in our dataset.
So let's go ahead and do do this in Tablo.
And this is where we talk about creating calculated fields.
So you have to do is right.
Click on measures, create calculated field.
And we'll call it total sales, and here we will call we will take unit price or units and we will multiply
units by unit price.
OK, so now we have a total sales value.
And as you can see, there's a little equal sign before the hashtag.
That means it's a calculated field.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to take total sales and we will drag it onto a chart to
replace the units.
So I'll just drag it exactly on top.
And as you can see, Tableau picks it up and aggregates it just as it did with unit.
Other way to do it is you can take this one off, remove it and then take total sales and put it on
where you need to be.
And so now we have some total sales.
And now if we order by this value, you will see that we have a different picture.
Now, Richard is no longer the best seller overall.
Susan beat him in the east region.
Mathew's the best in the central region.
And James James is still the best in the west region.
So now we know who has deserved the bonus.
It's Matthew, Susan and James.
And that was an example of how to create a calculated field in Tableau.
Hope you enjoyed that.
And I look forward to seeing you next time when we will be talking about colors.
Until then, happy analyzing.