Hello and welcome back to the courts on Tableau.
In the previous tutorial we imported our personal vehicle sales data into Tableau and we used the DA
interpreter tool to help us out.
And this is what the data looks like.
So it looks great.
It's it's clean it's it's got all the information that we need.
But the problem here is that as we discussed this kind of format is still more oriented at humans because
it's got the years in separate columns whereas in a machine in a raw machine format the years would
be in their own column and then you would just have the values in another column.
So ideally this dataset should be presented with four columns Region Country year and total sales for
that year rather than this and pivoted view.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to learn how to pivoted right here in tableau.
And as you can imagine I'll just bring up the spreadsheet here which we worked with before.
As you can imagine to achieve what we want to achieve by adjusting this data it would take us quite
some effort to move from this kind of format to a format where we just have a column for year and then
a column for the value.
But the beauty of Tableau is that it can do all this for you and it's very simple just observe how quickly
this can be done.
We're just going to select the columns that we want to pivot.
We select all of these columns and then you just select or one of the drop downs and you click pivot
and there go it's all done as easy as that.
So now you've got Region Country pivot or the year and the value or the total sales total number of
cars sold for that year.
So as you can see we can also just just to make sure we can compare to what we see in our spreadsheet.
So let's pick a random random row from this new table and we'll say let's say somewhere Europe Europe
Greece 2007 two hundred seventy nine thousand cars.
So now not going to bring up the spreadsheet since I can find it.
Here it is.
So Europe Greece to sell two thousand seven hundred seventy nine thousand cars.
Perfect.
So that means it's working and as expected and that is how you pivot data in tableau.
So we'll continue with our data progression in the next term.
And I look forward to see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.