Hello and welcome back to the course on tableau.
And today we're talking about aggregations and granularity is going to be a quite an important tutorial
because the things that you learn today you will take away and apply throughout this course and throughout
all of your work of Tableau because these things govern how tableau operates.
So let's get straight into it.
Here we've got the chart and the chart that we've created and it's showing us unemployment in the US
a month to month from 2005 to 2015.
Now the question that we have is how does tableau know that we want to see it at the monthly level.
How does tableau know that this aggregation that is doing summing up the unemployed variable how does
it know that we want to see it at the month level how does it know that it needs to sum it up at the
month level.
So the answer is quite simple.
Tableau will always aggregate measures at the level of granularity of your worksheet.
So in this case because we have this variable here month of period tableau knows that we are intending
to see all of this data that we're plotting at the level of one month or at the granularity of a month.
And so what that means if was if I remove this if I just drag it out of the dashboard or the worksheet
you will see one single dot.
So instead of lots of dots or a line tableau has no.
Now tableau has no clue at which level granularity we want to see the worksheet.
And it assumes that we just want to see it at the broadest level possible.
And that is at the level of the whole dataset.
So what it does is just sums up all of the values for this variable unemployed into one single value
and it plots it for you.
So I'm just going to control Z and return month of period.
And so that in this case month off period is the variable that governs granularity.
Normally what happens or quite like the concept behind Tableau is that measures get aggregated and dimensions
specify the level of granularity and we'll see how that works in a second.
In this case month of period even though it's recognized as a measure and it's green it is still the
variable that is specifying the level of granularity.
And that's because it introduces this axis or timeline at the bottom and it actually specifies that
we want to see it at the monthly level.
So it makes sense for Tableau to assume that we want to see this chart at the level of clarity of a
month so know what we can do to alter ego aggregation is we can go to analysis and we can actually switch
it off.
So if you just uncheck this box you'll see that you get this fuzzy chart and now we're just going to
replace it with a shape charge just to make it look better and you'll see that now instead of aggregating
the data Tableau is just plotting unemployed.
So basically it's plotting every single row of our data set separately on this chart.
So you're going to have a lot of values for the same month in the same year.
And that's because we have two genders and we have a lot of different age groups.
And now if we look at the bottom we will see that there is a total of one thousand seven hundred eight
marks and that is the total number of rows that we have in our data because our daughters at monthly
level.
So if we go back to our Plus here we just going to switch aggregation back on and I'll show you another
way we can alter aggregation.
Now what we can do is instead of switching aggregation off we can introduce a dimension which will change
the level of granularity of our dashboard and therefore it will affect the aggregation.
So we're going to take gender and we're going to drag it onto color and right away you can see here
that we have twice as many dots.
The blue dots represent male and they're orange dots represent female unemployment for that specific
month.
And now tableau knows that because we have this variable here which is month period and because we have
this dimension in our worksheet it knows that we want to see everything or we want to see all of the
measures aggregated at the level of granularity of month plus gender.
So if we look down here you'll see that this 244 marks that is twice as many marks as we had when we
had months I'll just take gender out for a second and you'll see that we have a hundred and twenty two
marks.
And so now if you return gender back into color there's two hundred and forty four marks and that is
telling us that the level of granularity has become even smaller or bigger actually.
So we the chart has become more granular because we've introduced this dimension.
What else can we do.
We can introduce more dimensions to increased granularity even further.
So let's take H and drag it into shape.
So now you can see many more marks and you still see orange and blue orange represents gender and a
blue already represents female and blue represent male.
But at the same time there's different shapes on the chart.
Now there's circles of squares as crosses.
There's pluses there's lots of different types of shapes and each shape represents a different group
or a different level kind of a different data points or a different point on our chart and Tableau knows
the level we want to aggregate at because it can see all of the dimensions and our worksheet can see
that we have gender we can add we have age we have a month period so it knows that this sum is known
had now has to be calculated having these this level of granular granularity in mind.
So that's how aggregate that's how granularity works and aggregation works together with granularity
credit clarity.
Let's have a look at different types of aggregations that are available.
So I'm just gonna remove age so it's not too cluttered.
And now what are we going to look at.
Is not some of unemployed we're actually going to change it.
And if you click this dropdown and go down to measure some here you can change what you want to see.
So let's say you want to see the average unemployment for that month.
If you click that you'll see the chart didn't change much but the axis actually change.
So when you had some it was the total unemployment for that gender for that month.
Now if you click measure average you will see that it is the average unemployment for that gender for
the month.
There's another one let's look at a median.
See now the chart changes because it's actually showing us and axis changes as well.
But now it's not proportional because it's median and now we can see that these marks are presenting
the medium median unemployment at the level of granularity of this worksheet and that level of granularity
is month plus gender.
And so basically that's how granularity and aggregation work.
The only one more thing that I wanted to show you and this is important is detail.
So sometimes you might want to increase your level of granularity.
You want to make your dashboard more detailed or more granular but you don't want to drag anything on
to your eye color or shape you don't want to affect the visual like coloring or other parts of your
dashboard but you do want to increase the level of granularity.
Well tableau has a solution for that.
There is this option detail in detail doesn't actually mean like detail as in words or description it
actually means that level of granularity of your chart.
And so let's do that let's take age and instead of dragging it onto shape like we did last time let's
put it onto detail and see what happens.
Now you can see that the shapes haven't changed but the granularity of the chart has changed.
So basically this is an option for you to add dimensions and measures to your dashboard without actually
affecting the visual representation but affecting the level of granularity.
And that's exactly why this but in detail or this option detail is here is for you to control at which
level the aggregation is going to happen.
So just remember about that because we will be using that going further in the course and you will definitely
find it helpful and handy when you're doing your own projects for work or at home.
So that's all for today I hope that was helpful.
And let me know if you have any questions whatsoever because these are important topics that we will
need going forward.
And in the next material we will start creating this awesome looking dashboard for unemployment worksheet
for employment worksheet dashboards will come.
All right.
I look forward to see you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.