Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And in today's tutorial, we will be talking about the differences between DOTD joining and Dota blending
to get that topic out of the way once and for all.
And also, we will look at when it is appropriate to do a Dota blend in Tablo.
So let's get straight to it for today.
We will need our data set.
Uh, we need to go to Superdad Hassans dot com slash Tablo.
If you scroll down here to Section five joining unblinding data, you will need the second dataset,
which is amazing, Marty.
You know, I won't download it because I already have it.
It's basically the same one that we worked with in Section four.
So let's open that up and have a look at it.
There it is, so here you can see, um, here you can see that this dataset has three tabs.
Um, we've already talked about it, but we'll just quickly recap.
So the list of orders tells us gives us a list of orders that had been conducted for the store, the
date when the order was placed, customer name this city, country, region, whether it was a home
office that the daughter was placed for or it was a consumer or corporate office.
Different types of customers, basically shipping day shipping mode and the state of the country order
breakdown gives us a breakdown of each order by the product that was contained within that order.
So basically this field or it is not unique in this, um, because sometimes orders have multiple items
within them.
So here you can see an example that this order had both posted markers and heldon folders and then the
discount on the order, the sales, the profit, not not on the order, actually on the product, the
discount on the product, the sales on the product, profit on the product, quantity, um, category.
So whether it was office supplies, furniture or technology and subcategory.
So what we will be interested in today is actually this field category.
It'll be important for us.
Um, and also we've got the sales target tab, which gives us targets for the three different departments,
which are furniture.
Office supplies and technology, and it gives us the targets for the different months of the data set.
So what the dollar value targets were for each of these departments for a certain month.
So that's our data set.
And what we will be looking to do today is we will want to compare, um, how the departments are meeting
or not meeting their targets.
But the caveat here is that that is not the only thing that we want to visualize.
So it is only part of a greater dashboard that we are creating.
So remember that dashboard that we created previously with the map and it was showing us different items.
I'll just bring it up actually, just to so we remember what we're talking about.
So I'll open up Tableau and remember this dashboard here in Section four that we created, which had
the different, uh, maps of the different regions and then how the customers were, which customers
were profitable, which weren't profitable and so on.
So we still want to be able to create all of this information.
But at the same time, we want to be able to analyze how the departments are performing, um, how the
different departments are performing.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So I'm going to close this workbook and we'll start a new one.
And that's just because I want every section to be independent so you can just pick up from any section
and start working on it.
So we're going to create a new connection.
We're going to create a connection to our Excel file and the Excel file is amazing.
Martlew and here.
We've got all three tabs, so we will recreate the join that we created previously.
So basically we obviously we want to order breakdown because here it's got the sales and those are the
values of the sales.
And we need to compare the sales to the targets.
But the order breakdown tab does not have information on the debt.
It does have the category, which is good but doesn't have the date of the order.
So we need the list of orders file.
So we'll take a list of orders will connected to order breakdown that creates an inner join.
And now we have the order date.
Then we have the sale that was generated on that item and we have the category under which the item
false, which is perfect.
And we still have all this other information that we need for the rest of the dashboard, which we just
looked at.
Now, the question is, how do we add sales targets into here?
Another thing is that we can't just simply drag it in and create another joint here.
Well, it does work, but we're actually doing a very incorrect thing by doing that.
And I have created a few slides, a few PowerPoint slides just to explain what exactly was going on.
So let's have a look.
Here we've got two tables that we want to join, so the table A plus B that we've already created through
a joint and the table C, which is our sales targets, table A plus B has information on order.
Edem has the date, has some more information, has the item within that order, has the category within
which the item falls and has the sales that was generated on the item.
Then also, of course there's lots of lots of other columns in there.
And as you can see here, there are other instances where the order ideas and duplicated because it
might consist of many items.
So that's how our table looks at the table that we've created table A plus B now we've also got table
C, which we want to connect or somehow we want to link these to so that we can compare the sales to
the targets.
But the thing is that the Tables C has a very different level of granularity.
Level of granularity here is not item.
So here the level of granularity is actually at an item level for each individual order, whereas here
the table is much less granular.
It's, um, it's got a month, is got category and has got the target.
So what that means is that if we do want to connect these two tables, then what will happen is we will
have to roll this table up, we'll have to roll it up by date and category in order to match this level
of granularity.
So basically, we will lose information on order ID and we will lose information on item.
We will lose all of the information except for date and category, and then we'll be able to take the
sum of sales for that specific month for that specific category and compare it to Target.
And basically that was what it means.
We're losing all of the other information if we're going to roll this table up.
And that would have been fine if that is what we were looking for, if that is the only thing that we
wanted to compare the total sales for a certain month for a certain category to their target, that
would have been fine.
But we can't do that, um, because we still need to create the rest of the dashboard.
Remember that caveat that we need to be able to create the rest of the dashboard.
So we need the rest of this information.
So that way we can just, um, roll up this table and join it to this table.
And moreover, I'm just going to end this.
So moreover, in Tablo, if we were to drag sales targets here, it doesn't actually roll the data up
for us.
What it does is just performs an inner join.
And as you recall, when there are many fields, so it's joining here, you can see it's joining on
category equals category, not even including month.
And when when that happens, it is duplicating lots of rows.
So basically this what just happened here is a whole another mess.
And if we wanted to even perform that rolled up joint, we would have to work on this a little bit.
But the good news is we don't have to do that because we can use a blend.
And that's exactly what we're going to do.
We're going to see how we can use data blending in order to connect this these two data sources.
So now, right now, we have one data source, which is called List of Orders plus.
So I'm just going to rename this list of orders plus order breakdown.
That's good.
And now we're going to create another data source, Excel and and the same file, but this time only
the sales targets.
And now if we've got our sheet, you'll see we have two data sources, list of orders plus order, breakdown
and sales targets.
So remember, we talked about blending in the previous tutorial.
Well, now we know that blending is a very smart joint that can happen on the fly.
And we're going to take advantage of that.
We're going to create, um, the visualisation that is required through blending rather than joining.
And we're going to do that in the next tutorial.
And today, we're going to finish up on this on the reason why we won't be doing a joint patrol.
We're going to be doing a blend.
And just to recap, the reason is that in this particular case, we would have had to aggregate our,
um, this dataset.
We would have had to aggregate our data set and we would lose information.
So basically the level of granularity of the two data sets is different and therefore we cannot perform
a joint.
And so that's one of the reason why you would ever want to do a blend rather than a joint.
And there's also a second reason why you would want to do a joint, and that is actually a bit more
straightforward.
It's when you are not able to do a joint because the data sources are different.
So if, for example, your other data source is not and is not the same Excel file, but is a rather
sad CSV file or a tablas server file or a muscular a Microsoft a scale database or something like that,
if the.
Data sources are different, then Tablo won't let you do a joint, you will have to be blending the
data.
So just keep that in mind that there's two reasons why you would want to do a blend.
One is different level of granularity of the data sets.
And number two is, um, the datasets are just basically different types of data sources.
So that's all for today.
I hope you enjoy the Turrill and next time we will create this blend.
It'll be quite an exciting and very visual tutorial.
So I'll look forward to seeing you then and until next time.
Happy analyzing.