Hello and welcome back to the course on Tableau.
In today's editorial it will create the remainder of the required of his life nations and use to tips
in solving our business challenge.
Now we need to create two new sheets.
So let's start off with the first one.
The first one we will actually call the average annual salary map because that is what we will have
on the four counties on the map of New York State.
And to do that we quite simply dragged in the county into our map.
And yours might look different but if you're also located outside of the United States yours might end
up like this having sixty 62 unknown land locations.
Now this normally happens when your original settings of your machine or your original settings of Tableau
is different to that of the United States when working with a data sets from the United States to fix
that is fairly easy.
You literally just click on the 62 unknown and edit locations you can also exclude the data by using
faulty data that doesn't make sense at all in this case.
But to be totally edit locations now then Tableau allows us to change the country which it needs to
focus on obviously located in the Netherlands at the moment.
So we wait for the Canadians but we will just go to the United States and we will also change the state
in the province because we know each of these counties out of all each of them all locate are related
to their state of New York.
And like magic everything disappears all of the problems and it draws us the map properly.
We actually want a filled map so we'll just click on map over there and these are all of our counties
in the state of New York.
Now we can continue.
We know we want to use the average annual salary as our colouring so we can just right click and drag
that onto color which will open up a field over there because we don't want this sum of annual salary
because remember we have all of the figures for every year.
We actually want to then calculate average over all year.
So we'll just take on average and I think we can make a few improvements.
Firstly the dark lines seem quite daunting so let's change that to white to white borders.
We can change also the actual transparency or the capacity to 65 to make it a bit more transparent and
see what goes on in the background.
And furthermore let's also change the color to black Korea always likes to do this is to change the
color green.
I also preferred like that.
And as we've done in the previous tutorial we want to see the names of each of the counties and displayed
in a nice way.
We can obviously see it on the tooltip but is this better a nice way we can just go again into map layers
and switch on the county names.
We don't need the borders.
We already have the borders but these are the names in the background map and obviously it shows it
for the rest of the counties as well but it doesn't really matter.
We can at least see it on our map nicely now and that's this visualization done very nice and quick.
Now we can just move that to the first as that's our most important one and we can create our last one.
So this is the one where we create the top five industries watch out which way we look at the average
annual salary.
And you show the top five so it's quite an easy chart again as well.
We will take the average annual salary put that in two columns and obviously change that to average
making sure we use average and then also take the industry and put that on two rows.
We will also use the industry while holding control down.
Put that into color and I just actually want to change the color here and make it something a little
bit different but more not as striking which is this on the ballot for now we know anything the top
five so we can use that.
So there will be a few repeats now but we will take industry once again and put that into filters because
we know we are only looking for the top five let's just top five over there and based on their average
annual salary and there we go.
So you can see obviously repeats are gone and the beats of the number of or at least of the industries
and we can see the top five overall for all the top five industries for all years in all different counties
in the state of New York.
And we can just rename this as well and just call this our top five industries right.
And then we can move on to putting it all together using the nice viz intuitive functionality so tableau
added this for us.
And I think it is just awesome.
So you will remember that our client specifically asked not to use a dashboard and to combine these
sheets and also not to keep different sheets.
And that's why this visit tooltip comes in handy now to add a to a sheet or a different sheet to your
visualization in the tooltip you just click on tooltip and obviously just go to the bottom two to added
below the text we already have and you would just add it from this insert button over here.
And normally we added fields from from there but we see this new option called sheets and now we they
we can select the sheets that we've just built.
So let's start with a staple line chart.
So we just click that and automatically tableau fills out all the required information so you can see
it specifies the sheet then the max with the max height.
So obviously the space within a tooltip is limited but there it's fair specifies the maximum space that
can be used by default.
And then also to make sure that all filters that are applied to our visualization here is also then
applied to that specific view.
What did that specific sheet say if we hit okay and start dragging a mouse or mouse pointer over the
graph you'll see how each county then updates the chart or it gets the joint updated for that specific
county.
Pretty helpful because now we can see specific spikes like that in Fulton County or you know even other
spikes in Steuben County.
So which we're not visible at all when we looked at them together.
So pretty pretty nice.
What we can then also do is add more than one well more than one sheet to this losing tooltip so we
can just click again.
Just put it at the bottom over there to say the same approach and add the top five industries you'll
see again all the same values are put in there.
Obviously the sheet name will be different if.
Okay.
Now you see we've got you over there.
So that is pretty neat.
And that's exactly what we wanted.
But this is obviously not where we'll stop.
We need to make some to some fixes on yeah.
I think the tooltip is way too big but loses the overall picture and there's information on there which
we don't need so to edit I'll tilt up.
I think what we can do is we can just change the maximum size and this is obviously we are able to edit
this.
So the maximum I'm not gonna change the measurement with apologies.
We changed the maximum height because we want to keep it small and we can also just change these all
these headings so we can make that much bigger.
So let's call that 18 and just give it a different color it just looks slightly different and we'll
just call this our average annual salary like that and we hit apply or wheat.
Okay.
And look at that.
She shit.
Oh.
Sheets are much smaller.
You can see the spacing use is a little bit less.
And and we've got a nice heading there as well.
So to go and edit the Axis use and maybe make the font size a bit smaller.
Also on the smaller individual sheets we can just go into each one and as we know we've done this before.
We don't need for instance the title.
It's self-explanatory.
And even for a year of a year we don't really need that.
So we can just remove all of it.
And then next we can just also format and take this to the smaller size possible.
And as you can see now it looks way better in terms of the use of space and the same with the top industries
we don't need that over there.
We can edit the access as we don't need any.
Well you'd need a title over there and let's just also make sure that we use the smallest size available
in this case.
And voila that is our visualization and doesn't that look great.
And that also then concludes our tutorials for this section in the next material we will actually be
doing a recap of the most important features which we've learned during this section and I look forward
to seeing you there until next on happy analyzing.