Hello and welcome back to the course on Tableau and in the period tutorial we created this dashboard
and what we're going to do today is we'll make it interactive and fix it up a little bit.
The make sure that the colors look great.
OK.
So now if I click around on the dashboard nothing happens which makes sense because it's not interactive
the only thing we can interact here with is the balance groups.
And that's because we created our parameters and one of the previous tutorials.
Well very quickly let's make it interactive we really know that we have a fast and efficient shortcut
to doing that if we click on the dropdown here and we click users filter right away in our dashboard
actions a filter has been generated a select filter.
And if we click Edit it's using the map to affect all of the other elements of our dashboard.
So let's go back and see how this works so if I click on Scotland now you can see the rest of the dashboard
adjusts united.
So England Wales Northern Ireland.
You can see that the dashboard is adjusting and we can really gather insights.
For instance in Scotland our gender split is much more very different to our overall split in the U.K.
72 percent of male and in Northern Ireland 74 percent of our customers are actually female.
Very interesting stuff.
OK.
So now let's do the same for the rest of them users filter users filter.
If you don't want to use something as filter then just don't use.
Don't do this for that element of dashboard burnout case.
We're gonna use all of those filters and now we can click on anything saying that we want to look at
all of the female customers of the bank we just click on that.
And now we can see all of them or we want to look at all the male customers or we want to look at all
of the white collar workers that would bankrupt us and we will also want to overlay white collar workers
with males.
Let's have a look where where they're situated.
You can see right away they're mostly in the UK.
What about males and blue collar workers.
Aha.
So most of them are actually in Scotland.
Very powerful stuff and same thing with balances if you want to have a look at the highest balances
say everybody above one hundred thousands who just select these and there you go.
You can see their age where exactly they're located and so on.
And to uncheck under a filter you just click somewhere and undone what else you can see right away.
Is this little annoying pop up.
Sometimes it's useful but in this particular case not really because we can see everything from the
dashboard we don't need to have this pop up following our mouse all the time and it can get in the way
so if I'm looking at these charts now this pop up is covering up my parameter control some other of
the some other bars and so on if I put my mouse here it's covering up the the number.
So let's go ahead and get rid of these pop up.
So you need to go to each of the worksheets and switch it off so go to let's start with map.
And here if you go to worksheet show tooltip and then just uncheck show tooltip.
Okay.
And if you go back to the dashboard this you know more tooltip still here and you have to for the other
ones as well.
But instead of going to the sheet you can just click on it go to worksheet here tooltip and check this
same thing worksheet tooltip uncheck.
No there's none here so worksheet tool to uncheck.
And the last one worksheet tool to uncheck voila.
So now whenever I put my mouse over something I don't see any tool tips which is great.
All that happens is I can select.
So that's how dashboard ready in the next tutorial we'll do some analysis.
And then in the tutorial after that we will start putting everything into a storyline.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.