Hi.
Welcome to the complete US developer course.
I'm a tool and I teach more than 150000 students so new to me on mobile programming and cybersecurity
courses along with co-stars by Rob Percival.
These are more than 1 million students on line with this experience.
We bring you one of the most comprehensive and one of the most up to date us courses ever created.
So first let me start by saying that you don't have to have any prior knowledge in order to take this
course because you're going to start from scratch.
And then you finish the scores.
You will be advanced in swift and US development where you're you going to teach you Terry.
But we're going to do it in a practical and interactive way.
We are going to build an Instagram clone at Foursquare as long as Snapchat clone and an Angry Birds
clone along with so many other apps.
So we're going to work in the real life examples.
You will learn how risk development by doing it yourself.
This course has it all.
Not only you will be able to build your own apps but also you will learn how to make money out of your
apps.
How to put them to the App Store and how to design your own.
Perhaps we are even going to provide you a one year loan that cost to you so that you can create an
marketing website for your apps on the top of that you're going to have a three hundred dollars worth
of visuals and images to use in your own apps.
Finally you will be able to participate the examinations of Cambridge sort of authority for swift level
1 and swift Level 2.
So that's it.
So if you want to be a professional US developer or if you want to build the app of your dreams then
it's time to enroll to the course.
If you have any questions during the course you can reach me in the Q and A sections all your questions
will be answered within 24 hours.
Now if you're ready let's get started.