Hi we didn't this lecture where you going to create our first X code project.
And we're going to start building our first AOS app.
So if you have closed X code for some reason you can come over here to launchpad and click on The X
code icon or you can hit comment and space in your keyboard and search for X code and find it and click
on it to open the X code.
Okay.
So if you have not closed the X code yet so it's better and you're seeing a screen like this.
So you have key options over here.
Okay.
So first you can start with a playground so playground is actually a playground in which we can play
with the swift code in which we can learn the basics of the swift and the third one is to clone an existing
project.
So this is basically copying an existing X code project but we want this one.
K we want in the middle.
So create a new X called Project.
If you click on that you will see a screen like this in which you will choose a template for your X
scope projects.
So as you can see we have a lot of templates and during the curves we will work some of these templates
and we will see this tabs as well.
So this is for TV shows and this is for Mac us if you know Swift you can just create apps for TV or
Mac OS or AOS but we're going to focus mainly on AOS and we mainly going to choose the single view app.
This is the most basic empty template because we are going to learn how to create teams from scratch
okay.
We're not going to need any templates for us at least at this moment in the future.
In the following sections we are going to see some other ready templates for us but for the time being
I'm going to go for single view app and also keep in mind that if you choose single view app you can
later on add some more features on it as well.
So here you see a game.
So this basically lets you create a game with a physical vert and you're going to see what it is later
on.
So this is for example an augmented reality app and we're going to work with that one as well and we're
going to see the other templates but right now do most basic thing to do is just to create a single
weave app and add everything in here manually and not worry about all these other templates.
At this moment so choose this and come here and click next.
So once you click next you will either present that this page or a very similar version.
So it has a slight difference in some versions and I'm going to show you what it is.
Don't worry.
So here we see the general settings of our project like a product name.
OK.
For example out for our product name.
I'm going to go for my first app and of course later on we're going to see how we can change this name
from our exe called Project as well.
And in fact we can change every settings that we're making here later on but we need to make sure that
we're just doing the right thing from scratch.
So I'm going to show you how to work with this.
So in the team you're most probably seeing does none.
And in my case I'm seeing my name which is not important at this point.
So if you're seeing none then it's okay to proceed with none.
Once we go into the X code I'm going to show you how you can add your Apple I.D. to your X code so that
they will be connected.
In my case now I see my name.
I'm just going to go with those.
But again it's not important right now.
We're here we have an organization name.
So either you write your company's name or you can write your own name if you're working for yourself.
So once you write your organization name it creates an organization identifier for you as you can see.
This is a reverse domain.
So it's com dot until Sam rather than until Sam dot com.
So this can be change of course but using this organization name and using these organization identifier
actually X code creates a bundle identifier for us.
So this is important because this is the unique I.D. of our app.
So as you can see takes the product name and it takes the organization identifier and creates a bundle
identifier for our app.
So this is a differentiating idea for our app so that the dummy upload these to the App Store they can
understand which app is which app by actually looking at their bundle identifiers so we can change this
later on as well when we open the X code.
But this is somewhat important.
So if you're building a real app just try to come up with a good product name and write your own organization
name you like your name.
And over here we how the language section as well.
And as you can see we have two options either swift or objective c we are focusing on Swift in this
cause because Swift has been released by Apple five years ago and now it's actually very popular programming
language and it's one of the best ones in the verdict so it's very easy to understand.
Very easy to use and it's I believe in my opinion it's much more better Rummy compared to the objective
c so we're going to go for a swift softer Swift has been released most of the projects has been shifted
to swift anyway so that's what we're going to learn in this course.
And here we how does the user interface tap.
Okay so we're going to choose storyboard from this tab rather than Swift UI so swift UI is actually
a new concept introduced by Apple to into our worlds and it actually creates lets us create stunning
user interfaces later on in the cars.
We're going to have a swift UI section as well but right now we're going to focus on storyboards because
this swift UI is kind of new and it would be effective as of a U.S. 13 so that people would have to
install AI is 13 or a bo into their phones in order to make this work.
So we're going to have to wait a little bit more to shift every project to swift UI and we're going
to use storyboards as most of the time in these cars for that perspective.
And don't worry the codes are the same actually we use swift in storyboards.
User interface and we use swift in swift UI as well and this is only related to the user interface.
The design of the app if you may say OK and over here you will see some checkboxes like used car data.
So this will let us create a local database to use in our apps.
Right now we don't need those.
Right now we don't need any tests as well.
Later on we're going to see what we can make with core data and the other screen that you can see when
you open your first project is this.
So again here everything seems to be the same.
Like this language tab over here you can choose swift or objective see from here you can write your
product name in everything but as you can see swift UI is in the checkbox list as well.
So rather than choosing Storyboard You can just ignore swift UI or here just uncheck it if it's checked
then it will create a project for you using storyboards.
So this is the only difference that you can get with regarding two different x code versions.
So Apple hasn't decided which version to go with yet.
So you can either see this or the previous screen that I have shown you and it doesn't matter.
Just uncheck the swift UI.
Or just choose this story bought from the drop down menu and after you do all of these things now you're
ready to create your first project.
So don't forget to fill this information up.
And don't forget to click next here because we're going to choose where to save our project next.
So I have created a folder in my desktop named IOW complete because I'm going to save all of the projects
in here.
You can just choose wherever you want.
You can save your projects wherever you want on your computer and after you choose your folder you can
just click Create here and in this source control pain you will see some option to create get repositories
reading to see why they get later only in the cars.
This is basically a save point checkpoint for your apps.
OK so he can't go back in time.
If you mess up with something in your code and I'm going to go for that and I will say create a get
repository on my Mac we going to see what I give.
Hop and what they get is later on as I said so let's create our projects.
And once you do that it will actually create some files and folders and this will be the project pain
that we are king that we will be working on those files and folders.
If you open your folder over here you will see some apps you will see some project files project folders
in your project folder.
Ok.
And in fact if I close this down and if I close my X good project down I can go back to my folder and
I can find my project file and if I double click on this it will pop open again so I can start working
on my project.
If you how come this far we can't stop here.
Are we going to continue building our app on the next lecture.