Hi within this lecture reading to see how to connect these views to our coding section.
So right now I have my user interface over here but nothing happens when I click on the button or click
on the image or click on the label.
I want something to happen when I click on the button.
Right.
I cannot reach my button or my image or my label in the coding section.
I don't have anything in my view controller that swift right now and that is where I'm going to write
my code right.
But in here I only have something called the did loads and we going to see whether this later on.
But I don't have my image I don't have my button in here.
Are we going to see how to have doge in the way controller that's swift.
We're just going to connect those views to our real controller.
That's swift in order to do that.
I'm going to click on this to open another editor and if you click over here you can choose where they
were you want to display in the second editor like this so you can choose where you controller does
Swift from here and you can display real controller on the right hand side and you can display the main
story storyboard on the left hand site.
Again if you couldn't open those you can come over here you can choose whatever you want from me or
whatever file you want from here.
OK and here I already have my mean that storyboard and for example if you click on this image.
If you hold your control key and your keyboard you can drag and drop this image to your class and as
you can see it shows me where I can drop this.
OK so I can drop this.
I cannot drop this outside of my class and reading to see why the class is later on.
Don't worry about it.
But right now I'm just dropping it below my class but not in my overwrite function over here.
I'm just dropping this under my class display and it asks me for a name.
So whether were I write over here it will be the name of my image in my coat.
So right now I'm choosing a name for my view.
I'm going to go for Image view.
OK.
And we're going to do this V S capitalized.
So does a big V Image view.
So this is a general convention in programming.
I'm going to talk about that later on.
And you have to choose outlet over here if it's not already chosen and that's it.
If I say connect right now it will just take this image view and it will define this as an image view.
OK.
And right now I can hit enter to create more space over here because I'm going to justify more objects
in here later on.
And for example if you just have misspelled imagery and if you want to change the name of the image
you if you delete this and if you define this one more time using drag and drop it will break your code
and don't do that right now if you have written something else by mistake.
That's OK.
But I'm going to show you how to change this anyway because this is a common error that we have come
across with the needs starting students.
They misspelled things and they tried to change the name and they break their code.
Why do they break the code.
Because once you connect an image or runs you connect any view in your class in your app in your swift
file here.
It makes a connection and we can use this connection outlets in order to see these connections.
OK.
So if I delete this connection it will be okay for me to delete or change this but without doing that
I break my code.
So for any reason don't do this but I'm going to show you how to do that for any reason if you want
to change your name if you want to change this image of user name you have to break the connection first
and then delete this line and then just do the whole thing one more time like this I'm breaking this
and now I see an empty circle over here which means that I can delete this and then I Kenya redefined
this again by doing the same thing dragging and dropping and sync Image view.
OK so this is how you create an image view and I believe you're done with the Image view.
Next thing to do is to decide whether we define this label in our code or not.
And I don't need this label right because I'm going to click on this changed by them and the image will
change.
So I'm going to definitely need the button and the Image view itself but I'm not going to use label
in any way in my code.
If I wanted to change the color or the text of the label I will definitely define this.
But right now I'm going to go for the button.
So if you drag and drop the button over here OK below the function or at both the function it will create
an action for you as you can see it gives the option of action when you define a bottom because that's
what buttons are created for you click on them and some something will happen.
So choose the action and name this button clicked.
OK.
So if you say connect this will create a function for you.
Now I'm actually done with connecting my view so let me close this down and let me go back to my view
controller dot Swift.
So here I have my Image view.
And here I have my function.
So we don't know what is a function right now but that's OK.
It's basically doing something when something happens and we're going to see whether this in the next
lecture.