Hi.
Following this lecture we're going to start learning about the swift basics and in order to do that
I actually need something very simple.
I don't need 80 main dot storyboards.
I don't need any simulators because I won't be building any user interfaces.
I won't be just displaying those user interfaces in my simulator.
I just need a very basic way to write SWIFT code and see these outputs without giving too much thought
into user interface or without having to run simulator every time and wait for it to compile and build
on it.
Show me the user phase and stuff and then in order to do that I'm going to show you two options.
And don't worry after this section after we complete the basics of Swift we are going to go back to
that as well.
We're going to create user interfaces we're going to build apps we're going to test them in the simulators
all the cars will be based on this practice.
However in the section in the basic section we don't need that.
We just need a simple method simple technique to write our code and see these outputs.
First one is to create a playground and that is the common solution in order to learn about basic swift
operations.
So as you can see we can explore new ideas quickly and easily in the playground.
So when you click on those it will ask you for a template again.
And of course we going to go for blank because we going to create everything from scratch and you can
call your playground whatever you want.
OK.
I'm going to call it the variables.
This will be our first topic and we're going to see what a variable is.
And we're going to create this and save it in whenever wherever I want.
I'm going to go for a desktop or I'm going to go for AOS complete folder in fact and you can just choose
it over here as well.
I'm going to save every playground that we are creating in my AOS complete folder.
And later on I'm just going to share all of those things for you.
So let me create actually a new playgrounds folder and save this playgrounds in my playgrounds folder
so that I can zip them and share with them easily.
So here we go.
May you first create the playground.
It shows you something like this.
OK so you're importing something importing means you're importing your library into this project and
you're running something called SDR.
So this is a variable actually and VAR is the keyword to define a variable.
We will see what it is later on.
If you click on this play button over here it will run this playground.
If you're doing this for the first time and I believe this is my first time on X called 11 for playgrounds
it's it's going to take some time.
So the most basic thing about the playgrounds they have to be fast and they have to be efficient because
we're just writing some code and we're expecting to see the outcome of discos codes fast if you get
stuck in playgrounds.
If this doesn't work for some reason I will show you another option because sometimes students experience
some difficulties with the playground.
It should be like this you have to see the output on the right hand side of this playground.
So if you don't see it you can try to close this playground and open it again and hitting the play button
one more time because it should display these variables very fast actually.
So let me create another one so you can just write it like me and I'm going to explain what these are
but these are print later on but just for right now know that I'm creating a variable and I'm trying
to print it.
So if I click the play button I will see the result on on the right hand side.
And since I am printing this I will see the results on the lower side of this playground as well.
So this is the print section and right hand side is where we get the output of our code actually.
So this is the logic of playground.
So you write some codes and you see the results on the right hand side.
For example I multiply temp buys 10 times five.
And I can see the 50 instantaneously on the right hand side.
So if this is working out for you.
That's great.
So you don't have to go for the second option at all because playground is actually better and I'm going
to explain a routine in the playground says well but I have come across some situations students could
not start playgrounds or whatever day try.
OK.
So they try to close this they try to restart their computers they try to delete the playground and
create it again but it won't start.
So if you come across a situation like this I'm going to show you a second way.
And let me show you the second way.
Let me go over here to X. go down say new projects rather than playground.
I'm going to go for a project but rather than I guess now I'm going to create something for Mac OS I'm
nuts of course going to build an app for Mac OS in this at this moment but I'm going to create a very
simple project in which we can write code and show the output instantaneously again without having to
deal with the main storyboard or deal with the simulator at 0.
So if you choose the Mac OS you can come here choose commands line two.
OK.
That's what we're going to create here.
And we have to give you the product name one more time.
So I'm going to say command line variables over here but I'm not going to write any coding here.
I'm not going to explain all the section in command variables.
But I'm just going to show you whether this.
So here you can choose Swift.
And as you can see we can write C or C++ called in here as well but we're not going to do that but the
rather we're just going to go for a swift time create our projects and as you can see this creates a
project just like as we did before but rather than having a wheel controller that swift or apt delegate
or scene delegate we only have something called Main that Swift.
So this is a basic swift file in which we can write code and then we played this when we run this here
using my Mac.
It will just run the code and display the results for me for some reason I'm getting an error message
let me see.
Yeah.
As you can see I'm not connected to my Apple I.D. even though I suggested you to go and do this in your
signing capability section.
Apparently I didn't do that.
So let me go to signing capabilities.
And here you go.
It doesn't see my account here so it doesn't see Molly.
See my Apple I.D..
So this is very easy to fix if it's not shown.
If it's not chosen for you just choose it and say sign in and then later on you can just give your Apple
I.D. password over here so that it can't connect you to your ex growth project.
And I believe this is not an issue for you because you have done this in the previous section for right
now it's an issue for me so I'm signing in with my Apple I.D. and it's going to a sign my Apple I.D.
2 x code project and this will be okay then.
So right now I'm here signed in let me go to my main that's 5th and try to run this one more time and
the errors will go away.
And as you can see now I will get the log.
I will see the output of this print as you can see I see the output over here on the right hand side
bottom.
So if I do something like this now I have to print this rather than seeing on the right hand side because
right now we don't have that kind of capability in the here.
So I'm going to wrap this around to print and if I do that it will just print the results for me in
here like this.
So you can use this technique or you can use the playgrounds and I suggest if it is working for you
you use the playground because it's simpler.
You don't have to write print every time in order to see the results.
Okay.
So you can create new tables like this in here as well you can see something like as he can say for
my number is four times four and print my number.
And if you just run this you will see the same result.
So we are seeing 20 in here and we will see the same thing in here as well.
If we run this.
Okay.
As you can see we see 16 because yeah I said four times four.
But it's working.
So choose one of them choose either of them.
Okay.
And if it's working go with the playgrounds.
If it's not.
Go with this.
There but.
Okay.
So we will stop here and following the next lecture we're actually going to start learning about what
a variable is.
And we're going to start with the basics of swift.