Hi within this lecture we're going to continue working on playgrounds and we're going to learn about
variables.
So far we have been creating variables.
As an example like this so like var tr is a variable.
My number is a variable.
So let me take an n here.
If you do two slashes you can't take in notes like this.
Variables and constants.
We going to learn what a variable is right now.
But this is important as well if you add two slashes before a line means this is a cold month so you
cannot type whatever you want in a coding section.
Okay.
So this is all relevant codes but if I do something like this so if I write something random like this
if I click the play button over here it won't play because it won't recognize what I'm writing.
So if you take a..
Just add two slashes so we call this a comment string a comment line in our code.
Okay so what is ever able as you can see we can create variables with keyword var.
But why do we need them.
Because we can not do everything in the code.
Maybe we want to take some input from the user.
Or maybe we want to get some data from the Internet.
We want to download something.
So we cannot know what's going to happen.
We cannot anticipate everything.
So we need to store those values in order to work on them later on.
For example if you're going to build an app like this you're going to take the input of the user for
their name.
So the user will just enter their name into a text box and then later on they're going to enter there's
her name.
We're going to just display this name as her name together.
So in order to do that you cannot just come here and you can not just say name is this name is that
or just show.
This just showed that you had to create something in order to hold these value inside of it.
So this is ever able.
This is what we call a variable.
For example we are just multiplying this ten by five here and it shows us the value of 50.
But maybe we want to multiply the age of the user by five.
So when I'm writing this code I don't know the age of the user.
So I need to create something like var my age then multiply it by five and let me do this by example
so you will understand it much better.
Okay.
So when I create ever able I use var keyword.
For example if I say var user name and b word that I'm using the second word with capitalized letters.
So if I say user name the N will be capitalized.
Why are we doing this.
I'm gonna show you.
Don't worry.
For example right now I'm going to assign you my user name to be James.
So why I'm using a capitalized letter.
So this is a conversation.
OK.
This is what we generally do in swift programming language.
Every programming language has their own connotation.
So let me take notes here.
So we have something called Snake case.
If we follow this convention we will do this in a different way like that user under name.
And this is a snake case convention.
OK.
Does it stay Kay's name.
So if we do something like this var user sir name OK.
With underscores it will still work.
It actually doesn't matter what we name our variables.
OK.
But generally we don't do that in Swift.
So when you go to the internet when you search for things you won't see that you will see this.
So I'm going to follow the convention of Swift which is a camel case.
OK.
So this is called Snake case and this is called camel case.
And again this is not mandatory but we are doing this in order to make our variables more readable by
coders by developers.
So I'm going to follow these norm in here throughout the course.
So that's why I'm using capitalized letters so for example I created a user name called James and I
created a user surname in the name of Hatfield.
OK so any time I can change those renewables because they are variables OK I can come here and say user
name is not James say the more user name is something else.
So I can do whatever I want to do with James that is so because this every both right because I stored
these value into user name and I stored is Hatfield value in the user name Strake and the string means
basically yet text okay a text value.
So what if I want to changed his user name.
If you type user name and if you say this is not James right now.
This is Lars if you hit shift enter rather than hitting the play button it will automatically run this
codes for you.
OK.
You can do shift enter when you type something like you can say print user name and you can say print
user name here as well and not user surname user name as you can see if I type user I can hit TAB or
I can just double click on whatever I want to choose.
And now what.
Now if I do play or shift enter it will play it for me for example as you can see for the first time
this run user name print the user name and it just gave me James and for the second time it gave me
last because I changed the user name in here and this tells us something.
These codes are actually run with order.
Right there running with chronology.
So it is running the first command.
Then the second comment than the term comment and the fourth comment and the fifth comment.
And because of that first I have seen James as a log as a print output.
And then I changed this James then I so Lars.
So for example if I go to the top and if I want to change the user name I cannot do that because the
user your name won't be even defined in here.
OK.
So if you could play button over here it will give you an error.
It will say this is an unresolved identifier because why.
Because I have initialized I have defined this in the tenth row in the tenth light user name isn't even
defined in the eight line.
So once you defined this with the VAR keyword then you can change it.
You can play it.
You can do what they were you want to do with it.
And this is for variables.
OK.
We are we also how constants and we use let keyword for that.
So it means that we're going to define this value.
And we not going to change it afterwards.
So for example let's say that let the user age is 50.
Now I can reach the user age when I type user age.
OK but I cannot do this.
I cannot say user age is now tardy because I have defined this as a constant as you can say this is
I resolved because I have misspelled it as you can see I have to run a with capitalized day.
OK as you can see it says that you cannot assign these value because user age is a less constant.
So this is not ever able anymore.
This is a constant.
So we have to create the variables with the right keyword.
If you want to change them afterwards and we want to create variables or constants with let's keyword
if we don't want to change them afterwards.
OK.
So why do we need constants for example if we if we are going to use something like Pi number in our
app we won't change it forever.
Right so pi is constant like G 14 and it doesn't make any sense to define these variables with a var
keywords.
So we need the Latin here.
So we multiply 10 by five before can we multiply user age with pi.
In fact we cannot do that because they're not even the same type.
So here comes a new concept.
So there is something called type.
Okay.
And as you can see one is in s integer and then another one is double.
So we then learn what those mean in the next lecture.
Don't worry.
But for right now know that variables are not the same.
So we have texts strings like James or Hatfield or Lars and we have doubles or integers.
So if you put Dad o over here in the user age value then it will compile and it will just do the multiplication
for you and show the results.
As you can see now they are the same type.
So now maybe you understood that numbers of decimals and numbers without decimals are not the same type.
And that's correct.
So we're going to stop here and within the next lecture we're going to discuss what are some different
kinds of variables that we can operate with in swift.