Hi.
We didn't this lecture reading to learn something new and it's called a rates.
OK so in order to do that I'm just going to save this playground.
I'm going to close it down.
Of course you may want to continue from this one as well but I don't want to make it too long because
it's it will get hard to actually keep track of what we're doing.
So I'm just going to create another playground.
I'm going to create an stand alone playground for our air race.
OK I'm saving all of this into my AOS complete folder.
Later on I'm going to share all of these playgrounds with you.
We are geared up.
So let me go to my playgrounds folder.
And this was named two variables.
Now I'm going to name these as Array.
OK so what is an array and how we can use those arrays.
So let me create this and I will tell you all about it.
Don't worry.
So arrays are actually collections of values collections of data types.
OK so let me run these and see if we have something wrong here.
Nope.
Everything seems to be working.
So I'm going to start by deleting this line and rather than creating a simple string over here I'm just
going to create an array.
So what are collections of data types.
So let's suppose that I have to store my favorite movies in something like this.
So if you say var my favorite movies you can just open the breaks open the parentheses but not like
this.
Now that curly brace but rather just like this.
So you do it with option an eight or option seven depending on your keyboard and if you close this that's
how you create on Eric.
OK so here I can write more than one value actually.
So for example I can just say pulp fiction with quotation marks and this is a string and I can just
do a coma and I can continue as long as I want.
For example I can go for Kill Bill.
OK.
And again with a comma I can just go for another movie that I'm fan of like.
Or is are void dogs.
OK.
So here you go.
I have created a favorite movie array so I could have done that with different variables.
Right.
So I could I could have gone like my favorite movie one varmint my favorite movie too to my favorite
movie three and a sign those values two different variables.
But what if I have like a thousand values then it wouldn't be efficient to create 1000 variables at
one time.
Right.
It wouldn't be efficient.
It wouldn't be easy and this is actually easy because let's suppose that I'm downloading these values
from internet rather than just writing those values.
So if I can download a list OK of a favorite movie of someone or of mine I can just store these all
of these values actually into one variable rather than creating everything one by one.
And I cannot even do that.
I can't go for my bar my movie One is this var my movie too is this but I don't know the exact amount
of the movies that is going to be downloaded from the Internet.
In most of the cases.
Right.
So in an array I can store as many as I want.
So I can use this area.
I can work with collections of values efficiently.
So that's why we're using arrays in programming language as you can see arrays you can see lists.
You can see these kind of values data structures in almost all programming languages because they're
so efficient.
You just create one variable and you saw as many as data you want in them.
So I'm just going to delete this variable over here because I'm not going to do anything with this.
For example if you say my favorite movies as you can see this is now an array of strings because all
the values in my area are actually strings so we just want to keep it that way.
Most of the time but if I want to can I add another value here like five.
Yeah I actually I can do that.
If you open this warning over here or error it gives you a suggestion.
It says that insert as any because this is not a homogeneous collection.
This is a heterogeneous collection right now.
So what does as any mean.
Let me fix does let me add this and I'm going to explain what it is.
And we're just going to use this technique in some other instances as well.
So any means any type we don't know the type yet.
So this is either a string or a boolean or an integer and as means cast this value as a.
So this was originally a strings of every array of strings.
Right.
So this is now an array of any.
So as means cast think ok and any means any object actually.
So this is an array of any object.
We don't know the type.
We don't care what the type is at this moment and we can't save anything we want in this area as long
as it makes sense obviously.
For example I can go over here and add a boolean for God's sake and so in my favorite movies I have
a string I have an integer and even I have a boolean or any means literally and any objects.
OK.
And we're going to use this casting and we going to use this any later on.
So now if I do my favorite movies it will show my array as an any object.
OK so if I do my favorite movies zero it means that get the first element and show it to me and it starts
with zero.
Yes.
And this is called an index and the index of an array starts with the number 0.
It goes 0 1 2 3 4 5.
So I can just say my favorite movies won.
OK let me play this as you can see on the right hand side we get the values the respective values.
OK so this is called index sync.
My favorite movie Zero gave me Pulp Fiction Kill Bill one 0 roadblocks tree and if I go for the other
elements I can get them as well.
So let me try and get them as well actually.
So my favorite movies too.
OK.
This will give mirrors a royal dogs.
My favorite movies tree.
This will give me five.
And my favorite movies for this will give me true.
So let me run all of this.
So 0 1 2 4 0.
Over here.
OK.
3 4.
And can I do something like my free movies 5.
No I cannot do that.
I already have what I have in my area or here right.
It will give me in there.
Yeah as you can see when I hit dot over here I cannot reach the methods or attributes or options of
strings so I cannot do something with Pulp Fiction over here.
Why is that.
Because it thinks that this is not a strength.
This is an annual object.
I can't try to manually write this on my own.
But as you can see it says that really the type of any has no member uppercase because this is and this
is not a string for Swift.
This is an any object.
And this is basically why we try to keep the same type values inside of an array.
In order to reach their methods reach their attributes and change them and do something with them.
I can have heterogeneous values as here with casting as any but if I have the same values inside of
an area like as string Gary.
So let me say that were my string array rather than my favorite movies.
So I'm going to go for tests.
Okay.
And test two and one more test treat.
Okay so this is actually an array of strings right.
If you do my string Gary you will see that this is actually an array of strings.
Now I can go for my string Gary 0 and this will give me test.
Now I can reach those methods I can reach those attributes in functions and everything.
So if I say uppercase and if I run this now I will see that I have converted this task to be uppercase.
So you can use this very efficiently victories you can just call what element you want and you can do
whatever you want to do as long as they're the same object stairs they have the same values.
So both technique has their own advantages and disadvantages.
You may choose when to use which to use.
So let me show you something else you can do something like this right.
My string Gary does count and it will give you the current count how many elements are there in that
list in that area.
So you can do something like this.
My string array and open parentheses.
And rather than saying two over here if I say two I will get test three.
Right.
I can't just try to get this with my string your eight.
That count.
Right.
And in fact you may try to post the video and get it on your own rather than saying to.
I can just go for my string array OK my string Gary dot count minus one.
So my string your a will give me three and if I subtract one from that I can get the same result over
here.
So this is useful right because I can maybe add some more over in my string Gary I can just go for test
four and if I run this this will give me an error because I forgot to add the quotation mark at the
end.
But if I run this right now I will still get test for I will still get the last elements.
OK.
And as you can see I got test for.
So you can use this.
And of course there is another method for that as well I can just go over here and I can say my Stringer
a dot last.
So this will give me the last object lost elements so I can get test for or here maybe I want to get
my surgery that's count minus two.
That makes sense to use this technique.
I can get test three I can get not the last but the one before that.
Using this my string array that count minus two.
So what else can I do with string arrays or arrays in general.
I can't do a hard and this will sort the array.
OK.
And let's see I get.
Test.
Test you test three test four.
And since this is a string text it will sort those texts alphabetically.
So let me change those values and we'll see we'll test that.
So test six tests to test one test four.
So this is not in alphabetical order right now.
So if I run over this if I run this it fully recompile the codes and as you can see my values has been
changed.
But if I run the last line over here I still get the same result.
Test one two three four or test one two four six.
So this is a battle order right now.
And if it was an integer array it will just order it will just sort the array based on the values of
the integers and we have been working with strings to this point.
But of course we can do something like an integer array so let's call this my number array and I can
go for one two three four five six seven over here.
So this will be an array of integers.
It's the same principle you can just add whatever you want to add inside of an array now we can't stop
you.
That's it for is at this moment because we're going to use a phrase in most of the apps that we going
to build anyway.
We're going to get to practice them so much.
Now we will continue some other array like data structures like stats and dictionaries and we are going
to learn what they are.
In the next lecture.