Hi.
We didn't this lecture regrowing to see what our if controls so we're going to control some condition.
Okay we're going to see if a condition holds or not.
And we are going to define what to do if it holds or if it doesn't hold.
So let me create the new playground.
I'm going to name this if controls OK.
And let me put it in my playgrounds folder over here so that I can share it with you guys later.
So let me start by deleting this automatically generate a line and we're going to start by creating
our own variable to work upon.
So we're gonna go like this.
We're going to create an integer and we're going to control to see if it is under some certain level
or if it is below or abot some certain level.
Okay.
What do I mean.
Let me just do it.
So why my age 32 and I'm going to check to see if my age is actually less than 30 or more than 30.
So we use the keywords if and it's fairly easy.
You just write it like this.
If my age is less than 30 then do this.
OK.
So like print 30 minus me if I run this you will see that this doesn't print anything.
Because whatever you write inside of this code block will get room.
If only this condition holds.
Right now as you can see my age is not less than 30 my age is 32.
And so we're not doing anything.
We're not printing up.
We're not executing the code like in the while loop or in the for loop.
What happens if the condition doesn't hold.
We got out of the loop right.
So this is the same thing.
So if I print something in here for example you will see it on the logs.
OK.
It doesn't affect anything beside itself but if I write something inside of my code block it will only
get executed if the condition holds.
So this is great right.
It gives us the power to run codes whenever we want when a condition holds one some number exceeds something
when I don't know when the time runs out.
OK.
So we can check to see these conditions and they can't say else.
If you say Ellis and I'll put a new curly braces you can't say it.
What do you want to happen if this condition doesn't hold.
For example you can say 30 plus.
And as you can see we will see the turn a pause in the logs as you can see it's here because my age
is now turning to this didn't hold.
And since I have given an L statement it's printed out the statement it got executed the end state.
And in fact this isn't the only way to go with the F controls as well.
We can have as many as control points in an if statement.
I can check for if my age is 32 e my age is 33.
If my age is 34 OK and to do that rather than saying LS I'm going to say else if.
So if my age is less than 30 print this but if my age is not less than 30 hours if my age is actually
greater than 30.
But also we can use a combined statement in here like N and or or operation.
So what do I mean by that.
I can go and do something like this with double ends.
I can just add one more statements.
So let me tell you about this a little bit so we can continue.
So we have less than greater than and we have seen the equal or not equal.
OK.
We have even seen less than an equal to greater than equal to.
But we haven't seen and and ah so how do we use an or in an.
And operator we say dad both conditions must hold OK and in or operate tears we say dad one of the conditions
must hold.
And in order to do this or operators sign you have to press option or alter in your keyboard with the
dash.
So this is piping by the way a pipe sign double pipe double and so double pipe stands for R and double
lines stands for.
And so in an ends situation you just control to see if both of the conditions hold like as if my age
is greater than 30.
And as if my age is actually less than 35 or something.
So this doesn't make sense right now because my age is greater than 30 and it should be 40 then I can
breed something like it's like.
I mean the 30s.
Okay so else now I can't say that I was else means right now.
If this condition doesn't hold okay and if these conditions do not hold as though then come back to
do whatever I write in the else.
If these conditions hold it will do what it that we told the if statement to do an ls it will print
out 40 plus for example.
Let's try this a little bit.
Let's run this and we will see turkeys because our age is thirty two.
OK.
And let me change the value and test is more so.
Let me do this something like forty five if I run this I will see 40 plus.
Right here you go we see the 40 plus.
So over algorithm does work.
And if I do something like ls if the age is between 40 and 50 50 and 60 I can add as many as I want.
Like as if my age is between 40 and my age is less than 50.
OK so I can do some I'll say again and I can print out 50 plus if I want.
Now if I run this rather than saying yeah I will say again for the plus because we're in the forty five.
One more time.
So let me do this something like ninety eight will say 50 plus.
OK here you go.
So we can check to see if a condition holds with if controls on we can say whatever we want to do if
that condition holds.
So this is actually great things to learn in programming languages.
So let me talk a little bit about this and or operator in a little bit more detail.
So if I say something like this tree's less than 5 which will give me true.
Right.
But if I add some and operator and if I say five is less than seven if I run this it will give me true
again.
Because why.
Because both sides of the condition holds.
So tree is actually less than five and five is actually less than seven.
But if I change one of this and if any of this doesn't hold it won't give me true because and means
both side of this equation is true.
OK so if I do it like this eight is less than seven.
This won't give me true even though tree is less than five because this is Ms.
And the logic brings us this if I want to use it in a way that if one of the conditions hold give me
true anyway then I have to use or K not and I can just say tree is less than five.
Okay.
For example this is ends and this is or so in here let me do something like this tree is less than five
or Okay double pipes eight is actually less than seven.
So this will give me true because why.
Because we didn't say and this side of the condition holds the other side doesn't hold.
But it doesn't matter for us because we used or in this case.
So you can use and operations and or operators in your if controls if statements to check and see if
a condition holds if you want both sides of the equation true you must use and if you just want one
side then you should go with R so do v use if statements with numbers are integers only of course not.
We can use it with strings as well.
For example let me create a string called James I can check to see if my string is actually James or
not.
So let me open my curly braces and I will just print out something like two ok and or yes.
So as you can see we see the s if I change some letter or here rather than making this capitalized if
I make this lower case it won't say yes because it has to be exactly the same in order these two strings
to be equal.
OK so we can use if statements with strings with billions with numbers whatever we want we are going
to use if if statements most of the apps that we were going to build obviously and we will practice
them much more later on.
So right now we're going to stop here and within the next lecture we're going to continue with the functions.