Hi I hope you made it on your own in your first assignment.
If so congratulations if you got stuck at that point don't worry you're going to learn how to do that
you haven't practiced anything so far so don't worry you're just going to see how would stump some creating
a new project over here.
I'm going to name Dale simple calculator.
OK and of course I'm going to go swift and then hit next.
Then I'm going to create my simple calculator or you can call it the Versed calculator ever as pho and
place it on your own folder.
So let me start by designing my app.
OK so let me go to mean that sorry over here because we're going to need some text fields and we are
going to need some buttons and labels.
So far we haven't even created the project except our first app.
So you may have experienced some difficulties doing all these operations by yourself if you tried to
do these assignments.
So how do we drag and drop some views over here maybe you remember you hit your shift Allen comments
in your keyboard or you can just click over here to this plus bottom and we going to go for text fields
OK.
So if you just search for text you can take this and put it on your own view.
So as you can see it displays around the direct tangle that can contain editable text.
It means that users can edit this tax and we can get what's going to be inside of this tax feel either
way.
So let me just put it and make it a little bit bigger like this.
So let me zoom in so you can see better ends.
Here you go.
This is our first text field right.
So let me put it this into the center.
So let me go to attributes pain over here and you don't know the attributes the options of this tax
feel at this moment but let me show you how it's done.
So there is a place holder text here.
It means that this while they were I right here we'll be staying as a place holder or like this first
number.
And if somebody or if user type something over here.
This will be deleted.
OK so this is automatically handled by Swift.
So this is the place holder.
If there is a tax it won't show off if there is not a tax.
It will show off.
So it's a cool feature.
So let's try to play with this tax feel a little bit.
So we have seen why the place holder is right.
But we have other options as well and we don't need to change any of this I'm just trying to make you
comfortable with X called a little bit.
So here you see the color you may choose whatever color you want.
So this is going to be your text color.
You'll see the alignment you see the farms.
You can change the font.
OK.
So in here we have some text input traits over here so for example in content type you may choose if
you're expecting a name input from the user or if you're expecting a job title from the user or location
or a street address.
And we're not going to do that.
OK I'm just going to go for unspecified but if this text field is specifically put for something you're
more than welcome to choose this for example or organization name for example telephone number.
OK.
And we don't need this right now we're just expecting a number from the user.
So I'm going to leave this here on unspecified ands let us see if there is some important trade yet
we have this keyboard type.
For example I can't go for default and it will bring the default keyboard.
OK.
If I choose anything like numbers or here like a number pad user will only see the numbers actually
it makes sense for us to choose in this app because we are just expecting numbers from user but I'm
not going to do that.
I will show you why later on.
So for first No that's okay.
But I have to copy and paste is in order to create my second numbers so you can do that with comments
see and comment V in your keyboards.
So once you copy the text field I can change this place holder to be second number.
And by the way of course I could have dragged another text field from this library as well but I can
just copy and paste so whatever pleases you.
So the next thing I'm gonna need that button right.
Because as you might to remember user w clicking the plus button and it will just some user of us quit
clicking the minus button and it will just subtract.
So we're going to do that.
I'm just going to copy and paste these four times and I'm going to change the size accordingly.
So first form will be some and this form deduction and this one multiplication.
Yeah this one.
And let's see.
Copy and paste.
One more time and this will divide the first number into seconds so that's OK.
So you can choose four of them together and just drag it like this.
Okay.
And after all we're done with this I'm going to display the results in a label.
OK.
So let me take a label and you remember we just put some tax in labels.
So this is nothing fancy if you want to show a tax.
You can use labels.
So let me make this a little bit bigger and put it over here let me just try and make this into center.
Yeah that's OK and for label we can just actually make this something like a results OK or we can just
leave this empty as well.
But in order to be clear I'm not going to do that because we cannot even see the label over here.
It's the same color as background.
So I'm going to leave this as their results.
So I think that's OK.
OK.
And you can work with this line break think in order to wrap the result or in order to have two different
lines but it won't fit.
But we're not going to go over.
That's right now I'm just going to go for dessert reset to suggest the constraints.
Remember we have to do that in order to make sure our views will stay in their places.
When we played them in simulators in actual phones so that they will be displaying similar in different
kinds of sizes.
So in the next section actually we were going to deep dive onto this.
But for right now you can just click on that and say rear it's head to suggest that constraints and
in fact I believe we're done with our design right.
We got what we need in here so the next step will be the just defining these into coding section and
then working with those views in order to reach our goal of doing four basic operations in a reverse
calculator.