Hi within this lecture we are going to work out with layouts.
So far we have been creating some exemplary apps and we have been working with mains storyboards but
we haven't seen the details of them.
We haven't seen how to use constraints and what our constraints really and how we can leverage those
so I'm going to go and create a new project that I'm going to call this project layout and I'm going
to of course go with swift and save my files in my desktop or a U.S. folder and we're going to keep
coding minimum in the section but you have to know this stuff before we go on and build some real apps
because this is one of the basic stuff that you need to learn in order to build up.
OK.
And here we have our view and we have our library in which we can drag and drop because we have seen
that before right.
But we haven't seen this.
So in this picture in this layout over here we can't change the actual out there right now.
The iPhone X R is chosen as default.
In my case so I can choose to display iPhone as C as you can see changes a lot.
So this is a lot bigger.
And iPhone is ease a lot smaller so I can choose orientation even so I can do per portrayed landscape.
So this is where you change the layout.
This is where you change the model of the iPhone or your station of the iPhone and in current days we
don't see too many apps that are supporting these layouts orientation landscape orientation sorry.
We generally use our apps in portrayed modes.
So maybe you wondered how can I make my app to be used only in portrayed mode.
It's actually a lot easier than you think.
You can go to the settings and you can just choose whether you will support landscape or not.
So if you do it like this if you live the checkbox only in portrayed mode your app will be supporting
only portrayed mode.
So even if a user switches their phone as a Landscape mode it won't go to the landscape mode.
It will stay in the portrayed mode there in the left hand pane we if we drag a view over here you will
see that it will be placed in the left hand pane as well so you can choose your view by clicking or
here or we can choose your view by clicking over here as well.
So we haven't worked with this before.
So it displays a hierarchy in which you can see the views and you can choose them from that list as
well.
So let me make my label a little bit bigger or here and let me go to attributes pane in which I can
change the attributes we have seen this before right.
So for example I can call this project layout and I can make this central and I can even increase the
font size over here to make my text a little bit bigger so I can play with these options and I can change
them in whatever way I want.
So let me drag and drop an image view so that we will see a good example of leveraging layout options
in a good way in order to make good apps.
So let me put this image view in the middle of my screen and then I'm going to need an image of course
to work with to show you an example.
So I'm going to go for Google and of course I'm going to Google Metallica.
Again I'm going to download an image and I believe the landscape image like this will be much better
for our purposes rather than portrayed images.
So go for a landscape and just download one.
You can do it with your own favorite band if you're sick of Metallica at this point.
I'm going to rename this Metallica.
I'm going to just take this picture and I can put it over there just make sure that this copy items
if needed to select it.
I can't reach Metallica that j pick from here or in the assets folder as well.
So far we have been dragging and dropping the images into assets folder but you can't do we'd like this
as you can see we now see the image inside of our image view.
So right now I have this image and I have stretched it a little bit.
Right next to the edge.
But there is some space between here.
So this is the look that I wanted in my app for example.
So let me run this and be aware that I haven't put any constraints from here.
So I have just put an image view on the label and I designed this in an iPhone X our layout and I am
running this on an iPhone makes our simulator and in fact most probably we won't experience any difficulties.
It's not going to be different than this because we're designing in the same layout same model as we're
running in the simulator.
And later on we're going to run this in another simulator in iPhone AC or iPhone 6 or something small.
And we will see if they look like like they've launched by the way because we're designing this in a
big screen.
According to this big screen so it should be something wrong displaying this big screen big design into
a small screen and an iPhone X are as you can see it looks perfect.
This is what I need to look at.
So this is what I want.
But let me go and change my simulator from here.
So if you don't have any simulators at this moment like a small one like iPhone 7 or iPhone AC you can
click over here and in the simulator section you can add whatever you want.
We have seen this before right.
So for example I have downloaded an iPhone as e so let me play let me run this in an iPhone ACA environment.
So right now I designed this in a very big screen but I am running this in a very small screen.
Actually I believe this is the biggest screen size right now and iPhone AC is the smallest screen size.
So it makes a perfect combination to see if my project will work the same in different green sizes.
So it's kind of important because when you put your app on the app store they will download your app
and they will try to run their own phones.
And by day I mean the users themselves.
So it's pretty important that it will look the same on different environments.
And as you can see it doesn't look the same or it was it isn't even close right.
So in the iPhone X R we have pretty much what we want.
Yeah.
This one but in the left hand side we see the iPhone as E.
So we don't see the rest of the image.
And this project layout label is pretty much skewed to the right.
So start in the center.
And this is not what we want.
If we don't do necessary actions if we don't take necessary cautions in the layout it won't work the
same for different kinds of models.
So we're going to stop here within the next like we're going to start learning about how to do these
kind of operations in a very efficient way.