Hi.
We didn't dislike your reading to focus on details of constraints and we're going to see how we can
change the constraints that we have previously added.
If you click one of these constraints you will see them highlighting as you might remember we have to
decrease this 58 number because it pushes the label from each side so it doesn't fit in the current
layout.
So I'm going to go for 10 instead of 58.
CAN I DO THAT.
YEAH SURE.
JUST COME HERE AND CHANGE THE CONSTANT.
Right.
So right now the left constraints and the right constraints of this project layout label is 10.
So in here I can see the order add to which the output constrains attributes as well.
So let me click one of these as you can see it connects the metal cage Apex top to the project like
layouts bottom and this one connects the project layouts top to the iPhone's safe area top and I can't
change that from here actually.
So let me zoom in so you can't see better.
So this is Project layout and it starts at the top as you can see and this is safe area.
And by safe area it means that the upper bound of this iPhone X or iPhone X are okay.
So as you can see if I click on this this is the safe area and it connects the safe area up to the top
of these labels so I can't change this.
I can't change I can say that.
Don't connect this to the top.
Just connect this to the bottom of the project layout for example or center of the project layout.
If I choose this as you can see go for bottom and it connects the safe area to the bottom of the project
layout.
And again this doesn't make sense it makes sense to connect this to the top of the project layer.
I'm just doing this for an example.
But there might be some cases where you want this to be connected to the center or to the top so you
can change it over here.
You can't change the constants values over here as well as you can see.
So this is now OK.
And in here I believe the choice of the metallic image was not good.
So it doesn't look good in big Image view like this.
So maybe we can go for some other content modes in order to see the actual size of this image view like
this.
OK.
So it actually starts a little below from the project lay out.
So this constraint actually works.
So this is five or eight so maybe we can do it something like 10 or 20 I don't know but it looks good
to me and we have the right and left constraints as well so we can see all image inside of iPhone AC
and iPhone X are.
So I'm going to change it back to aspect fit or maybe you can just leave it like this.
Maybe this is the view you want.
I don't know.
And I believe this is actually better to use because we can see the image views actual size in this
mode.
And let me click on this and let me try to increase this constant as you might see when I increase the
Metallica image goes down a little bit.
If I decrease Metallica image goes up a little bit.
So in real time it makes these adjustments.
So again I can change this.
For example I can do top.
So it connects the top of this image view to the bottom of these labels or top of this label and of
course this doesn't make sense but in some cases may be you may want to use them at the point that I'm
trying to make here.
After you actually add this constants at these constraints because in a real complicated app you will
have to spend much time adjusting these constraints in order to have a better looking app.
So you need to be comfortable to work on these constraints.
OK.
So we have a priority number over here.
So it really means priority when it comes 1000 as a default value.
Let me show you let me try and show you what these priorities do.
So when I add one constraint and when I add another constraint if they actually conflict with each other
we choose some priorities.
So let me add one more constrained to the right hand side of this image and make this twelve.
So I have two constraints connected connecting the right side of this image to the right side of the
form.
So one is ten and the other one is 20.
And as you can see we are seeing some rad constraints over here.
It isn't a good sign it means there is an error.
OK.
So we have to of course this doesn't make sense.
It doesn't make sense to use two like this but if I change the priority to 9 9 9 it means that I try
to leverage try to execute this too.
And if it fails if one fails.
Tried to go with the prioritized one.
OK.
So it's going to go with the ten instead of twelve.
In this case.
So maybe if you want to add two constraints and if they overlap or if they conflict you will have to
create a priority.
So you will D prioritize one so that the other one will be prioritized whenever there's a conflict.
And it will be in place.
So this is how it looks like.
OK.
You learned about this but there is still to learn about something as you can see there is a width and
height constraint in here.
And we haven't seen.
For example let me add that height and as you can see it adds a linear vertical line in here means that
whenever or wherever I run this image wherever I run this app regardless of the screen size it will
have this height.
OK.
So if you want some really strict images a really strict weave like this has to be 50 by 50 or this
has to be 100 to 100.
You can go for the width and height constraints.
OK.
And this will come in handy when you experience some problems with the constraints.
Sometimes we happen to come across in a situation like this.
We have to add this we then height in some situations if we add constraints.
And if you cannot see the view after you run the simulator it means that the constraints are suppressants
somehow.
So we cannot see the view as you can see when I add the reader in height it regardless of the screen
size it displays all the image in the height that I have specified.
So whenever you come across in a situation in which you can not see the view itself because of the constraints
try to use the width and height.
So it would make these values say tick it will make these values in a strict way so that they will be
executed.
And as you can see width and height constraints are shown in the different hierarchy because they belong
to Metallica J Pag image views hierarchy rather than the constraints hierarchy.
They're like an attribute right now.
So if you want to change them you can reach them under your image view.
OK.
So you can delete actually when you choose a constraint if you do a backspace or delete on your keyboard
it will just delete the coal strings.
OK we're going to stop here and within the next lecture we're going to see some easy ways to work with
constraints.