Hi within this lecture we're going to see how to create a bottom using this kind of code once more so
we're not going to be using main that storyboard again but doing that requires some other techniques
as well.
So we're going to learn how to work with selector functions.
OK so let me start by creating my you I bottom.
So this is not different from UI label.
So this is the bottom object that we need to use in order to create our bottom.
So I can just reach the attributes of my button like I can just say my button that set aside.
So and that's how you write something inside of a bottom.
So in here you can say for example my bottom and in this case it asks you for a controlled state if
you hit enter and hit dot you will see some options.
I'm gonna go for normal but there are some states like highlight.
OK so this brings up as a button in a highlighted mode.
So you really don't go for highlighters or other options generally but you can try to see what are the
other options and how does it look when you at the next thing.
I'm gonna go for a set titled color.
So in here I have to define a color and in order to define a color you just call you a color as you
can see this is an object that stores colored data.
OK.
If you do that you can hit dot and reach black blue brown.
So I'm going to go for blue.
And in here again it asks for a state.
And I'm going to go for normal.
So normally we have blue colors in buttons as you might already know.
So after that I have to give a frame as usual.
OK.
So I will call frame and see direct once more.
And it will ask me for x y width and height so we can do the same thing that we have been doing in the
previous lecture right.
So we can do this relative to the width and height.
So I can just say with our multiplied by 0 point four ends.
So let's go for y we begin to see how does it look.
And then we can change those values.
So for y I'm going to go for height multiplied by 0 7.
Now for the vids it embodies actually we can have some say tick numbers like a hundred or two hundred.
So I'm not going to create this relative to the screen size because Reagon I have my bottom tied to
anyway.
So if it fits then it will be okay for us later on you can add this to yours view by calling this.
And if I run this we will see the button appearing on our view.
Let's see where does it appear.
As you can see all point seven VI height multiplied by 0 point 7 brings us to this place.
So it's a little bit of maybe we can make this a little bit lower or something like 0 point 6 and let's
make this 0 point five minus one hundredth.
So I'm deducting D width divided by two one more because I want to make this in a central way.
So if I do this that I will see my button is placed right under my text right under my label.
OK then that comes the question How can I add an action to my bottom in order to do that.
I want to add that target.
So this is very you might get confused in order to do this.
We have to understand what the target is.
So for Target I'm gonna go for S and S refers to weave controller itself.
Okay.
As you can see when I write self it sees that this is we've controller.
And why would I do that.
Because I'm going to call and function as an action next.
Okay.
And I will explain this with the documentation in a moment.
So you will down their son much better.
Let me first write this down and then we were very going to go over it one more time.
So if it asks Senate selector as an action it means that we have to create a function in which we going
to call from view controller gave from self and then where are you going to assign this as a selector.
So let me create a function that you will see what I mean.
Let me called is my action.
Okay.
So I'm creating a basic function over here and in this function I'm just gonna go for tapped.
Okay I'm just going to print something I will see it's in the logs.
So right now I can come over here and I can just call my action.
But as you can see I cannot do that because it asks for a selector in order to make this work.
I I can't do this selector and it asks for an object to see method as you can see over here.
Now I can come here and just write my action but in order to make this work I have to go and say we
have controller.
That's my action.
Now I have to come to my action and put at object to see in the from in the beginning of this function.
OK so this is now an object to see function and it can be called as a selector.
So whenever somebody taps on my button dysfunction we'll get called and I will see the printing values
on the logs.
So and in here it asks for an event if if you hit enter and then he does it you will see some events.
It asks for them to call this.
So you will see something like touch up inside.
Touch up inside means whenever somebody touches up that's by them.
So right now I'm going to go over this one more time so we can see it better.
If you press command on your keyboard and click this you can go to the documentation like this.
It saves in the target parameter that this target object it is the object whose action method is going
to be cold.
So we're going to call the function of a view controller right.
And then you write self you refer one up class.
So we're inside of our v controller.
So if I say self it will refer to the V controller as you can see so I can add this as a target.
Then the action that I'm going to specify should be in that target.
So that's why I'm creating this my action inside of my class and this will be called if I touch up inside
to that button.
So let's testers as you can see if I touch my button it prints out tapped.
So this works right.
I can do whatever in I want in this function right now.
So what can I do.
Maybe all you want to change these labels text but I cannot reach my label from here because why.
Because it's not in the scope of this function.
And what should I do to reach that label form here.
Of course I have to define my label not in the reloaded load but I have to define my label outside of
the functions inside of my class.
So I'm going to take let my label UI label line up in the class and then I can reach it down my function.
So cut this line or just write it over here like wah my label UI label.
OK and then you can delete this line.
And then there's my label.
VILA referred to the pre newly created variable over here as you can see taillights.
When I click on it now I can call these my labels from with the ad load.
And from here as well.
Now I can say my label text is something new like tapped.
OK so this is how you connect to used together you have to define those v variables inside of your class.
But outside of your functions.
So let me test this.
So if I click on this you will see it's tapped.
Now you have learned how to create views just by using code without using mean that storyboard.
And it gives you great power it gives you power to create views relative to the screen sites.
And again there is actually a better way to achieve this result.
Now it's called SWIFT UI.
We're going to see what is swift UI in the next lecture but we're not going to deep dive into this because
you have to understand swift in an advanced way before we move on to that.
We're just in the beginning right now.
We're just learning about swift.
We're going to have intermediate swift takes a section.
Are we going to have advanced swift section and then we will move on to swift UI.
Right now I'm going to go and create all our applications with storyboards because why.
Because swift UI will be effective as AOS 13 and we're shooting for a starting design IOW 13 cars.
I know that but the migration to IO is 13 will not be completed in a month.
So people will have to download IO is 13 people will have to migrated like 80 90 percent of the people
will migrate it and then we will be ready to write applications purely in swift UI.
So that's why we're focusing on storyboards in these cars and we're going to learn about swift design
anyway in order to be ready for the future.
So let's do that in the next lecture.