Hi.
We didn't this lecture we're going to learn how to store data in the phone's memory.
So far we have been collecting input from the user.
For example users gave us some numbers in the calculator and we know how to get them right.
We then text feels or some other views but we don't know how to stored them.
What happens when a user closes the phone and what happens when they open it back.
If we don't start the data in that small database then we would lose it.
So we're going to learn about a good technique so that we can actually save small information into small
database so that we can reach that value whenever we need it.
I'm going to create an X SCOPE project for that.
I'm going to go for a single view app and we're going to build a bird.
They not take her.
Okay so I'm going to call this birthday note taker.
And again we're not going to use swift UI.
We're going to go like this.
So hits next and places on your desktop or any folder you want.
So in fact this app will let us only store one person's birthday as a note.
So this is not very useful because we're going to see how to Virg how to store in small amounts of data
right now.
Later on within the course we're going to see how to use large databases to save large datasets into
memory and then we can reach them whenever we want.
But right now we're going to learn a very practical technique so that we can start Data's and we can
just reach them whenever we want.
For example we can store high score data tells us we can score other No user name information in order
to reach them.
When a user closes their app and opens them one more time so I'm done to keep it simple I'm going to
gonna ask for a name and a birthday so I'm going to have a save button over here and I'm going to leave.
I'm going to put two labels on the below so that I will show the storage information in those labels.
OK so it's gonna be simple maybe you can try to do that on your own as well.
OK.
So two tacks feels button and the labels just do it and connect everything to the V controller dot Swift's
I hope you managed to do that.
So it's fairly easy right.
We're going to use tax fuels.
So let me open the library and search for tax fields.
We have worked with this before so I'm going to drag it and drop it over here and I'm going to make
this a little bit bigger so maybe our friend has a long name or some think OK so let me go to attributes
inspector and give you the place holder.
So first we can ask for a name for example.
And I'm going to copy this with command C. And I'm going to pass this below with command V.
And you can do it from the library as vote but copying and pasting actually makes it very easy.
So in the place holder this time I'm going to go for birthday.
OK.
So birthday we ask for a name and we ask for the birthday.
Right now I'm just gonna add some bottom to save this information to our database.
So let me go and do this.
OK.
By them.
So let me name this button save and let me make this a little bit bigger.
So here you go.
Save.
And again we will have two labels in which we will display this stored data.
So search for label and put it over here.
OK.
And make does a little bit bigger and put it in the place center replace.
And yeah I believe that's good.
Maybe we can make this a little bit bigger.
Yeah.
So let me make this in line centrally and the far label I can go like this.
I can just say name column with a space.
I'm going to write naming here.
So let me copy and paste this and we're going to display the birthday in this label again by the way
of course we could have just displayed this chart labels sort tax in here as well.
But I just want to display this in an obvious way so we don't lose track when we try to learn about
these saving into small database.
So this is OK.
Right.
We have what we need in here.
We can just go ahead and try and connect every one of these buttons into buttons and other views into
we control the dots.
So here we have controller that swift in here and we already have mean that sorry Bert over here.
So I'm gonna hit control on my keyboard and drag and drop to this class and I'm going to call these
name tax fields.
OK.
I'm going to go and open some new lines over here and again do the same thing for a birthday.
So birthday tax fields.
OK.
And we have to define our labels as well so let's go for a name label.
This is name label.
And lastly the BR they label will show birth the label.
I hope you managed to do that on your own by the way.
So let me just take this action by them and just save button clicked or save clicked.
So this is OK we have connected everything.
And before we forget let's add some constraints to here saying to reset to suggest constraints.
So they will be in the right place.
And let's run this actually and see if everything seems to be in order.
If not we can come back here and do some changes.
It's always wise to do that before we go to we've controller that's first.
And again here in the save button that we want to do is actually we want to save this information into
a very small database like structure but we don't know how to do that yet.
Before we do that I'm just going to go and display this value using the name label on birthday label
anyway because we're going to do that later on.
Right.
We're going to need it eventually.
So it works fine by the way so we don't have to change anything with the view.
So let me tidy up here a little bit.
OK.
So I think we're good to go.
So how do I take name label and show the name text fields value over here.
So yeah.
Correct.
Name labeled up taxed.
Name text field dot text.
So I'm taking the name text field out text and make it equal to name label dot text.
So we're going to do that for birthday labels right.
You know how to do that.
We have worked with this kind of thing before.
So a birthday text field that text.
So all this app will do right now.
I will write something in the name and birthday text fields.
It will display them over here.
But again it started with name in our examples right.
So how do I do that.
I don't want to just show the name tags feel.
I want to show it like this name column and the name text fields and if I come over here and if I tried
to say something like this birthday text field text it doesn't work because it thinks that this is a
string it is a text and this is in fact a text in order to treat this as a variable.
I have to use a spatial signed text in this quotation marks and in order to achieve this we are going
to use a reverse slash in here.
OK.
And then open the parentheses and then close the parentheses.
So between here I'm still writing a code.
I'm not writing any text.
Actually I'm just writing my variable.
So this will be displayed like name and the name text field that texts and again in here.
So this will be birthday birthday text field text.
So you can use this reverse slash and then open and close parentheses think in order to use variables
inside of strings.
So yeah we have to make this first our up and we're pretty certain that this text is going to give us
something because even if user doesn't give anything it will return an empty string.
Not the values so this will be ok to force unwrap.
Remember the optional as I remember the calculator team that we have built.
And if you haven't bought those sections I suggest you go back and do that.
So I believe we are ready to test and see if this works fine.
OK let me open this in simulator run more time and let's see if we can get the values and display them
in name label and birthday labels.
So let's say Dave here and for his birthday I'm going to go for Jan 20.
And if I say save then I see both Jan 20 in the name and the birthday because I accidentally put birthday
tax field that taxed in here maybe you have realized my mistake when I was writing this code.
So maybe you already have corrected this so this should be named text field dot text.
So let me call this one more time and in fact you will see that this Dave and Jan 20 Van TV right.
We cannot see them right now.
And I hit the save button I see this over here.
But once user closes these down and opens it again this information will go away.
So how can we make certain that this information will stay here.
Yeah that's right.
We have to write this into a very small database like structure and that's what we have been trying
to learn about and we're going to do that within the next lecture.