Hi within this lecture regrowing to learn about view controller lifecycle.
So what does it even mean.
So real controllers has actually a lifecycle they get created.
They get disappeared they will reappear one more time and there are certain functions like we did load
over here which actually defines what will happen when that event is going to be executed.
For example what do we do when we load.
We want to write.
What will happen when user first opens they wrap.
Right but in fact there are a lot more functions like this and we need to learn about them so we can
leverage them in a better way.
So let me open my simulator because I'm going to run and show you in the simulator in real time.
OK re going to call these other functions and we going to see then and there they're going to be executed.
So when I got second view controller for instance what happens in the background.
So when I go back what happens in the background.
We try and see that.
So we have two different views over here but I'm going to show these functions inside of our view controller
that swerved so that we can keep track what's being called.
So let me show you the other functions that we have been talking about so that you will understand it
better.
In an example.
So if you come over here under your reloaded loads we are not inside of we would not be inside of class.
So if you write veal did you can see veal did disappear like we did lot.
Okay.
So we're going to called as we did disappear.
So as you can see does not find the view controller.
That view is actually disappeared.
So we have a lot of functions like this and in order to keep track what's being called.
I'm just going to print the names.
So we did disappear.
Function called.
OK.
So we can actually do what we want in this.
We did disappear like we can set our labels we can just delete our data.
We can do whatever we want but for right now I'm just going to call all of this.
For example we will disappear and I'm going to print out so we can see them.
And why do they get called.
So we will disappear.
Function calls and we have some more.
Let me write veal.
Yeah.
We have we will appear.
Okay so.
And the names are actually self explanatory.
So this will be called when the view is about to appear.
Okay.
And we will appear.
Function cold.
Okay.
And we did load we did disappear we will disappear and we should have one more.
And by the way you may think that why did you wait so much in order to tell us about this.
I waited enough so that we will have two views to test this.
Okay so you will understand much better.
So Leslie I'm going to call.
We did appear so this is Will is about to appear and the below one.
Yeah we do.
Has appeared already.
OK.
Are we going to see that in action as well.
Don't worry.
So we did appear function calls.
So here we go.
We have a lot of functions defining our view controller lifecycle over here.
So let me call this and let me open the logs and once I open the logs I didn't even do anything yet.
But I.
As you can see we did load.
We will appear and we did appear cold and you have to pay attention to the order.
First we have the load has been called second.
We will appear and then view did appear so real.
Did the load actually gets cold before we see the view.
Okay.
Before the user sees the view we did load gets cold.
So for example let me go to second view and as you can see we will disappear and we did disappear gets
cold.
So right now my first view controller did disappear really.
And now we fight go back.
What do you think will happen.
Will we have did load.
Big cold again.
As you can see we did load is not cold again.
So we will appear and we did appear actually got called a.
So we did load only gets cold Vons.
The app is launched.
Okay.
Of your dad if you go to these views without killing this we controller it never gets cold.
So if I want something to be happening every time user goes back and forth I cannot use with the load.
Okay so if I want something to be happening when I go back I have to use we will appear or view did
appear.
I cannot use a view that they appear it won't make sense.
I can't use VR will appear for example let me write a teal and go to next.
Okay so I'm going into the second screen so we'll did we.
Will disappear and we'll do the cold and I go back and I still see the tail and this is default behavior
we expect to see that.
But what if while I want to get rid of this name.
What if what I want this name to be empty when I go back can I do that under we did load.
So let me try this.
Name tags that tax is empty string.
So let me run this one more time.
And of course we won't do that right.
Because we did load is cold right now but it won't get cold.
OK.
When I go here and go back.
So since we did load isn't cold name Tax that tax is not an empty string anymore so it doesn't work.
So we have to know the details of these functions in order to leverage them.
We did load only gets cold once once the application is launched.
Now if I do if I want to do something like that I have to do this under V will appear so that it will
be in place before the user sees it.
So I'm not doing that under the videotape here.
OK I'm doing it under V will appear so it will be in effect before a user sees it.
And it will get called everytime this view appears.
So let me go to a tail and a next and go back and this time as you can see my name tags that text is
actually empty.
So this is how you leverage these functions we're going to see some other examples of that when we build
apps in the following sections.
So I'm going to stop here and we're going to learn about alert messages within the next lecture.