Hi in this lecture we are going to complete our sign up registration form and congratulations on your
first sign up registration form.
If you managed to do it yourself.
If not that's OK.
We're going to do it right now together.
So of course I'm going to use if statements here.
OK I'm going to check if user name text is blank so I'm going to do it like this.
If user name tags dog tags is actually blank OK so that's all you need to do to check if a string is
empty string.
So if this is the case I'm going to show this message as user name not found.
And in fact I'm going to comment this out OK.
If you do slash and stir and if you do two slashes it will just comment out one line if you do slash
and stir it will create another star and slash for you if you do it like this it will comment out everything
inside of that block.
So these are all commented out.
These will not be counted as a code.
It will be counted as a note.
So I'm going to rewrite everything so that we can practice it so the LRAD is going to be a UI alert
controller.
I'm going to use the title air and the message will be user name not found and the style that I want
is the alert.
So I'm going to create okay by them and this will be an action indeed.
And the title will be okay.
Style will be default.
Okay.
And the handler I'm not going to need any handler so I'm going to say nil.
So ELA does add action.
OK.
Button and sussed out present alerts.
So this will present an alert.
OK.
And animated true completion nil.
This will present an alert if only if user name tags that tax isn't given to us.
So that's cool right.
That's all we have to do.
Of course if we are going to continue checking for passwords as well.
Right now we finished it so we can actually test as in our simulator and see if this actually works.
By the way I'm using this close as you can see so you can close it and open it anytime you want to have
more space in your coding section.
OK so here you go without the user name if I click on sign up this will be given.
If I write any user name over here.
OK.
And if I click sign up this won't display me any error messages.
So that's cool right.
It's working but I also want to control the passwords so username obviously works.
So if this is the case and we're going to display this message as if password text is missing OK so
password text that text is actually an empty string then I'm going to display all these messages one
more time so I'm going to copy and paste it and rather than saying user name not found I'm just going
to say password not found.
So this will be OK.
Right.
And if that is the case I'm going to display an alert message.
Else else if we have to check if password text and password to text match or not.
So I'm going to say as if password text dot text okay is equal or is not equal actually is not equal
to password to text texts dots texts.
Ok.
If these two do not match then I'm going to display another Ellard message and this will be password
one then password two are different or something passwords do not match.
So that's cool and else if everything works out fine.
What should we do if these conditions are not valid then I'm going to display an alert message saying
success.
OK.
And in this message I'm going to say user created or user.
So this will be our registration form.
So that's cool.
Let me run this and try it.
So user name user name not found.
OK.
So let me write another one.
So I'm going to write this as still okay.
And I'm going to leave the password blank for this sign.
So passwords not found.
Good.
So let me give me a password over here.
So it says that passwords do not match because I have not written anything in the password to texts.
So let me do everything right.
And as you can see it says that user OK.
Success.
So this is good.
This is working.
So let me try one more time let me try without user name but with passwords and this work as well.
Whenever I do something like this I'd like to try all the possibilities to see if I'm missing something.
And as it seems it works pretty good to me.
OK.
Actually that means that we have created our sign up registration app but I'd like to make an improvement
in here because maybe you have realized that we have copy them pasted these codes too many times so
we are using almost the same codes in every function in a if control then actually we can make this
into a more efficient structure right.
We can create a function creating user messages Alec messages and we can only change the messages or
titles and I believe we only change messages and for the last Elliott Bill we only change title and
message.
So maybe we can create a function in which we can ask for the title and the message from the developer.
And this function can generate this Elliott message and show it to the user.
It will be much more efficient than writing this or copying and pasting this all the way.
So let me create this function and you will see better because in real apps also you will see something
like this a lot because we will use other messages a lot.
So I'm going to say this is going to be a make Ellard function of course named do not matter.
Okay.
You can choose whatever you want.
So I'm going to copy paste an alert from here okay.
You can take this and you can call does make Ellard and it will display exactly the same message to
the user.
But we want to change this message and we want to change this title.
Right.
So let's get them from the developers.
So I'm going to ask this as a input.
So how do I do it.
I'm going to say title input and this will be a string.
And also I'm going to say message input and this will be a string guess both.
So rather than saying success I'm going to say title input in here rather than missing message I'm going
to say message input.
So this will create this UI Elliott for me with the title and the message that is given in here.
So when you write make a left right now it will ask for a title input and it will ask for a message
input.
So that will be much better than what we used to have in here.
So we're just going to use this messages.
So let me copy this and let me delete everything in here and say Make Elliott rather than saying user
Okay I will say pass Reg do not match and let me delete everything in here.
So rather than saying user Okay I'm going to go for passwords.
Password is missing or password not found.
Yeah.
And this will be error rather than success.
Right.
So this is password not found.
And finally we're going to delete everything in here and use the same function.
And going to say error and user not found.
So this is code.
And as you can see this is much clear this is much more structured and much more efficient than copying
and pasting everything.
So you can use functions efficiently like this.
So when I say sign up it will say user name not found.
Let me try the other possibilities as well to see if we broke something.
And everything seems to be working right now.
So if I say one two three four or run to three one over here and say sign up it say success user.
OK.
So that's it.
That concludes our Ellard message lectures.
We're going to stop here and we're going to continue learning ISIS advance operations in the next lecture.