High within the section you're going to get your second big assignment.
So first one was calculator and the second one is going to be this game.
So let me show you how it looks like.
So we have Kenny running away from us.
And if we can't catch him and if we can tap on him as you can see score increases.
So we're running against time and if time reaches zero it displays an alert message for us.
It says that time's up.
Do you want to play again and in here we can say replay or okay.
And on the bottom we have the high score.
So we start use value in a way that's if user closes this down and opens one more time.
This won't go away so we star there's value in our database.
So we started his value in a way that we only so started the highest score that has ever been achieved.
And we can tap on the replay to play one more time and if we can catch the Kenny in a higher score this
time this will be reflected in the higher score a parent.
They are not very good at this game so I could only do one and high score is still five.
As you can see since this is less than one so far we have been learning a lot.
So this will be a great chance to put all of this information into practice.
And you how some skill missing in order to complete this app and let me give you a hint.
You have to come up with a way to find to create the random variables or random numbers in order to
make this work.
And you may have to come up with a way to make animations or make some views reasonable or not reasonable.
And we have not seen that yet but you can easily try to figure out how to do this.
And you can easily find this information on Google and if you can not do that Don't worry.
This is a very hard practice by the way.
This is the hardest assignment that you will ever get during this course.
But after that you will see how you can actually turn your theory into practice and you can actually
see how you can use all of this information in real apps.
And again if you cannot do this.
Don't worry we're going to be building this app from scratch during this section.
So I suggest you pulls do video and tried to come up with a way to make this happen.