Hi within this lecture re going to start building our catch the Kenny game.
I hope you managed to build it yourself or I hope you tried at least.
So I'm going to show you my way of doing this so I'm going to go for a single recap.
I'm going to name this catch the Kenny K so this is going to be our game and I'm going to create this.
So before he starts I should tell you that this is not the only way of doing this game so I'm going
to show you the easiest way.
This is not the most efficient way or this is not the optimum way of doing this but this is the easiest
way.
So maybe you came up with a completely different idea that works and that is perfectly OK.
All right.
So I'm going to go for my main story board because we're going to start that the design of this app.
So basically we're going to need a kidney image and I'm not going to use one image in this app.
I'm going to use nine of them.
And in order to estimate the kidney I'm just going to hide them all.
Make them even visible.
And then I'm just going to select one and make that visible and this invisible and visible images will
change in time.
And we are going to do that randomly.
OK.
So you haven't learned how to work with the random numbers but it's fairly easy it's just one line of
code.
And I'm going to show you how to do that later on.
Don't worry.
So we're going to go for Kenny and we're going to find an image on line.
OK.
So any image will do.
But I'm trying to find something that is not too big so that's it.
We're going to use nine of them in our app so that it won't take so much space.
So that will do.
I'm going to name this Kenny and I'm going to go to a sets and that I'm going to drag this into my assets
and put that over there so I can reach this if I have an image view in my main storyboard.
So let me create an image for you.
Let me go to library or here and just search for Image view and drag and drop one or here.
So we had to make this a little bit smaller.
OK.
Because we're going to use nine of them as I said to let me go to attributes and try to choose Katy.
So that's good right.
We can make sure that this will fit three in a row.
So let me copy and paste and see if that fits.
So let me copy one more and that's OK.
Right so we can have our row like this.
And then later on I can select three of them and copy and paste one more time.
So this looks good right.
This is in line.
And let me do that one more time.
So we have nine caddies.
So this is perfect.
So what do we need else.
Let me make this a little bit central over here.
So we need our score label.
You need our time label and in here I'm going to select one of them to show to the user.
And I'm going to hide the other kiddies so that in real time it will look like the Caylee is animating.
So let me bring this label ebb and let me make this a little bit bigger so that I can display the time
and I can display the score.
So first will be our type.
So it can start with Turkey for example.
I'm not going to go for a turkey I'm just going to go for 10 in our app because I don't want to wait
30 seconds just to try just to test this app.
So let me copy and paste and make this one a little bit smaller this time rather than time I'm going
to display our score.
So this is OK.
I believe.
Time as score will be sufficient at this point.
So maybe we can just show the number of the time so rather than save time.
I believe this way.
This will be more catchy.
So this will get the focus off the user when he or she plays the game.
So here I'm going to copy and paste because we need another label.
And in this label I'm going to display the high score.
So we're going to have a high score as well.
And this will star the highest score that has ever been made by the users.
They are playing this game.
So let me select this view.
Okay and then give the constraints so a reset to suggested constraints.
And in this kind of game where you have a lot of views like this maybe you may want to go with width
and height constraints as well so that it will look the same in different kinds different sizes.
Okay.
In order to do that you can come over here and just select the width and height as well.
But right now I'm not going to deal with the layout so much because I want to focus on coding side of
this game.
So let me play this on my iPhone X are if it looks good on my iPhone X are.
That would be sufficient for me at least at this moment.
Okay so run this on your simulator and see how it looks like on your phone.
So it seems like it's going to take a.
So meanwhile let me open the assistant editor on the right hand side so we can define these views into
our coding sections.
So let me choose we have controller for the right hand side.
And let me go to main storyboard.
So we're going to have to define all of these images and labels so simulator didn't even start yet.
So let me start by dragging in this time label.
So this is where we display the time so I'm going to call this time label.
OK.
And again we cannot see the game yet.
I believe it's taking it's time to open the simulator.
Oh yeah.
Now we see it and as you can see it looks fine to me.
We can see the total game we can see the kidneys and everything.
So I'm going to focus on coding side as I said before.
So let me defined my score label over here and for the last label I'm going to go for high score.
So this is going to be high score label and then later on I'm going to bring in the images.
So there are nine of them and we have to do this one by one.
So I'm I'm just gonna name them.
Kenny one Kenny to Kenny tree because we want to make things simple.
K we're going to work with all of these images.
So I believe we can just call them Kenny 1 Kenny to Kenny 3 game and then again there are some other
ways to make this app with only one Kenny but by using animation by using other techniques.
But this is the easiest way to go.
So I'm just going to focus on that one for right now after you complete this whole course you will be
able to do whatever you want with swift and IRS development maybe then you can come back and have a
complete different way to do this on your own.
OK so Kenny eight and Kenny nine so the last one.
So here we go are ready I believe.
So let me close this.
We have already given the constraints so I can go back to my we controller.
So let me delete all of the spaces in here so we can have a decent look.
We are going to have a lot of code have a lot of variables in this.
So we have to make teams in a tidier Ray.
So let's stop here and continue within the next lecture.