Hi within this lecture we are going to find a way to estimate our candy.
And as I said before the way I'm going to do this is to hide all of these candies and then select the
one to display it only are we going to just change this selected one in a second or in a half a second
so that Kenny will be animating two discrete and in order to do that.
Of course we're going to use time we say again because that's an operation that we want to do in a given
preview of time and we want it to be working on the background without blocking of all the user interface
but before we go ahead and do that I believe first we have to create a function to test and see how
to hide Kenny's.
So we're going to take steps one by one.
First hide all the kidneys.
Second find a way to randomly choose one of the kidneys and display it.
And then later on turned make this into a timer.
So I'm going to create a Kenny array in which we will have a UI Image view.
OK so with in this array I will just add all of these candies.
So why am I doing that.
Why am I adding all the KDE inside of this category.
Because actually that's a lot easier to do when you have on the array.
We can have for loop right with Missouri.
You will see what I mean.
Let me just create disarray.
I will say Kenny won.
Kenny to Kenny tree and I will add all of the image views in this area.
So we're already working with a lot of variables a lot of images so I'm trying to make this as simple
as possible as efficient as possible.
Okay.
So I'm going to show you a good way to do this.
So if I want to I can actually make all of this Kenny arrays with that append as well but it's not very
efficient.
So you can just write it this way as well.
Right.
So right now wi fi call one of these elements.
What will I get.
I will get the image view itself right.
So if you're right Kenny you will see that this Kenny array is actually a UI Image view.
So if I get one of these elements I can reach their properties and attributes and do whatever I want
with them.
So let me create another function over here.
OK I'm going to call this function height Kenny and let me write it this way.
So if I call one of the caddies I can make it invisible.
So how do I do that.
There is a method to do that and you can just say is hit them.
So it's fairly easy.
So if you say Kenny one is here then OK this way.
And if you set it to true then Kenny one will be here then Kenny one will be invisible.
So I can do that for all of the kidney's one by one but I don't want to do that one by one.
I want to do that with a loop.
That would be much more easier for me.
That's why I created this category.
I'm going to say for Kenny in Kenya Ray now I can't reach all of this Kenny's one by one in a loop and
I can assign all these elements to a variable called Kenny and I can just say Kenny dots as you can
see this is still a UI image you can see that is hidden true so rather than doing this in nine lines
now I'm doing this inside of a loop.
So it's kinda cool.
Let us test this.
So let me call the height kidney function in our we load because if we don't do that it won't even get
cold and it won't be executed.
So let me run this simulator and let's see if we managed to hide the kidneys.
So here we go.
We don't see any kidneys right now but we see the countdown timer and we see the score.
We cannot tap on anything because they are hear them.
So that's good.
That's step number one.
We we have hit them all the kidneys.
Now step number two I want to have a way to select a random kidney and make it visible.
So how do we do that.
First of all if you don't know how to create a random number that's perfectly okay.
It's ask for random OK.
If you just call out for a run the method is a built in method that you can use in swift and this will
ask you for an upper bound if you choose to ask for a random uniform.
And if you say 9 for example to this upper bound it will return a value between 0 0 9 randomly so you
will get zero you will get two you will get three depending on totally random algorithms.
So for our upper bound of cause I want something between zero and 8 Y 8.
You will see in ten minutes.
But right now it asks me for a UI internally to bits.
So this is an integer.
So these are regular integer but it's 32 bit k if you just write a number in here it will be accepted
like 10 but rather than saying 10 or 8 or 0 or 5 I'm going to go for Kenny array that count because
it will make much more sense.
So if I say Canada or a dots count minus one this will be the exact number that I need because Tony
Kenny array that count will give me nine and I don't have an index nine indicate the array I only have
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 8 7 8.
So I can call it like this I can say Kenny array that I can erase 0 and it will give me Kenny 1 and
I can say Kenny 3 8 and it will give me Kenny 9 so I have to have something between 0 and 8.
There is no Kenny or a 9 K. So I'm not going to go for category that count but rather minus one.
So this will give me a number between 0 and 8.
So I'm going to use this a random number to call the Kenny in a random fashion and let me creates a
variable in order to assign this as a value.
OK I'm going to call this random and you have to convert this into an integer because that's not going
to give you an integer it's going to give you a UI in 32 bit.
OK and I can't call this random number inside of Kenya array and I can just say dot is here the true
right or is he them false.
Right.
This will make it reasonable one more time.
So step two is actually complete.
So I'm choosing your random Kenny and I'm making it visible so I am hiding everything in here and then
I'm making one reasonable.
So let's try this.
So we're gonna see one Kenny.
Yep that's working.
And we can click on it.
Let's run this one more time.
So most probably we'll see another Kenny visible like this.
So it works.
Now we have to come up with a way to make this constantly rather than doing this manually over here.
So far so good.
We have completed step 2.
Now we're heading towards Step 3 in Sep tree.
We're going to use timers one more time and I'm going to create another timer for that and I'm going
to call this height timer.
So can we do that within the same timer here yeah actually we can do that but I'm not gonna.
And I'm going to explain you why.
So let me choose scheduled time moreover here.
So in the schedule timer I'm going to give you time interval as all point five target as cells and for
selector I'm going to go for height Kenny right.
Because I have already my function in here.
That's what I want to run with this height timer.
And as you can see we have to add Objective C so user in for Neal and repeats true.
So this is going to get run once I run this.
So why am I writing this into a completely separate timer.
And don't forget to invalidate this as well or else does.
Kenny will be circulating Kenny will be animating all the time.
So we're going to call his height Kenny and the reason they're doing this in a different timer is basically
I need another time interval.
So as you can see in all points five seconds Kenny animates so this is cool.
So this is what we wanted from the beginning.
And as you can see once the timer is done Kenny stops.
And of course I can hit.
Okay.
And Kenny still there so I can tap onto Kenny and it's kind of a bug in our game.
So we need to fix this as well.
And I believe the easiest way to fix this would be to copy all of these hiding things hiding for loop
and pasted in our if control.
So if timer is ended.
If timer has reached to zero then I'm going to validate all of the time present I'm going to hide Kenny
over here.
Now we need to go and actually write a replay function and then high score function as well.