Hi.
We didn't this lecture re going to start writing Gover replay function so that a user taps on the replay.
The score will be reset and the time will be reset.
Kenny will start animating Bon soir.
So let's go to our replay function.
So remember we have to write this in our replay bottom where we control if counter is 0.
So we invalidate as our timer.
Right.
So we need to start timers one more time and then we also have to make sure that our score label or
score variables are reset.
So I'm going to say score zero and it gives me an error because we're inside of what is called a closure.
So we have to make sure that this is self.
That's core why we're doing this because the X code things that maybe we created another variable called
SCORE.
Right now we know to reach this car we had to say s that score maybe I created another variable over
here called score and in order to make sure that I'm not referring this score rather I'm referring the
variable that I have created previously I'm saying s that score and don't ever do that.
If you have some variable called score don't ever come here inside of a closure and say that okay I'm
going to create another variable that has exactly the same name as before.
So just create another name.
So here you can just say s out score as well but you cannot create another scoring here so that won't
be any problem.
But in here D it's inside of a blog and inside of another blog.
So you have to say s that in order to make sure that you're referring to the correct variable.
So I'm going to say South Scalia will doubt tax score and reverse slash s that score.
And after that of course we have to do that for the counter as well so I'm going to reset our counter
and timer label.
Okay time label.
So this will be solved our time label not taxed.
So string representation of self doubt counter.
And after that we have to make sure to call this timer's one more time in order to do that.
Let's go over here and just copy and paste all of these values to the replay function below.
So let's go here and paste and I believe we have to say SDR timer in order to make sure this works.
Yeah you have to say so SDR timer.
Okay let's fix it and you have to say s dots count down south dots height Katie and SDR timer s thought
Hi timer in order to make it explicit.
So here we go.
We are ready right.
We have finished our replay function.
Let's see if this works.
So let's run our game and let's try to hit on Kenny as you can see I can.
Tab on Kenny and score increases so time is running out.
And once I reached the zero I can say replay if I say replay time will start one more time and scurry
0.
Now wi fi tap on Kenny will increase.
So this works in a perfect way.
This is what we want.
If I say okay this will be zero and score will be seven but I cannot tap on Kenny anymore.
So we gonna The here actually and within the next lecture we are going to take care of high score because
in here we only reset all the variables right.
We reset score we reset counter we reset labels and we recall timer's but we don't take care of high
score.
So we're going to have to do that separately.
Let's do that in the next lecture.