Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to finish our app by taking care of high scores storage right now we
don't have any high score check.
So we have to do that when the time ends.
So I'm going to called is high score.
OK so that's where we're going to take care of this.
Why.
Because let me see.
We have a high score label here in which I want to show the highest score that has ever been made in
this game.
So maybe you think that these we are going to do this with user defaults and that's correct because
we're only going to save one little value and that's the perfect way to do it.
Right.
So are we going to control if score is higher than the high score his current score is actually higher
than the high score that I'm going to save this new score as a high score.
If it's not then I'm not going to change high score at all.
So this is how it's going to go down.
We're going to check to see if our score is actually higher than the highest previous score and in the
we did load of course we're going to check to see if we have scored any high score.
And we're going to take it and show it in our high score label.
So we need a high score variable in order to do that right.
So I'm going to save our high score zero and we're going to take this from the reloaded load from the
user default.
So it's actually easy to assign this to be zero initially and then we can check to see if we have any
other scores could start.
So when the time ends I'm going to check to see if self-doubt score is.
I actually hired Dan self-taught high score.
Right.
So if that's the case then I'm going to need to just start this valley as a high score.
So first of all I'm going to make sure that my high score in teacher myself that high scoring teacher
is now self-taught score.
So this will be updated but also I'm going to make sure that I I'm saving this high score real inside
of my user default database so you can just go and say high score labeled text is now High Score Column.
OK.
High Score Column A rear slash high score so or self-doubt high score.
Yeah.
So this is good right.
This will display this high score real to the user but also we want to store it so that we won't lose
it once the user closes down the game.
So user defaults dot standard that set.
You remember how this works.
You how to come up with a value and with a key.
So our rally is simple here self-taught high score OK because we already said it to be the highest score
and therefore key I'm going to use high score again.
But we can call it anything we want.
So I'm going to go for high score and we need to remember this key because we're going to need it in
a minute.
So far so good.
Let's go to we did loads in the we did load we have to check for high score as well.
Right.
Because there will be some cases that we store the high score and there will be other cases we didn't
score the high score for example for the first time a user opens this game there won't be any high scores
saved.
So I'm going to say let's start high score and I'm going to get this value from user defaults that sender
that objects and for key of course I'm going to use the same key that I have stated.
So this is high score and I'm going to check to see if this value exists or not.
So I can come over here and just say if start high score is nil.
Right.
So if that's the case then it means that I didn't start anything.
So I can just show high score as zero.
Right.
I can say high score is zero and high score labeled up text is actually zero or High Score Column zero.
Or let me do it this way.
This will be much more clear.
So high score.
OK so this will display the high score that I score labeled a text and it shows me as a result I identify
year because yep I misspelled the high score.
So this is good.
But if that's not the case this won't be even run right.
This won't get executed.
So I can just check to see.
Just try to cast this as an integer.
So I'm going to say if left new scar starts high score as integer optional integer casting optionally
as integer that is more correct.
And if I can do that it means that there is a new score and it means that I start the value and I can
cast this as an integer.
Now I can just say high score is named score and high score labeled up text is again High Score Column
High Score Column reverse slash high score.
This time I'm going to spell it right.
So high score yeah this is good.
So it says that new score is not used but that's not the case.
Yeah.
The warning went away so we're good to go actually.
So let me test is to see if that works.
So there is not a high score value stored right now.
And as you can see high score is shown as zero.
So let me try to tap on Kenny if I can.
Yes.
Chris one parent they are not very good at this game.
So as you can see high score is shown as one.
So let me try with another high score.
Hopefully I can tap on Kenny.
Yeah I did a score of four.
So let's wait.
And here you go.
High score is shown as four.
So let me close this and open it one more time and let's see if we can see the four as high score.
So here we go.
As you can see we managed to save this information in the user defaults.
So our game is definitely working and we finished this game actually.
And bear in mind that this game is created by me couple of years ago.
And you can find a lot of clones of this game in the App Store and Google Play.
It's absolutely fine to do that.
Just try to find an image that will not cause any royalty problems so you can google for royalty free
images and then just try to add some new more features to its for example.
A lot of students have actually implemented some new levels making it harder to tap on Kenny.
So a lot of students actually used cloud servers to save the high scores and try to make a leader board
or something in the game.
You cannot do that with your churns knowledge by the way after you complete the course try and improve
this game a little bit further.
So far so good.
We're going to stop here and within the next section we going to learn about something called Table
views.