Hi within this lecture we are going to add a delete functionality in our table to use as well.
So maybe you have come across apps that let you swipe left and delete the current data in the table
view.
So that's what we're going to learn within this lecture.
So remember we have assigned this to be a UI table view delegate so we can reach some functions related
to this UI table to use and editing style committee editing style is one of them.
So choose this commit editing style function and we're going to define an editing style in here and
we're going to say what to do when this happens in order to do that.
We're going to control is editing style over here so I'm going to say if editing style and as you can
see is a UI table view editing style.
Okay.
And we have some different kinds of editing styles actually if you say double eagle and hit dot you
can see delete insert or none.
So he searches for inserting some new data.
OK so this indicates a green circle on the right hand side but we're not going to go for that we just
want to learn how to delete it.
OK.
So this is kind of red when we swipe left.
OK so I'm going to go for if editing style is actually delete then I'm going to go and remove that relate
to the row from our chair and we'll.
And how do we do that since we can do landmark names data paint or landmark images that append we can
do the opposite as well.
We can say landmark names that's removed and we can remove data from an array using that method.
So if you go over here and say landmark names that remove it will ask you for an integer and this integer
actually specifies the index that we want to remove the value from.
So for example if I want to remove the Colosseum I can just say remove at zero.
OK.
And how can I get this index off course I can say index path that throw because this is given to me
in the function and I'm going to do that for Landmark images as well not to break the synchronization
of these two landmark names and landmark images arrays.
So that's how you delete the values from arrays but also we have to delete them from the table view
itself as vote.
So if you say table view we you can just go for table view dots delete two rows into will ask you Which
row to delete.
Right.
So we have the index path so it's it's asking for an index path and we have this here.
So if you just see the enter you can delete this and you can replace it with index path.
So this is the small one that is given us within the function.
And it says that do we do with animation.
OK.
So you can hit enter to hit dot and you can say Yeah why not.
You can do that fate.
So it will delete the row with an animation of fading.
So that's Oh I believe we can try this right now so let's open our app and let's swipe left a little
bit and as you can see we can delete all these values any time we want.
So it's reverse and if we just run this one more time of course we're going to see all the values and
it doesn't make sense to have this delete functional Tina app like this because we don't start those
values in at database we just write them in our code if we virtues store those values in a cloud database
which we will in the following sections by the way then it will make much more sense because we could
have deleted them the cloud file your base our cloud database as well.
But right now we know how to make this functionality.
So in the feature if we are working with that cloud database we can delete them from the arrays we can
delete them from the table view and we can delete them from the database as well and they won't be back.
So this is very useful to using your apps.
So going to stop here and we're going to continue making this clickable in the next lecture.