Hi.
We didn't his lecture re to see how we can leverage this in its function in order to create these properties
without initializing them.
So I'm deleting these initial risers and I'm going to do this inside of my in its function.
Okay.
So rather than printing musician created I'm just going to ask for some input in the in its function.
So I'm going to ask for a name in it.
It will be a string.
OK.
And again an agent.
This will be an integer and an instrument in it.
This will be again a string.
So what I'm going to do I'm going to take those values and I'm going to say name is now name in it.
Age is now age in it.
OK so you're going to have to say your name is equal to name in it.
And of course the instrument is again instrument in it.
You don't have to say in it you can just go for name.
You can just go for why there were variable name you want.
I'm just trying to differentiate them a little bit so you don't get confused.
Okay.
So whenever I create an instance of this class it will ask me for a name and age and instrument.
So rather than defining those values of to recreate the object.
Now we can do this in the same line.
So let me do an example.
So if I say let James and James is a musician it should have asked me there.
So let me the comment be.
Yep this is asking right now.
So let me do this from the beginning.
OK.
So if I do command beat I WILL GET SYNCHRONIZED as I said before.
Now it's giving me an error it says that you have a missing argument in here.
Now if you open parentheses you will see that it asks you for a name init agent it's an instrument in
its so far name.
You can go for James OK for age you can go for 50 and for instrument you can call go for guitar.
So now we fi print James starts.
It will give me 50.
So that's how you create objects with initialized is.
OK.
And the vial are added I believe we should learn about E numbers as well so E numbers make our life
easier when we try to categorize things.
What do I mean.
For example if I want to add a type of musician in here as a property I can just go and do that with
a string.
Right.
But rather than doing this drink I'm just going to go for e num and you will see what why why I'm doing
that.
In a clear way.
So generally you C E numbers enumerated type declarations in the top of this project file.
OK.
So you have to give and name here and in some name like musician type.
And in here you write some categories for example a rare musician can be a vocalist a guitarist or lead
guitarist.
Right.
So write them all so lead guitar.
It will be a vocalist.
It will be a drummer.
Right.
And it would be a bassist as well.
So maybe you can sing something like a while in the store or something.
OK.
So why are we creating these types.
We can have done this with strings as well.
I'm going to show you why.
If I come around here to my attributes I can easily add a new type I can just say type.
OK.
And this would be a string but if I do that my other developed reverb can go on this project can write
vocal OK and the other developer using this class can write vocalists.
And even if you're the only one working on a project like this you can do the same mistake as well.
Right.
You can go for a vocal you can go for a vocalist in some other cases maybe you want to standardize those
types.
So this is our E names come to play you kind o standardize the category so that would leave no room
for mistake at all.
So rather than saying this is going to be a string I'm going to say this will be a busy Shin type OK
as you can see musician type is a musician type type.
So this is an in.
This is not a class but we can actually use this to choose a category.
And now we have an error inside of in it because we have to ask for it type in it.
Right.
So I'm going to go for type in it and this will be a musician type rather than string.
Now I can come over here and I can easily say my type this type OK is going to be a type in it.
So right now we have created a category for ourselves and we have a signed it to be a property in our
class.
So let me do a build so it will get synchronized and once it gets synchronized as you can see we got
another error in here.
So it seems that you have to add a new parameter here called type init if you hit fixed.
This will be added automatically.
So I can hit that here and I can choose one of the categories that we have created.
So I can easily come here.
I can say James is a vocalist for example and now I can't reach this value as well.
Right.
So let me try to print this.
James that type.
Now I will see the type in the logs as well.
So this is how you use E numbers.
This is how you leverage items in your classes.
If you're looking for a way to create categories rather than doing this with a string you can do this
with E numbers and this will be much more efficient much more save for then doing this with a string
so that's all for right now.
We're going to stop here actually and within the next lecture we're going to see how we can add some
actions some functions to our class as well.