Hi.
We didn't this lecture re going to display those seem some models in our table view.
In fact we're going to display only the name of those Simpson values right.
We're going to display the other features in the details view controller.
So let's come over here and rather than saying these dummy values were going to use the exact values.
So first of all we have this Homer array in here and I don't like that because we're going to need those
Homer array values so I'm going to create Homer array in here.
Right.
And the Homer A's not a good choice actually.
We can call the Simpsons array or you can just call this my Simpsons OK and open the parentheses and
does my Simpsons.
We'll have Simpsons objects inside of disarray and we have to initialize this as an empty array.
OK.
So don't forget to just add some parentheses over here.
OK I'll put an open close parentheses and this will go away.
So rather than using commentary I'm going to punch my models a model objects inside of this array so
I can go over here as say my Simpsons.
OK.
Let me delete this.
My Simpsons.
So what was it called My Simpsons dots at punt.
And this is a Simpson area so it will ask me for a Simpson element and I'm going to add one by one.
So my Simpsons that the point Homer my Simpsons that's a pants March.
OK.
So let's do this step by step.
Marge Bart and then let's go for Lisa.
And then lastly my Simpsons dog the pants Maggie.
So here we go we have our very right.
And we can reach that array from anywhere in our class.
So I can go to other functions right now and called is my Simpsons array without hesitating.
So rather than saying return 10 I can just go over say my Simpsons dot count.
Right.
I can't.
I could I just said five.
But it doesn't make sense I can add some more values later on.
So I'm going to go over here and close the sushi down and say My Simpsons dots count.
So again this is OK.
Number of roses section.
We got it right.
But right now we have to make sure that we display the name of the Simpsons E side of our table view
cell.
So I'm not going to say Homer Simpson here.
Rather I'm going to go over say my Simpsons and four in Dax remember we can just go for and say index
path that's wrong because index path is given to us with the inside that function.
So you can just called and say index path that throw bus.
But this won't do it because this will return us a simple some object.
And I cannot show as Simpson object in my cell because I need a string in here.
Right.
So rather than saying My Simpsons index path that row what we like say.
So this will give me as Simpson object.
Right.
So if I say Simpson object dot it will display the name to me.
So I'm going to display the Simpsons names in my cell that tax labeled dot tax.
So this is going to work right now because we're done with the setup.
So if you run this on your simulator you will see the names of the Simpson objects.
Here we go we now see the Homer Simpson Marge Simpson Bart Lisa Maggie we have it all here.
So the next step will be to pass this information when we click one of these objects and display that's
related models or related objects values inside of our details.
We have controller we going to do that in the next lecture.