Hi.
We didn't this lecture re going to start building our travel book and first thing to do will be to learn
how to work with maps.
It's fairly easy.
You just bring in one view and you just start working with maps.
Thanks to something called Map kits in the swift.
Okay I'm just going to go ahead and create my project and I'm gonna go for a single weave app as usual.
Okay.
And then here I'm gonna check the used car data one more time because we we will be saving all of this
information into car data and for product name.
I'm gonna go for chaebol book so click next and placed is under my OS complete folders.
You can place it wherever you want.
And then I'm going to make it into a full screen mode so that we can see better.
And I'm just going to go ahead and show you that we have this travel book.
It's called data model but we're not going to go into that right now.
We first have to learn how to work with maps then we can just go on and save our information into car
data model because we already know how to work with car data.
Right.
So let's go to storyboards because in order to work with maps we are going to need a map view and it's
fairly easy to work with maps.
You just open your library search for a map and you will see something called Map kit view.
OK.
Just drag and drop the map view as you can see this is a regular view like we used to work with other
races before like UI imagery.
You can just drag and drop here and you can stretch it out for the all edges for example you can come
over here and just say 0 0 0 4 all constraints it will stretch out all to the edges.
Now when we run this when we set this up we will see a whole huge map covering up all the view controller
in order to set this up.
I'm going to open my weave controller in an assistant editor and I'm going to define his map by dragging
and dropping here and I'm going to call this map for you.
OK.
And once we do that we'll get an error.
So we have to do some set up first.
And it's fairly easy to do that.
So we get to how to use we did load because we have to set the delegate of this map view to the view
controller like we do in the table to use.
Right.
So this is all we have to do to make this work as you can see this is saying undeclared type.
So let me just say map we have that delegate is south and this is not going away because we have to
make our view controller delegates of map and K map kids view as Vo.
But in order to do that we first have to import map kit so import the map kids make map we've got delegate
equal to south and then come over here to we have controller and just say I'm j k I'm K map yes this
form M.K. map view delegate.
So this is exactly like what we do in the table we use right.
So we set delegate to solve and we make our way controllers an actual delegate of the related view.
So part map kit say this is an M K map view delegate and then map you that delegate is south.
So later on we're going to use another delegates as well because we're going to need a lot of functions
to be called in our wheel controller but for right now this is all we need to make this map run.
So if I run this in my simulator that I will get a map and it won't show me any location of the user
it won't show me in a specific location we're just going to see the map and we can wander around the
map we can zoom means zoom out whatever we want but it won't do any action because we haven't defined
one yet.
For example we're in the Europe.
We can zoom in we can zoom out.
We can do whatever we want with this map but we're just displaying the map right now.
We're not doing anything fancy.
And let me zoom in so let's see if we can see the details over here as you can see the see names are
appearing here right now.
So it seems fine.
I believe this is all for this lecture we're going to stop here and within the next following lectures
we're going to learn how to get the user location so we can start this map actually at the user's location.
And then after that we going to learn how to pin this map view in order to tag the view and get the
coordinates of that specific view so that we can later on at the navigation to it.
Let's do all of this in the following lecture.