Hi within this picture we are going to see how to pin the map.
However before we do that let's recap the previous lecture because we have learnt a lot.
As you might remember in the location we have chosen another location we changed the user's location
and the map got updated.
So it means that whenever I change my location we are going to get that location in the did update locations
functions and we're going to display it on the map so that then user walks or changes his location.
It will be reflected on the map because we're zooming in that through region K and again in the previous
lecture we have learned about something called spend and it defines the width and height of the current
map view.
So with 0.01 we get some view like that.
So let me run from the beginning actually and we can see or point the one in an exact way.
So it starts like this.
It's kind of a zoomed out I believe.
So let's try 0 point 0 5.
As I said before it will give us a zoomed in more zoomed in view.
I believe it will be much better.
And now as you can see it's much better and we can actually tried for 0 point 0 3 as well but I believe
this is optimal.
So I'm going to leave it as it is.
I suggest you try with other numbers and experience on with yourself.
So next thing to do is just to add a gesture recognize your here so that then user taps on one of these
map locations it will get pinned.
So yeah we're going to use the old gesture recognizing in order to do that but we're not going to use
these same old UI tap gesture recognizing because we want to look press on here for like three seconds
in order to tag this.
If we make it with a tap gesture recognize her then it won't be very good because if every time I touch
on a map it will just tag the map will just drop a pin and that's not what I want.
I want to choose a specific location in which I can long press like hold for three seconds and then
I can see the pin I can see the tagged location.
So let me show you how it's done.
We're going to create the gesture recognize her as usual.
Okay I'm going to say love gesture organizer and rather than saying you I tap gesture recognize her
I'm just going to go for you I long pressed gesture recognize her.
So this is again a gesture recognize her that looks for long pressed gestures.
OK.
And don't worry we're going to set it up as usual so we're just going to have to specify a target which
is itself and of course we're just going to have to specify a selector function like we used to do before.
So it's not different than UI tap gesture recognized.
So I'm going to say Objective C function and in here we can just something like we can just say something
like choose location OK and that's it.
That's how you create gesture recognizes with you a long press gesture recognize type.
But here we're going to do something different rather than just saying this going to be a function I'm
just going to give a gesture recognize your input here as well because we're going to need that gesture
recognizing type to work upon you know what I mean.
Let's write that and I'm I will explain later on.
So I'm going to call this gesture recognizing and it's going to be a type of UI long press gesture recognizing
ok like this.
So choose the UI long gesture recognize her.
And if I now come over here to this action and say choose location OK it will bring me as a view like
that and I can double click on this.
And that's how I assign this selector to my gesture recognize her.
So why did I even do that under.
Choose location function I have to use the properties of the gesture recognize her.
Like what.
Like I'm just going to see if gestures recognize her has begun.
So for example if I say gesture recognize her Dot I can reach the properties I can reach the attributes
of that gesture recognize the right.
So I can just control to see if gesture recognizes state is OK.
Double equal to dot began dot begin or cancelled or changed or failed.
If I want to see the current state of the gesture recognize her.
Now I can't reach and use it.
So when I do that it connects me to do you I long press gesture recognizing that my user will be doing
on the map so I can't see if it's failed or cancelled or begin I'm just going to control to begin by
the way.
So if we begin then I'm going to perform my operations but I'm just telling you for days like an example.
OK.
That's why I have given this gesture recognizing you UI long press.
Yes you recognize her in here.
And as usual I'm going to close down the series and I'm going to come over here and say map you dot
adjust you recognize her it will ask me for my gesture recognize her I'm going to give it one but before
we go on and do that we have two sets minimum duration of that gesture recognize her because it's a
long pass gesture recognize her and we gonna specify how long.
So whether we want something like five seconds or 23 seconds in order to do that say dot minimum price
duration and go for tree and we are going for tree because if we make it like one it would be too short
we can easily capture the other taps of the user by mistake if we make it something like five it will
be too long this time so user will think there is something growing I'm pressing over here and nothing
happens so I'm gonna go for a tree we generally use tree but you can experience with other numbers as
well.
So after dad under choose location I'm going to go ahead and actually control if this state is began.
So once my gesture recognizes begins I can get the clicked coordinates from that point Okay so we're
gonna see how to do it.
Don't worry.
First of all let's check if gesture recognizing that state is actually equal to begin so let's say that
that's state double equals sign dot begin so it means that has received touched objects as you can see
in the description.
So once we do that once it's begun it means that it received something called touch points and I'm going
to create that touch points with a variable I'm going to assign it to a variable because we're going
to get the coordinates out of that touch points in order to do that you have to say gesture recognize
the DOT location.
OK so this gives us a point in some view and of course we're going to say self doubt map the region
here because we're going to use that location from map view and again this gesture recognized gives
us a touchpoint.
So it means that very user touched on that in view K and we can create a coordinate with that touch
point and in order to do that you have to say s dot map view dot and converge and we're looking for
converting a point to a coordinate.
OK so we're looking for this one so we're converting it points and we could converting it from a view
so we have a lot of options here please try to choose the right one point two coordinate from so as
you can see this commerce a point in the specified views coordinate system to a map.
So I'm going to say touch point four for the point and we're going to say South dot map view here one
more time and again this will give us the touch point of the user and this will give us the coordinates
of that touch points.
Next thing I'm going to create the pin that we have been talking about and it's called annotation and
it's type of M.K. pinpoint annotation actually so if you come over here you can just say I'm K point
on notation as you can see this will create the object for us when you create an imitation you have
to give it some coordinates okay a notation does curdled and we say we have this coordinates right touch
coordinates and you can use subtitles to annotations as well I'm going to say annotation notation that
title new plays are new on notation and I'm just doing this for an example so that you will see what
is that title.
What is the subtitle and how they are displayed in the map.
Okay so I'm just going to go for travel book here so that you can see why we're using titles why we're
using subtitles and then you can just call the map USA.
Dot dot dot notation and choose the annotation that we have created.
So let me run this and if this works I'm going to explain it one more time.
Don't worry if it's got too complicated for you.
Now let's zoom in into Eiffel Tower and I'm going to hit over here and hold for three seconds.
And here you go.
Here we have the first annotation.
So as you can see it says that new annotation and under the new annotation we have the travel book subtitled.
So let me zoom in and so we can see better.
As you can see this is the title and this is the subtitle that I have been creating so far.
So we're going to use this annotation in our travel book and we're going to display the name and the
comment of the user not of the user in that notation with title and subtitle.
So what did we do.
We created this gesture organizer and once it begins it gives something called touchpoint and we can
get this by saying that gesture recognizes that location and we convert that point to a coordinates
and we give this coordinates to the annotation that we have created.
You are seeing this for the first time and it might seem complicated but once you actually get used
to it you will see it's actually very easy compared to what we have been learning so far.
So let's stop here and continue within the next lecture.