Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to save all this information into our core data database.
So in order to do that we are going to need a save bottom.
We can bring the save button on the bottom of this page or we can just put it on the top of this page
on the navigation controller bar like we did before.
I'm gonna do it on the bottom of this wave controller because it will be more clear like this is step
one.
The map is step two and step three will be the same bottom.
Of course you can do it on the navigation bar as well if you want but I'm gonna go for the bottom of
this page.
OK.
So I'm gonna decrease this height a little bit as well this time upwards and I'm going to bring in the
button on the bottom of this view controller so drag and drop bombard them not here but at the bottom
here.
So let me zoom in and let me make this a little bit bigger.
So like that and put it in the center of the view controller then we can call it save.
So this will be our Save button.
Let me open my assistant editor here and let me call the view controller.
Now we're gonna call the same button as an action in here so let me click control and drag and drop
over here and call the say Button Clicked.
Here you go.
Let me close this down.
And before we go home don't forget to add the constraints.
So choose the view controller and come to the bottom and say you reset to suggest it's constraints.
Let's check if everything has constraints.
Yes it seems so.
So let's run this and see if we have anything suspicious.
If we have anything distorted so we can come back and see the constraints but everything seems to be
fine right now so I believe we can move on with this kind of view.
Where you going to get named we're going to get the comment we get we are going to choose the map and
save it and remember when we click on this the keyboard will open in a real app and we have to make
sure that we have the necessary code in order to tap anywhere in the view and closed down the keyboard.
We have learned how to do that so I'm not going to implement this all over again because I don't want
to make this longer than it should be.
So in a real app maybe you may want to implement it yourself.
So right now I'm going to go to X called Data Model okay and I'm going to add a new entity.
And this time I'm going to call this places or something places or locations I before we called this
paintings and remember the entity name can be changed by clicking in here and saying whatever you want
like places and in the attributes where you're going to get the title or the name of the location that
we have chosen and then we're going to get a commands and then of course we need to save a latitude
and longitude.
So let's say title for the name and I'm going to call this it's going to be a string and then we're
going to have a subtitle and this will be string as well.
Later on we're going to get a latitude and longitude.
So what will be the type of latitude.
Is it going to be an integer.
Of course not because we have decimals on decimals actually matter in this case.
So I'm going to go for a double OK.
We save latitude and longitude as double in here and in the coding section as well.
And we create a latitude variable for example it should be a type of double.
So it's it's the same thing for longitude as well.
Let's choose longitude double.
And for the last one I'm going to go for I.D. and this will be a you you I.D. If you haven't watched
the previous section I suggest you go back and watch because we have discussed why are we using an I.D.
what is an universally unique I.D. And how do we leverage those I.D. things in our code.
OK I'm not going to go over that one more time.
So in the same building correct.
Remember we have to use card data.
OK.
So I have two important core data and come down to say by then click.
And first thing we're going to do where you're going to create the app delegate variables.
Remember we have to use app delegates in order to reach and use automatically generated Core Data functions
for us.
And then we're going to create this context and then we're going to use that context in order to save
delete are retrieved the values that we want.
So I'm going to say let's Abdullah delegate.
It's going to dry from UI application dots shared dot delegates and later all I'm going to say let's
context this is going to drive for a map delegate that's persistence container.
OK.
Doesn't show up.
Let me see you one more time.
So this is going to be persistence container.
Yeah.
It doesn't show up because I didn't cast this previous value as to be our app delegate.
Remember we have to force cast as app delegate.
Now wi fi say app that I get.
Okay.
That now I can see persistent container and then view context.
So I'm going over this very fast as we have done there's like a billion times right now.
I'm not explaining why I'm doing this because we are already seeing how to deal with card data in the
previous section.
Again if you haven't watch please go back and watch the previous section or else you wouldn't understand
what I'm doing right now.
So while I'm going to do I'm going to create an variable called new place like we did a new art before.
So I'm going to call this an N S entity description and insert new value he certain you object to my
entity and the entity name that I'm looking for is the places we're going to use this context in order
to save and retrieve information here.
So next thing is very easy we're going to say new place that set value and we have to provide a value
for some certain keys and keys our period defined for us by eyes.
Actually we have defined title subtitle latitude longitude to remember and we can get this title from
named text not text easily and we can get the comments subtitle from common texts right.
So this is going to be comment text that's text and the key will be subtitle maybe we should have used
comment to name four keys as well but since we have defined it I'm not going to change it later on the
next thing will be to get the latitude and longitude.
Right now I don't have any variables to reach out and get the latitude and longitude.
So what I'm going to do I'm going to create a chosen latitude and chosen longitude variables and I'm
going to define those variables as doubles and then later on then somebody chooses a coordinate from
the map in our app I'm going to get that chosen latitude and longitude from DUI gesture recognizing
that we have created.
Okay.
It's fairly easy to do that.
So we have worked with that kind of operation before.
What we want to do we have to come over here.
We already have our touch coordinates so we can get touch cordons that latitude touch cordons that longitude
and a sign those values to newly created variables like touch cardinals that longitude latitude as you
can see we can reach those variables.
OK so let's create our variables as doubles so let's go to our class and let's say we're going to use
var because we're going to change this after all.
So I'm going to say chosen latitude is at double okay.
And I'm going to say chosen longitude as a double.
So this will be our latitude and longitude variables.
And then in here we can just say chosen latitude is now touch coordinates that's latitude so chosen
longitude that's chosen longitude is actually touch the coordinates that longitude.
So that's perfect that's what we wanted.
So we are creating this chosen latitude and longitude from here we're assigning new values under our
chosen location function and when the save button gets clicked we can just put those information into
our car data model.
Of course I believe in order to be safe maybe you can check for if named taxis is empty if actually
and our notation has been created or not you can have different kinds of check points for that but I'm
not going to go into that kind of operation because we have already seen how to do that before.
Right.
And the last thing to be at is actually the I.D. itself and here we already have created I.D. and the
type will be you you I.D. So it's very easy to do that because X code takes care of this.
Then we write you you I.D. OK and it means that we have completed the setting value process.
Now remember we can just say context not save in order to save this into core data.
And then we say that it chose an error.
So we have to do that.
We do try catch structure so do try contexts about say and we going to catch if there is any error.
OK.
So let me cut this from here and paste is in here.
And if we have a problem we're we're going to just print out an error.
So if we don't have any problem we're just going to print out success right now.
If we even if this works we don't have any method to see if it works or not because we're not retrieving
the data yet.
So I'm printing out success just to test it.
So here you go.
Let me just go zoom in in the Eiffel Tower a little bit.
Are we going to save this.
So when I click over here without giving name and comment it will bring me a new annotation about it
doesn't it won't have any name and comment for this kind of thing.
I believe you should check if name Tuck's name Tax that tax is empty comment tax that tax is empty.
But I will assume that you can do it on your own.
So I'm going to give this Eiffel Tower and I love Paris here manually and then I'm going to zoom in
a little bit more so I can give it another annotation and it won't matter because every time I add a
new annotation the coordinates will get changed.
So why they were I did before won't matter man I add the new one notation.
This will change the chosen latitude and chosen longitude.
So I will be saving the latest coordinates that I have chosen in this app.
OK so then you come over here as you might remember chosen latitude and chosen longitude gets near values
every time I click on this.
So right now I have my name I have my command and I have my notation.
So I have my coordinates.
And as you can see that I hit save it gets saved on the card data.
So in order to be sure of course we have to implement that fetch request and get the information on
display to the user table view.
So let's stop here and we're going to do those things in the following lectures.