Hi within this lecture we are going to add another view controller in which we will display the table
view so that we can get the list of the names that we have saved and display them to the user.
So let's go to our main story Bert and this is not even the first V controller that we want to see when
we first opened the app.
Right.
We want to see another view controller in which we display the names that are saved in the card data.
So let me open our library and search for we have controller.
OK.
And let's bring in the view controller and let it lets us put it here and take this arrow and put inside
of the first view controller.
Remember desire always cold entry points.
So this will be displayed by me first open the app.
So let us create a new Swift file near we'll controller files so that we can associate our cocoa touch
class with this new wave controller.
So let's choose cocoa touch class.
I remembered this has to be a UI with controller but we already have a class called Wheel controller
so I'm going to call the something like table we've our list we have controller.
OK we're going to list the places in this.
We have controllers so you're more than welcome to choose anything you want in here.
So let's say next and create is in our tribal book folder.
So let me put this up here and then here.
And as you can see we have to delete this comments.
And I believe there is something buggy in here going round one more time.
So let me just see let me go to identity inspector and as you can see we cannot see the list.
We have controller in here so I'm going to write this manually and we have come across this kind of
problem in the previous section as you might remember even though it seems like it's working there is
something buggy.
So I'm going to just solve this problem by coming over here with so source code off the main story board
so I'm not going to explain why I'm doing that right now because we have seen how to deal with this
problem in the previous section.
So we have this custom module Lancaster module provider missing from the newly created The View Controller.
So I'm going to add it.
OK copy and paste it here and that's it.
That's all I want to do to solve this problem.
I did it a little fast but as I said in the previous section we already have seen this in great detail
so I'm going to go over to interface builder to work start working on my newly created view controller.
First of all I'm going to need a table view and I'm going to need a Segway between this and my new controller.
So let's say table with you and bring in the table view.
So I'm going to only have this table view over here so I'm going to say 0 2 all constraints.
So it will fill up the whole weave controller.
So let's bring in the Segway.
Click over here controlled drag as a show.
I'm doing this kind of fast and as you can see there is some gap over here but it doesn't matter because
I'm going to bring in the navigation controller anyway.
So let's say to we controller to the identifier of the Segway and let's go to this we have controller
and editor say Ed embed in navigation controller.
Once we do that as you can see the top of this we have controller gets fixed because it gets fixed with
the navigation bar.
So here what do we have we will have the table we do of course we are going to have an ad button as
well but we can add the Add button with codes.
I'm just going to bring in the table we've from here and I'm going to call this table view.
OK.
And that's it.
So as you can see this is filled up.
So it's working.
So let me close this down and I believe that's all for our user interface.
Now we are ready to start setting up this table view and add this add button on the list we controller.
So let's go to list.
Have controller.
OK.
In the we did load.
What are we going to do.
We're going to say table to you that delegate is self.
Ok table we got data search.
This is south again.
And as I said before we're doing this for like a million times so I'm going to go a little fast here.
This should be like a second nature to you right now so that you can easily do this.
OK so we're going to call a number of roads in section four right now.
I'm going to return 10 suffer all at index path.
OK.
This will ask us to return the cell so I'm going to create a cell.
This is going to be a UI table we cell.
I'm just going to return that cell.
And of course if you want you can display some tax in the cells as well like Soledad tax labeled tax
is tests.
So that's it for our table we have set up.
And in the we did load we have to do something else.
We have to add the navigation bar item.
OK.
So I'm gonna go for navigation controller dot navigation bar the top item.
That's right.
K right.
Bar about an item.
I'm just going to add it to right.
As you know there is left as well but I'm going to go for right.
So let's choose the UI bar about an item and I'm going to go for system items one more time.
Remember we have a lot of options in here but I'm going to go for ad targets will be self and the action
will be a function that we will create right now.
So objectives C function add the bottom clicked.
So this is how fast I can write swift code as you can see once I know what I'm doing.
If I don't know if I'm reading from somewhere else it should be actually much more slower.
But right now we all know how to do this stuff.
So I'm going really fast.
So if you cannot type that fast if you cannot write swift go that fast it doesn't matter you can just
pause the video and try to do it on your own.
I'm just trying to not make this course a little longer than it should be.
As you can see if I click on the ad button it brings us the view controller and in the list we have
controller we can see the table view that we have created so far so good.
It's working right now.
Now we have to get the data from the car data and display them to the user in the next lecture.