Hi within this lecture we are going to learn about dark moat.
So with the coming of U.S. church teen Apple has introduced dart mode into our lives.
OK so let me go to Google and show you what I mean.
So if you search for our dark mold IRS 13 you will have a lot of results.
Of course you don't have to do that.
I just want to show you the developer documentation of the IRS 13 4 dark mold.
OK.
So I'm going to go into do developer dot apple dot com and read the documentation.
You don't have to do that.
I'm just going to show you that there is a dark mold and we will use it.
So what is dark moat.
So it basically lets users choose whether they will use their phone in the light mold or dark mold so
dark mold means black backgrounds.
Okay whites labels white texts white strings rather than having a white background with a black text.
Now users will see dark backgrounds with white texts.
Of course it doesn't end there when a user chooses dark mold in their phone completely change phone
into dark mold in every menu in every app.
OK.
So you have to be ready to use this in your own apps to say I'm going to show you how to do that we
are going to create a very basic app so that we can see what it is to work in dark mode.
So I'm going to choose the single we've app as usual.
I'm going to name this dark mode app or dark mode.
OK.
We're going to have only two we have controllers with two views inside of those.
So let me click next and let me put this under my eyes.
Complete folder.
Once we create our project I'm going to make this into full screen.
OK so that you can see better.
And I'm just going to go into the main story birds.
So here as I said before I'm going to have to weave controllers in which I will have only one button
and one label so that we can see how they will react in dark mode.
So let me search for a real controller and bring in one.
OK and here I'm just going to add a button and this button will segway to the next we have controller.
OK.
That's all.
This button is going to do.
So let me make this a little bit bigger.
And here you go.
I'm going to name this change.
OK change by them because it will change the weave controller and I'm not even going to bother writing
the Segway code.
Rather I'm just going to do Segway from directly to this button from this button to DV controller and
I'm going to embed in a navigation controller so that we can see how navigation tidal navigation bar
will behave in dark mode as well.
Now we have this back button and we will see the color of this navigation bar as well.
So in the second v controller I'm just going to have a label I'm not even going to have a view controller
assigned to this view controller like a wave controller class.
OK.
Because we only want to see how this label will change.
I'm going to call this dark moat.
And as you can see we have a white background with dark black label.
OK.
So let me give this to you.
And this one to some constraints.
OK so let me add these constraints as well.
So here you go.
We're actually ready.
And the final thing I want to define this button into my v controller.
So let me open my assistant editor over here OK so that I can bring in this button to my coat and I'm
just going to bring this in as an outlet not as an action.
So make sure you bring this into your real controller OK by clicking and dragging and dropping it but
rather than action just choose outlet and see a change by them.
So we have this outlet over here because later on I'm going to change the color of this button.
OK.
So let me just first test design and see how it looks like in light mode and dark mode.
Let me open my simulator.
And here we go.
I believe we are ready.
So let me just see if this is done let me open my simulator.
Yeah.
Here we go we are still waiting.
Let me minimize the whole project from here so that we can only see the app.
Here you go it when we click on the change button it takes us to the second have controller and saw.
So this is pretty basic.
Let me take this into the DART mode.
So in order to go into the dark mode in Iowa starting you will be able to reach it from the general
settings or imperious settings.
But right now we in the simulator we have it under developer.
OK so if you go to developer you will see these dark periods.
If you cannot find it for some reason you can always search for it.
Right.
So let me close this down and no I don't want this as well.
So let me come over here.
A few swipe to the left one more time you can have this search bar and over here you can write dark
ads will give you dark periods of course you can search for dark experience as well and you will see
the related menu.
So when you click on that it will take you to the same developer menu.
And here you go.
Once I enable it now my app and my phone is actually in the dark experience mode.
Now I see the black background rather than this white background.
Right.
And I see texts in white rather than black.
Now let me go to my app and here you go.
My app is changed there as well because it affects all the apps and all the phone related menus and
everything inside of our phone.
Now I see the labels in white.
OK.
So this is cool right.
And it also adjusts itself actually.
So if you're working with black it will turn it to white automatically but you have to be sure that
this is working for example in this button.
It's shown in blue and I believe this is the default behavior.
But for some reason you may want to change this right.
Maybe you may want to maybe you want to actually show this in white rather than blue van user chooses
dark modes.
So we have to find a way to understand if the user is using their phone in the dark mode or light mode.
So is there a way to do that.
Of course there is a way to do that.
We're going to test to see we're going to check to see if the user has chosen this style in their phone
so that we can change what they were.
We want of course this is not mandatory.
Maybe we are satisfied with the current look current behavior but if you're not satisfied if you want
to customize.
Now we would have to know how to do that how to reach that variable that use the user is using their
phone in the dark moat.
So it's called trade collection.
So as you can see this is UI trade collection.
And this gives us the trade such as size class or scale factor.
So they generally describe the current environment.
So if you want to get something out of current environment then you're going to use this trade collection.
And if you say trade collection OK and if you scroll down a little bit you will see something called
User Interface style.
So there are some other aspects as well but you're not looking for a user interface idiom or level but
we're interested in the user interface style.
So if you double click on that that's what you want to get.
So let me as scientists do a variable and then you're going to see this is exactly the thing that we're
looking for.
So I'm going to called is user interface style.
OK.
And if you check if user interface style OK with a double A equals sign if you say dot you will get
either dark or lights or you can get the unspecified as well.
But most of the time it will be either dark or light.
So we are particularly interested in dark right now.
So if user is using their form in dark mode maybe I want to show the change button in white color rather
than blue.
So how do I do that.
It's pretty easy actually I already have defined this button as an outlet in my code right.
Then all I have to do is change the color of this button.
So if you say change button that color and you have to say tint color in order to reach the title color.
OK.
So you have to go for 10th color and you can just say you eye color dot White for example.
Now this will just make this into white when the user is using their phone in dark mode.
Of course you can just say the aisles as well.
You can see a change button that tint color you light colored dots blue.
So if the user is using their phone in dark mode then just do this button invite if this is not the
case then go for blue.
So here you go.
Now I how the White Bardin over here so text didn't change it was already in white.
But now my button has change.
So let me come over to the settings and try to make this into light mode.
So once I do that it should turn into the light mode.
But here you go.
It didn't turn.
Now I see my button in white and I can't even see it.
So button is over there actually in the center.
But since I did that we did load hasn't been cold and I wasn't able to change the button into the blue
tint color.
So if I tried to click on the button right now it would click actually.
So let me try it.
And here we go.
I can't click on it but I cannot see it because it's in white.
So it's kind of not what I'm looking for.
Right.
So I want to be able to run this code whenever I see the screen.
Maybe you would think that.
Yeah let's do that in view will appear and it would work.
Yates can work.
Let's try that.
Let's go to we will appear.
OK.
And as you can see if I run this one more time it will display those in blue because we have the load
gets cold.
When I run this from scratch.
But we have to do it in a consistent way.
So let me cut everything from here and paste under the we will appear as he or what's going on.
Yeah I couldn't do that.
So let me try it one more time.
Here you go.
Now let me run this one more time and see if we can get this.
Yeah.
We have the white.
Now we have the blue button and it's exactly what we wanted.
But if I change this and if I come over here it didn't change.
So we will appear hasn't been called.
So if I go over here and come back it will change into white but I wasn't cold in the first time I came
back from settings.
So maybe it can be a rare occasion that a user will change its periods while using our app.
But even so we have to figure out a better way to handle this situation.
So that many user changes the style then we will adapt our app to that style if we want to.
So how do we do that.
We're going to see how to do that in the next lecture.