Hi.
We didn't this lecture.
We going to see how to create customized keyboards.
So as you know when user taps on a text field in our app they get to see a keyboard.
And this is automatically shown by iPhone itself but we can actually customize this keyboard and we
can create a new keyboard that that can user use and we are going to see how to do that in this lecture
in order to do that.
I'm going to go for irregular single view app.
OK.
Later on we're going to add an extension for a keyboard.
So in here for product name I'm going to go for hardcore keyboard.
OK so let's just uncheck all of these like Swift UI core data and maybe you know what what their hardware
is or who Holder is actually if you watch Game of Thrones.
So this is a character from the popular TV series Game of Thrones.
OK.
And you're going to see why we're choosing this character in a minute.
So let me make this into a full screen and then let me go to my safari to find a holder image.
So let's open safari and let's go to Google.
OK.
And in Google I'm going to go for Ho da.
So this is our character.
OK.
This is the hardcore character from Game of Thrones and the special thing about Hodor is that he can
only say ho da so he can only speak the words of Hodor.
So we're going to insert this image in our keyboard.
So whenever a user taps on this keyboard it will just write her da.
OK.
So we're going to build this keyboard.
So I'm going to download this image in my downloads folder.
You can just choose whatever image you want it doesn't matter as long as it's a PSG or JPEG file.
OK.
Just select that Holder image and not bring in your project.
Right now we're going to do that later on because we're not going to be working on this we have controller
rather we going to add a new extension.
So let me show you how to do that.
We were working with Disney new file before.
OK but now we're going to go for new targets in order to do that.
Let's just choose this option here just general projects setting so the target will be put in the right
place.
So say target from here.
If you come over to this tab you will see we have a lot of extensions in here like we have this kid
contacts we.
We're going to work with this custom keyboard extension.
OK but if you browse is a little bit you will see a lot of extensions here like I message extension.
We have a call directory extension and a notification center.
In fact a secret back extension in fact we going to work some of these later on but we want to start
with custom keyboard extension.
OK.
Because this is a good practice and you have to do a product name to your extension as well like a holder
keyboard or hold or make sure your project and application is selected from here.
And just say yeah I want to activate this after you do that you will see another folder here called
Hard Art.
So this is the keyboard view controller.
So this is where we're going to work on.
So right now I have this hold our keyboard view controller and this defies our keyboard as you can see
hold your extension is now selected to be run on my simulators.
If not you can just choose it from here and choose one of the simulators as well.
Make sure the hardware extension is selected.
OK.
And in fact before we go on and write some code or just explore those codes I want to run this because
it will ask us an application to run on as you can see it asks us which application do you want to run
this on.
So since we're running a keyboard we have to choose an application that needs a keyboard like massages
or you can just choose whatever you want.
Actually I'm going to go with today because after you open this in your simulator it will pop up a screen
like this and you can just close it down there in like a regular phone because we have to go to settings
in order to make sure our keyboard is selected.
So let me show you what I mean let me run this vids something yeah like messages or Safari.
Let's go four so far.
It will bring up the safari but at this moment let's say OK.
And at this moment we cannot see our keyboard.
Let me try.
I tap on this keyboard will open and if it doesn't open for you make sure you go here to hardware and
go to keyboard and say connect heart rate hardware keyboard or just toggle software keyboard.
OK.
And what I'm going to do I'm going to click on the left lower side of this keyboard to change the keyboards
and as you can see we cannot see our custom keyboard here yet we can only see an English keyboard and
I believe at Turkish one is installed here.
So I'm going to close this safari and I'm gonna go for general settings over here.
And if I click on keyboard I will see keyboards.
And that's where I can add my newly created keyboard.
So this is not different than adding a new keyboard to your gerund phone.
OK so as you can see her door is now in the list.
And now if I go back and if I open the Safari or any other application that requires a keyboard if I
click on this.
Here you go.
And we got a crash but I believe this is just an X code bug.
So let me do let me stop this OK and let me do product clean and let me run this one more time with
Safari.
It should be about because we didn't even write any code here so let's make sure this works.
Let's open our simulator it will just being up to safari and it will display a keyboard.
So here you go.
Let me click one more time and this is the custom keyboard that we're working on as you can see there
is nothing in here right now because we haven't written any code yet.
And let me stop this and let me go to keyboard view controller to see what we got here.
So this has.
We did load and this is the same we did load that we used to see in here we do what we have to do on
this keyboard load up.
So we gonna write our hold our code in here as well.
So let's see what else we got here.
As you can see it creates a new button for us.
So it's named the next key button and it should have popped up in our custom keyboard.
So let me check it one more time.
Even though we see the custom keyboard over here we don't see anything as a next keyboard but this world
icon does the same thing.
It lets us to the next keyboard.
So I believe we don't have any problem right now.
And we're going to create our own buttons so we will see if we have any problem displaying any views
at all.
So in here we have a tax will change and it indicates a user's typing or not so text will change.
And this is text did change.
It actually lets us understand if text has been changed.
And as you can see we're doing this change to a proxy here called text document proxy.
And in fact that is what we were going to use to insert the holder text in the tapped place.
OK.
I'm going to show you have to do that.
Don't worry.
So let me write this header so we can understand what we're trying to do.
So I'm going to create my whole door button and this is exactly the same way that we have done before
in the layout section.
So it's going to ask that type if I hit enter and Dot I can just go for system.
OK.
And after the system bottom this is actually a button it's not a fancy thing.
So I have to give a frame.
Remember we have to specify very very it is going to be located what lead in height.
It's going to have.
So you have to just come over here order button dot frame.
It will ask you to create a your erect.
Remember Open parentheses and you have to come here to choose X Y with height.
So this is the x axis of the keyboards and y axis of the keyword.
Okay.
And I'm just going to go for some regular numbers like 100 100.
We can always come back and choose a better one here.
So like like an example I'm going to go for one hundred and fifty.
OK and for why.
Yeah I couldn't write it.
One hundred and fifty for why I'm gonna go for 50 let's say 100 to 100 for we then height as well.
So let me choose these numbers right now because I don't know how it's going to show up later on.
I'm gonna go over here and change this is I want so next thing will be the deep but in the background
image of this button.
Okay.
So if you choose harder button that background image or setback ground image you can set the holder
J pack that we have downloaded from the Internet.
So it asks for a UI image as you can see.
So all you have to do is just come here and take this whole DRP Angie in our Holder folder.
So I'm not placing this under our Holder keyboard app.
I'm just placing this under my extension.
OK.
Make sure you put this in your extension not in your app.
So after that you can come over here and say you I image named OK.
And the name will be HUD or dot BMG.
So far states just hit enter and you can just go for normal here.
So the next thing will be is to tell HUD or button to what we want to do with the holder button.
Right.
So whenever a user taps on the holder button I actually want to display a text.
So I'm gonna go for at Target as you might remember.
Right.
So that's what we do when we try to add an action to our bottom.
So it's going to take it from the south as usual and the action will be a select their function as usual.
OK.
And this event will be touch up inside the event as you might remember.
So when a user types up inside meaning that taps on the button it will get called.
So touch up inside.
OK.
So this is it.
Of course we have to create a new function over here.
So this is going to be our button tap.
So I'm going to call this keyboard or HUD or tap tapped.
OK hold or tapped so open close parentheses and open curly braces.
Right now I'm just going to go for HUD are tapped and we will see if this works or not.
So for selector I'm going to go for HUD or tapped as well.
And finally we have to add this to a review.
So let's go for we at DOD at sub view and the view that we want to add is the holder button itself.
So here you go we have created our Holder button image.
So let's go first how far you one more time and let's see if we can see how hot our image in our customized
keyboard.
So let's change.
And here you go the holder appeared.
So I believe this is not in an ideal size like we have to increase the with a little bit okay or 100
is obviously small for this.
And as you can see when I tap on the holder it says that Holder tap.
So it's working.
Very good.
We have to add a text here rather than printing out.
We're going to see how to do that.
But first let me choose this for like 120 or 140.
OK.
You can play with these numbers as I said before to find your optimal height and weight.
And in the print function I'm going to delete does in the Holder tapped function.
What I want to do is to create a proxy and add this text to wherever user tapped before.
So in order to do that you have to say text document proxy.
So as you can see this is an object that custom keyword is interacting to insert text.
OK.
So we you going to use this text document proxy and you can call this whatever you want.
I'm going to call these tax proxy.
After that you have to make sure you cast this to be a you.
I you I text proxy tax document proxy.
This one.
So you have to cast is as you a tax document proxy.
After that you can search your tax here.
All you have to do is just say tax proxy.
That is are taxed and just choose whatever you want.
So in our case we were going to say hold with capitalized letters of course.
So let me run this one more time and see if we managed to create a customized keyboard.
So here you go.
Let's tap on here to write something and let's find our customized keyboard by clicking over here.
And here you go.
We see the DA.
Yeah.
And the width is better right now as you can see it's perfect.
What I wanted actually say if I tap on this as you can see it's right so.
So I can tap as many as I want.
And it's with the right holder.
As many as we want.
So that's how you create customized keyboard for your apps.
And of course you can work with a lot of different images or a lot of different ladders in here to create
your own custom keyboards and you can make it right whatever you want then user clicks on that.
All you had to do is just create and you win here like this and add this sub view to your original view
and even the selector function.
You can just write whatever you want.
So that's how we create customized keyboards.
So let's stop here and within the next lecture we're going to see how to do sticker packs.