Hi within this lecture re to see how to create seeker packs and by fire.
This is going to be our easiest lecture ever because we're not even going to write any code.
We're just going to see how to create sticker packs so we can actually send them two messages or other
checking applications in our iPhone and this feature is specifically designed for designers about it's
actually beneficial for us to learn about does because it's so easy and convenient.
Just choose sticker pack with you from here.
But you create a new app rather than single you app and I'm going to name this Pokémon sticker app.
OK so we're going to download some Pokémon stickers and we're just going to work with the software you
create this project as you can see this is very simple.
So there is not think it's really all we have the stickers Assad's folders so this is basically we drag
and drop the stickers that we have created and we work with them.
So if you're a designer you can just create your own stickers and you can actually see how those on
the App Store are like.
I message X or a sticker pack.
Okay so people use a message in their daily lives so they are looking for just different kinds of stickers
and stuff every time and make sure I'm going to go for Pokemon stickers said and I'm going to work with
those.
So I'm just doing is a random example.
Make sure that you don't steal some copyrighted image from the Internet.
You have to find one without the royalty shoes or you have to create your own Citigroup packs.
If you wanna put those on AppStore or if you want to put those for sale.
OK so let's find some pokemon stickers here as you can see from the Google.
I just choose a random Web site.
And I'm downloading some Charizard I can here.
So let's go for another one.
So what is this one called Blast choice.
Okay let's go for blasters.
So let me download this a little bit and let me just do one more.
So as you can see we have different sizes here available but I'm doing this just for an example so I'm
going to go for another one and I'm going to go for biggest one of this.
So this is some kind of P.G. ghetto so let me know it's called her I my.
So anyway let me open this folder and I'm going to go for Cherry's art.
OK.
And so this one is blasters I believe.
And this is the Harry Yama.
So after Dad I will choose all of this.
I'm going to bring in this sticker packs and as you can see now we are ready to use those stickers and
that school.
And here you go.
This extension is chosen one more time to run on my simulator.
So when I opened this on my simulator you will see that VK used his own messages app.
So this works perfectly with the messages.
OK.
So if you open one of the messages from here you can click on this message.
And here we see our own secret back.
Like I can come over here choose Cherry's art and send it as a message to Kate.
So this is cool right.
This is all we have to do is to just to create that sticker pack.
And as you can see this is relatively easy.
You can create icons and you can work with the sticker bags if you're a designer.
And remember people really dig this stuff if you come over here you will see some other options as well.
And as you can see they have all icons.
Of course we don't have any one yet because we haven't put any icons in our app but we can see the Pokémon
sticker name actually here and we can just choose and we can add some more so there is this whole list
here.
So we can scroll down if we want.
Right now we only have three so we can only see three.
So this is one of the cool features of ISIS as well.
And it's good to take a break from coding for a while but that's it for right now.
So we're going to stop here and we're going to continue with face recognition in the next lecture.