Hi.
We within this lecture we going to see how to use face recognition in our apps and we're not only going
to see how to use face recognition but if you're working with something like iPhone 7 or iPhone 8 it
will also work on touch I.D. as well.
So I'm going to create a single new app.
I'm going to call this face recognition project.
OK so make sure that you choose swift and you you don't have to choose any of this checkboxes and then
he adds next and create so let's suppose that you're building an app and we want this app to be accessible
by only the owner of this current iPhone.
OK.
So if somebody else is messing with your phone they cannot open it because it can only be accessible
vit the face recognition or touch I.D..
So what we gonna do we're gonna add a sign in button here.
OK.
So let me bring in a button.
So this button will check us for the face recognition or a touch I.D..
And if we can provide this if you can't pass the test then we can go to the second view controller in
which we will have the real app of course.
We're just going to build a second we have controller as an ad as an exemplary controller.
We're not going to have any think fancy going on there but this will give us a great chance to learn
how to utilize facial recognition in our apps.
So I'm going to call this sign in.
OK.
So when a user taps on this app they have to click on the sign in button and make sure that the face
recognition matches with their face and then they can go to the second we controller.
So here we go to have this sign in button and maybe we can have a label as well showing the results
of the face recognition.
So if the result is actually successful it will take us to the secondary controller.
But if it's not it can say something like error try again.
OK so I'm going to have a simple label over here.
So make sure that this label is actually a little bit bigger so that we can write whatever we want here
like an error message and that's it.
That's all we want to do.
In this we have controller.
Right.
And later on we're going to add a second we have controller but before we do that let me come over here
to say reset to suggest its constraints.
So our button and label will have the necessary constraints.
So then open the view controller and drag drag and drop does it clicking on the control as a sign in
clicked.
OK.
So this is going to be our button and for label I'm going to go for my label.
And this will display the error message that I was talking about.
So let me just close this and that's it for the Vive controller.
Now let's go to our Web controller.
So this is where we're going to call for face recognition.
OK.
And after this is successful it will take us to the other we have controllers so we're going to do a
Segway in here.
In fact let's go back to our main story board and put that second view controller as well so that we
can have a Segway here.
So let me just call for a controller and drag drag and drop one here OK.
And in the second we have a controller.
I'm just going to have a label displaying the text of success.
OK.
So that I will know if I made it to the second view controller or not.
So let me come over here to the center of this view controller and I'm just going to call those successful
or assigned then OK.
And let me give the suggested constraints here as well.
I'm going to do a Segway from this one to this one.
This is going to be a show Segway.
And for identifier I'm just going to go for two seconds we see and in this stage I'm not even going
to add a second set Coco to each class like a V controller file because we're not going to do anything
in the second controller.
OK.
And of course if this was a real app I could have I should have added the controller and connected with
the second wave controller.
But you already know how to do that so I'm going to pass on that one.
So in the sign in clicked all I want to do is just call a local authentication.
So I have to import that library first.
And let me do a comment B.
I believe it's not seeing what it's supposed to see right now.
So let me do a product clean as well so let me come over here and say import local authentication.
So it has to be something like this but since it's not working I'm not going to take any this.
So if you come across in a situation like this just close the project and then go over your project
folder from here like face your cognition project and then open it one more time and I'm going to delete
this and write it one more time.
And as you can see it says indexing so I believe there was something on synchronized at the time.
So if I write local authentication it look it sees the module right now.
So I can call does local authentication from here.
I'm going to create a local authentication context so I'm going to call this off contacts and it's going
to be an L.A. context object.
So this a context comes from does local authentication library.
And this is a mechanism that lets us control the authentication process.
So far so good.
First we have to check if this iPhone or iPad is capable of performing this action.
So I'm going to go for out old contacts that can evaluate policy.
OK so this will tell us if the iPhone is capable of running facial recognition or touch I.D. and the
policy that I'm looking for if you hit that over here you will see device owner authentication with
biometrics and biometrics meaning facial recognition or a touch I.D..
OK.
So are we going to authenticate using biometrics so this method will give us either this has the capability
of not and this asks for an endless error pointer so we cannot simply come over here and hit enter and
just write an error.
So this is a spatial type and it requires us to create an NSA error object in order to do that.
I'm going to go over here.
Save our error.
And this is going to be an NSA error type.
OK.
This one.
And of course this is going to be optional at this time because we didn't even initialize it.
And then here I'm going to go for error.
And in order to make this a pointer I have to say and in front of this error because it will give me
a warning as you can see it says that I cannot convert this and this error type to be an this error
pointer in order to do that.
You can just type in and signing here.
So this will be it.
This method will give us whether this is working with face recognition or touch I.D. or if the device
is not even capable of performing this we're not going to do anything in here.
OK.
So after reading this if we can actually evaluate the policy itself so evaluating means calling this
for an action.
So it will check to see if we can parse for face recognition.
So in order to do that I'm going to say of context that evaluate policy rather than can evaluate policy
this time.
And this will ask me for the same thing one more time so it's asking me for the policy itself and the
policy will be the same thing.
If you hit that you can't choose the device or another authentication with biometrics.
And we are going to have to give a localized reason here.
Something like yeah I'm going to check your face in order to authenticate you.
OK.
So I'm just going to say is it you.
So this will be our reason localized reason.
And here it will give us a reply.
So if you hit enter on that reply you will see two variables.
You either get a boolean or an error.
So you can just write error in here and you can write something like success in here because the first
variable will give you if this is going to be working or not.
And if you come across any error this error will be stored in the error variable.
So this is called a closure.
OK.
And I'm going to call.
I'm going to check to see if success is true it means that we passed the test.
So successful authentication and ls it means that I didn't pass the test.
So I'm just going to go for print error or better yet I'm just going to say my labeled up tax is error.
So again this is called closure which means that we're doing some operation and in return we are getting
some responses.
And since we are in the closure we have to say s drop my label that taxed and in here I'm going to say
some of the perform Segway and the Segway identifier will be two seconds we V.C. and sun there will
be Neil.
So that's it for evaluating the authentication policy.
So what we did here we check to see if we can actually use this method in the current form that we're
using and if we can we just said that yeah I'm going to go ahead and do that.
I'm going to check for device owner authentication with biometrics.
And if this gives us a success then I'm going to do a perform Segway.
So before we test out you have to come into the info P list and hit a plus button to add a new row.
I remember we have worked with this privacy descriptions before.
So we're going to do the same thing as well.
So we are looking for face I.D. usage description under privacy.
OK so you have to give a good result here like to authenticate to you have to do this to go in or something
like that.
So after you do this let's go to we've controller and we can actually test is right now and this will
give us an error.
I'm gonna show you why.
But before we do that let's test is and see the error by ourselves.
So I'm going to run this on our simulator and simulators at right now actually lets us simulate the
face recognition as well.
So this is great.
We didn't have that capability before.
So in here the hardware face I.D. make sure that these enrolled is selected OK if you select as we can
test it to face I.D. reads our app.
So when you click on this it will ask you for your face I.D. And in order to simulate the face I.D.
you can come over here as a matching face or none matching face.
So matching face means that this actually matches.
And here we go.
We have the error that I was talking about.
So let's see what the error is if we come back to our Controller.
We see some kind of a purple message that we haven't seen before.
So if you click on this it says that this performs say good thing should be called from the main thread
on the.
So remember we had talked a little bit about threads before so if we're doing something that should
be run in the background in order not to block the user interface.
Let me come over here and see the documentation as well.
And we have done this with countdown timer so we run this on the background track.
Remember.
And in here these authentication method is running on the background is being run on the background
automatically.
But since we want to change the label or since we want to go to power from Segway we should do that
in a main thread rather than background thread or as this can or will actually crash as we have seen
in here.
So we have to make sure that the stuff that performs Segway or this soft out my labeled a tax should
be run on the main threat rather than background track.
But as I said before these old contacts is being run on the background track.
So is there any method to make sure that d if control after if control we go to the main track.
Yes actually there is a way to do that and it gives us as a documentation here.
So it gives us an example to use our in our code like this.
So a few say s that labeled a taxi it will give you an error.
So you have to come over here as say dispatch.
Q That's mean that I async so it will run on this on the main track is seen erroneously.
OK.
So rather than calling these on the background track I'm going to call his own the main tracks and in
order to do that I'm going to use to dispatch Q and As you can cedes to actually let us go back and
forth between treads and this is where we choose the main or background tracks.
So I'm going to do this as synchrony Asli on the main tracks and here we go.
This is all we wanted to do and we have to do this for the label as well.
So dispatch 2 that's main that N Sync.
And let me cut this and paste it inside this coding block so that's all that's all I wanted to do.
So right now if I click on this a run by then again I will see Bill late.
This face recognition one more time.
So here don't sign in.
Let's come over here to hardware as a matching face.
And as you can see now you're signed in.
We have seen the second wave controller so this works great.
So let's go back and do this one more do this one more time and this time I'm going to go for my matching
phase.
And here you go.
We have this error message that is automatically created for us by the face I.D..
And as you can see we see the error label as well.
So everything seems to be working.
And that's how we leverage.
That's how we utilize face recognition in our apps.
So let's stop here and within the next lecture we're going to see what a gift is.