Hi within this lecture we going to see what a Jason is and how we can use this Jason in order to process
this data and show this to the user.
So let me go to Google and search for Jason.
So as you can see it has its own Web site.
So this is Jason that's arc.
And this actually stands for JavaScript object notation.
So this is kind of a way to display data.
OK.
This is a format.
This is standard format in order to display data.
So in order to have an object the notation standard and it kind of looks like this but we're going to
see the real Jason data in a minute.
So let me go down here.
You will see a lot of programming languages.
So we don't use Jason only in Swifts only in IOW development.
So as you can see a lot of programming languages have some libraries that converge with Jason format.
So this is kind of a standard format centered Object Notation that we can use in a lot of programs in
a lot of software using in a lot of programming languages in lots of platforms as well so that we can
easily use this easily.
Corporate this to any data that we may want to display to the user.
OK.
So I'm going to go back to my fixer that I owe and I'm going to show you how our data will look like
in real example.
And you have to sign up for it.
So as you can see we have somebody over here saying that get free API key and after you sign up of course
you can log in.
But right now I'm going to show you how to create an account.
OK.
So when you click on here you have to choose free plan.
And then you choose your free plan as you can see it asks for an e-mail and the password and other details
as well so provide your e-mail password provide your mail address and the postal code and the city and
the country and of to clicking these buttons clicking these checkboxes actually you can just say sign
up and create your account.
I'm not going to do that because I already have an account.
I'm going to be logging in instead.
So if I say sign in it will bring me a dashboard like this.
So when you sign up it will bring your dashboard like this.
And in here this is called Control Panel dashboard.
And we have our own API access key.
So this is kind of important.
We're going to use this in order to get data.
If you see an empty string in here or a like an empty box.
You can always click or reset to get one of these API access keys.
OK.
So this is our dashboard and we have a small menu in here like you can upgrade your account.
You can just choose a subscription plan.
You can change your details from your account page and everything OK.
But right now we're interested in this quick start guide or documentation.
So if you click one of these like documentation it will take you through a web page in which you can
find the details of this API.
And of course I'm going to show you how to work with this but you will need this.
You're out.
OK.
As you can see this is the URL that we want to go if we want to get the data and then we get the data
like here in the API response.
We're going to be seeing adjacent data.
So this is how it looks like.
So this is kind of adjacent format and here as you can see we have different values and it looks like
some key value pairings in there right.
Right.
So this is kind of key and this is value.
So this is key.
This is value.
And as you can see we got the boolean we got an integer we got string we got a string again and we got
an error.
So we have some various values inside of a string to any dictionary in here as you can see.
And we're going to use that information later on.
So it's important to understand your Jason format.
It's important to understand what your data will look like once you get it and this is the response
this is going to be our response from this web page.
But before we get this response We have to create a request.
So in here in this section you're going to learn a lot of new things a lot of new codes a lot of new
techniques.
Remember that we're trying to get this response and in order to get this response We have to create
a request.
We have to go to a new URL to reach that data and the URL is written in here.
If you copy and paste this into your browser.
OK.
This is the data that I'm copying right now.
If I paste this over here it will ask me for my api key before providing that API key make sure you
delete the spaces between these words.
OK.
You don't want a space in here in order not to get any error and then delete does API key and replace
it with your own API key.
So let me go back and copy mine from here OK and let me delete.
Does API key and paste my own API key in here.
And as you can see we get as a result in here.
OK.
So this is what we are looking for.
So these are the exact steps that we are going to replicate in our own app.
So we're going to go into this you're all using of course programmatic way so we're going to create
a request inside of our app.
The app will go here.
It will go to does your URL and app will get this data and display it for us of course after getting
this data we have to process it so that we can be ready to display to the user.
But right now you know the exact steps that we're going to do so let's stop here and within the next
lecture we're going to create our project and start working on it.