Hi.
We within this lecture regrouping to create our project from here of course and we're going to create
our user interface.
So let me go with single view app as usual.
OK.
And let's uncheck this swift you I think and I'm going to call this currency converter.
So that's what you're going to do.
So let me hit on next and put my folder in my regular IRS complete folder.
Ok.
And of course we're going to start with creating our user interface.
But before we do that we have to decide what Carolyn sees that we want to show to the user.
We have to choose some currencies right.
We cannot show one hundred and seventy of them.
It will be a waste of time for us because we're just trying to build an exemplary app like we can just
show five or six currencies to the users so that we can on their sent have to work with API and Jason
us.
So let me go to main story Bert first and let me show you how this is going to work out.
So in here we have all this data.
OK then we have to understand what we are getting in here so that we can actually decide what to show
what to display to the user.
And I'm going to copy all of this data from here.
I'm going to displayed in a better way.
So if you go to Google and if you search for Jason beautify here like this.
OK.
And in fact you can just say J some beat file your own line.
This will give us a lot of options to be to FI Our Jason format.
So you can go for the first one or the second one.
I believe I have used this one before.
So this is called B to fight that's OK.
You can paste this value in here you can copy this and you can just pacing here and you can just click
on this beautify button in order to be to fly this Jason format.
So if you click on this as you can see now we have a very structured look.
So this gives me all these information.
OK.
So this is how Jason format is supposed to be shown.
So let me see what we get in our data.
So it gives me whether this is a success or not since we are getting the data.
As you can see success is true.
So you can use this value in order to understand if you're getting the data or not.
Maybe if the success is false then you can just show some Alec message to the user saying that yes there
was something wrong.
So in here we have the time stamp indicating where this is then this is actually requested and the base
currency is euro and the date is these six of the August in 2019 and in here we just seeing the relative
value to these crises to the euro.
For example if you come over here you will see the euro and it's 1 because euro over euro is one.
If you come down like a GBP.
This is great Britain pounds.
As you can see one Euro Q equals two all ninety two pounds.
And then here we have the USD one euro equals to one point eleven and we have some Turkish lira like
one euro equals to six Turkish lira us.
Are we going to choose some of this they tells you you're going to choose the currencies that we want
to work with every going to display them to the user.
I'm going to only work with the right.
I'm going to only display the currencies to the user.
But maybe you may want to get the date you may want to get the other values and you show them to the
user as well later on for right now you can just follow along with me and try to understand what's going
on in here.
OK.
So I'm going to create a label over here I'm just going to Chrome called his currency converter so that
we can have a title for our app.
OK.
This is going to be our title.
And let me make this a little bit bigger and put it over here and I'm going to bring in some more of
these labels because if you're going to be displaying all those values in the labels right.
For example if we're going to display the value of the USD we're going to do that using a label.
So we have to choose what we're going to display in here.
For example if we go back to our data we have this C.D. and it stands for Canadian dollars I believe.
So anyway I'm going to use it.
So let me just say S.A.T. and make this a little bigger.
OK then you can just copy and paste this by comment see and comment V.
OK and bring this here so that I can name this something else.
Let me see.
Yep.
This is Swiss franc.
So C H F Ok I'm going to go for CHF and let me copy and paste.
One more time if I can do it.
Yep.
Finally let me bring it over here.
And this time let's go for GBP.
So this is pounds sterling.
So that's cool.
Let me copy and paste one more time and in here I'm going to choose JP Vi.
So this is Japanese yen.
Okay.
And of course we're going to have to go with the USD anyway because this is one of the most comments.
And for final thing I'm going to go for Turkish lira.
So this is t r VI so that's good right.
We're going to display the six yes six of these currencies to the user and I believe that's enough in
order for us to understand what's going on in this app right.
Finally I'm going to bring in a button and this button will get me the rates does buy them will download
me the data.
So of course we can do all of these things in under like we did load or another function as well as
I'm going to do this with the bottom.
OK.
So that we can just call this whenever we want.
And let me reset to suggest that constraints.
And here you go.
I believe we have our constraints now.
I can bring this bring those labels in.
So let me open my assistant editor and let me start with S.A.T..
So this is Canadian dollars and I'm going to control dragged that here and I'm going to call the S.A.T.
label.
OK.
Let's next thing here is C H S label OK.
Does a Swiss franc.
So let me go over here and let's bring in the pound.
So this is GBP label.
Yep.
This is Japanese yen so JPY label and the USD label.
See why I have chosen six rather than 100 for example.
So it's going to take a little time so this is going to be t r y labels.
So that's good little thing to do is to bring in the bottom is an action.
So let me tidy up here a little bit and the final thing is to drag and drop this button as an action
and I'm going to call does get rates clicked.
So here you go our user interface is actually ready.
So I believe we can stop here within the next lecture we're going to start writing our first codes in
order to create these requests.