Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to see how we can connect this firebase project with our X gold project.
Okay.
In order to do that I'm gonna go for IRS here.
By the way they can't change these images.
They can change the layouts from here and you're just going to have to find the U.S. icon and click
on it.
That's all you have to do.
Okay.
And after that it will ask you for your IRS bundle I.D..
So this is the bundle idea of the project that you want to contact your file your base.
Okay.
So this is going to register our app and it asks for a unique I.D. like a bundle I.D. in order to connect
the two projects together.
So remember if you click on this you can see your bundle identifier and you can copy it and then paste
it here so that it will be registered to your bundle I.D..
So if you want you can give it you these app a nickname.
So I'm gonna go for D instead cologne firebase one more time and it's optional you don't have to do
that.
And later on it will ask for an app store I.D..
Since we haven't put our project in the App Store yet we can just skip this and say registered.
Yep.
So this will be registered and then it will create a configuration file for us.
So now you'll see the configuration file and this is called a Google service info that piece lists all
we have to do is just downloading this file and add this to our project.
OK.
So let me click on here.
Download Google's service info dot P lists.
And if there is any bug or something if this doesn't work you can't always come back later on to download
it from the settings of your project.
OK so let me drag and drop in here and make sure that you drag and drop inside of your insta glowing
file your base folder and make sure that this copy items if needed.
And Target is selected and you can just click on finished to import this file as you can see if you
click on it.
We have some credentials here and we have some API keys client I.D. and other some important stuff in
order to connect our service connect our firebase server so these values are actually just for us.
Derek created uniquely for our project.
So if you don't have this Google service that info or if you have a bad Google service that info file
your app won't connect to defy your base.
So make sure you do this step and then later on you have to add firebase SDK case.
So there is a guide to do that.
OK.
So I'm going to click on that guide and it will take me back to our dashboard.
So in here in the documentation we're going to how to find how to download how to integrate file based
software development kits to our X code project.
And as you can see their documentation for IRS Android flatter and lap.
So we're going to go for IRS obviously and we have a very good documentation here later on we're going
to see the cloud fire sir authentication storage and they're explaining everything we need to know actually.
In fact you could have just come over here and try to understand everything by reading from this documentation.
But don't worry I'm going to explain everything.
So right now we have to come up with a way to integrate SDK case.
If you follow here you you will see some steps like a project register your app you have already done
this right.
We have created an X code project.
We have registered our app using our bundle app I.D. And we even have integrated this config file.
The step forward would be to add the file your base the case.
So that's what we're looking for.
So let's see how it's done.
As you can see there are steps in here as well.
And it asks us to create something called part file and it says that you have to run this comment part
in it.
So what is a part.
So it's kind of a tool.
It's kind of a technology that lets us integrate this kind of SD case external libraries into our code.
So whenever we deal with this kind of external libraries the code that is written by other people that
we want to integrate in our project we are going to use parts and in order to do that we are going to
learn something called Cocoa pots.
It's a tool to utilize pores easily because we had to have this in our computer in order to work with
parts so that we can easily integrate every project in our own project.
And this is not only valid for a fire base as well.
We are going to use this a lot in other libraries from now on.
So we have to just deal with this part and then we have to call this bomb line like fire firebase app
that configure and I'm showing you all this documentation.
I can easily come and do this by on my own I show you how it's done but I suggest you follow the documentation
as well so that you get the habit of following documentation because you're going to be working with
other libraries later on when you're in AoS developer than but we have seen in the course.
So here we have something called Coco Pops as I say.
So the web address is Cocoa Puffs dot arc.
If you come to this website you will see how to install cocoa pods on your computer on your Mac OS.
So here we see our comments.
And remember we have used terminal before.
So that's what we're going to use in this lecture as well.
We're going to use terminal to run this install cocoa pods comment and we're going to use terminal to
initialize pods and integrate everything.
So make sure you close your X code project because we will be integrating some new files to it and then
search for terminal as we have done before.
All you have to do is just press command and space on your keyboard on his terminal.
And we have seen how to use this terminal right in the get section.
So if you have skipped it I really suggest you go back and watch it so that you know how to work with
terminal.
But I'm going to explain the basics one more time in case you missed it and if you don't want to go
back and but I'm going to do this fast.
OK so this is a terminal and if you write a command here like clear it gets executed it's as long as
it makes sense of course.
And either need to work in order to make this cocoa pods work in our computer we have to download it.
And it asks us to run this comment pseudo GAM is still cocoa pots if you write these and hit enter it
will download the cocoa pods for you.
It will ask you for your password.
This is your Mac password.
You type it and it will show as if it's not writing but it's for security.
If you write it and hit enter it will accept it and it will just start downloading the cocoa bots in
your computer.
So this is kind of going fast for me but it was already installed on my computer so I believe it's just
get it just got updated.
Maybe it will take a little me time for you and this come out goes like this pseudo gaming stole cocoa
pods and this is the comment that we use actually to install repositories in our mac.
Like if we if I want to add something else I could either say pseudo game install something else.
OK.
Since now we have the cocoa pods we can actually initialize the pod file and download the file your
base as the case to our computer.
So let me clear the screen and go back to our firebase documentation OK.
We're down with the cocoa pods right now.
It says that you have to see in your project directory and what is a seed.
We have seen it before.
It stands for change directory so we can go from one directory to another and we can see the content
of that folder and we can initialize a pod and we can write whatever we want inside of that pod and
then we can run this pod install command to install these pods in our current folder.
So let's do that.
Remember if we run unless or C.D. we can go back and forth between the folders and file system for example
if I write that.
It will show me the available content inside of that folder.
For example I want to go to downloads folder because that's via my I s complete folder is.
So I'm going to write CDE downloads and now I mean site to download so now wi fi say unless I will just
see the downloads contents and remember if you want to go to desktop for instance you have to write
desktop that capitalized D as you see in here.
So if I say unless if I open my downloads you will see this contents.
As you can see if I open my downloads folder These are the real contents that I see my downloads folder.
So I want to go to these IOW complete folders so if I write IRS and hit tab it will auto complete it
for me because for spaces we have some kind of extra spatial syntax in here as a reverse slash I can
just hit tab I need to load to complete it for me.
Now I'm inside of IO is complete.
Now if I say unless I will see all of these files and folders but I just want to go to insta clone firebase.
If I write ins and a tablet follow to complete it for me.
And now I clicked here.
I mean side of this folder and this is where I want to actually you run this pod in its combatants.
And remember we have to say pod in it.
It will initialize a pod File for us so that we can edit this file and we can download whatever we want.
So if you run this part in it then let me go back to here one more time.
Let me go back to Io complete the clone firebase.
Now as you can see we have the pod files.
OK.
We can actually open this file right now and edit it in a way that we want in order to do that.
I'm going to right click and say open with texted said it.
OK.
So this is our default pod files.
So let me zoom in a little bit so we can see better.
OK so let me make this a little bit bigger.
Yes.
This is what we want to use frameworks line hit some entries.
So we will have some place that is very I want to copy and paste the SDK names pod names so here for
example it asks us to import firebase analytics.
I'm going to copy and paste it in here.
So whatever I want to download I'm going to paste in this pod file and this is not the only module that
I want to go ahead and get why.
Because firebase actually provides modules you know separate parts.
For example we will have a pod for fires stored for storage for authentication.
Vi will de do that.
Why does it even bother to provide us with different pots.
Because maybe we're going to use only authentication feature or firebase in our app.
We're not going to use the fi your store.
We're not going to use storage so we don't want to make our app too big.
So that's in a very logical way.
They just provide us with different parts so that we can get whatever we want.
We shouldn't get everything in the fire base in order to limit our AB size.
So if you go to authentication and I guess you can say get started or you can just click on the first
line here and you're going to find the necessary parts in order to integrate firebase authentication
in our project.
We have already got analytics.
So I'm going to go for old and in the five years store as well if you come over here to introduction
and get started and not a real time database by the way we're going to go for five years sir.
And I'm Max I'm going to explain the difference between them.
But for right now just know that fire stories never so far your store is the how technology available
real time data bases old new.
So we're going to go for five years sir.
So let me copy these parts and paces in my project here.
So we're downloading car and fire sir.
And then the last thing that we want to get is this storage.
OK.
So let's click on get started and see if we can get this.
Yes we already have analytics.
So I'm going to go for a storage and that's it.
That's all I want to get.
Firebase analytics old car fires storage storage.
So let me causes after saving.
OK so let me go back to my original documentation here by clicking on the back button so let me hit
tab.
Yeah.
So this is what we want to run next.
So we have to run.
Party installed make sure that you save and close the party file.
Make sure your ex code is closed and right party install and hit enter.
So this will download these dependencies DNC case one by one and we will need to do that just once.
By the way we're going to do that once and then we can go back to our ex growth project so that we can
work on that every time you open the project.
And this is going to take some time by the way because firebase is big and we're going to be downloading
five modules.
So feel free to pause the video and come back when you're done.
So when you download a dependency for the first time it will show its line in green.
So as you can see we're seeing this in green and we're seeing the others in green when they're done.
So we are seeing everything in green.
If I run poly install one more time they will be all in black.
Okay.
So these are all integrated in my ex called Project right now we are done that those terminals so I'm
going to close this and I'm going to come back to my I guess folder so in instead closed file your base
here.
Now we have two files.
These are going to use this workspace rather than the X code project.
So what are what is the difference between those two.
So X workspace actually contains both the project and the parts.
So make sure you open the workspace.
If you open the project from now on it won't work.
So make sure you select the right files so we won't have a problem in here.
So let me make this into a full screen so that we can see what's in in the left hand pane as you can
see we still have the view controller and the old files that we used to have a right time.
But we also have the pause here and as well.
So if you open this frameworks if you open the files and folders you're going to see this.
These are the files.
These are the firebase project that we have downloaded so we can use it in our app so that's all for
integrating fire base in our app.
We're going to have to do a little bit of configuration.
We're going to do it in the next lecture.