Hi.
We didn't this lecture regrowing to see how we can sign the previously created users in and how we can
log them out so that we can complete the authentication process.
So in here rather than doing just a Segway I'm going to delete here and we're going to use this oath
again in order to sign the users in.
So let me just start by typing out.
And of course we can check to see if email dot tags is not an empty string again because if they're
actually empty strings we don't just want to send a request to the server we just want to display an
alert message to the user as usual.
So let's say that password tax dot tax is not an empty string then I'm going to do my thing and else
I'm going to display a message to my users saying that this error username and password.
OK.
So in here I'm going to use the fourth class from the fire your base one more time so I'm going to say
off that's all.
OK.
So I'm creating the instance again and rather than saying create user I'm going to say not to log in
but sign in.
OK.
If you write sign you will see a sign out and you will see a sign in and we're interested in that.
So sign in with email password.
And of course a completion block.
So this is exactly what we're looking for we're just going to provide an email and then a password.
So the email will come from email text not taxed.
OK.
And you can just force unwrap this and for Password Password taxed dot tax you can force our up does
as well.
And in the completion block if you hit enter it will give you data.
OK.
So all theta and error.
So if you say error is not nil if error is not nil.
We're going to display an alert message one more time.
So I'm going to copy and paste this s dot make Ellar think in here it will get this error from this
error this time.
So it gets reflected over here OK.
And if it's not nil it means that if it's nil actually it means that we're good to go.
So we can perform a Segway.
So we are doing the same thing basically but rather than creating the user we're just signing them in.
And this is a very cool feature because it's actually checks the password of the user.
So if we give the wrong password it displays the alert message for us.
So let's test that leads alerted Metallica dot com we don't have that user right now.
So rather than saying sign up if I say sign in as you can see we get this error message it says that
there is no user.
So.
So that's good right.
We know what we're dealing with in here so we get this cool error messages from firebase.
Let's do it with James but I'm giving wrong passwords one more time and as you can see it says that
password is invalid.
So let's do James with the real passwords One two three four five six.
And if I click on sign in here you go.
I'm signed in and it took me to the feet.
So it's going good.
We have created the user we manage sign in process all tanks due to firebase.
We tried that with the regular server without any back and support.
We will have to write tons of code in order to make this happen.
And thanks to the free rays we did it with a stamp over a finger.
OK.
So we are now inside of our feed we've controller.
But the thing is if I close these app and open it one more time it will ask me to give my credentials
again.
So this is not we want.
We want to remember if user has checked in signed in or not.
So every time I open the app I just don't want to give my credentials right.
Because nobody will use my app if I asked them.
So we have to come up with a way to solve this problem.
And in fact firebase has this capability to check if a user has signed in or signed out before.
So in the We've did loads in my weave controller I'm going to show you how to do that.
So we're going to use off again.
And if you say of that of that current user.
OK.
This one the current user.
It gives you an optional user as you can see.
And if this is nil it means that nobody has signed in.
If this is not snail it means that somebody has signed in before.
So if you sign this to a variable and if you check to see if current user is not nailed it means that
there is somebody already signed in before.
So I'm going to say if current user is not now then it means that I have a user and I can try to do
a Segway from this view controller to feed controller for example.
And this is what we did before actually when I run this you will see that this won't even work but I'm
going to show you anyway because if you google it if you Google have to remember user in the firebase
IOW Swift you will get this code.
But but in fact this is not what you're looking for.
So let me just sign in one more time James at Metallica dot com and let's say sign and it will sign
me in.
But if I run this from the scratch it should have taken me to feed the view controller anyway because
we have signed in before.
But even though I try again as you can see I cannot go to the feed controller.
So that's not the way that we want to execute this code.
We want to get this code and execute that in the scene delegate.
So far we haven't seen scene delegate yet and this is a great opportunity for us to learn how to do
stuff in the scene delegate as well.
So what I'm going to do I'm going to cut all of this from the weave controller.
OK very not going to check this in the weave controllers so let me select everything and hit command
X and let's go to scene delegate.
So we want to do it in here because we have a variable called window in this scene delegate.
OK.
Before we have this in the app delegates now we have this in the scene delegate so is seen delegate
we are going to do this check.
And if you have this window in app delegate for any reason I don't know maybe you're using an early
version of X code.
Now you have to do this inside of Abdullah.
But after U.S. star 13 there is a scene delegate.
And in this scene there is a function called I will connect to session and that's very we can change
this scene.
That's where we can change the window and by window I mean we're going to change the route we've controller.
As you can see if we change this entry point it defines which we've controller is going to be shown
first when we actually start this app and we're going to take this arrow to the tab bar controller if
and only if a user has signed in before.
OK.
We're going to do this program ethically.
We're going to do this within codes and in order to do that I have to come to tab our controller and
in the storyboard I.D. I have to give it an I.D. like tab bar and I'm going to use that tab bar in here.
OK.
So let me paste this here and of course this will give me an error because we cannot do a Segway from
here right because we're not in the view controller.
We're just in the scene delegate now and we are just going to check to see if current user is not.
No.
And in order to check this make sure that firebase is actually imported in the scene delegates.
If it's not you have to add it yourself like import Firebase and then it's going to be like this.
I'm going to check if the current user is not Bill and if it's not Neil I'm learning to change the root
of controller I'm going to move that arrow to the tab bar controller in order to do that I'm going to
create a board variable in which I will create my UI storyboard.
So what's the name of my storyboard.
Its main.
With a capital A capital M K and the bundle is nil and this is my storyboard actually so I can create
a view controller using that storyboard.
I'm going to call this tab bar.
I'm going to say bored dot instantiate v controller.
So here you go.
We have this option.
Instantiate view controller with identifier so we how created the identifiers for tab bar right.
So if you read the description we can create.
We can represent its view controller using that instantiate you controller.
I remember we had to cast as as UI tab bar controller because our tab our controller doesn't have any
class it's just a UI tab bar controller.
For example if I tried to assign my settings view controller as a variable here I had to I would then
have to cast as as settings controller bots right now in class I don't have anything so I'm just gonna
cast is as UI tab bar controller so remember if you're dealing with a specific class then you have to
cast this as a specific class.
Then I'm going to come over here and say window data route where you controller and this is tab bar
and this is exactly where I take the arrow and put it inside of my in front of my actually tab bar and
we're doing this only and only if the current user is not now.
So let me open this and try and as you can see we're in the feed we have controller we haven't got to
see the sign and we have controller ads all because we have already signed in before now we had to find
a way to log out so that we can test if this works or not.
And in the settings are you controller you're just performing a Segway.
But this is actually wrong right now because we have to sign out.
We had to let firebase know that we have signed out so I'm going to impart firebase in here as well
and I'm going to delete this because first we need to sign out then we're going to perform this.
So I'm going to call all that all that sign out and as you can see throws an error.
So what do we do.
We get and chose syntax in here.
We have to use do try catch structure if you remember we have to say do try.
What are we going to try.
We're going to try out that old Dot sign out and we're going to catch the error if there is any.
And for right now I can just do a print error.
OK and.
And then actually I can do perform say great thing in here and there are two ways to do that.
The complex ways to go to the scene delegates and call the function that we have written before.
In order to check if there is any signs in user and change the view controller route we controller one
more time.
But I'm not going to do that I'm not going to bother just taking all of this I'm putting into a function
and then trying to define this as as seen delegates variable and then try to reach that function.
Yeah they are there.
It's it's an alternative but it's I'm not going to do that because it's going to make this a lot more
complicated than it should be.
Rather after trying this I'm just going to say SDR perform dots s stock perform Segway and the identifier
that I'm looking for is to weave controller and the sender is nil.
So let me go to my main story board and by doing that let me check the Segway name.
Yep.
2 We have controller.
So now I'm certain that this will work.
But let's just test to see because I'm going to go into the field controller once I hit that because
I'm already signed in now I'm going to sign out OK so log out and now we see this sign in.
But in order to make sure we have to run this one more time then we can.
We have to see designing we have a controller now.
Yeah.
Here we go.
We see the signing we have controllers since we don't have any users signed in.
Let's sign in with one of the users.
Okay let's go for James at Metallica dot com and the password is 1 2 3 4 5 6.
Let's sign in and let's run one more time to make sure this is working properly.
Here you go.
Now this is working properly and officially we have completed the authentication module now.
Next thing to do for us to understand how to upload data to the database so that we can retrieve those
information and show them to the user later on.