Hi.
We did this lecture.
We're going to learn how to upload the chosen image from the upload.
We have comptroller to the storage of the fire base.
So far we have created this user interface so that we can go to the gallery and get the image back.
And we have to upload it to the storage and then to the database as well so that we can retrieve those
data and show them to the user.
And remember we use storage to store the media like image like videos and we use database to store the
data like a day commands or who uploaded this picture or do you roll of the stored image every again
and learn how to do that so that we can get those back and display them into the feed of the user.
OK the first thing to learn is actually how to upload the image to the storage so that we can get the
uploaded the euro and save it to the database.
And again like we did in the authentication we have to initialize this storage as well and we're going
to do that in the database.
And we're doing this only for once remember we have to initialize this.
After that we can use it as we want.
We can set up some security rules in the database and storage as well.
At the end of this section we're going to take a deeper look at in the security rules as well.
But for right now we're going to start as in the default mode so that we can write and read data from
the storage.
So if you click on this get started by then you will see the security rules of the cloud search.
So what we have here is defining who can read and who can write to the storage.
And as you can see says that yeah we a low return right.
If only and only if the request is authenticated.
OK.
So if a user gets authentication as in they can sign up and sign.
And so then after they can actually upload data or download data from the search and in fact that's
what we want to make our app more secure.
And we're going to implement in implement this in our database as well.
At the end of this course.
But this is a default behavior for our storage as usual.
So that's what I want.
I wants people to access my surge as long as they are authenticate it so I'm going to hit next.
And next thing it will ask me for to choose a location for my cloud search.
And here you can see we have Europe U.S. Asia North America and other locations.
So it really doesn't matter which you choose you can just access your data in any location you want
but if you're focusing on a U.S. market for example you can choose one of the U.S. market locations
or if you're focusing on Europe in your app if you're targeting Europe users you have to choose Europe
in order to make your storage in order to make your database act faster.
And by the way it won't affect too much maybe you're going to do curries in one seconds if you don't
pay attention to this location.
But if you pay attention maybe it's going to be less than one second.
But I eventually I believe you have to choose your location with careful decisions because you cannot
change this after you choose.
Okay.
Wherever you choose it will be state as your main location for your search and for your database as
well.
So if you're targeting all the world then just choose one of the locations like Europe or U.S. and if
you're focusing on specific location like Asia or U.S. or Europe then choose your related one end of
hits next and it will create your storage for you and this location will be used as a default location
when we initialize database as well.
So they will be synchronized.
And here we go.
We have our storage created.
So far we don't have anything in our storage as you can see we can manually add some folders from here
like if you click on this plus button you can call this media or you can call us images videos whatever
you want You may not choose to create any folder like this at all but I'm going to create a media folder
and I'm going to store our images inside of this media folder in order to be more structured.
But it's not mandatory.
OK.
And it's not mandatory to do this from here.
I'm gonna write a code for this later on and it's not mandatory to initialize this from this dashboard
is it.
If you have created your storage if you have chosen your location then it's OK.
So let's come back to our documentation and let's go for AOS as usual.
And in here we have great documentation regarding the storage.
If you come over here to get started you can see the necessary paths.
We have actually done this before right.
We have added the pods.
And as you can see we have some sample codes regarding how to upload a file how to download that file
and don't worry I'm going to show all of this in the course but I really suggest you go back here and
just read those documentation if you have time because in firebase has so many modules so many methods
so many functions we cannot go over them one by one but I'm just showing you the most used ones most
used operations but there are some details that may come in handy when you're developing an app with
freebase.
So I suggest you take a look around here.
So as you can see we have an example here we are creating a reference from storage that's storage and
we're selecting a child's name for our folders and we're creating some other references to upload and
download images.
We're going to do that.
Don't worry.
But I believe the documentation of the firebase is great.
So when a user clicks on this upload button we have to upload the image to the storage first.
So let me grab firebase library from here and then we can create this storage reference that has been
mentioned in the documentation as well.
So I'm going to call this storage and this will drive from the storage class of the fire base.
OK.
This the capitalized s storage.
And as you can see this is a service that supports uploading and downloading objects.
So this is exactly what we did in yards.
So storage dot storage.
OK.
So this will create a storage instance an instance of the storage class.
And we are going to use that storage instance to create the references and upload images.
So next thing will be to create our storage reference.
OK.
And you can do that in one line as well.
I'm doing it on purpose so that you can understand the steps more clearly.
So we're creating a surge instance and then we're creating a reference from that instance so that we
can use that reference to upload our image.
So that's what we're going to do in the database as well.
We're going to create a firestorm instance and a reference.
And let me create our media folder.
So that's the folder that I'm creating right now.
So if I see a storage reference dot Childs.
OK.
So whenever you see Dot Childs in far your basic means that we have to go one level below.
So if I had another folder inside of that media folder then I can say dot child media.
That child something else.
And now I mean the reference and I'm saying dot child to go one level below to media folder.
Ok.
So it will refer to my media folder if I say dot child media.
So again if I had another thing in here like images it will just create the images folder for me.
You don't have to manually go and create that media folder but I'm going to go for the name media.
And again if you put another thing in here like dot child media too it will create another example another
folder inside of your media folder.
Ok but I'm not going to do that because I only need one folder to say my images.
So let's upload our image right in order to upload our image we have to convert it into a data.
Remember what we did in the art book we just don't save images.
As a UI image to a server or a database we have to create the images to a data type so that we can get
them and upload them after downloading them.
We can also convert back to the UI image and we know how to do that.
So that's exactly what we're going to do in here as well in order to get our chosen image and compress
it and change it to a J pad data and just save it to the database or storage.
So remember I would do that if that data image view that image that J page data and it asks us for a
compression quality we have gun words O point five I believe and that was OK.
So I'm going to go four point five again.
So maybe you can try something like open three or point four to just work with some lower resolutions
as well.
And in here we are agreeing to say late let's media reference.
OK.
I'm creating a reference for my image right now not my media folder.
And it's going to be driving from the media folder dubbed child.
So whatever I give as a name here like in image that J pack it will save my image like that.
OK.
It will just rename my image like image that J again they'll save it to the storage.
And I believe this media reference is not a good name because we're creating air for us not for our
Media folder we're creating this reference for our media image.
OK.
So we are creating this for image here for us.
So I believe we should rename this.
So let me call this image here for this rather than media for.
OK.
So that you can understand it better and then I'm going to say image reference that put data.
It'll ask me for a data to put on the storage and we have that data right.
And we want with the completion block OK.
Because we want to check if we have any error.
If we manage to upload the folder managed to upload the file to the folder so that we can get back animator
data that we want so data is data.
Meta data is kind of a description that we want to send with the image and we don't need one in here.
OK.
So I'm going to go for Neil and completion is our regular completion callback function.
If you hit enter it will give us a main meta data and we're going to need that.
So I'm going to name this meta data.
And for error we're going to say error.
So as usual I'm going to start by checking if error is not nil and if area is not nil you can just show
an Ellard message to the user.
I'm just going to go for a print error that localized description and in the else of course we want
to do something right.
We want to get the euro of the uploaded image.
Why do we even need that.
Because we're going to save this euro to the database along with the other information like comment
and who posted post over there.
OK.
Adds date.
So every image every past a in the database will have an image URL a comment and other features as well.
And previously we had this by saying meta data that image euro.
But right now as you can see this doesn't give us the image euro.
You know here to get the image here.
Now we have to do something like image reference.
OK dot download euro but only after you complete putting data you dude.
So after you are done in here then in the else block if there is not any error you can just call image
reference that download the euro.
And in this I'm gonna call these Euro and I'm going to call this error and this time I'm going to check
if error is actually Neil.
OK.
I'm not going to show any Alec messages in here.
If the error is nil then I'm going to go for the URL so I can just call this image here.
Let's image euro is going to be your URL that absolute strings.
Look there there is an absolute euro as well.
We're looking for absolute string.
So pay attention here is string 1.
So I'm going to print this string.
OK.
I'm going to print this image Euro to see if we really managed to upload the image to the storage.
So now we can't test is actually let's run this in our simulator and remember our simulator has some
pre-built in images in their photo gallery.
But I really such as you go and find your some images on your own because these images are too big and
it will work.
It will get uploaded but I believe it's more realistic to work with an image like this.
So as a comment it actually doesn't matter if I write a comment here or not because we're not doing
anything with that comment right now we're just uploading this image to these stories.
So whatever you write here won't get attention by the tax code so just write something or just leave
it empty.
All we have to do is just hit the upload button to see if we can manage to send this to the storage
and once I hit the upload button as you can see in the lugs I get this year.
I get this optional year out because this is optional right now.
As you can see and we're going to take care of this later on.
But for right now we have to take this euro and we can see if we really manage to upload our image to
this euro.
So let me copy this.
Let me open safari or any other browser and paste this in to see if we get the image.
Yep.
It asks for a download.
Permission if I allow that.
Here you go.
We see the image as we have uploaded.
So now I managed to upload my image to the fire base storage and in fact let's go back to our media
folder in here.
Right now we're going to see our image renamed as the image dot J back and in here as you can see we
have the file location the you're out here and we don't have any meta data because remember we actually
chose this to be nil and if you want to save any description in here you can do that but we don't need
that right now.
So far so good.
In fact we're not done with the whole uploading process.
We're gonna encounter some issues because of the name of this image but we're going to take care of
that one in the next lecture.