Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to discuss the final details of the firebase for example in our database.
Remember we started with the test mode and it actually allows us to read and write without any condition
and it's not very safe to do that.
So let's try to view the documentation and let's try to make our fire base safer than it already is.
So this is the fire store security rules documentation and you can find tons of information in here.
You can see how to write.
Conditions have to love the read How to love the rights based on a different condition.
If you're going to publish an app on the App Store I really suggest you guys to come over here and take
a look at the security rules so that you may find a real good example of what you're wanting to do in
your app.
But for right now let me show you a quick way how to make your application safer.
So we're allowing everything in here read and write without any condition.
OK to add a new condition in here after you say a low read then right you will hit a space.
OK you will bring a space in here like this and you will have to put that column up to write an essay
if request that off.
So is not now.
It means that if the request has authenticated using our app like signing in or signing up then a low
read their rights if you hit publish it will just save the security rules.
And as you can see you can see the versions over here so that if it breaks your code or if it doesn't
work you can go back anytime you want after you change the security rules.
You should of course come over here and test to see if you can write something new to your app.
So let's try to upload another picture we're here say Mona and say upload and as you can see it got
uploaded and it got downloaded so we can read and write to our in our app so that it's working let's
try with another user let's sign in with James.
OK.
James that Metallica dot com.
So let's sign in.
And as you can see we can see the pulse with James says well we can write the e in the database so when
we hit it like it brings up the like count.
And in here you can see the version of the security rules so that if anything happens you can revert
back anytime you want.
So let me open my safari because I want to go to Firebase Google dot com to show you another thing I'm
going to go for pricings.
And as you know this is completely free when you test your app but after your app meets a certain volume
you may have to pay up to the firebase because it has some kind of limitations for example you can have
one gigabyte of data in the file your store.
You can have some kind of 10000 authentication in one month.
OK.
Authentication requests in one month.
And if you want to upgrade there's a flame plan.
It's twenty five dollars per month at this current moment.
And if you exceed this plan as well.
There is a place plan you pay as you go.
So if you have an app in mind and if you wonder how much should I pay if I reach like 100000 people
in my app you can come over here and trying to try to calculate what would be the sufficient amount
to invest in that app.
So if you come up with a startup idea or if you're looking for investors you will know how much money
you will have to invest with that kind of volume in your app.
OK.
And fi your base is kind of cheap.
I believe for just service they pay for a right cause they're providing a very good service they're
providing us with a very powerful back and they're providing with very powerful database we can do real
time updates we can do storage.
We can do the authentication.
It's hard to find that kind of service in these days.
We're going to see an alternative later on called pass.
But I believe fire your base is better right now.
So I hope you enjoyed this one.
So let's meet in the next section to continue learning about I ask developments.