Hi within this lecture we going to see how we can gather to play your ideas and save them to a database
like fire your base so that we can get those whenever we want.
Okay.
Right now we're sending our push notifications to this device but we don't send our push notifications
to this device only.
So we want to know what device that we should send our push notifications and in order to do that we
going together every play your I.D. every device that we have in our app and going to save all this
information into fire base so that we can gather them when we need them.
So there are a lot of ways to do that.
And even though we can use any other databases as well since now we have the fire base.
I'm going to do that in five year base and of course if you're working with parts or any other database
that you want you can do it with that as well.
Right.
Because all we need to do is just to find somewhere to store these data and then reach them afterwards.
So I'm going to comment this out because I don't want to send this same notification every time we run
this and I'm going together to play your I.D. over here.
So let me show you have to do that.
Of course you can find this in documentation as well but I'm just going to show you because documentation
can be messy sometimes or can get complicated.
It's not messy structural but it's sometimes hard to find what you're looking for.
So how how do we get the play your IED off the current device.
Of course we're going to use different signal methods.
So I'm going to create a status over here and the status will indicate whether this device is subscribed
or not.
And in order to do that I'm going to use something called or ask permission state subscriptions state.
OK so this is one signal permission subscriptions state.
And I'm going to get it from one signal.
OK dot get permission subscriptions state.
So this will give me the current subscription state.
If this is subscribed I'm going to get to 0 or if this is not subscribed I'm getting going to get false
but I can't get play your I.D. out of that state as well.
So let me create the play your I.D. and I will call the status and Dot.
And as you can see it gives me so many options over here.
What we want is the subscription status itself.
This one.
So if you come over here and say that one more time you can actually get whatever you're looking for.
So in this case we're looking for user I.D. even though it says user I.D. is actually the same as play
your I.D..
So I'm going to print out this play your idea and see if that's the real thing that we're looking for.
So as you can see it's an optional strange and you can check to see with a flat as well.
So for right now I'm just going to force a wrap this.
But in this case I believe it's safe to do that with a flat.
So let me run this and see if we can get the play your I.D..
So here you go now once it's five years up I'm going to see the logs and I'm going to just filter this
with player I.D..
And here you go.
Now we have this play your I.D..
Of course we can check this so that we can be certain are getting the same data.
And let me refresh this.
And as you can see this is the same play your I.D. that I'm seeing over here.
So I know how to get a player I.D. right now.
Right.
So if I save a replay your I.D. to firebase.
Now when I need them I can just get them.
Right.
So let's do that actually.
So after getting the play your I.D..
I'm going to create a five star reference and let's see if we have one.
Yeah we have imported Phi Phi your base over here and let me open my file your base file your store
as well.
Rather than saving under Paul's.
I'm going to create a new collection.
Of course you can come up with some other algorithm as well but I'm just going to keep it simple.
So let me create a five star reference over here.
OK so this will be five years store.
That's five years sir.
Remember this gives us some instance of these five years sir okay.
And then I I'm going to call these fires to reference that collection and I'm going to call this collection
play your I.D. so you can call whatever you want.
But after that you have to call and document and this will ask you for a data and a completion block.
So this will be our dictionary so I'm going to call this play your I.D. dictionary and I'm going to
save the mail of the current logged in user.
And remember we can get this from off that of dots turned to user.
OK so this one and I'm going to force unwrap this and say email and I'm going to force unwrap this as
well.
And this site from email I'm going to just save display your I.D. so I'm going to say play your I.D..
OK.
And this will be the play your I.D. that we're looking for.
So this one.
And here you go.
That's how we say play your I.D. to defy your store so that we can filter the results regarding with
e-mail and we can get those and I'm going to do this.
If that thing because it won't be safe to force our app this.
So I'm going to call this play your new I.D. And as you can see it's not optional anymore.
So I'm going to delete this and I'm going to take everything from here to there and rather than saying
play your I.D. over here I'm going to say play your new I.D. And I'm going to have a non optional string
and I'm going to use this play your I.D. dictionary to save in my five year term.
And then I can just call the current e-mail to get the related play your I.D..
So as you can see this is our play your I.D. dictionary and let's say it says that it's string to string
and I'm going to cast this as a string to any dictionary because Firestarter store asks me to provide
a string to any dictionary.
OK now if I come over here as you can see it's string to any dictionary and now it's done.
And if I hit enter over here it will give me an error if there is one.
And I'm going to check to see if error is not nil and if area is not nil your let me close the three
down and your if area is not nil maybe you may want to print out the error or you may want to display
the error message to the user.
It's your call at this point but I'm just going to test as if we can actually save this data to define
your base.
So let me run this in our simulator and let's see if we can see the data in the fire store.
Now it's over here running.
So let me refresh the fire store.
OK and let's see if we can get the new collection from here.
Here you go.
Now we have the player I.D..
If I hit on that you will see that Kirk at Metallica dot com has displayed your I.D. So it's working
fine.
But there is some sort of a trick or here that we may want to do.
Because let me run this in our iPhone as well to test this out and you will see it will work fine.
But I believe every time we run this app it will just upload a new value to the fire store.
And that's not what we want.
So let me go over here and see if we can see my iPhone's play your I.D. as well.
Here you go.
Now James said Metallica outcome has this play your I.D. but let me run this from scratch and let's
see if we can see two results but we won't be seeing this I believe because we're not checking for anything
else.
So let me run this in my simulator.
No not in my simulator but I'm running does it on my real phone.
And here you go.
Now we have to James is in our play your I.D. collection.
And even though they're having the same player I.D. We don't want to James in our play your I.D. collection.
Right.
Because it will get complicated.
So I believe we have to figure out a way to check for this if we have this I won't create a new one.
If we don't have this then I will create a new one.
So it's fairly easy to do and it's all related to the fire base not the push notifications but we're
going to have to do it anyway.
So I'm going to stop here and within the next six you re going to take care of this problem.