Hi.
We did this lecture we going to finalize our app by adding the push notification functionality and the
like function.
OK so far we know how to send push notifications and how to gather you play your ideas.
Now we are going to combine this together.
So let me cut this and come into our feed cell where we do the liking functionality right.
And over here I'm going to post to push notifications so let me bring in the one saying no and let me
import the one signal as well.
So that's how we do it.
Come over here and after like since the post I'm going to send the push notification as well.
So this post notification will work.
But rather than saying text message I want to say somebody liked your post and this somebody will be
the current user logged in.
Right.
So rather than saying somebody I'm just going to get the current user logged in from authentication
module.
So how do we do that.
It's very easy.
We say of that of that current user that's e-mail.
OK.
So don't forget to enforce our app this and after that you can just say something like has liked your
post or liked your post.
Ok so here you go.
After that we have to find the play your idea of you like to user as well.
So how do we do that if we come over here we know the e-mail of the post on the right.
We have this user e-mail labeled we can get that e-mail labeled and we can get the text out of that
label of course and we can use that email label to get the play your I.D. from fire or store.
So let's do that.
Let me call this user e-mail and say user e-mail labeled dot text.
OK.
After doing that I can't force our app is I believe because it won't be even just an empty value at
this point.
After doing that I'm just going to call five star database one more time because we're going to get
the player idea of this user email so you can just say collection player I.D..
OK.
So it was player I.D. or play your I.D. Let me come over here.
Yeah it was play your I.D. So player I.D. dot gets documents rather than that snapshot listener because
we're only needing these ones at this point.
So I'm going to call this snapshot or error so if error is not nil or if error is nil.
OK.
It's your call again if areas nil then I'm going to work on that snapshot I'm going to check to see
if snapshots dot is empty is false.
OK.
And snapshot is not nailed.
So once we do that we can just work on that snapshot and say for document in snapshot that documents
like this snapshot dots documents.
OK.
And once we do that don't forget to force our Raptors as well.
And now I can get this by saying document dots yet OK.
And the field that I'm looking for is the play your I.D..
And over here I'm going to try and cast this to be string.
OK because we're saving this player ideas a string.
And don't forget to give a very field over here.
And our field will be e-mail and it will be equal to user e-mail.
OK.
So we forgot to add this one if we don't do that it will bring all the player I.D. in the database.
So I'm going to check to see flat player I.D. document that gets s drink.
And if that's the case now I want to do this push notification thing.
So let me cut this one as well.
OK.
So I will send this push notification to the play your I.D..
So let me do this one more time.
Let me delete this and let me put.
Play your I.D. over here.
So here you go.
Now we know the content that we're using and we have this data error.
Yeah.
We have to put quotation marks inside of this curly braces are not curly races but a ray braces as well.
So come over here as a quotation mark.
And again quotation mark.
So that's it now we know they play your I.D..
Now we know the contents.
And now we are ready to test this.
So I'm going to run this on my real iPhone okay.
And of course I'm going to run this on my simulator as well.
So we will have two devices to test this.
Oh so let's see if we can make this work.
So let me minimize all of this window so that we can see our phone and simulator.
Let me close this down.
And on the left hand side I have my simulator.
And on the right hand side I have my phone.
So as you can see this is my phone.
So in the phone I'm logged in with James.
And in the simulator I'm logged in with Kirk.
So I'm going to like one of the posts of James.
And here you go.
Well I like this.
I will see the notification popping up in my phone.
And as you can see it says That's Kirk at Metallica dot com liked your post and it's fantastic.
As I click on it it will take me to the app itself.
So let me test this one more time.
Let me like this and I will get the notification over here and then I click on that it will take me
to the app itself and let me test this vile app is open.
So let me try to like this and let me just close down the do not disturb mode so we can see the notifications.
OK.
So if I like this here you go.
Now I see the notification and let's test this while using another app like let me go into the books
app so that we can actually test this.
So when we like it it will pop up on the top of our screen in our actual form.
And if I click on it it will take me to my Instagram firebase cone.
Here you go.
Now it works perfect.
Of course there are other features that you can implement with one signal like you can handle the incoming
notifications and you can choose what to do when a notification comes.
Of course you're going to have to read the documentation in order to do that but now you know how to
send notifications which is great so that you can integrate this technique with all of your apps.
Now let's stop here and continue within the next lecture.