Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to understand what is passe and why do we need it.
And why do we want to use it when we have five year base.
Okay.
So where are you going to see what this person.
What are the main differences between pass and fire base.
So in order to do that before we create a project I'm going to go over my safari or another browser.
Obviously I'm going to search for parts.
So the first result that we're going to get is parse platform dot arc.
So this is the official Web site of the pass.
So pass provides us a great tool to work in cloud servers and connect our server with our project with
its backend services.
So it's kind of fire base but this is completely open source.
So far your base is run by Google at this time and fire base is actually maintained in the fire base
a Google servers but in PA.
So we don't get any ready servers so we can get the parts and deploy it in any server that we want.
So this is the main difference between far your base and pass in fact pass was owned by Facebook in
previous years and pass had its own servers like we get to go to Paris platform dot org and create an
account and just create a server and just start to work within the server.
But now this is all open source and we get to get the pass codes in the server side and we get to deploy
it any device we want.
And in here if you come below a little bit you will see that this works on other platforms like we.
We have seen in the firebase as well so it works on Io as Android javascript unity BHP and the other
platforms as well.
Of course we are going to focus on ISIS but if you're thinking about releasing a multi-platform app
as well then this will do the job for you as we did in the base.
So some of these students some of the users actually find fire base a little bit more complicated when
it comes to simplicity.
So they can choose parts over fire but in order to have more easy to use system more easy to use as
the case.
But this has also some disadvantages as well.
So in your base We do relive couriers much better than in parts.
So my suggestion is that you just watch to your base section and you just watch two parts section and
then you can decide what to use on your own.
But if you need something like real time data what is if you're building something like a chat app if
you need a data from the server in less than one second.
My suggestion is to go with fire base and if you don't need that you can always try firebase umpires
and decide on your own OK.
And you're going to see this actually very easy to use and this is actually very easy to operate.
And we are going to build a Foursquare clone for example in the section so that we won't need anything
in less than one second so we can safely use parts.
In that case.
So if you click over the IRS then you will get to see the github of the pass SDK for AOS and you will
see the documentation to install this pass pass as the case into your X code project.
But as I said before this is not enough.
We have to find a server to run our power server on.
So there are a couple of ways to do that before previously.
We have actually told how to use this in Amazon servers.
OK.
In Iaw yes but now I suggest you go to this back for app dot com and use that power server over here
because it's much more better than.
Then we compare this to the AWB yes two years ago we didn't have this OK.
We had to work with either with us or any other server but now we have this and it's much better.
But in any case I'm going to show you to and ideal yes Web site as well if you want to go and deploy
your own server you may do that in Amazon but right now in this section I'm going to build my pasture
reusing back for app and you will see this is very user friendly very easy to use and very easy to actually
create an account with free trials of course you can just start for free.
And it does has its own limitations you can come over here and look pricing as well like in firebase
when you actually exceed a certain quota hours certain amount of users you may have to create a premium
account as well.
So I cannot seem to open a double yes for some reason.
So let me google it from here.
Maybe then we will see it.
It's actually that.
Yes that's Amazon dot com.
Yep.
This one.
So this is Amazon Web Services and they provide cloud computing services in which you can find ready
to deploy power servers as well.
But as I said before we're not going to do that in the section because it's not practical and it's not
as good as back for app because back for app actually improved the PA server by their own improvements
by their own development.
So we get to see something some cool features like add I mean app push notifications and other stuff
as well.
So we're going to use these documentation to bring pass as the case into our X code project and we're
going to use back for app documentations in order to connect our server with our X gold project.
Okay.
So we have a lot to do in the section I believe now we are ready to stop here and we didn't the next
lecture we're going to create our X code project and bring the process the case in.