Hi we didn't this lecture we going to find a way to remember the user so that every time we open the
app it won't ask us for a user name and password.
If the user has been previously logged in it will just take the user to the places we've controller.
So what we going to do is the same thing that we did in the file your bass section.
So we have used this scene delegate.
Maybe you remember we have used this will connect to session function so that's what we gonna do in
this section as well.
But before we go on and do that I'm going to show you.
If you do that under we did loading the view controller it won't work again.
So let me show you how this goes if you create the user called current user.
And if you say APF user dot current.
So this gives the currently logged in user and returns the instance of it.
So if this is not nil it means that there is a current user.
Right.
So if you say current user you get a P.F. user and if this is if this is not Neal again then you can
actually see the email or user name or password of this user.
So let me run this and let's see if we can get this user in our logs.
OK.
So let's come over here and as you can see we can see the James as optional.
So James has been previously logged in even though this is logged in we cannot take user to the places
we controller.
So can we do something like if current user is not Neal take us to the places where you controller by
doing a Segway right.
No we cannot do that actually because it won't work.
And as you can see let me writes with that identifier two places we see and try to perform the Segway.
So once I do that it won't take me to the places we've controller because we have to do that under seen
delegate before everything loads up and we have to change the routes we have controller.
Right.
That's what we did in the firebase section and it doesn't make sense to do a Segway here it doesn't
make sense to load these weave controller at all.
So best way to do that is to check this on the scene delegate and if that's the case then change the
route we've controller.
So let me cut everything from here on come over here under our scene delegates.
So first of all in order to use this class I'm going to import pass in here as well done P.F. user won't
give me an error.
This will give you an error because we cannot use perform Segway in scene delegates.
We don't have any controller in here.
Rather I'm going to create my UI screen board storyboard.
Actually as a variable.
So the name of this storyboard is main am going to create a variable representing our places we have
controller right.
So that I can instantiate that we have controller.
So I'm going to say boards that instantiate instantiate we've controller and it asks us for an identifier.
So I don't have any current identifiers because we haven't give them one.
Right.
So if you come over here to places we've controller you can give them but in fact you don't want to
give any identifier to places you controller you want to do that in navigation.
We've controller so choose navigation we have controller and say something like navigation controller
as a storyboard I.D. and the remembered the class here is UI navigation controller.
It doesn't have any specific dots moved files.
So we are going to cast this as a navigation controller.
So in identifier I'm writing the exact same thing that I have written there and I'm going to first cast
this as UI navigation controller.
And since this is actually a UI navigation controller it won't fail.
So rather than calling this places we see I'm going to call these navigation controller in order to
avoid any confusion.
And in here I'm going to call the window as a route wi controller and say navigation controller.
So what does it do.
It takes this entry points inside in front of.
Does navigation controller so that we can change the launching we you controller.
So what we're going to see when we first launch the app is going to be the places we have controller
if and only if the user has been previously logged in.
So here you go.
Now we see the places we controller right and this works.
But this time we got another problem.
We have to have a lock out button here so that the user can log out any time they want.
So how do we do that.
Let's go to places where you controller and we're going to add another navigation bar item this time
it's going to be a left bar item rather than a right bar item right.
So I'm going to say log out here.
And if this works then I'm going to go back to my sign in week controller.
So let's go to places we have controller and let's add.
And Neil Bogden over here let's call navigation controller dot navigation bar dot top item.
OK.
Dots left bar about an item.
So this is last for about an item.
So this is going to be on the left rather than right.
This is going to be the only difference.
And actually the other difference will be the style of this button.
So I'm not going to go for a bar button system item this time because I just want to have a title in
my bottom.
So I'm just going to give a specific value something like logout.
So I'm going to choose this one with sites of.
So this asks us for a string and string will be log out and sail again.
I can just choose something like done or plain.
This is regular style.
Let's go for plain for example and let's see if this looks good and if it doesn't we can always come
back here and change it.
Targets will be self for action let me create another function called log up button clicked OK so that
we can add this as a selector over here.
So this will be selector and logout button clicked.
Here you go.
Now what we're going to do here is to log out from the pass and bring the user to our sign up.
We have controller.
So let me import the parts first of all.
And we're going to take the user to the weave controller that Swift.
So for logging out I'm going to use P.F. user dot log out.
And again we have some options over here I'm going to go for log out in background with block so that
if I have any error like losing the internet connection or something I can just show it to the user.
OK.
And let me choose design hit enter.
It will give me error.
If there is any error I'm just going to show it to the user.
If there is not.
It means that it's worked out well.
So let me create the error here and we don't have any other messages right now so I'm going to create
one.
Let's do this fast.
So this is going to be an Elliott controller with title error message error that localized description.
OK.
Style will be entered that style.
So the next thing will be for me to create an ok by then.
This is going to be an action and for a title I'm going to say OK.
And for style I'm going to go for default.
And I don't think any handler I'm going to add this to my efforts as an action and I'm going to display
the zealot bit soft present and then I'm going to go to Elliot's here with animation without completion.
And if that's not the case if there is not any error it means that I get to go from here to my weave
controller and in order to do dots I don't have any method right now.
Right.
Because I cannot use navigation controller like we did before.
So here I have to come from here to my sign in which controllers.
So let me do a show Segway right.
And if I do a show Segway it gives us a navigation bar by them which I don't want I don't want the user
to go back from sign in view controller to here.
So I'm going to present this model T and I'm going to do this full screen so that's good.
And I'm going to give you an identifier to sign up.
We see.
And this is not named sign up right now I'm going to change its name later on but for right now I'm
going to copied this and come over here and say self-taught power form Segway for identifier.
I'm going to say to sign up LISI AND SON There will be Neil.
So let's test this let's run this in our simulator it shall take us to the places we've controller automatically
because we are already signed in and here we go now we see the log out bottom if I click over here it
takes me to my sign up we see now let me run this from scratch and if it takes us to the sign up we
see that it works fine and here you go it works fine because you have already been logged out let's
run in with James One two three four five six.
Here you go next.
Now let's run it from scratch.
One more time to see if we see places we see here you go.
Now we are in.
So sign in sign up log out.
Everything seems to be working pretty good.
So we are dumb.
We it's our authentication procedures.
So let me rename this.
In fact there are a couple of ways to rename this and I'm going to show you the easiest one.
OK.
You can just click over here to view controller to rename this file manually but then it means that
you have to change everything manually.
Most basic way to do that is to come over here and right click and say Refactor Rename.
So when you do that it will change everything regarding to view controller.
So it will rename every line that we are using this view controller in.
OK so if you want something like sign up then you're more than welcome to do it and say rename once
you say rename it will change the class name from here from here.
And if you're using it anywhere in the project it will change it as well.
So best way to rename variables or classes or any object is to right click on it and say Read fact to
rename.
So when I run this on my simulator everything seems to be working so it didn't break anything.
We are done with our authentication.
Now we need to move on.
First of all I'm going to create a user interface I'm going to bring in all my weave controllers so
that we can start working on them.
Finally let's do that in the next lecture.