Hi within this lecture we going to learn a new concept called singleton class.
So we're going to see whether this but what we're doing so far is to create this ad plays view controller
in which people will choose the name type an atmosphere and then they will click next.
So why do we need that Singleton because when we click that's next we're going to go to these maps we've
controller and we how to transfer is information the name the type the atmosphere and the image to the
maps we have controllers so that we can upload them to the pass right.
And you know how to transfer data between we have controllers as you can for example use prepare for
Segway in order to achieve these results.
But sometimes there are a lot of data to transfer between.
We have controllers like in here we have four data but maybe in some cases you will have five.
We have controllers and in which you will have like five different data points.
So you're going to be dealing with 25 data points and it will be harder for you to transfer them.
So we're going to come up with a way to transfer these data with more efficient structure.
And there are a couple of ways to do that.
I'm going to show you one way which is the easiest but it is not preferable due to its nature.
Later on I'm going to show you a lot more clear a lot more structural way and we're going to use that
and it's called singleton class.
First of all I'm going to show you something called global variables.
So far we have been defining our variables inside of our classes.
Now I'm going to define a variable outside of our class.
So this is above the class as you can see and trying to come up with a way to create global named global
type and global atmosphere.
And they are going to be initial initially empty strings.
Okay of course we can do that for global image as well.
And then next button is clicked.
I can just come over here and say global name is name tags.
So what was it called place name taxed.
OK.
That text.
So it will assign whatever is written inside of our place name text to global name variable.
And since I defined that global name outside of my Clyde's class now I can come to map B C and I can
just call this global name from here and I can reach its current value.
So let me try to let me try to print the global name inside of map B C even though I defined that variable
inside the F place V.S. as you can see now I call that variable E side of my map C so let me try this.
Let me come over here.
Let me write something like James restaurant or James.
OK.
And here next and in map we see as you can see we managed to get that information and write it down.
So this works so you can just do this operation with global variables.
But this is not preferable.
Why.
Because maybe you're working with a big team like you have 10 developers in your project and you're
creating some variables.
And if you define all these variables as global variables someone may just take that global variable
without knowing it and change its value somewhere.
So it's not very safe to use that in this case we are all alone and we are developing our own project
and we are capable of tracking what we have done so far.
So I believe it's no harm to do that but I'm going to show you a better way to use that so I'm creating
a swift file.
OK and the Swiss file is going to be a class I'm going to call this place model.
So we're creating a place modelling here and we're going to assign all the properties all the values
that we want inside of a place to this model and this model will only have one object one instance so
that we can reach it from anywhere and we can change it from anywhere.
I'm going to show you how to do that.
So this is going to be our place model.
OK.
And this is going to be a regular class.
But before we go on and go on and do that I'm going to show you what a singleton is.
So I search Google for a singleton class in swift and this came up.
So this is a simple code for singleton class as you can see defines the class as a regular way.
And it's create something called static left.
So does a static variable and it's can be reached from anywhere.
OK.
So we're going to reach that shared distance but the key point here is that use is something called
private initialized.
Remember when we use initialize is we define what will happen then an instance of this class is created.
So this is the same thing but V defined as initialize is as private.
So that this instance of this class an instance of this class can only be created inside of this class.
So this is kind of not very useful if you want to have a regular class where you want to create more
than one object but if you want to have only one object if you want to have only one instance then this
is great.
You can create your own instance from here and people can access this instance and change its value
from any class you want.
Let me show you what I mean.
I'm going to call this place model as I said before and I'm going to create a static variable so static
lat and I'm going to call this shared instance.
OK.
So this is going to be a place model object and this will be the only instance of this class we cannot
create any instance of this class because I'm going to add private initialized or out inside of this
class of course I can choose whatever attributes that I want to assign to this object or assigned to
this class in general.
And people will get to choose.
People will get to change these variables but only for this shared instance.
Okay.
Not for another instance is because there will be no in other instance for example these sample shows
us it created some account information.
I don't need that.
I'm just gonna go for place name.
Okay so my place name will be an empty string and place type again an empty string place atmosphere.
Again an empty string and we're going to have some place image.
So this will be a UI image and we cannot do that because we only imported Foundation in here.
We have to go for UI kit so once we do that now we cannot initialize the UI image as well.
Now let me call private in it.
OK.
So that no other instance will be created out of this class.
So this is private in its as in here.
And I believe I forgot to add this parentheses.
Yep.
OK now we are ready to test the singleton class.
Let's go to our ad place.
We have controller and let's go to next button clicked.
I'm gonna delete this.
We're not going to be using these global variables.
I'm going to comment this out.
I'm going to leave it here as a note so that you know there is something called global variables but
it's kind of frowned upon to use it in big projects.
So let's come here and call for place model.
So generally we just do that place model dot shared instance and we get to reach the attributes when
we hit dot or here.
Right now we are getting some weird air and I cannot reach the variables so let me create a place model
over here.
So it would be much more clear what I'm doing.
So I cannot do that for example I cannot say that place model place model because it will say that any
Schweizer is inaccessible because we have this private protection level.
So rather I have to say shared instance.
And as you can see we we get an weird error when we say that let me do a command B to build this up.
Oh yeah we really have an error.
Oh yeah.
In the map we see we still printing the global name.
So that was the error that we are getting.
So let's go back to that place we see and we have commented everything out.
And let me do another commands B to see if we really have another error.
No.
Yep.
Now we are good to go.
Now if I say that shared instance.
Yep.
You're not getting in error.
And if I say that I get to reach the attributes.
Now in here if I say place model not this place model but the displaced model that we have created.
Yep.
This one if I say place model dot now I can change the place name.
Now I can get it from place name tags dot text ok place name text.
That text.
So again in here in map we see we can call this OK.
We can call this place model with capital p place model dot shared instance dot place name and a you
will see that this will give me the same result that I have assigned in the previous week controller
because we only have one instance.
So let's go for test and it next.
As you can see we managed to print out the tests so this works.
So our singleton class actually doing its job.
So let's go to Ed place we have controller and actually do the other things as well.
Before we go on and first I'll wrap all of this.
I want to check to see if place name text is empty is not empty actually place site tax that text is
not an empty string and place atmosphere dot text.
This one that text is not an empty string as well.
So if these conditions hold then I can create my place model and I can assign all their related values.
What do I need I need actually an image as well.
Right.
So I'm going to check to see if let's chosen image is going to be a place image.
Let's see place Image view dot image.
If I can get this OK then I can be certain that I can call place model dot place image.
So let's do that place model that place that in place name text place model up place type place type
text not text.
Okay we have one more tag.
So does this place Utmost Fear and place Utmost Fear text that text.
Here you go.
And finally we're going to have place model image so place model dog place image.
And this will be equal to chosen image.
Here you go.
I believe now we assigned everything that we need.
If this works out we can do the Segway right.
So I believe we can do the Segway inside of the first.
If so if they are not empty we can go over here and perform the Segway and else if they're empty we
can just do.
We can't just show an error message and I believe we don't have any left messages in here.
So let me create one more fast.
The title will be error the message will be the place name place type and place utmost fear missing.
OK so that user will know they have to give some texts.
And here I'm going to say OK.
Bottom is going to be a UI alert action and this action will have the title of OK.
The sale of alerts or not other default and handler will be nil.
So here I'm going to add the action to my real effort.
OK.
And I'm going to present this by saying present and I'm going to present the Ellard with information
without completion.
Here you go.
Now I believe we are ready to test this.
In fact we're not going to see if this works or not because we will be transferring data to maps we
have controller but we're not using that data right now.
Just let me test this and see if we get an error or not.
Let's click on Next.
Yep.
We don't get any error and actually we printed out the test while more time we going to see if this
really works when we upload the data to past server right now let's stop here and do that within the
next lecture.