Hi within this lecture we're going to add a needle gesture recognizing to our map to choose a location
from the map.
So we have done this in the art book section.
So I'm going to be a little bit past you know how to do that already.
In fact you can post a video and try to do it on your own.
So I hope you managed to do that.
So what we do is to create a recognizable in here and this will be a UI long press gesture recognizable.
So remember we get this gesture recognize ran a user presses for a long time over some view.
So this asks for action and the selector so we have to create the selector I'm gonna call this choose
location.
OK.
And under in this actually in this choose location where you're going to ask for a gesture recognized
her so that we will reach our UI tap gesture recognize or remember and this will actually give us opportunity
to do something with that gesture recognize her and I'm going to call this choose location gesture recognize
her and we have to give this some minimum price duration and I'm gonna go for tree as usual.
And later on I'm going to add this yes you recognize here to my map view.
So here you go.
And of course under this choose location we will start to check to see if this gesture recognizes or
has actually begun.
So how do we do that.
We just say if gesture recognize your dot state is a you I gesture recognize or dot state DOT begin.
So if that's the case remember what we do remember we create some touched points.
So we're going to say let touch is and this will get Yeah.
This will be gotten from the gesture recognize dot location and it will ask us for a view and this is
map view.
And again we are going to create this coordinates out of that touches.
So I'm going to say self that map view that convert.
And we want something called converting points to coordinates from.
So regarding going to convert this touch this touched points into coordinates using our map.
So I'm doing this kind of fast because we have done this before and I explained what are those.
So if you don't know I suggest you go back and watch as a refresher.
So let me create my own annotation so my annotation will be M.K. point on notation and the cardinals
will be of course the coordinates.
Okay.
And we get some errors over here.
So yep this is called the map you.
Why are we getting that error.
Because I misspelled it.
Yep.
This has to be Matthew.
And the annotation coordinates will be coordinates.
Yep.
We have just created that coordinates and we can give it some title and subtitle as well title I could
be the map the place name actually not map name place names so you can get that from place modeled up
shared instance that's a place name right.
And we how we can have a subtitle as well we can just write the place type here like shared instance
that place type.
Okay.
If you don't know why the subtitle and title of the annotation is you going to see in a minute and later
on we going to have to just add this notation to our map view right.
Because we have defined our coordinates.
We have defined our title subtitle and everything yep we are ready to see a self doubt map.
Have dots adds on notation and we want to add our current annotation.
So that's it for us notation.
That's it for choosing location.
OK.
This will give us the coordinates.
And later on we're going to get this coordinates every going to get the current selected locations coordinates
and get its latitude and longitude to save it to the pass.
So let me create a chosen latitude and chosen longitude over here.
They will be doubles because we can actually have these strings as well we can just save our values
as strings to do pass.
You will see how we can do that.
I'm going to show you.
Don't worry.
And in here I'm going to go for self that chosen latitude and this will come from coordinates.
Latitude.
OK.
And this will give us some coordinates.
And we're going to convert it to a string.
By saying this and I'm going to go for our chosen longitude again strings and coordinates.
That's long you toots.
So here we go.
Let's see.
Let's try to transfer data from the ad place we've controller from here so let's say this is James restaurant.
OK.
And this is going to be a restaurant and for atmosphere I'm just going to write something like nice
and this choose a picture so that it would be much more real.
And then here let me go over to Frank House and choose a location for James.
So let me hear that here for three seconds.
And here you go.
We managed to add our annotation.
So if you click on that notation you will see James first round and the restaurant.
So we managed to transfer the coordinates not the coordinates transferred the place name and place type.
So that now we're ready to get everything together and upload everything to the pass because right now
we have our place name place type place atmosphere.
We have our place image.
We have our latitude longitude and everything.
Now all we have to do is just create a P.F. object to save this information to the PA server.
Let's do that in the next lecture.