Hi within this lecture regarding to process this information that we got from PARS so that we can show
the place name the place type the place Utmost Fear and accordance to the user in our details we've
controller.
So how do we do that.
Of course I will start to see if objects is not normal or not.
So if objects is not nil I can go and do my thing.
If objects are nil then there is no point of doing that at all.
In most of the times we have to go in a forward looping here because we are working with individual
objects.
But in this case I expect to see only one object right.
So I can't try to create this object by saying let my objects objects zero.
So this will give me the first objects.
First element of this area.
This will ask me to first cast this and I believe it's kind of safe to do it in here because we have
already checked to see if objects is not nil but maybe in order to make the safer we can check to see
if it objects.
That count is greater than zero.
So that we know the objects is not nil.
And there are some elements inside of our objects array and this asks us to first cast this but it doesn't
make sense to do it like this.
So I can just control like those if objects not count is greater than zero then I believe this is much
more safer.
OK so that I can create my individual object like this without having to have a for loop because we're
going to be dealing with only one object and let's call this chosen place object.
OK.
My object is not a very good choice for a variable name.
So in this chosen place object if we say something like object for ki I can just get whatever I want
out of this.
Right.
Like if let's place name then I can just say for key name.
Remember we have defined this as name.
I will cast is optionally a string and if that's the case I'm going to change little name label details.
Name labels so details.
Name label DOB taxed is now the chosen place place names are so I'm going to do this for other variables
as well.
So let me corporatism pasted so I did this for place name.
Let's do that for a place type.
So this will be type again this will be a string and details type label dot tax going to be place type.
So far so good.
Let's go for the third one.
So rather than type I'm going to go for atmosphere.
Okay so this will be place atmosphere rather than place type atmosphere.
So this will be place utmost fear and this will be details utmost for your labels are tax so that's
all for labels I believe.
Now are we going to have to get the results from our yes.
It asks us to use s I believe.
Inside in front of everything.
So let's first scrap this and let's say self in front of this.
Yep because we're in a closure and then later Owen we're going to have to get the image and also the
latitude and longitude first go for latitude and longitude if left place latitude chosen place I.D.
chosen place object sorry that object.
And four key I'm going to go for latitude and we're going to have to convert this to double later on
because we saved it as a drink.
So let's create some chosen latitude and longitude over here as doubles.
Okay.
We gonna need the doubles eventually.
So let's say chosen longitude.
This is a double as well.
And we're going to convert this gem convert them in here to be double so I'm going to say if let's place
latitude double Okay double parentheses place latitude.
So this one if I can make this string into a double then I will say self-taught chosen latitude is place
latitude double.
So that's how you actually convert double to string and string to double right.
You know this every going to do the same thing for longitude as well.
If that place longitude is chosen place object object for key and the key that I'm looking for is the
longitude I'm going to cast is optional as string and say placed longitude double again double with
parentheses place longitude and then later on I'm going to say self that chosen longitude is now chosen
longitude is now place longitude double and the last thing that we have to do is just to get the image
and we know how to upload the image but we don't know how to download it yet it's fairly easy to do
we just get the data and we download the data and if we can make it then we're going to convert it to
an image so let's see how we can do that first of all I'm going to create something called Image Data
right because we have saved this as data another UI image and we're going to download this as data again
now we're going to use that data to displayed in an image view.
So let's say that if that image data is chosen place objects dots object and the key that I'm looking
for is image.
OK.
Remember we saved this column as image and I'm going to cast this as PR file so PR file objects and
I'm going to check to see if we can actually download this.
So after you get your variable you have to manually download this to get the data.
So you're going to have to say image data dot image data that gets data.
OK.
As you can see if you say get data we have something in background.
So get data in background.
It's either gives us data or an error in this time I'm not going to check if error is not nil and maybe
we can just check if error is nil like this.
OK.
If error is nil then you can check to see if data is not nil.
One more time but I'm just going to go for data.
Not this one s dots details imagery.
Yep.
This one dot image.
So this will be a UI image.
OK.
And this will ask you for a data and the data that I'm looking for is the data itself.
So if you do that it will ask you to first cast this.
OK.
You can do that of course.
But again you can check to see if data is not nil like this to be extra cautious so that you won't crash
your app.
So far so good.
So rather than just zooming in the map I believe we have done everything right.
So let's cut everything from here because we made that we did load we have filled up so let me create
another function called get data from pass and paste everything under that function and call that function
under my we did load.
So I believe now we are ready to test this.
We want to get the map animating to this selected location but I believe we can do that in the next
lecture as well.
Let's see if we can get the other details so let's open our simulator.
Now let's choose the only place that we have.
Here you go.
We see the image we see the image name the restaurant name the type and everything.
So we don't see the data in my maps yet.
But we are going to see it in a minute in the next lecture.