Hi.
We didn't this lecture we're going to finalize our app by testing to add some new places.
So let me open my app and let me click on James restaurant and I can get this map and I can get whatever
I want so it works fine.
So let me create another place and let's see if that works as well.
So let me call this Kirk pub and this will be a pub and for the atmosphere you can just call whatever
you want.
OK I'm going to choose an image up here next.
Let's go for a red light district this time and select one of the places over here.
So this will be our Kirk pop location.
And once I do that I can see the notation and once I hit the save.
Yep.
Now I see the Kirk pump the problem over here is that we lost in navigation bar and again we have lost
it before.
And I said that yep we going to take care of this problem later on and we see those maps over here.
But I believe this is the Maps app that we have opened before.
Yep.
This one.
So this isn't related to overturn.
Problem actually.
So let me go back.
Yeah.
The current problem is that we don't have the navigation bar and it's related to say where's we're going
to take care of that in a minute.
Once I hit the James Shore restaurant and once I hit the Kirk pub it's opens but it opens as a pop over.
So again it's a related to say grace.
So we have to take care of this problem right.
But the good thing is that Kirk pub is displaying its values so everything related to parse operations
actually work.
So how do we take care of that.
Let me close this down and go to main story board.
Let's find our lost Segway.
We're doing this Segway from our maps we have controller to our table view to our places we have controller
what we want to do actually is to make this segway to our navigation controller rather than table view
because navigation controller will display the places we controller anyway.
But what we are doing here to skip the navigation controller and just go directly to the places we controller.
So it actually doesn't understand that's places we have controller has one navigation controller.
So in order to solve this problem I'm going to copy this Segway identifier from here.
I'm going to delete the Segway by clicking over here and clicking on the backspace or delete in my keyboard
and I'm going to take this from map we see and bring it to my navigation controller.
If I do a show Segway it will distort all the views one more time.
So rather than doing a show let's come over here and do a present model and we going to go for a full
screen and for identifier I'm going to paste in what I have copied previously.
So now I'm doing my Segway to navigation controller so that navigation bar will be still in place even
though we add on the place and come back to our places we have controller.
So let's test this as well.
Let's go to.
As you can see it works out fine right now.
Let's go to add a new place and let's add LA's diner and this will be a diner and the atmosphere is
kind of a friendly atmosphere and let's go for our photo library and choose one of the pictures that
we have downloaded and let's go to choose a location within our Amsterdam map.
So let's zoom in.
Yep.
This one looks good.
And off to you press for three seconds hit save.
And the moment of truth.
Here you go we see the last diner we see the Kirk pub at the James restaurant and we see it's in and
navigation controller so that we can come over here and go back and it works as they as in the way we
want.
So I hope you enjoyed this section.
I believe this is working very fine.
And I believe you can do much more better using power servers.
So you have seen far your base you have seen pars now you're capable of building apps using cloud servers
and you can do much more than you would imagine when you first started this course.
So let's stop here and continue within the next section.