Hi.
We didn't this lecture we're going to see how we can get free and great images to use it on our own
games.
So this is one of the most important aspects of the game right.
Because if the visuals if the images are not good then people won't use our game even if we do it in
a very well structure.
So let me open a Web site called open game art dot org.
So this is open game art.
And in here you will see a lot of images and lot of visuals to use it in your games.
In fact you can use most of the images here for free in your apps and month for just testing purposes
are not just for educational purposes but you can actually put them on the App Store as well.
So come over here to choose one of them or you can come over here to browse for to the arts for example
or 3D arts or any other things like textures music you can just click one of the items over here to
see the license and copyright attribution notice as well as you can see this is public so you can just
come over here and use it on your own.
Yay.
And since we're building an Angry Birds clone what we need is actually a bird right.
Which seems to be angry.
So I'm going to come over here to search bar search for bird as you can see we have a lot of birds catches
over here.
So I like is the blue one down below.
But you can go for other ones as well as you can see it says that free game sets.
So it's completely free I believe.
I'm going to go with this.
So this is a flying bird and it looks like it's kind of an Angry Bird.
So I'm going to use it anyway.
And if you want to have more than one image which is the case most of the time you you're more than
welcome to download this but also you're more than welcome to check the other assets of the same altar
as well.
I'm going to show you how to do that.
So let me just create an Angry Bird image downloads folder so that I can stack my images or here.
So let me open this.
OK.
Now let me delete this and let me go for PSG file over here and as you can see we have four versions
of this bird so that we can use it on our game.
I'm going to use only one of these images but it's nice to have far so that we can use whatever we want.
Right.
So how can you check the same out there for different kinds of images so that we will be consistent
in our game using the same kind of image in here you will see the outer name like this is be ruling
dot com if you click on it you will see the other images from the same author.
So as you can see same author has same kind of style.
So I can take any image from here that I want I can use it on my own game to be consistent with the
images to be consistent with the art.
So let's search for other images like I want to have a tree I want to have a background I want to have
some bricks I will search for them inside of this all through of course if I cannot find I can go back
and find something else anytime I want from some other alter as well but it's nice to have the same
old.
So when I like something I will open it in a new tab.
OK.
And then I will choose what to download later on and I believe this is much better than the previous
three that we have found because it looks like some slingshot as well so that we can use it as a slingshot
to throw our bird as you can see we have great images over here.
For example I used this grumpy bee in one of my games before.
So it's kind of neat to come over here to get free images and use it on your own game.
So this open game art that art is actually a very good Web site for developers who try to build their
own game but don't know how to design new stuff.
So here we have some wooden bricks.
I'm going to open it as well because we will need some birth of wood and bricks as I said before and
I believe this looks good.
OK.
And we have some three and I believe I'm going to go for this one because this looks like a slingshot
more than the other.
So let me try to borrow some more because we need a background as well to use as a background in our
own game.
And as you can see we have a pink birth here as well we can use some different kinds of birds if we
want to.
So here we have a free background.
Yep that's what I was looking for.
So I'm going to open this one and I will continue to browse this to see if we get another think.
So here we have some cool characters cool monsters we have some other free background as well.
Let me open this.
And again we have some other free background as well.
And here you go.
We have other birds other monsters.
I'm not going to use those in our game in order to not make things too complicated right now but I believe
we are good to go with the backgrounds that we have found.
So let me try to see what what is the difference between these backgrounds that we have found.
So far we have our chief we can just download this.
OK.
And we have our bricks.
Well we can just download this as well.
But let's choose a background from here.
So this is one background and this is some nicer background I believe this has some kind of pink mountains
and I believe this is the same thing as before.
Right.
So it looks like the same thing to me.
So I'm going to go either this or that.
So let me try to download this.
So this is two hundred thirteen kilobytes.
And this has exactly the same size.
So I believe they're are the same anyway.
So we're good to go with the first one.
If you don't want to spend time downloading all of this you can of course get it from my github page
as well.
So let me go to Angry Birds and let me try to unzip all of these files.
OK.
So I'm going to use archival utility and let me double click on others as well so that we will check
to see if we really get the images that we want.
So let me go over here to background and here you go I believe that's good.
We can use this as a background in our game.
Right.
So let's close this down and let's go for this one.
Yep.
This is good as well.
Our old tree and in here we have a break.
So this is one brick.
This is two bricks and this is tree bricks.
So I'm going to use one brick and we can copy and paste bricks in our game if we want to.
So let's bring all of these images into our assets folder so let me open my game and go to assets and
let's open our downloads folder as well.
We have to rename them because we going to use the name anyway.
So I'm going to call this Burt.
I'm going to bring this in.
OK.
Let's go for the background.
I'm going to rename this as background and let's bring this in as well.
Come over here two three.
I'm going to name this tree.
Let's bring this in one more time.
And for the last one we're going to use this brick.
OK so I'm going to name this brick.
And here you go.
Now we have what we need in terms of images in terms of textures so textures is a neat term that we
are going to be using in this section.
Don't worry we're going to see whether this.
Now you're ready to test our images we're ready to go into the game scene that SDK.
We're going to do that in the next lecture.