Hi within this lecture we going to finalize our app with adding some scoring functionality.
So far we can detect this collision and when this happens I want to increase my score by 1 but I don't
even have a score variable and I don't even have a score labeled right now.
So let's go over here and create them.
I'm going to create a simple variable called score and this will be initially zero.
I'm going to create a score labeled and this will be an S.K. label note.
So rather than having a sprite note we are having a label node over here so this is spatially designed
for bringing in labels for our games.
So let's go back to our did move to function and we're going to create our label.
So we have actually created our variable but we're going to give it some properties over here and I'm
going to say something like that font name and let's how Helvetica for font name.
OK.
Later on we're going to have a font size as well.
So let's try something like 60.
And if it's if it's is too big we can change it later on and let's go for our score labeled text.
It will be initially zero.
OK.
And then we can try to specify the position of this core label with a C.G. point.
So this will ask me for an X and Y.
I'm going to say 0 4 x because I want it to be in the middle of the screen but for y I'm going to say
something like soft dot frame that's height divided by four.
And I believe we have to say score labeled dot position.
Again not position z position again and make it two so that it will be in the front of everything every
time.
And later on I can just say s dog Ed Child score label like we did before.
So let's try this.
So if it's too high or too low we can change this Y.
But I believe that's perfect.
That's what I want.
So let me try to change this.
Let me try to increase the score by push the bird.
And when I hit one of the boxes so let me run this and you will see something strange maybe.
So let me try to just push this.
And it is you can see when I hit one of these screen edges the contact gets cold.
So it will add my score to one when I hit something other than boxes as though it's because of our collision
bit mask type of Bert and we're going to take care of that.
But I just want to show you that it really doesn't work in a way that we want.
So I'm going to come over here and rather than printing this contact I'm going to add one to our score.
I'm going to make my score labeled not text to be string of score right.
So that you can see for yourselves.
Now when I just push my bird and then it just hits one of the edges it will add one to my score like
here.
So I just make my bird hit the edge like this.
It will add score and that's not what I want.
I just want to add my score when I hit the boxes.
OK so that's what I want to change.
So come over here to collegian bit mask rather than saying bird over here to call either type I want
to make sure that this is bucks and this is bird over here and it's correct but I just want to detect
the collisions between boxes and birds.
So you have to go like this in the box you set it to Bert and in the bird you set it to bucks.
So when I do that right now it doesn't increase my score because it doesn't detect the collision at
all.
But when I hit one of the boxes it increases my score.
So that's good.
That's what I wanted.
OK.
And off to you reset the position of the bird.
You may want to reset the number as value you may want to reset the score as well.
So if you want to do that you can just come over here to update function and just change discard variable
if you don't want to do that.
It's okay as well but if you want to do that you can just come over here as a zero as car labeled that
text is string score so that it will reset the position and it will do reset the score and then you
can set the game started to the false.
So let's try that.
Let's push our bird it hits and it resets.
So that's good.
That's what we wanted to create.
Of course using this Sprite kid techniques using this physical work that we're provided by the sprite
kid you can create whatever you want after you complete the course after you're certain that you're
capable or you're comfortable working with Swift.
You can just try to enhance your sprite kid's skills a little bit and you can create much better games
using the same techniques.
I hope you enjoyed this section were you going to snap here and continue within the next section.