Hi we didn't this lecture we going to see what is trucked is and why do we have to use them in our projects.
And why do we choose them over classes sometime.
So as you can see it's kind of a class it's similar to class but it's very different technically.
So I'm going to tell you all about these differences and I'm going to tell you about the theory of the
strikes first and then later on we're going to see them in practice so that we will have a complete
understanding of strokes versus classes.
OK so strikes and classes are kind of similar but they have dared these advantages and advantages.
First of all the biggest this advantage of the struct is the inheritance.
OK.
So strikes do not have inheritance while classes have.
So remember the intermediate swift section.
We used classes to create models.
We used classes to create a musician model for example and we created a super musician which inherited
the methods and attributes of the musician class and we could have used all these methods and attributes
inside of the super musician as well.
We cannot do that instructs.
So this is one of the biggest differences and I believe this is the only disadvantage of destruct.
In fact Apple suggests to use struct.
Most of the time and if you ever going to work with inheritance if you ever need inheritance then you
just switch to the classes.
So April suggests using strikes over classes.
OK.
Why is that.
Because strikes are actually faster and simpler and the main technical reason for that is they they
run on stacks rather than heap.
So maybe you have heard these terms before their kind of memory management storage management objects
or tools residing inside of RAM.
So if you come over here and just search for heap versus tech GOOG in Google you will have like a millions
of results so you can just go along with any of these results and see for yourself.
So we use tech and heap for memory allocation for memory management and you will see a lot of explanations
in C programming language because this is actually related to programming and computer size.
So when the subject is that basic when the subject is that essential people tend to teach people tend
to explain things in C programming language.
Of course we don't have to understand C in order to understand stack and heap memory allocation.
We have to understand how they work so they actually store some memory for us they actually store some
data they actually store some values for us so that we can go and take that value from RAM and RAM is
used for short term memory as you might know and in our iPhones and in our iPods of course we have RAM
and we use that memory allocation tools so heap works on fearful first in first out principle.
On the other hand stack works on a fellow first in last out principle so whatever first whatever value
stored in stack first it gets out last.
So this gives us faster and simpler operations.
Okay.
And then classes since we use heap we use reference types so when we create an object with our classes
we actually create a reference to that object inside of the heap but instructs b don't create a reference
as we create values we create another object for example when we copy an object inside of a class.
It means that we create another reference when we copy an object inside of a struct.
It means that we're actually copying and creating another object.
So this gives us faster and simpler operations in struct.
Of course you cannot stands right now because you had to see this in practice and you will see in the
next lecture.
Don't forget the last thing you may want to know about struck.
They give us the opportunity to work with true immutability where as in classes we don't have that feature
and we will see that in action as well.
Everything I'm telling you right now will be put in action during this section so that you will understand
it much better.
I'm just trying to compare the class and strike right down so that you would understand.
They're similar but they have some disadvantages and advantages over each other.
The final advantage of the class is that they work with objective c.
While we cannot work with objective c in the struggle but I believe that's not a very big disadvantage
because we generally use Swift.
Right now we know you development.
However I believe only this advantage of district is the inheritance.
Let's see all of this in action so you will understand that in a much better way.