Hi within this lecture we're going to see the difference between a reference type and value type.
But before we go on and do that we have to understand the immutability part as well.
As I've said before obstructs actually provide us to opportunity to work with to immutability.
So what do I mean.
So I created this class with left and I created the struct with the left.
So I created both of them with constants.
Right.
Can I come over here and say class that James.
Our Class James that age is 51.
And can I print it.
Let's try that.
OK.
So first I get this.
Okay so let me comment this out.
I know the initial value of this 50.
Can I get 51 one in here.
Yep.
I kept so we can do that and we have seen we can do that before but can I do that with struct James.
Let's try to give fifty one here and let's try to prevent this strike.
JAMES That's H.
Let's run this.
I couldn't even run it because as you can see it says that's Chuck James is a.
Constance.
So why does it happen.
How could I change the age of this class James.
But how couldn't I change the strike.
James H.
So if I come over to class I will see that this age is variable.
That's why I could have changed it but it's variable inside of struct as well.
So as you can see we don't expect this to be happening but in order to change the attributes of a struct
you have to declare it as a variable in the first place.
So if I do this if I change it to work then this error will go away.
And if I run it I will see 51 51.
So this gives us both options if we want to have a true immutability which means that if I just defined
it as a constant and I don't get to change the attributes as well but if I want to change the attributes
later on I have to define it as a variable.
So we have both options in the struct in class even do I do it with left.
It lets me change the attribute.
So this is for mutability and immutability part.
OK.
Immutable struct.
And now we're going to focus on reference and value types.
So remember classes are reference types where as districts are value types and best way to understand
the behavior difference between them is to copy an object.
So we're going to copy this truck James and we're going to also copy the Class James as well.
So let me create another variable called copy of Class James.
Okay.
And I'm gonna make this equal to Class James and I'm going to do the same thing for struct as well because
I'm going to compare the behavior differences between them.
So this is going to be struck James.
So I'm basically copying this and I have to define this as var in order to overcome this immutability
problem.
Okay.
And I can define the copy of class as var as well.
But I'm not going to deal with those because it's already immutable.
So if I print the copy of Class James that's H and if I print copy of struct James that's h what will
happen.
Of course we're going to get fifty one again.
Right.
As you can see we we are getting 51 because we have changed them to be 51.
Now can I just change the age of our copy struct or copy class.
Yep.
Of course.
Can I come over here and say copy of Class James that age is now 52.
And can I do that with stroke as well.
Yep because I declared it as a variable right.
So I can do that.
So let me print those ages one more time and see if we have a different behavior than we expect.
Now let's run this.
And here you go we have 51 51 52 52.
So there is no unexpected thing going on here.
So where is this surprise the surprise will come if you print the Class James that age and class struck
James that age.
So did we change the age of the class James and did we change the age of the strike.
JAMES No we didn't.
So we expect to see 51 51 when we print this.
Right.
So we are going to be seeing 51 51 52 52 and then 51 51.
So that's what my mind tells me.
But if I run this I'm going to get a very weird results.
So I'm getting 50 one one Yep that's good 52 52 but I'm getting 52 as the Class James that age I didn't
even change it why does this happen.
So this is happening because classes are actually referenced types.
So when I create a new class of new objects out of the same object it doesn't create a new object for
me.
It just creates a new reference to the heap to find that object where as in this trucks we don't work
with heap.
We work with stack.
So in the stack we create a new value new object.
So when I change the class James copy of Class James H.
It actually changes the class.
James age as well so reference types are associated with classes and this is what happens when i copy
an object.
I copy the object and it just creates a new reference rather than creating a new object.
So same object with never reference pointing to the heap to find that object.
So we have multiple references with a one object in this case well we can't do that for multiple occasions
so we will end up with a lot of references trying to work on the same object.
It's kind of dangerous because we might lose track from some point on but however in struggles we don't
have that right.
So in here we have one objects okay and we have two references on the other hand then we work with the
value types and it's associated with the struct when we say copy it goes and creates a new object so
new objects rather than creating a new reference so we end up with two objects so that when we change
the age of the needle copy cat we won't change the age of the previous struct objects.
So this is very important in struct we deal with value types in in classes we deal with reference types
and the logical way of thinking is to work with struct because we create a new value and Apple actually
suggests that as I said before they say that you have to work with struct as much as possible.
And if you're really looking forward to work with a reference type or if you're have to work with an
inheritance type then you're going to go to classes but again then you will have to be careful because
if you create more than one reference you can mess up with some values add at some certain point without
even noticing it.
So that's it for the major difference between district and the class.
We're going to have to see something called mutating function in order to understand this completely.
That's what we're going to do within the next lecture.