Hi within this lecture we're going to learn a new concept called tuples.
So tuples provides us tools to store collection of data.
So it's kind of airy but it has a different structure and so far we haven't been using tuples.
But this is an advance with section.
So you have to know how tuples work.
So if you work with them in the future or if you encounter one of the tuple returning functions then
you will know what to do.
Let me comment out this prince so that we can continue within the same mean that swift and we will have
our own tuple lecture.
So let me show you how to create a tuple and how to store data in it.
So it's very simple actually.
You can just say my tuple and you open one parentheses and it's a regular parentheses it's not an array
parentheses or it's not an dictionary parentheses it's a regular parentheses and you can just write
whatever value you want inside of it like an integer or a string or a boolean or even an array.
So it goes like this open the parentheses and say 1 3 for example you put comma to differentiate between
these values.
OK.
So this is the first element and this is the second element.
And how does it differ from the array.
So when you create a tuple you may want to get one of these elements by just going to another line and
say My tuple and as you can see it's an Integer Integer tuple right now because we defined it.
So if you say dot you can just choose the zero in order to get the first element.
OK.
So let me print this out and you will see we will get the one integer right like this.
If you say my tuple that form of course you will get treat.
So this is how tuples work if you want to save a couple of cardinals for example or if you want to save
another couple then tuples might be for you.
Of course we can do it like this if you want to have a triple number.
You can just define it and you can just call 0 1 or 2.
So for example if I call too it will just give me five.
So this has the same index logic of the array.
So can I do that.
Can I change the to pull value.
So let me try to print out my two pull dots too and you will see we cannot do that in order to do this.
We have to define my tuple as a variable rather than constant.
So this is one of the difference between tuples and arrays.
So you can just create a variable tuple but if you don't want to change the elements later own you can
create it as a constant.
So let's see some other examples of tuples to understand them better.
For example let me created to poultry.
OK.
So it will have a string and then no inside of it like let my tuple tree will be my name like a tail
and we can have a number in inside of my tuple as well.
And if you write my tuple tree you will see that this is a string to integer tuple.
OK.
Can I just have strings or integers.
Of course not.
I can create a tuple with an array.
For example let me try to create it like I can come over here I say turn.
But then I can open an array and I can send 10 20 30 for example in my tuple for how can I reach the
number 20.
So try to post the video and try to print it on your own.
So it goes like this my tuple for OK.
If you say dot and if you say one it will give you the array of integers.
Yep this one.
And if you open a parentheses and you an index here like zero it will give you 10.
If you go to the index one it will give you to any.
Right.
So that's how you reached the number 20.
So can I predefined the values that a tuple is going to get.
Of course I can.
Like I can't predefined a variable to be a string like this.
Right.
So we can say let my string is going to an optional strike and this will take only the value of a string
not an integer.
So I can do that for tuples so I can say let predefined tuple is going to be as drink two string tuple.
OK so that I can just come over here and say predefined tuple that 0 is a 2 and predefined tuple that
one is some for example and if I run this nothing will happen because I didn't even print it out.
So let me say print predefined tuple and it will print out this string to string tuple as you can see.
Now we have the LTL stamp in a tuple.
So can I predefined the keys of the values.
Yep I can do that as well.
For example let me create a new tuple and in here I'm going to say a name.
And this will be a James and the Metallica member boolean.
Yep.
This will be true for example.
And now we stead of saying to pulled out one or two people that zero I can just say print nil tuple
dot Metallica or print need to pull that name.
So this is another difference between arrays and tuples I can just predefined these keys of the values
inside of a tuple as well.
So this is cool right.
I can just come over here and say new tuple dots.
Name new to pulled up Metallica.
So this is how you work with tuples and in swift you won't come across tuples such often but in another
programming languages like in python you will just see them a lot.
And if you come across a library or a module that returns tuple then you know how to do it.
You know how to work with them right now.
And of course you can create your own tuples and you can effectively store a couple of data or a cheap
Bill of data inside of a tuple so that you can reach them later on.
So let's stop here and within the next lecture we're going to see a new concept called guards let's.