Hi we didn't this lecture regrowing to learn about speech case control statements.
In fact this is not a very advanced topic but we haven't had the chance to see this at this point.
So we are going to see this so that you know how to work with speech cases.
This is kind of an evil state but this is kind of fun if check but it has a rather different syntax
and rather different usage.
You're again to see what I mean.
So let me comment out this prince so we will have a good look.
Cat over here and let me comment.
Are these lines as well.
So we will have a clear look.
OK so now I believe yeah we have to comment out some other lines as well like this.
So let me run this one more time.
Yep.
Here we go we have a clear log.
Now let me come over here and show you the switch case usage.
And in order to do that I'm going to show you the remainder sine text as well.
We haven't seen this before as well so that we will learn two subjects in this lecture.
For example I have an integer called my num and it's eleven.
So what if I want to know what we like get as a remainder if I divide eleven by two.
So if I divide eleven by two I will get the remainder of 1.
Right.
If I divide it by tree I will get the remainder of two right.
Five divided by four.
I will get the remainder of three.
Yep you can do this easily on your mind but if it was a too large number then you would have the difficulty.
So let me show you how this goes with Swift.
So you're right.
My NUM and have a percent sign over here like this.
OK.
And then say the number that you want to divide it.
That for example.
Now let me print out this might remain the variable and you're getting a see it's going to print out
one because if I divide eleven by two it will be one.
If I divide eleven by three.
The remainder will be two.
So it's working.
So if I divide my number by for her they remain there will be three.
Yep.
Now it's working.
Now suppose that I want to have an if check on this remainder.
So let me write this if my remainder is 1 then I'm just going to print out it's 1.
OK.
So it will be like this and as if my remainder is.
Is 2 I'm going to print out it's two and then one more time.
Else if my remainder is three then I'm going to print out it's three.
So it goes like this.
So you understand these structure right now.
Now if I around this of course is going to print out it's three and it's working but we can do this
easily with switch case as well.
So let me show you how to do that.
How to do the same thing with switch case control statements.
So switch cases can be very helpful if you have a lot of else if statements.
So it goes like does you say switch.
OK.
You use the switch keyword and then you have to specify the variable that you're going to switch the
value.
So in our case it's my remainder.
OK so I'm going to write switch and say My remainder OK and then I'm going to open a curly brace and
this will be my coding block but this time rather than saying if or else if or anything I'm going to
bring in some case keyword.
So this means that if the value of my remainder is one then what I'm going to do as you can see I'm
using a column this time rather than curly brace and it's the first time that we're seeing this but
it's the syntax for switch case.
So if you say Case 1 and hit enter you can't write what will happen if this is one.
So I'm going to print out Case 1 it's 1 and in the case 2 I'm going to say it's 2 OK.
And in case 3 I'm going to say print it's three and we have to provide a case default over here as well.
So default means if this doesn't fall into any category that I have defined a bow.
Then this will have this value.
So this is kind of an else statement.
And I will just called is none of the above.
So if I run this right now I will get the exact same result that I got in my if control statements.
OK so let me comment this out so that we can see the switch.
So let me come over here.
If I run this you will see it saying that it's tree.
Now it's working.
And you know how to run switch cases and sometimes it's a lot easier to work with switch cases because
you can do this as well.
So you can say that case one two three.
And let me delete all of this and if the case is between 1 and 3 then it will print out one two three.
So if you have a lot of else is done just remember that you can use switch cases in order to write this
more efficiently.
And if you have a case like this where you can specify some range from 1 to 50 for example again switch
cases will be very helpful for you.
Now let's stop here and within the next lecture we are going to see breakpoints.