Hi.
We didn't does lecture regrowing to learn about breakpoints.
So breakpoints are literally the points that we want to take a break from running the code.
So it's spelled like this and I'm going to show you a showcase and in here I believe we have to comment
on the sprints so that we worlds have a clear lock cat over here.
OK.
So let me comment on this as well.
And let me come over here to have a very simple example.
And this gives me an error because we have to have some statement in this switching case.
So let me live this as it is.
We will see this.
It's one two three thing but it won't matter.
For example I'm going to create a variable over here.
OK.
And I'm going to assign this to be a number and then later on I'm going to change this number and I'm
going to try to figure out that I am changing this number.
So let me say that.
Let x is five and let's make it variable rather than constant because we're going to change it.
And let's bring it up does X and then later on I'm going to add the wanted as X and printouts one more
time for example let's suppose that I have a very complex code in my project and I'm trying to put the
value of x in a label.
So it prints out six as it's supposed to.
As you can see it prints out five and then six.
And because it's really six but for some reason suppose that I cannot figure out why it's printing out
six or why it's showing six in the labels.
So I'm trying to find that I'm adding one to this.
For example if I click over here in the line 158.
Now when I run this it will stop my code.
It will stop executing my code at the break point like I have crashed the application of course it's
not a crash it's just a breakpoint and it will give me a perch unity to debug this code.
And as you can see now we see all the variables all the objects that we have created in this file and
also we see the values we see the current values that are assigned to those variables.
So this is a very good very comprehensive information to debug.
Now I can just see that my ex is 5 for example.
So I know before line 1 Von 58 I believe Yep before line 58 158.
It was okay.
It was still five.
Now if I come over here to 159 and I can just drag this and drop over here to delete it and if I run
this one more time then I will see old values one more time and now I see my ex is six.
Now I can know that I know that before line 1 58 it was 5.
Now I'm having this issue in line 158.
Of course this is too obvious and you cannot understand the importance of this but in a very complex
code you would find this very helpful to stop the code and see all the values assigned to all the variables
because maybe you're not looking for a single value maybe you're looking for a data that you download
from the Internet or maybe you're looking for a very complex set of areas.
OK.
So either case this will be very helpful when you try to debug your code and begin there is actually
by accident tap on these lines and they add breakpoints and they don't know how to delete them.
So you can beat them by dragging them out of your code.
So that's it.
Let's stop here and continue within the next section.