Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to see what s tech is and we're going to play with this views so that
we can get a hold of swift UI.
So we have this text and text is some kind of a label E side of our swift UI framework.
We use it to show strings we use it to show text to the user.
For example if you say dot after the text you can just choose any attribute any method you want.
For example if you choose bold it will make your text bold.
Right.
So let's see another one.
If you just say dot you can come over here to change the font for example and it asks you for a font
and if you hit dot over here you will see some options like a color like a caption or look like a large
title.
Just choose the large title and you will see that it will increase your form size.
Let's try something else like footnote for example and still make it a lot smaller compared to the large
title.
So that's how it goes.
That's how you can add some new features like this.
You can just hit that once again and try to make it bold after you change the font.
Of course you can continue experimenting does by adding some new features like adding dots and trying
to find some options that is relative to texts but there is another way to do that if you don't know
anything about who you are.
You can come over here by hitting comment on your keyboard.
If you click on text you will see a menu like this.
You have to go does inspect menu and it will give you something like an attributes page.
Okay so remember in the main story birds we had that through Spain and we could have changed any attribute
that we want.
This is something like that.
It EC exactly lets lists the common attributes come on options that you can change over here like found.
And if you want you can just change it from there as well.
For example let me go for a headline and will do headline code over here.
So it adds the code automatically if you choose it from this menu.
So you can see how to add this how to add those codes by choosing from this menu for example a color
just I want to make this blue.
So it added the foreground color color that blue automatically.
So I know right now how to change the color so I come over here I can change the alignments but it won't
make sense because we're stuck in this frame and we're going to see what the frame is later on.
But I can change it by clicking over here.
Right.
So this is good.
This is very cool.
We can't even change the tax from here as well.
So this lists the common attributes that we can change from here Come on properties and don't hesitate
to use this inspection menu whenever you come across a new view to see what you can actually change.
So we have this frame over here and it refers to this blue line wrapping around our text and we going
to see what it is later on.
It actually defines the size of our view but I believe view.
Good to go with images when it comes to frame to understand it better.
So right now what if I want to add another view on top of this view.
Can I just do that like hello world.
OK.
Will it show up.
Nope it will give me an error because it may sound stupid right now but you can only return one view
inside of her body.
So you may think that you do I get to have one view in swift UI in every screen from now on of course
not.
There is some bypass to this problem as well.
And we're going to use it a lot in other projects.
It's called Stack.
OK so we're going to create this stack and we're going to wrap everything around as tags so that we
can return everything inside of that act like this.
So if you say we stack and open and curly brace and then you can just stack whatever you want inside
of that V stack like this.
So take everything and put it inside your Fritzi stack and you will see that this new tax will show
up and you will see the hello world and hello to you as well.
Now in this buddy I'm just returning the V stack and inside of that we stack I'm doing what I want.
So right now I can just add as many views as I want inside of this vertical stack and V stands for verticals.
Tech is stacked so we stack the views inside of the stack and we have other options as well.
For example if I want to sack views horizontally there is an eight stack to do that just change V to
H and you will see they will be side by side like this.
So this is horizontal stack.
And the again this is we stack and as you can see I can use this V stack and I can use that a stack
in order to have structural stacking of my views.
For example right now I'm using this vertical sack but my views are actually very close to each other.
So I want to move them further away a little bit.
So I have to come over here to one of them and add the padding as you can see this blue frame wrapping
around our helo world just got expanded and it's called frame.
As I said before it actually determines what size will our view hold.
As you can see in the helo swift UI now I'm just wrapping around it.
So if I say padding over here as well it will just expense and it will move.
Hello World further away.
So that's how you add a padding to actually sets your views up so that they will have the size that
you want and they will have the margin of space that you want Reagan to work with frame with images
in order to understand it better later on in the next lecture.
Don't worry.
And aside from waist tag and 8 SAG we also have something called disease tech as well.
So if we change it to Z you will see that they will overlap and this is kind of z position that we have
seen in the sprite kids.
OK so this defines reach ever view is going to be shown first and it doesn't make sense in this case.
But if I had an image is rather than hell of world.
If I want to write something on that image okay.
That that would make sense to use this tech.
In this case of curse we don't have to use these tech.
I'm going to go with the V stack in order to have a proper look.
So that's it for stacks.
That's why we use taxing swift UI so we're going to stop here and within the next picture we're going
to dig a little deeper and understand swift UI features better.