Hi.
We did this lecture.
We're going to work with lists so we don't have a table we use inside of swift UI but rather we have
lists.
So come over here and create a new Swift UI file.
I'm going to call this turd veal and really daring to see how to work with lists because as you know
we work with table views a lot and we have to know the substitute of that method inside of swift UI
as well.
So suppose that I have an array inside of my struct over here and I want to display those elements the
elements of the array inside of a list.
So traditionally we do that with table view but now we're going to have a list and arrows of data.
So let me create my area over here under my struct but not inside of my body.
OK so my array will have the values of James.
LAUGHS Okay.
Kirk I rob.
So that's what I want to display inside of lists.
So how do I do that rather than having this text I'm going to go for a list.
So let me delete this and just write list so dirt two ways to do that actually and as you can see this
presents the rows of data range in a single column.
So if you choose the list and open a curly brace there are two ways to do that you can use a for loop
or for each loop or you can just give this array as a parameter inside of your list so open the parentheses
and choose your array.
Now after doing that you have to create your own closure and in order to do that you just going to have
to come right to your curly braces K after your curly braces.
You have to a sign some variable to hold the individual holding the individual elements like this element
in.
So that will assign every assign everything inside of your list to an element and you can just come
over here and say text elements.
Now what this will do is this is going to take James.
This is going to take Lars Kirk and rob one by one and assign it to be an element every going to show
them inside of a text.
It has to work but right now as you can see it gives us an error so maybe we can see over here.
In this case this is correct but just keep in mind that swift UI doesn't show some very quality error
messages at least for right now.
So if you get any error message it might not be the message that you are looking for.
So if you do something and if you get an error message somewhere else then just check what you have
done last.
Okay.
I know this is not ideal but does it.
That is the case for a swift UI right now.
But in this case this error message is actually correct.
We have to make this array identifiable and we're going to see how to do that structurally within a
model later on.
But right now we're going to do it manually what means identifiable is that the list has to understand
which index it will show the elements.
Okay.
So we're going to use the same index as our array right now but later on we are going to create some
identifiable models and they will have their own ideas and in order to make this work right now I'm
going to assign this I.D. manually over here.
After I just give this my array as a parameter to my list.
So if you say come up and say I.D. after works as you can see it pops up then over here we have to say
something like backslash dot self.
Okay.
So this means to use the array indexes and as you can see V how James Lars Kirk and Rob displaying inside
of a list.
So this is how you work with lists.
This is how you work this work with a race inside of swift UI.
It's actually easier than it looks.
You create the list you you the array is a parameter and you display it in a way that you want and you
can't change the font.
You can add whatever you want inside of your list as well.
So this does have to be some prototype cell that we have seen before.
For example I can even add an image over here easily.
I can just call the Metallica image.
Okay.
And as you can see now with displays in each row it's too big.
So I'm going to make this very sizable.
And then later on I'm going to set the aspect ratio to be fit.
OK.
The content most to both fit.
And then later on I'm going to give a very small frame so that we can display them inside of our lists
our rows like this.
So this is very easy to do with swift UI as you can see in traditional Main storyboards.
We had to create a new cell and we had to create an swift file for that so and we had to work our way
around this.
But right now I just did it with a simple line.
So that's very cool.
That's one of the powerful features of swift UI as well.
And as I said before this is not the only way to display data inside of lists.
Actually there is another way but this list is actually much better and much easier to work with.
So I suggest you go for this unless you have a specific reason to do the second method that I'm about
to show you.
The second method actually let me just comment this out for right now.
OK.
So let me come over here and after opening this parentheses I have to close this as well.
So inside of my list I'm going to do a for loop.
So this time I'm going to go four for each loop.
So this is kind of for loop but rather than saying four elements inside of list we are going to say
for each array in that element.
OK.
So this is vice versa.
In terms of sine texts.
Let me show you what I mean.
I'm going to give my array as a parameter inside of my list and I have to say I.D. backslash that s
one more time I'm going to open my curly braces and then I'm going to close it and have my own closure
one more time and then I can just say text elements.
So this is exactly the same as I did in the list but I'm doing it with a for each loop but if you if
you want to bring in an image right now you will have a problem over here.
So that I suggest you go for the list and give the array as a parameter to the list.
And if you have a specific reason to use the for each loop then you can come over here and use it as
well.
We're going to see both examples later on when we deal with an app.
But just know that this is the way to go to create table we use to create rows of data and work inside
of arrays with inside of swift UI.
So let's stop here and within the next picture we're going to see how to work with data inside also
if the UI is about.