Hi.
We didn't this lecture were you going to see how to work with data in swift UI and how to create buttons
to create our own actions.
So let's go and open another view because we're going to work in a different view and we have our own
preview so that we can do that.
But I never we won't.
So let's go and create the new suite to iView.
Okay.
And I'm going to call this fourth view and let's come over here and bring this for you to the top and
on heater is you.
So what I want to do in this lecture is to create a variable.
Okay.
And we're going to change that variable for example right now we're displaying Heller wrote inside of
that tax.
Why if I want to create a variable and display that variable inside of this text.
Can I do that.
Yep.
Of course we can.
So make sure you create your rabble under your struct but above your body.
And I'm going to call mine my name.
OK.
So my name will be a till then rather than displaying hello world.
I'm going to display my name inside of this text.
So if I hit resume I will see a tail here.
So this is good.
Now I want to add a bottom and then I hit that button.
The name will change.
OK.
Can I do that.
Of course we can.
Let's see how we can achieve that result.
So I'm going to wrap this around the V stack because we're going to have more than one view.
OK I'm going to have my text and I'm going to have a button.
So if you write button over here you will see the button.
OK.
And if you open parentheses it will ask you for some parameters and the parameters that we are looking
for is the action and the labels.
So the action is the actual action if you hit enter over here it will create a coding block for you
in which you can write your own code.
And whenever you tap on this button this will happen.
OK.
We're going to change our my name variable inside of this action and for label for label we generally
just hit enter and write whatever we want inside of that label for example at text or if we just want
to show an image for a button then we can just bring in the image.
But this time if I hit enter it will create a weird coding block for me a closure for me and I don't
need that closure K rather I'm going to delete everything regarding to that closure and I believe I
deleted the currently braces as well.
So after the action you can just open your own curly brace and or here you can just write text and just
choose your own bottom text like my button.
And as you can see as I type it will appear on the right hand side.
And as you can see now we see the button over here and the good thing about this preview is that you
can hit this light by them and make your preview live so that you can actually test the actions as well.
So right now I don't have any action but if I had I can just click over that button using this preview
rather than opening the simulator and I can just test the actions like navigation like button and everything
inside of this preview.
So for example I can hit my button right now.
Nothing will happen because I didn't write anything.
So let me give a padding to my text because they are really close to each other and in fact let me just
give some large title to this phone so that we can see the name better.
OK.
So this is much better and under my button action I want to change this name.
Right.
So how do we do that.
It's fairly easy in swift.
Right.
You can just say right My name is something else like James for example and this should change my name
but we cannot do that.
As you can see it says that self is immutable and we get this problem but we work with struct so remember
instructs we have the possibility of to immutability even we had to use some mutating functions in order
to meet sates our way bills in side of these functions when we deal with structure before.
And in this case we have to change this variable right because Mary's side of this button and we cannot
have some constant variables every time and we have to change the variable.
At some point in our app.
So if you add state in front of your rainbow and of course you have to add s that as well then this
will be okay.
And this at State signed text is appropriate to wrapper.
Then you add this at State.
It means that you get to change the variable and also then you change the variable.
It will re render the whole view so that you can actually see the change inside of your preview or inside
of your app as well.
For example let me run this and hit my button and as you can see now it saves James.
So whenever you make some variable at State variable it means that then you change it.
The view will get re rendered and we will see the change.
Now it works.
So do we have more like states.
Yep.
We have some more property wrappers as well.
So let me show you some tutorial on the map.
I have seen this block and I liked it so I'm going to share this link with you.
So let me just go over here and find it.
Yep this is the one so I don't know these guys.
So apparently he's called midgets but I believe he actually read.
He has actually written down the appropriate to represent a good structure and you cannot even find
that tutorial you cannot even find his explanations in the Apple Developer rep site right now.
So I have read this appropriate trappers and I believe they are actually very well written.
As you can see there are a lot of property wrappers and you're going to see the most common ones in
this section and unfortunately we won't have time to see everything related to swift UI.
That's a subject for a whole another course.
And in fact we have another course on Swift UI with code SaaS.
You can check this up if you want but again if you're capable of understanding everything about swift
if you're very good at Swift and U.S. development you can always go to developer dot apple dot com and
read the documentation and try to figure out on your own as well.
Because when you complete this course you will be more than comfortable to work with U.S. development
work with swift and create whatever project that you want.
But keep in mind that we're going to learn the basics the introduction part of the Swift UI and there
is much more things that you have to learn in order to master the swift UI as well.
So let's stop here and see one of the most important concepts called binding in the next lecture.