Hi.
We didn't this lecture we going to see a new concept called bindings and in order to do that I'm going
to create another file as usual.
OK I'm going to come over here and say Neil swift UI file and I believe this will be our fifth view.
OK so in this fifth we you I'm going to change our text one more time but rather than changing it constantly
I'm going to take the input from the user.
Okay.
So regrowing to use a text field along with our text as well.
So let me wrap this around the V stack because I'm going to have a text field just under my text and
text field is the actual text field that we have used before in storyboards as well.
Right.
So this is where we get input from the user.
When you open the parentheses it will ask you for some parameters.
Where are you going to go for the first one which asks for a title and a text.
So title is actually just a place holder and the text is the binding string and we going to see whether
this.
So in text fields in the texts side I'm just going to say place holder and it will display this message
if there is nothing on the text field.
OK but in the text I'm going to create a state variable as before and I'm again going to call this my
name and this time I'm going to go to James as my name initially.
OK.
And after that we're going to display James over here in the text section.
So this will display my name rather than hello world.
And I'm going to bind my name to the text fields.
So how do I do that.
And what does it even mean to bind something you will see if you write my name it will give you an error
it will say that yeah I'm asking for a binding string and you're just going to you're just trying to
give me a regular string rather than binding strings.
So how do we convert something to be binding.
You put dollar sign in front of the variable name.
Now it's bind that.
So it means that when we changed this text field value the state variable will also get changed.
OK.
And we get to see the change in the text as well since this is a state variable.
It will be re rendered.
So here we go.
Now we see the James in the text and we see the James in the text field.
So let me just bring this up a little bit by adding yet padding and just increasing the font size a
little bit so that we can see it better as as you can see now we see the James.
Now I want to change this text field so that this binding variable will get changed as well.
So let me click over here.
OK.
And you cannot see the keyboard but you can just type with your own keyboard.
And as you can see once I delete and once I add some characters this changes.
So this is very cool right.
In order to have something like this in all the regular main story boards we had to go for delegates
and we had to bring in some new functions on everything.
Of course we can't reach this result in old way as well.
But this time we're doing this just with one line we're just binding this variable to our text field
so that when we change this value the same variable will get changed and everything I showing that state
variable will also get re rendered and we will see the new result.
We will see the new value on that text as well.
So this is again one of the cool features of swift UI.
It may seem a little bit complicated when you compare it with previous methods like we didn't have this
binding game we didn't have this at state before.
But right now we have this.
And once you get to know this you will love it because you can actually create whatever you want with
swift UI in less time in less code and in a more structural way.
Now we have a lot more to learn regarding swift UI in order to do that.
I'm going to stop here.
I'm really going to start building an app.
It's called favorite book.
Every we'll just learn along the way when we built the app so we will get to practice what we have learned
so far and we will learn a lot more things along the way.