Hi.
We then this lecture regally to create our user model.
So what do I mean by that.
We have to upload the user name to the fires or when we hit the upload button in our Snapchat clone.
Right.
So let me come over here.
As you can see in the feed we've controller we going to get the data from five star and in the upload
we have controller we're going to upload the data to the your star.
But in the upload we have controller.
I also want to upload the user name.
Who made this snap.
Who made this post to the file year star.
And in order to get that I'm going to get it in the feed we have controllers so that I can share it
with my other view controllers as well.
So I don't want to run a five year base clergy in a review controller.
It wouldn't be efficient.
So I'm going to get that once in the feed view controller.
I'm going to share it with other controllers.
So that's what we're going to do within this lecture.
So let me create this five year base import this five year base in the Feed the controller.
OK.
And I'm going to get this under and they function because we're going to get a lot of things inside
of our feed view controller and getting user info is just one of them.
So I'm going to write this under a function.
So under this function I'm going to do a very simple thing first I'm going to create my five star database
variable.
OK.
So this will be five star instance as usual.
So far your store far your store and in the under get the user info I'm going to use this database to
reach my user info collection.
And here actually I'm just going to get the data sets.
So right now I have only one document.
Of course I will have like a thousand of them when this app is released.
So I'm going to filter my results with e-mail.
OK so I'm just going to get the data who matches my email.
So that's how I get the user name.
And by the way we don't have to add an snapshot listener in this case right.
We can just get this data once.
Remember when we want to check for updates we use this at snapshot listener.
But this time I don't need to listen for changes it won't even get changed so I can just use this dot
get documents to get this for once.
So remember these get documents.
Now we're going to use it.
So first of all let me filter this and the field that I'm looking for is the e mail.
OK.
And this will be equal to my user my signed in users email.
So all thought of that current user I can force I wrap this because I'm signed in right now and say
that's email.
So later on I can just say get documents and this will give me a snapshot.
BLOCK And let me close this down and once you hit enter on that you will either get a snapshot or an
error.
So now we're here if error is not nil.
We are going to display an error message to the user.
OK.
And if areas nail down we're going to go ahead and just pass this snapshots process this snapshot to
get the user name.
So let's do that.
If error is not mail.
OK.
So else and I believe we have to go back and find the make Ellard function in order to speed things
up.
So come over here.
Copy this come below and paste it so that we can use it over here.
OK.
If areas not nil I'm going to display an alert message to the user.
So this will be error.
This will be airdropped localised description.
And we're going to say error.
So if that's the case if error is nil then I'm going to check to see if snapshot is empty false.
OK.
And if snapshot is not nil.
So it means that I really have a snapshot because over here I'm going to say for document in snapshot
that documents and I'm going to force our app this I remember this gives us a snapshot array so that
we're just looping through this area.
And once we iterate that array I'm going to say document that get and I'm looking for the fields user
name right.
And if we say user name we can just cast his optionally as a string.
And of course I'm going to do if let's.
In order to get that.
So that's easy.
That's how we get data from the five year base and we already know about this.
But right now how I'm going to transfer this information to the other controllers.
That's the question.
So in order to do that I'm going to create another group which is called model and I'm going to create
my model in this folder.
Ok.
So I'm going to go ahead and create the new Swift file by right clicking over the model folder and I'm
going to say a file and choose swift file because you're going to create a class rather than that Coco
touch class.
So I'm going to call this something like user Singleton.
OK we could have just called it user but I believe there are other classes called user so I don't want
to confuse and make things complicated.
OK so I'm going to say.
Class User Singleton and open curly braces for some reason if you haven't watched the Foursquare close
section then you wouldn't know what a singleton class is.
It is a class you that you have only one instance.
OK.
So nobody can create any instance from this class but we will because we are going to have our initializing
function as private so that nobody will reach and create an instance of this class but rather we are
going to create this instance ourselves so that we can reach it from anywhere we want during this project.
So I'm going to create a static variable called shared instance.
And of course we can't call this something else.
We have used this shared instance term before.
I'm going to call this shared user information.
Not now series so shared user info.
So this will be our only user Singleton instance.
OK.
So that we are going to set some values and we're going to get this exact same values in other view
controllers and we're going to have an e-mail and the user name in this case.
So we're going to change this e-mail and user name and we can get the same values from other controllers.
So that's what we have used in the Foursquare clone.
So if you haven't watched it now you know how to work with Singleton classes.
So let me do a comment B and come over here so I can say user Singleton that shared user info dot e-mail.
OK.
So this will be the email of the user.
Of course you can use of lot of dots.
Current user dot email in order to get that.
OK.
And you can go for user Singleton That's shared user name for dot user name is the user name that we
have just created.
So here you go.
Now we have defined our user name into a singleton class so we can't come over our upload view controller
and we can easily reach that data or here.
I'm not even going to test this because we have done it before because in the next lecture regrouping
to upload a picture to the storage anyway and we're going to see if that works or not if it doesn't
work of course we can go back and revise our code.
So let's go to the next lecture.
We will upload our data.