Hi.
We didn't lecture we going to start building our feet.
We have controllers so that we can retrieve those data from fires start to display them to the user.
And right now we didn't inside of our field we have controller we don't even have a prototype so.
So I'm going to increase this to one and I'm going to create my prototype cell.
So you know how this works.
We have done it in the Instagram clone section right.
We're going to have only one big image over here displaying the image of the user the one of the snaps
of the users.
And on the top of that I'm going to show you the user name.
So lets me call this something like user name for right now just to be sure that this is the user name
label.
So let me make this central.
And here you go.
I believe that's good.
And we need another thing and this is image for you because we're going to display one of the snaps
in our post over here.
OK.
So we can make this as bigger as we want because we're only going to display this image and the user
name anyway.
OK.
So I believe that's good.
We will have this huge image showing up in our feet.
So I'm going to give this some who you say are suggests its constraints and I'm going to give a V then
height.
OK so here you go.
Now we are ready to create a new feed cell.
So let me come over here on say new file.
I'm doing this kind of fast because we know how this works.
So I'm going to go over my cocoa attach glass and I'm going to search for UI table view so ok not controller
about so.
So this will be our feed cell so that I can have a class at cocoa touch class in order to assign it
to my newly created cell.
So let's bring this in.
And I believe by mistake I put it on there we have controllers even though it's just a view but I'm
not going to bother with that.
OK.
We know it's just sitting right there.
So let me come over to my cell.
OK.
This one table we use cell.
And if you go to identity Inspector you can choose the feed cell.
And over here you had to give it an identifier as well.
I'm going to call it cell.
And then we have to bring those views in.
So let me come over here and in the assistant editor I'm going to go for our feed cell and over here
I'm going to bring in this image view.
I'm going to call this feed Image view.
OK.
And connect it and we're getting the same error that we have gotten previously.
So I believe we have to close this down and open it one more time to let it index.
So it's kind of an X gold bug but it's it just doesn't interfere with our work too much.
So I believe they will resolve it anyway.
So once you open them restart it's it will start indexing and once it completes you can try to bring
this in one more time and call it feed the Image view.
And here you go now it's working.
And then we're going to do the same thing for label as well.
So bring in the label and I'm going to call this feed label OK or feed the user name label.
So that's good.
So let me close this down and let me go to my feed we have controller.
OK.
Because we don't even have the table view set up yet.
So let me do these steps as well so I'm going to say this this table view delegates.
OK.
And also you I table view data source so remember how this works.
We have done it like a million times so I believe you can do it yourself as well.
So table we've got delegate self table view that's data source is self as well.
After we do that we have to call two functions.
I'm going to call number of rallies in section first.
And we need s for all with index path.
So far right now I'm just going to call the return 10.
And now we're here.
We're going to create the cell and the cell will come from table view the D Q your reusable cell and
it will ask us for an identifier and an index path and the identifier yourself and index path is index
path.
And of course I'm going to first cast this as feed so so that I can I reach the label an Image view
over here.
OK.
So right now I cannot reach that.
So let me do a comment B and return this cell.
OK.
So that I can come over here and say Soledad and I can reach as you can see.
So in fact let me just called is feed user so lame label and just make it equal to test.
OK.
And of course I cannot do that I have to say Soledad feed user name label dot text.
So here you go.
Now we are ready to use our table view inside of forward coat.
So let me do a command B to make this error go away.
OK.
Now we're ready to write our retrieval function.
So I'm going to call this get snaps from fi your store.
OK.
Or via your base.
So let me open up curly brace over here and I'm going to call this function over here so what do we
want here of course we want to create other steps.
Right.
So we're going to get our snaps and we're going to pass this information to display our steps.
So let me do that.
I'm just going to call this forest or database that collection and this time we don't need to have any
filters over here because we're going to display all the snaps but we have this data value so maybe
we want to order by this date so that we can see the most recent one as the first SAP.
So I'm going to say order by and I'm going to choose this descending boolean as well because this will
be descending.
Yep.
So I'm going to call this date and descending will be true.
And then later on I can just get my data and this time I'm not going to say get data about I'm just
going to add a snapshot listener because I want to get the updated information here as well.
So if you say at snapshot listener and hit enter it will give you either a snapshot or an error.
OK so let me close this down and here over here I'm going to check to see if error is not no and if
that's the case I'm going to call my make Ellard function and say error and message will be error that
localized description.
OK.
So don't forget to put call here the question marks and I'm going to say error soap else if that's the
case.
What I want to do to get this information and display them in the table view.
So let me do the checks first.
So I'm going to control to see if snapshot that is M.S. is false and if snapshot is not Neil.
OK.
If that's the case of course I'm going to go into a for loop and I'm going to say for a document in
snapshot that documents.
OK.
And this will give me the documents.
Now I can reach the snap owner I can reach the image you're all array and I can reach the data as well.
But so far we have been just getting this information and saving those information into arrays so that
we can display them in our table views.
But this time I'm not going to do that but rather I'm going to create a snap model using trucks.
Let's do that within the next lecture.