Hi we didn't this lecture we going to retrieve our information and save them into a model so that we
can display them in the table view.
So in order to do that I'm going to come over here to our models folder and I'm going to create a new
file and this will be as swift file because we're going to only have one struct.
OK.
So for our model name I'm just going to call the snap any side of the snap.
We're going to have a struct cold snap as well.
So in this model I'm only going to have three variables for right now.
So what I'm going to have is the snap or the user name of the snap owner.
OK so I'm going to call this user name not the user e-mail actually I'm going to go for a user name.
So.
And again we're going to have an image URL erased not an image URL string.
OK.
And we're going to have a date and this will have the type of date as well.
So as you can see we have three variables but three different types.
So that's good for practice right.
We're going to use this model to save our information.
So each time we get the new document we're going to create as snap objects out of that document.
So let's see how this works.
I'm going to check to see if I can get the user name first.
So I'm going to say document that gets and devalue the field actually that I'm looking for is the snap
owner remember.
Right.
So maybe you can use some more consistent names like if you're calling this snap or winner you can call
the snap owner in the model as well.
So let me come over here and check for image URL all airy and this will be documents dot document dot
yet.
OK.
And the value that we are looking for is the image you're all airy.
So it has to be spelled exactly like this image earlier.
And I'm going to optionally cast this to be as an array of strings.
And finally I'm going to get this date and this will be document that get and devalue that I'm looking
for is date and I'm going to cast is as timestamp.
We cannot cast is as date I'm going to show we have to do that later on.
OK.
Now we have all the values that we need.
We can use our snap model to create our first step.
Right.
So that's what we're going to do.
I'm going to call this snap Ok.
And this will be a snap object.
So right snap over here and it will give you the initial visor.
So it will ask you for a user name and image URL array and that date.
So user name is the user name imager I'll erase the image you're all right.
And date we have to convert this to be a date.
And it's very easy you can just say date that date value.
So this converts timestamp to be a date.
And here we are here we have our first snap.
Now we have to make sure that we have a snap array or here so that we can display our snaps in our table
view.
So I'm going to call the snap array and this will have the object of snaps right.
So that's it.
So let me delete this dot.
So come over here and add this to our snap array.
So soft dot snap or a dot that pens and we're gonna append the snap and remember in situations like
this in order to prevent duplication of values we have to come over here and clear all the values from
SNAP array so you can just say remove all keeping capacity falls.
And here you go.
Now let's come over here and connect this to our table view.
Say return snap or eight that count.
And over here in the Feed the user name label.
I'm going to take snap array index Pat throw.
So this will give me the snap object itself but I just want to get the name of that snap object so you
can just say data user name Alf Gergiev are you going to have to do that for Image view as well.
But right now we don't have necessary tools to go with that.
So later on I'm going to take care of this for right now we have another problem because we have to
check to see if 24 hours is passed or not.
So I'm going to do it like this if 24 hours is passed.
I'm just going to delete the data from five star since now I have the data over here.
I can't easily check that.
OK.
And there is a method to do that.
In Swift.
So I'm going to show you how this works so I'm going to create a difference and this will be the difference
between my date and current date.
So I'm going to use calendar in order to do that as you can see this is the relationship manager between
calendar units so you can use this to understand the difference between your date and the current date
in order to do that.
You have to say calendar that's current.
So this is the user's current calendar.
And over here you have to go for date complements.
OK this one.
So this will ask you for the compliment of the date.
Like I if you want to get an hour or if you want to compare the months or years and it will ask you
to parameters which dates you want to compare.
So I believe that's not the one we want because it only has one parameter so let me write dates complement
one more time.
And yep we want this one competence from and to so we have to have two date variables over here.
So make sure you choose this one.
Okay.
So we're going to specify the dates on there does from end to values and in the competence we're going
to go for our okay because we want to see if we can get 24 hours out of that one.
So you add to you date in here from okay in the from parameter and of course you have to say date that
date value in order to get the date and you can just say dates over here to get the current dates.
Once you do that you have to say dot our to get ours out of that function.
OK.
So this will give you an integer indicating the difference between two dates as an hour.
Again we're comparing the dates value with current date to get our values out of that one.
Okay.
And we're going to check to see if this difference is actually more than 24 hours.
So if difference is more than 24 hours actually greater than or equal to 24 hours then going to just
delete this document.
Right.
So I'm going to delete and if that's not the case I'm not going to do anything actually but I'm just
going to pass this information to another we have controller.
So let me delete this.
So I'm going to say self-styled fire's star database that's collection.
So this will be the snaps collection and we will need the documents I.D. or here.
So let me create this document I.D. I'm going to say document I.D. is document that document I.D. And
we are going to say that document to reach the specific document I.D..
And after that you can just say dot delete and this will give you a completion block.
You can see if there is any error messages as well.
So you can just go for air and you can just do something like printing out the air if you want and if
that's not the case if difference is not greater than 24 hours then I'm not going to do anything.
So I'm just going to pass this information to every snap the controller because remember that's where
we display the time left.
So in snap your controller users will see the time left to deletion.
So we're going to pass this information to snappy controller I'm just taking notes so that we won't
forget about this.
And the other thing not to forget is to display the image inside of our table view as well.
So in order to do that we're going to work with SD rep image like we did before.
Let's do that in the next lecture.