Hi within this lecture regrouping to test our app to see if it's working properly or not.
And regarding to improve our code if we come across with any problem as you can see and I've type left
is twenty three hours because one hour is passed so that we will know when it's going to be deleted
or not.
So let me look out from this and let me create a new user.
I'm gonna call this La said Metallica dot com and give a user name like Lars Ori and give a password
like One two three four five six and sign this up.
Once I do that I can see the James Hadfield snaps as well.
So this is looking good.
Let me create my own snap to see if this works or not.
So let me choose the Mona Lisa from here and let me try to upload this so once I do that it will take
me to the feed.
And here we see the lights.
All right so that's cool.
Let me open this and we will only see one image and we cannot slide yet.
So I believe there is a problem.
Maybe you have realized that it's also showed the 23 hours label.
So let me try it one more time I'm sure you're going to take care of that later on.
So here we go.
Let me open this and now we can slide over here to see the surface.
But I believe we have some problem regarding the time label as you can see this is 23 hours on this
is correct because in fact we uploaded them one hour ago but we just uploaded.
Lars Ulrich snaps and it still shows 23 hours.
So I believe we have something wrong with our time left function.
So let me try to debug this in real time so that you will understand how these things work as well.
So let me come over here to my five year base five star.
And let me see if data is correct or not.
So it seems correct.
As you can see now the it's 2 o'clock or here and here you go.
This is one o'clock and the date value is actually correct in both James and Lars will release documents.
So it must be us it must be the code that understands the difference and passes this along to the snap
view controller.
So if we come to our feet we have controller we have to find this difference.
Yep.
This one and now I'm going to test to see if we have any issues over here.
So now we're checking to see if difference is larger than 24 hours and I'm going to print out the difference
over here to see if we have some different weird values.
So let me say something like difference.
OK.
And let me put actually a back slash over here as a difference so that we can filter the results in
our looks.
So let me run this from scratch and since it's going to be just executed in the field view controller
we can come over here to our looks and search for a difference to see this difference value.
So let me search for a difference and here you go we have 1 0 and 1 1.
So I believe we're doing something really wrong or we're here because we're getting this 1 and 0 and
they're actually correct.
So it has to be 24 hours in last and it has to be 23 hours in James but we're not saving these values
into this specific individual snaps but rather we're just passing this along to snap.
We have controller so that we're just using one time difference value for old snaps.
So that's not correct.
So let me print out date that date value so that we can see the individual dates as well.
Even though we are getting everything right.
And even though we're doing every calculation right as you can see we're getting two different values
regarding dates even though we're getting these two different values we're just using one value in SNAP.
We have controller and that's why we're failing at this moment in order to overcome this problem.
I believe we have to create a new variable inside of our snap model so that we can integrate this time
difference to our risk top model as well so that we can use this inside of our model.
It will be much more structural and safer than what we already have over here.
So I'm going to test this OK because it's not working clearly.
And as we move along to the other snaps as we increase the number of users it will get only worse.
So let me come over to my snap model and let me create some variable called Time difference or time
left for example.
So this will be an integer.
So once we do that now I can come over to my feed V.C. and before adding my snap to this snap array
I can add this value to my snap model as well.
And it doesn't auto complete.
So let me delete everything from here and write it from scratch.
So when I open parentheses it should ask me for this time left.
Let me delete this and he'd comment B to synchronize everything.
So once I do that when I open this snap Yep.
Now this is asking for a time difference so the user name is the user name.
OK.
Image URL area.
Yep this is the same thing.
So date is still date updates value and four time difference.
I'm going to go for this.
Twenty four minus difference here as well.
So once we did do that yeah we cannot reach the difference over here.
And I believe we can just get our snap creation methods from here and cut this and paste over here so
that we can reach the difference ends.
Now I can add my snap to the snap array and we're not going to use that at all because right now I have
my snap model over here with time difference.
We're not even going to use this anymore so I'm going to delete this and I'm going to delete this as
well.
We don't need it.
Right and we don't need to get this snap selected time from here as well.
I'm going to delete this as well.
And this one.
So we don't need to pass this information using say grace.
Now I can get this from here I can just say time label dot text and this will be time left.
OK.
And if you open a backslash and parentheses you can just call snap that time difference.
So that's how you get the time difference for individual snaps with different values.
So let me test this and see if this works or not.
And that's how you do real time debugging as well.
So if you come over here now we have 24 hours in class.
If you come over here we have twenty three hours in James.
So that's great.
Now we have different time left values for our different snaps.
Now let me come over to my feed we have controller because we make we have to make sure that this works
as in the way we want.
Let's see if we have any more errors over here.
We can't do that in an else statement right.
So for example right now if difference is greater than 24 hours we are deleting these documents and
else we don't want to delete this but just add snap.
Instead of leading this so let me delete all of this.
Why did I put this over here.
Because if this is actually more than 24 hours it will get deleted.
It will be deleted and I won't need to create this snap.
Right.
And we're getting this error and I believe I misspelled owls or something.
Yep.
This doesn't refer to the if control that I want.
Just let me cut this and delete this.
So I want to control owls for 24 hours difference.
Yep.
This one so let me test us and see if this still works or not and if this still works I believe we're
done building our Snapchat clone because we have all the functionality that we need.
Here you go 24 hours.
Here it is and in the James we have twenty three hours and we can slide all the images and so on.
Now we made a real good app that you can work on if you want to work with firebase.
We have learned how to work with your URL erase inside of our five your store.
We have learnt about consolidating these values and updating these values we have learnt about image
sliders and everything.
However there is still an issue regarding our app for example.
Over here we have the same date for all snaps.
So even though we upload something at the last minute it will get deleted.
If our first snap is uploaded 24 hours a go.
And if we update the date then we upload something then the 24 hours a go snaps won't be deleted.
So you have to have different dates for each snap as well.
If you really want to build a snapchat clone and put it on the App Store.
But since we're just trying to learn and trying to master the firebase I'm not going to go into that.
So right now you can understand how to create some different areas how to unders create some different
structures because you have learned so much about fire your base and you have learned so much about
Swift.
Then you can work your up way from here.
So I hope you enjoyed this course.
Let's stop here and continue within the next section.