Hi within this lecture regrouping to create our user interface in order to have our image recognition
app.
So let's go over here and select single view app and I'm going to called is machine learning image recognition.
OK so this is kind of a long name but it's self explanatory I believe.
So here.
Next on here.
And try to choose the folder that you always choose to create your first project of nation learning.
So here you go.
Let me put this into a full screen.
OK.
So let me make this like that so that we can see it clearly.
And we're going to start by creating our user interface and it's going to be fairly easy.
It's going to be fairly simple.
All I want to do is just an image view to display the image that the user has chosen.
OK so that we can see what the chosen image is in here.
And then we're going to have a label just below just under it is Image view.
OK.
And this will display the results of our process.
So this is going to be something like yep this is a monkey.
OK.
So let me make this a little bit bigger.
And let me make it central.
And the next thing I'm going to bring in above them.
So I'm going to change the image or select the image by using this button rather than the UI Image view
that we have done before.
OK.
Because it can be complicated.
In this case to click on this UI Image view to select an image because we want user to clearly understand
they can change the picture by clicking on this button as well.
So that's all we want for user interface in this app.
So let me raise reset this suggests its constraints.
OK.
I want to give this a fixed width and height constraint as well.
And once I do that I believe this is kind of distorted.
So let me bring this in turn.
Better looking straight on say update constraint constants.
Yep.
Here we go.
Now I have this label issue.
Let me select all of this and bring them into the center one more time.
OK.
That I can't say update constraint constants and in fact let me try to make this a little bit bigger.
I say update constraint constants one more time.
Maybe we can make this a little bit bigger as well because we don't know what we're getting as a result
right now.
So it can be a little bit longer than this.
So let me say update constraint constants one more time.
And here we go.
So now we're ready to bring all of these views in our view controller.
So let me drag and drop this image view.
OK.
So this is going to be an image view.
And this is going to be my result label.
OK so let me called as a result label.
And in here I'm going to bring this as an action.
And I'm going to say change button clicked or change clicked.
Yes.
This is good.
So now we're done over here.
You can just delete this label because we don't want anything in here.
Maybe you can just say something like SELECT image.
OK.
And in the change clicked I'm going to write my function.
So first of all I want to choose a picture form from the gallery from the photo library of the user.
So you know how this goes right.
We create a picture.
So this is going to be a UI image picker controller.
Then we are going to have to make this delegate to self.
And once we do that it will give us an error because we can.
We have to come up over here and say this we've controller is in fact a UI image picker controller delegate
and also a UI navigation controller delegate as well.
Once we do that the error just will go away.
And remember you can just select if the speaker will allow editing or not I'm not going to do that because
I don't want to allow other things.
I just want the original picture in this case.
So what I'm going to do I'm going to select the source type of the speaker and this is going to be the
photo library.
OK.
And then later on I'm going to present this.
So let me just say present and choose speaker and the animators will be true the completion will be
nil.
So the next thing to do is actually specify what's going to happen once the user chooses an image out
of photo library.
Remember how we do that we have to write did finish launching with options.
So this is what we looking for.
I remembered this gives us a dictionary in which we can get the original image.
So in order to do that we are going to call the Image view.
OK we're going to say Image view that image and this will get its data from the info dictionary with
original image key and we're going to cast this as a UI image and then we're going to display this dismissed
as actually in order to display the V controller so soft that this was animated.
Of course true and completion will be nailed and we're not done yet here actually after the user chooses
this picture we want to call the function to recognize this image and we're going to call this function
in here so that user will see what the picture contains once they choose is it.
And of course we don't have that yet.
We don't have that function yet.
And remember you can just come over here team for that list and just give it that photo library usage
description if you want but I'm not going to do that.
I'm just gonna test this on my simulator as you can see if I choose any picture here and let me see
if I choose one more time it will display on my Image view.
So that's it for our user interface.
So we're going to stop here and we're going to bring in the model in the next lecture.