Hi within this lecture we are going to see how we can create our own views inside often lamented reality
project.
So in order to do that I'm going to create a new X code project because eventually we are going to create
our own solar planet app.
In this project as well so I'm not going to use the old one.
I'm just going to create a new one.
Okay.
So come over here to create a new project and make sure you select augmented reality app.
One more time and this will be our solar system app.
So I'm going to name the solar system a market and make sure seen KID IS SELECTED THIS TECHNOLOGY AND
I'M GOING TO PLACE IS UNDER MY AOS app folder.
So here you go.
Now our app is created so let me bring this up and let me make this into a full screen mode.
So let me come over to my real controller and I'm going to delete everything because we're going to
create everything from scratch.
So let me get rid of this as well.
All we had to do is just leave the scene with that delegate to solve in the we did load because we are
going to create all the Cs nodes and everything in here.
So first of all we're going to see what the node is and we're going to see how we can add our nodes
to the scene we use.
And of course in order to create nodes we have to create other objects as well.
As I said before nodes by themselves do not do much.
They just actually specify the coordinates.
The materials that we're using inside of our seat.
So as you can see fire right ACM I can see there are some options like ACM bucks ACARS fear and other
things as well.
We're going to work with all of this things.
So first of all I'm going to create an ACM bucks.
So this is a view.
This is and box view that we can create and as you can see it has some width and height and length and
on as the fourth parameter we have some radius as well maybe you can think that this isn't even a sphere
why we have.
Why do we have a radius over here.
But in fact ACM bucks is not a rectangle or a cube by itself.
It can be a polygon all think so that we can have more than 4 dimension over here.
Okay so for width I'm going to go with 0 point 1 and for height and length I will do the same thing
and for radius I'm not going to go for something big I'm just going to go for all point 0 1 and remember
all these measures are in meters.
So don't go crazy in here you have to specify something less than one meter most of the time.
OK I'm going to assign this to be a variable called my box.
So this will be my box.
You have to do that I have to specify the texture the material that this box will have.
So if you say my box starting materials as you can see it asks us to create an ACM material array in
which we define the contents of this box and I'm going to say this will be equal to some array but in
order to do that of course I have to create that material first.
So let me create this and I'm going to call this something like Box material okay.
And of course you can call it whatever you want.
After that it will be an ACM material like this.
And this will be not sufficient.
Of course if you have to specify the texture or image that this material will take.
But eventually we will come down to here and say this will be box material.
OK.
Inside of an array just like it asks later on we can specify the image that this material will take.
So in order to do that let us find some images let us find some textures that we can use.
So I'm going to go over to this open game art that's or one more time.
Remember that's what we used in the sprite kid section as well.
So we have some free images over here to use it.
Use them in our games in our augmented reality apps and in other apps as well.
For example we can see the 3D art we can see the textures over here.
So I'm going to create a box and I want to wrap this box with some texture and I will just look around
over here to find a good texture.
I'm just doing this randomly.
So you can try with other textures as well.
For example I see a wood texture over here.
It would be good to wrap my box around.
So let me open this in another tab and I will continue to find other textures textures as well.
For example we have something over here.
It kind of looks like a vol that I don't believe it's good.
So I'm moving over Yeah I see a grass over here so it may be interesting.
So let me open it as well.
And over here I see some ball.
I'm going to take this as well.
So if you don't want to do the steps you can just take them out of my github a counter as well but I
will download those and I will try them one by OK.
So let me take this grass and I believe we have a lot of grass options alternatives over here.
It doesn't matter let me just download it and we have two walls over here I'm going to go for the first
one.
So let me download this as well.
And here you go.
Now we're ready.
Let me open my downloads folder and I'm going to create a new folder called A R kit visuals and I'm
going to bring all of these images inside of my folder so that we can see it better.
OK so under this folder now I have a zipped file I'm going to open this with archive utility or any
other unzipping software that you have.
For example we have different kinds of grasses over here.
OK.
So let me name this wall.
Let me name this wood and let me choose the grass from this list.
And yep I believe this is good.
Let me name this grass and we bring.
We're going to bring them in to our art that the SAT's folder.
So let me choose everything from here and bring them in like this.
OK.
Great.
Now we're going to use those visuals in order to wrap our box around.
So way to do that is to give this as a content to our materials.
So you have to come over here and say box material that diffuse and if you say diffuse you get to change
the content of this material.
Okay.
So after that you can say contents like this and it will ask you any objects.
And I'm going to give it a UI image object and it will have the name of our newly brought involved up
PMG or other things but we cannot come over here and say Waldock PMG we have to say art that is an asset.
So whatever we see over here.
So it has to be exactly the same as it is.
Okay.
And then a slash and then something like Waldock PSG say if you're doing this with another visual then
you're more than welcome to do so but you have to specify art that a CNS it's folder first.
And after that we are going to create our node because we want to specify the position that this box
will take in our scene.
So it will be an ACM note.
And this note will have a position.
And if you're right position like this you can see that this asks for an ICM vector 3d dimension.
OK.
So let's choose this.
And if you open parentheses you will see that it asks you to give some x y and z coordinates.
Again I'm going to give 0 4 x and 0 point one for Y.
So it will be 100 centimeters above us.
And I'm going to say minus 0 point 5.
So it will be 500 centimeters away from us.
OK.
After that we are now ready to add this to our scene view actually.
But let me give this geometry first because we have to connect our node with our ACM box.
So that's the way to do it.
Now I can come over here and say seeing view that's seen Dodd's root note.
OK.
So remember the root node.
That's how we add Charles to the root node so Ed child node and this will be the node so that's why
we have done this for loop before in the previous lecture remember I told you you will understand it
much better once we do that.
And now you see why.
Because we can reach all the nodes each side of the scene with that loop that we have done in the previous
lecture.
So let's run this on our fold so that we can see how we rolled up PSG we look like in our living room.
So let me run this.
And here you go.
So I'm going to bring in my phone to my screen.
OK.
And once I open the app you will see the Bucks wrapped around the world up PSG.
And here you go.
Now we can see every aspect of this.
And as you can see it's looking good right.
It's a cube.
And it has the world that PSG wrapped around.
Now I believe we can test this video.
Other visuals as well.
For example let's go for the grass.
OK so let me run this one more time to see grassed up PSG wrapped around my bucks.
So let's run this with our phones again.
So here you go build succeed it's and once we open it we will see the grass.
Yeah.
It doesn't look good because this image is not very suitable for our bucks I believe but this is working
well at least yeah.
So let me test this with other visual as well.
I believe it's called Wood but wood that JP rather than PMG.
So make sure you change the extension as well.
So once we do that.
Here you go.
Now this is better.
So this is a cube wrapped around with wood that JP.
So as you can see we can bring in our own wheels.
We can create the we use we can set some materials and contents.
We can assign them together to show them in our A C so that's cool.
So let's stop here and within the next lecture we're going to create a sphere rather than a box and
we will wrap this sphere with our contents so that we can see how it looks like.