Hi within this lecture we're going to load our ads and we're going to show them to the user when they
click on the next button.
So we already have initialized our interstitial ad.
So let me go back to documentation and see how it's done.
So here we have lower than at and we have showed the ad sections so again loading the ad doesn't mean
showing them to the user first we have to create a request and we have to load that request so that
our ad will be ready to be presented.
So I'm going to do that under we did load as well.
Once I initialize my interstitial ad I'm just going to create a request and load it and then later on
you can show it to the user when you want as you can see this has an is ready method.
So if this is ready we can present the interstitial ad using the S as a route we controller.
So I'm going to copy this if block of course you can copy the else block as well if you want.
If this is not ready you can do whatever you want.
So let me go back to my app and paste in or here so that I'm ready to present this to the user.
Now it's if it's ready I'm going to present it.
If it's not I'm not going to do anything else.
So let me run this and it will display a test ad not a real ad so that we can see if it's working or
not.
So once I click on Next here you can see the test ad over here so it's a full screen ad rather than
seeing a not good ad over here Regis going to see real really good ads.
So let me close this down and as you can see now we have learned how to display ads.
So remember to change this ad unit I.D. once you complete your app and once you're ready to deploy this
to the App Store from here and from the info that people list as well.
And that's not all.
Actually you can't do much more things with the ads if you come over to the documentation you can see
that you can actually have a delegate in your interstitial ads and you can set the delegate to the V
controller itself.
By doing that and it will give you some power to call these functions.
So this is like a lifecycle of ad you can just choose to do something when interstitial ads did receive
some ads or if it fails to receive or it will present to the screen or it will dismiss from the screen.
So you can choose to do some actions when this happens.
OK.
So you can use these functions in order to have much more complicated algorithms regarding the displaying
of the advertisements in your app.
So here you can take a look at other options as well like banners or rewarded ads.
So that's it for bringing in Google ad mobs into your projects but you have to know some other features
of Google ad mobile dashboard as well so that you can control your ads in a real good way.
For example let me go to Google.
Add them up and here after you create your ads you after you do your setup up you can come over here
to blocking controls in which you can choose whatever ads that you want to display in your app.
For example here we have some categories and they are all allowed ad at the beginning.
For example if you want to block some certain kind of categories like if you don't want to show any
auto mobile ads or if you don't want to show any art ads you may choose to do it.
So for example you can see there are a lot of categories over here.
So for some reason I don't want to show an auto mobile ads so I can't come over here to auto and vehicles
and disable this ad block.
This ad category so they won't be shown in my app.
OK.
And there is no reason to block Auto mobile ads.
Most of the time but you can come over here to sensitive categories in which you will find something
like dating or drugs and supplements or I don't know politics.
OK.
So you can't choose to block these ads like a religion if you don't want to display any religion related
ads.
You may choose to do it.
So from here.
So it's important to choose these categories OK depending on your app.
And we have other features to block or filter dads like you can come over here to add content rating
so you may want to filter do ads regarding their content rating or something else like if you don't
want to show ads that are directing major people or directing the minor people you may choose to do
it so and you can just choose some advertiser your URLs to block the ads.
So as you can see it gives you complete control over your ads and it's fantastic.
So you can use this Google ad mob to make money out of your apps.
So that's it.
We're going to stop here and continue within the next section.