Hi.
We didn't this lecture regrowing to see how we can create an ellipse or a circle and a triangle with
idle B.
So let me really do everything from here and we're going to choose this ellipse or a circle and as you
can see it's the same thing as a rectangle we get to choose its field we get to choose its borders we
get to delete the borders we get to increase the size of the borders the thickness of the borders.
So it's the same as a rectangle a few hits shift while you create this view it will create a proportionate
Elop so it will create a proportional circle for you like this.
OK.
So if you don't hold on.
So shields then you can create any circle like this.
OK.
And if you want to create a perfect perfect circle like this you have to hold on to shift and you can
use this option think in here as well.
So if you hold on to option it will just take the first point as a center and it will expand the circle
around your center.
So that's it actually for the circle let me just try the three a triangle as well.
So as you can see we can create the triangle here with the same technique but I'm just going to show
you something that we haven't seen before.
So let me create an image triangle over here and let me go over to select two.
And now after you create that view if you double click on that it will go into the edit mode.
So now we get to edit and by editing I don't mean changing its color in something we get to edit everything
every aspect of this view like this.
So we can just take one corner and we can just movie there out and we can do that for other coroners
like this as well.
So once we create the triangle now we're not down we can just get to we can just change it later on
and let me take this more on further steps.
So if we come over here we can even choose this path to move around so we can create something like
this rather than a triangle.
Now we're having some V shape over here.
So as you can see we have a great freedom here.
Like we can just play with this thing we can just make this a little bit bigger a little bit longer
and we can just fill this up.
We can do whatever we want with that.
For example I can rotate this like that.
OK.
And let me just move this around a little bit and let me zoom out so that you can see it better.
Let me give it a black color.
And like I can't just make this a little bit smaller so that it would look like the Send message thing
or send the direct message thing in Instagram right.
So I can get to edit this a little bit more if I hit double click on that.
And here you go.
Now we have a Send message icon.
Of course it's not perfect right now.
And are you going to have to work on that a little bit if you want to use this on your app.
But I believe that's the essence of this section so we get to create some basic images basic visuals
easily by using these Adobe axes and as you can see we can do that in circles in ellipses and in every
other views as well.
Now I get to change this ellipse in whatever whichever way I want.
Like I can't even come here and do like this.
Right.
So it gives us a great freedom.
I get to change the ellipse I get to change the circle I get to just change whatever aspect for their
point that I want in a way that I want.
So as you can see I managed to create a very ugly object in a very simple manner.
OK and it doesn't make sense to create views like this but it's actually very good to have this freedom
so that we can change the shapes change the views in a way that we want whenever we want.
So let's stop here and move along within the next lecture to see the other views as well.