Hi.
We didn't this lecture going to see an operation called masking.
OK.
So in order to that I'm going to delete those two views and I'm going to create fresh ones.
So let me create them rectangle over here and I'm going to give you a blue color in the field and I'm
going to lose the border and then I'm going to create another view over here let me do a triangle this
time.
OK.
Like that.
And now I have a triangle and I have a rectangle.
OK.
Now I will just change the colors so that we can see the triangle in a better way.
Now I want to mask this by using this triangle.
So if I choose this views to weaves together I can come over to my menu to the object I can say mask
which shape.
So it will mask the view with a shape like that.
OK.
So he took the triangle out of that rectangle and it's it's actually masking this view right now.
If I double click on that I can just see the contents and I can just see the contents from these layers
as well.
If I click on that I can see the individual views as well.
So I get to edit them later on.
But it is not a great example of masking so let me show you a great usage or an ideal usage a real time
usage of the masks in order to do that.
We're going to need a real image.
So I believe the best way to display disease to find an image of a person so I'm going to Google myself
out and I'm going to bring in an image of myself.
OK.
So this is my picture.
Let me copy this.
OK.
And closes down and paste it over here with command V.
And here I have my picture now.
Well I want to do I want that clip my picture so that I can just show a circular image.
So how do I do that.
Just choose the circle over here.
And by holding the shift I'm going to create this circle or an ellipse.
OK.
And I'm just going to live this over here like that in the center.
So choose them together and say mask.
And here you go.
Now I masked my image.
Now I have this beautiful circular image you you that I can use on my screen and I can actually double
click and edit if I'm not satisfied with how it looks.
But I believe it's looking great so that you can create shapes like that.
You can actually create masks with shapes like that in real life examples as well.
So let's stop here and try to export some of the views that we have done to use them in the X code in
the next lecture.