Hi within the section re going to practice what we have learned in the previous section.
So we are going to be driving some icons and we are going to learn how to create logos icons for our
app and in order to do that we are going to use that there'll be sixty one more time and you will see
it in practice.
So I'm going to go for custom sites this time because we are going to be creating icons rather than
a full size screen.
So I'm going to come up here and choose the art part okay.
Then I choose this it creates the iPhone X as default but actually let me show you another thing.
So let me delete all of this and let me go over here and choose one.
If you draw something over here it will create this in a specified size.
Of course you can actually change the size after you create any art bought by clicking over the art
board and coming to properties inspector as well.
So let me go to Google and search for a concise so that we would know what I can say is that we have
to use.
OK.
So here as you can see there are a lot of different options for icons.
But in my experience I have seen mostly we use this 24 by 24.
OK.
Of course we can adjust it to another size later on but I'm going to go for 24 and 24 so that we would
have a realistic art board over here to create our icon.
So for our first icon I'm thinking of and a home button icon like in Instagram.
And this is generally in the shape of a house or of a home.
OK.
So we're going to create a home over here.
You know we're going to do that.
I'm just going to take this rectangle and just draw some rectangle over here.
OK.
So let me put it this way.
And then later on I'm going to need their roof and in order to that I'm just going to use this triangle.
And let me just put this triangle on top of my house over here and let me try to adjust its size by
making this a little bit bigger or a little bit smaller.
And I believe.
Yeah.
We can't leave it like that or we can just do like this.
OK.
So let me try to adjust this Here you go.
Now we have a house OK.
We have the roof.
We have the house.
So let me draw a door as well in the shape of a rectangle one more time.
Of course we can adjust does a little bit.
So it looks like a house.
It looks like and home.
I came to me but we can just do some tweaks over here to make it look better like this or like that.
OK.
So of course you can try to make this in a better way by adjusting the size or just deleting some lines
on the bottom.
So let me just rename this by double clicking over here and I'm going to name this home icon or a house
I can.
OK.
And then if you do comment C.M. comment we will just copy the art bought and paste it in the right hand
side of this current artwork and I'm just going to call this home I can too so that we can create another
house icon over here with another technique.
So over here we have this icon.
But maybe you didn't like it so I'm going to delete this and I'm just going to use pen this time.
So I'm going to start from here and draw a straight line you can he hold on to shift in order to draw
this line in a straight way and I'm just going to draw my house like this and then I'm going to come
over here and close this line and then later on you can just draw a door over here like that.
OK.
And this would be another example of an home icon like this.
So if you're not satisfied with either of those of course you can just adjusted that little bit so that
you can see this in a better way like that.
OK.
You can just make it central you can make it a little bit smaller.
And don't worry if you're not satisfied with this at all.
I'm going to show you how to find a better I can so that you can use it for free in your apps later
on as well.
But right now just try to play with it and try to make it look better so this is how we try and draw
icons in Adobe.
STEVE In fact I'm going to stop you about within the next lecture we're going to see another examples
of I can draw Rick.