Hi.
We didn't expect you re going to create a profile.
I can and also I comment I can say I'm going to copy and paste this and I'm going to name this profile
icon.
Okay.
And if you come over here you can just delete this triangle and then I'm going to bring in some circles
some ellipses so that we can have a body and a head for our profile like him.
So this will be the head of our profile person.
Okay I'm going to field is in with this color one more time.
So this is like the head of our icon.
Okay.
And we're going to have a body.
And for the body I'm just going to copy and paste this and make this a little bit bigger like that.
Okay so that I can have this as a buddy but I'm just going to cut this in half so that we can have a
smooth by the over here like that.
So let me bring in some rectangle and once I bring this in if I just choose this okay together and subtract
from each other.
Here you go.
Now I have my body like that.
So here is my profile.
I can I can easily use this as a profile like in my tab bar forever.
Social media apps like Snapchat or Instagram right.
So it looks good and let's see how homes search play profile.
Let me copy and paste so that we can create a tag like icon as well.
So for example I'm going to go for an upper arrow over here in order to make a post like or dislike.
OK.
So let me create this simple line and let me give it some thicker boundaries like that for example five
will be the choice for us.
And if I add a triangle over here like that I can just make this feel in the same color as this.
And then I can just choose to select two and make this a little bit bigger like that.
And here you go.
Now we have our upper arrow.
We can easily use this.
And I believe it should be a little bit shorter than that.
So we can easily use this to like an icon or you can just reverse it to dislike and post not an icon.
OK.
So you can just use this or you can just reverse it and use it as well.
So I'm just going to cold is up I can.
And one more time I'm just going to copy and paste this because we're going to create our comment.
I can.
So let me come over here and let me delete this.
And this one as well because we're going to create on comment I can like that with a rectangle.
And once we do that we can field is in with this color one more time.
And let me make this a little bit smoother over here.
So let me choose this.
And I believe he can just do it from here as well.
So for example let me come over here and give this for values for you for is a little with too much.
So let me go for a.
And here you go.
Actually this looks good.
So I just want to make this look like that.
OK.
So you can just use zero in one corner or we can use three over here as well but just bring in a new
triangle or some other shape.
So let me do this with triangles.
So you will see what I mean.
Once I do that I'm just going to field is in and I'm just going to rotate it to look like this.
OK.
So I believe that's good.
So let me try to add justice and let me feel listen.
So here you go.
Now it looks like a comment icon of courage we can do some tweaks like.
Let me zoom in so we can see it better.
As you can see it's not perfectly aligned so you can just take this corner and make this perfect Clay
lined like that.
So here you go.
Now we have our comments icon of course we can try to make this look better like maybe we can create
a triangle over here or a rectangle over here.
And I believe it doesn't look good so it was much better when we didn't have that body you can choose
to create your own icons in your own way.
So that's how you come up with new ideas new drawings and I actually suggest you to try much more so
that you can work on your Adobe Steve skills.
But this is not all we are going to stop here and we're going to do more practice in the next lecture.