Welcome back everyone to the course set up an installation lecture.
In this lecture we'll quickly discuss the following topics.
What is Anaconda and how to download it how to download the notes.
Setting up the Course environment and working with the Jupiter.
So is Anaconda.
Anaconda is a distribution of python and all that distribution means is that it contains various Python
libraries and it makes sure that they all work well together.
Some of the more complex libraries have certain dependencies in a card that just makes it easy and make
sure they're all working together well.
If you're an advanced user that is someones already has programming experience with Python you probably
already have Python installed and you may or may not need to install Anaconda.
If you're an advanced user who already has Python and you're familiar with Pipp install a command line
in order to follow along this course.
At this stage all you have to do is let your command line your terminal say Pip install Jupiter and
that will install the Jupiter notebook for you.
Now for everyone else let's go ahead and show you how to download Anaconda and it jumped to my browser
now OK.
So once you're at the browser go ahead and google search for Anaconda Python download.
You should end up seeing a link that says something like continue.
I o slash downloads go ahead and click on that and it will take you to a page that looks something like
this.
Every once in a while they change what the page looks like but somewhere on the page there should be
a link for actually downloading the Anaconda distribution for your preferred platform.
You have Windows Mac OS and Linux so go ahead and choose the installer that's for your platform and
make sure you download the python 3.6 version.
So we're going to download Python 3.6.
This is a 64 bit.
If you're on a 32 bit computer they have a valid 32 bit option as well.
And then there's Mac OS and then there's Linux.
Once you've downloaded that go ahead and come over here it's where it says how to install Anaconda.
And that will take you to a link for their documentation.
And there's three separate pages one for installing a Windows one for installing a Mac OS and then one
for installing on Linux that basically a step by step instructions on what you need to do depending
on your operating system.
However I want to give you a quick note.
If you're on Windows so if you're on Windows essentially.
Quite easy to graphical installer you just click next next next.
But eventually it's going to add you or ask you the following.
It's going to ask you whether or not you want to add anaconda to your path environment variable.
If you click on that box it's going to say they don't recommend adding anaconda to your path environment
variable.
However if this is your first installation of Python on your computer you don't have it yet go ahead
and check that box anyways and make sure that you add anaconda to your path environment variable.
If you don't check that box what's going to happen is you're not going to be able to call in a condo's
Python directly from your command line so that may cause issues down the road when you're calling things
like Jubran output.
So go ahead and make sure that you add anaconda to the path environment variable.
All right so once you've installed that go ahead and open up your command prompt and let me quickly
tell you how you can find that.
So if you're looking for how to actually reach the command line if you're a Windows user Go ahead.
After you install Anaconda search your computer for Anaconda prompt.
If for some reason you can't find any on a prompt on your computer just go ahead and search for the
term ACMD.
They'll take you to your Windows command prompt.
If you're on a Mac OS or Linux just search for the term terminal and open up your command line.
So again Windows users search for on the prompt or ACMD Mac OS and Linux users search for the terminal.
This will bring up your command line.
Let's go ahead and jump to the command line now.
Once at your command line go ahead and change directory tour ever you have your unzipped note file as
a resource in this lecture.
You can download a zip file containing all the notebooks unzip it to a desired location and then from
your command prompt CD into that location.
So the way you can do that is to just type CD in the name of the file path that you want to locate to.
Or you can just go folder by folder.
So for example I can begin typing in a folder name here.
Hit tab to autocomplete and then it will change directory into that folder.
If I ever need to change the directory back up the directory just see the space two dots and then I
go back up one.
So I'm going to CD to the directory where my information saved so will see the to this and then eventually
you want a CD into your Python for finance repo or wherever you happen to have the unzipped file so
that unzips file contains a bunch of notebook files.
But it also contains an environment file the environment file is an environment that you can activate
to actually have the same environment that I used when I was creating this course.
So the way you do that is once you're actually in the repository with the environment file it's the
environment.
Why M-L you'll say Konda E and vi create dash f environments thought y m l and to make sure the check
that you're actually in the correct directory you should be able to tap autocomplete this environment
thought why M-L.
If you're not able to tab autocomplete that you're probably not in the right folder.
Make sure that you're located in the same folder as the unzip notes.
Have this environment.
Thought why an elf file inside of them.
Once you've done that go ahead and create that environment trough this.
You should see a bunch of downloads begin to occur.
Once those downloads are finished you can then do is say activate PI finance and once you've activated
PI finance you should see over here on the left hand side that pi finance is now activated if you aren't
on a Mac or Linux computer you're going to need to say Source activates high finance and then use that.
So again that's for Mac OS or Linux users.
And you can check out the resources for a link on more information about Konda environments.
Once you've done that you should be able just to call Jupiter notebook.
Hit enter and eventually this will open up your browser.
Now if this is your first time using this make sure to copy and paste this URL so says HTP localhost
8 9 and that it has a token for you.
So if this is your first time using Jupiter notebook go ahead and copy this entire URL with the token.
Otherwise you may go to your browser and it may be requesting your token or password so you'll need
to copy and paste this entire you are.
Once you've had that lets go ahead and bring over a browser and see what it looks like.
You should see something that looks something like this in your browser so to zoom in a little bit and
essentially you have here are the files for the course.
We have the python crash course none apply.
General Pandurs visualization Panas time series etc. and these are more or less aligned with the actual
section titles of the course itself.
So if you go on to me each section has a corresponding folder here.
So for example if it's time to go into the stock market analysis kept some project you'll just click
here and then you'll see the actual CACP files that go if that stock project stock market and Alce project
solutions etc..
So again all the information you have is here for you.
In order to create a new notebook.
Just come over here.
Select new and you should see Python 3.
Sometimes this says something like Khand the roots are called the default.
That's OK as well.
Just click on whatever is underneath.
Notebook.
Once you click that you've gone ahead and created a new Jupiter notebook Jupiter notebooks have cells
where you can type in Python code so you can do something like two plus two.
And if you want to run this just do shift enter and you'll get an output.
Now as a quick note the notebooks can also show you methods and functions.
Then work on which show you all that in the Python crash course.
But as a quick show if you want to check the length for something it's a Eliane And if you do shift
tab right after this function you'll end up returning the documentation string.
Now keep in mind the function must already be defined in order to see this documentation string.
And if you have an object such as a string it's all say x is equal to my string do shift enter to run
that I can do X dot tab and I'll see the list of all the methods.
Again this won't show up unless I've already defined string or this x variable in a cell.
And again we'll discuss that more in the Python crash course but hopefully you already have some familiarity
with this before enrolling in this course.
All right.
If you have any questions on the installation process please feel free to post the Kewaunee forums.
I'm always happy to help out.
Sometimes the operating systems have a little trouble with the installation process so please feel free
to post any questions you may have over this process.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.