Welcome back everyone and welcome to the trading algorithm exercise solutions lecture and this lecture
we're just going to code out the actual kind of simple Bollinger Band strategy on the Quanto platform.
So it's up over Quanto up in ID and get started.
All right.
So I've already opened up the idea.
A new algorithm.
The first thing I need to do is set up initialize and remember this takes in context and then we're
going to do here is set the actual security we're going to be using.
I said to use Johnson and Johnson although you definitely could have played around with other securities.
So you can just kind of began typing out Johnson you'll end up saying Johnson and Johnson.
So 4 1 5 1 is the idea and then the other thing we're going to have in here is schedule function.
So we're going to schedule some functions to operate.
Remember we want it to only happen centrally once per day so it will create a function called check
bands and then the date rule puts the rules is going to be every day and that's all I'm going to specify.
You could also specify whether you're going to do it 30 minutes before market close or after market
opens et cetera.
But for simplicity we just want to schedule this check bands function every day and this check bands
function which we actually haven't created yet is going to be the function that has all the logic of
our trading strategy.
So let's go ahead and try it out.
We're going to see if Czech bands and it's going to take in context and data and we'll do the following.
The first thing actually to get is the current price.
So set the current price as a variable.
And remember we can use data that current to grab this and we're going to grab it directly off the context
so we need to pass in the asset and the field I'm looking for is price.
And you can always click here on learn more to check the documentation for all the supported fields
Okay.
So so far I've been able to grab the current price so as I'm backtesting the current price is going
to be that day's price.
Now what I need is historical data.
So we can make something called prices and it's kind of up to you what variable name you want to choose
here but I'll kind of show prices for the historical data and we'll have data that history.
Remember this takes in an asset fields Parkhouse count frequency.
So we want the same asset so that Johnson Johnson then the next thing I want to do is say hey give me
the price for Johnson and Johnson and I'm going to wants a frequency of 20 days or excuse me a history
of 20 days and I want the frequency to be daily.
So one day.
So what prices actually is then is just the 20 days of history for this particular security stock price.
Once we have that all I need to do is create a couple of variables here to calculate my bandwidth.
So I'll say the average is just prices not mean and essentially these are just Pandurs codes because
I only have one contex there that Johnson and Johnson.
This is essentially just a series.
So it's a series of the last 20 days of price data for the daily price so they will say prices and say
Steria deviation and then let's create our lower bands and our lower band is going to be the average
minus two times the second deviation that our upper band is going to be the average plus two times Asturian
deviation.
So this sort of calculation should feel really familiar to you especially if you went through the Panthers
time series because we actually showed exactly how to do it.
There was a little tricky is actually realizing that stated that history when you just pass in one single
asset is going to be essentially a time series but you can always print out anything and then do kind
of a one day full back test and see the logs and see what's actually being used here or returned here.
Now it's time to actually implement the logic.
So it's going to create a couple more lines here.
And the first thing to check is if the current price
is less than or equal to the lower band
I will do the following.
I'm going to call order target percents and remember this kind of an extreme strategy but we're going
to say context JJ 1.0.
So what I'm actually saying.
If the current price as we're back testing the current price for today if it's actually going to be
less than or equal to the lower band so that's kind of that dip.
So remember lower band is average minus two times turned deviation then I expect the price to go back
up according to my strategy.
So I'm going to buy it and then we can actually print something out saying that we were buying it
elif.
Else if the current price is greater than or equal to the upper band that means we're kind of in a short
situation.
Remember back to that visualization where the current price has gone over the band.
Then we want to actually short it.
So again a pretty extreme example but for our strategy it's kind of really simple to implement.
So will say Order target percent's and same stock context JJ and then we'll say minus one point zero.
And that basically says Okay allocate all my money to short the stock.
Now there are some issues with this.
After all we haven't really talked about leverage yet.
So whether or not this is realistic or even if you're going to have enough money to pay it back that
will definitely affect this as far as a realistic implementation of a strategy that shorts your entire
portfolio.
But for actual implementation it's going to be fine.
So then I'll say shorting so kind of we'll see little reports in the law when I'm buying when I'm shorting
and if that's not the case when I'm going to do just pass and my strategy is really really simple here
because I'm only detecting the lower band and upper bands.
I don't really have any sort of other exit strategy which kind of makes us reckless.
But again pretty simple to implement just as a review I take the current price.
I grab the historical price for last 20 days calculate the average the standard deviation from those
two I can grab the lower band and the upper band then I just compare my current price to the lower bands
go along.
This happens to be less than the lower band.
Otherwise if the current price is greater than the upper band short it because I think it's going to
come back them else just pass again pretty reckless pretty risky but really simple to implement.
And finally let's go ahead and record some stuff.
So I'm going to call the record function and I remember the record function essentially just works with
the name of whatever you want to call the little symbol here that you're recording.
And then the actual value you're going to record.
So we'll say record the upper bands recall record the lower bands then we'll say we can go ahead and
grab the moving average so same moving average 20 day moving average at least is equal to the average
which is equal to the average and then we'll also log the price say current price so that will give
us a nice little plot that kind of shows the error bands the lower bands.
Now we should be able to see the average as well.
OK.
So that's really all we had to do.
And the solutions there's a couple more print statements to try to make it a little clearer to you but
hopefully you were able to get the key assets of this and the main parts that I really want you to get
if you're coding along is schedule a function the ability to schedule functions to happen every day
every minute etc..
The current price of using data current getting historical information using data history and realizing
that essentially data that history either returns a single series for an asset or an entire data frame
and using your panel's knowledge you can actually just calculate statistical information off that data
frame or time series then using that you can implement some sort of strategy here like this kind of
really crude Bullinger band strategy.
So let's go ahead and build this algorithm and test it out see how we did so could build the algorithm
here.
And I'm testing it.
Well looks like we got an error global named Price is not defined in check bands.
So let's make sure that we check that out.
OK so line 12 here prices.
Looks like I messed that up and a quick note in case you ever want to debug something that's a little
more complicated than that.
You can actually highlight one of the lines here and then when you hit save and build algorithm it will
only execute the code up to this highlighted line and then we'll have a little debugger here.
So this debugger can then actually take in things you can input variables to check what they are.
So they'll say something like Hey average is not fine because it's only going to execute up to but not
including that line.
However prices should be defined.
So you see prices hey it's a series and then you can kind of expand this and see a time stamp with a
particular price.
So if you don't want to do a bunch of print statements in the log to figure out what's actually being
returned you can always use the helpful debugger to kind of play around the variables inside a little
console environment.
Once you're done with this you can do is just say like finish back test that will drop this and then
you can say either cancel or let it continue the back test.
So I hit cancel here cancel the back test say less and let me build this algorithm one more time and
whoops cancel this mixture.
I don't have this highlighted now save.
Now Bill the algorithm and this should run relatively fast given how simple the actual test is or strategy
and it looks like it performed really well.
So you'll notice that we got fifty nine point six returns alpha point 1 9 beta negative point 1 6 sharp
ratio point nine to that's all right.
But what's really nice here is I can see the upper and lower bounds.
The price in the movie average and you kind of see when it dipped below.
And we can see how many times we shorted it how many times we bought.
So shorting buying etc..
And you can see here the dates.
Sometimes it's the day after Sometimes it's weeks after we're actually buying and shorting stock kind
of an issue of strategies to play around with.
Once you're able to get this really basic Bolinger strategy down what I would really encourage you to
do is play around with it see if you can play around add an extra exit conditions.
Maybe if the price ever comes back to the mean average or it gets around a certain percent of the mean
you could exit out of the positions instead of just holding it until the next Bolinger Bancroft's.
So maybe have something that says hey if the current price is within some sort of limit of the average
go ahead and say Order target percent context thought J.J zero and just exit out of that position that
might make your strategy a little more stable once you've kind of played around the check bands function.
What I would encourage you to do is play around and and another security we can see we did really well
for Johnson and Johnson but is that just a general strategy or is it only working for Johnson and Johnson
so maybe passen another security here.
Really whatever you want so what.
I don't know we can play around with this.
Let's try something like Apple stock.
So I will say Apple Apple Inc.
24.
Let's save this.
Build the algorithm and see how well it performs against this.
So again this is the really simple version and you can see here it should probably not perform that
well against this yes.
You can see here towards the end of we basically started progressing towards the actual benchmark but
we're still able to get pretty good returns.
So let's try another tech stock maybe try Amazon.
So will try that as well save it build the algorithm
and you can see after running the algorithm Amazon stock we did horribly we got minus for a 3.8 percent
return so we did.
Way way worse than the actual benchmark.
In fact we lost almost half our money.
Definitely something to keep in mind here and you can see the bands are much closer to the means here.
So the actual standard deviation may not have been such an extreme signal.
All right I hope you are able to get us out of this exercise.
Remember the main thing here is focusing on how to use Quanto Appian platform is actual Bollinger Band
strategy is way too simple to actually execute.
As you can see depending on what stock you choose it could fail horribly.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you the next lecture.