Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on pandas operations.
There are a few pandas operations that don't really fit into any of the topics so we previously talked
about.
So we're going to do is just kind of put them all into this grab bag lecture where we discuss different
operations things like pivot tables or how to count how many unique values you have in your data frame
over things you know book and get started.
All right.
Here I am at the Jupiter notebook.
I went ahead and just copied the first cell of the operations the book that goes with the structure
in order to create this data frame.
It just has three columns.
Call 1 call to call 3 and has an index of just numbers 0 1 2 3 and call 1 we have 4 digits called 2.
We have four numbers here.
But notice that 4 4 4 is repeated and then call 3 which just has four sets of strings.
Let's talk about finding unique values in a data frame.
There's three main useful methods concerned with finding unique values in different imagine you want
it to find all the unique values in column two.
The method we can use for that is just the unique method and this will return a higher rate of all the
unique values in column two instead of actually wanting the array of unique values.
Let's say you just actually want the number of values self.
Well there's two methods for this.
You could just check the length of the array that gets returned and this would respond to three.
There's three unique values in column two but Palace actually has a built in method for this and the
schist and unique.
And if I run the cell I get the same answer.
All right.
So we have unique for actual returning an array of unique values and unique.
If I want the number of unique values the last useful function I want to show you is value counts.
And this basically means if you want a table of the unique values and how many times they show up you
can just use value underscore counts as a method.
Run this and this returns.
How many times each unique value occurred in that column.
In this case 4 4 4 occurred twice and the other numbers occurred one time each.
All right those are three very useful methods and you'll find yourself using them often in the exercises.
Let's go ahead and talk about selecting data.
We've already gone over conditional selection.
But I want to reemphasize just how important it is and how powerful it is as a tool.
We have our data frame DMF and we can use conditional selection by passing in a conditional selection
statement such as saying return that F where column 1 is greater than 2 and this will return all the
rows of the data frame where column one happens to be greater than 2.
Remember that this command insight is essentially just a boolean series of False False True true.
Now as a quick reminder if you want to combine conditions you can wrap these conditions in parentheses
and then use either an ampersand or a pipe operator depending if you want and or or.
And then you can say in other conditions such as where called to pass the sin as a string has equality
with 4 4 4 and the return just that last row 3 and there it is.
OK.
So just a quick reminder of how to select data using conditional selection.
Now let's talk about the applied method.
The applied method is going to be one of the most powerful tools in your tool belt when using pandas.
So let's go ahead and show you how it works.
Magin we have a function DPF times 2 that takes in a value X and then returns let's say X times to.
All right a very simple function.
Now you know that you can already grab for instance a column and call a built in function off of it
such as the sum and the return the sum of the column.
But what if you want to apply your own custom function such as times to where Panthers has the ability
to do that.
You can just say the column name and then apply and then you just pass whatever function you want to
apply.
This case we're going to go ahead and apply times to and this will broadcast that function to each element
in that column 2 4 6 8.
You can also apply built in functions such as length.
For instance if we take a look at column three we had a bunch of strings.
Let's say we wanted a column there were present at the length of each string.
Well then we could just say apply the person Elyon now returns the length of the stream which in this
case was three for all those strings apply.
It's going to be especially powerful when you combine it with land expressions.
That way you don't need to take the whole time to define an entire function.
If you're just going to apply it once for instance let's go ahead and make a lamp expression out of
times 2.
I'm going to go out and say Lamda X colon and then just x times to and I'm going to apply this to call
them to let's go ahead and see how this works.
And there you have it.
We were able to multiply each value in that column by two and we were able to do this without having
to write an entire function for it.
We just do this as a lamb the expression and this is the sort of thing you're going to be using all
the time as you get more and more comfortable with Panthers.
This probably one of the most powerful features of pantless the ability to apply your own custom lambda
expressions or functions.
All right let's talk about removing Kobes again if we have.
We want to let's say remove.
Column 1.
We can just say ZF drop passin the column we want to draw c o l 1.
And then remember since these are the columns we have to specify access is equal to 1.
And this will drop that column if we want this to occur in place.
We have to specify in place equals true.
Let's go ahead and not run that.
So we retain our original data frame if you want to get the column and indexed names off a data frame.
Those are actually just attributes of the data frame itself.
Meaning you can say DFI columns will return this kind of index object essentially just a list of column
names.
This is going to be especially useful when you're trying to index a column and maybe the spacing is
weird or you can't quite figure out what the string is.
You can just call DFA columns or whatever your data frame name is.
And Ill return this list of column names.
You could actually do the same thing for an index you could say at the index it will give you information
of the index.
This case since it's a range index it actually just reports back the start stop and step size of the
index.
All right let's talk about sorting and ordering a data free.
Here we have.
And imagine you want to sort it by column 2.
Essentially we want 4 4 4 and then 4 for 4 again before we see 5 5 5 and 6 6.
We can use sort values in order to do this you call T.F. sort underscore values.
And then as an argument you say by that we check shift tab here we can say bye and you could order this
off of either the rose or the columns.
But essentially you just Pessin as an argument the column you want to sort by.
So I want to sort this by column two and you can say just column two such shift enter.
And now I have sort of this data framed by column to know how the index stays attached to the row so
you don't ever lose that information there.
And that's the same thing as saying by column two same thing because it expects by to be the first.
All right let's talk about just a couple of more useful operations.
A really useful message to find no values in your data Freyne is that diff is no and this attorney data
frame of booleans indicating whether or not the value was know or not this case you get a boolean of
all falses because we have known nulls in our data frame.
All right.
Now let's finally talk about one last function or method in pantless called the pivot table and this
methodology will be really familiar for Advanced Excel users.
I want to go ahead and copy and paste some code from the notebook to create a new data frame.
Go out and check out the state of freight.
We have something that looks like this.
We have AVCHD columns and notice here that we have repeating values in both the A column B column and
the C column.
So a column has foods and bars B has one twos.
C has X and Y and then D has some integer values.
You can use DFT pivot table to actually create a pivot table.
And if you're not familiar of pivot tables I wouldn't worry about this too much but if you are maybe
an Excel user who is familiar pivot tables Hopefully you'll find this functionality useful.
Basically what we're going to do it not excel users is just create a multi index out of this table or
data frame the method to do this is have it underscore table and pivot underscore table takes in three
main arguments the values the index and the columns.
In this case let's go ahead and indicate that the values we want in our table are these values.
So what we actually want the data frame data points to be made up of.
So I'm going to say values is equal to the D column.
And then I will set my index to be equal to the A column and the B column.
And that's basically going to make a and b into a multilevel index.
It's going to pass in a list that says it's more than one column in the x and B and then finally I want
my actual columns to be defined by the C column.
This case just see that I can past that in as a list here and note that I'm saying See it's going to
be the column.
So I should end up with a column for X and a column for y.
Let's go ahead and see how this works.
I'm going to run this one more time here so we can compare the original data frame versus the pivot
table that I'm about to create.
All right so I ran this pivot table command.
And let's go in and compare that two.
Looks like I created an index out of those AB columns so that makes sense.
Looks likely a bar and foo and then one and two repeat it then the actual columns I want where the values
in this case Schuss X and Y and the actual data point values were the columns.
I do have some no values here because there are no values that match up for that specific point.
Meaning if I look back at the original data frame there is no value that goes with bar to x.
So if you look here you won't find Martu X you'll only find part 2 y and similarly for food to y.
There is no food to why there's only food to X and that's why we had to fill in no values here.
OK.
Feel free to post that Q&amp;A if you have more questions on Pivot Tables or what some more resources for
examples on Pivot Tables.
We won't really use these that often in the course.
In fact there's only really one exorcized question later on.
We're all working with heat maps as far as how to use the pivot tables for now.
Well the concern yourself with them if you're already familiar pivot tables from something like Excel.
OK.
I hope some of these operations are useful to you.
They see just a grab bag of useful functions and methods that are available to you and paths you can
go ahead and reference the pandas operations lecture no book that's underneath the panda's folder.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.