Hello everyone and welcome to part one of the Arema code along lecture.
We're actually going to be using Python since that's models to implement Arema and seasonal Arema on
a real data set.
And I think at the end of this entire series of lectures you'll get a good understanding of why Arema
probably may not always be a good choice for financial data and stock information.
Let's hop over to a Jupiter note book and get started.
OK here I am at a new Jupiter notebook and the general process for Arena models is the following.
First we want to visualize the time series data actually get to understand it.
Then you want to make the time series data stationary if necessary they will want to plot the correlation
and autocorrelation charts.
Remember that's the HCF and then also partial autocorrelation charts that will help us understand what
parameters what values we should use when we construct our Arema model that we actually use that model
to make predictions on future data points.
That is called forecasting.
So when you go through all these steps and the very first step is to actually get the data.
So we're going to be using some data about monthly milk production.
It's a seasonal data set and it's already saved the C S V file for you under the time series analysis
folder.
But let's go ahead and do a couple of imports here and get it loaded up going to just do the usual ones.
Well important on Pi isn't the import pand this is PD will import stat's models API as S M and then
last visualisations will say important plot lib pipe plot as Piel T.
And if you get this warning Don't worry it's just a warning.
Later on they'll updates that's models to be up to date so the latest panel's version is just a warning.
It's not actually an error.
And finally it will say that plug lib in line.
OK so let's go ahead and read in that dataset will say DFAC equal to PD.
Let me zoom in one more level here will say DFAC equal to PD.
Read the underscore c v and R file that were going to be working with is called the monthly milk production.
So let's go ahead and grab that.
Say monthly and we should build hit TAB autocomplete.
I can it because I'm in the same directory.
If you're not in the same directory just passing the whole file path to the CSP file and then we're
going to check out the head of this OK so we have this month column and then this kind of awkwardly
named monthly milk production pounds per cow.
January 62 to 75 and there's little question mark there because it wasn't able to interpret that letter.
OK so we're going to do now is kind of work with this data and make sure it's in the correct format
for our Erina model.
Couple of things we probably want to change this.
This is a really long name.
It's unnecessary to say in the column name or that they are.
We also want to change this month to be a date time index and get rid of this normal index.
So let's go ahead and clean it up.
We'll start off by just rename in the columns I'm going to say these columns.
Let's go ahead and keep month that works for now and then we'll say for this other column will say milk
in
pounds per cow.
And Sue the Fed.
OK so we get milk and pounds per cow.
We got rid of this kind of awkwardly.
January 6 to December 75 portion and then we're also going to do so if we check the tail of this data
frame.
You know this is kind of weird a value here for that month.
It's like a string and then it's missing some data.
So we're going to do is we're going to drop that sort to say DSF drop 1 6 8 axes is equal to zero.
And we'll say in place equals true.
And then if I check out my tail now I've gotten rid of that index for the 168.
OK.
Up next we're going to convert the monthly column to a date time column and that's easy we know how
to do that we just say a month instead of equal to the to date time and then we'll see if now if I took
out the head of my data set it should look the same except now I have a little day here in the Kading
that it's month.
So let's continue on in this next step.
We're going to do is actually set the index so they set the index to be the month column and we'll have
this be in place equals true so that if I check up the head of my data frame I have converted this month
index milk in pounds per cow.
It's a time series I can confirm that by saying the appendix and I see it's the time index and perfect
and as a nice little final step we can do here now that we've cleaned up the data is called the scribe
on this.
And then I I personally like to transpose the scribe data frame so I get it out kind of like this nice
one row.
I can see the count.
The means turn deviation the max etc. just typical information.
And I have 168 rows looks like on average it's seven 754 pounds of milk per cow.
So now we're on to Step Two numbers Step two is to visualize the data.
So this is actually quite easy for us essentially just to index and one column so we can say the plot.
I can see here the milk in pounds per cow and you should immediately start thinking this is seasonal
data.
Clearly there's some sort of seasonal behavior.
So we have a seasonality portion to it and it seems to also have a trend that seems to be trending upwards
a little bit.
So what you should also be thinking is hey I can confirm that it has a trend that's back and that it
has a seasonality aspect by actually doing some sort of on this some sort of error trend seasonality
decomposition.
So we're going to explore that later on in just a little bit.
But what I also want to show is calculating for instance the 12 month rolling average or simple average.
So let's go ahead and say my time series is equal to DSF milk in pounds per cow just tab autocomplete
there.
So now if I check the type of Time series it's a series instead of just a data frame.
And I just reassigned that to time series so I don't have to keep typing out this giant column name.
So then what I'm going to do is just grab my time series and I'm going to call rolling on it.
And let's go ahead and calculate the sense of what is a 12 month rolling simple average and the simple
moving average is a reflection of the yearly moving average because remember each row at each index
position is a month worth of data which means total those months that's a year.
So that I'm going to plot this.
And let's just give this a label will say 12 month ruling mean and then I'm also going to plot the time
series itself.
All right so if we see this we can see here that this 12 month rolling mean is definitely showing some
sort of upward trend the milk.
It's also pretty obvious just to our eyes that there is some sort of upward trend here and we can kind
of almost just visually here separate the trend versus the seasonality.
And what's also common to do in these sort of plots is to plot out the standard deviation So we want
to kind of check is the variance changing at all.
So we'll say SDD here and we'll say instead of rolling I mean I'll say SDD.
So this kind of checking hey on a yearly basis is the standard deviation changing a lot is when you're
kind of crazy for milk production.
Now let's go ahead and say peel tea legend so we can see the actual names of the columns in that plot.
And this is a really common plot you'll see with time series data where you see the actual data the
kind of rolling mean or simple moving average trend line and then usually at the bottom you'll see some
rolling standard deviation.
Usually the scale of standard deviation is much lower than the actual values and that pretty much makes
sense for most time series data sets.
Well you don't want to see is kind of some crazy behavior here on this 12 month rolling standard deviation
if in comparison it looks pretty flat to and compare to your normal dataset.
Then you know you're dealing with something that's pretty workable.
All right.
Now the next thing we can check out visually is our ETF the composition plot that is the air trend and
seasonality the composition.
Remember that the composition plot what it does is it mathematically separates out the trend component.
The seasonality component and then the residual that's the error that's not explained by seasonality
or trend.
It plots them up nicely for us and we can do that.
That's model pretty easily.
So we end up saying we'll save from stat's models that TSA that seasonal import seasonal decompose and
then will go ahead and do is we'll say the composition or it will just say the comp here is equal to
seasonal decompose and then we'll pass in that time series that we've been messing around with.
Remember that's just the milk in pounds column from our data frame.
And then all we have say is the comp that plot and we'll get back our decomposition data.
So our the composition you can see the observed values the trend the seasonal values and then the residual.
You'll notice here that because of the way that's models currently interacts with Jupiter notebook you
end up getting two plots and that's the way it's returning the plot.
So if you actually want to make sure that you just get a single plot we can and that doing is something
like this you can set fig equal to D-cup that plot and then you'll get back one plot.
Now what's also nice about this is if you want to edit the size of this plot you can say fig dot and
call sets underscore size and there's a bunch of map plot live calls here that you can do.
And you can set size inches.
You can do something like.
Well I don't know let's say 15 by and this will kind of clear it up for us.
Notice I'm really zoomed in.
So it may not look this way for you it won't be this large.
Well probably a little smaller but here we can clearly see our observed data.
There's clearly an upward trend.
The seasonality component seems to be kind of on a yearly frequency here and then the residual data.
There's another argument you can specify for the seasonal decompose and if we take a look at it here
we chose an additive model to default because it looks like it's just kind of some linear earth if it
doesn't look like it's a multiplicative.
And then there's filt and frequency.
So this frequency argument that we've kind of touched on before a little bit is the frequency of the
series.
So it has to be used if x is not a panel object and if it is a Panas object what it's going to do is
override the default what's known as pure this city.
So basically what you end up doing here is if you wanted to make sure that every period was a yearly
period for the season you could say hey set my frequency to be 12 and then you would see something like
this.
Now basically is the exact same result but where you're kind of specifying here is OK every 12 months
is going to be year.
And that's what I kind of want you to focus on as far as the seasonal data and usually can do this automatically
if it's a panel date time index so typically you don't need to provide it but I just want you to be
aware of it just in case you ever find yourself needing it in the future.
OK the next thing I want to do is test for stationary.
Well go ahead and do that.
And the very next lecture video now we finished the visualization tasks.
So we're going to move on to some of the more mathematical tasks that allow us to set up for the remodel.
Coming up next.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.