Welcome back everyone to this series of lectures on Quanto Appian pipeline's.
Now that we understand the basics of Quanto Appian research notebooks and we realized how to use Quanto
in IEEE Let's move on to this Gus Quanto be in pipelines.
Pipelines are useful for our rhythms that follow a set structure.
Let's quickly review the set structure.
Typically the pipeline structure follows four key steps.
You first need to compute some scalar value for all assets then that's usually based off some rolling
time period.
So essentially for each asset in a known or large set such as the S&amp;P 500 or all U.S. equities you compute
some sort of scalar value for the asset.
Maybe the 20 day rolling mean so you do that for all the assets in a really large set.
Then the second step is to select a smaller tradeable set of assets based on the values computed in
step 1.
So basically what you end up doing is out of all the U.S. equities you calculate that known scalar value
and then you're going to filter for that particular scalar value.
Then once you have that you move onto step three which is essentially to calculate the desired portfolio
awaits on the set of assets selected in that second step.
Once you've done that the last step is to place orders to move the algorithms current portfolio allocations
to the desired way it's computed in step three.
Now there are several technical challenges with doing this robustly and those can be things like efficiently
queering large sets of assets such as queering the entire U.S. equities pricing data set performing
computations on these large sets of assets handling the adjustments such as splits and dividends doing
things like taking care of asset listings in case a ticker gets the listed and will Quanto business
try to do is with the pipeline kind of system.
It exists to solve those challenges by providing a really nice uniform API.
Now the opium pipelines really offer a nice syntax to perform these operations repeatedly and we're
going to be breaking up each major step into a separate lecture.
Now all I keep saying that it's a nice syntax.
It does take some time to getting used to.
So take your time with this topic while the concepts are pretty simple and there's really only that
kind of these four major steps.
The syntax can be tricky at first you need to give your time to let it click.
So remember to reference the notebook in case you need a copy and paste any code into the research notebook
that first will be basically just dealing with research notebook who won't deal Quanto an ideally.
And I actually recommend you upload the provided notebook to your Quanto profile so you can just directly
follow along.
All right let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.