Hello everyone and welcome to Quanto Appian pipeline's.
We're going to begin using pipeline's by discussing just a few key parts mainly classifiers and factors
and as well how to actually create a pipeline.
So let's quickly discuss what a classifier is a classifier is a function that transforms the input of
an asset and the time stamps it takes.
An asset is an input and the time stamp as an input and it converts it to some sort of categorical output.
And an example of this is passing in Apple or the Assaidi of Apple and time stamp of 2017 and then reports
back some sort of categorical output such as tech sector.
So I could pass and the asset the time stamp and then reports back Apple in the year 2017 happens to
belong to the technology sector.
So that's an example of a classifier essentially just classifying this as ID at this particular time
stamp.
And the reason we have to provide that time stamp is because companies change maybe Apple completely
changes to actually become a fruit company and that's in the agricultural sector.
You never know.
So that's where we have to provide both the asset and the time stamp.
Then a factor is similar except that it actually returns a numerical value.
So it takes and again an asset and the time stamp.
But instead of returning categorical output or returns a numerical one such as a 10 day moving average.
So in this lecture we're going to create a pipeline that returns back all equities available at some
time stamp.
And I think that's part of what makes pipeline's a little confusing at first is the fact that you essentially
grab everything and then start to create factors or classifiers and then filter those out.
So we have learned about filters yet but we're going to kind of start with grabbing all the data and
the next lecture will learn how to kind of filter for it.
So again we're going to create a pipeline returns back all the equities and then we're going to use
Quanto opens built in U.S. equity pricing data set to match up prices to those IDs then we can create
a factor that will compute some numerical value given the pricing information such as the 30 day moving
average in a lot of these functions are actually going to be imported from built in Quanto up in pipeline
libraries.
So we don't really have to cut out that much and said we're just going to do a lot of convenient imports.
OK so let's see how these concepts fit in with the pipeline operator in Quanto in I'm going to jump
to a new research note book now.
All right.
I've created a new title notebook in my research notebooks on Quanto in and the first thing going to
do is say from Quanto in the pipeline and sometimes it has trouble with the tab autocomplete for Quanto
in that pipeline.
It's sometimes automatically goes to quando So just keep that in mind.
Then I will say in poor pipeline.
OK so I've imported this pipeline object and then the next thing to do which may seem a little strange
if you're pretty familiar of Python but we're actually going to create a function called Make pipeline
and all it does.
It just returns in instantiation of the pipeline object.
Again not typical for normal Python programming you usually just call pipeline.
But the reason for that is when we begin to add things like factors classifiers filters having everything
inside a function makes a little more sense.
So now that we have this function that essentially makes a pipeline we're going to create a pipeline
object will say pipe is equal to make pipeline.
So if I take a look at what pipe actually is it's essentially this pipeline object from the zip line
library member that's the open source version of a lot of these Quanto open tools.
At this particular point in memory so I have my pipeline object ready to go.
The next thing I need to do is import run a pipeline and that's going to allow me to run this pipeline.
So we'll do the following.
We'll say from Quanto in research in poor run pipeline.
So then we're going to say result is equal to run pipeline and if you do shift tab here you'll notice
there's three main arguments that we want to focus on here.
When you pass and run pipeline you pass in a pipeline and then a start day and then end date and there
is a chunk size as well.
Computing in chunks is useful when you have pipeline's computed over a long period of time.
So kind of does stuff in chunks but right now we're not dealing with that so we'll just say pipeline
the start date and the end date.
In effect we only really want one day of information.
So we'll have the start date be the same as the end date.
So I pass in my pipe object and then I'm going to pass in some sort of date.
So let's say 2017 0 1 0 3.
That was essentially the first day of trading in 2017.
And if you actually pass in the first tier it will jump up to the third the first day of trading for
the year and we're going have the end date be the same thing.
So 2017 0 1 0 3.
And what's nice about this is it can just pasand the strings in this particular order year month date
with dashes and it knows that there are time stamps.
So I'm going to run that and then I have my results so let's check out what our result actually looks
like.
So when you run this you get kind of a funky looking data frame.
You'll notice that there's a ton of equities here.
And if you scroll all the way down you'll end up seeing that you have 20:17 0 1 0 3.
So what is this actually representing here.
Well if you take a look at the info Ill say multiday index eight thousand three hundred forty three
entries and says it's an empty data frame.
So this kind of two key things to note here one is that there actually are no columns in the state of
frame.
If you look at results that columns notice there weren't actually any columns there and that's because
what we're actually looking at here is just two sets of indices one set on the very outer left is a
multiyear index or there this whole thing is a Maltais index on the outermost layer is the actual time
stamp.
So we have 2017 the 3rd of January and this insight index we have the equities.
So it's the ID for this actual stocks we have the symbol of stock and the Assaidi at this particular
moment in time and essentially return every single Assaidi available for us at this particular moment
in time.
So again this is what kind of makes it a little weird because we're getting back everything.
It's not until you learn about filters that are going to filter out based off some sort of value but
to get those values you need to use things like factors.
So let's go ahead and kind of discuss what factors are now going to hash tag that out.
So now right now we have that result object essentially just a multi index there's actually no information
there beyond the index.
So we will say from Quanto up in the pipeline that data built in import.
And we're going to import U.S. equity pricing and this essentially contains the price information for
all those equities in that index.
So now we're going to create a factor that's going to allow us to take in the ID and that time stamp
information.
Essentially the information from the index and calculate some sort of numerical value from it and it's
going to calculate that using the U.S. equity pricing information.
So we're going to do the following.
We'll say from Quanto up in that pipeline that factors import.
And if you hit tab here you'll notice that there's a bunch of factors available to things like average
dollar volume business day since previous events Bollinger bands a max draw down then you have Morningstar
for all those fundamental data points returns etc..
Simple moving average true range.
So we're going to start off with just simple moving average run that imported simple moving average
from Pipeline that factors that I'm going to call simple moving average and it will take something like
inputs and you passen us equity pricing and then you get tap here.
And you'll notice that you have all the pricing information the close price domain high low open volume
etc..
So we're going to just pasan close here.
And if you do shift tab's simple moving average will tell you what it expects.
So it expects these inputs which kind of go off.
U.S. equity pricing and then expects a window length.
So that's essentially how many days do you want.
For the simple moving average So we're going to pass in here window lengths
equal to 30 days.
All right.
So we have this right now.
If I just read this I won't really get anything back.
Just a simple moving average so we need to use this in conjunction with our make pipelined function.
So let's scroll back up grab our make pipeline function.
Remember I said previously it was a little weird to do this but now you're going to see why we need
to do it this way.
We have this function pipeline an envoy to do the following.
I'm going to create a variable here that says something like I mean close 30.
So that is the average closing price over the last 30 days.
Otherwise known as our simple moving average with the inputs of the U.S. equity pricing that close with
a window length of 30.
So I'm going to copy that and paste that in here.
So then I have this variable mean close 30 and right now I'm just returning pipeline.
So inside a pipeline will you end up doing is the following you create a new parameter called columns
and columns ends up being a dictionary where the dictionary ends up having the key of the new name of
the column such as 30.
They mean close and then you pass in the factor itself.
I remember this is the factor.
I mean close 30.
So remember this is a factor object because we imported it from factors.
So we're going to kind of copy and paste this here
and pass that here for us.
Run that.
And now we have our pipeline object now because these can be really complicated methods.
What we want to do is pass this into run pipelines so we make sure it only runs when we're ready for
it to run.
So let's take results now and say run the pipeline and we're going to pass in our pipeline object.
So there's two ways we can do this.
We can either do what we did above here which is say pipe is equal to make pipeline and then pass it
in or what sometimes people like to do is they just copy this line right here and instead of creating
in another variable is copy and paste that in here instead.
So that's what we'll do.
So we'll kind of just passen make pipeline here instead and then we're going to pass and the dates say
which just is for one day.
The 3rd of January here and then 2017 0 1 0 3.
So we're doing this just for one day and getting our results now pending on the complexity of make pipeline.
This could take a while because remember central we're doing is we're saying all right for every single
US equity on this day and time.
Go ahead and calculate the simple moving average So the 30 day moving average and we're going to do
that on the close price because it called us equity pricing close.
Okay once this is done running may take some more like 30 seconds in a minute depending on your date
range where we can end up doing it check out the results so say give me the head of the results here
and then we end up seeing the following Lucy the 30 day I mean close remember that's what we call this
actual column and you can feel free to call this whatever you want.
And then we have the factor which is the number right here.
So remember the factor it takes and the falling it takes in some time stamp and some SITD some asset
and returns back some numerical values such as the third they mean close.
And this is a factor with topia and pipeline's.
So so far so good.
The actual concepts are pretty simple.
It's just the fact that the syntax is a little weird to get used to and a lot of the kind of weirdness
of the syntax in my opinion is the fact that you kind of have to know where to find a lot of this stuff.
He had realized that he had to import simple moving average you know at a passen the inputs themselves
and to be honest a lot of that kind of experience or knowledge just takes a lot of time looking through
the documentation.
OK.
So we have the results here and we have the factor 3 they mean close.
So we have time stamp asset turnback some numerical factor.
Let's discuss having multiple factors and combining factors.
So what we're going to do now is the following.
We're going to grab this make pipeline copy it put it in a new cell and we're going to add in another
factor to calculate.
Let's go ahead and say latest close is equal to and we'll say U.S. equity pricing close dots and you'll
notice that if you see another tab here you can grab a bunch of other parameters here.
So one of them is latest Braben latest there.
So we have the latest close which is the latest U.S. equity price in clothes here.
And then we're going to add that in this new column.
So I'll say
latest clothes and this is going to pass and latest clothes and we're going to run that so we'll say
results are equal to run a pipeline and going to pasan make pipeline.
And then we will say some start the 2017 or ones or three and we'll say the following let's say 2017
0 1 0 3 notice here that if you were to add in another kind of larger date you'd have more and more
rows because you're using multi indexing.
Now we're going to run this.
And again this may take a little bit of time but hopefully if you did the first one already it shouldn't
take that long.
But let's go ahead and check out the head of the results here.
The head and I can see I have two columns now the 30 day I mean close and the latest is and just as
a quick note this is the latest close based off this time stamp.
So this is essentially its closing price on January 3rd 2017.
And this is the average closing price over the last 30 days before January 3rd 2017.
So just keep that in mind.
This is not today's latest close.
This is the state's latest close and it's the state's 30 day average close.
So now that we have those results we can end up doing is actually combined them and combining factors
is actually quite simple.
Here we have two separate factors.
So the combined them all you need to do is say something like percent diff.
So that's going to be the percent difference between the 30 day clothes and let's say let's just say
the 10 day moving average or something.
So let's go in and copy this.
We're going to copy that and we're going to paste that in and we'll change the window length to be 10
and we'll make this 10.
And whether or not this is a useful calculation you know it's kind of up to you but I just want to show
you how to combine two factors.
So I mean close to 30.
That's a factor of the simple moving average over the last 30 days then going have mean close 10 which
is going to be a simple moving average of the closing price over the last 10 days.
And so what we're going to do with that Issei percent difference is going to just be equal to mean close
10 minus mean close 30 divided by I mean close 30.
So again kind of just an arbitrary statistic to measure here but this is more just to show you what's
possible and then we're going to call this whatever we want we can say percent's difference.
And again totally up to you.
We want to call it you can call this column Jeli just to make it clear that there's no restrictions
on the name and we'll add that in.
So let's make that pipeline we will run that pipeline again.
And let me make sure.
Percent.
If an Whoops looks like I said pre-sent not percent.
So let's run that again.
There we go.
Now we get our results run that and I have the percent difference where the percent difference between
the mean close and 10 days versus the mean close over 30 days and that's how you can calculate single
factors and actually combine factors to grab more information.
We're going to do next is discuss filters and screen.
So typically you're not going to want to grab every single equity at some particular time stamp.
Well you want to do is grab the time stamp grab the IDs calculate some sort of factor off of it.
And then what you'll do after that is filtered off based off some sort of factor.
So let's go ahead and show you how to do that in the next lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.