Hello everyone.
Welcome to the Quanto open pipeline series where we discuss filters and screens.
So we're going to continue learning about pipelines and filters and screens basically allow you to take
an asset and a time stamp and then return a boolean and the screen portion of it allows you to actually
execute those filters in your pipeline.
The best way to learn about this is just by coding them out.
So let's hop over back to that same research notebook we were using in the last lecture.
OK so here we are back in the Jupiter notebook.
Let's quickly review the make pipeline function from the previous lecture in the previous lecture we
had a couple of factors such as the 10 day simple moving average the 30 day simple moving average grabbing
the latest close prices.
And then we had this custom factor or the combined factor of percent difference or percent DFS.
And it just calculated the percent difference between the 10 day and 30 day simple moving averages.
Now let's go ahead and create a filter off of this.
Now the filter is essentially just going to be a comparison operation against one of the factors you
imported or created.
So for example we can say if we remember if we run this show this again I run those three cells I can
see percent difference is sometimes negative and that it's sometimes positive which makes sense.
So we're going to do is let's say we only wanted to grab where percent difference happened to be positive
or we can do is falling will say
PERQ filter percent filter whatever you want to call this and we'll grab where percent difference is
greater than zero.
And then we're going to do is adding a new column here and we'll have this be something like we can
just say percent filter and pasand the actual filter itself.
So let's run that make sure it worked out for us and he can see our new percent filter column.
Remember a piece or a filter in general takes in an asset and some sort of time stamp and then returns
a boolean So you're taking in the time stamp and the asset and it's returning a boolean.
Now that Bulleen is then calculate on top of a factor so keep that in mind as well.
So we can see here that false this is not Graydon's zero.
Falses not ground zero and true this is greater than zero.
So let's actually discuss the screen.
Typically you're not just going to ask for a filtered column where you want to do is actually execute
that filter.
And the way to do that is with the following method.
When we zoom in here so it's a little clear here we already have the columns argument inserter pipeline.
We're going to add a new argument and that argument is going to be called screen and that screen argument
isn't going to allow us to actually execute the filter so I'll say screen is equal to.
And then you just pass in the filter itself.
So we're going to run that again grab our results and you'll notice you only get back where the filter
happens to be true.
So you see true true true.
And all these percent differences happen to be above zero.
Now let's say you wanted to do the opposite.
You want it to just quickly reverse this filter.
Well one way you could do that is instead of saying greater than zero you could say less than zero.
But what's nice about using the screen methodology is you can put the tilde symbol there and it will
reverse the screen for you.
So let's run that and I can see you have the opposite everywhere where the filter was false.
So that's the way you can use filters and screens.
And that's also how you can then reverse the filter.
What's also nice about this is that you can combine filters sourcecode and create another filter.
So we're going to say Pearch filters percent difference greater than zero.
And then we'll say the small price is equal to.
Let's go ahead and grab the latest close price have it be less than $5 and I'm filtering on two things.
I want the percent difference to be positive.
And then I want the latest close price to be less than $5.
So relatively small small price stocks I mean it's hard to tell because we're not really asking for
market cap or that sort of thing but I was kind of low priced stocks.
So in order to actually combine these into a single filter.
So we're going to combine filters right now what you end up doing is you say something like final filter
is equal to and then you just use logical operators to combine your comparison operators.
So say Tilke percent filter here.
And you're going to use ampersand and then you use a pipe operator for or case you want to combine them
that way.
But we're going to say Pearch filter and small price.
So it was a little different between pythons built in and in OR.
But that happens to do with the same logic when we're discussing panderers comparisons the fact that
the truth series ends up being ambiguous so you need to use either ampersand or that or operator.
And then if you want knots it's going to be an exclamation point.
But so far we just combined those two filters the percent filter and small price and then we call that
final filter.
So let's go ahead and for our screen we'll pass the final filter so we're going to run that run that
run that.
And you'll notice our present filter happens to be true for all of them which makes sense because it's
part of the final filter that has to be greater than zero percent difference and we also have small
price.
So notice all the close prices are less than $5.
All right.
That's really all we need to know about using a filter and then using screen to actually execute the
filter.
So again all I need to do to create a filter is simply grab a factor and then use a comparison operator
on it.
If you want to combine multiple filters just use logical operators in this case ampersands and then
the pipe operator that you can passes in to grab a new column and then play around with the empanadas
Or you could just pass it into screen and then actually filter out the results when you run the pipeline.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.