Welcome back everyone.
And in this lecture we're going to continue right where we left off and discuss continuous futures.
And as a quick review of what continuous futures are.
Remember that when we plotted out the volume being traded for each individual's features contract you
get the behavior of a lot of volume being traded as you can get close to the maturity date and then
Elly's for natural gas.
But a month before you know the speculation of the market price is starting to match probably the true
market price value at the point of maturity so people start kind of declining in their trading and maybe
there's some event to give you a little spike.
But eventually it goes down to zero once the actual maturity date has been reached.
So again this is volume being traded.
So it would be nice is if we could somehow kind of get some sort of continuous value here that we wouldn't
have to deal with the hassle of kind of jumping from a futures contract the futures contract.
So it continues.
Future is an abstraction over these underlying assets.
So for example if we wanted to trade crude oil we could create a reference to see oil that's the crude
oil reference code instead of a series of seal contracts.
So we're going to be able to use continuous features and just type in natural gas instead of typing
in a natural gas January 2018.
We can just say natural gas.
So we use the continuous fut. object as part of the platform to get a continuous chain of historical
data for futures contracts taking some of these concerns into account.
Now one of the things we're going to discuss when talking about continuous features is how do we actually
adjust for the change from one fut. to another.
You can see there's kind of a crossover point here but at what time should we crossover or should we
just crossover when the volumes kind of overlap should cross over at the maturity date and should we
kind of make any sort of mathematical adjustment in pricing here.
So we're going to talk about that adjustments as kind of a huge part of continued features and there's
different ways to do it and there's multiple options that you can provide.
So as a quick reminder continues.
Futures are not actual tradable assets.
They are just an abstraction over the actual tradable assets which are these individual futures contracts.
So what they really do is they maintain a reference to the current active contract related to the given
underlying contracts.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and kind of explore how you can grab continuous fut. and as a quick no.
I know the wording is kind of confusing sometimes because I'm using consecutive versus continuous.
So just to make it clear especially if English is not your first language what I showed here were consecutive
contracts.
So I can see one contract after another after another after another.
So these are consecutive what I'm going to discuss now is continuous.
So some sort of abstraction that allows us to be kind of a single continuous line.
So hopefully that kind of clears things up.
I know it can be a little confusing especially because the words kind of are so similar to each other.
All right so I'll say from one toping that research experimental import continuous future and at some
point in your future if you're watching this video at a later time it may a little longer be under experimental
So definitely check the documentation of CONTO Appian to see where he should import continuous future
from.
And then I'm going to just say continuous future and print out the documentation for you so you can
see here it takes in some parameters.
The root symbol.
So that's the root symbol for the continuous future.
Again it's just a symbol.
The actual thing you're tradings it come back here to this notebook.
It's just going to be one of these symbols like natural gas or energy because it's continuous.
We're kind of doing away of the date and time codes.
Then you're going to have what you could do is an offset.
So the distance from the primary contract you can always just use the default zero.
There's going to be rules and then adjustments which we're going to talk about at a later time period.
So again root symbol is a symbol for the underlying offset the distance from the primary contract.
Zero icles primary one is equal secondary.
Talk more about that later.
Role is how do the term the current contract of the continuous feature and the current options are volume
and calendar.
So the volume approach here chooses the current active contract based on trading volume.
So as I discussed up here I was kind of mentioning Well how do we decide when to jump from this kind
of blue future to this green future.
So there's two ways to do that.
We could choose the one of the highest volume being traded at any given time.
So we would switch over kind of when they roll over here or we could choose to kind of hop over to the
next future.
Once this futures contract has reached maturity and then we would kind of jump back up to here.
We're going to usually use the volume way of rolling over.
But again it really depends on your current situation and what kind of data you want.
Then there's finally the adjustment and the adjustment is how to adjust historical prices from earlier
contracts and the options are and you l for multiple multiplicative adjustment D for ADD additive adjustment
and then none for no adjustment.
And we'll talk about that later we'll kind of play around with them to show you how they each affect
your continuous futures contract.
So let's actually get our continuous feature so we're going to say continuous Gunton US natural gas
and we're going to use that continuous future function we pass in the CO-2 want ngi for natural gas
when we use a default offset.
We're going to roll over based off volume.
So basically at any given point in time we're going to choose the futures contract that has the most
volume being traded.
And then we won't have any adjustment for now or actually let's go ahead and pass the multiplicative
adjustment later on we'll show you what it looks like no adjustment.
Okay.
So we grab that data we're going to grab continuous energy and you can see here it's a continuous feature
has some sort of code based off where we actually provided route symbol and then these three parameters.
So what we're going to do is grab historical information for this continuous natural gas.
Previously we just did it for one futures contract.
Now we're going to do it for this continuous features kind of abstraction object so forsake natural
gas continuous I'll call it active because it's kind of like which ones are the most active right now.
Well passen that continuous natural gas object and then I'm going to ram multiple fields from this we're
going to say grab the contract the price and the volume.
Now let's go ahead and say that frequency is going to be daily we'll see the start dates and we'll say
start from 2016.
Let's just grab from kind of the same date so was it before.
So kind of October 2016 end date.
2017 let's say August 1st.
OK so we have that information and if we actually take a look what this ends up looking like it's a
data frame just as before.
And we can see here we have price volume and then the contract name.
Now there's something important to note here is since this is continuous versus what we did before which
was kind of grabbed this historical information for various individual futures contracts.
You'll notice that this contract is going to end up changing as we go further and further out in time.
So to show you that I'm going to say ngi continuous active and let's go ahead and say contract and then
say unique and you can see here I have various features I have natural gas x 16 natural gas Z 16 x cetera
and basically this is indicating at whatever particular point in time and the index this was the future
with the most volume being traded.
And that's kind of what the rollover is trying to do here.
That ruling style.
So let's go ahead and kind of plot it out.
So let's plot out the price so we can see how the price changes over time.
So going to copy and paste this pasand price let's just plot that out.
So I can see here the price and now I have kind of this continuous pricing abstraction over what I did
previously and we can see the same thing for the volume.
So if we kind of just copy and paste this and instead of pricing we check out the volume.
I get the same thing here.
So I can see a sort of continuous volume instead of multiple futures.
So again this is an abstraction.
Now typically for most students just seeing a chart like this is a little confusing and it's hard to
connect this chart to the chart we saw earlier over here.
So we're going to do is actually plot them on top of each other.
And then I think you'll make it really clear what the continuous features object is actually doing.
So we're going to do is we're going to come back up here to where we said ngi consecutive contract volume
copy this come down here and we're going to pace that again.
Remember this is consecutive not continuous.
We have the same contracts but what we're going to do is at the same time period that we had heard this
continuous object which was 2016 10 1 for our starting date here we started a little bit earlier.
So basically we just have to do is switch out this one date.
OK so now I have the consecutive contracts of individual contracts that go from October 2016 to August
2017.
My continuous values also go for that same amount.
Let's go ahead and plot them on top of each other to see how this works.
And Renie's a little bit of kind of map plus lib tricks here.
So I'm going to say OK my continuous active natural gas.
I'm going to save volume and then I'm going to plot this out and I'm going to say the line style is
a dash line going say the color is black I believe is the single letter code for that.
And let's go ahead and make the line with that a little thicker like three.
So if I plot that out I essentially get the same plot I did before.
It's this plot right here except it has a little bit of different styling.
Now the reason I kind of wanted the different styling and the make this just a little thinner is because
I'm going to plot this chart on top of what we saw earlier which was this chart and you're going to
see now how the roll over kind of takes effect.
So let's go ahead and do that.
The way I can do this of PANDAS is I'm going to grab my consecutive contract volume.
That's the one I just created a peer.
I'm going to then plot it out and I'm going to set the access equal to the axes I just created.
So that's why I assigned this to A-X.
That way I can plot these two pandas plots on top of each other.
So I'm going to run this.
And now you're going to see the behavior.
So no here I have my blackline that's my continuous abstraction over this.
And then eventually it's going to line up exactly with the kind of most volume traded for any features
of that particular point in time.
And then you can see where the rollover occurs.
Right here we switched based on volume to the next fut. volume.
And this kind of gives you it continuous substraction over what's going on.
OK.
So I hope that made it a little clearer and you can kind of play around with this if it's you know if
you prefer kind of a thicker line with so you can really see where it's kind of above everything you
can do that as well.
You can essentially see how it's rolling over based on volume from one contract to the next.
So it gives you a better idea of some sort of continuous value for natural gas over time and sort of
his individual futures contracts.
And then we can kind of show the same plot for pricing so an issue with that looks like right now we
have Engy consecutive contract volume it just grabbed the volume field.
I'm going to copy this paste it down here.
But instead of volume we're going to grab price.
So I'll change that to consecutive contract price change this field.
So the price that I'm going to run that and then later make sure I have those fields as well in my continuous
active.
So looking over here it's continuous active.
It looks like it has everything I need the contract price volume for the same time stamp so that should
be good.
So I'll come back over here and I'm going to first plug out the consecutive so we can see those prices.
OK so remember these are my consecutive individual features.
So I can see the prices for those for whatever unit of natural gas as time goes on and you can see as
they reach maturity date eventually they have no pricing information.
So this one expires in March and April and expires in May.
This expires in June or maybe keeps going.
Et cetera.
But you can see here how they kind of each dieoff their maturity date.
So now let's go ahead and show you what this looks like for the continuous versus the consecutive.
So I grabbed my continuous fut. object.
I believe it's called continuous active you grabbed the price in column off of that and then I'm going
to plot out.
Let's go ahead to make the color black again.
And make the line with equal to 3 and you can see here I kind of have a continuous representation of
that.
Similar to what we saw for the volume.
However you'll notice that this sort of represents the underlying commodity natural gas on the most
actively traded contract at this particular point in time.
So this is much easier to look at for pricing information versus like all these prices especially if
you're kind of looking at a time stamp where you have multiple contracts being traded at any given point
in time.
Now here's the thing you'll notice here on the Y-axis that we our values go from like 3.0 to 3.6.
And when I plotted out continuously It now starts at 4.0 4.5 for that same time stamp.
So the best way to explain this as why there is that reference is to plot the price history of the unadjusted
continuous feature.
So here we have some sort of adjustment being taken place which is why we're kind of getting a different
price here.
So we'll show you the unadjusted version of this.
So I would say continuous natural gas unadjusted is equal to I'm going to use that same continuous future
function.
So when we imported pass a natural gas pass and the offset is equal to zero.
I'm also going to roll off volume again.
The other option was to roll off calendar which basically rolls off when the calendar switches over.
And then for the adjustment I previously did m u l for multiplicative and specifically type and none
no.
So there is no adjustment.
And then I'm going to do the same thing for history so I'm going to say grab this and then replace Engy
contracts with continuous ngi unadjusted because I want the unadjusted features.
Same field so actually that person contract as well.
So we can see how the contracts change see contracts and price for these fields.
And now let's call this something else.
This is going to be my on adjusted history.
So now I have my natural gas it's unadjusted history.
So if I take a look at the head of this data frame unadjusted history I can see here I have the price
and the particular contract that's being referenced as kind of the main contract at that point in time.
So now if I plot the sell natural gas and a just that history and I plot out that price I can see here
now with no adjustments.
It pretty much matches up with what we saw appear as far as the range.
So then I'm going to do this as well for the original on that well we can have them kind of back to
back.
Let me come up here and copy this.
So again this is the unadjusted plot.
And then these are the consecutive ones so we can see here.
So the unadjusted one remember it's being figured by volume.
So we can do is to kind of plot these two on top of each other.
We can use what's known as a pivot table trick.
Don't worry too much about understanding the logic behind the pivot table.
There's more of kind of an advanced panderers thing but essentially it's just going to allow us to kind
of create a nice chart for you.
So let's go ahead and explore that.
So I'm going to say pivot on an A just as equal to the unadjusted history object that just made that
data frame and I'm going to pivot it.
The index is going to be the same index unadjusted history the index of that data frame.
But I'm going to make the columns equal to the contract.
So let me show you actually happened here with that pivot first kind of remind you what the undigested
version looks like.
So we see this unadjusted version it has a price column and a contract's column here.
What I'm going to do is make these particular individual contracts kind of group them together and pivot
this.
So each individual contract ends up becoming a column.
So if we show you what the pivoted version of this is just it looks like I'll show you the head of it
I can see now I have these price columns and each of these represents a feature and at certain points
in time some of these features don't really exist yet or they're not being traded.
So the future for kind of something in 2017 in October 2016 it doesn't have any volume being traded
or doesn't really have any pricing information for etc. so you can see this one is going to come up
and then they'll die off and then these will start kicking in.
So let's go ahead and plot this so you can see what that looks like.
And again you can always copy and paste from the notes.
I know I'm writing a lot of code here.
But here we're going to essentially plot the prices and you kind of see them jump from one to the other.
So here's kind of the current price for that contract that it jumps to the next one.
Based on volume that adjusts the next pricing that interrupts next pricing pricing jumps and you can
see here its price is jumping from contract to contract.
So these are the actual individual features.
So let's show you the unadjusted so we can kind of plot it on top.
So I will copy and paste this.
We're essentially going to be doing the same thing we did earlier.
So here's the unadjusted plots of the individual ones.
And let's get our unadjusted history and plot that out and say access to access are there on top of
each other.
Well is it the lifestyle to be a dash line and will that color to be black we will run this.
And now I can kind of see what's happening here.
So this unadjusted history price if we do no adjustments it's essentially just falling along based on
volume pricing.
It should go based on the individual contracts.
So that's the relationship between what is essentially this plot and these plots.
Except this is a kind of messy to look at.
So we can use that pivot table so we can see based on the highest volume being traded What was that
price as we jump.
Contract contract which is essentially what the unadjusted history is doing.
Now typically you will use some adjustment you're not going to use unadjusted.
And there's two main types of adjustments.
It's multiplicative or earth Medich which is just adding an emule for the multiplicative technique.
This essentially computes the adjustment as a ratio of the new contract price divided by the old contract
price whenever the active contract rolls to a new contract.
So that adjustment does again again it's a new contract price divided by the old contract price.
Whenever you decide to roll to the new one either you decide to roll based off the calendar or we decide
to roll based on the volume.
And I would say volume is more common than calendar rollovers but again it really depends on your specific
situation.
The arithmetic technique or the adding adjustment type is just going to adjust with new contract price
minus old contract price.
So then multiplicative new contract price divided by old contract price when you roll over additive
technique is just new contract price minus the old contract price.
When you roll over Ok I hope that was a bunch of useful information on Quanto Appian futures for you.
That's really the basics of what we can learn on Quanto open.
This is a really complex topic and definitely there's a lot more to it than what we covered here.
So check out the resource links if you're interested in reading more about futures.
Thanks everyone.