Welcome back everyone to part two of the Arema code along we finished visualizing the data.
And we also then eat the composition plot on the data.
Now it's time to actually test the data is stationary or not.
It's pretty obvious that it is not stationary just from viewing the data.
There is some clear seasonality to it but let's show you how you can test this mathematically using
stat's models specifically.
We'll be using the decie fuller test.
Let's go ahead and hop over to Jupiter notebook and continue on.
All right back to the Jupiter No but we're going to scroll down here and let's check out what our data
looks like just so we can remind ourselves.
We have this daytime index that we've called month and then we have milk in pounds per cow.
But we actually want to do is see if we can mathematically show that this data is either stationary
or non stationary.
And to do that we can use the augmented decie fuller unit root test.
Essentially what it is it's a statistical test that has a null hypothesis and the null hypothesis is
that it is a non stationary time series.
And the alternative hypothesis is that the series has no unit and actually is stationary.
And we're going to decide on this based off a p value returned a small p value typically less than point
0 5 indicates strong evidence against the null hypothesis.
So you then reject the null hypothesis remember that our null hypothesis here is that the time series
is non stationary.
A large p value if we get back a p value greater than points or 5 that indicates weak evidence against
the null hypothesis.
So you fail to reject the null hypothesis.
Don't use the word accept the null hypothesis.
You just fail to reject it because you don't really know if the null hypothesis is 100 percent true.
You just don't have enough evidence here that will allow you to reject that completely.
So let's show you how you can use that models to actually run the augmented Dicky for tests on our data.
We're going to do is say from SATs models the TSA stat tools we're going to import 80 fooler and this
little function Eighty-Four has everything inside of it that we need.
So all we end up doing is we just create a result variable and call the fooler on our actual time series.
In this case just the DFA milk pounds per cow.
And if you take a look at shift tab here it kind of explains the decie for unit test.
There are some other things you can add in as parameters.
We won't get too fancy if it will just leave everything default and then it also will explain what it
actually returns so returns this ATF test to stick it returns the P-value that's that we're going to
be most concerned with.
They'll also tell you the number of lags used and then number of observations critical values etc..
So let's run this and then we're going to create a little function here called ADF check that takes
in time series and then we're going to perform the following so we're actually going to kind of function
size the way we actually check out the result because if you look at the result right now it's just
the tuple here and it's not really nicely formatted.
So we're going to create a function that kind of nicely formats this for us.
So we'll say the following.
Zoom out one little level here so I can see the whole function as I program it.
We're going to do is define a function f check inside this function we're going to say result is equal
to the fooler the time series so we'll actually just pass a time series into the function itself.
This will allow us to kind of repeatedly do it the check in case we need to do it later on once or then
that we're going to print out just the name of the test we just ran.
Augmented decie full or test then I'll create a list of labels and labels are going to correspond to
what that result actually has in its order or the tuple.
So we have an ADF test statistics statistic that was the first one.
The next one is that P-value lips start a the line there will have a p value.
Next thing then the next thing is the number of lags.
You saw a number of lags and then what we're going to end up doing is basically kind of nicely print
these out.
So less what we want to come here is of observations.
So if you knows we have the ADF testers to stick the P-value number of lags in number of observations
we don't really concern ourselves with these other values here.
These are the only ones who want to care about the labels.
So let's go ahead and we're going to end up doing the following.
We'll say for value label in that it will zip together the result to tuple with my labels list but just
going to print my label plus we'll just have some space there then plus the string of my value so cases
number just make into a string that way prints out nicely.
And then after this once that's done I'm going to say if results 1 and remember that is my P-value right
here.
The second one.
So 0 1.
So if this p value is less than or equal to 0.05 I'm going to print the following statement strong evidence
against null hypothesis.
So there's strong evidence against the null hypothesis which means I'm going to reject the null hypothesis
so I'll print another line.
Reject all hypothesis
which then I'm going to say data has no unit root and if it ends up rejecting an all hypothesis it has
no root.
I will say and is stationary else it's going to be the exact opposite sign going to essentially fail
to reject the null hypothesis.
So I ain't going to do the following.
So Otherwise if that p value is greater than 0.05 I'm going to say strong evidence.
Whoops I mean weak evidence sorry.
Weak evidence against null hypothesis that I'm going to present fail to reject null hypothesis
and then after that I'm finally going to Prince since we reject the hypothesis we're going to assume
that time series has een in the kitting it is not stationary data has a unique root.
It is non stationary.
OK so now we have this Niceville function here that basically is going to print out everything nicely
for us and only have to do is pass in the state of frame or that column of the data frame.
So let's try that out.
Let's call it the check on our time series.
In this case it was just m. Compounce pako.
Well run it and we get back to falling.
OK we have the tests to stick the p value is 0.6 to number of observations etc. so it says weak evidence
against the null hypothesis failed to reject null hypothesis data has a unique root.
It is not stationary and that is actually what we expected remember when we plotted out this data.
Clearly it is not stationary.
There are some serious seasonality to this and there is even a trend there.
So it is not stationary for sure.
So given that doing is differencing So remember that we can take the first difference of a time series
which is just a change from one period to the next so we can easily calculate this with pantless.
So I'm going to take the difference.
I'll take the first difference.
I'll take the second difference and then also show you how you can take a seasonal difference so will
show you all those different CG techniques and it will pass those in to the ADF check function that
we just did and will check which one of them provides a stationary dataset for us to work with
so I'll say the familiar pounds per cow then I'm going to say.
Well let me actually save this to some sort of value.
Will say well ADF and let's make a new column called first difference.
So say.
Milk in pounds per cow and then we're going to do is we're going to subtract DMF milk pounds per cow.
Then I will shift one over.
So we're basically subtracting everything shifted over one time series or one type step excuse me.
And now if I take a look at my first difference if I just plot this you'll notice the effect is kind
of drastic here.
This is the first difference so it's definitely been flattened out.
You kind of removed that trend and the variance looks pretty average So we'll see if this is enough.
Let's actually end up calling the fact check on our first difference
and make sure that's correct.
But I need to do is drop the N.A. values because we took the first difference we're missing one value
here at the very beginning so that messes up the ATF function.
So try it again.
And there we have it.
So check first different stripe and a we can see here we have a p value of 0.03.
It says strong evidence against null hypothesis reject the null hypothesis data has no unit and is stationary.
And if I look at this visualization It does look pretty stationary but let's say this still wasn't enough
to make a stationary.
You had kind of this weird time series The first difference wasn't enough.
You never know.
Different time series that did more than one difference you can do.
A second difference.
So I'll show you how to do that.
In case you ever find the need for it to take a second difference what you just do is say create new
column milk second difference and what that it's going to be equal to is milk first difference.
Make sure it's called just first difference excuse me first difference minus DMF first difference shifted
over by one and then we can do or eat the check against that second difference.
So say the check against the milk second difference run that again.
We have to drop the any values.
Sorry I forgot that now are missing 2 on the second difference here and there we have it.
So then we get I went to Turkey for a test P-value point 0 3.
You can see that not much has changed.
And in fact if we just plot this out the milk second difference dot plot you can see here it looks almost
the same on the second.
Different.
So really it was the first difference that did most of the elimination of the trend.
OK what else want to discuss is because we have seasonal data and we will do a seasonal Arema at the
end of this.
You can also take a seasonal difference.
So the way you can do that is the following.
You can say DMF
seasonal difference is equal to the.
And we'll take our original call a million pounds per cow.
Now I'm going to subtract it from 15 pounds per cow but I'm gonna shift this over by an entire season
that is by 12 and then if we take a look at our seasonal difference and plot that out we get something
like this.
So this may or may not be enough to pass our tests.
Let's go ahead and copy this and actually pass it into our check.
And again sorry I keep forgetting I dropped in lvalues
and there we go.
We are P-value point 1:06 that's actually not enough.
This is still considered a non stationary dataset and you can see it's definitely not stationary because
it looks like as you get further in time the variance begins to increase.
We can kind of see that visually here.
So sometimes though people like to do is when they want to take into account a seasonal difference but
it's not enough like this.
You can do a seasonal first difference so the way that works is you create in your column we'll call
it seasonal ferse difference and then you said equal to T.F. the milk first difference or I believe
wasn't milk it was just the first difference of this and then you're going to subtract the first difference
and for the second difference we shifted by one but the seasonal first difference so shifted by an entire
season.
And there you have it.
And check out these seasonal first difference.
Plot it out see what it looks like.
OK this looks pretty stationary but let's actually confirm with mathematics for EDF check.
We'll get our seasonal first difference here.
And you do think I remember it by now but I guess not.
We have to drop it.
And there we have it.
So it looks like strong evidence against the hypothesis reject the null hypothesis.
Data has no unit and is stationary and you can see here the P-value says 1.9 1.
But notice it's either negative 5 so that's one point nine times ten to the power of negative 5.
So definitely a very low P value there.
So strong evidence that it's stationary.
OK.
Now that we learned how to do a first difference a second difference and then also explored seasonal
differences as well as seasonal first differences.
The next step would be actually plot out the autocorrelation and the partial autocorrelation of plots
will go ahead and do that in part three in the next lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.