Welcome back everyone to part three of the three Makoto long lecture in part three will focus on creating
the autocorrelation and partial autocorrelation plots.
Let's hop over to you put a note book and continue where we left off.
All right so back of that you put it up but what we'll do is we will do the autocorrelation plots and
partial autocorrelation plots.
But we're actually going to do it for several of the time series so we created.
So you will run these plots on your different datasets.
Now we created several different state assets such as the seasonal first difference the first difference
and the second difference.
So let's go ahead and show you what autocorrelation plots can look like on various different datasets.
So the way you do this is first we have to import it will say from Stets models thought graphics thought
TSA plots import plot HCF and plot PRCA and then using these functions is actually quite easy you'll
just say create some figure object and let's call this figure object fig first because we'll do this
plot of the HGF that is the autocorrelation we'll do it first on the milk first difference.
Or I believe it's just the first difference.
There we go and we need to drop and Ayon this well run it.
And here we see the autocorrelation.
So this is the gradual decline autocorrelation that you may see in some of your differenced time series
data the other type of autocorrelation that's common to see is the sudden drop.
So to do that let's create fig and we'll just do seasonal let's say seasonal first here and we're going
to do is we'll plot the autocorrelation function for DMF and we'll say milk actually will say Seasonale
first difference and we'll need to drop in a here so we'll run that and we can see we have the autocorrelation.
And here is the sudden drop off.
So that's a very common autocorrelation plot to see.
And just so you know pantless actually has this functionality built in but it only has for autocorrelation
plots not partial autocorrelation functions.
So I recommend using stat's models for the sort of plotting but I do want to show you how you can create
this autocorrelation plot with pantless we end up doing as you say from panderers start plotting import
autocorrelation plot and then from there you can say auto correlation plot and then pass in whatever
you want.
So you get passen the seasonal first difference that we just did drop a.
And this will give you the autocorrelation plot.
So it's autocorrelation plot looks a little different.
It doesn't do these connecting lines here and if you actually don't want these connecting lines that
see parameter you can pass into plot HCF.
So if you do shift tab here it will ask you whether you want to use the vertical lines or not and whether
you want alpha.
So you could say use lines equals false as an argument so we can go in and pass.
I mean if you want see what that looks like.
And it won't put the actual vertical lines but panderers is a kind of K'NEX seems to be you can see.
It also keeps it from negative 1 to 1.
You can see the that's models will kind of auto adjust to the lowest and highest points in your autocorrelation
plot.
So that's why it looks a little different here.
It's really up to you which one you prefer but I would recommend sticking to stat's models.
That's the one that's going to be able to do both autocorrelation and partial autocorrelation.
So we'll continue on here.
Let's go ahead and move on to partial autocorrelation.
That is the plots.
And to do that all you need to do is call plot's underscore P-A C-f and that here will just pass just
pass in the seasonal first difference again.
And we'll drop and a
and let's just go ahead and assign this to result.
And we'll see the partial autocorrelation.
So just as a quick note if you do not assign the result here you may accidentally see it twice.
So you can go ahead and do that assignment just to see it one time and there's a partial autocorrelation
plot.
And this is a sudden drop off.
And typically you'll see the sudden drop off pretty much for almost every partial autocorrelation plot
you're working with it.
It really depends on your time series but this is quite common to see the complete drop off there.
OK.
So as far as interpreting this as far as the partial autocorrelation is concerned typically a sharp
drop after let's say K number of Laeg segments on the x axis indicates you should use some utterer aggressive
K number model.
So if there is a gradual decline and this partial autocorrelation or it suggests a moving average model
so go ahead and check out the Resorcin links if you want more information on learning about how to interpret
autocorrelation and partial autocorrelation plots since we've run quite a few plots already on different
different data sets.
We're going to do this just quickly create our final HCF MPAC plots and these are the ones we're going
to be referencing for the rest of the tasks for the arena model.
So I'm going to create a figure here and I'm going to do say Piazzi Well what I'll do is just say the
following will say plot HCF and we'll just call the seasonal first difference and then I'm also going
to do is whip's say drop and a
all run that and then what I also want to plot is the C-f.
OK so we have the partial autocorrelation and the autocorrelation.
So kind of the pends on what order you run these lines in as far as what order they come out.
So don't be confused by that.
But here you can see partial autocorrelation and autocorrelation and you can muster out fix sizes if
you want.
So you can say something like purity that figure you can see in the notebook that we provide.
We kind of did some stuff to mess around the figure size but basically we just need these two plots.
So we'll continue along here.
And the very next step that we do is actually use the Arema model.
And in this case our data was Seasonale.
So we're going to need to use the seasonal Arema model.
So in the next lecture will actually fit and build over the seasonal Arema model and then we'll use
it to forecast future values.
And I think you'll find that pretty cool.
How good of a forecast you can get just off of some of the basic stuff we've been learning about here.
Again some of these forecasting techniques don't work very well.
Security's financial data but it's still worth learning about.
Just so we can understand how to analyze time series data in a general format.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture where we actually fit the Arema model.