Welcome everyone to this quick lecture on the efficient market hypothesis EMH or the efficient market
hypothesis is an investment theory that states it's impossible to beat the market essentially because
the stock market efficiency causes existing share prices to always incorporate and reflect all relevant
information.
So according to the EMH stocks always trade at their fair value on stock exchanges making it impossible
for investors either purchase undervalued stocks or sell stocks for inflated prices.
As such it should be impossible to outperform the overall market.
Their expert stock selection or market timing and the only way an investor can possibly obtain higher
returns is by purchasing riskier investments.
So now the question arises is the efficient market hypothesis true.
Well if the efficient market hypothesis was true then a lot of what we're going to learn in this course
doesn't really have a point to it.
So hopefully it's not true just for that aspect but it would also imply that many hedge funds are just
extremely lucky hedge funds with continued success of picking securities and beating the market have
just been extremely lucky if the efficient market hypothesis is true which is unlikely.
So the success of different strategies and hedge funds implies that the strongest interpretation of
the efficient market prothesis is probably not true.
There are also events that have shown the market to be overvalued at certain points in history such
as the financial crisis and the com bubble.
So while some aspects of the efficient market paths certainly are true especially as information is
more widely accessible we're going to continue on the assumption that the market is not a 100 percent
efficiencies there are any efficiencies that we can exploit using our trading strategies and even things
like insider trading which is illegal are also strong indicators that the market is not 100 percent
of where of all information.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.