Welcome everyone to the section of Python finance fundamentals we're not going to really begin focusing
on using Python for finance and also trading in this section.
We're going to cover some key concepts in regards to trading for discuss things like portfolio allocation.
The Sharpe ratio per fully optimization the efficient frontier and then the capital asset pricing model
will also be introducing several other financial topics like how the actual market works how orders
get made and general arbitrage opportunities then we're going to interchange those shorter quicker discussions
of general finance topics with longer more detailed discussions of the actual implementation of these
topics in Python.
All right let's get started.
I'll see at the next lecture.