Welcome back everyone to our first lecture on PI.
We're going to be discussing Empire days.
Let's open up a new Jupiter notebook and get started.
All right.
So to start off we're going to do is just important umpire.
You just import it.
You can just say important umpire and by convention it's as and P.
And we're going to discuss.
Here is some pie arrays.
Empire pirates are the main way we're going to be using numpty throughout the course.
Non-power rays essentially come in two flavors.
Vectors and matrices were vectors are just one dimensional arrays essentially just a straight list and
then a matrix are two dimensional.
But you should note that a matrix will have only one row or one column.
So don't worry about that terminology too much because sometimes people tend to mix them up a little
bit.
All right let's start with just creating a new umpire.
And so how to actually creates a pie or a well you can create an umpire a through various methods.
One thing you can do is if you have a list one two three you can cast that to an array.
You can say N.P. dots and then call the array function.
You can do shift type here to find out more about it.
But essentially you just pass an object such as a list and it will output the array.
And what happened here.
Jupiter is actually telling you hey this is no longer just the normal Python list.
It's actually an array.
And if you want to confirm that you could for instance save this as a variable x and then check the
type of x and you can check that it's now and pi and the array.
So that's one thing you can do if you actually want to build a matrix.
You can create a variable matrix and have a nested list.
So that's a list of list will say one 2 three 4 5 6 7 8 9.
So note what I have here.
I have a list with three items in it and each of those items is a list that self with three additional
items.
So now if I pass this to some PI array pass in my matrix I get back in array.
But the actual dimensionality has been taken into effect.
When displaying the output so pi smart enough to realize that this is a two dimensional array or a two
dimensional matrix where I have three columns and then three rows and each they mentioned is notated
at the very end with a set of brackets.
So one set of brackets one dimensional two sets are brackets it's to them missional you can go to three
sets through them and for them in tonal center for financial data really don't go beyond to.
And sometimes three depending if you want to include another feature but really it's just to the data
we're working with.
OK so this is because a few built in methods to generate arrays sometimes you're working with financial
data.
You want to quickly model something that isn't that a random or straight zeros or straight ones or straight
fives etc..
An umpire is a really nice way to quickly create an array like that.
So if you remember we have the builtin arr. function in Python.
So if I cast range from 0 to 5 that gives me back a list of integers 0 1 2 3 4.
There's actually a PI version of this and it's arr..
Note that there's just one are there.
And it basically works the exact same way say N.P. that range 0 5 and it creates an array version of
that list.
So pie's version of range.
It's just a range.
So you can think of it as like array range.
So that's one way to do it.
And just like range it can take in a starting point and end point and then a step size.
So this has me back all the odd numbers starting at one going up tube and not including 11 and step
size of two.
That gives you all those odd numbers if you want.
Even ones you start at zero.
OK.
So let's continue along and talk about generating arrays of zeros and ones and this will be useful in
case you ever want to do some sort of financial model.
So I'll say P and we'll call zeros in zeros allows us to quickly create an array or a matrix of zeros.
So if I just pass in one number here it returns in array of three zeros and know that we see here there's
zero dots.
And that basically in the case that this is a floating point number.
So there's two major types of numbers.
In Python there is a single integer such as 1 and we can check this.
We can say type 1 it produces integer.
If I say type 1 point zero it produces a flow when a work of Pi and Pancho's and start doing operations
on our numbers.
Even if we take things in as an integer usually especially if panderers it will convert it to a floating
point number to make sure you don't lose any data.
That way if you have something like 0.5 it doesn't accidentally get round down to zero around up to
1.
So that's why when you put the zeros you get this little dot there.
It just stands for floating point.
So that's how you can create a one dimensional array.
Again just zeros.
And in person how many numbers you want the array you can actually do this for them engines as well.
You'll say zeros and then you can pasan a couple or a tuple of mentioned.
So if you want five by five matrix of zeros there you have it if you want something like a three by
five.
You have that so remember three the very first one at index 0 of the tuple stands for how many rows
you have.
Index 1 over here stands for how many columns you have similarly to zeros there's a ones function.
And as you may have guessed ones operates the exact same way except it gives you back an array of ones.
And again you can pasan a tuple of dimensions of three by three.
And that gives you back a three three mention of ones.
Now if you want to return evenly spaced numbers over a specified interval you can use Lyn's space.
Unless space is a little different than range Let me show you how so he can grab in space by saying
that land space.
And this stands for linearly spaced so it takes an a start a stop and then a number and what that does
is it returns evenly spaced numbers over the specified interval of start and stops.
It's a little different than arr..
Remember arr. just takes your starting and stopping and then gives you in one step or two steps or whatever
step you wanted it just gives you integers linearly space is a little different.
You take a stop or excuse me a start and then just stop and then you ask for how many numbers you want
in between the start and the stop.
So if I want three evenly spaced numbers between 0 and 10 I get back 0 5 and 10.
I can also change this to say Give me back 30 evenly spaced numbers between 0 and 10 and then you get
back zeros or 0.3 for etc..
However these are all evenly spaced so the space between zero and this 0.3 four is the same space between
0.3 4 and 0.6 a Saints based between this one and the next one and so on.
So this linearly space that spacing them out evenly so we can do things like give me 50 etc. you can
say give me 51.
He can get starting at zero in spaces of 0.2.
Something to keep in mind.
It's a little weird if you're not thinking of indexing starting at zero.
You may suspect that this should have been with 50 to get the 0.2.
But because indexing starts at zero you usually have to do either plus or minus 1 to get these nice
little even cut offs.
So that's linearly spaced elements.
There's also an identity matrix that you can call which the function sets and I and this actually just
takes one number in because an identity matrix is a square matrix square meaning that it has the same
number of rows and same number of columns an identity matrix is just a matrix of zeros where the diagonal
happens to be 1.
So that's an identity matrix.
All right.
Now let's take the time to talk about some Pye's random library numpad has lots of ways to create random
number arrays.
And when we work in the financial data and we want to kind of randomly model something like a Monte-Carlo
simulation we're going to be using them pie's ran the module.
So let's go over how it works.
The first we end up doing is say any random and they are going to say dots.
And if you hit tab here you'll notice that there's a bunch of different methods and distributions you
can use for creating random numbers.
So we're going to end up doing is saying are a and D off of random.
And if you do shift tab here it basically kind of explains what this is going to do.
So what this does is it says random values in a given shape.
So it's going to create an array of the given shape and populated with random samples from a uniform
distribution over 0 to 1.
So what is a uniform distribution a uniform distribution basically says that all the numbers between
0 and 1 have the same probability of being picked.
So if I just ask for one number one random number between 0 and 1 I get back an array of 0.1 8.
And if I run this again I get back another random number between 0 and 1.
Notice these are floating point system not integers.
I can also passen multiple numbers here.
And what this says gives me a five by five matrix of random numbers between 0 and 1.
And this formatting looks a little weird.
Let's make this kind of a little smaller so it looks a little nicer.
There we go.
Now we have a five by four.
All these random numbers are between 0 and 1 and all of them come from a uniform distribution meaning
every single number has the same odds of being picked.
The next thing we're going to discuss is sampling from a random standard normal distribution which unlike
Rand is not uniform.
So we can do any random Rand.
And if you do shift had people give me information saying this is returning from a standard normal distribution.
So a standard normal distribution basically looks something like this right.
Here you have the means centered around zero with a variance of 1.
So the closer you are to zero the higher probability of the number being picked.
Unlike uniform where every number between 0 and 1 has the same odds of being picked.
Now keep in mind if you expand this here let me zoom out just a little bit so we can read this a little
better.
They'll say down here that this is from a standard normal distribution.
It's sometimes also known as a Gaussian distribution and it has a mean of 0 and the variance of 1.
So given that the mean is zero that means we can actually get negative numbers off of this and the variance
is one.
If you actually want to kind of supply your own arguments of where Lamine should be what the variance
should be etc..
There's other functions you can use stuff like non-pilot random thought standard normal and then you
could do non-pilot random normal etc..
There's a lot of functions for that kind of play around with there so Legacy's rant and the standard
normal distribution and we'll say here is let's say any five numbers and now we can see there's five
numbers here randomly chosen from the standard normal distribution.
So then we can say Give me a five by five matrix of numbers again with five by four.
So it looks a little nicer.
OK.
So you can see here instead of being a uniform distribution from 0 to 1.
Now we're doing a standard normal distribution centered at zero for a variance of 1 and you can see
that the closer you are to zero the more likely probability have of being picked as a random number.
If you just want a random integer that's also pretty straightforward.
You just say that random thoughts ran I.A. you shift enter here and it just returns a random integer
from low to the high and the highest Xclusive just like we've been dealing with for list in fixing so
saying OK give me a random number anywhere between 1 and then up to and not including 100.
So there you have it just a random integer and you can keep calling this.
You'll keep going back different random integers between those two points.
And if you actually want more random integers and that you can specify kind of a third argument here
of the size of your race you can see getting back 10 random integers between 1 and 100 one inclusive
100 exclusive.
OK.
Now discuss a few Auray attributes and methods that are useful.
I'm going to create an array will say a variable A R R and B zoom in one level here.
So a r r.
That's going to be equal to arrange and I will say 25 and then I'm going to say Give me a Ranh array.
That's just going to be random just some random integers let's say between 0 50 and give me 10 of them.
OK so we have our array here.
And then because I'm zoomed in the formatting looks a little different but if I start zooming out you'll
see that the formatting kind of fixes itself.
So they zoomed in.
You get different formatting than me.
Don't worry that's just the display thing.
And then the random array looks something like this just kind of some random integers there.
OK so a really common method to use is the reshape method and that returns an array containing the exact
same data.
However if a new shape.
So take a look at my array.
Right now it's just a one dimensional array.
It goes from 0 to 24.
I can call reshape on this and reshape it into an array of different size.
For example I could reshape it to a five by five matrix and I have the numbers in a two dimensional
matrix five by five mansions.
Now keep in mind if I try to do something like five by four you'll end up getting an error because it
can't reshape a size 25 into a shape 5 by for a quick clever trick for this.
It's just these two numbers right here need to multiply to equal this one.
So it could do this with 20 numbers but I can't do it with 25 numbers so 5 by 5 ends up working because
five times five is twenty five.
So you have enough spaces to fit in all those numbers.
So that's the reshape it's really useful for quickly creating a matrix.
Then we're also going to discuss the shape attribute.
So the shape attribute is just a shape of the array.
So if I take a look at my original array that is the sky but I can end up doing is asking for the shape
attribute and no it's just an attribute right here and it says back 25 comma nothing.
So essentially what this indicates is that this is a one dimensional array.
So just has twenty five on one axis.
If I were to reshape this into a five by five and then call the shape off of that I end up getting Hey
now your dimensions are five by five and I could reshape this to be 25 by 1 which is basically going
to instead of having 25 columns in one single row.
It's gonna have 25 rows in one single column.
What that looks like.
Real quick.
So now the dimensions look like this.
And if I ask for the shape that's going to say hey now you have a 25 by 1 instead of just a straight
flat 25.
So that's kind of difference between seeing just 25 comma versus 25 comma 1.
So keep that in mind.
If at any time you want to know the data type that your array is holding you can just grab your array
and ask for the D type attribute and it returns back what kind of integer it has or what kind of float
has etc..
So you can see here this is 32 which just describes has like 32 bit integers and they're finally we're
going to discuss four key methods that are really useful and we're going to do these off the random
array.
So because this is a random number right you may not get the same values I have here but that doesn't
really matter for our purposes.
If you ever want to grab the max number in an array all you need to do is call the max method and this
returns back the highest or maximum number here.
In our case 37 your number may be different if you actually want the index location of where this max
number is you can call our good Max.
So our Max what it does.
It returns the index location of this maximum value.
So if you go to index 7 so 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 I can see here that's where my maximum lies.
And similarly there's the men which gives you the minimum value and then there's argument which gives
you the index of the minimum value.
So a minimum value is index three.
The number six.
OK.
And that's really the basis of umpire arrays.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.