Welcome everyone.
The first part of the Python crash course before we go to the Jupiter note book and actually code through
some of this stuff.
I want to quickly discuss what we're actually going to be covering.
We'll talk about the fundamental data types things like numbers strings dictionaries etc. We'll discuss
comparison of logical operators in Python.
We'll talk about control flow statements things like if elif else statements for loops and while loops
then we'll discuss functions how to create your own.
Some built in functions and they'll also talk about some few built in Python expressions.
OK let's open up a new Jupiter note book and get started already.
Here I am at a Jupiter note book the very first thing I want to discuss is how you can comment your
code to create a single line comment.
Just to add hash tag type comments and then you'll notice if I run the cell or shift enter I don't get
anything back.
So if I actually want to see something back I can enter like a number 10 I'll do shift enter and I can
see my output is just 10.
If I don't want to actually see this or have it run I can comment it out.
Now I don't get any output.
OK let's start off with just discussing simple numbers.
So numbers are quite easy to work with in Python.
It's just the plus sign if you want to do subtraction just one minus three.
Multiplication is just something with an asterix.
So two times three is to Asterix three.
If you want to do division just a forward slash one divided by two and I'm doing spaces here.
But just so you know you don't actually need those spaces.
It'll work either way if you want to exponent.
It's just too abstract science intro to the power of 4 16.
If you want to do the mod operator that is get the remainder of a division.
It's the percent sign.
So let me show you that real quick.
So if we do for mod 2 that should return 0.
So this is actually returning the remainder component.
So for the Vita by 2 goes it evenly twice with a remainder 0.
Now if I do 5 divided by two they'll end up being 2.5.
So 2 goes into 5 twice and then it has a remainder of 1 otherwise known as 1 over 2 which is point five.
If axis want to get the whole remainder value I could just add something like 5 mod to that will return
the remainder 1 so 5 divided by 2 is 2 remainder 1.
All right.
And then lastly you can actually specify order of operations in Python.
So if you were to do something like two plus three multiplied by five plus five this would actually
end up multiplying 3 and 5 first and then add 2 and 5 together if you want to specify for the addition
to happen first.
You can just do parentheses so it can say print sees two plus three multiplied by five plus five.
Now if you run that you get 50.
OK so that's the very basics of numbers.
Hopefully that was pretty straightforward.
Nelse quickly discuss variable assignments.
So in Python your variable assignments are going to just pretty much always be lowercase and follow
snake casing.
That means the name of the variable as far as separated words are going to be separated by underscores.
So will have some name of the variable.
Then we just use the equal sign for assignment and I will set that too.
For example I can say X is 1.
And why is equal to two.
And then I can do something like.
X plus y and get equal to 3 Kircus set a new variable z is equal to x y and then ask for z back out
and I get 3.
That's the basics of variable assignment.
Moving on to other fundamental data type strings strings can either have single quotes or double quotes
so we can have single quotes as a string and then I can have double quotes as the strings.
So notice that when I actually ask for the string to be returned the default is just to have it as a
single quote.
Either way it's pretty much the same thing.
The reason we have the option of single quotes and double quotes is in case you want to wrap a single
quote.
So for example in case you want to say something like I don't care without getting some sort of unfinished
string error because there's a single quote there.
I'll just wrap it in the other quote type which is double quotes.
And here we can see we don't actually get an error there and it says oh this single quote isn't actually
a stream quote because it's wrapping it in double quotes.
OK now discuss.
Actually printing out strings so you can see here that the strings are just being returned that are
actually being printed out.
So in order to print things out all you do is use the princess function.
So if I have a variable x equal to hello and I ask to print x.
Notice I just get back hello.
The way the Jupiter note book works is it denotes printing by not actually reporting that it's a string
with quotes.
It also doesn't report aid output so it just prints out whatever he said to print out.
So likewise I could say something like Prince double and it will just print out the word double.
No quotes and no output cell there.
Then I want to talk about prints of formatting.
Sometimes is known as string interpellation where you want to insert a variable into a string when you're
printing it out.
So for example if I wanted to say my name is Jose Portsea and I'm going to print out Hello my name is
and somehow I want to insert this variable called name into this print function or print statement.
The way I can do that is I input these curly braces and then at the end of the string I call a format
method.
And then I pass in the variable name.
So when I run this what's going to happen is Python is going to look for the variable name which I've
already defined appear as Jose Portsea and then it's going to insert it into these curly braces.
Now this can actually get a little more complex.
So let's go ahead and define another variable we'll say defining a number value or a number variable
and we'll call this number let's say 12 and then what I'm going to do now is Prince Hi my name is curly
braces and my number is curly braces.
There we're going to say the format and then I'm actually going to insert not just the name but also
that number variable then if I run this it says Hi my name is Jose Here am I numbers 12.
We can continue to actually expand on this by giving these to some local temporary variable names so
I can say something like x is equal to name and Y is equal to number here.
And then inside these braces I can say X and Y and then when I read this I get the same result.
But what's nice about doing this sort of local variable assignment is that I can not have to worry about
the order that I pass them into the format method.
I can say why why and this is going to say hi my name is 12 my numbers 12.
Or I could reverse the order and say Hi my name is of them in numbers.
Jose Portsea So this is a nice little trick to use this variable name the local one inside your string
and that's the basics of string interpellation and print formatting statements.
OK let's move on to lists.
Lists are basically Python's form of an array.
So the way to find a list and it's going to come in here or Takuma a list is you have square braces
or square brackets and then you separate out the items with a comma.
So that's a basic list.
Keep in mind a list can actually hold multiple data types so you can hold a string here and they can
hold numbers and it won't actually complain.
And the other thing to note is that you don't need a pre-define.
How long a list is going to be beforehand.
It's a dynamic array and you can just keep adding stuff to the list.
So let's create a list called one to three.
Well I'm actually creating a variable called my list which consists of a list of one to three I'm going
to run that and actually want to add an item to this list.
I can say my list append and I call this a pen method on the list and then I'm just going to type in
what I actually want to append.
Let's say the number four or in this case the number for a string called for.
Then if I return or ask for my list it returns back 1 2 3 4.
So the way you can add item to the end of the list is just append if you want to index an item off of
the list.
Indexing starts at zero.
So let's read the fine or list to be a b and c.
Let's get one more letter in there.
The stuff I ask for my list.
And you can use tab to quickly autocomplete this.
You'll get back ABC if I want to grab the elements a what I end up doing is using indexing.
I can say square brackets off the variable list and then pasand its index location and indexing and
Python starts at zero so I'll say zero there they're all run that.
And then we get back a if I want to grab the letter D.
There's actually two ways I can do that.
One way just counting over 0 1 to 3.
So capacity 3 and that returns the Python actually supports negative indexing means I could say minus
1 and that will automatically return the last element of the list.
So starting at zero it goes backwards one towards the end of the list.
And that also returns the.
All right.
Now let's quickly discuss slicing a list.
So right now we can use indexing to just grab a single item off of the list.
But if I want to actually grab multiple items that are together remember this is a sequence that's ordered.
So there are 1 2 3.
Let's say I want to grab a and b when I can end up doing is say the starting position at 0 and then
colon and then we add up to but not including the last position.
So if I want a and b that's going to start at 0 and then go up to but not including index to.
So if I run this I then get back a and b.
So this is a little confusing for beginners at first who aren't used to this sort of notation of indexing
at zero and cash coming in from their language which as I believe Matlab starts indexing at 1.
But sometimes people expect this to say ABC.
The thing to remember here is that the first one starts at that index colon up to but not including
that index.
So I can zoom in one more time we see list ABC and then zero call into returns 0 1 and then up to bet
on including two.
OK.
If you want to do everything in the beginning a shorthand for that is to say colon too and that will
return the same thing.
You can otherwise do the reverse and say starting an index to call and give me everything to the end.
Now no b c the remember this first index does get included.
And then if you're adding in the last index it's going to be up to but not including that.
And then finally you can have a nested list.
So I'm going to create a variable called nested and I'll set the sequel to 1 2.
And then as the third item in this list the index to I need to have another list of a B.
So I noticed double sets of brackets here.
So if I call nested in nested list if I want to grab the letter A.
But I have to do is say OK 0 1 2.
So I passen to here run the cell and now I have that list that was at position to then I can add in
another set of indices which is going to grab a.
So it's going to be zero of this list.
And that's how I can grab a by itself.
And that's how you can use a nested list.
OK so now let's discuss dictionaries.
Dictionaries are a hash table as it is known in other languages for a python and it essentially consists
of a key value pair or a key item pair notation for a dictionary ends up using curly braces.
So I'm going to create a dictionary called the as the variable name.
I'm going to have curly braces here.
And you have some sort of key as a string colon and then some value such as a number 10.
And then if you want another key value pair you'll add in a comma.
You'll have some other key I will say this is key too.
And then you can have some other item corresponding to key to let's say second item as a string send
out the thing to remember about a dictionary is that a dictionary does not actually retain any sort
of order.
Instead it's acting as a hash table where instead of storing things as a sequence of items in a particular
order it stores them a key value pairs.
So has a key and then a value.
So if you actually want to grab a value or item from a dictionary or you end up doing is saying the
square braces and then you pasand the key.
Unlike a list where you pass an index position for that dictionary it doesn't really make sense because
it's an ordered.
So we end up doing is just passing in a key.
So if I want to grab the string second item I just passen key to run this and that returns second item.
And that's the way a dictionary really works is just key item Peyre essentially operating like a hash
table.
In other languages for booleans that is true and false in Python it's just going to be true.
Capital-T everything else lowercase and false capital F everything else lowercase.
There's a few more data types that we're going to discuss and that's tuples and sets and then we'll
finish our discussion of the fundamental data types of Python.
Tuples are really really similar to lists except instead of square braces using parentheses.
So we can see here I have a tuple.
Some people also call them supples.
So we have a tuple or a tuple consisting of three elements one two three.
And I can index these just like I could with a normal list.
It returns back 1.
Now if I have a list and I said it equal to 1 to 3 and I index it the exact same way I get back to the
same result as a couple or a tuple.
So you may be wondering well what's the difference between this tuple and the list.
Well a tuple is immutable meaning you can't actually change an item once it's in there a list is mutable
meaning you can mutate it and actually change items.
So let me show an example of the list versus this tuple object.
So I can say grab my list element at zero and set that equal to the string.
New.
So if I call back my list I get back new to 3 instead of one to three.
So I can see that this list object is mutable.
If I try to do the same thing with this tuple member tuples defined by those princes I can get zero
set equal to something that's new.
I'm actually going to get an error and the error is going to say this tuple object does not support
item assignment.
So a tuple is immutable meaning you can't do this sort of re-assignment no reason for that is because
sometimes you're going to want to store data in a format where you don't want a user or your program
to later on have access and switch things out and usually want to reserve this for things that shouldn't
be changed.
Maybe for example the days of a calendar those are going to be the same no matter what you're doing
so you probably want to store it as a tuple in order to not really mess around with things later on
your program as you program more and more of Python will become more obvious where a tuple is a good
choice versus a list is a good choice versus a dictionary.
But now you should just be aware of the various data types and the final data type we're going to discuss
is a set a set is an unordered collection of unique items.
And that kind of looks like a dictionary in that it does use curly braces but you just pasand the items
themselves there's no key item value pairs here.
Now the thing to remember about a set it's that an unordered collection of unique items.
What that basically means is is if you pass in multiples of the same item or elements when you run this
set it's only going to grab the unique instances meaning it's only going to grab one of 1 1 or 2 and
1 of 3.
So what's nice about this is you can use the keywords set past in a list that has multiple elements
here run this and you'll get back a set of the unique elements and that basically concludes our discussion
of the fundamental data types of Python.
So remember we started out with numbers and did some simple arithmetic and math.
And as a quick note in case you ever want to do some more complicated math than what we showed here
going to put and you sell here you can actually import the math library and this math library actually
comes a lot of abilities.
You can say math that in the Jupiter note picking a hit tab and it will show you the various mathematical
functions that are available.
So Python is sometimes called a language that comes with batteries included because this math library
is already built into Python.
Now we'll talk a lot more about importing other libraries that are going to be using panels that plot
lib etc..
But things like basic math that's actually already included.
So for example if you want to take the square root of something you could say math that square root
and then if you wanted to find out more about this you can do shift tab and you will report back to
stock Dementation string which is return to square root of x and we'll talk about the documentation
string later on when we discuss functions in this crash course.
For example square root of 10.
And for that we get back 3.1 6 etc..
So that was the basics of numbers and arithmetic.
Then we discussed the variable assignment and we also discussed string so we can use single quotes and
double quotes.
And as a quick note about strings for instance I have x is equal to hello here I can use the same indexing
we used on a list on a string.
So if I wanted to grab the very first letter such as H I could say X of 0 and I'll return h.
So he should do in order to get a little practice of indexing is try to create a string such as Y is
equal to Hello World and then say try to grab a random letter so see if you can grab this are for instance.
All you have to do is count over 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 passen 8 and then you get our.
Then we learned about Prince string interpellation list basic arrays.
We learned about nested lists and how you can grab stuff from a nested list.
We learned about slicing this nested various Spraggan notation dictionaries booleans tuples and sets.
All right.
Thank you everyone and we'll continue this along in the next lecture where we will be discussing control
flow and functions.
I'll see you there.