Welcome back everyone to where we left off last time we were going to do now is put all of these sort
of factors and filters and masks into a nice make pipeline function.
So let's go ahead and we're going to create a couple of new cells to get a lot of this stuff out of
the way and down here we'll say make pipeline and then I'm going to comments the actual steps we're
going to do.
So the first thing is going to be our universe and that's just going to be those fifteen hundred most
tradeable stocks.
Then after that we're only going to grab energy sector stocks.
Then after that we're going to basically make some sort of masks I will say make a mask of 15:00 us
an energy so we'll kind of combine those.
As we've seen before combining filter's then we'll go ahead and say the following will grab average
dollar volume and we're just going to grab that information.
Offer that will say grab the top 5 percent an average dollar volume and we'll make this dollar volume
over the past 30 days.
So grab that information using that information will grab the top 5 percent of stocks based off dollar
volume that those are the ones that are in 15:00 us and then the energy sector dentals go ahead and
asks just added some more maybe we'll then combine the filters again.
So we'll have a combined filter here a 50 100 U.S. energy.
And then I'll combine that one with this filter that we created here.
So we'll do that again combine the filters then after that we're going to now grab some information
such as just go ahead and do what we did last time.
We'll say grab the 10 day I mean close grab the 30 day I mean close.
Let me get some more lines here.
We did this last time we were discussing pipelines and then we got the percent difference between those
two and then we'll make a list of short spaced off that percent difference just like we did last time.
And then a list of Longs stocks that go along on and then we'll create some sort of final mask or filter
for anything in shorts or a longs.
That way I don't see everything else.
I only see the list of stocks that are going to short or long and that's going to be based off the percent
difference just like we did last time.
And then finally I'm going to return this pipeline Okay.
So there are all the steps that we're going to follow.
And let's go through it.
So some of these are going to be easier than others but the very top one is going to be probably easiest
of all.
We're just going to say my base universe is equal to Q Fifteen hundred us and remember going to have
to import all of this.
So when we actually go back to the I-T we're going to have to kind of re put in all these imports that
we did up here.
But right now the snow pack knows they're all imported.
So we're kind of just go along as if we already know they're all imported.
They don't want to make some energy sector filter and that's going to be sector equal to the energy
sector which is three or nine.
Then I'm going to combine these to make some sort of combined filter.
So I will say no to call this base energy.
So it's my base universe and the energy stocks.
So I will say that's going to be stocks that are based universe and energy sector.
So basically combining those two filters and you can see I'm using the term mask and filter a little
bit interchangeably and that's really because the way you apply filter may make it into a mask.
So just keep that in mind.
Then we want to grab the 30 days of dollar volume.
So I'll say dollar volume and we already imported average dollar volume and then I'm going to give it
a window length of 30 days.
I want to grab the top 5 percent an average dollar volume.
So I will say give me the high dollar volume.
You also want to be careful of adding in too many filters because if you keep filtering and filtering
and filtering there may not be that many security to trade on.
If we limit ourselves to fifteen hundred and we limited that to the energy sector and now we're limiting
it to only the top 5 percent an average dollar volume.
So keep that in mind.
So will be dollar volume and since we won the top 5 percent not the top five or top 10 we're going to
say is percentile between say 95 and 100.
So those are top five percent of stocks.
And now let's combine that with our base energy.
So we're going to do something like
let's say top 5 base energy and all be equal to the base energy filter and the high dollar volume filter.
So now we have those.
And then we're going to grab the 10 day mean close price and the 30 day mean close price and calculate
the difference.
We've actually done this before.
So I mean 10 that's just going to be the simple moving average and we're going to take in U.S. equity
pricing close price as an input.
We're going to say the window length is equal to the past 10 days and then I'm going to apply the mask.
So instead of calculating the 10 day mean on every single stock in U.S. equity pricing I really want
to grab it on this one the top five based energy stocks.
So after this we'll say mask is equal to and top five based energy and we're going do a really similar
thing for the 30 days.
We just changed this with the length to 30.
And that's how we can use kind of these filters as masks so we don't calculate the 10 day I mean clothes
and threw them in clothes for every single US security and said we just do it for the past 10 days past
three days.
Then percent difference.
We've actually done this before.
It's just mean 10 ups mean underscore 10 minus.
I mean underscore 30 divided by I mean underscore 30 cents per percent difference and then we create
some sort of logic on what we're going to short.
So anything that has a negative percent difference wups percent difference.
Anything that's less than zero because I think it's going down.
And then long as anything that has a growing percent difference because according to my logic I think
that's good.
Healthy behavior.
Again this maybe not a strategy you want to trade on just some kind of generic logic here.
And then finally let's go ahead and securities to trade
I'm going to set that equal to shorts or longs.
So at the very end of my pipeline.
I only want to see the ones that I'm actually going to trade.
I don't want to see the top five based energy.
If they didn't happen to go through this.
So I also don't want to see everything in U.S. equity pricing eventually at the end of the day.
I just want to see what am my shorting and what am I going long on.
So I'm going to return pipeline and was put in some columns here number where you have column this is
an argument with a dictionary.
And I will say Long's sequel to lungs and a lot of times people put this in some sort of context object
will say shorts equal to shorts.
And then I will say perked if is equal to that percent difference that we just made.
And then at the end of all this we have some final screen which is the securities to trade.
And that is our kind of giant pipeline function.
So we're gonna be copying and pasting this into the idea later on but let's go ahead and run the cell
and make sure that we don't have a typo in here.
Make sure it worked well say results run our pipeline and we're just going to call our make pipeline
function and let's kind of put in some years here.
So I'll say from May 2015 the 5th of that kind of an arbitrary choice 2015 05.
So I'm just doing this for one day.
That way I don't get some huge data frame and then we'll see the results.
Okay it looks like we have a typo here so global mean 30 is not defined.
Let's come back up here and make sure that's fixed.
So it looks like XLE type didn't mean 10 here change it to 30 now run it again results percentile difference
is not the.
Looks like I have an error there.
What line is this on.
This is on shorts.
So that should be per cent difference in that percentile difference okay.
And that should be let it run.
And here we go.
So now I have longs the percent difference and shorts so I can see anything that has a positive percent
difference has a true go along on it.
And he falls short on it.
So if we scroll down here we basically just have one of these stocks of a negative value and can see
here.
True I'm going short on it.
And you notice all these stocks if you were to look them up or Google them have something to do with
the energy sector.
So go ahead and I would recommend you kind of just copy and paste one of these into google search and
then see what the actual stock ticker represents.
But it should be related to the energy sector somehow.
It should also be a highly traded stock because remember we're basically just asking for the top five
percent of all these stocks.
So these are all really highly traded stocks which means we're going have a lot of liquidity here especially
because we already kind of filtered it by the top 50 or 100 tradable stocks.
So we should never have any issues here of not being able to put our trades that should be a pretty
rare occurrence.
OK so now that we have our make pipeline function.
Let's go ahead and execute this entire strategy in the IDC and see how we can combine this with an initialize
function some sort of before trading start function as well as a rebalancing function.
Make sure you actually reference the notes here because we're going to copy and paste this into the
ID in the next lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.