Hello everyone and welcome to the first part of the solutions for the stock market analysis project.
Let's hop over to the exercise notebook and get started.
OK here I am at the notebook.
I'm going to scroll down a little bit and the first part it's just import the various libraries so part
zero.
We're going to say important umpires and the import pandas is the answer is we know we're going to do
visualisation we'll say import that plot lib pipe plot as PLDT and in order to see the visualizations
inside might you know but I will say that plot lib in line so I'll run that and part 1 is getting the
data.
So as a quick note in case you were able to use Pandurs data reader you can always just do read cxxviii
and grab the Tesla stock see as reviles but we're going to walk through it with Pandurs data reader.
So the first thing I want to do is say import Panda's data reader and then I'm also going to import
date time in order to set the actual dates and then the last thing I want to do is also say imports
will say import Pancho's data reader data as well.
OK so let's start off with the start date.
So the start date is going to be January 1st 2012 so we can zoom in one more level here.
So General first starts school say Star is equal to time thought the time and we'll say 2012 one 1 and
then we're going to just copy and paste this for our finish or ending date and then that's going to
be the exact same thing at the start of 2012.
They'll say 2017.
So once we've done that or we're going to do is set a variable called Tesla equal to web dot data reader
the stock ticker for Tesla is capital T S L A.
We'll use the Google API for this and then we'll give it the start and end dates let it read that and
hopefully we should get the Tesler that head and there it is.
Looks like all our data is matching.
Perfect.
So now I want you to repeat the same steps to grab data for Ford and General Motors is actually pretty
simple.
We're just going to create two more variables will say Ford said that equal to where the data reader
the ticker for Ford is f just capital F say use the Guly API and then give it the start and end dates
and we'll do the exact same thing except instead of forward we'll have it be General Motors and that
ticker is GM.
And then if we check out for instance the head of Ford that matches up open at 11 dollars and for check
out the head of General Motors that shows up opening twenty point eight three.
OK great.
So that concludes Part 1 actually getting that data should have been pretty straightforward if you were
having issues of Panas data reader you can always just use the C Espey files.
Living on support to visualizing data.
So we're going to do is follow along and recreate the plots below.
According to the instructions and explanations.
So the first thing to do is to recreate this linear plot of all the stocks open price.
So hence for the legend you can use the label parameter and plot legend.
So that's an easy way to actually get this legend here to show nicely.
And let's actually walk through that now.
We're going to do is say Tesla that was that variable for the data frame grab the open column.
So that's the opening price and then going to plots and I'm going to give this the label Tesla and we'll
just say Fix size is equal to let's say 12 by 8.
I think that 16 by 8 but doesn't really matter too much and we'll give it the title opening prices here.
So that title that figure size is going to fall along with anything else I plop below this.
So then if I do GM open all I need to say is plot and give it its label.
In this case GM and then it going to save Ford again just the open column that is going to plot this
one as well.
So give that to label Ford and then any to call people that Legin in order to actually see the results
of this and call it some open and closed Princie So if I run this I should get now the same plot that
I saw earlier.
So this is the same plot as it is here just a different figure size.
I think 16 by eight is the actual matching figure size so there it is.
And as a quick note if you're using Jupiter notebook you may get this thing right here it says legend
if you want to not see that I believe you should be able to just add a semi colon to the end of this
and then it will hide this output.
So if we run this again go ahead that little Lijun output so you can put a semicolon there to hide that
just a little quick.
OK let's continue along.
And now we want to plot the volume of stock traded each day.
This is actually going to be extremely similar.
So what we can do is just copy and paste from the cell because essentially we're doing is doing the
exact same task except instead of plotting the open column we're going to plot volume.
So I'll say volume for this and then sort of S. open prices or opening prices we will say just volume
traded well such as up for volume here.
And then switch us up for volume there.
Run this and there we go.
That's the total volume traded.
So you can see it looks like Ford had a really big spike somewhere in late 2013.
So in late 2013 you would see this huge spike it's well above anything else.
So you can see here this is 1.5 times the power rate.
That's this line right there.
If we zoom in on this line this is above two times tenth power base.
This is huge.
So we want to know is what was the date of this maximun trading volume for Ford.
So those were Pandurs comes into play.
And then as a bonus question what happened that day.
So it's actually check this out.
So in order to figure out this time stamp what I need to do is figure out where is the maximum of the
volume being traded.
So let's go ahead and just do that with Ford and what you might think to do it just get the max here.
But if you just do Max that's going to return the actual amount.
So ended up returning back how many units of stock were actually traded $220 million.
If I want the actual dates I need to use arguments and it returns back that it was December 18th of
2013.
Now to answer the bonus question as far as actually what happened the they all ended do essentially
Google search forward plus this date.
So 2013 December 18th and you'll end up getting a bunch of news articles and there's links in the solutions
notebook that say things like aggressive forward plans hit profits shares fall.
So what ended up happening is that they are the before Ford basically made an announcement that the
cost of launching new products would cut into next year's profits so that ended up causing a big sell
off and you can see that big selloff happening on that particular day.
And if you kind of take a look at Ford by itself.
So if you take a look at Ford's opening price and then plot that let's give this a fixed size of let's
just say I don't know 20 by 6.
If we take a look at that actual day it's kind of late 2013 you'll end up seeing the drop right here.
Now in context of this entire huge time period it's not actually such a huge drop.
So it's not as noticeable as the spike here.
So keep that in mind.
And what's fun to do is kind of take a look at these other spikes and see how it corresponds with the
actual dips because it is a much larger kind of a mid-2014.
So if we take a look at mid-2014 over here we end up seeing a little spike here.
So not as significant as this large spike.
So just kind of interesting things to check out as you're kind of playing around and visualizing this
data.
OK.
So the open price time series visualisation that is we look all the way back at this first one right
here where we see Tesla's huge stock price versus General Motors and Ford kind of laying flat that visualization
makes it look like Tesla's always been much more valuable as a company than General Motors and Ford.
But to really understand this we actually need to think about is the total market cap of the company
that is the not just the stock units themselves but the stock price multiplied by how many available
units of stock there are.
That's the market cap of the company.
So our current data doesn't actually have information of total units of stock in the company it just
has volume traded.
So we're going to do just as a really simple calculation try to represent the total money traded that's
going to be multiplying the volume column by the opening price.
Remember this still is not the actual market cap.
It's just a visual representation of the total amount of money being traded.
So basically 100 units of stock at $10 each versus like you know a hundred thousand in stock at $1 each.
Just how much money is actually being traded for each of these companies on these given days.
So first off why don't you to create a new column for each data frame called Total traded which is the
opening price multiplied by the volume traded.
And this is not a real technical analysis so we usually want to do something like this.
This is mostly just to explore your panda skills.
So I'll say Tesla total traded and also equal to Tesla the open price of the column.
And then we'll say Tesla the total volume traded.
So this is what we're doing is we're trying to get an idea of more or less how much money was actually
traded.
Now again this is not an exact calculation because the opening price is not the average price for that
day you can do a lot better estimations than when I doing here.
And this is kind of just the practice or panda skills.
So we're going to copy and paste this and do this for the other two.
So that's going to be Ford it's going to be Ford and that's going to be Ford.
And then the last one is going to be General Motors General Motors General Motors OK.
So we have three total traded and now we're going to plot this against the time index.
So we're going to do is basically copy this total traded column and then say dot plot and we'll give
this the label Tesla and let's give this the fixed size 16 by 8
and then we'll say General Motors total traded plot that with the label GM and then say Ford total traded
shooting type to autocomplete there and we'll give that the label Ford let's add in our legend T.
Legend and then it's put a semicolon there.
OK.
So this is essentially a visualization of the total amount of money being traded.
So now you can see that Tesla is a lot closer throughout many of the actual years.
Now there is a huge spike for Tesla.
So on this particular day there's a huge amount of money being traded for Tesla which we can explore
later on.
But as far as the difference between this particular visualization and if we scroll back up this particular
ization the actual amount of money being traded is a lot different.
So again the opening price the actual individual price per stock unit is quite different between Tesla
General Motors and Ford.
But again this doesn't do a good representation of total market cap.
Now total market cap is not something we can actually get from the data we have at hand here.
All we have are the open high low close prices and volume where we can kind of get some sort of idea
doing kind of this crude calculation of open price times volume.
This is again not a market cap but more discussion on how much actual money is being traded each day
for each of these companies.
And you can see here that for a lot of these days a lot of money is being traded around for all of the
companies.
Now Tesla again quite a bit more money being traded around especially during certain years when those
being shorted a lot for various reasons but deciles also kind of a crazy company when it comes to its
stock price so just keep that in mind.
So going around or going to do is continue on.
And if he keep continuing on scrolling down you'll end up seeing it says.
Interesting.
Looks like there was a huge amount of money traded for Tesla somewhere in early 2014.
So that's this number right here.
You can see there's a huge amount of money somewhere early 2014 that's being traded.
So one of those What was that day and what actually happened.
We are actually going there really similar thing to that earlier we'll just say Tesla grabbed the total
traded column and then I'm going to ask for RMX and that should return a February 25th of 2014.
So what actually happened that day.
Well if you google searching this day plus Tesla finding news like this where it says Wall Street Journal
Tesla shares surge on Morgan Stanley report.
So essentially what happened is some Morgan Stanley analyst gave a good report on Tesla shares.
So that caused a huge spike.
That particular day.
So we're we're also going to do is practice putting out some moving averages.
I want you to plot out the moving average 15 then moving average.
Two hundred.
So let's go ahead and do that.
That's going to be actually quite straightforward.
We'll just do this for General Motors.
Now all the stocks as it says in the instructions still say General Motors call it a 50.
That is the 50 day moving average is equal to GM open.
And all you have to do is call the rolling method on this 50 and then ask for the mean.
And it's kind of up to you whether you want to set this as a new column or not but setting this as a
new column in the original data frame allows us to kind of do a nice little call at the end and get
the legend automatically.
So this is going to be moving average two hundred will be equal to GM.
The open column
rolling 200 days that's quite a large window.
Just keep that in mind it's more for visualization purposes.
And then let's actually just pass in a list of columns.
So we're going to pass in a list of columns will say open a 50 and then made 200 and then we're going
to plot this and give the label.
Actually we don't need the label really we'll just say Fix size equal to 16 by 8.
So let's run this.
And we should see the same plot result here.
So we can see the opening price which is blue the movie average for 50 day moving average kind of getting
that trend.
And then the even more macro trend which is the 200 day moving average.
OK.
So again quite a large window of 200 days a little more for realisation purposes.
But you never know certain technical analysis techniques require really large windows.
So finally we're going to do it see if there's a relationship between these stocks.
After all they're all related to the car industry in some form or another.
So we can actually do this easily through a scatter matrix plot.
So what I want you to do is import scatter matrix from panel start plotting and use it to create a scatter
matrix plot of all the stocks opening price.
Now something you may need to do is rearrange the columns into a single data frame and there's some
hints and info so we check out this link.
There's hints and info on how to actually use the scatter matrix plot so you can come over here to the
actual documentation and I'll describe how I'd actually use SCOTTER matrix and give you some visualization
examples as it loads up there.
Let's hop over to Jupiter now.
It can actually do this ourselves.
So when you say from pandas plotting in poor Scouter matrix so I will import that and then I'm going
to create a variable called car companies and I'm going to just concatenate a couple of things I'm going
to concatenate the open column of Tesla and then the open column of General Motors and then the open
column of Ford and I want to do this all access equal to one because sweep's X equal to one.
And if I just take a quick look at what I've done by checking out the head of this essentially is concatenated
three open columns here.
So Tesla General Motors and Ford.
So this actually doesn't have any column names yet.
They're all open so let's change that.
They're all still in the correct order that is concatenated them.
Tesla General Motors Ford.
So let's define this as car come columns and I will say Tesla open General Motors open.
And then Ford open will run that the now facey car company is the head of it.
I get this nice little Tesla open General Motors open and Ford open and now we're going to do is just
use a scatter matrix to create this portrait here.
So we're going to say scatter matrix Pessin passenger data frame which is that car company data frame
and we can set the size to really whatever you want I'll just say eight by eight.
If you're not zoomed in as me you won't need to do that.
And I'm just going to run this and we'll go over a few more arguments.
So if you just run that you end up seeing kind of this big thing of Auray telling you the map pulling
axes and then you get something that looks like this.
So there's a couple of things you can do this in a zoo much the second so you can see the whole scatter
matrix plot.
We can see that there's a clear positive correlation between General Motors and Ford.
Tesla is quite a bit different has some different behavior and that makes sense because we saw there
was kind of a huge jump in Tesla stock price while General Motors and Ford kind of stayed at the same
level in comparison what you can do to kind of get a better idea of this scatterplot is add an alpha
variable.
So I'll say Alfa is equal to English you say 0.2 because we're dealing with a lot of data points here
and now it's going to appear much starker where there's more points stacked on top of each other.
So that's something you can do and if you want to actually add in more bars this histogram will you
end up doing is you add in as an argument.
H I S T underscore.
KW The s and this is going to be a dictionary and what the stick represents is these are histogram keywords
based off map Hotlips own histogram so you end up doing is you go to a map outlives documentation check
out the keyword arguments for using a histogram lib and you can pass isn't as a dictionary.
So the one we are concerned with is Beenz.
So that's the parameter colon as the value you give it.
The key one so 50 bits and I think I misspoke I said the key you want you just want to give it the value
you want but the key the key is bin's values 50.
And if you want to get rid of this array you can just use a semi-colon again here.
And there are a scatter matrix and that basically concludes part 2.
There is a bonus visualization task but we'll do that in a separate lecture.
That was the main visualization tasks you had to do for this exercise.
Coming up next we'll tackle this bonus viz. task and then we'll move on to part three basic financial
analysis.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Q&amp;A forums but also make sure to check out the
solutions.
No but for the full code and explanations I'll see you at the next lecture.