Welcome back everyone to this first part on data frames and this lecturer will begin learning about
data frames which are built directly on top of the serious object.
We just learned about data frames where we're mainly going to be working with when dealing with financial
data.
So it's important that we really learn.
Well we'll have three parts of this.
So let's get started.
All right.
Here I am at the Jupiter notebook.
I'm going to go ahead and say important piece and then import Panas PD and I'm going to do one last
thing here.
The save from them that random import Rand and and then I'm going to go out and set a seed.
And what a seed means just to make sure that we get the same random numbers.
That way if you're following me you'll see the same random numbers that I see.
You're going to say NPE thought ran them seed.
All right.
Let's go in and explore the different command and the ADF is equal to the data frame.
And you can actually use tab here using Jupiter up to complete this.
And notice that the EFIS capitalize on the new shift to check out the docstring and the initial signature
for this PD data frame.
We have a data arguments and an index argument just like we did for series but then we have this additional
columns arguments.
Let's go ahead and build this up with some random data and we'll see what a data frame actually looks
like.
First I'm going to do is passen that data arguments and I'm just going to call Ranz and 5 comma for
and then the next ones we want to pass is the index in the index.
You can just make that a list of character here I don't go in and say ABC the.
And then finally for the columns I'm going to go ahead and say the x y z.
So I'll say W X Y.
Z going to go ahead and run this and then passen the data from just the split and then we get a nice
display.
And this probably looks and feels a lot like Excel trees and a Jupiter notebook and that's good.
If you're using another ID editor you may not get such a nice crisp display but you should get a printed
output that looks similar to this.
All right.
So basically what we have here is a list of columns w x y z and corresponding rows ABC the E.
Now each of these columns is actually just a panel series.
So W as it panned the series has all x y and z and they all share a common index.
And that's basically all data frame is it's just a bunch of series that share an index.
Let's go ahead and show how we can use indexing and selection to actually grab one of these series objects
or several of these columns out one way and the main way to do this is by saying DMF and then using
Rackett notation and then passing the column name.
This case is go ahead and grab the W column.
So as a string of passen W..
And this returns the W column.
And now take a look at the output.
Now this actually looks like a series.
And that's because that's exactly what W column is.
It's just a series and you can actually confirm this by saying type of d f of W..
And it shows that it's Panas that core that series that series.
If I just say type on the DFA object itself I will get a data frame out.
So again just to reiterate that fact that a frame is just a bunch of series that share the same index.
Now there's two different ways you can grab a column from a data rate.
The main way and the way should always do it is using the sort of bracket notation and then passing
the column name.
However if you're really familiar of sequel a lot of times you're selecting a column you pass in a table
and then the column name.
This actually also works for pantless you could say dot and then the column name.
However I would recommend that you don't use this because it may get confused with the various methods
that are available off of the data front.
For instance if I say DFA and then click tab I see a whole bunch of methods available for me.
And those are a bunch of methods that we're going to learn about as we learn more about pandas.
But what may happen is that one of these methods gets overwritten by a colony.
And then panda is going to get confused whether you're asking for a method or an actual collimate.
So you should do to avoid that it's always use a sort of bracket notation when requesting a column OK
if you want multiple columns back then you can go ahead and pasan a list of columns.
So know that I pass in my brackets and then I'm going to pass on a list of column names which is going
to result in another set of brackets here.
For instance I want to columns W and Z.
I pass on a list here highlighted WNC and I get back a data frame containing those two series.
And that means when I asked for multiple columns I'm actually getting back a data frame by ask for just
a single column that I will get back a series and in the Jupiter notebook system that's the noted.
By the way the output is displayed OK.
Let's go ahead and move on to creating a new column.
Palla's supports creation of new columns by just specifying the column as if it already exists for instance
new.
Now if I run this I'll get an error and it's a key error.
Scroll all the way down here.
Say here.
New and it basically just trying to tell you that it can't find it that there is no key new there.
However when you're creating a hash tag that out and put this back in when you're creating a new column
you can actually define it as if it already exists and then on the right hand side of the equal sign
use other columns with arithmetic in order to pull off a new column.
For instance you can say if new column as if it already exists is equal to DFW plus f y.
And this will run with no error.
And now if I check out DMF that new column is actually in place there and for removing columns you can
say the drop you can say DFA drop and pass in the actual column name you want to drop.
Now if you just do this by itself you'll get an error.
And let's go in and check out what that air is.
Say value error.
If we scroll down it says labels new not contained in Access and if I click shift tab on the drop method.
Notice that by default it says access is equal to zero access equal to zero for the drop method refers
to the index.
If I actually want to refer to the columns I need to specify access is equal to 1 and then it will drop
that new column here.
Now there's two things to note when using this drop.
The first thing to know is that this doesn't happen in place meaning I'm not actually affecting the
state of frame unless I specifically specify this to occur in place.
I want to show you what I mean by that.
I'd call it a slight defect drop new access equal to 1 if I called DSF I'll see that I still have that
new column.
That means I need to actually specify as an argument to shift have to show it the in-place argument.
In many many Panas methods all require this in place arguments to be set to true.
And the reason Pancho's does that is that for you not to accidentally lose information in case you've
done a bunch of adjustments to your data you don't want to accidentally lose it.
So Pandurs requires you to say in-place equals true if actually a lot of these changes to stay and occur
in place.
And now if I call DFI running the cell notice that new column is now permanently removed because it
occurred in place and something to note here is that we can also use the drop to drop rows.
For instance let's go in and use this sitrep the Ebro I'll say Dhia got drop I pass an E and I can also
say access is equal to zero.
Now remember you actually don't have to add that in as an argument.
That's the default.
So let's go and just say the drop E and there we've been able to drop the e since Access is equal to
zero and it works either way I could say X equals zero.
And this will work again and note here I'm not doing this in place.
OK.
Sometimes a point of confusion is why are the rows zero as far as their access.
And why are the columns one of the reference actually comes back to pie says Data frames are essentially
just fancy index markers on top of a pipe or a to show this.
I can say DFI thought shape just like we did of a pipe matrix and know if that shape is a tuple or two
that missional matrix here and at the zero index are the number of rows.
So if I say ZF here I have five rows a b c and d e.
And then on the index one I have four columns W X Y Z which is why rows are referred to as the zero
axis and columns are referred to as the one axis because it's directly taken from the shape just as
you would have a pie array.
OK.
Now let's talk about selecting rows.
We've talked about selecting columns which you just do by saying DFA and in brackets you passen the
column name.
Or if you want many columns you pasan a list of the column names such as Z and then comma X then it
close off that bracket.
So I'm passing a list of column names and I return a data frame of those columns.
Let's talk about selecting rows when I take a look at my data frame again.
Here's my data frame.
ABC is my rose WXYZ are the columns.
There's two ways to select rows in a data frame.
And you have to call a method off of this and there's two methods to use.
One is Loek ellos see for location.
And this is going to take a label.
So you can also do shift tab here to see this property and something to note here.
I'm using square brackets which is a little weird but that's the way it works with panderers you Pessin
LRC.
And then you person in brackets the row you want for instance if one of the Ayro I just passen ELO C
or passes the label of the index and this returns note a series.
And this comes to our second conclusion that not only are all the columns series but the rows are series
as well.
As far as the way they're going to get returns when you request them in pantless Let's discuss the second
way to grab a row which is based off of next position.
I can use día.
I Loek to actually pasan a numerical index position.
Even if my axes are labeled by strings for instance if I want see that row I can do that two ways I
could either say ELO see for location and in brackets pass the row name which is C or I can say I O
C which is index space location and count index.
So 0 1 2 and then on I Alosi pass and 2 and this also returns that row.
And that basically means you have two ways of selecting rows using EHLO see if you want the location
or labeled based index or I EHLO see if you want the numerical based index OK.
Let's talk about selecting subsets of rows and columns and this will actually be very familiar to you
since we just learned about pi.
We can say DFI thought Alosi if you want to select a subset of rows and columns we can pass in just
like we did with Num. Pi using common notation.
The row we want and then the column was.
So I want the Ghali Robie column Y.
And this returns just a single value there.
So if I take a look at my DFA again looking at ráby column y I have this negative 0.8 for they get the
same result here.
So just like pi you can use this row comma column notation and if you want a subset of this can say
Dhia ELO C and then pasan a list separated by commas.
For instance let's say one of the subset of A B rows with the W Y columns so basically I wanted this
2.7 0.9 and 0.6 5 and negatives are twenty four.
That means I can just pass in a list of the rows I want which in this case is a and b
and then I can pass in a list of the columns I want in this case that's w and y shift enter that and
they get the subset return of the data frame.
OK we're going to stop here for now and continue this discussion.
In part two of the data frame's lecture and this is all in the notebook called Data frames under the
panda's folder.
Let's get a quick review of what we've learned.
As far as creating a data frame you just need to say PD data frame passing your data passen your index
and then pass in your column names.
Usually we won't be building data Frayne's by hand.
This manner will actually be reading data from some sort of source like a CSP file but we learn how
to do data input and output later.
For now if you want to mainly created data frame that you can do it.
Then for selecting columns from a data frame you can say DMF and then in brackets pass pass in the column
you want or pass in a list of the columns you want.
Remember that each column is actually just a series.
You can create new columns based off of old calls by using this sort of arithmetic.
Then you can drop columns or rows using DFA dropped.
Remember you don't need to have say in-place equals true if you want the effect to be permanent.
You say access one for columns and then access 0 for rows.
And again that comes from this shape tuple 0 index was rows 1 index was columns as far as selecting
rows from a data frame.
There's two methods here.
There is Alosi method which is a label based index location or there's that i Alosi which is the integer
based index location.
And then if you want to select subsets of the data frame you can use see and passen either values or
complete lists to return subsets of the data free OK.
That's it for the very basics that data frames.
Coming up next round of this.
Even more of what you can do if upin the state of frame such as using conditional selection.
All right thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture.