Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on Quando.
So as you previously noted quando is actually a company which means it does charge for its services
on a premium tier.
However everything that we're going to be showing here can be done absolutely for free.
So will do in this lecture will hop over to quando dot com explore the Web site a little bit explain
a little bit more about the company and they will open up a new chapter notebook and show you how you
can use the free Python API.
Let's hop over to the browser now OK.
So if you come to the quando Web site it will look something like this.
It may have updated itself by the time you're watching this video but there should be alternative data
in core financial data somewhere on the page.
So we'll end up doing is we'll click on core financial data this alternative data.
It's actually a really interesting product they offer.
I am not paid by call to say this but if you click it basically certain data companies will sell you
specific data things like how many Toyotas were sold yesterday so that might be interesting to you but
it's not free.
So you actually need to kind of pay for these sort of services.
However a lot of the core financial data is free.
So you know that's what your core financial data.
You have a filter here that allows you to select premium or free will to select free and then you'll
see all the free data here.
So there are a ton of data sources a lot more than what Panas data reader has access to things like
and that they stock prices which we've worked for or things like the London Metal Exchange or real estate
research from Zillow or Intercontinental Exchange futures data.
So there's a lot of stuff here.
You can specify by data type by the region it's from by the asset class cetera.
So what we'll be doing is we'll be working with the wiki and the stock prices so that they stock prices
dividends and splits for 3000 U.S. companies.
And it's basically just public domain.
So we'll go ahead and click on that and this will end up being a database for folks to access and Lotusphere
it says create an account for full access so you can create a free account to do that.
Just click on sign in and then you will click over here which says create one.
I've already linked this to make it a counselor.
Click also look at hubcap and it should then refreshed the page for me.
And now I'm signed in so I'll come back to core financial data select free wiki and the day stock prices
and then once it's refresh the page you'll see something that looks like this.
And essentially what this is it's just a huge database or a huge table of end that they stock prices
dividends and splits for 3000 U.S. companies and it goes up to about 40 years of history depending on
how old the company is.
So it's an absolutely immense table.
But what you can do is if you want you can click here an exporter and then you can bulk download you
can export the full database if you want it to.
I don't recommend it is because it's a ton of information and you probably won't need it all but you
never know what you can do is you can request to see SVGA center SML file it will generate a large zip
file for you to download which you can later unzip on your computer.
However we'll be using the python API click a little Python symbol.
It will tell you how you could request the entire table.
Again we're not actually going to grab the entire table if you wanted to you could.
But what I want to know here is that there is a little special code wiki prices.
These are the Quon the Kurds will be using throughout the Jupiter notebook section of this lecture.
So just to show you how you could actually kind of get information from this.
Let's go back to that previous example of trying to get Facebook stock data we would come do is click
over here on ticker and you click on this little blue symbol and you can select stickers so you can
say B select that be in the hit filter.
And then it will filter Facebook so that we can see the various dates.
And if you click on it here you can filter by dates so you can do just a single day or you can even
do a date range and then select a range of dates.
So from.
Well let's see from the 6 to 7 think cetera.
So it could filter by that and then we get back two rows of data.
So whatever you want it's available free here.
Once you've done that you will end up getting this request code or it's data quando get table and then
will actually specify the ticker you want and then the arguments you want etc..
So you could actually just do this manually over here.
Select what you want make sure looks good and then just copy and paste this request we're going to show
you the four ways of doing this when we hop over to Jupiter notebook.
So in another tab here I have a Juber notebook open so let's actually go through a couple of examples
of calling quando data.
So the first we're going to do is also import quando and then to get data we'll say in my data quantum
lips trees.
Well that's right quando dot get.
And if hit top here you get and get table get what it usually is for.
It's just a single time series get table is to get an entire database.
So if I just use get what I can do is pasan a code.
So there's lots and lots of codes available for Quando.
And one of them could be something like a forward slash petrolium or P-T or WTC.
So that crude oil price underscored.
So what this does is it returns the WTI crude oil price from the U.S. Department of Energy.
So if you run that with that specific code it's going to reach into quantiles databases using your special
code that you provided and then call my data.
And there you have a time series of the crude oil price from the U.S. Department of Energy.
Ever since 1986.
So what you could do if you wanted to you could import map plot lib pipe plots as Piazzi and then say
map plot live in line run that you can actually then just plot your data.
And there we can see oil prices from around the early 1980s to present day you can is kind of a big
crash and I guess during the financial crisis in as a quick note this returned this as a Pandurs series.
But if you wanted to you could get this as a pie array so you can do as an additional argument specify
returns some pie and then if you run that and then you actually instead of Plotinus we just asked for
my data.
You'll notice it's kind of a numb piracy of these tuples where we have a tuple of time and then the
actual price.
Usually I would just tell you to use everything as pandas because Pan built on them anyway so you might
as well just get the pandas time series.
Keep in mind you can only do 50 of these requests a day without providing your API key.
So if you're going to do more than 50 you'll have to get an API key and then provide it using quando
OK.
Let's show you how you can actually grab these codes.
We already showed you how to grab the Facebook that we talked about earlier but let's kind of specify
a different example.
So we'll come back to quando Well and let's go ahead and click core financial data will hit on free
over here.
And then what I want you to do is kind of just pick any of these or go ahead and pick Zillow real estate
research.
And then once you click on that it will end up showing you various things so I'll say like home value
index for various cities.
Let's say I'm interested in San Francisco real estate.
So Type in San Francisco and in London telling me different things that are available.
Things like the home value index and if it keeps falling down it will tell you things like rental homes
index per square foot middle tier homes multi-family residences cetera.
The prices for things and what you end up doing you'll see that there's a code here Zillow slash and
then something.
So this is the Zillow rental index per square foot for all homes in San Francisco.
So you can do is you can just copy this code come back and then replace this right here.
And then you say this is like real estate run that and then eventually they'll read it in and they have
real estate data for San Francisco provided to you by Zillow directly which is pretty nice.
Now typically we're just going to be getting stocks and securities information.
So let me show you the general format to do that you could do it manually.
And the way we should earlier by actually just visiting Qualcomm but there's a couple of key codes that
should be useful to you to know just off the top of your head.
And one of them should say my data and then you'll say Crondall DOT gets and you'll pass and the code
Wicky that is that free wickie database and that they prices forward slash and then the stock ticker.
So let's say we wanted Apple stock you can pass that in and then if you call the head of this data once
done being read in you'll see we have all the information for Apple stock data from this wiki we have
the open high low close volume and then we also have dividend split ratios or just open interest that
high low close adjusted close and then just that volume.
So again these are adjusted those take things like stock splits into account and if you're using Panas
data reader usually what ends up returning are these adjusted values.
Ok so we can see here we have information Apple ever since 1980.
Sometimes you don't want all these columns so you can do is offer this you can just ask for a single
column and starting from in solution one way you can do is say Apple does one run this and if you run
my data again you'll notice you just get the open column so all the columns are available to you.
Or if you want you can actually just grab a single column by inputting its number at the index position.
However that does require you to remember what the column names are.
So keep in mind that's all available to you.
There's a lot more information on quantiles Web site and always what you can do in case you don't remember
those actual codes or the one deal of memorizing those codes just come to core financial data free wiki
and that they stock prices and then you can mainly grab stuff here and then just export it to C S V.
Or just ask for the Python code.
OK.
That's really all there is to Quando.
I hope you find that useful.
It's a really great python API for grabbing data for all sorts of things.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next section of the course.