Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on e ts models as a quick note for the next few lectures
we're going to be discussing topics conceptually in slides.
Then afterwards we're going to revisit these topics using Python and stat's models to actually code
through them.
So what doesn't an ETF model any TS model stands for error trend and seasonality and exponential smoothing
trend methods models and IATSE composition are all related to this general idea of an ETF model.
So we're going to be working on several of these using the python stats models library but let's discuss
a little bit more about the error trend and seasonality components of a time series dataset.
So yes or error trend and seasonality models will take each of those terms for smoothing purposes and
they may add them multiply them or even just leave some of them out.
So when you're working of a time series dataset you'll have an error term a trend term and a seasonality
term and based off these key factors we can try to create a model to fit our data.
So let's discuss how we can actually break down a time series into each of those terms.
So each time series the composition with us is a method of actually breaking down a time series into
those terms and visualizing the data based off its the composition is a good way to build an understanding
of its behavior.
Basically what we're going to be doing is taking a silent time series and then breaking it up into these
three main factors the error the trend and the seasonality components.
So it is the decomposition actually look like when you plot this out.
Well we'll start off with a dataset called the airline passengers data set.
It's kind of the famous data set when dealing with time series data.
Now we can see here on the x axis we have some months so we say from January 1949 all the way up to
September 1960.
We can see how many thousands of passengers were taking trips on an airplane or airline travel in general
and in general we can see that there is an upward trend which makes sense from 1949 up to 1960s.
Airline travel began to modernize and thus more people began to actually take these flights.
Also we see there's a little bit of a seasonality to it.
There's kind of peaks and valleys happening right about every year.
That's probably due to people traveling during the summer and then not traveling so much during the
winter.
And you can see some smaller peaks and those may actually have to do if like winter holidays.
So what we see here is the visualization of TSD composition at the top we have the observed values.
Those are the actual data points of our time series.
So we stretched out the x axis a little bit.
But keep in mind that top plot that says observe that's the exact same plot that we saw earlier here.
It's just stretched out a little more.
So we can see the seasonality it's a little bit stretched out.
And then we can all see the general trend what the composition allows us to do is to actually exclusively
grab those specific terms or attributes of our time series.
So using Stets models we can perform a test composition and grab for instance right below the observed
values we see the general trend.
And that allows us to clearly see visually that there's a clear upward trend certain time series aren't
as obvious as the one airline passengers were the trend.
So doing is it.
Yes the composition can clearly show us that yes or is some sort of upward trend here and then we can
break and exclusively get the seasonality term or the seasonal term here and we can see that.
Yes in fact there is a seasonal term and it seems to be really repetitive which is good for us because
that's what we suspected and then we get the final residual term.
So that's kind of the error term that's not explained by the seasonal term or the trend term.
So time series decomposition with us is a very useful tool and we're going to be discussing it a lot
more when we reach Arema models.
For now we're going to kind of put this on hold and actually go to E.W. a models are exponentially weighted
moving average models.
So keep in mind that this idea that we can decompose a time series into a trend a seasonality term in
an era term or residual term exists.
We'll revisit it later on.
Let's go ahead and talk about the male models.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.