Welcome back everyone to Part 3 of the series of that pot lib lectures.
This is going to be the last part of the Matt Potter lectures and then after this we'll have an exercise
and then the solutions to that exercise and then we'll jump into Panda's visualization.
Let's hop back to the Jubran notebook and finish this off.
Let's go ahead and talk about setting colors with MAP plot lib.
So I'm going to go ahead and just say fig equals P.L. T-Dog figure.
And then I'm going to go and add a set of Access's figure x is equal to Fig dot and underscore axes
and I will set this at 0 0 1 1 and then loops and then off of that sort of axes I want to say X stop
plot and do X come alive.
And this is a reference to the same x and y that we've been working with.
So if I go in and plot that I get something that looks like this.
Now I can edit this color of the plot by putting in the color parameter and the color première can actually
take multiple arguments it can take in arguments such as common color strings like blue or let's go
and put in orange or we can see an orange line out or green and you get a green line.
So very basic color names.
It can actually except as a string if you want to start getting more detailed.
You can actually put in RGV hex codes so I can put in hash tag and then some RGV hex code such as Gaudens
copy this from the notebook f f 8 C 00 Whoops.
And that gets you a more custom color so you can go ahead and google search for RSGB X code maker or
Creator and you should have plenty of tools available freely online for actually coming up with these
are G-B hex codes in case you want to make a very custom color for very basic colors basically kind
of Crayola colors such as purple.
You should be able to easily plot them and just pass the string OK.
So that's the basics of colors.
Now let's talk about line with and line style if you want to edit the line with.
You can actually just passen line with as an arguments and just put in a number.
So for instance if we put in one that is the essentially default line with we want to go double the
default and say line with is equal to 2 and that will double the width and we can continue doing this
if I want a very thick line just like with equals 20 That's 20 times the thickness of the default line.
Or if you want a very thin line such as have the default thickness 0.5 you can start getting thinner
and thinner.
Other very useful tip as far as line with line visibility is the alpha arguments suddenly go ahead and
set my line equal to line with three and you can specify the alpha argument which allows you to basically
control how transparent the line is.
So I can say Alpha is equal to 0.5 and if I run that I can see we actually have a little bit more transparency
on this line.
So you can combine color line with an alpha in order to get the exact appearance that you want.
One last thing to note here is for short hand you actually don't have to type in line with completely.
You can just type in LW and it will still work just fine.
OK.
So we talk about line with color and Alpha going to go in and remove the alpha call.
Now let's talk about line style so I can type in line style and line style there's quite a few options
and they're listed in your note book that it basically just defines the style of the line such as a
dashed line or a dotted line.
For instance if I person two dashes I end up getting a dashed line and just passing this in as a string.
Or if I pass a dash and then a period I get the sort of dashed line.
So that point that points and then there's a couple of more options such as Colin which gets me these
smaller dashes here and you can check out the Jupiter note book for this lecture to see what other options
you have.
And you can also do steps.
However I rarely use those.
Most often I'll just either do a dash line or if you just put in one dash it's just a solid line.
OK.
And just like with line with you actually don't need to type in line style.
You can just put ls and it will end up working just the same.
OK so he talked about line with and line style.
Now let's talk about markers.
So markers are going to be used when you have just a few data points.
For instance if we take a look at X as a reminder of what it is we can see that X is just an array of
go ahead and check the length of X of 11 points.
Let's say actually I wanted to mark were those 11 points occurred on this plot.
Well I can specify marker as a new arguments should be a comma and then I can pass in a string.
So there's lots of possible marker symbols and they're listed in your note book.
But the most basic one in common one is just this lowercase O as a string.
And there you can begin to see some dots that basically mark out each points on X versus Y here.
And there's a wide variety of markers available to you.
There are always that in the notebook but just to show you a couple who can do things such as plus signs
which don't show up too well here.
You can do things such as Little stars like Asterix symbols.
You can do things such as passing in these number codes I'm going to make the line with a little thinner
so you can actually see these markers here.
So we wanted to make these markers bigger.
Well you may have guessed that marker size isn't arguments so you can go ahead and specify marker sizes
essentially just one is the very small size.
And then if you want to make it quite a bit larger You could say 10.
And here we can begin to see these kind of triangles being in the form.
So let's go and say just huge markers at 20 and then we can specify marker type ear you can say plus
we get these plusses here etc..
So all these options are listed in the documentation and more importantly in your Jupiter notebook.
So there's so many different types of strange you can pass in as marker for marker codes.
And if you really want to customize your markers for instance go ahead and put this back to lowercase.
Oh so we get these points here and change this line with back to one.
There's actually quite a few options as far as specifying what the marker looks like.
You can specify the marker face color the marker edge with and the marker edge color.
So for instance I'm going to go out and add these arguments.
So just press comma enter for a new line and I'm going to go in and say Mark face color
you can specify the marker face color.
So I'll be the color inside of that circle.
Let's go ahead and make it yellow and run this and that changed the marker or face color.
Let's say I want to change the marker edge with I go and edit that as well.
Make that a little thicker such as three that makes a little thicker.
And let's actually want to specify the color of the marker edge I can specify a marker edge color and
it's good to make that green.
All right.
So you can see there's a lot of customized ability here and there's a lot of options if you want to
see a bunch of examples of different options you can go ahead and jump to the Jupiter note book for
this lecture.
When you go out and do that now it's going to go ahead and click on over and if you see here and there
the map Cutlip concepts lecture.
Right now we're in the section line marker and line and marker styles here there's basically a figure
where we did 12 by 6 on the subplots as far as figure size and did a bunch of plots and edited the colors
the line with the line styles.
And here's a bunch of examples so you can go ahead and read them out.
And if you're looking for a different possible marker symbols are all here as comments or line cell
types etcetera.
So there's a lot of different examples here the kind of copy and paste from or build your own knowledge
off of.
Finally let's talk about control over access appearance and plot range.
And if we hop back over to our original notebook over here we can go ahead and show how we can set the
Y limit and the limit.
I'm going to make this just a very simple plot again.
Go ahead and just make this line with equal to and let's make lifestyle equal some Ashlynn.
OK great.
Let's say I only wanted to show the plot between 0 and 1 on the x axis.
Well to do that just clear access and then say set underscore X Lim and then you pass any list with
a lower bound on the upper bound.
So we'll go from 0 to 1.
And here we can see we've set the lower bound and upper bound of the x axis.
Now let's go ahead and do the same thing for the Y limit.
Just call your axes and then say sets underscore why Lim and as a list you pass an upper bounds and
lower bounds so lower bound zero comma.
Let's make the upper bound.
It's going to just put it at two.
And now we can see this plot.
And notice as we zoom in the plot looks more and more like a bunch of straight lines connecting points
which makes sense because we don't have as much detail.
There's only 11 points as we zoom out we see more of a curved line and we can fix that by getting more
data points or by zooming out.
All right and one last thing I wanted to show you before we actually end the series of map plot lib
lectures is that if you go to the map Cutlip concepts lecture and scroll all the way down you'll end
up seeing a little subsection all the way towards the bottom that says something about special plots.
So beyond plot range or special plot types so there's actually lots of specialized plots we can create
such as bar plots histograms scatter plots and many more.
But most of these plots were actually going to be creating using pandas visualization.
All those panel visualizations are based on top of that plot live.
So basically under the hood pansit is calling Matt plotless commands.
But I do want to show you that you can do that clip here so you can do a scatter plot that plot live
basically passing an x and y array.
You get a scatterplot you can do things like a histogram which kind of shows you a distribution of things
that you can to appeal to the highest and we'll see how to do that later of pandas.
And then you can do things like box plots which also show you statistical distributions of categorical
data sets.
And if you scroll all the way down you get a further reading there's lots of helpful links here.
In case you want to check out more about my plot lib.
One of the ones I really recommend beyond just the page and the official gallery and tutorial is if
you click here it says good map Portlands Tauriel kind of second from the bottom.
Laurie f r.
Click on that link.
There's a really nice live tutorial here that basically walks you through a lot of the stuff we already
talked about defaults instantiating defaults changing color line with cetera.
But it's a really nice reference in case you need something a little extra than just the note book we
covered.
OK.
So we're going to now is have a quick little exercise for you will go over the exercise and then the
lecture after that we'll go over the solutions just so you can test your new skills with Matt plotless.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.