Welcome everyone to the lecture on using pi for indexing and selection Let's hop over to a Jupiter notebook
and get started.
OK.
So the first thing to do in this notebook is say important up-I as and piece and then I'm going to create
a array using just N.P. arrange and will save from 0 and up to and including 11.
So that should get me through 10 as an array.
OK let's talk about bracket indexing and selection.
The simplest way to pick one or some elements of an array is actually pretty much exactly like we did
for a python list.
You can grab the array and use bracket indexing to grab an index location.
So for example if I want the element to index 8 I just asked for index 8 and it returns 8.
In this case it matches up perfectly because the first element is 0.
If you actually want to get values and a range you can use slice notation which essentially follows
the exact same thing as a python list.
You include the starting location colon and then up to but not including the last index.
So this should give us 1 through four if you want to get everything up to a certain position and not
including it.
You can do colon 5 and that will give us 0 to 4.
And likewise you can do a starting position up to the end and that because you three all the way to
the end so bracket indexing and selection works exactly like a python list or even a python string.
Broadcasting is another topic we're going to talk about.
So an umpire res differ from a normal Python list because of their ability to broadcast.
Let me show you what I mean by that.
If we look at my array I have zero through 10 what I can actually do is broadcast the re-assignment
so I can actually grab a slice of this let's say 0 1 2 3 4 and I can set that slice all equal to 100.
And you can't do this for normal Python list.
So now if I ask for that array back I end up seeing that these first five elements here 0 1 2 3 4 are
now all the number one hundred.
And this is known as broadcasting.
So let me reset that array because Note that the change is actually permanent here.
Those are two 11.
Now check out my array it's back to normal.
So what's important to note here is that if you have some sort of variable that's a sign to the slice
of an array for instance will say 0 lips 0 colon 6.
So if I check up the slice of an array here I have those first elements and if I reassign this if I
say slice of array and then I say OK select everything that's just a simple call and select everything
in that slice and set that equal to ninety nine.
If I took up the slice of my array I have everything ninety nine if I check back on my original array.
Notice that that slice was essentially just a pointer to that first half of the array.
So it actually changes the original array as well.
So you can see here that data is not actually copied.
It's just a view of the original array.
And the reason for that is to avoid memory problems.
A lot of times the work of Pi and then panderers as well it's built on top of some pie.
You're probably working in a pretty large datasets and you don't want every single variable assignment
to create another copy of your dataset.
Otherwise you would quickly run out of RAM if you had really large data sets.
So instead if you actually explicitly want a copy you need to say so.
So you need to say something like this variable array copy or previously that slice is equal to array
dots and then you call copy and if you check out this array it's 9 9 9 9 6 through 10.
And if I do something to array copy such as grab everything and set it equal to 200 MY or a copy has
been changed but my original array is still that same thing.
So you have to explicitly call copy if you want a copy of your array.
OK let's talk about indexing a two dimensional array.
Otherwise known as a matrix the general format for indexing an array looks something like this.
You have some to them mentionable array or call it mat to make it like a matrix and then you end up
saying square brackets the row you want to index and then the column you're on index.
So again it's going to be row comma column.
The other way you can do this is by actually splitting up into steps.
You can say bracket row and then bracket column.
So that's for indexing.
Let's show you a couple of examples of this.
I'm going to create an object called Matt and I will say it's an NPR-A.
And let's actually just make this be a nested list so we'll say five 10 15 next item in this list are
going to be 20 25 30.
And then finally one more will say 35 40 45.
So here I'm just passing the nested list into NPR-A to get back matrix it looks like this.
So five 10 15 20 to 45.
Lots of ways we could have made this matrix.
This is just the simplest doing it manually.
So let's say I want to index an entire row I end up saying mat braces and then ask for the index position
of the row I want.
So if I want that very first row 5 10 15 I just pass in a zero net returns back that very first row
if I want that last row that's going to be 0 1 2.
So we pass into that chasm back that very last row.
If I to actually grab an individual element value the way I can do that there's two ways.
Let's say I want to grab we.
Let's take a look at our matrix for a quick phone grab 25.
How would I do that.
Well I can say that it's at RHO position 1.
And then as another set of braces or brackets I can say the column position which is again 1 0 0 1.
So it's in the first row or it's in the index one row at the index one column and the x me back 25.
Now more commonly you actually see this done in one step like this one comma one.
So typically this is the way you'll see it done in examples in the documentation.
You'll use this common notation instead of the dual brackets because this common notation will also
expand to slice notation.
So try this one more time.
And what you should do is pick a number.
Kind of in your head.
Pause the video and see if you can index it out using this common notation.
So let's see if you can index out 15.
Go ahead and positivity and try that yourself.
OK I'll do it now.
So if we look at 15.
What ROSETT in.
Well it's in Roseborough and what column is in its index column 2.
And there you have 15.
So let's talk about to the array slicing of we take a look at our matrix again.
All right so to do slicing we end up doing is let's say we wanted to grab 10 15 here and 25 30.
So we wanted to grab this little square 10 15 25 30 then we would do that is we say the rows we want
as a slice.
So basically I want everything from the first row 0 up to but not including index 2.
So I can say colon too.
So as far as the rows go grab everything up to not including two that's rows 0 and rows 1.
And then I actually want the similar aspect of the columns themselves for the columns I want to start
at column one or column index one and then go all the way to the end so 10 15 25 30.
So it's going to be start at column 1 and then go all the way to the end so if I do this then I get
back 10 15 25 30.
OK.
So go ahead and try to pick out another square and see if you can index it.
See if you can index out 2025 and then 35 40 this little square right here.
I'll do that right now as an example.
So 20 and 25 what rows are those in.
Well that's going to be rows 1 and 2.
So we can say the fallings start at row 1 go all the way to the end.
Those are the rows and then for the actual columns will that starting at 0 and then going up to and
not including index 2.
And that's going to be basically opposite.
And there we can see we have 20 25 35 40 essentially the reverse of what we did on the first one.
You put a note book that goes along with his lectures a couple more.
Indexing help examples.
Well actually there's stuff like this too often because we'll mostly use pandas and named indices.
This is just kind of to get your brain in the mode of thinking of to them internal slicing.
But as far as the actual syntax we don't use it that often.
Instead we're mostly going to be doing something called conditional selection.
And this is a really fundamental concept that will directly translate to Pandas in the next section
so make sure you really understand this specific part.
This is a really important topic and it's called again conditional selection.
So conditional selection and to show this off we're going to create an array and it's just going to
be rearranged and we'll say 1 to 11.
So if we took out our array just one through 10 there.
So let's imagine that I wanted to grab elements off of the cerate based off some sort of comparison
operator.
I wanted to grab every element that was greater than for the process for doing this is the following.
I can actually compare my entire array to the number four I can say where is this array greater than
the four.
And it returns back this array of boolean values where the first few ones are false.
So 1 2 3 and 4 are not actually greater than 4 hour 5 and beyond are greater than four so you get true
here.
So this is an array of booleans.
And then what I can do is I can assign will say boolean array.
I can assign that result to this boolean array and then I can grab my original array.
And then passing that array of boolean values and what it ends up doing is it only returns the array
where the boolean values happen to be true.
So again I'm getting this boolean array array greater than 4 Sunday.
So this boolean array and then passing that in to my original array and ends up returning only the values
for the index location matches true here.
So that's how I get 5 6 7 8 9 10.
Now typically you actually don't separate this out into three steps.
Instead what you commonly do is the following.
You grab your array and then say OK give me back where the array is greater than 4 and you get this
sort of notation we see array twice here.
Once inside the braces and once outside the braces and you get back the exact same result.
And this is what's commonly done when you work with some PI and pantless and this is known as conditional
selection.
So you can do the same thing for any sort of comparison operator.
You can say going back where the array is less than or equal to nine and you get back one through nine
etc..
So again conditional selection we're going to see this a lot and we'll get a lot more practice with
this when we work with pandas.
And that's the basics of selection and indexing with some PI if you have any questions feel free to
post them to the Q&amp;A forums.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.