Welcome everyone to the numpad exercises lecture and this lecture we're just going to be going through
the notebook and explaining the exercises.
Let's hop over to non-pay folder and show you how you can find the notebook and go through it.
OK.
Under the Python for finance repo you can see here there's the pie folder.
Here are the three notebooks so we just went through arrays indexing selection and operations.
And then you have the exercises and the exercise solutions will be going through solutions in the next
lecture video.
But let's hit the non-pay exercises notebook for now.
And here we see some non-pay exercises.
And there's one important note that I want you to be aware of.
Make sure you don't run the cells that are directly above an example output shown otherwise you'll end
up writing over the example output and I'll show you what I mean in just a second.
But basically what I wanted to do is you'll see some tasks in bold and you need to do it.
So for the first one we'll show you important umpires and P.
That's quite simple.
All you say is important umpires and we run the cell and that's the answer to the first one.
The next one is create an array of zeros.
So what I mean by making sure you don't run the cells directly above the example output as you can see
the example output you would expect.
What you shouldnt do is code in the cell.
Otherwise when you run it your output may be different.
So you should say code here and then when you run the output such as Prince high you don't end up overwriting
this array.
So you can see there's a little extra cell in all these questions to say code here.
So you don't actually end up writing over these arrays.
So the first couple of questions are just creating arrays here I want you to create this array create
the Saray create a three by three Matrix three by three Matrix.
Now apply generating random numbers generating random numbers from a standard normal distribution.
I want you to create this following matrix see if you can figure that out.
Then more and matrices and finally you'll be non-pay indexing and selection where you have this matrix
given to you of the numbers 1 through 25 it's a 5 by 5 matrix.
And what I want you to do is write code that reproduces these arrays here.
Now remember you don't want to actually write the code in this array otherwise you'll overwrite this.
So instead write the code in this comment to write.
So you want to select an stuff from that matrix array.
OK so you'll do the following tasks.
And then you also get the sum of all the values that matrix the stand deviation of all the values in
the matrix and the sum of all the columns in the matrix and then this question right here it says get
the sum of all the columns in math.
That is the matrix So remember Matrix is a two dimensional matrix.
So if you come up here and see this code again this is the code that actually produces the matrix.
If you come down here and put this code in then you sell and check out what matrix looks like.
What I want you to do is figure out how can you take the sum of all the columns so you can see here
that the sum of the first column is 55.
Sum of All the elements in the next column is 60 65 70 75 etc..
Now we haven't actually shown you how to do that directly.
Well we have shown you as Matt that some.
And what I want you to do is explore how you can use this access argument.
If you get stuck on this just hop over to the solutions lecture will fully explain it there.
But this kind of left is something for you to discover.
Do you have the ability to go into the docstring and understand how to use this access argument and
as a hint it has to do with the shape of the array see.
Take a look at the shape the letters you get back a tuple which means if you asked for shape of zero
you get back the number of rows.
If you ask for a shape of one you also get back the number of columns so keep that in mind that may
be a useful hint.
The fact that you can use a 0 or 1.
So again when you're calling matrix some there's an X argument here.
All right.
Hope that's a heavy enough hint for you in case you get stuck on it.
Feel free to hop with the solutions lecture.
Is a less of the bonus question.
So we worked a lot of random data with no Pi.
What I want you to do is figure out there's a way that we can ensure we always get the same random numbers.
And there's a little hint here that you can click on that a little google search.
All right.
Best of luck with the exercises in the next lecture.
We'll cut through solutions.
See if they're.