Hello everyone and welcome to the E.W. or exponentially weighted moving average coatl long lecture.
This lecture we're going to review a simple moving average using rolling pin method from Panchos and
it will show you how to use the exponentially weighted moving average capabilities with pandas.
Let's open up a new Jupiter notebook and get started.
OK I've opened up a Jupiter note book Inside the time series analysis folder inside that time series
analysis folder.
There's a C S V file called airline passengers CXXVIII.
That's the C as we fall we're going to be using before we actually use it.
We're going to need to import a few things we'll see import pandas as PD important up-I and we will
import map plot lib pipe plot as Piazzi And then since I want to see the visualizations in my book will
say map lib in line.
All right.
So once that's actually imported Well we're going to do is read in our data.
I'll create a variable called airline to hold the data Freeman and it's a C as we files all say airline
passengers thought cxxviii you can use to autocomplete and we'll set the index column to be month.
Now typically what we do is we would say something like parse dates equals true but it's actually not
going to work for us because there is a couple of missing data points inside this data set.
So it would end up doing is once we see our airline checkup the head of it we see that we have this
month index and thousands of passengers.
But if we check out the index itself it's actually not a date time index that just happens to be like
street index in order to fix that.
We're going to do say airline index or first we'll say airline drop and away and we'll have that in
place to be true.
So we got rid of all the airline missing values here and there we're going to say airline index is equal
to the to date time and then passing the index again we'll see airline index now.
Check out the head of our data frame
and we see that includes Now the first day of the month kind of indicating that it's now a date time
index.
And if we want to check again we can just say airline index and here we see the date time index.
All right.
So we've actually already shown how to create a simple moving average to just as a quick review.
We can create a simple moving average just by creating a new column in our data frame.
For example let's say six month civil moving average and all set equal to the airline.
And it's called Thousands of passengers just tab out complete that we call rolling off this column and
you give it a window we'll give it a six month window that's in relation to our actual periods and those
periods are a month each.
So took us from the first and second month third month.
Obviously if you had daily data you'd have to change that.
But there's a six month simple moving average and don't work is going to call the mean off of this so
called Mean and we can just copy and paste this and let's create a 12 month moving average so a yearly
and we actually saw this in the slides.
So then I'm going to take my airline data frame and anoints plotted out and this is how you can get
the thousands of passer's six months simple moving average 12 month moving average to get a lot more
clarity you can also specify the size.
So we can specify something like Timba.
And you get something that looks like this.
I'm also zoomed in so it looks a little blurry in my screen zooming out to a normal zoom a look a little
better.
OK.
So that was a simple moving average just using the simple rolling.
Now we're going to do is show you the exponentially weighted moving average.
And remember that the exponentially weighted moving average overcomes a lot of the weaknesses of a simple
moving average things like smaller windows leading to more noise.
You always have this lag.
If you notice at the beginning of this plot there's kind of a lag there are going to be able to fix
that with E.W. may it also never really reaches the full peak or value of the data due to averaging.
So you can see here no matter what our window sizes we're never really going to actually reach the top
peak here.
And what we want to do if exponentially wait a moving averages is let these more recent points have
more weight than these past points.
So let's go ahead and try that out.
The way you do this is you simply zoom back in here call airline and then we create a new column we'll
just say E.W. Amay and I will say 12 here and then we'll say the airline will grab that thousands of
passengers call them again and then instead of calling rolling you call the W.M. you can do shift tab
here and it says provides exponential weighted functions.
And you'll notice that there's a couple of arguments here.
Their CEO m span and Half-Life and you can see here it stands for the dictate terms.
So you can you specify the Kames decay in terms of cion them spam or Half-Life or even an alpha term
and to discuss what all that means in just a second.
But let's show the span first lips span not Spain.
And then set that equal to 12 and let's grab the mean here run that and then what we're gonna do is
say airline and we're going to plot the original thousands of passengers and they will also plot E.W.
may 12th.
Let's see what this looks like.
So if we look at this plot and let's actually create the physics side just a little better so we can
really get a good look at it.
Well say 10 by 8.
If we look at this plot we can see that the behavior at the beginning is different than the behavior
at the end.
You'll notice that the sort of seasonality trend is a lot more clear.
Towards the end points than versus the beginning points.
And that's because we've waited the points closer to the present time heavier than the points during
the more historical values of the older values.
So let's now take a little bit of time to describe the mathematics or the formula behind this sort of
exponentially weighted moving average and then how you can decide what kind of parameters you want to
use when you call DOT GWM in order to do that.
We're going to hop over to the notebook that's provided for you.
There's actually some mathematical equations in there they'll be useful to reference so let's go to
that notebook now.
OK so here I am at the notebook we provide which is the GWM exponentially weighted moving average notebook.
It's just under the time series analysis folder and I'm going to hide that header and I'm going to zoom
in just a little bit.
It's going to be some equations and no book that we're going to be referencing.
So I'll kind of zoom in a lot and then I'm also going to toggle the toolbar.
So let's scroll down.
Here's all the code that we just went through as far as the simple moving averages so we can see we
created the six months simple moving average the twelvemonth's simple moving average etc. and then we
kind of saw here and it's a little blurry because I'm zoomed in.
But now let's go ahead and move on to the exponentially weighted moving average.
How does it actually work mathematically.
And what are the important parameters that we need to know as users of pantless.
So as we just discussed in the previous slides lecture E.W. M.A. it takes into account and tries to
improve on some weaknesses.
Esmay are simple moving average.
Some of those weaknesses just to review them are things like smaller windows leading to more noise.
You always have this lag where the size of the window.
It never really reaches the full peak or values of the data due to averaging.
And that doesn't really inform you about possible future behavior.
It just describes general trends in your data.
So in order to fix those things we use E.W. M8 so E.W. may exponentially weighted moving averages will
allow us to reduce the lag effect from simple moving averages and it will put more weight on values
that occurred more recently.
So really we want to figure out is how do I define that particular weight that w variable.
So there's full details and the mathematics behind this in this link.
So if you're really interested in this you can just click on this link and kind of dive into the mathematics
of it.
We're going to kind of give you a higher level overview of the math.
We'll talk about the alpha parameter a little bit and we'll talk about the three parameters that you
can use when working with pandas.
So the general formula for exponentially weighted moving averages is this following formula right here.
You have a Y value at time t you have X of T being the input value you have w of I is the applied weight
and know how the applied way w of-I changes as you go from equals zero.
The very first value 2 equals T.
And then as I mentioned why is the output So really the question is here how do we define this weight
term.
They'll be of I.
So how am I taking in these input values and getting the output values of that exponentially weighted
moving average How do we decide that weight term as it changes.
When you start from the beginning of the series all the way to the end.
So that really depends on what the adjusts parameter you provide.
E.W. method is.
So there's a parameter we haven't seen yet called adjust.
So when it just is true and that's the default value that Pandanus provide the weighted averages are
calculated using these weights.
So you have y of t the actual output value is equal to x of T plus 1 minus Alpha times x of T minus
one plus one of minus Alpha squared times x of T minus 2 plus etc. so on and so on and so you get this
find a formula where we have one minus alpha to the power of t for that original input value x not only
divide the whole thing by the sum of all the weight.
You can see here this is essentially a expanded formula of what we have up here where we're just replacing
W of I with this one minus Alpha at time t.
And that's important because we can see that there's a decreasing weight as you move further and further
into the time series because we'll have one minus Alpha and Alpha needs to be between 0 and the 1.
And what that will happen or what that what that will cause is that this is a decimal number or a fraction.
And then if you keep squaring a fraction are taken a fraction to the power of some other higher number.
Then what happens is you get a smaller and smaller value.
So you can see we're providing smaller and smaller weights for the data as it gets older and older.
So that very first data point has a small sway attached to it.
And the very most recent data point has the most weight attached to essentially just one OK.
And then we divide that by the value or sum of all the weights.
So that's the formula.
When it just is true when it just equals false specified moving averages are calculated as the following
you have.
Why not.
Is equal to x not mean that first input values equal to the first output value and then the rest of
the outputs y at times t is equal to 1 minus Alpha times Y at T minus 1 plus Alpha multiplied by X of
t the input value which is equivalent to using these weights right here.
There'll be a Y is equal to Alpha times 1 minus Alpha power of II if II is less than c and if I happens
to be equal to t have one minus alpha to the power of-I.
So basically that's what's going on here.
Just another way of rewriting w of-I.
OK so again one must have Alpha B between 0 and the 1.
And while since version of Pandurs 0.18 it's impossible to pass an alpha directly.
It's often easier to think about either the span the center of mass or c o m or the half life of the
exponentially weighted moment.
So this whole thing that we've been discussing kind of comes down to these three terms that we're about
to discuss.
So how do we actually choose this weight term.
Well with pandas The easiest way to think about it is when you say Alpha equal to one of these three
possible methods you either think of it as the span.
Think of it as a center of mass or think of it as the half life.
So what are these three terms actually correspond to in a general higher level sense.
So span that is s corresponds to what's commonly called in and day exponentially weighted moving average.
So in our case we were dealing with month values but typically you'll be dealing with daily values.
So if you want to use an exponentially weighted moving average where you can do is use the span argument
and set that in your mind as an end they exponentially weighted moving average where you just define
spanned by that kind of period that you're thinking of maybe a seven day or a 14 day and they exponentially
weighted moving average So that's how you can think a span center of mass that is the C value that you
provide has a more physical interpretation and it can be thought in terms of c is equal to S minus 1
divided by two.
So it's kind of a inverse relationship with spanne itself.
Then there's half life and half life is the period of time for the exponential way to reduce to one
half.
And then you can also do Alpha directly which just specifies a smoothing factor directly.
Typically when we're working with exponential weighted moving averages the easiest one to think about
is spam.
And if you want more explanation on the mathematics find this again.
Check out that link.
But typically we'll just be working with this span parameter because it's the easiest one that is intuitively
understand.
I would say the one that's second easiest to understand is the halflife especially if you've dealt with
things that have the sort of halflife mathematics before.
So what we end up doing like we just did is we set a new column and in this case we said DWM is the
span of 12 meaning kind of a yearly span in our case because 12 months is one year and then we take
the average and we get this exponentially weighted moving average.
And you can see here each year is kind of more and more strongly weighted as you get closer and closer
to the end of the time series.
And you can kind of play around with these and explore them yourself.
All right.
So that's really all there is for now as far as exponentially weighted moving averages.
If you're interested in this further than what we've discussed here definitely check out the link in
the notebook that gives you the full details on the mathematics behind this and how it works with pandas.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.