Hello everyone and welcome to part two of your first training algorithm.
Let's go ahead and actually implement what we discussed in the research note books in Quanto.
Id and hop over to Quanto Penn Dot Com and get started.
OK.
Here we are.
Quanto paeans ID and the first thing to do is important umpires MP because we'll be using that later
on.
And then let's find out the steps we want to do.
So first off we're going to need to initialize everything inside of this.
We're going to need to schedule one of our functions and the function we're going to schedule is essentially
going to be our what we'll call a check pares function and this chick Paris function is essentially
going to implement in the Ideally everything we discussed there in the research lecture for the notebooks.
So we're going to do things like calculate the 30 day moving average get the 30 day standard deviation
get the one day moving average compute the z score and then we're going to have essentially two and
three cases.
So let's go ahead and try this all out.
So we'll start off initialize because that's pretty easy.
We'll set up T.F. initialize context and remember this is called only once at the start of the algorithm.
So we're going to have insight of this is a schedule function and leave it blank for now because we
haven't actually created the check appears function that we're going to end up scheduling but for now
we can just say check pairs and check pairs is going to take in context and data.
Remember if you're going to schedule a function it's going to need to take in those two arguments and
more likely than not you'll be using those two arguments in some capacity.
But there's our schedule function and then later on what we're going to do is we're going to say context
American Airlines and get the security I.D. for that.
So if you start typing American Airlines You should see A-L.
And then for United Airlines will say contex thought you A-L and that stock ticker it's basically a
holding group so you can say whale.
And it should eventually find it for you.
If not we can search for you AOL.
And there it is.
United Continental holdings.
That's the company we're looking for and all this code is available to you in the notebook.
In case you need a copy and paste it and then offer this initialize.
We're also going to have two more flags.
So these are going to be called long on the spread and that will set that equal to false.
And then we're going to have another one called shorting spread and also equal to false and it'll become
more clear and just a little bit how we're going to use these to basically flags or checks.
So let's go ahead and grab everything we're going to be needing to compute the score because basically
our whole strategy is based off to the score here.
So one thing I'm going to do for convenience is instead of having to call context thought a context
thought all the time I will say ha equal to contex thought AA and I was able to contex thought well
that way this context.
AA which remember it's just a security ID for American Airlines is now set to the variable AAA instead
of this check pares function and now we're going to do is get the pricing history so I'm going to say
prices is equal to data call history off of this and I to pass into assets AAA el.
And then I just want the basically the price and I'm going to grab 30 days of price information and
because I want it daily I will say one the and then off this price Remember this is a data frame and
if you wanted to you could print this out and check what it looks like but it's essentially just the
data frame.
So I can do the following I'm going to say short prices is equal to prices.
I see negative one colon and that basically Razmi the prices for American Airlines and United Airlines
at the current time stamp in my back test.
And then we need to get them moving the 30 day moving average.
So say moving average 330 days one way to do this is to just say I mean grabbed the average.
I remember actually want this to be the spread.
So we make sure that's clear everything is in the context of the spread between both of these.
So I want them 30 day moving average of the spread and I will say prices American Airlines minus ups
prices of United Airlines.
So those two security IDs.
So that's my 30 day moving average of the spread.
I want to get the same thing for the stair deviation over 30 days.
So I'll say SDD 30 and the deviation and we'll say prices.
American Airlines prices United Airlines and then the last thing I want is basically the one day moving
average.
So the current price of the spread and I will say moving average of one is just equal to P..
I mean we're using this notation so it matches up with the notebooks that we discussed earlier.
And grab a short prices.
American Airlines minus short prices.
United Airlines.
And if you ever have any questions of what is prices or what is short prices what does moving average
or what is standard deviation.
The quickest way to get the answer that is just printed out and then check the log.
So if you're ever unclear with any of these variables are just go ahead and print them out run them
and the logs will tell you what they are.
OK so we have everything we need for the spread.
Now let's begin computing the z score so I'll start off I'm going to say if stere deviation of the past
three days is greater than zero which means now I have three days worth of information.
I will do the following I'll say the score is equal to the moving average one minus moving average 30
divided by a C the 30 number that was the same.
These were calculation we just did in those no books before.
And then we're going to have two entry cases.
So one of the entry cases is when our z score threshold has been topped over.
So that means the spread is currently above our z score threshold.
The second case will be when our spread is below the normalized threshold.
So let's go ahead and choose some arbitrary threshold values when we were planning it up previously
we chose one point zero.
And you can kind of imagine that the higher your threshold.
It means it's a little less risky because it's unlikely to peak or go below those threshold values.
So I will say if my z score is greater than 0.5 so is my ruling a z score is greater than 0.5 and I'm
currently not contex thought shorting the spread I will do the following.
Remember that the spread is equal to American Airlines price minus United Airlines price.
So if my spread if my currency score is above 0.5 then I believe that American Airlines is currently
overvalued and will eventually regress down to the mean.
So what I will do here is I will say Order target percent's and I'm actually going to shorts.
American Airlines.
Now this is a pretty aggressive strategy.
So keep that in mind but it works far kind of simplified version of thinking about things.
And then for United Airlines all go along on it.
So let's kind of look at the logic here.
I'm saying OK in my ruling the score has now reached this particular limit 0.5.
And in the previous plots in the last lecture it was one point zero.
Whatever you want it to be is kind of fine you can test out different ones see what works better for
you.
So right now my score has breached this arbitrary value that I chose and I'm currently not shorting
the spread.
So does that mean that I'm going to say OK if my spreads American Airlines minus United Airlines then
I believe the American Airlines are going to come down in price so I will.
Short American Airlines and I believe United Airlines is going to continue so we'll say long on that
and then I'll do the following.
So I want to make sure that my algorithm is aware that I'm currently shorting the spread.
So I will say that shorting spread equal to true and in case I was going previously long on the spread
I want to set that now equal to false.
OK so that's one of the things we're going to check.
Then I'm going to check another condition and that's going to be if my score is now less than 1.0 and
I'm not currently long on the spread
I will do the following.
So it's a couple more lines here.
So this is essentially the opposite entry condition.
So remember now American Airlines is supposedly undervalued.
So I would believe that I should go do the opposite.
Go long on American and then order target percents and go shorts on United Airlines
because I believe that United Airlines is overvalued.
So that's causing a big subtraction for American Airlines causing the spread to go down.
And then ingoing those context variables here.
So we'll say I'm not sure in the spread.
Set that equals false and I'm currently long on spread so that equal to true so setting this context
long on spreads equal to true.
It makes sure what it does is it makes sure that I'm not already going to continually execute this.
So I'm only going to execute this once the score is less than one point zero and I'm checking for the
long odds spread so I don't do this over and over again I just do it once.
What is it.
And then I need to exit out of the positions so it's exit out of the positions.
We're going to need some sort of kind of minor threshold and we'll say the absolute value of the z score.
0.1 or something like that.
Kind of a smaller value.
So once the absolute value of that Rollings z score has become less than 0.1 which means we're kind
of basically hovering around zero.
I will exit my positions.
So say Order target percents get rid of all my American airline stock.
Turn it back into cash and then in order orders target percents get rid of all my United Airlines stock
as well and then I'm going to reset these contacts.
So shorting spread is going to be false as well as context long on spread is equal to false and then
off of all this.
Let's just go ahead and have record here.
So it might be nice to record some of this.
So I'm going to record the z score.
So we'll say something like z score ups and set that equal to the actual z score.
So again this is just going to record the z score as we go throughout time.
And you can record kind of whatever you want.
You could technically record the prices etc..
The moving average any amounts you really want to record and see plots for.
You can do that as well.
OK.
So there's our actual check pairs function.
The next we have to do is schedule it.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we're going to schedule this function and let's have it the calls will say check pares passes some
rules and it's going to happen every day.
And let's make sure that's a thought not comma.
It's already said Make it happen every day.
And as far as time rules are concerned let's just go ahead and have it be done at market close and let's
have it be done.
Should we begin executing it like 60 minutes before the market closes I could have just one hour.
Either way is fine.
All right.
So that should be it for our overall strategy.
Let's quickly review what's happening here.
I'm grabbing American airline stock United Airlines stock.
The security IDs and I'm sitting along on spread false and shorting spread false and then I'm going
to schedule this check pairs to happen at the essentially at the end of every day.
We'll make sure that time rules.
That's right rules.
And then 60 Minutes for the market closes I'm going to check the pairs.
So what does that actually do.
Well again to have American Airlines United Airlines are going to grab the previous 30 days of history.
I have my short prices was sincerely just today's prices that I have my 30 day moving average sarod
deviation of the last 30 days and then essentially my current spread.
So I have spread over three days straight deviation and spread over three days and then my current spread
and we're reusing and that means so kind of goes along.
What we did in the previous lecture and once I have 30 days of information than my standard deviation
will be above zero.
And then I can calculate the score.
So I will say hey I'm moving average today minus moving average of the past three days divided by the
start of the nation or Thursday days so I'm normalizing the amounts.
Then we're going to say the following.
If my score is above one point zero and I'm not currently shorting the spread I'm going to short American
Airlines because I think it's overvalued because it's above that z score threshold and I'm going to
stay long the United Airlines then I'm going to say hey I'm currently shorting the spread.
So don't keep repeating this if statement and then I'm saying I'm no longer long on the spread.
However we have the opposite case which means I think United Airlines or valued because it's taking
away too much from that spread to say hey Mazi scores less than 1.0.
And I'm not crawling along on the spread go long and American and start shorting United Airlines stock
because I think it's going to come down soon.
Then again I say I'm not shorting the spread I'm currently long on the spread else and this is essentially
how we actually get out of these positions so how we exit these positions and we say if we finally are
hovering around zero.
So if the absolute Mazi score is somewhere between world the score somewhere between zero point one
a negative point one then it's reset these to be zero and am currently no longer shorting or going long
enough spread and I'm going to record the z score as we go along.
So let's try this out.
What I always recommend is just trying this out on essentially just a few weeks of data to make sure
there are no errors here so let's quickly build this algorithm or it looks like I got an error line
44 invalid syntax so if I take a look at that it looks like axially else here.
This should be if the reason for that is because I'm actually checking on condition or Imber else statements
don't check on the condition.
So that should have been Elif we technically could add an else here that says pass or something but
we don't really need it.
So once that saved let's try building this algorithm again see if we get any other errors.
It looks like we don't have any runtime error so we're just producing those logs and it looks like we
actually generated something so over 1 week we got pretty bad returns.
Let's go ahead and try this over two years and see how it performs.
So we'll build the algorithm again and let it run.
I'm going to hop forward in time until this is done backtesting this particular algorithm shouldn't
actually take that long to back test because most of the time we're not going to be actually ordering
something and we're not ordering something every minute.
In fact it just finished by the time I'm done talking so we could see here that the returns were actually
negative for us and we performed way worse than the index.
But hopefully you can see here how we were actually able to implement a particular strategy of ours.
So again not a good strategy overall but the implementation was the important part here to understand.
So we successfully imported a very simplified version of our strategy.
If you have any questions make sure check up the notes for this.
If you've got an error or something or got a bug go ahead or just copy and paste from notes make sure
it matches exactly as shown there.
But hopefully now you have a basic understanding of how you can create your own trading algorithms and
implement them in Quanto Appian.
Because coming up next we're going to give you an idea for a trading algorithm and then your task is
going to be to implement it in the IEEE as an exercise.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.