Welcome back everyone to this lecture on emerging joining and concatenating data frames learning how
to actually join two data frames together is an important part of the process especially when you're
dealing with data sets from different sources.
Usually you'll end up dealing with datasets by getting them from Panda's data reader or quando which
will learn about later on then you'll have different data frames and you'll want to join them together
before you actually continue your analysis.
So we're going to learn the basics of merging joining and concatenating.
We won't use all these methods and in fact I would highly recommend checking out the documentation on
these methods because the documentation really lays out examples very clearly with pictures and example
code for a variety of merging and concatenated tests.
We're just going to go over the basics in this lecture with simple words the Jubran a notebook and get
started.
All right.
Here we are at the Jupiter notebook for merging joining and concatenating.
First off we're going to create some example data frames to work with here.
I've imported pandas PD and using a dictionary and a list of index numbers.
I've created three data frames one DFA to a DFT.
We take a look at these data frames will see that we have diff one which has columns A B C and D and
indexes 0 through 3 and then the 2 has the same columns except the indexes are 4 through 7 and then
diea 3 has the indices through 11 Let's talk about concatenation concatenation basically glues together
the data frames.
Keep in mind that the dimensions should match all on the axis.
You're trying to concatenate on for this.
You just use PD dot com and then pass on a list of the data frame's to concatenate together you're going
to concatenate data frames one two and three by passing them into a list into the PD.
Concat function.
You can see that by default the access to join on is zero meaning it's going to join the rows together.
We see here that successfully concatenated or basically glued together the data frames.
And we can see now we have a b and c and d as columns with the indices zero all the way up to 11.
Each of the data points lining up nicely.
Now you could also specify x is equal to 1.
If you want to join and merge along the columns or concatenate along the columns.
And this is an example of what happens when you use PD that Comcast on these three data frames along
x is equal to 1.
Notice here we have a bunch of missing values and that's because these data frames didn't have values
for all the indices that you want to concatenate on.
For example with data frame 1 A B and C and D you had indice values for 0 through 3.
However for all the way up to 11 you had no values and that's why fill it in with Knolles when you joined
this are concatenated on data into a data frame 3 which basically means when you're working with concatenation
and Piddy that concat you'll want to make sure that you have information lining up correctly when you
join on the axes.
In this case we wanted to join an axis equal 0 to line everything up correctly had we specified the
join along the columns facts equal to one.
We'll have a bunch of missing information.
Most often you'll probably be joining columns together so you'll in fact be joining along.
Access is equal to 1.
However make sure you know your data and what you actually want to concatenate before choosing an access.
All right let's go ahead and move along.
We'll create some more example data frames.
In this case one called left and one called right here.
Take a look at left.
We have columns A and B with some values in them and then we have a key column k 0 through K3 we have
the right data frame which is a very similar data frame except it has different columns C and D.
However the key column is exactly the same as the left so heavily left data frame and the right data
frame pandas is capable of using the merge function to do merge logic.
That's very similar to merging sequel tables together.
And if you don't work of sequel you don't have to worry too much about this but I'll show you the basics
of how to merge two data frames.
You just say PD that merge and then passen the left data frame and the right data frame or just pasan
data from one data frame to whatever data frames you want to merge together.
By default it will merge them on inner.
And if you're unfamiliar with inor as regards to siecle merging don't worry about it just use the default
inner.
More importantly learn about this on.
Basically when you're merging you're going to want to merge on a key column and you can actually pass
in one or more key columns which we'll see later.
But basically what's happening here is we're going to combine or merge these data frames together on
this key column.
And that way instead of concatenating them we would have two key columns we can merge so that we merge
them or join them on the same key column that they share.
So the logic here is when you're easily Peetie that merge instead of just gluing the data frames together
you're going to see where the values match up on columns.
In this case the key column and then create the rows using that key column.
Let me go in and show you a couple of more complicated examples.
Here I have left and right data frames and will notice here that they have two keys he one and key two
otherwise they're exactly the same as the left and right we just saw earlier you can use PD that merge
just pass in the first data frame and the second data frame and then you can specify on and you can
pass in a list of keys if you want to actually merge on multiple keys such as key one or key to.
And here are some more examples using merge outer or merge.
Right now if you're not familiar of sequel syntax such as inner outer right or left joins don't worry
about this too much.
We don't actually use these in the course we will always default to something that looks like this in
the course we just use an inner join.
However if you find yourself trying to do the sort of sequel merging and you're already familiar of
SQL syntax just know that pandas has this.
How operator are parameter for you to use.
In case you want the extra functionality but basically depending if you're using outer writes inner
etc. You may find that you have some missing values so keep that in mind as you're working with PD that
merge.
Here's an example of left.
And finally we have arrived at joining joining is a convenient method for combining the columns of two
potentially differently index data frames into a single resulting data frame.
You can essentially think of this as the same thing as merge except the keys you want to join on are
actually on your index instead of a column.
So here I've created two data frames left and right.
Notice they have columns AB and then CD and then the index is actually the keys are going to join them
and the syntax you can use is say left join right in will automatically do an inner join between the
left and the right.
Based off of the index keys if you wanted to merge these two data frames based off of one of their columns
you'd have to use merge but the join method functionality comes off of one of the data frames.
You say that join and then pass on the other data frame and just like merge.
You can specify how such as inner left outer etc..
And remember this only for and sequel users who are already familiar with that terminology.
If you're unfamiliar with that don't worry about it too much.
Let's go ahead and do a quick review of how to join merge into cottony data frames and we'll go over
the key topics you should get out of this lecture.
As far as merging joining and concatenating data frames in order to concatenate or glue data frames
together the process is quite simple.
You just say PD non-cat and you pasand a list of your data frames and then you make sure to specify
the correct axis depending if you want to join them together by the rows or by their columns.
Next you have PD that merge and PD that merge allows you to merge data frames together and you just
passen your first data.
You want to merge and then your second data frame you want to merge and then you say on and you can
Pessin just a single column key.
Or you can pass any list of keys and by default it will merge on inner.
If you're unfamiliar with merging sequel tables don't worry about this how too much just worry about
one data frame on the left one data frame on the right and then on a certain key column are on a list
of key columns.
That's really the only functionality of the merge that we'll be using throughout the course.
And then for joining is a more advanced method for combining columns of two potentially differently
indexed data frames.
It's very similar to merge except the actually joining on the index instead of a column and the syntax
for that is just the name of the Left data frame drawing on the right.
We actually won't be using join throughout the course but I want you to be aware of that and you can
reference this notebook or the documentation in case you ever want to review joining.
All right great job.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.