Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on portfolio analysis with PI Fulvio so Quanto it has a built
in library called pi Foleo and PI ff..
Also open source you can check out its own page and has great documentation on its own Web site which
I would definitely encourage you to check out.
There's a link in the resources for you to check that out and what it basically does is it creates tear
sheets which are just sheets with a bunch of information on them and then it also has a bunch of informative
plots that can easily create with one liners.
So we're going to explore this.
The main things we're going to do this lecture is just set up two algorithms for us to get back to us
on.
And then we'll do a bunch of full calls and see all the plots that are available to us.
So let's head over to Quanto up in.
I don't have a notebook and an ID open.
OK so here I am at the research notebook and I'm going to do a couple of imports.
I will say import let me just zoom in here by Fulvio as P.F. and then I'm going to import that plot
lived up pipe plots as Piazzi and I'll import another library that's built in here that we're going
to be using later on called empirical OK.
Then the next thing I want to do is get some actual algorithmic returns.
So he wants algo returns and we're going to use the same algorithm we use in our leverage lecture.
So remember if you come back to the IEEE slimmy go back to this algorithm we had our leverage example
and the leverage example is really simple.
It just said send half her portfolio to go long on Amazon and half your portfolio to short IBM and then
we also set some set max leverage.
You can also just hashtag that out.
Really what I want to do is just have this really symbolic rhythm that every day it essentially goes
long on Amazon and goes short on IBM.
So we're going to back test this let's say for two years.
So from January 2015 to January 2017 and then I'm going to run the full back test in order to actually
get the hash code for the test so I can remember GRABBE up here from the L.
That second half after the forward slash that is the back test Tasche.
So we're going to copy and paste that you can see here we have pretty good returns makes sense because
we essentially knew the future when we designed the algorithm.
So we're going to come back here and we'll say the following.
We're going to say BT is equal to get back test.
And then I'm going to in that hash.
It's going to get the back test for me and then I'm going to grab some information that we're going
to be using from this.
So we're going to say Beati returns is equal to BT dots and if you look at all the things that are available
here as far as attributes one of them is called daily performance and you can go ahead and grab return's
off of that.
So within that back test we have daily performance information which if you come up here you can see
there's daily positions and gains.
So that's the information we're kind of grabbing in a different format.
So we have our back tax returns.
And I'm also going to do a couple more things here.
We're going to create an object called back test positions and set that equal to back test PI Foleo
positions which is another attribute we're going to be using.
And then we're going to say BT transactions is equal to BT The PI Foleo transactions.
So you can already see the Quanto IP and has a lot of these things built in mind that you're going to
be using by Fulvio as part of the analysis kind of aspect of this whole platform.
She'll be getting back to us from whatever algorithms you're messing around with grabbing the returns
grabbing the positions and grabbing the transactions with these three key things we can do a lot of
plots with by Foleo and get a lot of informative information out.
So whatever algorithmic returns what we also need in order to do a lot of these comparison plot's is
actually get benchmark returns.
So the way we're going to do that is we're going to create a really simple algorithm and I encourage
you just to copy and paste this.
So we're going to come back here to the algorithm itself and I'm going to delete everything we have
here and I'm going to copy and paste the algorithm that's available to you.
And you know book and if you want you can do this yourself.
But basically the main idea is I'm going to end.
We don't really need this Max leverage but that's ok.
I will set spy as the security and I'm going to say 100 percent of my for Foleo to go long on Spy Maurice
spiciest be five hundred.
So this is essentially going to mimic the benchmark.
So I'm going to now run a fallback test on this same time period and that's kind of important.
It needs to be at the same time period as you did for the other one otherwise you have kind of mismatch
data.
And you know decir that our red line and Blue Line are almost the same thing.
Basically we just have some tiny bit of losses due to commission and trading or slipping etc. but that's
kind of a quick and dirty way to essentially get the benchmark.
So we're going to do here is grab this back test hash code and then this is for benchmark so will say
a benchmark and then I'm going to do the following.
I'll say benchmark returns is equal to get the back test my benchmark and then we're going to do the
following.
We'll say B-M returns is equal to benchmark returns.
Whoops.
Some other stuff here so let's say.
Bench mark Retz that and the same thing as last time we'll say daily performance.
Give me the returns.
And this is probably not a good choice I should call this like benchmark or something.
But essentially we're doing the exact same four steps that we did earlier.
So we grabbed the returns and then we're going to say benchmark positions is equal to benchmark Rhett's
portfolio positions and then we're going to say B.M. transactions is equal to benchmark on the score.
Yes the PI Foleo underscore and we want transactions.
So we're going to run those two things.
And now we have all the information we need in order to use phileo.
So let's go ahead and check it out.
So there's also empirical which kind of gives you a bunch of information.
So if you want you can use empirical and you'll notice it has kind of alpha beta and all of volatility
Daily's the ability of time series etc. Sharpe ratio.
So it allows you to quickly grab information off a back test object or some returns.
So for instance if you look at the Sharpe ratio do shift happier what it expects.
If you provide the returns report back the Sharpe ratio of the strategy.
So for example we can pass in our back test returns I mean zoom in one more level.
Kind of these little clear and reports back that the sharper issue for our initial leverage algorithm
was 1.3 to you can compare that with the sharp ratio for just the benchmark itself saying empirical
Sharper's show and I will say be Emirates Hearn's run that and it's 0.4 7.
So you can see is a lot more volatility in the actual market itself versus kind of your own trading
strategy.
And it also has a bunch of other things to it.
You can play around with this library a lot but let's say you wanted to get your beta where you can
end up doing is you passen your returns versus the benchmark returns.
So that would look something like this.
You'll see your back to us returns versus the benchmark returns and it reports back your actual of value.
Okay.
So we have that information.
Let's go ahead and create some pie Fulvio plots.
Now if you're using a different time frame or a different algorithm your plots may look slightly different
than mine but it's okay as long as you actually get the plots and we're essentially just going to be
copy and pasting from the notes so keep that in mind.
The first thing to do is the following I'm going to make sure I don't accidentally call this benchmark
returns object by accident so I'm going to say benchmark rets is equal to be returned just to make sure
that they're now the same thing.
So let's start off with cumulative returns and then daily non cumulative returns and those are really
easy with Foleo.
So again I just copy and pasting from the notes here because a lot of this is just calling a single
line to plot.
So you can see here I calling PI Foleo P.F. plotting dots.
And then there's a ton of plots you can do.
So just to make that really clear be called for pi Foleo and then call P.L..
You can see all the different plots that are available for you.
You won't show all of these will just show the most useful ones that you can not do plotting dots and
you'll see a bunch of other stuff you can plot.
So a ton a ton of plots here and PI Foleo we're going to show you the most useful ones.
So if you run this you'll end up seeing a plot for Kulemin of returns and then daily noncommutative
returns.
And usually you want to compare it to a back test so you can see our returns versus the back test returns.
So our return is a lot flatter than the back itself.
So that's the actual trading algorithm performing a lot better than the S&amp;P 500.
And you can see here using plotting that plot returns.
It also has an automated plot for the returns themselves.
So that's one way of putting out your returns comparing it kind of on a cumulative return basis and
our returns themselves now we're able to actually do all this with pantless.
So let's go in and show you a couple of more plots again.
Copy and pasting from the notes pasted in here.
Run this and you can see here we have three different plots.
We have the annual returns for our back test the monthly return distribution and then the monthly returns
heat map.
So what does this actually mean.
Well we have three plots.
We have annual returns.
So we can see here what our returns on average in excuse me are returns for 2015.
You can see we have around 60 percent returns.
And you can see for 2016 we actually had negative returns and the average between those two.
Is this dotted line here.
So that's the annual returns.
Here we can see the distribution of monthly returns and you can see kind of like the sister gram and
then the average marked by this dotted line and then that black line just represents or 0 percent returns.
And here is the number of months that had that particular amount of returns.
And finally over here on the right.
We have a heat map where it tells you the actual monthly returns and percentage.
So this allows you to tell that this basically allows you to quickly see what were your good months
and what were your bad months so you can quickly see our worst months were February 2016 and then kind
of our best months were the seventh month of 2015 and the 10th month of 2015.
So that kind of shows you early 2016 wasn't that great for us and kind of later 2015 was pretty good
for us.
Okay.
There's a bunch of other plots you can do you can also return the Quon tiles so we can run this and
this essentially gives you a box plot showing you the distribution for the returns distribution for
daily returns for weekly returns and then for monthly returns and it makes sense that you know a larger
timeframe your distribution of returns goes wider.
There's also a rolling beta plot.
So again just copy and pasting from the notes here.
So if you run this you're going to need to pass in your own bench your back tax returns versus the benchmark
returns.
Remember Bayda is calculated against some sort of benchmark.
So here we can see the six month and 12 month rolling beta.
So you can see how Bayda changes the pendant on the market conditions.
So then we have our average Bayda this kind of dotted line here.
So that's another thing to check out.
You can also see a rolling Sharpe ratio which is kind of fun.
So I'm going to pass that one in its plot underscore rolling sharp and that's when you just pass and
you're back to us because it's just telling you what was the ratio of your particular back test over
time.
So this is the ruling Sharpe ratio.
And by default it's a six month rolling Sharpe ratio.
But if Cziko shift tab here you can affect the window to whatever you want but here rolling six months
of operation and then it shows the average and then hear that black line is just zero.
Then there's also a bunch of other factors you can plot out something you can do like draw down so you
can say P.F. plot.
Draw them periods again.
Remember to check it those resource links back and rediscuss draw down.
So this will show you the top 10 10 draw down periods and it kind of colors them for you.
But what's also nice about this is sometimes people like to do what's known as an underwater plot which
is kind of almost like an inverse of what's going on here.
So if we run this it will show you the draw down underwater plot.
So here you can kind of clearly see the actual percentage draw downs as a factor of time here.
It will just color them for you and kind of show you the difference I mean like the peak in the troughs.
OK.
So again check out the research links for more information on that.
You can also do things like plot the gross leverage.
So I'm going to copy and paste that from the notes.
So this one again you're comparing it to the back test returns versus back test positions.
So it needs those two arguments here and then we'll show your gross leverage throughout time.
Then there's also things like tear sheets that you can do.
So it's going to copy and paste this from the notes but if you have a bunch of securities in your algorithm
it'll show you things like what were your top ten long positions of all time top ten short positions
etc. all positions ever held the maximum amount of time you were holding them etc. so you can see here.
In our case we were always shorting IBM and always long on Amazon.
So it didn't really change for our case but for more complex strategies where you're holding hundreds
of securities this will be a much more useful term sheet.
And if you're really interested in a full tear sheet that means just a bunch of information about your
portfolio you can say P.F. dot create roundtrip tear sheet.
So does create roundtrip tear sheet and it takes in the returns the positions and the transactions and
it basically gives you a huge Well just a bunch of data frames with a bunch of information.
So surgey the summaries that's so all the trades all your shorts all your longs what time are the percentage
really profitable.
How many winning trips how many losing round trips how many times.
Even the total profit gross profit center average trade net profit a lot of useful information here
on returns that successor.
And then if you keep scrolling down it will also show you the sort of like mapping plot for two positions
that are short and long.
It won't be super useful but definitely check out the examples in the documentation for what this would
normally look like.
But essentially it's just going to go blue when your long and then go red when you're short.
So in our case this entire time period we were short on IBM the entire time and long on Amazon the entire
time.
But if you have a much more securities and you kept jumping in and out of long and short positions you
kind of see what not what's not exactly heat map but it looks like a bunch of scattered red points and
blue points.
So it's kind of useful in here.
You can also see the probability of making a profitable decision.
The better algorithm that means higher probability you have.
And then also here holding time and days for the stock on average histogram of that information round
trip returns and percentage per round trip etc..
So lots of useful information there.
And that's basically what pipeful is therefore to make your life a lot easier.
Previously when we had a plot all this we had to do it manually if pandas but you can check of that
documentation for portfolio.
It has more explanations on what each of these charts means.
We didn't go through every single plot type but as your algorithms get more and more complex by Foleo
it's going to become a large and larger part of your ability to analyze your portfolio strategy.
OK.
That's it for this lecture.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you in the next one.