Hello everyone and welcome to this trading algorithm exercise.
So as I mentioned welcome to your trading algorithm exercise and keep in mind this is really an exercise
and using to Quanto platform and reviewing everything you've learned such as scheduling functions grabbing
historical data.
You shouldn't take this as an exercise in learning a real trading strategy while older trading strategies
did use Bollinger bands which we're going to discuss in just a second.
The actual execution that we show here is really too simple to be effective so keep that in mind.
So we're going to have you execute a very basic blunder bands trading strategy.
So let's quickly review of Bollinger bands are.
But keep in mind to actually discuss them previously during the rolling mean lectures.
Bolinger bands record bounce above and below the 20 day rolling mean or rolling average and Bulgar bands
consist of two bands an upper and lower bound.
The bands are calculated from the 20 the rolling mean and 20 day rolling standard deviation.
So the way you calculate them is you just take your 20 day rolling average or rolling me and then for
the upper bound you're going to add on two times the 20 day standard deviation or the 20 day rolling
center deviation and then for the lower bound you're going to calculate the 20 day average and then
subtract from that two times the twenty day standard deviation.
And if you actually want to see this implemented go ahead and go back to the pan this time series lecture.
We do have an implementation of these actual bands in case you want to see how to do this pandas.
So we're going to use these bands and compare them to the current price and use that as a trading signal.
So let's see a visual representation of what these bands actually look like.
So if we just plot this out T-Ray have a very simple example of the current price this purple line and
then I have the upper bound and the lower bound and those are my two Bollinger bands and you calculate
them by calculating the 20 day rolling average or attone they mean.
And then you add on two times a 20 day rolling standard deviation and that creates your upper bound.
And if you subtract two times to 20 standard deviation that is a 20 day rolling second deviation.
You end up getting that lower bound.
So we're going to be implementing kind of an extreme version of the boulder band strategy.
Our basic idea is the following.
If the current price is ever above the upper band we're going to short the stock.
Now we're going to send 100 percent of our portfolio to short the stock.
If the actual current price is ever below the lower band we're going to go long on the stock and we'll
have 100 percent our portfolio go long on this so our version of the strategy is extreme in the sense
that we really only enter exit positions based off the upper and lower bands.
You may want to play around of exiting off some smaller band off the mean.
Maybe when the price comes back and crosses the 20 day rolling average you exit out of that position.
But our strategy is pretty extreme because we essentially only look at the upper band and a lower band
and that's because it's the simplest to.
So again the strategy is pretty reckless and I would actually never recommend it to anyone.
However it is simpler to implement.
So it's perfect for us to use our practice on the Quanto open platform.
So you'll be implementing the strategy on the Johnson and Johnson stock although really you can kind
of play around if any stock you want and you can check out the notebook for the back to start and back
end dates so you can make sure that your actual code matches up with the results of the example solution
code.
So let's quickly review it using the visual representation the actual strategy that is.
So what does this actually look like in practice if we implement our strategy.
Well you can see if calculated some upper band that upper Bollinger Band and the lower bowl in your
band.
And as I'm going along through the time on the x axis if my current price that purple line ever surpasses
the upper band I'm going to take that as a signal that the stock or security is overvalued and will
have to come back down.
So I'm going to short the stock using my entire portfolio.
The other signal I'm going to look for is if the current price ever then goes below the ban on going
to buying go long on the stock for 100 percent portfolio.
So keep in mind those are my only entrances into the strategy.
If it goes above the band or below the band I'm never going to exit in another fashion.
That's why it's pretty extreme version of this.
So you're only going to check these bands once per day meaning you will need to use the schedule function
and you can check up the notebook provided for a full overview.
Now all of this seems a bit overwhelming since you've just started learning about Quanto in code along
the solutions lecture first and then go back and see if you can implement it on your own.
All right let's go ahead and get started.
Again remember to check out the trading algorithm exercise notebook for full details on how to implement
this.
And in the next lecture we'll go over the solutions.
Thanks and I'll see you there.