[Autogenerated] Hello.
Welcome to the planning and configuring A W s systems manager
module within this managing AWS operations course.
Now, what are we going to learn in this course?
Well, we're gonna have a deep dive into A W s systems manager.
We're going to discuss monitoring and compliance
dealing with Cloudwatch and Cloud Trail.
We're gonna look at leveraging service catalog to offer our applications and
services as needed to separate clients or our own organization.
And then we're going to explore the different S
three features that AWS provides.
So let's dive into this first module in this module.
We have a few learning objectives that we want to cover.
The main overarching objective is we want to have a
deep dive into A W S systems manager.
Now this breaks apart into three things.
We're going to identify benefits of the service itself.
We're going to explore actions that can be performed using the service.
And then we're going to look at managing actions
and events using systems manager.
So with that,
let's go ahead and break here and in the next clip will pick up by diving into why we want to use systems manager