[Autogenerated] All right, let's dive into systems manager now.
Why would we want to use a systems manager in AWS?
Well, there's three main reasons now.
The first is that it allows us to group.
Our resource is into resource groups,
which allows for easier management using those resource groups.
We can then analyze our workloads and gain insights toe
operational data that we're working with inside a ws.
And then using those insights,
we can then perform actions on our resource groups as needed.
Now we'll dive in deeper to each of these three topics as
we work our way through this module.
In this course now a W s systems manager is really a suite of
tools and services offered to us by a W S.
They all simply live under one roof called systems Manager.
So let's talk about the first subsection now.
The first thing we see in the Consul which will see here
upcoming in the next clip is operations management.
Now,
Operations management is a sub suite of tools built into A W s systems manager.
It has something called Explorer, which allows us to customize dashboards.
Four reports of our resource is in our accounts.
We then have ops Center and this is going toe offer us
a centralized place for viewing,
investigating and remediating operational tasks that we need to perform.
So a good example here would be patching, weaken.
See that hate?
We need to go ahead and re mediate these instances and get them up to
date for the patching standards that we put into place.
The next thing that's offered his cloudwatch dashboards.
Now we'll discuss dashboards in depth later in this course,
but at a high level,
they allow us to monitor cloudwatch metrics from
within the Systems Manager page.
This is a handy thing toe have.
Since you'll be poking around the different systems,
you don't wanna have to keep hopping back and forth between
services like system Manager and Cloudwatch.
Now it's in one location,
and the final capability is trusted advisor for real time
guidance in the Personal Health dashboard,
which monitors A W s health events.
And it will put event notifications in our consul for us to view.
So if AWS is having a service malfunction in a specific region,
it would appear in our personal health dashboard.
Now that's going to do it for this overview on operations management.
Let's go ahead and jump away from the presentations and let's get into the console and start exploring each of these capabilities.