[Autogenerated] Okay, Welcome.
Now, in this clip,
we're gonna actually start talking about cloudwatch dashboards.
So when I select dashboards on the left side of my screen here,
we can actually see I already have a few already created.
Now, if you recall, we actually made this plural site.
Andrew Demo Dashboard.
When we were working through this from the Insights menu in Systems
Manager and we can see we have our widgets that we added.
So let's go ahead and go back to dashboards here,
and we're gonna walk through this again.
We're going to create a new dashboard, so I'm gonna click, create dashboard.
Let me go ahead and give this name the default name,
if you remember, which is cloudwatch Dash default,
someone a click on Create dashboard now.
And it brings us to this ad to dashboard screen,
which is where we select our first widget type.
Now, before we go through with this,
let me show you some examples of what these look like.
A line graph is going to look like that so you can see there's
lines here and in this particular example,
there's this dots because there's not multiple indications on that
graph but depending on the metric you're measuring,
those lines might be connected all the way.
Throughout that graph, we have a number widget, which is what it sounds like.
It displays a text number on the dashboard itself.
We have a stack area, so this has a shaded portion underneath that line.
It basically builds off of that first line widget that we see on the
left of the screen and building some shading and some coloring to
make it a little bit easier to picture.
And it makes it look nicer.
And then finally, we have text, which is marked down now.
I don't see this one use very often, but it's good to know that they do offer it.
You can basically have a marked down page as a widget on your dashboard,
so it allows you to do a lot of different handy things.
Anything you can do in mark down, you can actually do in this text widget.
Now, one last important thing is the Remember to always save your dashboard.
After adding your widgets,
I stress that in the systems manager module and all stress it again.
Any time you make a change, or add a new widget.
You need to save your dashboard.
Let's go back to the council now.
So for this one, let's just go ahead and do stacked area.
We'll click on Configure and then let's give this a graph
name we can see here on the top left weaken,
Click on this little edit button and we'll call this graph one.
I'm gonna click this little check mark to accept it,
and I'm gonna scroll down to all metrics down here.
And if we scroll through this, we can see we have building cloudfront E B s logs,
Lambda E.
C two and then s three and S s.
Now,
the reason we see these metro groups listed and not every
single one is that's because we have only these resource
is within our account active.
So let's go ahead and let's select SNS for now.
And we can do several things.
We can look by the country or SMS type.
We can look at topic metrics or we can look at metrics with no dimensions.
So for this example,
let's click on topic metrics here and you can see here we have one topic.
There's four topic names, but it's really all the same topic.
It's just different metrics that are being measured.
So if I scroll down, let's just go and see number of messages published.
So I'm gonna select this because I want to see the total
number of messages that were published.
And I want to change this graft metric here to a statistic of some.
So I want to see the total sum of messages published.
And let's turn this up a little bit.
I'm gonna go to Period and let's go down to one minute.
So that's a very active monitoring period.
And then finally, I want to go up to custom here the timeline.
And let's just do three months so you can see here that we've had exactly two
messages published in the last three months and that's a sum.
So it's a total of two messages.
So what I'm actually gonna do is I'm gonna pause this clip.
I'm gonna go published a few different messages on this topic,
and then we'll come back and check this out again.
So for now, I'm gonna click, create widget.
I'm gonna save my dashboard, remember?
And then I'm gonna pause this and then I'll resume it
after I published a few messages.
All right, so I posted a few more messages.
Three to be exact.
And we can see here.
Now that our graph is updated, you can see the count now is at three.
Number of messages published.
Three.
Now, one thing to keep in mind here by default.
When you create this widget and it gets on the screen,
there's a default period here that's gonna check every five minutes.
So to speed this up or even customized for your own stuff if you want,
what we did here is I wanted to actions.
And then from this,
you can see there's a period override now with in this period over right?
I said it toe one minute, so it would be a lot quicker,
and we don't have to wait a long time,
but you can see that it actually allows you to do a lot.
You can do one second five seconds all the way up to 30 days.
And what this period is is the amount of time that it's collecting data.
So for every one minute,
Cloudwatch is going to post an updated amount of data on this graph here.
So I sent it to a one minute, but usually it's gonna be set,
Otto, or five minutes now.
Since I changed that, I'm gonna save my dashboard again.
And the next thing I want to do is open up this actions menu again.
Now,
what we can do here is we can make a new dashboard weaken
save this one is a copy to a new one.
We can favored it.
Weaken, rename, delete and weaken, view and edit the source.
And then here at the bottom, we can actually even inter full screen,
which is kind of a cool little thing.
If you have maybe a monitor or display that's strictly for
monitoring this dashboard Nyman exit full screen here.
And the next thing I'm going to show is we can add another widget.
So using this add widget button that I just clicked on,
it brings us back to this main screen.
So if he wanted to weaken, select another widget,
we can configure it and we can go back in and
measure metrics again if we wanted to.
So let's just do lambda I'll do by function.
Name will do invocations.
Forget SSN parameter.
And another handy thing here is if you're looking for a
specific metric name or even us resource name,
you can click on this little drop down here,
this little tree, and you can actually search for this on Lee.
So if I wanted to, I can look here.
It indications.
And I can search for this on Lee and we can see that I only
have one function here that's being measured.
But if I had more than one,
it would show indications Metric name for multiple function names and you
can see that it's populated here in this search bar.
So I'm gonna select this.
I'm gonna go to graft metrics.
I'm going to select the some again, and then we'll do a period of one minute.
Now I'm gonna say this.
So create this widget.
I'm going to save my dashboard.
So now if we had any indications on that land of function,
it's gonna populate this number widget for us,
we don't have any.
So that's why it's a dash dash.
But one last thing.
I want to show you up here we have our timeframe again.
So if I went to one week now you can see a better view of
what a stack area graph looks like.
We see two originally.
And then it went up to three during this period.
Now let me save this dashboard.
And the very last thing I'm gonna show you is if we go
back to this overall screen here.
If you remember,
they had this where we can scroll down and we can see our default dashboard now.
And that's because we named this cloudwatch default.
So now it shows up when we scroll down on this overview
screen because of the name we gave it.
Now that's gonna do it for the dashboard portion of this module.
Go and wrap this up and I'll see you in the next one. We're going to start talking about alarms.