[Autogenerated] Okay, here we go.
Now, in this clip,
we're gonna work on publishing a new version of our existing product.
So I'm in the plural site products screen here.
And if I scroll down two versions,
we can see there's a few different things we can do.
We can create a new version of our product,
or we can click on actions here, which is going to allow us to activate,
deactivate or delete in existing version.
So what I want to do is I'm gonna click on create version
and I'm actually gonna choose a file here.
Now, What I did is I went ahead and updated our existing service catalog product.
I just took away one particular parameter,
and I'm gonna give this a new version title.
So I'm gonna call it new and improved because it's new and it's improved,
and I'm gonna give it a description that calls out the differences.
And there we go.
So this newest version is limiting the instance types that are deployable,
some to click on save here and there we go.
Success.
A new product version has been created, so we now have two versions.
And if I scroll down here, we can see both versions.
So let me go and clear this message here.
And if I scroll back down, let's go ahead and de activate our initial version.
So I'm gonna select it.
I'm gonna goto actions, and I'm gonna deactivate it.
So we get a warning here, we're gonna continue,
and we can see now that our version was deactivated.
And what this means is that are provisioned.
Products can no longer launch this version,
and you can see that they actually market with an inactive tag here,
right next to the name.
So now, if I click on new and improved and I click on actions,
this is the new activated version, so we can see we have activate is great out.
But we can now deactivate or delete this version as well.
So basically any new deployments of our product are going
to deploy this new and improved version.
So if I load this up,
we can see the description at the top and then some of the
actions that might be associated with it.
And then they also describe the template,
or they list the template that was uploaded here.
So this is a long Yamil based cloud information template.
So now you can see how weaken,
activate and deactivate and even delete older versions.
So if I go back here and I go down and select the initial version,
let's go ahead and delete this version.
So I'm gonna click on, continue here after our warning, and there we go.
We now have only one version, and that's the new and improved one.
So this is how the version control ties in to the service catalogue offering.
Now, before we wrap this clip up,
I'm actually gonna go ahead and let's actually look at our products list.
This is a different view than what we have seen.
So this is where we can upload new products if we want to,
to an individual product list.
And that would allow us to add these products to existing
or new portfolio list that we create.
So, underneath this menu again,
you can see that we also have our portfolios list,
along with other options, something to click on portfolios list,
and that takes us to our portfolio screen.
So be sure to poke around this consul menu and really see what
you can do using the service catalogue service.
You can see you can even set colors in a logo specific to your service catalog.
So they really allow for custom branding and very custom specifications
that you can set all for your particular product.
Now, we're gonna go ahead and wrap this clip up on AWS service catalog,
and I'll see you in the next one where we're gonna start diving into storage management tools.