[Autogenerated] let's begin diving into application management Now.
Application management is the next set of capabilities
that systems manager allows us to use.
It's a sweet if you recall from our presentation that it allows
us to manage our applications running in AWS.
So the first thing we want to do is I'm gonna go over resource groups now,
under resource groups, you can see I have some defined,
and we're gonna go ahead and create our own here in a minute.
But resource groups are going to allow us to organize many
different resource is within a W s all in one group,
and this is going to allow us to perform actions and automation on several.
Resource is with one particular automation task.
Now automation is coming up in the next section,
which is actions and change over here on the left.
But resource groups are a staple for systems manager,
so it's important that you understand how they work and how
you can use them Now before we get started.
Just some background here is I spun up to different buckets.
You can see ones, Devin ones prod.
And then I also spun up two different instances and If we look at the tags here,
you'll see Dev and then you should see prod Perfect.
So we're going to use these Resource is to demo how resource groups work.
So I'm gonna click on Create Resource Group and
this brings us to our group type.
Now we can either search for resource is based on tags or we can
search for cloud formacion stack based tags.
Now, we'll do both.
But for this first go around, let's do tag based.
So now that we have tagged based selected,
we go to grouping criteria and this is where we can select what type of resource
is that we want to collect and add to this resource group.
When we search, you can see there are tons of resource is in here.
So be sure to check this list out on your own time.
From this case, I'm gonna do all supported types.
Now, let's go ahead.
I'm gonna give this an environment key value and then,
for the actual value of this key, you'll see it auto populated.
I'm gonna do prod.
We want a group.
All of our prod resource is so if we wanted to,
I could click preview and it's going to give us a group of our resource is
that belong to this resource group based on our query there.
So all of these resource is right here near the bottom.
All have a tag of prod with the environment key.
So now if this looks right, we can scroll down.
We give our group of name.
We can give it a description we can give our group tags,
so this will apply tags to the resource group,
but not your actual resource is.
And then we can click on Create Group And there you go.
It's that easy.
So we've now just created a resource group,
which has production related Resource is all in one group.
So now we can use this later on and you'll see how in upcoming clips and
we can perform automation based around these groups.
Let's go back and let's just look at the cloud Formation Stack based group type.
So I select Cloud Formacion stack,
and then we can see the different confirmation stacks
within this region for our account.
So these 1st 2 are my Web servers that I deployed,
and then the bottom two are are different buckets.
So let's just go ahead and do Dev Web, and we'll do all resource.
Is that air supported once again?
So if I preview this, you'll see we get to Resource is there's an instance.
And then there's a security group, and if I go to this instance,
so 71 E two is what it ends with.
And if I go to tags, this is what it's using right here.
In order to query for this resource group,
this is the cloud formacion stack I d.
That's used when we create this group.
So if I go back,
that's where these two re sources are coming from so we can give this a name.
Now, let's do Dev Web servers.
We can give it a description.
I'm gonna click on Create Group and there we go.
We now have a Dev Web Servers resource group that contains any resource
from that dev Cloud Information stack that I deployed.
So now if you go to save resource groups,
we can see our Devil Web servers here and then our prod web resource is So Now
if I go back to systems manager and I refresh this page here we're going to
see our new resource groups that we just created.
So now we can go in here quickly,
weaken view our details and this gives us all of the
details of our resource is for our group.
You can see there's a details pain.
We have config.
So if we have config rules in place, it would show their compliance.
Here we have our cloud trail section so we can check the different
events that have occurred on our resource is we can monitor it with
cloudwatch metrics and cloudwatch logging.
And then we have our ops items.
And if you recall, we went over ops items when we were in Ops Center,
and this is where we can go ahead and perform operational
related tasks specific to our resource groups.
And the last thing I want to show we're not going to
really go all the way through it, but we can execute automation.
So this is what I was talking about when I was discussing
actions and change on the left in automation.
Now I'm not going to do this right now.
Will demo this in upcoming clips,
but it's important to be aware that you can perform
automation tasks on your resource groups,
so let's go ahead that's gonna do it For resource groups,
it's very important that you understand how these work as they
are a fundamental piece of knowledge that you need in order to
properly use systems manager, at least at an efficient level.
There's other ways to do it, but it's not going to be the most efficient way.
So let's go ahead and wrap up here and then in the next clip, we're going to start discussing APP config.