[Autogenerated] Okay.
Now building off of cloudwatch events.
It leads us into cloud trail.
Now A W s Cloud trail is the service that AWS provides that you can use to
help ensure that you meet strict auditing guidelines and maintain a strict
security posture within your AWS accounts.
Now, there are three things that I want to touch on before we dive in.
The first is the cloud trail helps enable governance compliance
and then risk auditing of our AWS accounts.
And with this,
it's actually turned on by default as soon as our account is created
and we'll take a look at this here in a minute.
And then the last key point is that this is the key tool for
maintaining security and operation best practices.
So this really allows us to maintain that strict posture I was talking
about by allowing us to identify any malicious events or maybe out of the
norm events that occur within our AWS accounts.
We can create a trail to trace us back to the source.
Now, a little tip here is that any time you hear auditing,
you should be thinking of cloud trail.
It was designed with auditing in mind.
So let's go ahead and check out the consul here.
And if I go up to services,
we can see that cloud trail actually falls underneath the
management and governance section of the services.
So let me load this up here,
and you can see it brings us to this welcome to cloud Trail screen.
Now,
the first thing we see here is that we can create a trail
which will do here in a little bit.
But then the next thing below that is, we have recent events,
and you can see these are the most recent events recorded by Cloud Trail.
And if I scroll around through here, you're going to see that we have event time,
the user name our event name, and then the resource is that were affected.
So this is a trail of the most recent events that occurred within our account.
Now, if I want to get a deeper history,
I can go over here on the left and I can load up event history and
you'll see the first thing they show us is Hey,
you don't have any trails.
And what they mean by this is we have not created
our own trail specific to our use.
So we'll do that here again in a minute.
But I just want to show you this event history section.
So if I scroll down here, you're going to see we have an event History page.
Now, as you can tell,
we can view the last 90 days of events and all of these events are going to
contain the actions taken by people groups or AWS services in your account
and that includes all read or write events.
So if I scroll down to this tab here or this page,
you can see there are tons of events that have been going on within my account.
You can see the day you can see the time the user name
the event name like we talked about.
And if I expand one of these,
we can see it breaks it down in pretty great detail.
We can see our access key that was used.
The region The event I d.
That is a unique I d to cloud trail.
We get the event name the event source.
So we deleted a bucket from S three and then we have our event time.
It was not a read only event.
We have a request.
I d the source i p that the request came from and then the user name that
actually committed this event or perform this activity.
So this gives us a very detailed breakdown of exactly who, What, and win.
So I'm gonna close this down now and let's go back to dashboard.
So let's create our trail.
I'm gonna click create trail here and we'll call this plural site.
If we wanted to,
we could neither apply it to all regions or we could just do it toe one region.
And you can see that by doing all regions,
it creates the same trail in all regions and delivers
those log files for all regions.
Or we can just lock it down to one region.
So I'm gonna click.
No, because I only want a monitor North Virginia right now.
And then I'm gonna scroll down to manage events.
Now,
management events is where we define what kind of
events that we want to monitor.
So do we want all read and write,
or do we only want one of the other or even none now?
Good thing to keep in mind here is that read.
Only events are going to be like describe or get or list And then
our rights are gonna be anything that's creating,
updating or deleting so usual standard practices to capture all events.
But you might have a use case where you want to just
specify a specific event type,
so we'll leave all for now and I'll scroll down here and you can see
they give us another section called data Events.
Now,
this is where it can give us mawr insights into specific resource is that
AWS has and you can see it's s three or lambda so we can record object
level ap I activities like get object put objects for our buckets or within
Lambda we can actually see all invoke a p I operations as well for all of
our functions in this region.
Now, I'm not gonna capturing these,
So let me scroll down here and the next thing we see is storage location.
So this is where we place our cloud trail trails at where do
we want to store these audited events?
So I'll create a new bucket here Well saw select.
Yes, I'll go and give this name of plural site hyphen Andrew,
just so it's not taken.
I know that buckets not taken.
And then if I expand advanced right here,
we can see we can give our log files prefix.
So if I wanted to, I could give this a prefix of demo.
And now every log that goes in there is going to start like
this Demo a ws logs account I d Cloud Trail,
which is the service and then our region.
Now we can also encrypt log files which will do so.
Let's use service side encryption here, and I want to create a new key.
And I'll just call this test for now because I'll go and delete it and clean
it up after this clip and one little tidbit to notice here,
which is pretty standard that your kms key and buckets need to be in
the same region if you're using the existing key and the next thing
we have is we can enable log validation.
So this is gonna let us essentially verify and validate that our cloud
trail logs have not been tampered with in any way.
So you definitely want to keep this enabled if you're using
this for auditing purposes and then lastly,
if we wanted to weaken, send an SMS notification for every log file delivery.
So if we want,
we can maybe receive an email every time we get a file dumped into our bucket.
So I'm gonna go and leave that as no.
Now, quick refresher.
Before we continue, we're creating a new bucket called parole site.
Andrew, we're giving a log file prefix of demo.
We are gonna encrypt our log files with service side encryption using kms,
and it's gonna be a new came s key that we're creating.
We are gonna validate our log files to make sure they're not tampered with,
but we're not gonna alert when they actually get delivered.
So I'm gonna scroll down here and I'm gonna click on create.
And there we go our new plural site, Cloud Trail Trail.
Now, this is gonna take a little bit to catch up.
So what I'm going to do is load this up here and I'm gonna go ahead and
start poking around my account so we can get some events flagged within
our cloud trail trail that we just created.
So I'm gonna pause this and we'll be right back.
Okay,
so I've let the cloud trail kind of sit in the background
for a little bit while I perform some events and let's go
and see what this is all about.
So we've configured this cloud trail to use this bucket with our prefix,
were encrypted and then were writing to s three.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
I have s three preloaded here,
and we can see now that our cloud trail events have
been pushed in the designated format.
We have our bucket over here, followed by our prefix of demo.
We have our logs account I D Cloud trail our region,
and then what it does is it breaks it up for a date.
So we have 2019 the month and then the day.
And what I did here is I opened one of these cloud trail events up,
and I want hadn't made it pretty over here in V s code.
I just wanted you to see what it looks like from an event standpoint.
It's essentially just a giant Jason payload that allows for
quick scanning and references to certain key value pairs so we
can see we have our records here, which is a standard event for AWS.
And then within this list, you see, we have our I am user.
There's our access key or a principle i d what user it
was weaken CMF a was authenticated.
So I was using MF A for this.
And then if we scroll down here, we can see the event itself.
We have our event time, the source,
the event name our region R I P address which I blocked out for this and then
you can see there's actually even some request parameters.
So this is when we created our cloud trail earlier within this clip.
So this captures aton of information.
I mean, if I just scroll through this quickly,
you can see there's line after line of trail events within this,
so this can really get populated pretty quickly.
So I'm gonna scroll back to the console and let's go
back to Cloud Troll Management.
Now the next thing I want to show you is we can actually configure cloud
trail to push to cloudwatch logs where we can build alarming or notifications
off of so we can push it to a law group and then,
using that law group, weaken,
utilize cloudwatch events in metrics to post toe on SNS notification or topic.
I should say that gives us a notification to check everything out,
so I'm not going to do that in this clip.
But it's just something to keep mind.
If you want to build alerting,
you'll want to utilize cloudwatch logs using this log group
functionality and one last thing before we wrap up here.
A neat little feature for Cloud Drill is,
if you're part of an organization,
you can actually enable this at the top or the master account in the
organization and create a trail for all of your sub accounts that can push
all to essential place for you to monitor in audit.
So that's a pretty handy way to audit all of your
different accounts in a simplified manner.
So we're gonna go on wrap this clip up on Cloud Trail,
and I'll see you in the next one. We're going to start diving into Amazon, Inspector