[Autogenerated] Okay,
welcome to this clip where we're going to start diving into Amazon,
Inspector.
Now,
Amazon Inspector is a tool in service that's offered by AWS to
allow us to perform several different functions that help us
maintain this strict security posture as well as meet compliance
standards and requirements.
Now, the first thing it lets us do is perform active auditing.
So we're gonna be able to actively monitor in audit our
current AWS resource is and then, if needed,
to alert on any violations.
The next thing that it allows us to do is identify applications security issues.
So if we're missing some patches for some operating system
packages that we might have installed,
we're gonna be able to identify and act on those different issues.
It also allows us to gain a better understanding of our resource is as a whole.
With this insight,
we're going to be able to truly understand what's going on within our resource
is such as those missing security patches or some type of auditing or maybe
some type of malicious software that we might have installed on our resource
is specifically are easy to instances.
The next thing it allows us to do is to really work with
configuration scanning and monitoring.
So if some of our ec2 resource is don't meet our standard for our configuration,
we're going to be able to scan in,
monitor and pick up on things that are violations.
Now.
It also comes with a built in content library.
And what this means is they provide certain baselines for us to use.
When we're running them against our temple,
it'd targets, and we'll discuss what that means here in a moment.
And then the last big benefit is that we can automate everything
via an A p I so we can perform a P I calls to automate our scanning
in configuration monitoring processes. So let's actually go ahead and check out Amazon Inspector in the console.