[Autogenerated] Okay,
Welcome back to Part two in this parameter store discussion to start off.
I want to talk about the string list parameter that we haven't covered yet.
So once again, let's just enter our path here will leave the description blank.
I'll talk on tears here shortly, and then we have our string lists.
Now,
this is where you provide a list of values in a comma
separated format for us to use.
So what we could do here is I get Inter Andrew for a user name will do, Bob.
And then let's do Jill as well.
So we have three users in a list I'll click on create.
If I go in here, you can see our list.
Let me copy this name,
and I'm gonna use that same parameter store function that we used before.
Now, in between clips, I remove that with the decryption equals true value.
So we can start using this again.
I'm gonna click on edit.
Let's save this environment variable.
And let's test.
All right, we see succeeded.
And there you go.
We now have our three users in a list that we just pulled from parameter store,
so you can perform some type of action based on this list.
Like maybe we want to update some permissions for a specific set of users,
and we can store that list of users in one location here in parameter store,
so it allows for scalability in reuse of parameter
values amongst ER applications.
Now the next thing I want to talk about is I want to talk about the tears.
So if I go back in here, I create a parameter again.
Let's just call this prod advanced.
You can see we have a tear option.
Now the standard tier sets a limit of 10,000 parameters,
and you can see that can only go up to four kilobytes.
So they're limited in size and number, and we can't specify a parameter policy.
But they're free.
There's no additional charge to use standard parameters.
Store parameters now advanced, on the other hand,
offer us a little bit more flexibility.
We can create more than 10,000.
They can be up to eight kilobytes in size,
so double the amount we can specify are parameter policies.
But another big difference is that charges apply to
advanced parameters and you'll notice you cannot revert
back to a standard once it's advanced, but you can do the opposite.
You can go from standard to advanced.
You'll see it's the same types.
Nothing changes there.
It's just now we have more characters that we can implement,
and you can see that here at the bottom.
So if I go to this one,
the standard you see 40 96 advanced has 81 92 so immediately were
doubling the value amount by going to advanced.
Now you'll also notice what you didn't notice.
In Standard is a parameter policy.
So if we wanted to,
we could expire this parameter at a specific or relative time.
And what's nice is we can also notify based on cloudwatch
events with some specific settings.
So let's say we want to notify before it expires one hour before,
So this will send a cloudwatch event that we can alert through SNS.
If we desire, I'll click on Disable here and then I'm gonna click on Cancel.
Now that's the key differences between a standard
parameter and an advanced parameter.
They're very key in critical differences,
so be sure you know which one you want to choose for your use case.
Now let's look at settings here now under settings,
you'll see that we can set a new limit for our parameters Store throughput.
Now, this is newer.
It used to not be Edita ble,
but now we can go ahead and accept charges and then set
throughput limits for our parameters.
And we can also change the default here.
So if we just create a parameter quickly,
we can say, Hey, I want it to be intelligent.
So choose, depending on the request, I want to advance by default or standard,
so it allows some flexibility in customizable selections.
Now, the final thing I want to touch on here is our hierarchical storage.
Now what this means is we can use path based or hierarchy based
naming structures to control who can see what.
So, for instance, in our parameter store demo here,
this has full access to S S M.
But what we could do is I can go to parameter store,
define these Dev database values, creates,
um, Dev application values, and then I congrats permissions based on that path.
So if I do recursive and I do slash Dev and a search will get
everything with a slash dev And then whatever is behind it.
So we have database, password, database user and then users.
So what we can do with this is we can specify in I am policy that Onley allows
that particular user or role to access stuff with this path,
but not slash pride so it allows for segregation of privileges as needed.
And then, really, if we wanted to, we could also get down to the second level.
So let's say we only want our Lambda function to have
the prod application specific value.
So if I do this and I search now, I forgot one level here.
So let me go back.
We'll do recursive I enter the path here.
There we go.
We can lock that down to a specific path that we want all the
way up to the last value in that name so we can define this
entire name here if we wanted to,
or I can give it a path and give it some permissions to
access everything under that path value.
Now that's gonna do it for this demo on parameter store
and the different types of parameters.
Be sure to play around with this as much as you can as it's a
free alternative compared to secrets manager.
But there are some tradeoffs that you have to be aware of.
So do some research play around, and then when you're ready,
we're gonna move on to the actions and change capabilities that we have in systems manager.