[Autogenerated] Okay,
welcome to this clip where we're going to start
looking at Amazon guard duty now,
AWS defines guard duty as a continuous security monitoring service that
analyzes and processes the following data sources.
We see VPC flow logs, cloud trail event logs and then DNS logs.
Okay, but what does guard duty really do while the first thing is,
it uses machine learning to identify malicious attacks on your AWS account.
Now it does this by utilizing different threat feeds which can contain
resource is like lists of bad I peas or malicious i peas or maybe some
reported abnormalities within accounts.
So they're using all of this built upon data to identify these
different malicious attacks automatically.
Now, it also scans for exposed credentials,
privilege, escalations and malicious traffic.
So basically,
it's gonna be able to see if any access keys static credentials were exposed.
If you've had unwanted privilege escalations to maybe admin level roles or
if you have some type of incoming malicious traffic into your AWS account
and then lastly it's going to be able to detect compromise resource is as
well as unauthorized deployments.
So if someone does get into your account and they compromise or resource
is and maybe start deploying tons and tons of unauthorized resource is
just incurring an enormous amount of cost.
Guard duty is going to be able to alert on that.
So let's check out guard duty in the console.
Now, when you load up guard duty for the first time,
you get brought to this getting started page.
Now, this is a pretty familiar page for most of us,
and it just has the getting started guide,
the different steps that go along with it.
And then we have documentation in support here at the bottom.
So I'm gonna going click on getting started and you can
see were greeted with a welcome screen.
Now the first thing is going to do is warn us about
the service permissions needed.
So we are granting guard duty permission that analyze our
cloud trail logs are VPC flow logs in our DNS query logs
to generate these findings,
which is kind of what we discussed in that first slide.
An important note here is that we can suspend or disabled guard duty at
any time to stop it from processing and underneath that you can see when
we enable guard duty for the first time,
your account is automatically enrolled in a 30 day free trial.
And I can tell you from experience that guard duty can get pretty expensive.
If you're using in all of your different regions,
it adds up pretty quickly, but it is a great tool to use.
So before we enable this,
we can actually view this service role permissions that are going to be needed.
You can see the permissions here.
And then we also have our trust relationship,
which is saying that hey, guard duty is allowed to assume this role,
so I don't see anything funky in the permissions.
It looks like it could basically just describe our images and instances.
So I'm gonna close this out and let's go ahead and enable this.
Now we can see were brought to our guard duty dashboard.
So we're in our free trial mode here, as it's noted.
And if I click on this, you're gonna see hate.
We have basically 29 more days of our free trial here,
and then eventually, after this gets going a little bit more,
they're going to be able to provide us an estimated cost after our trial ends.
So you're not gonna see this updated in this clip?
But if you enable this on your account, you will see this after a few days.
We can also see here that we can have different accounts underneath this.
So this is handy.
For if you have organizations where you're having a
ton of different sub accounts,
you can have one master account that has all of your different
member accounts underneath it in one location.
So you basically send out an invite to these sub accounts,
and they accept it in order to be added to your account screen here.
The next thing we see here is lists right above that.
And this is where you can essentially white list certain items.
So the first thing we see here is trusted I p's.
So it's going to essentially ignore any eyepiece that
you adhere in your trusted I P list,
and it's not going to report on any of those findings.
The next thing underneath that is the threat, Lis.
Now,
the threat list is going to essentially allow you to add a
known malicious I P address toe a list so that guard duty can
immediately generate findings on it.
It's not gonna have to take a little bit of time and generate some
type of threat model based on some machine learning,
because you can specify immediately.
So it kind of helps guard duty out and speed the process up.
The next thing we see here is our settings.
So if we go to that,
we can see our about guard duty section weaken CR permissions,
which is the service role that we gave earlier.
The next thing we see is our cloudwatch events,
so we can automatically send notifications to cloudwatch events here
and then we can set up or frequency that we want.
So new findings are going to be updated immediately.
You can see here and they put a caveat of hate that's really within
five minutes and then any updated findings we can specify so we can
send it to a default of every six hours or weaken set these one hour
or maybe every 15 minutes.
And then the next thing we see is our sample findings.
So this is where we can generate sample findings to help us
visualize and analyze the different types of findings that
are produced by guard duty, so it just kind of helps us South.
Let's just go and click this button here and we can see that.
Hey, it successfully generated sample findings,
so we'll go over that in a minute.
But let me continue on this page and we can see we can suspend guard duty.
So when you suspend, it stops your monitoring and doesn't generate new findings.
Now,
a key part of this is that you're not going to be
charged when the service is suspended.
So if you want to take a break from it,
you can just suspend it and you're not gonna be billed for that.
The next thing we can do is disable it.
So if you want to disable it completely, you can do this as well.
And obviously, a W s will not bill you if you disable it now.
The big difference between these two is that when you suspend it,
your existing findings are going to stay there.
You don't have to reconfigure your settings and rediscover your findings.
But when you disable guard duty, you're going to lose everything.
You don't recover anything if you decide to re
enable it and you can see they say,
Here you can save or you should save a copy of existing findings.
So with that understood, let's actually look at these findings here,
and you can see that these air,
the generated ones that we had because we obviously don't
really have any traffic on this account.
But you can see how they classify everything.
So these air sample events that are found v a guard duty.
You can see it looks like we have a tour I p caller.
And when you hover over it,
you see the message in the reason why and you can see it
pretty much scans for a lot of stuff.
A tor relay, our cloud trail logging was disabled by a user,
and then you can even see we actually hate.
We have a ______ here,
and it was on our particular instance here of I and then
repeating nines so it gets very detailed,
and it can actually scan pretty deeply into our resource is within our account.
Let me go and click on one of these and then you can
see when I do that and I select it,
it's gonna populate our screen over here on the right,
we can see our unique finding I d.
And then it gives us a reason or a status of what's going on.
We can see that this instance is attempting to query domain
names that resemble Expo traded data.
So this could be an indication of a compromise.
Instance they classify as, ah, high severity.
It gives us the amount of times it was hit,
the region, the resource and then the resource affected.
Underneath that which shows the resource role is an actor.
The instant state, what image it is the different daisies,
what type of instance,
and really just all types of very detailed information that
we can use to isolate and maybe fix or just completely
remove this particular resource.
So this is a very,
very powerful tool that a lot of organizations use when they
need to enable some type of overall compliance monitoring
from a centralized standpoint.
So I do recommend you go ahead and check guard duty out,
especially if you're in enterprise account and play around
with it to see what works best for you.
That's gonna do it for this clip.
We're gonna wrap it up and then we'll wrap up this section overall in the next clip with In I Am Best Practices Review