[Autogenerated] All right.
Welcome to this last informational clip within this second module.
Now, in this clip, we're going to start looking at I am best practices.
Now I imagine you're already pretty familiar with I am,
but we just want to do a quick review on some of the best
practices to really ensure that our account is going to be
compliant and as secure as possible.
Now,
the first main thing is obviously I am is the core service for all
access control and authentication for our AWS accounts.
Everything starts with I am essentially whenever were interacting.
Now the next is a list of some key best practices,
and the 1st 1 is to always enable M f A,
especially on the root account, and then lock away your credentials for route.
If you can.
A lot of teams will take this.
They'll enable M f A and then take their credentials for root and lock it in a
safe somewhere where only certain individuals can access it.
The next is to always take your least privilege approach,
so only give out what is actually needed.
Don't give too many permissions.
You always want to utilize roles for delegating permissions,
so avoid using static users whenever possible.
And then, if you do have static credentials,
be sure to regularly rotate those now it's actually
recommended to rotate every 90 days or so.
And then the last point I want to touch on is that you should always use
managed policies instead of in line whenever possible.
And this is really for tracking purposes.
More than anything,
you can control these managed policies a lot easier than in line policies,
and the last note here is obviously understanding I am is extremely important.
So I do recommend you deep dive into I am whenever you get the time.
So let's go ahead and look at I am Indy Consul itself.
Now you can see I'm at the I am screen and this is
the default dashboard that we get,
and I'm really just gonna show you a few quick things.
The first thing is the security status here on the middle of the page,
you can see that we have activated MF A on our route account.
We created an individual user to log in as we used groups,
and then we applied a password policy,
so these air the 1st 4 steps that AWS really recommends when we
first get in that I am now to set some of these.
We really want to go to account settings here,
and this loads air password policy.
So this is where we're going to specify are different minimum
requirements for passwords for our static users.
And it gets pretty detailed weaken set different requirements
for a password itself when they can change it,
or if they're allowed to.
And how many of the last ones are remembered that they cannot use.
And then another little nifty feature here is at the bottom.
We can actually disable security token service per region.
So I deactivated everything outside of the U.
S.
Because I'll never use it.
And I can always be sure that I only ever have STS active in the U.
S.
Regions.
Now,
the very last thing I want to show you with this before we
wrap this up is this credential report.
So what this does is it allows us to download a report of all the accounts,
users and the status of their credentials.
So I already downloaded one of these and let's take a look at what it looks
like now we can see here we have a root account here,
and as you can see, we can see our first user is our route account.
And then we have me and it shows a few different properties.
We can see our user creation time are password enabled,
which is either true or false.
When it was last used, Last changed.
We can see if M f.
A is active if our access keys air active and it actually
shows on both pairs of access keys, which is really nice.
And then if I scroll all the way to the end,
we can see if we had Certs active for authentication,
they would show up here as well.
So this is a very handy report that you can use to quickly view the
status of different credentials within your AWS account.
Now that's gonna do it for this clip on.
I am best practices.
We're going to wrap it up and I'll see you in the next one. We're gonna have a summary in an overview of what we all discussed