[Autogenerated] cool.
Let's dive in tow actions and change.
So with our overview, we just had we discussed it.
How the Actions in Change section provides capabilities for
us to take actions on our AWS re sources.
Now the first capability I want to talk about is automation.
Now automation allows us to simplify common tasks revolving
around R E C two and other AWS re sources.
Now there is flexible as performing one off tasks like creating a snapshot.
Or you can develop your own complex work flows to
perform these automation tasks.
This automation capability really allows teams to free up a
lot of their time by automating all of the tedious tasks
that they normally complete.
So let's just explore this here really quickly.
I go to execute automation.
This brings us to our choose documents screen.
Now we'll talk about documents in depth a little bit later on,
but for now we'll just walk through this process so you
can see how automation works Now.
The first thing you might notice is that we have four tabs currently available.
We can filter by owned by a Mazon owned by me,
shared with me or all documents so If we go toe owned by Amazon,
you'll see that they have their own categories listed here on the left.
And these all fall under a main or common ops related task
that you might complete like E C two tasks.
There's patching tasks or even am I management.
Now what I want to do,
just for the sake of this demo is I want to go to
create image some a select AWS, create image,
and you'll see it populates our document details.
Here at the bottom, we see our name, the description,
and then we have our version selection.
Now it goes to default, which makes sense.
But you can also specify latest or you can specify a specific version.
If there were multiple and again,
we'll dig into this a little bit deeper coming up when we
talk about documents over here on the left,
so I'll leave it at default.
I'm gonna click on next, and this brings us to our execution phase.
So do we want a simple execution where we just execute on specific targets?
Do we want to rate control it so we can execute these tasks on multiple targets?
But we can limit the concurrency.
So based on how many targets we want to do it once or a percentage,
as you can see down here,
we can control granular early How many executions we want to
take place so we can limit toe one at a time.
We can do 50% of the targets at a time,
and we can specify our error thresholds now.
The next option is multi account and region,
so this does exactly what it sounds like.
It allows us to execute our automation tasks and
multiple accounts and multiple regions.
But we can do so from one central location.
You'll see when we select this option,
we get this target accounts in regions section that we can fill out.
So what we can do is specify account I ds or an O.
U I d.
From an organization we can specify are regions.
We defined the automation execution roll and then
we can add more or remove them.
Now,
you also see we have an optional ray control so we can do
the same thing where we can limit the number of targets
that are being executed on.
And we can also set an error threshold.
So this would allow us to essentially deploy to an entire
organizational unit if we wanted to, with one task.
And then the last one we see is manual execution.
So this is where we go ahead and manually specify all of
the settings and the steps one by one.
For the sake of longevity.
In this demo, I'm gonna pick simple execution,
and you can see we have input parameters that I need to fill out.
So we need to pick the instance I d of the EEC two
instance that we want to make an image of.
So if you have them already in a list somewhere,
you can populate this string here.
Or you can toggle this little interactive picker so you'll see
that we have one instance running right now.
I'm gonna select that instance and you can see it's
populated now at the top of this little section and then
we have a couple more parameters.
We have no reboot.
So if we want, we can skip the reboot phase of creating an image.
And if we set true, that means no reboot will occur.
So let's go ahead and do that now and then we specify our
role that we want this automation to assume.
Now I'm gonna select one that was set up previously.
And then you can also see that we can specify tags.
So weaken group in filter our results.
Now, one last thing before we execute this is if you open up the Seelye section,
it gives you the command that's needed in order to execute this.
So if I wanted to, I could do see a lie,
and it auto populates this information for me.
This is a neat little feature, and it's often overlooked.
So I'm gonna go ahead.
I'm gonna click on execute and you'll notice I actually get a failed status.
And I'm guessing this is gonna be because of some permissions.
So if I go in here to the step, i d.
Where it failed, There we go.
Yep.
It cannot create the image.
So let me really quickly.
I'm gonna pause this clip, and then once I edit, my role will resume.
Okay, So I edited my role and gave it easy to permissions.
Let's go ahead and I want to rerun this execution,
so I'm gonna go back to automation.
We're going to select execute again.
I'm gonna choose the same document,
and I'll fill in the exact same information as we did before.
So instance I d.
We set this to true and I'm gonna pick that same rule.
Now click on Execute, and we'll see that it's pending now.
So what I'll do is I'll refresh a couple of times and
I'll go ahead and pause the clip here.
Once again, we'll let this run and when it's done,
will resume and we'll dive into it.
Okay, so that took a couple of minutes.
But you can see we have a success status now.
It took the create image action.
And then there's a step name and once again will dissect
these a little bit deeper later on.
But if you notice, we can check the input that we provided and the output.
So what it did is it gave us the image I d.
That was created from this step.
So now if I go too easy too and I load the AM eyes,
I should see this am I here and there you go.
Right there.
I dio so 5445 5445 So it is the I D.
That was just created,
and you'll see that it automatically created in AM I name for us as well,
and we'll discuss how this was done here later on.
So that's how you can execute an automation with a
simple Siris of clicks or a CLI command.
This allowed us with the click of a button to shut an image down,
snapshot an image or create an image from it.
Name that image and make it available,
and then reboot that server back up and make sure that it comes up successfully.
Now, when we get into the shared resource is section of this course,
you're going to see the amount of tasks that you can perform and
how you can use this in your own daily work.
It really opens up the door for a lot of automation for tasks,
so you can free your time up to do something a little bit bigger and
better outside of patching and operational tasks.
So with that, we're going to go ahead and wrap up this automation section.
When we picked back up in the next clip, we're going to start looking at change calendar and maintenance windows