[Autogenerated] Okay, Welcome back.
Let's dive into instances and nodes.
This section is going to be broken up into several clips
because otherwise it would be a little lengthy,
and it be hard to follow after a certain time.
So let's knock out a few of these capabilities in this first clip.
The 1st 1 I want to talk about is compliance Now.
Compliance allows us to scan our instances which need to be managed instances,
and we'll talk about those here coming up in this clip.
But we can scan these four compliance and configuration and consistency.
So a collects and aggregates data for us to view from our
account and even other accounts and regions.
So it allows for a central pane of glass in a central view
into what's going on in our environments.
The first thing we see at the top here is we have our compliance filtering.
So what do we want to see?
We can look at Type Patch Group, which will talk about here in a little while,
or even the famous resource group so you can see it pulls up our prod.
Web resource is resource group in that same instance, now, in the middle here.
It gives us a summary of our compliance.
So based on some config rules and some patch manager rules,
and we'll look at ST Manager and Patch manager here a little bit later on,
it scans these instances to say, Hey, are they compliant?
Are they noncompliant?
Are they critical?
High, medium, low, etcetera.
So they have several categories that they can fall into.
Now we have one instance in its compliant,
and you could see that here at the bottom.
So if I click on this, it will bring us to our managed instances tab.
Now, before we dive into this, let me go back.
And if we select this instance here, you can see the I.
D of the compliance check, the compliance type,
the severity which is non existent, and then some other details.
And if I click on this, this is going to bring us to state manager.
Now, don't worry about this yet.
We'll talk about it here in the upcoming clips,
but I wanted to show you how you can get there very quickly
and what it relates to or what it's referring to when you see
that I d let me close this out.
I'll go back to my compliance screen.
And when we click this instance, it brings us to our managed instant screen.
So this is a good jump point in to manage instances.
Now, manage instances are machines configured for use with systems manager.
So they have the s s M agent running on them,
which is required, and they're connecting toe S s M and reporting status.
So this instance here D six FD one.
If I go to this instance,
you'll see I have a role associated with it easy to S s M user.
So this is very important.
Your role has to have permissions,
assuming you're using easy to so that it can successfully be
granted authorisation to access systems manager.
Now, I set this one up with way too many permissions,
but this was easier just to show you do not set it
up for Amazon S S m full access.
If you do not need to follow the principle of least privilege.
So with that role assigned to this instance here,
that's what's allowing us toe essentially have an online status.
It reports the different attributes of this instance,
and it gives us shortcuts to the instance and configure ALS.
Now,
a neat feature here is we can actually auto update
that S s m agent on these instances, if we wanted to,
I won't do that here, but this is very handy.
So now if I go into here and I've you are managed instance
you can see we get our descriptions.
It gives some attributes that we configured.
We'll skip inventory really quickly.
You can see we can view our tags, the associations,
which is what we just looked at when we checked out state manager.
And again, we'll talk about that coming up.
There's patch.
So what kind of patches and updates are installed and
needed in which ones aired out?
I haven't done any patching yet, so we don't see any.
And then we have configuration compliance, so isn't compliant or not.
And when was the last check?
Now let's jump back here to inventory,
and this is going to jump to our next in last capability
of this clip the inventory capability.
You'll see that we can collect inventory of our instances so we
can see what's installed and you'll see there are tons of
capabilities and options that we can choose.
We can see a W West components.
And here's the S S M agent.
We can even view network interfaces all from this one dashboard.
This is an awesome capability that systems Manager
provides for operational management.
If this was a Windows instance,
we could view the registry details for the registry on that instance.
It's really sweet.
So what I'll do is I'll go ahead and go over here to inventory.
And let's just talk about this really quickly.
Now, when you get here, you'd have to set up your inventory.
So let's just act like we're gonna do that here.
I would give it a name we can specify are targets,
so weaken select all managed instances.
You can specify a tag, or you can manually select him from a instance picker.
Now I'll do all we define a schedule.
So how often do we collect data?
And currently, 30 minutes is the lowest you can go, so I'll leave that at 30.
But if we wanted to, you can see weaken,
specify several days or if we wanted to every so many hours.
Now I'll do minutes and then let's check out these parameters.
So this is where if we look back and managed
instances here and I go to inventory, this is where all of these air coming from.
So in inventory, we would define what we want to collect.
Now, let's just assume I'm only working with Lennox instances,
So I'm gonna get rid of all of these windows specific components and parameters,
so I'll leave the other stuff.
You can see we can sink our inventory logs to an S three
bucket for compliance and auditing.
So if I wanted to, I can enter a bucket,
name and prefix to store these execution logs,
and then I would click set up inventory.
Now, I've already done this, so I'm gonna cancel out.
I'll go back to inventory, and after your data is collected,
this is what you would see.
Something similar to this you can see we have are managed
instances that show which ones have inventory enabled.
It shows our components that were collecting the different applications,
etcetera, etcetera.
So it's showing us all of those different parameters that we specified.
Now, if I go to detailed view,
this is where we can use a little bit more complex data.
Analytic tools like a FINA and glue to perform data sinks on our instance types.
Now let's just go ahead and go through this.
I'm not going to create one, but we would give it a name.
We would type the bucket that we want.
We would do a prefix if we wanted to specify which region
that buckets in and then we can encrypt.
This is, well, we would create it.
And then we could have a resource Data Sync set up so we can
view inventory data from multiple sources.
Now,
last thing before we wrap up this settings now settings is
where we can view our inventory associations.
So the one we just created today is right here,
and you can see the different description and attributes that go along with it.
There's a description.
There's resource is our parameters that we specified targets,
versions and execution history, and you'll notice when we followed this I d.
We ended up in state manager,
so I'm not going to cover any more of state manager in this clip.
Let's go ahead.
This is a good breaking point in the next clip will pick up with hybrid activations