[Autogenerated] Okay, welcome back.
So let's talk about hybrid activations.
So what this capability does is that it allows us to set up
servers and V EMS in a hybrid environment,
which is very common in enterprise environments.
And we can actually set up our instances or should say,
RV,
EMS and servers that we have on premise as managed instances reachable from AWS.
So what we would do here is we can create an activation.
We can give it a description.
The total number of servers that we want to register.
You can see the max is 1000 but that's changeable if
we go ahead and change are setting, but this will incur some costs.
So keep that in mind.
The next thing we do is we specify a role that allows us
to create those managed instances, and we can set an activation expiry date.
So if we wanted to expire activations at a certain time,
we could do that to verify that no one else will
activate after that point in time.
And then finally, we can also specify a default instance name.
So if required,
weaken set that I'll leave it blank since it's optional and
then what I would do is I click create activation and this
gives us an activation I d.
So if you look at the top AWS provides a temporary output,
it gives us an activation code, and then it gives us an activation.
I d Now how we would use these is we would install the s s M agent
on our virtual machines or on premise servers.
And then we would run through the install command, which will look at here.
And we provide that information as we're configuring r s
s m agent on our hybrid instances.
So if I go here and I go to manually install this is where we can
actually go through and you can see we install the rpm,
we start it, etcetera.
So this is easy, because this is E.
C.
Two.
But how it differs is that E.
C two uses roles for permission in our on premise hybrid would
use these activation code and I ds in order to essentially
authenticate with systems manager and say,
Hey, I know the secret password.
So go ahead and add me to your managed instance groups,
and then you can start running, run commands and automation is on me.
So if I view the details here,
you can see if we had registered instances with that,
I d.
They would show the number here.
Now,
I'm not going to do that because that's a little bit more
in depth in this course will cover.
But the documents provided do a great job of walking you through installing
this agent and setting it up for hybrid environments.
You can see they have,
ah hybrid environment section here with all of the steps
that are required for setting that up.
So if this is something you need for your environment,
be sure to check this out and walk through these steps.
So let me go and close that.
And the next thing I want to talk about is session manager.
So this is an awesome capability.
Honestly,
One of the top capabilities offered by Systems manager session
manager allows us to connect to our Windows and Linux instances
via an agent as opposed to RTP or ssh.
So it eliminates the need for a jump server or a bastion host.
So this is really cool, and it's a very big positive for security posture,
improvement in.
A lot of security teams love using this.
So for a quick start guide, I would click on start session.
You would select the instance that you want to connect to I would start it.
And what this is doing is it's loading a connection via the agent in my consul.
There you go.
You can see my session idea at the top.
The instance were connected to and then I get a prompt.
So now I'm in that instance within, Easy to.
And I connected via an agent.
I didn't have to ssh in.
So let's go ahead.
And I want to curl that metadata your l That's local on instances
and you'll see that we get the instance I d.
Right here.
That matches the instance I d in the consul.
So we verify they were connected to that instance and
we did it using the s s M agent.
So now if I go in here, I go into a bar log.
If I list Amazon here, there's an s s M directory.
So if I go into S S m, we can actually view our agent log within this directory.
So let me go ahead and actually tail this log and you can see
right there s SM session worker and it shows our session I d right
there and then how it's connected in all of the errors that come
from some of the connections.
Now, also, to build on this as a Sino,
you can see that we also had an association come through,
and it's saying that the next one will occur at this particular time.
So this relates to that inventory association that we looked at previously.
So let's go ahead and wrap up this.
I'll terminate our session on click.
Yep.
Terminate And then let's just look at our session history.
There you go.
We see our unique session I d.
Whoever did it So my role that I assumed what instance it was when it
started when it ended and what status it's in now,
Quickly, let's just look at preferences.
And this is where we can edit our preferences for default
sessions so we can use the default and use the credentials of
the s S M user on the instance, which is what we saw in that log.
Or we can enable run as support and specify a user or role to use
with a user name within our operating system.
We can also enable kms encryption for our session data.
So any data transmitted between us and the instance would be encrypted.
With a kms key, we can write our session output toe s three.
Now, this is why I hadn't aired because I didn't have a bucket set up for this.
But we could output log files to say, Hey, who was doing what?
And what time were they doing it?
And they could be stored in a centralized security bucket for auditing Later on,
we could encrypt it as well, and we can give it a prefix specific to our needs.
Now, the last tidbit here I want to touch on is the cloudwatch logs.
And this allows us to push log data to cloudwatch in order to
collect logs as if they were normal application logs.
Which makes sense because it's a connection like ssh.
And we can log that data in either set metric filters on them or just
export them for auditing and collection Later on,
Let me go ahead and cancel, and that will wrap it up for session.
Manager and let's move on to run.
Come in Now run command allows us to perform remote commands on
servers with a click of a button from Systems Manager.
So let's just demo this out.
I click on Run a command and we get a list of command documents now.
We'll talk about documents later on.
These are very important to understand how they work,
but I already know what I want to do.
So let me find this run Shell script document will use the default version,
and then what this is doing is it's running a shell script
or command on our targeted instance.
So let's test this out.
If I go ahead and I specify a shell script here,
let me go ahead and echo a value into a temporary file,
and then we'll verify that worked.
All right, so I'm just simply echoing, Hello, plural site.
Peeps toe a temporary file in temp, and it's called success.
Now.
If we wanted to, I could specify a working directory.
So where do we want to start working from?
We specify a time out, so a one hour to fall,
but you can go all the way up to 48 hours.
And then we specify our targets so we can go buy tags
we can do manually or once again.
Hopefully you're starting to see the pattern here.
We can choose a resource group so I could perform this command on our prod
Resource group and specify what kind of resource it ISS.
Now, I'm gonna go ahead and do manually,
just so this doesn't mess up because I haven't gone
back and cleaned up some of my mess.
But normally you would want to do resource groups or tags based on your needs.
So you might do development based servers than test based servers and then,
finally, production.
That's a general work flow.
So I select my instance, I can give a comment and a time out for the command.
I can set a rate control so I can specify either a static target or a
percentage for both concurrency and air thresholds.
And then we configure our output actions so we can write thes
toe S three for logging and tracking purposes.
So that way we can view it later.
Now, I'm gonna skip this step,
but it's important to know that you can actually do this.
We can also send it to cloudwatch logs,
which is similar to what we just looked at.
So I could specify a log group toe output.
These log files, too.
I can configure our SMS notifications to give me status is on what's
going on and then here at the bottom that give you a seal I shortcut
that you can copy and paste once again.
This is a often overlooked thing, and it's pretty cool.
So I'll click on Run and I actually left this enabled.
Sorry, let me go ahead and de Select that.
I'll click on Run and there we go.
So now it's in progress and what I'll do is I'll were fresh and there we go.
That was pretty quick.
So you can see we targeted our instance.
It was successful.
We see our description and parameters.
And if I click on my instance here, it brings us to a details for that I d.
Of that execution now.
There was no output because we didn't specify any,
but if there were, we could see it here.
Somebody go back,
and one last thing I want to show is which is a new and helpful feature is
we can rerun this command or we can copy it to a new one.
So these are really quick shortcuts to allow us to
rerun these commands on demand.
It used to be where you have to go back in and start a new run command and go
through the entire process each time you wanted to run it.
Now, let's just verify that worked.
I'm gonna go back to session manager and let's start a
session on that instance and let's verify that it actually
worked and created that temporary file.
So I'm logged in once again with my session.
And if I go to temp and I list there it is success.
So if I cat success Hello, plural site, peeps.
There you go.
It created that file that we worked with using that run
command from within systems manager itself.
We did not even have to interact with the operating system at all.
We just utilized the Amazon s s M agent that was installed on this instance.
So that's another good stopping point.
We've covered hybrid activations at a high level.
We talked about session manager and it's uses and
we just looked at run commands,
which allow us to execute commands on instances utilizing the agent
as opposed to a having to connect via ssh or RTP.
So let's go ahead and wrap this clip up.
And in the final clip of this capability section will look at ST Manager, Patch manager and distributor.