Let's now write some code
in order to get a better understanding
of what happens in the event loop.
So just like before, to get started
with the coding part of this section,
go ahead and grab the starter files
for this section, copy them somewhere,
and then open up the project in your code editor.
So I have it here on the desktop,
and in my VSCode, and all we have here to start
is this test-file.txt, and so I'm gonna create
a new file here, and I'm gonna call it the event-loop.js.
Alright, now it is actually extremely difficult
to simulate the event loop properly,
because we can't really put many callbacks
in all the callback queues that we
talked about before all at the same time, right.
That situation happens when for example
a lot of requests are coming into your app,
but here locally, that's just very hard to replicate.
But anyway, we will still do some very interesting
experiments using some of the stuff
that we learned in the last video.
And what we're gonna do is to write a bunch
of lines of code, and then try to figure out
in which order they should be executed
in the event loop, and analyze if the results
that we get actually make sense.
So let's start by writing a setTimeout,
so basically in order to set a timer,
and I'm using an arrow function here,
and the only thing that I'm gonna do
is to log to console some string,
so console.log, timer one finished,
and I want this to expire right after zero seconds.
Okay, give it a save, and then you see
that it actually corrected this string here,
so it changed this quotes, and added the semicolon,
and that's because of the Prettier
extension that we installed before.
Now I'm not gonna configure it here,
because for this small example,
that's not really necessary, okay.
So that is setting a timer, then let's also use
setImmediate, so remember that from the last video.
Okay, now I'm not gonna explain a lot here,
for now let's write this code,
and then analyze what happens, okay.
So setImmediate, and just like the other timer,
it receives a callback function.
And all we're gonna do is to write
immediate one finished, and this one doesn't have
any time, because it's not necessary
because as the name says, it is immediate.
Then another thing that we want to do
is to read this file here, and then pass
a callback function, okay, so the first thing
is that we have to require the correct module, so FS,
and now fs.readFile, and we want text-file.txt,
and then something to happen.
And just like before, let's just say here,
in this case I/O finished, alright.
So I/O because this callback here
is actually related to a I/O task,
which actually gets it's own phase in the event loop, right.
And then finally, let's just add a console.log here,
saying well, hello from the top level code.
Okay, and so top level code, because it's actually
the only one that is not inside of any callback.
So in this very small example that we have for now,
let's try to figure out what should happen first.
Well, remember that the first step
when we load a module is that it's top level code
gets executed, so right away we should see
this console.log here, right, only then later
we should see the other logs coming from
these other callbacks, because these callbacks
will actually run in the event loop.
So let's try to see if that's actually the case,
and then analyze it a bit better even.
So opening up the console here, and again,
I'm doing that by using terminal,
or actually in the view, so this terminal here, alright.
So note, event-loop.js, or actually
before we do so, I need to fix this typo here,
so it's test file, not text file.
Okay, but now we're ready to run this command,
and the results are in, so the first log
that we have here is hello from the top level code,
and that was expected, right, because
this is a code that gets executed immediately.
Then after that, we have these three outputs,
but they are actually in no particular order,
and that's because this code here,
so this code, is actually not in an I/O cycle,
so it's not running inside of the event loop,
because it's not running inside of any callback function.
Okay, so in your computer, you might actually see
this log here before this one,
and then this one here is only the last one
because this kind of big file here
takes some time to read, and so it's
probably always gonna be the last one.
So again, at this point, the order of these three here
doesn't have anything to do with the event loop,
because they're actually not running
inside the event loop just yet.
For that, we will have to move them,
or at least move these two here, inside a callback function.
And so, for that we're gonna use this one here actually.
So let me put it here, and say timer two and timer two here,
or immediate two, and I'm also gonna add another timer here,
so timer three, and this one is gonna run
for three seconds, so that is 3000 milliseconds.
So let's now try the result of this one.
But before we do that, let's actually think
why right after all the code before had run,
the program then exited and went back to the prompt here.
So remember how Node.js decides if it should continue
running the event loop, well it does so
by asking if there is still any time running
in the background, and if so, it will not finish,
and if there is still a pending timer,
well then it's not gonna exit the program.
But if there's not, which was the case
in the first example here, then it immediately
exits the program, okay, but now we actually
have one timer here, so this one will run
for three seconds, and so let's try
to figure out what happens here.
Okay, so you see that it's not exiting,
and only now, after timer three has finished,
it did then exit the application.
Okay, so let's actually just see that again,
so all these logs timers running, timer finished,
and so it exited the application.
Now about these results here, let's actually make
this here a bit easier to see,
and add just a small separator here.
Okay, clean this, okay.
So these four ones here are the outputs
that were not really running in the event loop,
but these three here were actually coming
out of the event loop, so let's now analyze these results.
Now, if you'll remember the diagram
from the previous lecture, you will probably have thought
that the timer, so timer two here,
should actually finish before the setImmediate,
because in the diagram, it actually appeared first
right at the top of the event loop.
So we have to set timeout here with zero,
which should kind of be the same as setImmediate, right.
So why does setImmediate actually
appear before the setTimeout?
Well, there's something that I didn't really explain
in the last video, because I didn't want to make it
even more confusing, and that is that the event loop
actually waits for stuff to happen in the poll phase.
So in that phase where I/O callbacks are handled.
So when this queue of callbacks is empty,
which is the case in our fictional example here,
so we have no I/O callbacks, all we have
is these timers, well then the event loop
will wait in this phase until there is an expired timer.
But, if we scheduled a callback using setImmediate,
then that callback will actually be executed
right away after the polling phase,
and even before expired timers, if there is one.
And in this case, the timer expires right away,
so after zero seconds, but again, the event loop
actually waits, so it pauses in the polling phase.
And so that setImmediate callback
is actually executed first, so that is the whole reason
why we have this immediate here after we have the timers.
Okay, and I know this sounds very confusing,
and I completely agree, but really
that's just the way Node.js works.
And now let's make this even a little bit more confusing,
and add the process.nextTick that
we talked about also in the last lecture.
So we say process.nextTick, and then just like before,
we simply pass it a callback function.
And again, I just wanna log to console,
and I'm gonna say process.nextTick.
So what do you think will happen in this case?
Go ahead and make a guess, and once you're ready
you can then run this, so let's do that.
Save it here first, run it, and so here we go.
So the results are again in, and now the first callback
that was executed was actually this function here.
So that's why we have process.nextTick
right in the first one.
So why was this callback function of process.nextTick
the first one of all of them to be executed?
Well, remember that nextTick is part
of the microtasks queue, which get executed
after each phase, so not just after one entire tick.
And so what happened here is that this callback function
actually ran before the phase where this callback function
here ran, and the phase before that, okay.
Now nextTick is actually really a misleading name,
because a tick is actually an entire loop,
but nextTick actually happens before the next loop phase,
and not the entire tick, so that's what I was saying before.
Then on the other side, setImmediate would make you think
that it's callback would be executed immediately,
but it actually doesn't, right, so setImmediate
actually gets executed once per tick,
while nextTick gets executed immediately.
And so their two names should actually be switched.
They should be the other way around,
and this can cause a lot of confusion,
so it's best to just always stick to one of them,
and that's usually setImmediate and not process.nextTick.
Now anyway, as I mentioned in a last video,
these mechanisms are actually more for pretty advanced
use cases, which is why we will
probably not use them in our project.
But if you want to learn more about them,
you can always read the official Node documentation.
Okay, so with this we have simulated
some aspects of the event loop,
but to finish, I want to just quickly
introduce something about thread pool as well,
and for that we're gonna do a more complex operation
that will actually be offloaded to the thread pool,
and take a look at how long these operations take to run,
and how we can change the thread pool
size that we talked about before.
So we're gonna use some cryptography here
to basically encrypt a password.
So that's a new package we hadn't used before,
and it's called Crypto, but I mentioned earlier
that actually, all the functions from this package,
they will be offloaded automatically by the event loop
to the thread pool, and so that's
what we're gonna test out now.
And let's use this now, so crypto.pb,
so we're gonna use an encryption function called pbkdf2,
so kind of a weird name, and now we pass in
the secret string, which let's just say password,
then we need a string to solve the passwords,
and the implementations here don't really matter,
so for now I'm not gonna go into any detail
of how this works, we're gonna do that later, okay,
so here we just need the key length,
so this number here is just for the number
of iterations, then this is the key length,
and then finally the algorithm,
which is gonna be used to encrypt the password.
So these numbers will simply increase
the time it takes for the encryption.
Okay and then finally, it also takes a callback function,
and all I'm gonna do here is to do another console.log,
and just say password encrypted.
Now, for the purpose of this demonstration,
I actually want to show you how much time
each of these operations take, so what we're gonna do
is to basically define a variable in the beginning,
set it to date.now, so that is the current date
in milliseconds, and then here, all we have to do
is to log not only the string, but also date.now,
which will be the date at this point in milliseconds,
minus the start, and so that will then give us
the amount of milliseconds that have passed
in order to do this calculation.
Okay, so let's try it out, give it a save,
and run it again, and so here you see
that it took 1855 milliseconds,
so almost two seconds to encrypt this password.
Okay, but now let's actually duplicate
this code, or actually I want four instances
of this to show you something.
So if we run this now, it should probably take
approximately the same amount of time,
and yeah it does, so it was 1.8 seconds,
now it's 2.2 seconds, which is quite similar.
Okay, and remember that I told you in one of
the earlier lectures, that by default
the size of the thread pool is four,
so there are four threads doing the work
at the same time, and so that's why
these four password encryptions
take approximately the same time
and happen basically all at the same time.
But we can actually change that thread pool size.
So, let me show you how we do that,
and we do that by saying process.env,
and that's an environmental variable,
and again we're gonna talk more about that later,
and UV, which stands for LibUV,
threadpool size, so if we set this to one,
we will only have one thread in our thread pool.
So let's try that again, and so let's see what happens now.
So you see that they all take much longer to calculate.
Basically, they are calculated one after the other.
So this one the first, then this one here takes
double the time, and again that's because
this one can only start as soon as
the first one is completed, and the same
with the third and the fourth one.
Now let's say we change it to two,
then we should see the first two ones
with the same time, and exactly,
the second two also with a similar time.
So that makes sense, right.
Just for the sake of completion here,
now the same with three, so these three
have a similar time, and then the last one.
Alright, so this is how the thread pool works basically,
so I decided to not only focus on the event loop,
but also to give you an overview, a very quick one,
of the thread pool and how we can change
the thread pool size, okay, keep in mind
that this code here is actually still
asynchronous, because we passed in a callback function.
Okay, and we could actually use the synchronous version,
but that would then block the event loop.
Wanna see that?
So let me very quickly show that to you as well,
so that one was not really planned,
but let's do it anyway, 'cause it's
very interesting to see that I think.
Okay, so that will work like this.
We use again the sync version of the same function,
which a note, is many times available.
Remember we have the same for the read file,
so we have read file, which accepts a callback,
and we have read file sync, which is the synchronous version
which doesn't accept any callback, so just like this.
So this one will then encrypt the password,
block the code execution, and then move on to the next line,
which will then log this here to the console.
So let's now duplicate this here.
That was too much, get rid of this one here,
and so now these four password encryptions
will no longer run in the event loop.
And so they will no longer be offloaded to the thread pool.
Okay, and so now even if we have the thread pool size
of four, let's see what happens.
So you see, they happen completely in a synchronous way.
So one after the other, and what is even worse,
is that all of these timers here,
even nextTick and the immediate one,
only appeared after the password encryptions happened.
So this really was blocking the entire execution,
even if this timer here, for example this one here,
was finished after zero seconds,
and this one after three seconds,
but they all have to wait seven seconds
until all of these password encryptions here
were finally ready, again because they were not running
inside the event loop, but these were.
And so they were basically working in the background
and could only be picked up by the event loop
when they were ready, right after these four
password encryptions, so this one was
another great example of seeing the
code blocking and event loop all in action.
Okay, so that was enough for one lecture,
I hope that you found it interesting,
and I'll see you right in the next one.