As the last part in this section,
let's talk about how NODE.JS modules actually work
behind the scenes.
First of all in the NODE.JS module system
each JavaScript file is treated as a separate module.
And we already played around a bit with modules
in the intersection,
'specially by using the require function
and exporting data from modules.
So that's the fundamentals of Common JS modules
which is the module system that node uses.
Because it works especially well on the server.
Now, there's also the native ECMA script
or ES module system that
you might already be familiar with,
'specially if you took my JavaScript course,
or if you have been writing JavaScript
on the front end lately.
This ES module system that I was talking about was developed
to work in the browser using the import export syntax.
So, I just wanted to make it clear that these are
two different module systems that you will see
in different situations,
so don't be confused.
There have also been attempts to implement
native ES modules in NODE.JS,
'specially using file extensions
like .mjs.
But so far, it's not really become
a popular thing to use.
So unless you're watching this course
in the far future,
you will probably always be using
the Common JS system with node.
Now, you might be wondering why in NODE.JS
each and every module actually gets access
to the require function in order
to import modules in the first place.
Right?
I mean, it's not a standard JavaScript function.
So where does it come from?
And how exactly does it work behind the scenes?
Well, let's find out.
So the question here is,
what happens each time that we require
a module by calling the require function
with a module name, is the argument.
As a very broad overview,
the following steps are executed behind the scenes.
First, the path to the required module
is resolved and the file is loaded.
Then a process called wrapping happens
after that,
the module code is executed
and the module exports are returned.
And finally the entire module gets cached.
So let's now look at each step in more detail.
First off, how does node know which file to load
when we require a module?
Because remember, we can actually load
three different kinds of modules.
Node's core modules,
our own modules or third party modules from npm
like express which is the node framework that we're
going to use throughout most of the course.
So this process is known as resolving the file path.
And here is how it works.
When the require functions receives the module name
as its input,
it will first try to load a core module with that name.
Like for example, the http module.
It will automatically find a path to that module
and then load it.
Now if the path starts with a dot,
or two dots,
it means that it's a developer module.
Because we indicate the relative path to our file.
So node will try to load that file,
but if there is no file with that name,
then it will look for a folder instead
and load index.js if it's in that folder.
So in this example,
it will try to load lib/controller.js.
Remember that we can drop the dot js
when requiring a module.
In case there is no file at this path,
it will then, instead, try to open
index.js from the lib/controller folder instead.
Make sense?
And finally, if the required module
is neither a core module,
nor a developer module,
node will assume it's a module from npm.
And remember, on a module that we load from npm,
we actually don't need to write the path when we require it.
Just the module name,
just the way it works on a core module.
So these third party modules are stored
in a node module folder,
so node will step into that folder and try to find
a module there and then load it.
And of course, if the file can't be found anywhere,
then an error is thrown and the execution
of the app is stopped.
Moving on, after the module is loaded,
the module's code is wrapped into a special function
which will give us access to a couple of special objects.
So this step is where the magic happens.
It is here where we get the answer to the question,
where does the require function actually come from
and why do we have access to it?
It's because the nodejs run time,
takes the code off our module
and puts it inside the immediately invoked
function expression, or IIFE that you can see here.
So node does actually not directly
the execute the code that I rewrite into a file,
but instead, the wrapper function that will contain
our code in it's body.
It also passes the experts require module,
file name and dir objects into it.
So that is why in every module
we automatically have access
to stuff like the require function.
So these are basically like global variables
that are injected into each and every module.
Now by doing this, node achieves two very important things.
First, of course, is giving developers access
to all these variables we just talked about,
which is very helpful.
Second, it keeps the top-level variables that we
define in our modules private.
So it's scoped only to the current module
instead of leaking everything into the global object.
So imagine for a second,
that we declared a variable x in one of our modules
and then included an npm module that also used
a variable called x.
Without this mechanism,
our own variable would then get overridden
and the entire app would just not work.
So each module having its private scope
is absolutely crucial and is achieved
through this clever trick of wrapping our code
into this special function.
Let's now take a quick look at each object
that our module gets.
First the require function,
which we already know about.
Then, there is a module object,
which is just a reference to the current module
and which for us is most important
when it comes to exporting data.
The same applies to the export's object
which we're gonna discuss in a moment.
Finally, there are the convenience
variables file name and dir name
which simply contain the absolute path
to the current module's file
as well as the current directory name.
And that is how the wrapping step of loading a module works.
Next up, the code in the module,
or to be more precise,
in the module's wrapper function,
actually gets executed by the NODE.JS runtime.
So, nothing fancy here.
Up until this point,
the require function has been called with a module name
as the argument the path
to the module's file has been resolved into file loaded,
all the code has been wrapped into the wrapper function
which has then been executed.
Now, it's time for the require function
to actually return something.
And what it returns is the exports of the required module.
These exports are stored in the module.exportsobjects.
It might look a little bit like this.
So, again, in each module we can export variables,
which will, in the end be returned by the require function.
And we do that by assigning variables to module.exports
or simply to exports
where it is just a pointer to module.export.
We will do this in practice in the next video,
because I know this sounds kind of confusing
when I just say it like this.
Anyway, here's what you need to know
about when to use module.export or just export.
So if all you want to do is to export one single variable,
like one class or one function,
you usually use module.exports and set it equal
to the variable that you want to export.
Just like in this example.
On the other hand,
if you're looking to export multiple named variables
like multiple functions, for example,
then you should create these
as properties of the export object.
For example, if we were doing a calculator module
you could create exports.add,
exports.multiply,
exports.divide and so on and so forth.
Makes sense?
Again, we're gonna do this in the next video
and it will make more sense to you by then.
This is effectively how we export and import data
from one module into the other.
Of course, this is also why we usually assign
the result of a require function called to a new variable.
So that we can save the returned exports.
Now, just to finish this video real quick,
the last step is that modules are actually cached
after the first time they are loaded.
What this means is that if you require the same module
multiple times, you will always get the same result.
And the code in the modules is actually only executed
in the first call.
In subsequent calls,
the result is simply retrieved from cache.
Perfect.
So I hope that all the logic behind
how to work with modules
doesn't really look like magic anymore.
It's really important to know how all of this works,
in order to become a great,
and above all,
a more independent NODE.JS developer.