Let's now implement a route handler
for post requests so that we can actually add a Natour
to our data set.
So just like with the doGET() request handler,
let's start by adding a new route.
So app.post this time, and remember
now we use post so the post method here,
because that's the kind of request that we want to handle.
So requests that are made with the http post verb right?
V1
and tours.
Just as we talked about in the REST API lecture,
the URL is actually exactly the same.
No matter if we want to get all the tours,
or if we want to create a new tour,
the URL is exactly the same.
Then only thing that changes is the http method
that we used for doing these requests.
To get all the tours and post to create a new tour,
then in here, our typical call-back function
where we get access to the request
and to the respond object so that we can get some data
from the request and send back an appropriate response.
Now remember that with a post request,
we can send data from the client to the server, right?
This data is then ideally available on the request.
The request object again is what holds all the data,
all the information, about the request that was done.
If that request contains some data that was sent,
that data should be on the request, right?
Now out of the box, Express does not put that body data
on the request, and in order to have that data available,
we have to use something called middleware.
We are gonna talk in great detail about middleware
in a couple of lectures, but for now,
in order to make this work, we need to include
a simple middleware here at the top of the file.
So actually, right here.
What we need to do, is to say app.use
then express
.json
Okay, and that's it.
So again, this [express.json] here is middleware.
And middleware is basically a function that can modify
the incoming request data.
It's called middleware because it stands between,
so in the middle of the request and the response.
It's just a step that the request goes through
while it's being processed.
And the step the requests go through, in this example
is simply that the data from the body is added to it.
So it's added to the request object
by using this middleware.
We use app.use in order to use middleware like this.
And again, we will talk a lot more about middleware
a bit later in this section.
For now, just know that this is how we use middleware.
All the details will then follow later.
So for now, just to start, I want to actually show you
the data from the body in the console,
just to verify that it actually works, so req.body.
Again, body is the property that is gonna be available
on the request, because we used that middleware
a couple of moments ago.
So we want to log[req.body] to the console
and then we also need to send back a response.
So res.send and for now just some place holder here.
Just 'Done' okay.
So we always need to send back something
in order to finish the so-called request/response cycle,
which again we're gonna learn a bit more about later
in this section.
So let's now test this out, and create a new request
for the post.
Now here in postman, we can do something really nice
which is to save all of these requests.
I'm gonna start by creating a new collection,
which I will call Natours.
New collection.
Now I will save this request inside that collection.
So this one is Get all the Tours.
Put it into Natours, and save.
So now we have our Get requests right here.
Well let's now copy this one right here,
create a new one.
So this one is a post request.
Before doing it, I will actually also save it right
to this collection.
So Create New Tour.
Here on the left side, we now have both of our requests.
Let's now actually specify our body here,
so the data that we basically want to send to the server.
We come here to Body, and there are different ways
of doing it now, but the easiest one is to simply say,
Raw, and then Application JSON.
All we have to do here is to basically specify some JSON,
and that will then get transmitted to the server.
So the first thing we want to specify
is the name of the Tour, and you remember that in JSON,
everything has to be in quotes and actually double quotes,
not just any quotes.
Let me just call this one a Test Tour, and let's take a look
at what else we have in the tour data.
So we have the name, we have the duration,
and let's just put also the difficulty.
So I'm not going to specify all of these
because that takes way too much time.
Let's just say the duration is 10 days,
and the difficulty
is easy.
That as our body will be transmitted to the server.
So that's tested out now, hitting send
and here we get back our response, which is done, remember.
Here is the response that we sent, so done.
And you see that down here in our console,
we now have an object which is basically the JSON
that we sent in our body, right?
So perfect, it works!
It is no longer JSON, as you can see.
It is truly a JavaScript object.
Just to show you that we really needed middleware,
let's comment this one out.
Send it again.
Now no longer have the request.body, right?
That's why it's undefined now, 'cause it no longer exists.
Give it a save, send our request again,
and so now it's back.
We have our post route all set up, it's working now
and we also get access to the body,
and so what we want to do now is to actually persist
that data into this tour simple JSON file.
We're actually gonna modify this file, so that the data
is saved to our fictional database here.
This JSON file right now kind of works
as our fictional database.
So let's now take care of that.
I'm gonna go ahead and comment this one out.
So let's get started.
The first thing we need to do is to figure out the id
of the new object.
Remember, again in the lecture about REST API's,
is that when we create a new object,
we never specify the id of the object.
The database usually takes care of that.
A new object usually automatically gets it's new id.
Well in this case, we do not have any database,
and so what we're gonna do is to simply take the id
of the last object and then add +1 to that.
Let's do that very quickly,
and that's just basic JavaScript.
So newId it is tours, right?
Remember that tours, we already have the data
in this tours variable.
So that's an array of all the tour objects,
and so we want to get the last one,
which is tours.length - 1,
then the id property of that and we add + 1.
So that is the new id.
Next up, we create a new tour,
and that tour will basically be the body that we send
plus the new id that we just created.
So we can use object.assign, which basically allows us
to create a new object by merging two existing objects
together.
So the first object is gonna be
id=newId,
and then we want
request.body.
We could also had done req.body.id=newId,
but I did not want to mutate the original body object.
I just left it like this.
That is the new tour, and now what we want to do
is to push this tour into the tour array, right?
So tours, is the array of the nine tours that we have
at this point.
We say push and push the new tour in there.
That is the array which now has the new tour in it,
but of course now we have to persist that into the file.
That again is quite easy for you at this point,
so use fs.write file.
So which one should we use?
writeFile or writeFileSync?
The answer for that is very simple.
We are inside of a call-back function,
that is gonna run in the event loop.
We can never, ever block the event loop.
What we're gonna do is to use writeFile
and not to Sync in this one.
We want to pass in a call-back function
that is gonna be processed in the background
and as soon as it's ready,
it's gonna put its event in one of the event loop queue,
which is then gonna be handled
as soon as the event loop passes that phase.
Remember that from the Event Loop lecture?
Anyway, let's get the file name from up here,
because we will really override this file
so that when we restart this server,
it's then gonna be there.
So where-
right here.
So that is the file that where we want to write to.
The data that we want to write, which is tours,
and then our call-back function,
which in this case only has the error.
Here I just noticed that we need to also stringify
this object, right?
We want json in this JSON file,
and this right now is just a plain, normal JavaScript object
and so we need to convert that.
But that's again simple, already did that.
JSON.stringify
of the object.
What do we want to do as soon as the file is written?
Well, what we usually do is
to send the newly created object as the response.
Let's do that.
So response, and then as always, we start by
specifying the status code.
In this case, it's not gonna be a 200, but a 201.
So 201 which means created.
200 stands for okay, 201 stands for created,
which is exactly what happened here.
We created a new resource on a server.
So JSON, and it keeps adding this message here.
Status is again, success.
I'm not using the results property here, that we had before,
because now I'm only sending back one result.
Data is our envelope here.
Tour is new tour.
That's it!
Give it a save here, and so that format it,
or code a little bit.
Let's add some more space here.
I think we're ready to now give it a try.
We can actually create a new tour, using this data here.
So adjust this Test Tour,
and with this data, and let's wait for it.
What happened here?
Let's see, ah okay.
We have a problem that we sent a response twice basically.
So we sent a response with JSON,
and then again with .send.
That's not allowed.
That's actually why we get this error here.
So it's actually nice that it happened here,
so that you know what this standard error here means.
HTTP_HEADERS_SENT cannot set headers after they are sent
to the client.
That happens when you try to send two responses.
We need to get rid of that.
Yeah, that was the only error that we had.
That should now fix it.
Give it a try.
And indeed, here we go.
So we have our id of 10, which our code created for us,
and then the entire tour which is exactly the data
that we sent as a body in our request.
Now the thing is, that when we do get all tours here,
it will not yet show up.
If we go down here,
actually it is already here.
We have the one from before, so when we had that error,
it actually also created this tour here.
Then of course, the tour that we created with the id of 10.
So this tour here is exactly this one
that was created right now.
If we do now, Test Tour 2, with the duration of just 5.
Let's give this one a try,
and if I do get all tours, then that shows up here as well.
I said in the beginning that it wouldn't work,
so that it wouldn't show up right away,
because this only works if we restart the server.
This file,
the tour-simple.json file
where our tours are coming from,
is only read at the beginning when we start the server.
Now the thing is that each time we save something
to this JSON file, it will also reload the server.
Let me prove that to you, so if I hit now save,
then look what happens down here.
So I save it, and so you see that down here
it restarted the server.
It also formatted the code, because of prettier.
But what matters here, is that this code updated.
That's why each time we save something here
with our API, it will then immediately reload the server
and will reload the content from the file into the tours,
and we can then read that right away.
That's why we have access immediately
to all the newly created tours.
Make sense?
Well if not, please feel free to just ask your questions,
and of course Q&amp;A section, right?