Let's now completely refactor
our application that we have so far,
and create a lot of new files,
and a whole new file structure.
So remember from the last video
that we wanted to separate our routers
into different files.
And so that's gonna be the first step that we will do here.
So I'm gonna create a new folder called Routes now,
and then in there I will have one folder for tour routes
.js, and then user routes,
.js as well.
Okay, and so this is gonna be the first time
that we will really work with different modules,
okay, and actually use them in a very meaningful way.
So, let's start with the tour router.
Copy it here, then take this tour router here,
and put it here.
And so, next we need actually Express here,
because we're using that variable,
and so we need to import the Express module.
So express,
require express.
Okay, it's kind of a convention to simply call this router,
and not tourRouter.
So router, and now we will export the router,
and then import it into our main application, okay?
So, remember how we do it
when we only have one thing to export?
Well, we use module.exports,
and then put the router on there.
Give it a save, and of course, we still get some errors,
but that's because the tour router
is not defined in our main application file.
Okay, also what's not defined in this file
is all of these functions here.
Okay, so let's very quickly get them,
and put them in the router file.
At least for now, we will later create
a new file for that as well.
So it starts here.
Careful, not copying everything.
Yeah, so just like this.
And actually, I'm gonna put them before the routes.
Give it a save.
And so that should work now.
And now do the same for the user.
So get the router.
And don't worry about all these errors that we're getting.
Again, that's just because we are missing
some variables in some places.
So again, we'd express here,
then we call this here just router,
and then we export it.
Okay, and now I'm also getting the handlers.
Okay, so we can get rid of these route handlers now.
Okay, and actually this one here is missing
in our tour routes,
so this piece of code where we actually read
the tours from the JSON file.
So put that right at the top here.
And now finally, we actually need to import
the tour router and the user router
so that these routes here continue to work.
Okay, but that should be fairly easy, so let's do that.
So with the tour router,
is at require,
routes/tourRoutes.
Okay, and we don't need the JS,
and then the same for the userRouter.
So tourRoutes actually is here, the userRoutes.
Now you might be wondering why I actually called
the variables the userRoute,
but then the file is userRoutes,
and well that's because this folder here is called routes,
and so in there we have the tourRoutes and the userRoutes.
Okay, but what we actually export from that file
is simply the router, alright?
But I believe it makes more sense
to actually call this folder here Routes.
Okay, and so that's why we have this small difference
between routes and router.
Now we still get some error here,
and so fs is not defined,
so let's take that, and actually we don't need it here,
so let's put it in the tour routes right here.
We get another error.
And this time, because this folder here is now not defined,
because our dirname is now the routes.
So we need to get out of that.
So go up one folder, and then in there,
go into dev-data, data, and tour-simple.
Now don't worry about getting all these errors.
That's kind of normal when we are doing all this refactoring
'cause we're changing stuff all over the place,
so it's normal that stuff breaks.
Anyway, it's now back to working,
and so we are now in the place where we can
retest our routes here.
And indeed, it works.
The same for the users, let's suppose.
And so everything is correct.
So we have our routers now each in one different file,
and we can say that each of them
is one small sub-application.
So one tour application and one user application.
And we then put everything together in our global app file
by importing these routers,
and then mounting the routers
on the two different routes
that we have currently implemented, okay?
So again, this is where we mount our routers.
And I know that this concept
can be a bit difficult to grasp,
but don't worry about that.
The longer that you keep working on this project
and the more code you keep writing,
the clearer everything will automatically become.
For now, the most important thing to keep in mind
is that we created these different routers
for each of the resources to have a nice
separation of concern between these resources.
So basically creating one small application for each of them
and then putting everything together in one main app file,
which is of course this one.
So this app.js file that we have here
is usually mainly used for middleware declarations.
So we have all our middleware
that we want to apply to all the routes.
So in this case, we have these four middlewares here.
So one, two, three, four.
These middlewares, we want to apply it for all of the routes
and then for this route,
we want to apply the tourRouter middleware,
and for this route, we want to apply
the userRouter middleware.
Okay, so again, these two routers are actually middleware,
which is why we can use app.use in order to mount them.
Okay, and with that being said,
let's take it one step further,
and actually remove these route handlers
from the routes file.
Okay, and so let's again create a new folder here,
and this one will be called controllers, okay?
So I've been calling them route handlers,
and so it would make sense to create a handlers folder.
But later in this course,
we will start using a software architecture
called the Model View Controller,
and in that architecture, these handler functions here
are actually called controllers.
And so that's why I'm going to call the folder,
and also the files in there, controllers.
So let's now create the tourController.js,
and the userController.js.
Okay, and this will make a bit more sense
once we reach the part of the course
where we actually talk about the MVC,
or Model View Controller pattern.
Alright, so let's now take this code,
and put these handlers into the controller folder,
or file actually.
So all of this code.
It's the tourController, yeah, that's the one.
Also, we need this FS module here,
obviously at the top.
And here we go.
Now, we want to actually export all of these functions
from this module, so how do we do that?
Well, in this case we do not only have one export,
so we're not gonna use module.export,
but instead we will put all of these functions
on the exports object, okay?
And so let me select all of these,
consts, so that I can actually
replace them all at the same time.
So exports.deleteTour, and .updateTour,
createTour, getTour, and getAllTours.
Okay, so that exports everything from this file.
And so now, let's go into the tourRoutes,
and simply import them.
So const, tourController, equals require.
Okay, now we're in the routes folder here, right?
So we need to move up one level,
and then go into controllers,
and into the tourController.js.
Okay, this is not correct, and alright.
Now, remember that when we export data from a file
using the exports object.
So just like we did here.
When we then import everything into one object,
then all of the data that was on exports
is now gonna be on tourController.
And so we will have tourController.getAllTours
.createTours.getTour,
and really, all of these, okay?
So this object here will be the equivalent
of the exports that we have here.
Remember that?
And so, it's really simple.
All I have to do now is to create
tourController., and that's it.
Now I could have also used the structuring,
which I also showed you before.
So just to demonstrate,
I could have used it like this,
and then specified the exact same names that we have here.
So getAllTours, and then createTour, and all of these,
and then I could have used them directly here
without having to write tourController, and dot.
Okay, but I actually like it like this,
and I see no problem of having it like this.
So it makes it nicely visible
that all of these functions here actually come
from this tourController module.
Okay, so I saved it now, and so it should keep working,
so let's test that, and yeah, it does.
So, that's working now.
Let's actually close it up, and now the same, where is it?
Ah, here.
Now the same of course with these functions.
Put them here,
and then export all these guys.
So exports.
Yeah, so that's correct.
Now here, we just imported module,
and the same as before, we need to move up one level.
We go into controllers, and userController.
Now finally, just add that here.
Give it a save, and test it for this guy as well.
And indeed, it works.
So everything we did here was correct.
So we're starting to have a bunch of files now,
and so it's important to really get familiar,
where exactly all the different pieces
of the application are located, okay?
So just to recap, the flow goes like this.
We start receiving the request in the app.js file, right?
It will then depending on the route
enter one of the routers, so let's say the tour router,
and then depending, again, on that route,
and of the request, it will then execute
one of these controllers here,
and so these are in the tourController files.
And that's where then finally the response gets sent,
and finishing the request-response cycle.
Okay, so we have now three files,
instead of having everything just in one file.
Alright, but that's still not the end of the story,
because I'm adding one more step here.
So what I'm gonna do is to create a server.js file as well.
So server.js.
And why am I doing that?
Well, simply because it's a good practice
to have everything that is related to express in one file,
and then everything that is related to the server
in another main file.
So starting now, server.js will actually be
our starting file where everything starts,
and it's there when we listen to our server.
So let's actually go ahead and copy, or cut,
this part from here, and move it into the server.
Now of course, this module here doesn't know about app,
and so we need to import it.
And to import it, we need to first export it.
So we use module.exports,
and we export our application from this file.
Okay, and so now we have everything
that is basically the application configuration
in one standalone file.
Okay, so back in the server, let's now import that.
Require, and since it's our own module,
we need to use this ./ to say
that we're in the current folder,
and here's it's simply app.
So, simple as that.
And later on we will actually have other stuff
in this file that is not related to express,
but still related to our application.
So stuff like database configurations,
or some error handling stuff, or environment variables,
all of that stuff will live in this server.js,
which is kind of our entry point, okay?
So let's now finish the process that we have here,
because now we do no longer run nodemon app.js,
but instead, we need to run server.js.
Okay, and actually since we're doing that,
let me create an npm script for that.
Closing that guy very quick.
And so let me add here, npm start,
nodemon server.js.
Because this way, I no longer have to really know
which is the file that I actually want to run.
So all I have to write is npm start,
and there's no doubt that it's gonna work.
Otherwise, I might have to think,
hm, is it app.js, or server.js, or what?
What do we have to start here?
But like this, I don't have to think,
all I have to do is npm start, and it's gonna start.
Okay, so just like this,
and here we are back running our application.
Close that guy, and by the way, this works,
even without having nodemon installed
as our dev dependency,
because I have nodemon installed globally.
So we did that in the first section,
and hopefully you did it there as well.
If not, then go ahead and in another tab
do npm install nodemon,
so if for some reason you skipped that section,
you type npm install nodemon,
and then you can either install it globally like this,
or you can install it as a dev dependency,
like this, alright?
So just make sure that you have nodemon installed,
no matter if it's globally or as a dev dependency,
okay, in order to make this work.
So final check, just to make sure,
and want this one, and yeah, indeed.
We have our app correctly refactored.
So these were a lot of changes in one video alone,
so after you finish this one,
please go ahead and analyze everything that we did
and really try to trace a path
that a request will do inside of our app
from start to finish.
This way you will really get a feeling
of how everything here works.
And I'll see you after doing that in the next video.