Let's now learn
how to serve static files with Express.
Now what do I actually mean with static files?
Well, it's the files that are sitting in our file system
that we currently cannot access using all routes.
So, for example, we have this overview.html file
here in our public folder.
But right now there's no way that we can access this
using a browser, right?
And the same for these image files that we have here,
or the CSS or the Javascript files.
So let me show that to you,
and let me actually use the browser this time.
For now I'm copying this URL here
just to show you that it's gonna work,
obviously also in the browser.
Okay, so this is our unformatted result here,
from the same route.
But let's say that we actually want to access that HTML file
that I was just talking about.
So we can, of course, not just write
public and then, for example,
overview.html, right?
There's no way we can access this right now.
And that's simply because we didn't define any route
for this URL, right?
We do not have any handler that is associated to this route.
And so, if we actually want to access something
from our file system,
we need to use a built-in Express middleware.
So let me now show you how we can do that.
For example, after this one.
Now in this section we're actually just talking about an API
so we don't actually need to serve static files
like images or HTML, so what I just showed you.
But since this section is an introduction
to Express in general,
I also wanted to quickly show this content to you anyway.
So, as I was saying, all we have to do is
to use a simple built-in middleware
that goes like this.
Express dot static, because we wanna serve static files,
so this is an obvious name for that.
And so in here we pass the directory
from which we want to serve static files.
And in this case, I'm gonna use the public directory.
So this folder here where we have these HTML files, okay?
And actually let's use a template string here
so that I can go ahead and use the dirname variable,
then slash and public.
Give it a save and go back to the browser.
Then we will be able to open this overview.html.
Now it's not going to work in this URL here.
It actually has to be like this.
So without the public, just /overview.html.
So let's see, and it actually works.
Okay.
Now, why is that?
Why don't we need the public folder here in the URL?
Well, simply because when we open up a URL
that it can't find in any of our routes,
it will then look in that public folder that we defined.
And it sets that folder to the root.
Okay, so let's pretend that the root
is now our public folder.
So this here, and then the overview is in there.
And so that's why we have done access to it.
So in there we also have images, for example.
Let's say we wanna open image and then this pin here.
And we can do that.
So image,
pin png, and so here we go.
Here is the image.
Now what we can't do is this, because this is not a file.
This looks like a regular route,
and so Express actually tries to find a route handler
for this one, which it can't
because you didn't define anything.
All right?
So really it just works for static files.
In which case it will, again, not go into a new route,
but simply serve that file that we specified
from the public folder,
or in the folder that we specified here in this middleware.
Now take a look at the console here and see all the requests
that were actually done when we open up that page.
Let's now clear this here just so we see all the requests
that actually just come from that overview page.
So let's write again overview.html here.
And these images here are broken
and that's because this html is not supposed
to be served like this, all right?
I'm just using it now here
so that we get some visual feedback.
I'm not interested at all in the content here.
Now just take a look at all the requests
that were done for all of the assets.
So as I said right in the beginning,
for each piece that is part of the website
our server actually gets a separate request.
And you see here that most of them get this 404.
So that's why the links are then broken on the web page,
well simply because Express cannot find them in this folder.
But again, that's not the point here.
What I just wanted to show you
is how we can serve static files
from a folder and not from a route.
All right.
And so that wraps up the basic introduction to Express.
In the next two videos we will talk
about something called environment variables
and we will also set up ESlint in oral VS code.