Welcome back.
In this video you will learn all about
environment variables.
So what they are, how we set them, and how we use them.
Now this is not exactly about Express,
it really has to do with node JS development in general,
but we really need this in order to move on
in the project and so this is a good time
to talk about this.
So node JS, or Express apps,
can run in different environments.
And the most important ones are the development environment
and the production environment.
That's because depending on the environment,
we might use different databases for example,
or we might turn login on or off,
or we might turn debugging on or off,
or really all kinds of different settings that might
change depending on the development that we're in.
So again the most important ones are the development
and the production environment.
But there are other environments
that bigger teams might use.
So this type of setting that I just mentioned,
like different databases or login turned on or off,
that will be based on environment variables.
Now by default, Express sets the environment to development
which makes a lot of sense because that's what we're doing
when we start a new project.
So let's just for the sake of demonstration
take a look at that variable,
and we're gonna do that here in the server.
So remember that everything that is not related
to Express we're gonna do it outside of the app.JS file.
So we only use this one here to configuring our application.
So we only use this one in order to configure everything
that has to do with the Express application.
But the environment variables are really outside
the scope of Express.
So let's quickly do a console.log here
of app.get
and then end.
Give it a save here and down here you can see development.
Let me clear the console here, save it again,
and so here again you see development.
So that is the environment that we're currently in.
And so you see that this app.getenv will get us
the env environment variable.
So in summary, environment variables are global variables
that are used to define the environment in which
a node app is running.
So this one is set by Express,
but node JS itself actually sets a lot of environments.
Now this env variable here is actually set by Express,
but node JS itself actually also sets a lot
of environment variables.
And so let's actually take a look at those as well.
So these ones are located at process
.env.
Give it a save and so here we have a bunch
of different variables okay and I will not go through
all of them but let's just see they really
are a bunch of them,
and node uses most of them internally.
For example a task to current working directory here
in this environment variable and really a bunch
of other stuff as you can see.
For example my home folder or my login name
you see the script that we use to start this process
so really a bunch of stuff that for some reason
node JS internally needs.
Now these variables, they come from the process core module
and we're set at the moment that the process started.
And as you see,
we didn't have to require the process module right.
It is simply available everywhere automatically.
Now in Express, many packages depend on a special variable
called node N.
So it's a variable that's kind of a convention
which should define whether we're in development
or in production mode okay.
However Express does not really define this variable,
and so we have to do that manually.
And there are multiple ways in which we can do it,
but let's start with the easiest one which is
to use the terminal.
So I'm gonna finish this process here, clear it,
and so when we last started this process
we did it using npm start.
And npm start in turn stands for where is it?
So it stands for nodemon server.
And so let's copy this actually here.
So we use nodemon server.js to start the process.
But if you want to set an environment variable
for this process, we need to pre-plan that variable
to this command.
So we say nodeenv,
which is that special variable that I just talked about
equals
development.
And if I start this process now, let's take a look.
And so right now we have here node N set to development.
And so this is the result of doing this console.log
off process.env.
And so that variable that we have here actually comes
from that command.
And we can actually define even more if we wanted.
So let's just say X is 23 just for testing purposes
start the process and now you see the X environment variable
is attached to this 23 string all right.
So again many packages on npm that we use
for Express development actually depend on this
environment variable.
And so when our project is ready and we are gonna deploy it,
we then should change the node N and variable to production.
And we will do that of course once we deploy the project
by the end of the course.
So we set node N and X as environment variables,
but we can do a lot more.
And that's because we usually use environment variables
like configuration settings for our applications.
So whenever our app needs some configuration for stuff
that might change based on the environment
that the app is running in, we use environment variables.
For example we might use different databases for development
and for testing until we could define one variable
for each and then activate the right database
according to the environment.
Also we could set sensitive data like passwords
and user name using environment variables.
Now it's not really practical to always define
all of these variables in the command where we start
the application.
So imagine we had 10 environmental variables
and it would be not really practical to having
to write them out all here inside of this command.
And so instead what we do is to create a configuration file.
So let me go ahead and create
config.env.
And so env is really the convention for defining a file
which is these environment variables.
And VS code actually recognizes that and put this
configuration icon right in the file.
So let's now define this variable here
and paste it in here.
And we can also use some of this sensitive data
that I just mentioned.
So let's say the user is Jonas in lowercase
and the password is one, two, three, four, five, six.
Now as you see, these variable names they're usually always
in upper case.
So that's kind of a convention that we use.
Now in your VS code probably all the text is just white
so you have no syntax highlighting.
And I have that because they use this .env extension here.
So if you want your .env files to look nice like this
please go ahead and install that one.
So we have user password, let's also define the port
on which our app should be running.
So that's also kind of a standard variable
that is usually in a .env file like this.
And let's set this one to 8,000.
Now how do we actually connect this .env file
with our node application?
So we need some way of reading these variables
from this file and then saving them
as environment variables.
Because right now this is just a text file and node JS
has no way of knowing that these variables are in here.
And so for that the standard is kind of using
a npm package called .env.
So npm install.env,
all right,
then let's go over to our server and actually require
that module.
So const.env
is equal to require
.env, so simple.
And down here we can simply use this dotenv variable
called config on it and then in there we just have
to pass an object to specify the path where our
configuration file is located.
So path,
config dotenv.
And so what this command will now do is to read
our variables from the file and save them
into node JS environment variables.
So let's now run npm start and that should then
block all our environment variables to the console
because of this line of code.
And so let's wait for it, and indeed here we have nodeenv,
we have the port, the passwords,
and of course the rest of the data should be somewhere
here inside this gigantic list.
It doesn't really matter where it is here.
So the user was actually Jonas.io already
and so we should call this here user name.
Then resave this here in order to rerun the server again,
and so now we have a user name down here
and so these are the four environment variables
that are defined in our file.
Great, and just to finish, let's now actually go ahead
and use this nodeenv variable and also the port variable.
And to do that we go into app.js and somewhere here
the port should be defined and somewhere here we have
oral logger middleware and what I wanna do now
is to only run that middleware so to only define it
when we are actually in development,
so that the login does not happen when the app
is in production.
So we have that right here,
and so let's go ahead and say if
process.env
.nodeenv is equal
to development well only then use Morgan.
Now you might be wondering why we actually have access
to this environment variable here when we didn't really
define them in this file but in server.js.
And the answer to that is that the reading of the variables
from the file which happens here to the node process
only needs to happen once.
It's then in the process and the process is of course
the same no matter in what file we are.
So we're always in the same process
and the environment variables are on the process.
And so the process that is running,
so where our application is running is always the same
and so this is available to us in every single file
in the project.
So this is how we use this variable,
now let's go back to the server and let's say that the port
should either be the one coming from the environment
variables or this 3,000.
So process.env
.port or 3,000.
Now something is wrong here, let's take a look,
and oh I see I'm already using 8,000
in some other applications that's running somewhere
on my computer.
And so let me actually go ahead and change that here
to 3,000 as well.
But it doesn't really matter, you can leave yours at 8,000
if that works for you.
Clear it here, give it another save, and now it works.
You can also get rid of this console.log here
because we don't need to see these variables all the time.
And let's now quickly do an http request to see
if our logger still works and I'm gonna do that here
postman again, so this one,
going back, and now our login is gone.
Well let's see why.
So we have it here in development which is correct.
And so this should actually work,
so this is also correct here right, development.
Well let's do a console.log and take a look
at a tier,
but we do get undefined down here.
So let's check what's going on here,
and so yeah I see the problem which is that we actually
require the app file before our environment variables
are read from the config file.
And so it needs to be the other way around.
So let me move that up here
and then only after that we want to run the code
that is in the up file.
And then only after that we want to run the code
So again we couldn't read the process variable
inside app.js because it wasn't yet configured.
So if we give it a save now,
then indeed you see development here.
And if we do our request now, let's send it,
then of course we get our logger back.
So that's working now.
And now finally as the last test,
let's add a new start script to our package.json.
So right now we have start nodemon server,
but I also want to add another one for production
just so that we can test what happens in that situation.
So start prod, and so let me call the other one dev,
and so in production we simply want to set
the nodeenv variable to production.
So nodenv equals
production and then the rest is the same.
So nodenv,
server.js.
So let's finish this one here
npm run start
production.
And so now you see that our nodeenv variable
is actually set to production.
So that is coming from this console.log here.
And if now do this request,
we will then not get our logger.
So it's not here as it was before.
And so this is basically how we run different code
depending whether we are in development or in production.
So let's get rid of this one here,
we can close this one as well,
and so let's go back to our development script of course,
so npm run start
dev and all right here we are.
Just one final test
and indeed here is our login result.
So that's it for environment variables,
let's move on to the final lecture in this section.