Just like in the previous sections,
before we dive into a new technology,
let's actually learn what it's all about.
So in this case, let's learn what MongoDB actually is,
how it works, and a quick overview
of how it compares to more traditional databases.
And let's begin with a simple overview.
So MongoDB is obviously a database,
and it's a so-called NoSQL database.
Now some people also say No S Q L,
but I'm just gonna keep saying "no sequel", all right?
Now, the other type of database, which is
sort of more traditional, is the relational database,
which NoSQL is often compared to.
Anyway, in Mongo, which we can also say instead of MongoDB,
each database can contain one or more collections.
So if you actually are coming from one of
these more traditional relational database systems,
you can think of a collection as a table of data.
Then, each collection can contain one
or more data structures called documents,
and again, in a relational database,
a document would be a row in a table.
So each document contains the data
about one single entity, for example,
one blog post or one user or one review,
or anything else, really.
You get the point, right?
Now the collection is like the parent structure
that contains all these entities.
For example, a blog collection for all posts,
a users collection or a reviews collection.
And you can also see here that the document
has a data format that looks a lot like JSON,
which will make our work a lot easier
when we start dealing with these documents.
And of course we will talk a lot about this later,
but for now on, let's learn about Mongo's main features.
So, according to MongoDB's website,
MongoDB is a document database with the scalability
and flexibility that you want,
and with the querying and indexing that you need.
Now, that sounds a bit over the top,
so let's try to understand what this actually means.
So, as we saw before, MongoDB is a document-based database,
so it stores data in documents which
are field-value paired data structures like JSON.
So again, it stores data in these document
instead of rows in a table
like in traditional relational databases.
It's therefore a NoSQL database
and not a relational one.
Also, MongoDB has built-in scalability,
making it very easy to distribute data
across multiple machines as your apps
get more and more users
and starts generating a ton of data.
So whatever you do, MongoDB will make it very easy
for you to grow.
Next up, another big feature of MongoDB
is its great flexibility.
So there is no need to define a document data schema
before filling it with data,
meaning that each document can have a different number
and type of fields.
And we can also change these fields all the time.
And all this is really in line
with some real-world business situations,
and therefore can become pretty useful.
MongoDB is also a very performant database system.
Thanks to features like embedded data models,
indexing, sharding, the flexible documents
that we already talked about, native duplication
and so much more.
And you don't need to know all of this, of course,
but it's sure nice to know that MongoDB is highly performant
if we need it to be.
Finally, I just wanted to add that MongoDB
is a free and open-source database,
published under the SSPL license.
So in summary, we can say that MongoDB
is a great database system
to build many types of modern, scalable
and flexible web applications.
And in fact, Mongo is probably the most used database
with no JS, and so it's a perfect fit
for us to use in this course.
Okay, now let's talk a bit deeper
about these documents, and returning
to our blog posts example from the beginning,
this could be a very simple representation
of a single post document, right?
And now just for the sake of comparison,
here is how that exact same data
could look like as a row in a relational database
like MySQL, or even in an Excel spreadsheet,
if you're more used to that.
So as I mentioned a bit earlier,
MongoDB uses a data format similar to JSON
for data storage called BSON.
It looks basically the same as JSON,
but it's typed, meaning that all values
will have a data type such as string, Boolean,
date and teacher, double object or more.
We will learn all about this later in practice.
So what this means is that all MongoDB documents
will actually be typed,
which is different from JSON, all right?
Now just like JSON, these BSON documents
will also have fields and data is stored
in key value pairs.
On the other hand, in a relational database,
each field is called a column.
So here again you can see how
these databases arrange data in table structures
while our JSON data is so much more flexible.
Take for example the tags field,
where we actually have an array,
so we have basically multiple values for one field, right?
So MongoDB, space and DV in this case.
But in relational databases, that's not really allowed.
We cannot have multiple values in one field,
and so we would actually have to find workarounds for this
which could then involve more work
and more overall complication.
Now another extremely important feature in MongoDB
is the concept of embedded documents,
which is, again, something not present
in relational databases.
So in our comments field here,
we have an array which contains three objects.
One for each document,
and each of them could actually be
its own document, right?
So just imagine we had a comments collection
which contained a bunch of comment documents.
Each of them could actually look exactly like this,
so with an author and with the comment text,
but instead of doing that,
we include these comments right into the blog post document,
so in other words, we embed the comment documents
right into the post document.
So this process of embedding, or de-normalizing
as we can also call it, is basically to include,
so, to embed, some related data all
into one single document.
In this example, the comments are related to the post,
and so they are included in the same document.
And this makes a database more performant
in some situations because this way,
it can be easier to read all
the data that we need all at once.
And this is something that we're gonna talk about a lot
when learning about data modeling,
but for now, I hope that this still makes sense to you.
Now, the opposite of embedding or de-normalizing,
is normalizing, and that's how the data is always modeled
in relational databases.
So in that case, it's not possible to embed data,
and so the solution is to create
a whole new table for the comments
and then join the tables by referencing
to the ID field of the comments table.
Now we're not gonna use relational databases
in this course, but I believe it's still important
to know the differences if you wanna become
a good back-end developer.
Anyway, and now just to finish,
two more things about BSON documents.
First, the maximum size for each document
is currently 16 MB, but this might increase in the future.
And second, each document contains a unique ID,
which acts as a primary key of that document.
It's automatically generated with the object ID data type
each time there is a new document,
and so we don't have to worry about it.
All right, and that should be a brief enough overview
to get us started,
and to actually use MongoDB from the next lecture on.
So, let's move on now.