So no matter if you installed MongoDB
on Windows or on Mac OS, we will now create
our first local database, using the Mongo Shell.
So this terminal application which is the Mongo Shell
works exactly the same on Windows and Mac,
so from now on it doesn't matter anymore which
platform you're using.
So here in this terminal tab I still have
my Mongo server basically running in the background
on this port, and so let's go ahead and open up
the Mongo Shell.
So remember, that is just typing Mongo here
in the command line and that will then open up
the Mongo Shell, then Command K to clear the terminal,
and so now let's actually create our first database.
And we do that by using "use".
So we use the "use" command inside the Mongo Shell,
and then the name of the database that we want to create.
Now this command here is also used to switch to
a already existing database, but if we try
to basically switch to a database that doesn't
yet exist, it will then create a new one.
So let's say, "use
natours-
test",
okay.
And so it created that database, and it also switched to it.
Okay, and now this blank database
is ready to receive some data.
Now remember that inside a database we have collections,
and then each collection has documents in it.
And the data that we create in the Mongo Shell
is always documents.
And so of course we have to create the document
inside of a collection, and so we specify that
collection before we insert a document.
And this works like this, so db, which stands
for the current database, which is in this case
natours-test, and then we specify the name of the collection
which is tours, and then on that
we use the insertMany function.
So insertMany just like that, so just to recap here,
Database is the currently used database that is
right now active, and when we want to insert a
document into it we need to specify the collection
where that document is gonna live.
And we do that by using dot, and then
the name of the collection, which is in this case "tours".
Now right now this collection hasn't been created,
and so it will create it once we run this command, okay.
And later on we will then have a collection for users,
or for reviews, so basically for all the resources
that we created in the last section, right.
So, using tours here because that is one of our
resources in our application, okay.
But don't worry too much about that for now,
we will talk about data modeling a bit later in the course.
Okay, anyway, let's now actually insert a document
into this database collection.
And it's actually very simple.
So, remember that MongoDb uses BSON,
which is quite similar to JSON,
so we can actually simply pass a JavaScript object
into this insertMany function, and it will
then convert it into JSON and BSON, okay.
So a regular JavaScript object like this,
and then just like before, let's define
the name of the tour.
And I'm calling it The Forest Hiker, which is
one of the tours that we actually have in our JSON
document at this point, so The Forest Hiker,
let's set a price
to
297,
and then also a rating, like an average rating,
which can be 4.7
okay.
So this here looks like just a regular JavaScript object,
now we could also use quotes on the property names,
but that is actually optional, okay.
Now here on these,
and here we probably need the double quotes,
okay so JSON does not recognize the single quotes,
and so to be on the safe side
let's just use the double quotes here, even though
I usually like to use the single ones.
And now just before we hit return, we actually need to
also correct this function here, because it's not
insertMany, because we're actually only inserting
one document here,
so it's called insertOne, okay.
So we use insertMany to create multiple documents,
and we use insertOne when we just wanna create one.
Okay, so let's now hit return, and just like this
we created our first document in our database.
Okay, and now just to check that, let's use DB,
which again is the current database, then .tours
.find
all right and here indeed is the document
that we just created.
And notice how it also automatically created
this object ID here which is the unique identifier
of this document.
So remember how I said that MongoDB would automatically
create these unique identifiers behind the scenes,
and so that's exactly what you see here.
And besides that, well, you see that this really
is just a regular JSON object.
And so this makes it great and really easy to work with
JavaScript, and so as you can guess, this is going to
make it really easy to work with MongoDB data in JavaScript.
Because we're already using kind of the same format
that we're already used to in JavaScript.
And so that is one of the main reasons why MongoDB
is so popular for Node JS applications.
Okay, now another very useful command is show dbs,
which will basically show us all the databases that we have
in MongoDB, and so here you see our natours-test database.
But we also have some other ones,
which MongoDB automatically creates for us.
And yours might not be the same as these three,
but if not, don't worry, and just like before
we could use the "use" command to switch to one of these.
So let's say we now wanted to use admin, and so now
we switched to DB admin, all right.
So again, "use" is to switch to an existing database
or to create a new one, if the name that
we pass into it does not yet exist.
So we want to go back to natours-test
because now I want to show you
just another quick command here,
so "show collections".
And so here you see the tours collection
that we just created before.
So remember how I said that back here when we created
the document we also created the tours collection,
because every document always has to be inside of
a collection.
Okay, so these are the very basic commands
in the Mongo Shell, and over the next couple of lectures
we will then create documents, query them, update them,
and also delete them.
So basically all the craft's operation.
For now let me just show how we can actually quit
the Mongo Shell.
So, very easy, you just type quit like this
and it will then exit it.
Just to quickly show you that our database was
actually persisted, let's simply run the Shell again,
then clear it quickly again, "show dbs",
and you see that natours is still here,
and we can also use it.
Okay, so everything is still there, meaning
that we're now ready to move on to the next video.