So in the last lecture, we learned about
Mongoose schemas and models,
and so let's now implement a very simple
schema and model for our application.
And for now, let's do that right here
in our server.js file.
Later, of course, we're gonna move
that into a different file.
So, Mongoose is all about models,
and a model is like a blueprint
that we use to create documents.
So it's a bit like classes in JavaScript,
which we also kind of use as blueprints
in order to create objects out of them, right?
So again, we create a model in Mongoose
in order to create documents using it,
and also to query update and delete these documents.
So basically, to perform each of the CRUD operation,
so create, read, update, and delete,
we need a Mongoose model, and in order to
create a model, we actually need a schema.
So, we actually create models out of
Mongoose schema just like we learned
in the last video, and we use the schema
to describe our data, to set default values,
to validate the data, and all kinds of stuff like that.
So just as you will see right now,
because now we're actually gonna start creating
a very simple schema for our tours.
So, let's say tourSchema
is a new mongoose.Schema.
Add that in here we actually pass our schema as an object.
All right, we can then also pass in some options
into the schema, but I'm leaving that to a future video
where we actually need that feature.
So, remember the tour documents that we used
to create in the last section when
we started exploring Mongoose DB?
So we always gave them a name,
a rating and a price, right,
and so let's now replicate that here
by saying name, and then describing
what type of data we want after name,
and we want it to be a string.
So Mongoose actually uses the native
JavaScript data types, and so here we can say string,
or after rating we can say that we want a number
and the same as the price.
It should also be a number, right?
So this is the most basic way of describing our data.
So we have a name, a rating, and a price,
and we specified the data type
that we expect for each of these fields.
So again, this is the most basic way
of describing a schema, but we can take it
one step further by defining something called
schema type options for each field,
or only for some specific field.
So let's start here with the name,
and instead of just specifying it
as a string, let's actually pass in another object.
And so now, we say that we want the type
to be string but we can now
define a couple more options, okay?
For example, we can say that this field is required,
and so we simply set
the required property here to true, all right?
So again, this object here are the schema type options,
and they can be different for different types,
for example the number type has some different
schema options than the string here,
but many of them are also similar.
So for example, the required, we can use it
on number as well, and so let's do that here.
So the type, we still want it to be a number,
and we also want it to be required, okay?
Now, here in the required we can actually
specify the error that we want to be displayed
when we're missing this field.
So, in order to do that we just have to
pass in an array, and the first one is true.
So the first element is true, and the second one
is the error string.
Let's say, a tour must have a name,
and then here let's do the same.
The tour must have a price, okay?
Then we can also set default values
and let's do that here for the rating.
So again, I'm gonna specify some
schema type options here, which is not mandatory,
so it's enough to simply define
the type here like we did, but if you want
some more features, then we need to to at least
specify the schema type options object.
Okay, and then we need to specify the type again,
which is number, and as a default, I want it to be 4.5.
And so if we'd now create a new tour document
using this schema and not specifying the rating,
it would then automatically be set to 4.5, all right?
And just to finish, let's try another one here,
which is to say that the name should be unique.
So, unique and set it to true,
and so like this, we can now have two
tour documents with the same name, all right?
So, this is our very basic schema,
let's now go ahead and actually
create a model out of it, all right?
And that's very simple,
we simply create a variable called Tour,
and then mongoose.model,
then the name of the model, which is Tour with an uppercase
T here, all right.
And so that's just kind of a convention
in programming to always use uppercase
on model names and variables.
So here it's the same, so I also created
this tour variable here with a capital T
just so we know that we're dealing with a model here.
All right, so the name of the model
and then the schema, and that's it.
So just like this, we created a tour
out of the schema that we created here in the beginning.
All right, and so in the next video
we're gonna then use this model here
in order to create our very first tour document, all right?
So just a recap here, we used new mongoose.Schema here
to specify a schema for our data.
So, basically describing it and also doing some validation.
For example, this required here,
this is actually something called a validator
because it is used to validate our data.
In this case, simply to validate
if the name is actually there.
And there are a lot of validators in Mongoose,
and we can actually also create our own,
and so of course we're gonna talk about that
a bit later, again, once we actually need these features.
Anyway, let's now quickly move on
in order to finally start using
the model that we just created.