Let's now start creating documents,
testing the model, and really start using Mongoose.
And I'm really excited about this video,
so really let's get started here.
So what we're gonna do is to create a new variable,
and I'm gonna call it testTour,
and this will be a new document
created out of the tour model
that we created in the last lecture.
So what we're gonna do
is to say new Tour,
and then in there pass an object with the data.
So name, let's say,
again, 'The Forest Hiker,'
just as we've been using before,
then the rating, let's say 4.7,
and then the price,
let's say 497, okay?
So, this is, again, a new document
that we created out of a tour model,
or function constructors,
and so as I said before, this is kinda
using JavaScript function constructors,
or JavaScript classes if you're using ES6,
basically to create new objects
out of a class, right,
and so that's exactly the same syntax, actually,
so we use the name keyword,
and then the class name in ES6,
just like this, all right?
Now here, it's not exactly the same,
but this analogy is helpful
to understand how this works.
So this test tour document that we just created
is an instance of the tour model,
and so now it has a couple of methods on it
that we can use in order to
interact with the database.
So let me show that to you.
So we can now say testTour.save,
and this will then save it to
the tours collection in the database, okay,
and it's really as simple as that.
So again, we have our document instance
which is testTour, and on there
we can then call the save method
in order to save the document to the database.
Now this save here will then return
a promise that we can then consume.
So for now, let's use then for that,
and in the future, we will actually use
async await in order to consume these promises,
but for now, let's keep it simple
and not create any more functions,
and so instead, we're just using
the then method here.
So in here, we get access to the document
that was just saved to the database.
So, basically, the result value of the promise
that the save method returns is
the final document as it is in the database.
And so let's now actually go ahead
and log the document to the console, all right?
Now, on the other hand, saving this document
to the database might also go wrong,
and so let's catch that error, okay?
So just like before, we used the catch
method in order to catch any potential errors,
and so if there is an error when
saving the document to the database,
we will be able to catch that error
here in this method.
Okay, so basically, here in this function
that I'm passing into catch.
Okay, for now, all I wanna do, really,
is to also log it to the console.
Let's say, 'Error,' add some emojis here
to make it more visible in the console,
and then we can pass in a second argument
into the console log, which will
then be the error, okay?
Are you ready?
Then, let's give it a save now,
and that will then execute the code that is in here,
so basically create this new tour, and try to save it
to the database right away, okay?
So, let's give it a save now,
and see what happens in the console,
and indeed, here we go.
So you see, that this is the document
that was just saved to our database, all right?
So here we actually see the ID as well,
and that is simply auto-generated by MongoDB,
and it's simply the unique identifier for the document.
So just like it happened before in the MongoDB section,
we automatically get this unique identifier
for the new object.
Then Mongoose also automatically adds
this V, and set it to zero here,
but that's not really important at this point, okay?
What matters here is that our new document
was actually successfully added to the database,
and just to make sure, let's actually move over
to Compass and take a look at our database there.
So here, we have the tours collection,
and then we have the document that we just created.
So it has that exact same ID, and of course
all the other data that we put in there,
and so indeed, this is the object
that we just created.
And keep in mind that we had actually deleted
the tours collection here in one
of the previous videos, right,
but Mongoose automatically created
this new collection here as soon
as we created the first document
using the tour model,
and so this name here basically
comes from that tour model, it simply
gives us this plural name, just as we had before.
Perfect, we just made our express application
really interact with a MongoDB database
for the very first time,
and that's actually really amazing, if you ask me.
So this means that right now,
we are able to create documents right from our code.
So, that makes me really happy,
and so let's actually try it again
with another one, all right,
but actually before we do that,
I want to just reload this file here
which will then try to save this document here
to the database again, right,
simply because all this code here is run
each time that we save the file.
Now, let's try to guess what is gonna happen
as soon as I save this file.
Can you guess?
Let's wait for it,
and indeed we get something different now,
we get an error here,
and the error that we see is this
duplicate key error collection,
which down here says this duplicate key, okay?
So we already have a tour with the name
of 'Forest Hiker,' and so now we were
trying to create another one,
and since in our schema we have this
unique property here, that is not allowed,
remember that?
So we set this unique here to true
in order to make it impossible
to have two tours with the same name,
and so we just proved that this is actually working.
All right, so let's simple replace
the code that we have here
in order to create a new tour with another name.
Let's call it 'The Park Camper,'
and let's go ahead and remove the price
and also the rating.
So, can you guess what's gonna happen now?
Let's actually clear, or actually it
already loaded it because as soon
as I clicked here, it then saved the file,
and so, yeah we just got another error,
so you can see that up here,
meaning that we didn't successfully save
this document to the database,
and what we got here now is a validation error
coming from the price field
saying 'A Tour must have a price,'
and so that is exactly the message
that we specified up here, right?
Simply because in this line we said
that the price is a required field, all right,
and so this required, as I mentioned,
is a validator, and so down here,
we then get a validation error.
And so let's now fix that
and specify the price, let's say 997,
and give it another save.
Now this time, it should work
because the rating is not required,
and so when we come down here,
our document was actually successfully
saved to the database, you see?
Now, we didn't specify the rating here
in this test tour, but you see it's still 4.5,
and that is because we set
the default to 4.5 up here.
So I just wanted to show you
that here in this quick example.
Okay, so we were successful again,
so let's come back here, reload,
you're clicking this button, and indeed
we now get our two tours.
Great, and I remember how amazing it felt
for me when this worked the first time
when I was starting to learn Express and Mongo,
and how to build these applications,
and so I really hope that you're
feeling the same way right now,
as you just created your very first
documents using Express
and, of course, MongoDB.