We just learned a lot about MVC,
and so lets now very quickly refactor our code
in order to fit that architecture a bit better.
And actually we already have our controller folder here,
and the tour and user controllers in them,
and we already have the routes
here in the route folder.
And so really what we need to do in this video
is to create a model folder,
and create a tour model in there.
So, let's do that.
(clicking)
So, models and in there
the tourModel.js
Let's close out these guys,
and so let's go ahead and copy,
or cut actually, this schema
and this entire model declaration here,
and put it in the tour model.
We will also want the Mongoose importing here.
All right, and in fact,
let's get completely rid of this code.
All right, so this here was just for testing,
and we don't need it anymore.
So it has done its job,
and so all we really want to do
in this file here is to connect to the database,
but everything that is about the models themselves,
will always live inside of a file,
inside of the models folder.
All right, now in here eslint tells us
that this variable here has not been used,
but actually we want to use it
because we want to export the model from this file.
So module.exports, and this should actually
be the only thing we export from this file,
and so we use the kind of default export with module.exports
Okay, and so this is our very simple tour model
that we created in our last lecture,
and now here we put it in it's own standalone file,
and then finally exported it from here.
Okay, now where do we actually need this tour.
So, in other words, where are we actually going to create
and query, and delete and update tours.
Well we're going to do so in the tourController, right?
So right here,
and so let's go ahead and actually import the model in here.
So right here at the top,
(clicking)
and I'm giving it the exact same name.
So still tour,
and now I want to require, so the current folder,
then up one folder,
and then down into the models folder,
and in there, tour model.
Okay, now of course it's telling me
that I'm not using this variable,
but don't worry about that for now.
So, next up, I want to get rid
of this place here where we actually import
the data as a json file.
So, of course, we no longer need this.
This here was just for testing purposes.
So let's get rid of it.
You can also comment it out
if you want to leave it maybe as a reference for yourself.
Then just go ahead and comment it out.
Then down here we get this error
because the variable that we just deleted
is no longer defined,
and so let me comment out this piece of code here
because, again, we're gonna need something similar to this.
Okay, get tour, let's comment all
of this here out as well just so that we don't get
any errors as soon as we save this file.
Then here, actually, we can get rid,
well kind of, of all of this.
So we're no longer gonna use any of this.
So let me just keep this piece here.
So I'm gonna copy it,
delete everything else from this,
and put it back here.
We still got this error,
and so I'm commenting out this piece of code.
All right, and here we don't get any errors.
So let's just leave it like this for now, okay?
So what I just did here was to basically
clean the code that we wrote before
in order to no longer depend on the data
that we had in the json file.
All right, so now we should have no more errors,
or actually we should in this checkID function,
and this checkID function, we,
in fact, no longer will need it, okay?
Because from now on we're gonna start working
with the IDs that are coming from MongoDB,
and Mongo itself will give us an error
if we use an invalid ID,
and so this function that we have here
was actually very useful for showing you
how middleware actually works,
by giving you this very practical example here,
and later in the course, people,
of course, use more middleware,
but this particular function here,
we will no longer need it.
So, let's get rid of it,
and also of this file system import,
again, because we're no longer using the file here.
So we still got some error here.
Let's see what's happening,
and it looks like it is in the
in the tour routes, okay?
And so actually that was the one
that I was gonna change next.
So the problem here is that
this tourController.checkID, of course no longer
exists because we just deleted it,
and so let's get rid of this as well,
or actually let me just comment it out, okay?
So you keep in mind that you can use
this .param function here to define
parameter middleware in your own applications, okay?
So I don't want you to forget that,
and so just leave it here in your code
so that maybe later when you come back to it
you still know that it's there, okay?
So now I saved it,
and so we're back on track here.
So everything is back to working,
and our code is now sufficiently well refactored
so that in the next video we can actually start
implementing the correct functions in our API.
So basically, getting all tours,
creating tours, deleting tours, and updating tours.
So, one by one, we will start
implementing these controller functions,
or handler functions if you prefer that,
starting in the next video.