Just like Express,
Mongoose also has the concept of middleware.
And so let's now learn about the first type
of middleware, which is document middleware.
Now, just like with Express, we can use
Mongoose middleware to make something happen
between two events.
For example, each time a new document is saved
to the database, we can run a function
between the save command is issued and the actual saving
of the document, or also after the actual saving.
And that's the reason why Mongoose middleware
is also called pre and post hooks.
So again, because we can define functions
to run before or after a certain event,
like saving a document to the database.
So middleware is an absolutely fundamental concept
in Mongoose, so just like in Express.
And there are tons of possibilities
and use cases for middleware, and we're gonna be
using middleware all the time in this project.
So there are four types of middleware in Mongoose:
document, query, aggregate, and model middleware.
And in this lecture, we're gonna talk about
document middleware, which is middleware
that can act on the currently processed document.
So just like the virtual properties,
we define a middleware on the schema,
so tourSchema.pre.
And so this is for pre middleware, which again,
is gonna run before an actual event.
And that event in this case is the save event.
And so this call back function that we're
gonna define here next,
so function
so this function will be called before an actual document
is saved to the database.
So this is document middleware,
and it runs, let me write all of that here.
So it runs before the save command
and the .create command.
But not on insert many.
So if we use this command here, so insertMany,
then that will actually not trigger the save middleware.
So always keep that in mind.
It's very important to realize that only on save
and on create actually this middleware here
is gonna be executed.
And so let's start by doing a simple console.log
and what I'm gonna log through the console is this.
And so in a save middleware, the disk keyword here
is gonna point to the currently processed document.
And that is the reason why it is called document middleware.
Again, because in this function here,
we have access to the document that is being processed.
So in this case, the document that is being saved.
And so let me just very quickly show that to you
using this console.log.
And so in order to now trigger this function,
remember we need to run a save command or a create command.
And so we now need to create a new tour using our API
in order to, yeah, to then trigger this middleware.
So let's go here to, to postman, and I'm gonna start by
by saving these two new routes that we created
in the previous lectures, so get monthly plan.
And this one here is get tour stats.
So now I can close them and create new tour.
And we specify the data here in the body.
Now not all of the stuff here is actually required,
so let's take a look at what actually is required
and get rid of the rest.
So the imageCover is required, the summary,
of course the price, and yeah.
So let's get rid of the stuff that we don't
really need here just to keep it at a minimum.
So the ratings, quantity, average,
so these are not necessary.
So I'm just gonna call this one here
the test tour, just to keep it really simple here.
Now let's send this request and indeed,
it created the new document and now let's take a look
at our console and see that document here.
And indeed, here it is.
So let's increase this here a little bit
and so this is what our document is looking like
right before it saved into the database.
And so here we have ratingsAverage and quantity,
which are set by default.
Remember, so 4.5 and zero, and then
the createdAt time stamp, and you can even
see the virtual property that we defined here.
So again, this is right before we actually
save this data to the database.
And so at this point of time,
we can still act on the data before it is then saved
to the database and that is exactly
what we're gonna do now.
So down here in our middleware function.
And what I wanna do here is to create a slug
for each of these documents.
So remember how in the first section,
we created a slug for each of the products
that we had in the store.
And so a slug is basically just a string
that we can put in the URL, usually based on
some string like the name.
So in this case, we're gonna create a slug
based here on the tour name.
So remember how for that we used the slugify package.
And so let's now go ahead and install that.
All right, and while that's doing,
let's go ahead and then require it here.
So require slugify.
Let's go back to our first window here, actually.
And now, down here, we no longer want
to log this to the console.
But instead we can now say this, and remember,
this is the currently processed document.
So we can now define a new property on it.
And that's exactly what I'm doing.
So this.slug should be slugify,
and then just a string that we want to create
a slug out of, and so that's gonna be this.name
and then we also want to pass in the option
that everything should be converted to lower case,
and so that's lower: true, and now I'll give it a save.
And one thing that we didn't talk about yet
is the next function.
So just like in Express, we also have the next function
in mMngoose middleware, basically to call the next
middleware in the stack as we already know.
Now in this case, we only have one middleware function,
which is why we didn't run into any problems,
even not calling next, but let's actually now do that.
And so each middleware function, in a pre save
middleware has access to next.
So that's exactly the same as in Express,
and so by the end of the middleware we call next,
and that will then call the next middleware
in the stack.
So let's try this out again.
And this is gonna be called test tour number two.
Very simple, send to sky,
and let's wait for it.
And now for some reason, it's not really here.
Let's see if we got some error,
and we actually did not.
But the reason why it's not working
is that right now we don't have any slug in our schema.
And remember this actually happened to us before
when we only had a couple of fields in the schema.
And when we, then we'll define some fields
that were not in the schema, then they were
simply not persisted to the database.
And the same thing is now happening here,
so we defined the slug property, but it's not in our schema.
And therefore it was then not saved to the database,
and so let's quickly fix that and let's put it,
oh, I don't know, it doesn't really matter,
can put it here right after the name,
so the slug should simply be a string.
And so that should fix it.
So let's go back and create the test tour number three.
Because it cannot be the same, because remember
we cannot have tours with the same name.
So do it again, and now indeed we have the slug property
right here and it is indeed based on the name,
as you can see here.
Great, so let's go back here,
gonna reduce this a little bit.
And so here we have the pre document middleware.
Let's now just very quickly experiment, also,
with a post middleware.
So tourSchema.post and let's use save again.
And then the callback function,
which in the case of post middleware
has access not only to next, but also to
the document that was just saved to the database.
So let's call that one doc and then next.
And so post middleware functions
are executed after all the pre middleware functions
have completed, all right.
So in here we actually no longer have the disk keyword,
but instead we have the basically finished
document here in doc.
So let's just log that finished document
to the console and then call next.
Now in this case again, we only have one
post middleware and so we wouldn't really need next,
but it's a best practice to simply always include it.
Now another thing that I wanted to show you
is that we can have, of course, multiple
pre middlewares or also post middlewares for the same hook.
And hook is what we call this save here.
So this middleware here is basically what we call
a pre save hook.
So you will see that terminology all the time.
So some call it middleware, and some call it hooks.
And so this is gonna be a pre save hook
or pre save middleware.
So function, and this one has access to next.
And so let's just log something to the console here,
like will save document.
And then next, and that of course, should be next.
Just to see if we get some error,
I'm gonna omit the next here.
Just to see what happens when we do not call it.
So I'm gonna create a new tour,
and by the end of this lecture I'm gonna delete
all of them, but for now we need them here.
And so now you see that it's not really finishing,
so we're stuck in that one middleware function
that doesn't have the next call.
So basically we're stuck in here.
So let's cancel the request
and then get it back here,
and try that again.
And so now it worked indeed.
So our slug is here, right,
and so let's take a look at our console,
and so indeed, our second pre middleware also run,
so the one logging will save document and then
our post middleware then logged to the console
the final document, and so that should also
already have the slug and yeah, here it is.
And that's actually all I had to show you
about document middleware.
Now I'm just gonna comment out these two here
because I don't want to pollute my log here
all the time with these console.logs,
but I'm still keeping them here, again,
as a reference.
So what I want you to remember from this lecture
is that we can have middleware running before
and after a certain event.
And in the case of document middleware,
that event is usually the save event.
And then in the middleware function itself,
we have access to the disk keyword,
which is gonna point at the currently being saved document.
And it's also very important to keep in mind
that this save middleware only runs for the save
and create Mongoose methods.
It's not gonna run, for example, for insert many
and also not for find one and update
or find by ID and update, which we already used before.
So for example, we somewhere here we have
we have findByIdAndUpdate, but that is not gonna trigger
this save middleware.
So that's very important to keep in mind
because actually a bit later in this project,
we will have to work around that limitation.
All right, so this is document middleware
to manipulate documents that are currently being saved.
Next up, we're gonna talk about query middleware.