So we have our user model set up
ready to save users with secure passwords.
And so next up, we're gonna really implement
user authentication and authorization.
So in simple terms, the whole work flow
of logging users in and allowing them
to interact with certain protected resources
that non-logged in users cannot access.
Now there are many authentication methods out there,
but the one we're gonna use is a very modern, simple
and secure approach called Json Web Tokens or JWT for short.
So Json Web Tokens are a stateless solution
for authentication.
So there is no need to store any session state on the server
which of course is perfect for restful APIs like the one
that we're building.
Because remember, restful APIs should always be stateless.
And the most widely used alternative to authentication
with JWTs is to just store the user's log-in state
on the server using sessions.
But then of course does not follow the principle
that says that restful APIs should be stateless
and that's why we're opting for a solution like JWTs.
So now let's take a look at how authentication
actually works with Json Web Tokens.
And assuming we already have a registered user
in our database, this is how a user logs into the app.
So the user's client starts by making a post request
with the username or email and the password.
The application then checks if the user exists
and if the password is correct.
And if so, a unique Json Web Token for only
that user is created using a secret string
that is stored on a server.
And a JWT itself is really just a string
that looks something like this.
But we're gonna talk more about the JWT itself
in the next slide.
Anyway, the server then sends that JWT back to the client
which will store it either in a cookie or in local storage.
And just like this the user is authenticated
and basically logged into our application
without leaving any state on the server.
So the server does in fact not know which users
are actually logged in.
But of course, the user knows that he's logged in
because he has a valid Json Web Token which is a bit like
a passport to access protected parts of the application.
So again, just to make sure you got the idea.
A user is logged in as soon as he get back
his unique valid Json Web Token which is not saved anywhere
on the server.
And so this process is therefore completely stateless.
Then, each time a user wants to access a protected route,
like his user profile data, for example,
he sends his Json Web Token along with a request.
So it's a bit like showing his passport to get access
to that route, right?
And that's probably the best and easiest way to understand
this whole idea.
Now once the request hits the server,
our app will then verify if the Json Web Token
is actually valid.
So if the user is really who he says he is.
And more about how this step works
a bit later in this video.
Now if the token is actually valid, well,
then the requested data will be sent to the client
and if not, then there will be an error telling the user
that he's not allowed to access that resource.
And as long as the user is logged in,
this is how it's gonna work each time that he requests data
from any protected route.
Now what's very important to note here
is that all this communication must happen over https.
So secure encrypted http in order to prevent
that anyone can get access to passwords or Json Web Tokens.
Only then we have a really secure system.
But we will talk about that later in the section, okay.
So I know that this can look quite confusing
in the beginning when you first try
to wrap your head around it, but actually
the principle itself is actually quite simple, all right?
And this is really all you need to know in order
to be able to implement authentication using JWT.
But let's now dive a little bit deeper into how
the JWT itself actually works.
So a Json Web Token looks like left part of this screenshot
which was taken from the JWT debugger at jwt.io.
So essentially, it's an encoding string
made up of three parts.
The header, the payload and the signature.
Now the header is just some metadata about the token itself
and the payload is the data that we can encode
into the token, any data really that we want.
So the more data we want to encode here,
the bigger the JWT.
Anyway, these two parts are just plain text
that will get encoded, but not encrypted.
So anyone will be able to decode them and to read them.
So we cannot store any sensitive data in here.
But that's not a problem at all
because in the third part, so in the signature,
is where things really get interesting.
The signature is created using the header, the payload
and the secret that is saved on the server.
Remember that?
And this whole process is then called
signing the Json Web Token.
So again, the signing algorithm takes the header,
the payload and the secret to create a unique signature.
So only this data plus the secret
can create this signature, all right?
Then together with the header and the payload,
these signature forms the JWT,
which then gets sent to the client.
Now as I mentioned briefly, right in the first slide,
once the server receives a JWT to grant access
to a protected route, it needs to verify it
in order to determine if the user really is
who he claims to be, right?
In other words, it will verify if no one changed the header
and the payload data of the token.
So again, this verification step will check
if no third party actually altered either the header
or the payload of the Json Web Token.
So, how does this verification actually work?
Well it is actually quite straightforward.
So once the JWT is received,
the verification will take it's header and payload
and together with the secret that is still saved
on the server, basically create a test signature.
But the original signature that was generated
when the JWT was first created is still in the token, right?
And that's the key for this verification.
Because now all we have to do is to compare
the test signature with the original signature.
And if the test signature is the same
as the original signature, then it means that the payload
and the header have not been modified, right?
Because if they had been modified,
then the test signature would have to be different.
Therefore in this case where there has been no alteration
of the data, we can then authenticate the user.
And of course, if the two signatures
are actually different, well, then it means
that someone tampered with the data.
Usually by trying to change the payload.
But that third party manipulating the payload
does of course not have access to the secret,
so they cannot sign the JWT.
So the original signature will never correspond
to the manipulated data.
And therefore, the verification will always fail
in this case.
And that's the key to making this whole system work.
It's the magic that makes JWT so simple,
but also extremely powerful.
So let me summarize it again.
Without the secret, no one will be able to manipulate
the JWT data because they cannot create
a valid signature for the new data.
I mean they could manipulate the data of course,
but it will always fail the verification step.
Now, don't worry, we're not gonna actually implement
these JWT algorithms by ourself.
They are very complex and we're not gonna
reinvent the wheel here, all right?
But it's still very important to actually understand
how this whole process works behind the scene.
And I hope that this lecture did just that for you.
But now, let's move on to the next lecture
to actually start using all this.