So in this lecture
we're gonna implement the functionality
of logging users in based on a given password
and email address.
And just like before, the concept of logging a user in
basically means to sign a JSON web token
and send it back to the client.
But in this case we only issue the token
in case that the user actually exists,
and that the password is correct.
So, let's start to implement that.
Exports.login is...
request, responds, and next.
And the first thing is we is to actually read the email
and the password from the body.
So let's say const email equals req.body.email.
Okay, and now eslint gives us this warning,
or this error actually, and it says
that we should use object destructuring, okay?
And so I let this happen here on purpose
just so that I can show you how we can do it
with ES6 destructuring.
And I think I talked about this before in the course,
and I also hope that you're already familiar
with the concept, but anyway,
since the name of this property here
is the same as the variable name,
we can simply do it like this
and get rid of the property name here, okay?
And also we want to get the password.
And so that would be the same,
so basically password equals to a request.body.password.
And instead of doing that,
we can simply do email and password.
And so just like this, we basically create
these two variables of the body object, okay?
So basically this is how the user
is gonna send in the login credentials for us to check.
Okay, and that check process has a couple of steps,
and so let's actually lay them out here
before we start coding.
So first we need to check if email
and passwords actually exist, all right?
Then number two, check if the user exists,
and at the same time if the password is correct.
And then third, if everything is okay,
send the token, so the JSON web token back to the client.
Okay, so the first one is very easy.
So if there is no email or no password,
then we want to send an error message to our client.
Now how are we gonna do that?
Well we're gonna do that using the tools
that we implemented right in the last section.
So basically our app error, remember that?
So we will simply create a new error here,
and our global error handling middleware
will then pick it up and send that error back to the client.
And so let's actually start by importing that error.
So remember it's this one here
from our AppError class, right?
So let's say AppError, and then require.
So one level up from here, then in the utilities,
and then appError.
Okay, and so we need to call the next middleware,
and then this is where we pass in the error, remember that?
So new AppError, and the message is:
please provide email and password.
And the HTTP error code is 400 for bad request, okay?
And now I've got some errors here,
and so that again is eslint helping me to fix some bugs.
So I see that up here, again,
I used it with a T instead of D,
and if I save it now, everything is correct.
Okay, and so let's actually start testing this right away.
And for that I will simply start
by creating a fake token here for now, okay.
And so then let's say res.status 200 for okay.
JSON, and then of course, as always,
the status set to success, and then also our token.
And that's actually all that we're gonna send
as a response to the login, okay?
So no user object because that's not necessary at all.
All we want as a response for logging in
is actually the token.
That's all that matters when the user logs in.
Next up, we need to implement the route,
so let's do that again in our user router, okay?
And this one is actually pretty similar to this one.
Let's just duplicate it and then replace signup
in both instances here with login, okay?
And again, this is only valid for a post request,
because of course we want to send in
the login credentials in the body.
And so again it's a post,
but not a get, not a patch, and not a delete,
because that doesn't make any sense in this case.
So let's test it right away.
I'll copy this URL here as well.
It's gonna be post, login,
and then the body of course.
So again, raw and JSON.
So let's create a simple body here.
All right, and so let's try to send this
without any password, and see what happens.
And indeed it works, so we get our message here:
please provide email and password.
And again, since we're in development,
we're getting all of this error stack here,
and the complete error with our status code,
the status, and also of course saying
that it is an operational error.
So just like we defined in the previous section, okay?
Now let's try the same with the password.
So password, set it to I think this was the one,
and then get rid of the email.
And that of course triggers the same.
Okay, and with everything correct that should then work,
and indeed we get our fake token here.
Now just one thing that we should do here
is to also return.
So we did that many times before,
and let me explain it again.
It's simply because after calling the next middleware,
we want to make sure that this login function here
finishes right away, all right?
And since we didn't have that before,
you now see this error here again.
So this is already kind of familiar at this point, right?
So cannot set headers after they are send to the client,
because again, we sent two responses.
First the error response, and then also this code here run,
which of course shouldn't have done.
And so again we use return here to fix that.
Okay, next up, let's check if there actually is a user
for the email that was posted.
So const user, and so let's now use the findOne actually,
because this time we're not selecting a user by the ID,
but instead by its email, right?
And so we need to pass in that filter object
where we can say email equal to email, okay?
So the field is called email,
and the variable is also called email.
And so in ES6 we can abbreviate that simply as this.
Now before we move on here,
there's actually something important
that I need to do for security.
So let me show that to you in Postman,
where we signed up for a new account.
And so you see here that in the user output,
we actually get the password, okay?
It is encrypted actually, but still,
it's not a good practice to leak the password data
out to the client, okay?
For example, if we had our get all users here,
and this route is not yet implemented,
but if we were to get all the users from the collection,
then all of them would have the password visible,
and we don't want that, okay?
And so fixing it is actually quite easy,
because we did it before.
All we have to do is to say password,
and then select and set it to false.
And so like this it will automatically never show up
in any output.
And to let me actually prove that to you
by signing up as something else, so like this.
And let's see, oh, actually we already have a user
with that email, so let's just do test3.
And now the password is actually still here,
but I guess that is simply because we could just create it,
this new document here,
and so therefore it's not really selecting it
because we're not actually reading it from the database.
So let's just very quickly
actually implement this route here,
that's only gonna take a minute.
So just to see if this here actually works.
Because this step is actually important
for what we're gonna do next, okay?
So let's actually go ahead and copy this code
from the getAllTours, and not really copy,
but what we're gonna do is quite similar to this of course.
So I'm simply gonna copy this,
but without the API features.
So I'm not really interested in that, okay?
And so this one I'm actually gonna do
in the user controller, because getting all the users
has nothing to do with authentication.
And so in this case the user controller
is the perfect place for doing this.
Now of course I also need to quickly import
the user model here, and so let's also copy that
from the tourController, which is not the same but similar.
So let's grab actually all of this
into our user controller.
This one we don't need, but we also need to catchAsync.
Okay, so tour is gonna be user,
and here it will be userModel, all right?
Then here we have tours, and down here and down here,
so I hit Command + D to select all of them
and change it to users.
And then here of course what we are awaiting is User.find.
Now since we have an await here,
we need async, then we also need next,
and since we have an async here,
we should then wrap the entire thing into a catch async.
So let's do that.
Okay, and so at this point
this is nothing new to you anymore,
we're already used to doing this kind of stuff, right?
So, this should already work at this point,
so let's try it out.
So get all users, and now indeed we see
that their password is not included in the output.
And that is important because actually, in the find,
so back here in the AuthController,
this here will now also not contain the password, okay?
And so the output of this here
will now also not contain the password.
But we do need the password in order to check
if it is correct, right?
And so we need to explicitly select it as well.
So remember how we used select before
to basically simply select a couple of fields
from the database, only the ones that we needed?
Now in this case, when we want the field
that is by default not selected,
we need to user plus and then the name of the field.
So password in this case.
And so like this, it will be back in the output, okay?
Of course we need to await this query,
and then mark the function as async.
And then just like before,
in order to avoid that ugly try catch block,
wrap this entire function into catchAsync.
All right, makes sense?
So let's now quickly just log the user to the console,
just to see if it works.
So this one here.
We get our success, and indeed we get the user here.
So with exactly the email that I just posted,
and then the password is now also back to being included
in the output, all right?
And so again, that's because we explicitly selected it here.
And so now it's time to actually compare
the passwords that we have in the database
with the one that the user just posted.
But how are we gonna do that?
Because for example, the password might be,
or is in this example, pass1234, but the one
that we have stored in the document looks like this.
So how are we gonna compare this?
There's not really a way of doing it, right?
But actually there is, all we have to do
is to again use the bcrypt package, okay?
So we used bcrypt to generate this hashed password,
and we can also use the same package
to basically compare an original password like this here
with the hashed password.
Of course this password here, since it's encrypted,
there's no way of getting back the old,
so the original password from this string, right?
So that's the entire point
of actually encrypting a password.
And so the only way of doing it
is for this package for this algorithm
to actually encrypt this password as well,
and then compare it with the encrypted one, all right?
So let's implement a function that's gonna do that,
and for that we will use, again, the bcrypt package.
And we will do that in the user model.
And you might ask "Why we're doing it in a model
"and not just here," but that's, again,
because this is really related to the data itself.
And also we already have that package in there,
and so it's easier to simply do it there.
So let's just get rid of this string,
and then create a function here,
which will check if the given password
is the same as the one stored in the document.
So for the first time now we're gonna create something
called an instance method.
So an instance method is basically a method
that is gonna be available on all documents
of a certain collection, okay?
And it works like this.
So again, it's defined on a userSchema,
and then we say methods, and now in this case
we want to call the function correctPassword, all right?
So function, now this function is gonna accept
a candidatePassword, so the password
that the user passes in the body,
and then also the userPassword, okay?
Now inside of these instanced methods,
since they are available on the document,
the this keyword actually points to the current document.
But in this case, since we have the password
set to select false, so this here, remember?
Okay, and because of that,
this.password will not be available.
So ideally we would do it like this,
and so this way we would only need
to pass in the candidatePassword and not the userPassword.
But again, right now that's not possible
because the password is not available in the output.
And so that's why we actually
have to pass in userPassword as well.
So the goal of this function
is to really only return true or false.
So basically true if the passwords are the same,
and false if not.
So return, and then bcrypt which we already know,
and then we are gonna use the compare function, okay?
And the compare function is really easy,
all we need is to pass in the candidatePassword
and the userPassword, not userSchema, userPassword, okay?
And just like the hash function up here,
this one is also an asynchronous function.
And so just like before we use await, and then here async.
Okay, make sense?
So again, this compare function here
will very simply return true
if these two passwords here are the same, and false if not.
And again, we cannot compare them manually
because the candidate password is not hashed,
so it's the original password coming from the user,
but userPassword is of course hashed,
and so without this function here
we would have no way of comparing them, okay?
So here we return true or false,
now all we need to do is to actually call this function
in the authController.
Let's close a couple of these.
All right, so this here was only here for demonstration.
So let's simply call this here correct,
and now remember that the function that we just defined
is an instanced method.
And so therefore it is available on all the user documents.
And so this variable here right now
is a user document, right?
Because it's a result of querying the user model.
And so we can now say user.correctPassword.
Now all we need to do is pass in the candidate password,
which is password, remember.
So this one here, and then the userPassword.
And so that's in user.password, all right?
And so this here will now be either true or false.
All right, and now let's actually use these two variables
in order to figure out if the user exists
and the password is correct.
So we already figured that out,
but now we need to actually write our if statement.
So if there is no user, or the password is incorrect,
so basically correct is false, which is what this means.
In that case, we want to, again,
return and go straight to our next middleware
with a new AppError.
And in this case saying incorrect email or password, okay?
And then the status code is 401,
which means unauthorized, all right?
Now we could've done this separately,
so first checking for the user,
and then checking for the correct password.
But in that case we would then give a potential attacker
information whether the email or the password is incorrect.
And this way here it's a bit more vague.
So we're not really specifying what is incorrect here.
So if it's email or if it's the password.
And so if there's some attacker
trying to put in some random data,
then they will not know if the email actually exists,
or if it's just the password that's wrong, all right?
Now just two things here, and the first one
is that we actually need to await
this asynchronous function, okay?
So remember that correct password
is an asynchronous function,
and so here we also need to await for that.
And then also there's another problem,
because of this user doesn't exist here,
then this next line of code cannot really run, okay?
Because for example, user.password
is not gonna be available.
And so we actually need to move all of this,
or actually only this code,
we're gonna move it here into the if else statement.
All right, and so this way,
if the user does not exist, so if this is true,
well then it will not even run this code here,
and then there's not gonna be any problem.
But if the user exists, then it will also run this code
and check if the password is actually right.
And so if the password is correct,
only in that case we ever reach this piece of code here.
So that's the whole idea of this function.
So basically we check for the negatives.
So if there's no email and no password,
then we get this error.
If there's no user, or if there's a wrong password,
then create this error.
But if there was no error at all,
well in that case we reach this part of the code,
where we now generate a token
and then send it back to the user.
Now creating this token is gonna be the exact same thing
as we did before here.
And so instead of repeating all of this code,
let's actually create a function for this, okay?
So I'm gonna copy this code,
and then here very quickly const signToken,
which is gonna receive as the only input the user ID.
So ID, and it will then return the token, okay?
So it will simply sign this and return it right away.
All right, and so here what we're gonna do
is signToken and pass in this ID.
And then of course we also need to change it up here, okay?
So set this ID to this ID,
which as you already know at this point is the same as this.
All right, and so let's now go ahead and do the same here.
signToken, and then in this case it is user._id.
Phew, that was a long lecture,
let's now go ahead and try it out.
So it should now work.
So remember, well this is now another user,
but I know that this is the password that I used.
So let's for now let's use another one,
so just test12, and let's see what happens.
Let's wait, and indeed, incorrect email or password.
And so we get of course also our 401,
and indeed it means that our code is currently testing
for the password already.
So if we now choose the correct password,
then it should pass, so let's wait for it.
But, we still get this error.
Well, so let's simply get rid of all of our users here,
just to make sure that it doesn't have to do anything
with the users, and then create a new one, all right.
So hello@jonas, and pass1234.
Let's go ahead and copy it, I will send it now.
And so these credentials are now correct for sure.
So if it doesn't work now there's some kind of bug.
But now actually it worked, great.
So here is our token, and it looks exactly like before,
so we can assume that it is correct.
Now let's now try it again, deleting this, okay.
And so with the wrong password it does not work.
Let's now put the password right and the email wrong,
and then we get the same error.
So incorrect email or password.
And again if we put everything back,
then we get a new token.
And so we are now really logged into the application.
And I know this might look kind of abstract,
so all we really get is a token, and then that means
we are logged into the application, right?
But, well, that's how it works on stateless authentication.
Later on when we really build the dynamic website,
then of course it's gonna be a lot more visible
if the user is either logged in or logged out, right?
But it will still work behind the scenes
using this same token.
So if there's no token, then the website will look one way,
and if there is a token then the website's
gonna look another way, with the user image
and the username right there in the website, for example.
Anyway, this was quite a long lecture.
Make sure to go back here and really try to understand
all of this code that we have here, all right?
Because I know that some of this
might be a bit confusing.
For example, this correctPassword function here.
And then I'm sure everything will make sense to you.