Welcome back.
So, we have implemented authentication
in our project up until this point.
And, it works just fine.
However, sometimes, simply authenticating,
so, logging a user in,
is really not enough.
And, so in this video,
we're gonna implement authorization as well.
So, imagine the act of deleting a tour
from our database.
So, not every user should, of course,
be allowed to do that.
Even if the user is logged in, right?
So, we basically need to authorize
only certain types of users,
to perform certain actions.
And so that's exactly what authorization is.
It's verifying if a certain user has the rights
to interact with a certain resource.
So, again, with authorization we basically check
if a certain user is allowed to access a certain resource,
even if he is logged in.
So not all logged in users will be able to perform
the same actions in our API, all right?
And this is a very common scenario that should
be implemented in each and every
web application usually, all right?
So we're gonna build another middleware function here,
this time to restrict certain routes.
For example, for deleting tours.
So, this means that we're gonna build another
middleware function here.
This time, to restrict certain routes,
like, for example, deleting tours,
only to certain user roles.
Okay?
And so let me actually show you how that would look like
in practice.
So here, in the tour routes,
let's go back to that example of deleting tours,
and so let's add some middleware into the stack here.
So authController, protect.
So first, we always need to check
if a user is actually logged in, okay?
So if an administrator is trying to delete a tour,
they would still need to check
if he's actually logged in, right?
So the first middleware in the stack here,
will always be the protect one.
But then, after that one, we will also have the
authController.restrict.
So restrictTo, okay?
And into this function we will then pass some user roles,
which will be authorized to interact with this resource.
In this case, with deleting a tour, okay?
So let's set this one to admin.
So, only to administrators.
Okay, and so now we are dealing with user roles here.
So just like admin.
And right now, we don't have that in our user model.
And so let's quickly implement that here.
All right.
So, let's do that.
Actually, before the password stuff, so like here.
And down here you can actually see how our uncaught
exception handler is working just fine,
because restrictTo is not yet a function, right?
We didn't implement it yet.
I simply used it in order to show
what exactly we're gonna build.
And so of course there's an error,
and so nodemon is now waiting
for us to restart the server, okay?
Anyway, the role here should be of the type String,
and now I'm gonna use the enum validator in order to only
allow certain types of roles here to be specified.
And these are the general, so the normal users,
so let's just call them user.
Then, we have the tour guide,
we have the lead tour guide,
and we have the administrator.
So, I'm just calling that admin, all right?
And these user roles that we have here will of course
be specific to the application's domain.
So, for example, when you're running a community site,
it's not gonna make much sense to
have a guide and a lead guide.
Instead you will probably have, like, moderators
or contributors, or members.
So, you will always have different names,
depending on the type of application that you're writing.
But in our case, this is what makes sense.
Then, we also want to set a default here,
so we actually don't have to specify always
which type of user we're creating.
And so user, the normal user, let's say,
is the one that's gonna be created by default.
So let's now actually go ahead
and delete the users that we already have,
because they don't have any roles,
and so we don't need them like this anymore.
All right.
And so let's actually also go
ahead and create some new ones.
So, I'm gonna sign up here as
as hello@jonas, and so that's now gonna be a normal user,
and now we could not get any response,
and that's of course because we have this error here,
and so, let's very quickly take out this line of code.
And now the error is gone.
And so now it should run,
and indeed we now have this user,
with the role of user, okay?
So that's our default,
but now let's create an admin here.
And to make that really clear,
let's put it here in the email as well,
and now we need to really specify the role,
and set that one to admin.
Send that, and so now we got here our system administrator.
Cool.
So, let's go back here, actually put this code back on,
and we will now make it so that we can actually pass
multiple arguments into this restrictTo.
So, I want the admin to be able to delete tours,
but also delete a guide.
All right?
And so let's add that here as well.
Okay?
So the admin and the lead guide can now delete tours,
but not the normal guides, and also not the normal users.
All right?
So this is how restrictTo is gonna work,
let's now go ahead and implement it.
So exports.restrictTo,
and now, how are we actually going to implement this?
Because usually, we cannot pass arguments
into a middleware function, right?
But in this case, we really want to.
We want to pass in the roles,
who are allowed to access the resource, right?
So this case, the admin and the lead guide.
So we need a way of basically passing in arguments
into the middleware function in a way
that usually does not work.
So, how are we going to do that?
Well, in here, we will actually create like a
wrapper function, which will then return the
middleware function that we actually want to create, okay?
So, this is the restrictTo function,
and in here we want to pass an
arbitrary number of arguments.
So, basically, of roles.
And so we can use the rest parameter syntax,
which is again new in ES6,
and this will then create an array
of all the arguments that were specified, okay?
So we're creating this function,
and right away we will then return a new function.
And this is the middleware function itself.
So, request, response, and next.
Okay?
Make sense?
And so this function here will then basically
get access to this role's parameter here,
because there is a closure, okay?
So, just as a comment here to explain,
roles is an array.
So, for example, it might be, in this case,
admin, and lead guide, okay?
So when will we give a user access to a certain route?
Well, basically, when its user role is
inside of this roles array that we passed in right?
So let's say we have the normal user now,
which has a role of simply user,
so let's write it here.
Role is now just user.
And so basically it's not contained in this array,
and so therefore, that user does not have permission, okay?
And so, let's write that in code.
It's actually quite simple.
So, if not roles.includes, and okay,
once more includes is a very nice array method
that is in Java Script available on all arrays, okay?
So, if this roles array does not include
the role of the current user,
then we do not give permission to that user.
And where is the role of the current user stored?
Well, let's remember the line of code
that we actually put up here,
right in the end where we grant access
to the protected route,
we store the current user in request.user.
And remember how this protect middleware
always runs before restrictTo, right?
So, here, we first have protect,
and then we have restrictTo.
And so by the time this middleware function here runs,
this one has already completed,
and has put the current user on the request object.
And so now, we can use that here.
So request.user.role.
So that's where the role is stored.
So, simple.
In this case, we create a new error.
So just like before, and now we say
you do not have permission to perform this action.
And now a new status code, which is 403.
And this one means forbidden, okay?
So there really is a specific
http status code just for this case,
so for authorization basically, all right?
And, well, otherwise, we simply call next.
And that's really it.
So that's as simple as it is.
So let's quickly recap what we just did here.
So, in here, we first run the protect middleware.
Then, restrictTo middleware,
and only if these two middlewares pass to the next one,
we go to the lead tour.
And so basically this route handler,
or this route controller, is protected,
and is also restricted by this
middleware that we just created.
Then into this function,
we pass all of the roles that are
allowed to interact with this resource.
So, basically, which are allowed to run
this handler function, okay?
And so, this restrictTo function will then run,
and return the middleware function itself, okay?
And that middleware function itself is actually this one.
It will then, because of the closure,
have access to roles, okay?
And so, let's say that the role of the current user,
which is, remember, stored in req.user.role, right?
So, let's say that his role is user,
and since that role is not in this role's array,
well, we then get this error, okay?
And so that's what this roles.includes tests here for, okay?
But of course, if it is included,
then we pass to the next middleware.
Which again, is then the route handler itself.
Cool.
So, I hope that makes sense.
Let's now go ahead and quickly test it.
Okay?
So right now, we have this token here,
stored into the JTW variable, right?
So remember that from the last lecture.
So, we are in this dev environment,
and so here is that variable.
So exactly the one that is down here.
All right?
So if we were now to delete a tour,
we would then have to specify that variable in there, right?
So let's go to authorization,
the bearer token,
and then it actually already puts it here for us.
So it already knows that this is the
one that we want to use, because, well,
we used it before, okay?
Now, I want to start by showing you that
a regular user cannot delete a tour now, okay?
And so let's start by logging in as a regular user.
And so that's hello, right?
Remember, right now we have hello@jonas.io,
which is a normal user, and we have admin@jonas.io.
And we still have this old one here, let's get rid of it.
All right.
And so I'm gonna start with hello@jonas.io.
Okay?
So, logging in, then that token is gonna be stored
into the environment variable,
and now we are ready to delete a tour.
We actually also need to get an ID now,
so let's quickly get one from here,
so we're basically gonna delete one of our tours here.
So let's just use the last one here.
So, the stargazer.
Okay?
And let's see if we get our error message.
And, indeed, you do not have permission
to perform this action.
So, 403.
So, indeed, it's kind of working, right?
But, to make this complete now,
let's of course login as the admin.
So, admin.
Login.
And so this token is now stored into this variable.
And so if you run this now,
we should be able to effectively delete the tour.
Wanna see?
And, it's gone.
So we have a code of 204, no content,
which is the standard when deleting,
but now if we get all our tours,
we should now see a number eight here,
so only eight results,
and that means that the last one is now gone, okay?
And so right now, as we just proved,
an administrator has the permission
to effectively delete tours, okay?
And, I really cannot stress enough
how important this piece of code here is.
So basically, where we get the role from the current user
from the middleware before, okay?
So, storing the user onto the request as we did here,
is really crucial in order for
this next step to actually work, okay?
So, the ID that is encoded into the Jason web token
is what makes our code then know whether
the user that's trying to perform the action is a user,
or if it's an admin, or if it's a lead guide, or whatever.
Again, because that data is coming
from this protect middleware.
Great.
This was yet another important piece of the puzzle
in implementing our authentication workflow here.
And of course, you want to restrict a lot of other routes,
for example, like updating here, okay?
But I'm gonna leave that for a
later point of the course, okay?
Right here, I just wanted to show you
how all of this works, okay?
So, I think I did that successfully.
I hope you understood how this worked,
and of course, if not, you can always ask a question
in the official Q and A section.
Anyway, there's some more great content coming up right now
and so, let's move on.