So, everything that we did in this section so far
was to secure all application
and our users' data as good as possible.
And I talked about a lot of things
we can do to achieve that.
But all of this information was kind of
spread out all over these lectures.
So I decided to create this quick summary
with many best practices that we already implemented
and that we're still gonna implement
in the rest of this section.
Because security is so extremely important,
but unfortunately, many courses don't address it enough.
Now, I'm also not turning this
Node.js course into a security course.
There are better courses and experts for that.
But I will show you a couple of things that
you can do to properly secure your applications and data.
And I'm gonna look at a couple of common attacks
and give some suggestions to prevent them.
And first up, we have the event of a compromised database,
meaning that an attacker gained access to our database.
Of course, this is an extremely severe problem,
but to prevent even bigger problems,
we must always encrypt passwords and password reset tokens
just like we did in the videos in this section.
This way, the attacker can't at least
steal our users' passwords and also can't reset them.
Now, about actually preventing attacks,
let's talk about the brute force attack
where the attacker basically tries to guess a password
by trying millions and millions of random passwords
until they find the right one.
And what we can do is to make the login request really slow.
And the bcrypt package that we're using
actually does just that.
Another strategy is to implement rate limiting,
which limits the number of requests
coming from one single IP.
And this one we're gonna implement
in one of the next videos.
Also, a nice strategy is to actually implement
a maximum number of login attempts for each user.
For example, we could make it so that
after 10 failed attempts, user would have to
wait one hour until he can try again.
Now, I'm not going to implement this functionality
in this section, but please feel free
to experiment with it on your own.
It's probably a really cool learning experience
to code this up by yourself,
and it's actually not that hard.
All right.
Next up, there is the cross-site scripting attack,
where the attacker tries to
inject scripts into our page to run his malicious code.
On the clients' side, this is especially dangerous
because it allows the attacker to read the local storage,
which is the reason why we should
never ever store the JSON web token in local storage.
Instead, it should be stored in an HTTP-only cookie
that makes it so that the browser can
only receive and send the cookie
but cannot access or modify it in any way.
And so, that then makes it impossible for any attacker
to steal the JSON web token that is stored in the cookie.
Again, we're implementing this in a second.
Now, on the backend side, in order to prevent XSS attacks,
we should sanitize user input data
and set some special HTTP headers
which make these attacks a bit more difficult to happen.
And Express doesn't come with these best practices
out of the box, so we're gonna use middleware
to set all of these special headers.
Next, we have denial-of-service attacks.
And maybe you have heard of these.
It happens when the attacker sends
so many requests to a server that it breaks down
and the application becomes unavailable.
Again, implementing rate limiting
is a good solution for this.
Also, we should limit the amount of data
that can be sent in a body in a post or a patch request.
And also, we should avoid using
so-called evil regular expressions to be in our code.
And these are just regular expressions that take
an exponential time to run for non-matching inputs and
they can be exploited to bring our entire application down.
Okay, next up, we have the NoSQL query injection attack.
And query injection happens when an attacker,
instead of inputting valid data, injects some query
in order to create query expressions
that are gonna translate to true.
For example, to be logged in even without
providing a valid username or password.
It's a bit complex
and you should definitely Google it to learn more.
But what you need to know is that using Mongoose
is actually a pretty good strategy
for preventing these kind of attacks
because a good schema forces each value
to have a well-defined data tab.
Which then effectively makes
this type of attack very difficult to execute.
However, it's always a good idea
to still sanitize input data, just to be sure.
And we will take care of that a bit later.
All right, and now to finish,
I just have a couple of best practices and suggestions
on how to improve the authentication
and authorization mechanisms that we implemented.
So, the first thing I need to repeat
over and over and over again
is that in a production application,
all communication between server and client
needs to happen over HTTPS.
Otherwise, anyone can listen into the conversation
and steal our JSON web token.
Next, always create random password tokens.
Not generated from dates or something like that.
Because they are effectively passwords
and so, they should be treated as such.
Plus, always give them expiry dates,
just like we implemented it.
All right?
And we also implemented that a certain JSON web token
is no longer valid after the user has changed his password.
So, we basically revoke the token
as soon as the user changes the password.
Which makes a lot of sense, but again,
many tutorials out there simply do not do that.
Another big thing is to never ever commit
a configuration file, like for environment variables,
to a version control like Git.
In fact, do not upload it anywhere
because this file contains
the most sensitive data of the entire application.
For example, if someone gets access to
your JSON web token secret,
then your entire authentication process is compromised.
Okay, and now just a small detail is to
whenever there is an error,
do not send the entire error to the client.
So, stuff like the stack trace could give the attacker
some valuable insights into your system,
and so, of course, we don't want that.
Next up, we can use the csurf package
to fight a type of attack called Cross-Site Request Forgery,
which is an attack that forces a user
to execute unwanted actions on a web application
in which they are currently logged in.
We're not gonna do that in this section, though.
But I still wanted to mention it here.
Next, we could require the user to
re-authenticate before performing a high-value action.
For example, making a payment or deleting something.
Again, this is just a suggestion
that you can try out for yourself.
Another cool feature that you can implement
is a blacklist of untrusted tokens.
So, we already know that there is not really
a way to log users out of the application
if they show some malicious activity.
But what we can do is to create a list of untrusted tokens
that are then validated on each request.
And next up, a feature that we could have implemented is to
confirm the email address after an account is first created.
So, basically by sending a link to the user's email,
like many real apps actually do.
But I wanted to just keep things simple here,
which is why I didn't do this here.
But please feel free to just implement this yourself
if you feel like it.
Now, a big feature that many apps have
is the concept of refresh tokens.
Which are basically to remember users.
So, to keep them logged in forever
or until they choose to log out.
Our current implementation makes it so that
the user has to basically log in again
after the JSON web token expires.
But, with refresh tokens, that's no longer necessary.
And it's a bit complex to implement and so,
it's a feature for another time.
And finally, the last one
that we could have implemented is two-factor authentication,
which I'm sure you're familiar with.
Basically, with two-factor authentication,
after logging into the application,
the user needs to perform
a second action to really get authenticated.
And typically, that is to insert a code
sent via text message to a mobile phone.
So, these are a lot of functionalities
our authentication could have.
And if you want me to implement any of them,
please let me know so in the Q&amp;A section.
And, if there is a lot of demand for one of them,
then I will show you how it works.
Okay, but again, I didn't want to
turn this Node.js course into
a whole security and authentication course.
And just to finish, something that we will implement
in the rest of the section is
to prevent parameter pollution.
For example, try to just insert two field parameters
into the query string that searches for all tours.
And if you do that, you will find that
there will be an error because
our application is not prepared for that.
And so, attackers try to use these kinds of weaknesses
to crash applications, which is, of course, not good.
And so, we need to fix that.
Okay, so this turned out to be a lot longer than I expected.
And there are entire courses about security
if you're really into security.
All right, but I am leaving it at this,
and so, let's now move on right to the next one.