So we learned in the last lecture
that the JSON web token should be stored
in a secure HTTP-only cookie.
But right now, we're only sending the token
as a simple string in our JSON response.
So in this video, let's also send the token as a cookie,
so that the browser can then save it
in this more secure way.
So we're in our code.
Do we actually send the token to the client?
Well, remember, that's in the authController
and right here in the createSendToken function.
So before, we had basically all this code
in many different places, but then we refactored all of that
just into this createSendToken function.
All right, and so this is where we're gonna work now.
Now, I'm sure you are familiar
with the way cookies work in general,
but just to make sure we're all on the same page here,
let's talk a little bit about cookies.
So first of all, a cookie is basically just
a small piece of text that a server can send to clients.
Then when the client receives a cookie,
it will automatically store it
and then automatically send it back
along with all future requests to the same server.
All right, so again, a browser automatically stores
a cookie that it receives and sends it back
in all future requests to that server where it came from.
Okay, now, for now, this is not gonna be
really important for us
as we're only testing the API using Postman.
But a bit later, when we're gonna render dynamic webpages
and really interact with the browser,
then it will become really important
that the browser sends back the token basically
automatically in each request.
Okay, and by then, of course, we will talk more about that.
But anyway, let's now learn how to actually create
and send a cookie.
So in order to send a cookie, it's actually very easy.
All we have to do is to basically attach it
to the response object.
So we say res.cookie and then all we have to do
is to specify the name of the cookie,
and I'm calling it JSON web token,
then the data that we actually want to send in the cookie,
and so that's of course gonna be the token variable
and then after that, a couple of options for the cookie.
And the first option that we're gonna specify
is the expires property.
Okay, so basically, this expires property
will make it so that the browser or the client in general
will delete the cookie after it has expired.
Okay, and so we set the expiration date
similar to the one that we set in the JSON web token, okay.
So let's actually create a new variable for that,
okay, because the JSON web token package
can then work with this format.
Okay, but in JavaScript, this is kind of meaningless
and so instead, let's create a variable with a real number.
So let's call it still JWT,
then cookie,
expires in, and we still set it to 90, so 90 days,
but again, without the D.
Okay, so that now we can make actually operations with it
because we will need to convert it to milliseconds, okay.
So when should this cookie expire?
It should expire at a new date.
So in JavaScript, when specifying dates,
we always need to say new Date
and then it should expire at right now, plus these 90 days.
Okay, so now, like this of course.
And then process.env,
and now, let's use this one and then
simply put the cookie in there, okay.
But now, of course, we need to convert that to milliseconds.
So we have 90 days right now.
So two hours, it's times 24.
Two minutes, it's times 60.
Two seconds, it's times 60 again.
And then to milliseconds, times a thousand, okay.
And of course, I could do it all in one go,
but this is just to specify what exactly we're doing.
So to show that we're actually
converting it to milliseconds.
The next option is gonna be the secure option.
And so we're gonna set this one to true
and so like this, the cookie will only be sent
on an encrypted connection.
So basically, we're only using HTTPS, all right.
And then finally, it's that httpOnly option
that we've talked about before.
Okay, so we set this one to true
and so this will make it so that the cookie
cannot be accessed or modified in any way by the browser.
Okay, and so this is important in order to prevent
those cross-site scripting attacks.
All right, so all the browser is gonna do
when we set httpOnly to true is to basically
receive the cookie, store it,
and then send it automatically along with every request.
Okay, and that's actually it.
So this is how we basically define the cookie,
so let's say this part,
and then we send it using res.cookie.
Now, if we wanted to test this right now, it wouldn't work
because right now, we're actually not using HTTPS.
And so because of this secure: true,
the cookie would not be created
and not be sent to the client.
All right, and so basically,
we only want to activate this part here in production.
So what I'm gonna do is to basically export
this entire object here into a separate variable.
Okay, so let me show that to you.
So const
cookieOptions
should be equal to this and then here, we pass that in.
All right.
Now, of course, we then don't want this part here,
but only when we are in production.
So let's say
if process.env.NODE_ENV,
remember that's where it's stored
if we're in production or not.
So if that's equal to production,
then set cookieOptions.secure
equal to true.
Okay, and now, we can remove it from here.
Yeah, so now, only when we're in production,
we will get the secure options set to true.
And otherwise, it will only be sent like this,
so just with the expiration date and httpOnly.
Okay, and so let's now actually test this.
And I'm gonna test it with creating a new user.
So here in Sign Up actually
and let's call this one
user@jonas.io.
Always with the same password.
I'm gonna call him User as well
and let's say that the role here is a guide,
so just so that we have some different roles here as well.
Give it some more space.
And now, let's try it actually.
And response is just as we expected
with the difference that now,
we get one cookie here in this Cookie tab.
And so indeed, here, we get
the name of the cookie, the value.
We also have the expiration date,
which is exactly 90 days from right now.
We have httpOnly set to true and also, secure set to false.
All right.
Great, we can also see all the cookies that we have
here in this Cookie tab.
And so again, we see that one cookie that we received
from this domain, all right.
Now, just one last thing that I actually want to change
in that function that we're just working on,
so the createSendToken,
is to basically get rid of this password here in the output.
Okay, so in our schema, we actually have it set
to select false, so that it doesn't show up
when we query for all the users.
But in this case, it comes from creating a new document
and so that's different and so that's why we see it here.
Okay, but we can actually very easily fix this.
Okay, so all we need to do actually is to set
user.password
to undefined.
All right, and so that should
remove the passwords
from the output.
Okay.
So let's just delete this user here that we just created.
And try it again
just to see if the password doesn't show up anymore.
And yeah, indeed now, it is gone.
And still, our cookie, of course, is here.
And when we now come here to our Cookies tab,
well, then you still have only one cookie
because the old one was now basically overwritten
by this new one
and that's because they have the same name.
So the name is like the unique identifier for a cookie.
And so if we receive one with the a name
that was already given,
well, then the old one is simply replaced.
Okay, and that's actually it.
So this is how we send an HTTP-only cookie
and again, we will talk more about this
when we build our dynamic website.