So, in this video,
we're gonna use yet another NPM package
in order to set a couple of
really important security http headers.
So, to set these headers
we will yet again use a middleware function
which will come again from an NPM package.
So, let's install that
and it's called helmet.
So this is kind of a standard in express development
so everyone who's building an express app
should always use this helmet package, all right.
Because again, express doesn't use
all the security best practices out of the box.
And so we basically need to manually go ahead
and put them there, okay.
So, const, helmet,
require,
helmet.
Okay and so let's do this right after this one,
and this one couldn't be any easier
all we need to do is call helmet here
and so that will then produce the middleware function
that should be put right here, okay.
So in app.use,
we always need a function, not a function call, right?
So here we are calling this function
and this will then in turn return a function
that's gonna be sitting here until it's called, all right.
And it's best to use this helmet package
early in the middleware stack
so that these headers are really sure to be set, okay.
So don't put it like somewhere at the end
put it right in the beginning
and actually let's put it really here in the beginning
as the first of all middlewares, okay.
And we are really growing our middleware stack here
let's just give each of them a name.
So, security, HTP,
headers.
That of course, not correct.
and too let's actually use a VRP.
Set security HTP,
limit requests
from same API.
Now we here we have this one as well.
So this is development logging basically.
Then this one here is called the body parser.
So basically reading
data from the body into req.body.
Okay.
And actually, since we're here,
let's implement that thing that I mentioned
in the theory lecture
where I said that we can limit the amount of data
that comes in the body.
Remember that?
So, here in json, we can actually specify
some options and for that as always
we pass an object.
And so we here can say,
limit and let's limit it to 10 kilobyte, okay.
And so the package will then understand
it will parse this string here
into a meaningful data, all right?
And so now when we have a body larger than 10 kilobyte
it will basically not be accepted, all right?
Then finally, this one here
is for serving
static files, okay.
And this is finally just like, some test middleware here.
Let's just keep it here because sometimes it's useful.
For example, for taking a look at the headers here
like we did back then.
Okay, so that is helmet.
Let's now do a request
and then take a look at all the headers
that it gives us basically.
So let's send it here
and then now you see we have 14 headers.
So that's a lot more than before
and so the new ones are basically this one here,
prefetch control off.
we have this strict transport security,
you have the download options,
there's also this one here for XSS protection
and so the browser understands these headers
and can then act on them basically, all right.
Let's quickly actually take a look
at the helmet documentation.
So of course as always
that's on GitHub.
And so here you see basically all the middlewares
that are included.
Because helmet is in fact
a collection of multiple middlewares.
So that's actually what is says here.
So it's a collection of 14 smaller middlewares
and some of them are active by default
which are these ones here
marked like this.
And so if you're interested,
you can take a look at all of these others
and then if you think you need some of them
you can of course then turn it on specifically.
and it tells you how to do that
also up here in the documentation, okay.
But I'm fine just with the default options
And so...
Now, that was actually very simple
and so let's now quickly move on to the next video.