So up until this point in the course,
we have just been building our API,
which can be consumed by a web client,
in order to build a website,
or a native application.
But now, in this section, we will finally use
everything that we've built until now,
to create server-side rendered websites.
And this is now quite easy to do
because we've already done
most of the preparation work before,
like building a working authentication system,
modeling all our data,
and really so much more.
So in this section, we will really start to see
our application coming to life,
with a beautiful user interface
built out of HTML and CSS,
and not just the JSON data.
So I can't wait to finally start this part
of the course now.
(upbeat music)