In this video and the next one,
together we're gonna build the tour detail page.
And along the way
you're gonna learn some more Pug techniques
like conditionals and mixins.
And as I showed you before,
this is what the tour detail page actually looks like.
And so that's what we're going to build in this video
and the next one.
Now the only thing that we're gonna leave
for a bit later
is actually this map.
All right, but everything else
we're going to build in these tool lectures.
Including these reviews.
All right.
So right now we have our overview
and we have of course
these buttons with the URLs already created.
But then when we try to access this page
we of course get this error.
All right.
So let's go back to our VS code
and I actually want to start this
with a small challenge for you.
So what I want you to do
is to create a route for the detail page
according to the URL that we just built before.
And it's going to be similar
to what we already have here
but you have to tweak it a little bit.
Okay.
Enough of that,
I also want you to build this controller.
So get to it.
'Cause right now we only have
like this place holder.
And so let me actually give you the steps here.
And so as always,
first,
we need to get the data.
This time for the requested tour.
And for that,
keep in mind that we actually need the reviews here
and also the tour guides.
Okay.
So,
again let's take a look at that.
So we have these tour guides here.
Right, and so they are a separate data set basically.
So users.
And then here we also have the reviews.
Now these tour guides here,
I believe they're actually automatically populated
in a model.
So let's take a look at that very quick.
So the tour model
and so,
yeah.
So down here,
we have this auto populate
whenever there is a find query
but only for the guides.
And so don't forget to also populate
the reviews.
Okay.
Then after that,
we will build a template
but that we will do together okay,
so I don't need you to do this part.
And then finally,
I want you to complete this part here as well.
So render
template
using the data
from step one again.
All right.
So that's very simple as well.
And so what I want you to do
is to create the route
and then also get the data.
Okay so pause the video here and good luck with that.
So I hope you did that
and to let me know, solve it here for you.
And we're gonna start with the route.
And now all we actually need to add here is this slug.
And of course, we're doing that as a URL parameter.
So just like this, calling it slug.
So before we use the ID right?
And so we had it like this
and now let's just call it the slug.
All right.
Because again,
that is what the overview page looks like.
We have tour slash slug basically.
Okay, and so that's what we will then use
to create for the tour in the controller.
So let's do that now here.
So const,
tour
equal
await
tour
and findone.
So this time we cannot use find by ID.
Well because, we do not know
the ID of the tour.
And so instead,
we are searching by the slug.
And the slug is
as I hope you know
request.params
dot
slug
all right.
And now finally, that's all to populate
the arrays field.
All right.
So the path to populate is reviews.
And actually we do not need all the fields here.
So let's just specify the ones that we need.
And so,
that is only the review,
the rating,
and the user.
Because remember
that we actually display
so the user name and the user photo.
And then of course,
the review itself and the rating.
Okay.
Then of course,
it's complaining that we didn't use async.
And of course I wasn't gonna forget that.
But anyway it's good
that ES Line warns us about this kind of errors.
It really takes away a lot of bugs
from development.
Okay.
And then here of course
we're going to pass that tour variable
into our tour template.
So that one.
Give it a save.
No more errors.
And so that part is actually now complete.
And so all we need to do now
is to go ahead and build our template.
Okay.
So,
we already should have that here.
And that's the dev data.
So we have a lot of folders
and a lot of data.
And it can become a bit
confusing at some point.
Okay.
And so,
let's get rid of this placeholder content here.
And before we do anything else,
let's again take a look at the original HTML file.
Which is in that
public folder that I just closed.
Let's actually close all of these here,
'cause I find this really confusing.
Okay, the models as well.
And so now what we need is public
and then tour.html.
So the header we already have of course.
And then here goes all the content.
So,
all of these sections
that we have on our page
are of course translated here as HTML.
And just like before,
I actually already created a Pug template
based on all of this HTML code.
All right, we wouldn't want to translate
this here manually together.
Okay.
So I have it here already in this template file.
But of course,
again, if you feel like it,
you can pause the video now
and translate this on your own as well.
All right.
But what I'm going to do now is to
go ahead and copy all of this code.
Which is still a ton of code as you can see.
So let's copy all of this and go into our tour
and paste that here.
Now the annotation is going to be wrong again.
So let's copy, or actually select what we just pasted here.
And so everything except the first line is incorrect.
But all we need to do here is to add one more tab.
And that's it.
So now they're all inside of this content block
all at the same level.
So section
and section
and so basically all of the sections
are now at the same level,
so they're all siblings.
Great.
So let's just close up all of these
we no longer need.
And so just like before,
we now have this static page here
with all of this static data.
Which we know we'll have to go ahead an replace.
But before actually doing that,
let's just take a look if our route
is already working.
Okay.
So let's reload it
and that gives us the same error.
And I guess that's because
here we have tours
and not tour
as I think we have it in our route.
Right so here we have tour.
And that actually is the way it makes sense.
And so let's go ahead and change that here in our
overview.
Okay and so here
we actually want tour.
'Cause in fact,
we're actually only seeing one tour
and not multiple tours.
Right?
And so if we go back to the overview now,
we load it,
and now open up The Forest Hiker,
then you see that it's going to be tour.
And then of course,
we get the HTML for the page
that we just created.
Now for some reason the CSS is not here.
Let's just try to reload this.
Well, what's going on here?
Let's try to inspect this.
And I see we have a couple of errors.
So we can click on that.
And so the reason for the missing CSS,
because instead it's trying to load the file
in the wrong place.
So it's trying to load it in the CSS folder
inside of tour.
But that of course does not exist.
And so that is because
we're here on this tour route, okay.
And so we need to basically fix
the way that we import the CSS in our base template.
Let's go there.
And so here in fact,
we should have another slash.
Okay, and the same actually here.
And so that's
for the exact same reason
that I explained to you before in the overview down here.
So we started this URL as well with a slash.
And so again, that is then going to start
at the root of the page.
And that's the way it's supposed to work.
And in fact, the same applies to all of the images here.
So all the images should always
also start relative to the root URL.
So let's add that very quickly here to all of these images.
And,
yeah, that's it.
So that's all of them.
And so,
with that we've fixed the overview
and also this base file.
So if we now reload,
we should then get access to the correct CSS.
And indeed, here we go.
There is just one more error
which is here in this image.
And so again,
it's because it's trying to load it here
from the tour
and not from the root URL.
And so,
that problem is here in the header.
And so of course,
here we also need to make it relative
to the root path.
Probably the same in the footer.
And yeah.
All right.
Just to quickly confirm that,
yeah indeed, here we go.
Great.
So as I mentioned of course,
this has all the static data
about The Park Camper Tour
which is the one that we have in the template.
But we are looking at the forest hiker.
And so, let's now start by fixing our template
and basically using the dynamic data right in here.
So, remember that the variable that we passed in here
is called tour.
Right?
So it's simply called tour
and so that's what we have to call it here.
So tour
.name,
and also the same up here.
And now you already know that
we need to use a template string here
because we in fact want to create a string.
So named .tour.
And here this path is also not correct.
First of all it needs to be a template string
and then our images,
I'll write image slash tours
slash the name of the cover image.
So tour
dot, and now I don't remember if it's image cover,
or cover image.
So,
yeah.
Image cover.
Okay.
So let's quickly try that out.
And so remember, we're at The First Hiker.
And so that should now be the name.
And yet another error.
So,
it says here, cannot read property tour of undefined.
So let's go back and
yeah.
So here is this stupid mistake.
So it's of course tour.name
and not name.tour.
So,
what was I thinking there?
Let's reload this
and now indeed, we get The Forest Hiker
with this real nice cover image in the background.
Great.
And let's keep moving here.
So create yet another template string.
Tour.
Duration,
and then the number of days.
Then down here,
we have again the start location.
So,
tour.start
location.description, remember.
All right.
Now down here
we have these overview boxes here.
So overview box detail.
And as you see,
we have four equal boxes here
where the only thing that changes
is this icon name,
then the date and the next date.
Okay,
so here what changes is not the next date,
what changes is the description of the boxes.
So next date, difficulty,
participants and rating.
All right.
And so basically,
this code here is always the same
only with three pieces that change.
So the name of the icon,
the description and the value of that description.
And so,
since we don't like repeated code, right?
Let's use another feature of Pug
that we haven't used yet
which is called mixins.
So mixins are basically reusable pieces of code
that we can pass arguments into.
So a bit like a function.
And also it's exactly like mixins in SAS.
So that's a CSS pre processor
that you might be familiar with.
So let's copy this code here for this overview box.
So copying it.
And now out here, out of this block,
let's then create a new mixin.
So we write mixin and then the name of the mixin,
which I'm calling overview box.
And then a bit like a function,
we can specify some arguments.
And so remember how we have the description of the box,
then we have the value of that description
and let's just call it text here.
And then also, the icon name.
Okay.
So now, let's copy that text in here
and of course
this now messes up our formatting.
Let's just quickly fix that.
And so now,
these variables here,
they really work like all the other variables in Pug.
So,
here this should now be the text.
Right?
And this here should be the description.
So equal description.
Well here it's actually called label in the CSS.
So let's call it label here as well.
Okay so label, text and icon.
And so here we also need to change the name of that icon
and all of these icon names
always start with icon dash.
And so all we really need to replace
is this part.
So let's create again a template string.
And then get rid of this.
And icon.
Okay and now we can use this.
I also wanted to say that
we could also have exported this mixin into another file
and then included that file here.
But I think this doesn't make much sense.
In this case because it is
not really a lot of code.
Anyway,
let's now actually go ahead and use this mixin.
So let me copy just the name of it.
And so here instead of this overview box.
And for now let me actually just duplicate it here.
Okay, so we used this mixin
by writing plus
and then just like a regular function,
we passed empty arguments into it.
And so our first overview box is next date.
Then for now, just the date that is here.
So just that I can show you that it works in fact.
So August 20,
21.
And then here,
calendar.
Okay because that's the name here of the icon.
And so now we should get
two boxes.
So this one and this one
which should look exactly the same.
So let's quickly confirm that.
And so then we can move on
to actually use the mixin properly.
And yeah,
so here are our two exactly same boxes.
Great.
So let's get rid of this first one.
And of course then here
we want the real date.
Okay.
And so that is,
add tour
.start,
dates,
zero.
So let's take a look at that.
And remember,
that this is going to look a bit weird.
Such as it did before.
Okay.
So let's ahead and fix that.
So let's actually take that from here.
And so what we need
is basically this instead.
Now I don't want to make this line here
all too long
by simply pasting that here.
And so why not just create a new
java script variable for that.
So remember we need to use this syntax here
in order to create java script code
that's not going to produce any output.
And then
again we can simply write java script here.
Okay.
And so now in here I'm going to simply use
that date.
Great.
And now let's just duplicate this here a couple of times
for all the boxes that we have.
So the first one is for difficulty.
And the icon is trending up.
Then the next one is for participants.
With the icon of user.
And the last one is rating.
And the icon is a star.
So here we have the date but,
here in the difficulty we actually have tour
.difficulty.
Then here for the participants
we want this string.
Like 10 people.
So a template string
saying tour
.mix,
group size,
and then
people.
And finally we want the rating
and then out of five.
So tour,
and I can never remember
what I called this field.
And it is ratings average.
All right.
And then,
out of
five.
Okay.
And that should be it.
Now we can get rid of all this code.
And this way it looks a lot nicer.
And just to make sure that works,
let's give it a save here,
reload,
and indeed,
we get easy, 25 people, and the rating
five out of five.
Awesome.
So we already covered a lot of ground,
but let's split this video into two
and continue with the rest of the page
right in the next one.