In this video you're gonna learn about image processing
and manipulation with Node JS,
and in this particular case, we're going
to resize and convert our images.
So everywhere in our user interface
we assume that the uploaded images are squares.
So that we can then display them
as circles like this.
And so this only works when they are squares,
but of course in the real world
users are rarely going to be uploading images
that are squares.
And so our job now is to actually
resize images to make them squares.
Alright, and so here is how we're gonna do that.
We will add yet another middleware before the update me
and then that middleware will take care
of the actual image processing.
Alright, so actually let's do it here in the code
right after this one,
because they are kind of connected aren't they?
So, exports dot,
resize user photo.
And before we continue, let's actually
add this middleware to the middleware stack
in this particular route.
So that's in user routes,
and so here right after the photo has been uploaded
in this middleware,
we will then resize it.
So resize, and here it's actually
the user controller.
Alright.
Let's actually go down here
and going back.
And so at this point we already have
the file on our request.
At least if there was an upload,
and if there was no upload,
then of course we don't want to do anything.
So that means that we want to go to the next middleware.
So if there is no file on the request
then return right away and go to next.
Okay, but otherwise we of course, then
want to do that image resizing.
And for that, we are going to use the sharp package.
Alright.
So, well first of all let's actually install it.
So MPM install sharp
Alright, and since that is doing its work
let's go ahead and put that here already.
So sharp,
and require, sharp.
And sharp is a really nice and
easy to use image processing library for Node Js
And there's fairly a lot of stuff
that we can do with it.
But where it really shines is for
resizing images in a very simple way.
And so, that's exactly what we're looking for here.
Alright.
So, we say sharp and then here
we basically need to pass in the file.
Now, when doing image processing like this
right after uploading a file,
then it's always best to not even save the file
to the disk, but instead save it to memory.
We already talked about that before,
and so that's now actually do that in practice.
Okay, so for that we need to change
a little bit or multer configuration
and actually just this multer storage,
because now we no longer need any of this.
And instead to multer storage,
will be simply multer dot memory storage.
And just like this, okay?
And so as I mentioned earlier,
this way the image will then be stored as a buffer.
And so that buffer is then available
at request dot file dot buffer
and so this is way more efficient like this,
so instead of having to write the file to the disk
and then here read it again.
We simply keep the image basically in memory
and then here we can read that, alright?
Anyway, calling the sharp function like this here
will then create an object on which we can chain
multiple methods in order to do our image processing.
And so the first one that we're going to do is resize.
So, resize, and then here we can specify
the width and the height.
And so let's say 500 and 500
so remember we want square images,
and so of course, the height needs to be
the same as the width.
Now this will then crop the image
so that it covers this entire 500 times 500 square.
And actually we can change
this default behavior if we wanted to.
And so, let's again, take a quick look
at the documentation.
So let's say, github sharp,
but actually their own website
is a bit better, a bit more complete.
So let's click that link here, and so then
here we can come to resizing,
which is what we're currently doing
and then here is what I was just talking about.
Alright, so the default here is that image
will be cropped in order to cover
both the provided dimensions.
But we can also choose contain, fill, inside, or outside.
And, we would do that by setting the options here.
So we can set width, height, and then as a third option,
we could set this options object
where we can then define the fit.
We could also define the position,
which is center by default.
You see that there's all kinds of stuff
that we could really define to fine tune
our image processing.
But in this case, what we have is enough.
So let's move on to the next step.
Because what I want to do next is actually
convert the images always to jpeg, okay?
And for that, we use to format,
and then jpeg.
We can also then define the quality of this jpeg.
So basically to compress it a little bit
so that it doesn't take up so much space
and so for that, we use the jpeg method,
and set an option in this object with quality
and let's say 90 percent here, alright?
So each method into its own line here
that's much nicer, but actually we're not done.
We're almost done, but not entirely.
Because now, in the end,
we then, finally want to write it to a file on our disk.
And so for that, we can use to file,
now this method here actually needs
the entire path to the file.
So basically public
images, slash, users,
and then finally here the file name, alright?
So let's get that actually from what
we had here before.
Because of course, we want our images
to have a similar format.
Alright, so let's copy that.
But actually I will not put it right here.
Instead, I will actually save it to
request dot file dot file name.
Now why am I doing it like this?
Well it's because right now this file
name is not defined.
So, when we decide to save the image into memory
so as a buffer, the file name will not really get set,
but we really need that file name
in our other middleware function, right?
So that's down here in update me right here.
So we rely on request dot file dot file name
in order to save the file name into our database, right?
And so actually, we should define that.
And so, previously it was of course defined
by the multer upload that we had, but since
that is gone now, we should then basically redefine it here.
Okay?
Then here, actually, we can get rid of this part
of the extension, because we already know
that it will always be a jpeg.
Because of this to format, okay?
And so here, we can simply put jpeg.
So there's no need to get the file extension.
And so now here,
we can then use that.
Req dot file dot file name,
and that's actually it.
Okay?
So all we need to do now to finish
is to then actually call the next middleware in the stack.
And so that will be the update me handler function.
So of course, let's now actually test that.
So, we no longer need this one.
Let's come here to Postman,
and now the user that I want to update
is called arrav, I think.
Let's take a look here at our data very quick.
And so yeah, so this is the non square image
that we're going to be uploading now
and actually you see the size here
which is 1000 times 1500,
and so let's later compare that with
our resized uploaded image.
Alright.
Anyway, let's now get the name for arrav
Actually we don't need, they're always the same so
arrav like this, so let's log in.
So that we can then update it
and you see that right now is image here is user 11.
And just to see it a bit better
let's actually update,
let's actually log in, into our web application
using that user.
So test one, two, three, four.
Alright, so that is the current image
and now let's go ahead and update that.
Select files, and here is our image
open that and let's see what happens.
And we're done.
That was actually very quick,
so let's see if it's correct.
Well at least the name here seems correct.
If we take a look at our users now here,
that's in public, or right here.
So that should be the one
actually it's not.
And actually it's nowhere to be found.
Let's reload,
ah, and here it is.
Now, that's the one.
So you see that now it's at 500 times 500
it's much smaller here,
so 55 compared to the 315 we had before.
So that's a lot better,
and as you will see here, it should
now be updated here as well.
And that's perfect.
So the face is actually right in the middle here.
So that resizing really went kinda perfect.
Cool.
And I hope you will find some use
for this kind of image processing in
your own applications as well.
So just to quickly recap what did we do here.
Well we created a new middleware function
that is going to be running right after
the photo is actually uploaded.
And that upload is now actually happening
to a buffer and no longer directly to the file system.
Right?
And so that's why we use this memory storage here,
but of course this multer filter here
is still working.
And so we can still only upload images, alright?
So then here in that middleware
we put that image's file name on
request dot file dot file name
so that we can then use it in the update me.
Alright, and then here we have the
actual image processing itself.
Where we first resized it to a square
and then formatted to a jpeg
with a quality of 90 percent, and finally
we then write that file into our file system
to the exact same folder that we specified also before.
Alright, so this is how it works
when you need some image processing,
but if you do not need it, then of course
you can keep using it this way, okay?
And so that's really important
that we learned how to do it
in both ways here.
Alright, next up in the next video
we will then actually make this form here work
so that we can upload to user photos
directly from here.