All right.
So let's now create a new booking document in our database
whenever a user successfully purchases a tour.
So we're back here in the booking controller
and in the raw tender,
which creates the checkout sessions, right?
And remember that here we have this success url
and this url is the basis of the functionality
that we're going to implement in this lecture.
So whenever a check out is successful,
the browser will automatically go to this url,
which right now is basically simply our homepage, right?
It's also at this point in time,
so when a checkout is successful that we want to create
a new booking, right?
So basically we want to create a new booking
whenever this url here is accessed.
Now we could now create a new route for this success,
but then we would have to create a whole new page
and that's not really worth it in this case.
And that's because what we're going to do in this lecture
is only a temporary solution anyway
because it's not really secure, okay?
So remember how we said some lectures ago
and that nice diagram that later when a website
is actually deployed on a server we will get access
to the session object once the purchase is completed
using Stripe Webhooks.
And so these webhooks will then be perfect
for us to create a new booking.
Okay?
But for now, since we can't do that yet,
let's use a work around,
which is simply to put the data that we need to create
a new booking right into this url as a query string.
Okay?
And we need to create a query string because Stripe
will just make a get request to this url here,
and so we cannot really send a body or any data with it
except for the query string.
All right?
So let's do that and what we need here is basically
the three required fields in our booking model.
So tour, user,
and price.
So
tour
is equal to
req.params
.tourid
right?
So what did I do here?
So that's correct.
Next up we need the user.
So user,
which is at request
.user
.id.
And finally we need the price,
which is
at tour
.price.
All right.
Now as I said before,
this is of course not secure at all
because right now anyone who knows this url structure here
could simply call it without going through the checkout
process, right?
And so anyone really could just book a tour
without having to pay.
All they'd have to do is to open this url
with the tour, user, and price
and then they would automatically create a new booking
without even paying, okay?
So again, not really secure,
but for now as a work around it works just fine
because not many people will of course will know
that this our success url.
Okay?
Because actually we're going to hide that fact a little bit
in a second, okay?
So let's now create the function that will actually create
the new booking in the database.
So that's going to exports
dot
create
booking
checkout
and it's called create booking checkout
because later on we will also have create booking,
which will then be accessible from our bookings API.
All right.
Anyway.
Here as always.
And let's start by getting our data from the query string.
And so for that I'm going to use the structuring.
So tour,
user,
and price are available at request
.query.
So remember that is the query string.
Then we actually only want to create a new booking
if all of these here are specified.
And so basically we say that if they don't exist
then we turn and go to the next middleware.
So that's our very standard procedure, right?
So we say that if there is no tour and
no user
and
no price.
So basically we require that all on them exist.
And so in that case,
we go to the next middleware.
Now what exactly is the next middleware actually?
Well remember that we want to create a new booking
on this home url.
So this one here.
Because again that is the url that is called
whenever a purchase is successful with Stripe.
And so what we need to do is add this middleware function
that we're creating right now onto the middleware stack
of this route handler.
So what route handler is that?
Well it's in view routes and it is this one,
right?
So that probably sounds a bit confusing.
But again this is the route that will be hit
when a credit card is successfully charged.
And so this is also the point of time where we want
to create a new booking.
And so here is where we need to add that middleware function
so let's actually do that
and require our controller
and now we'll just duplicate this here.
So booking controller and now I will actually edit here
right at the beginning cause it doesn't really matter
if we're logged in or not for this.
So bookingcontroller.get,
or actually dot
create
bookingcheckout.
Give it a save and
okay.
And again this is here just kind of temporary
until we actually have our websites deployed to a server
where we will then be able to create a better solution
for this.
Okay?
So here in the booking controller
it is now time to actually create that new booking.
And so actually we now need to import that model.
So let's do that here.
Booking
and
booking model here as well.
And for some reason here I have these weird path.
So these don't make any sense at all.
I'm not sure why I wrote them like this back then.
So what we have there is exactly the same as this.
But of course this is more readable.
Anyway.
Let's now create that booking.
And so for that we will have to await
booking
.create
with an object
of
tour,
user,
and price.
And that's it.
Now we also need to mark this one here as async
and as always
catchasync.
Okay?
And we're not saving this into any variable
well because we don't really need it.
We're not going to send this back as an API response.
At this point all we want to do here is create
that new document, okay?
Next up we could then say
next, like this.
And so that would then go the next middleware
but that's not really ideal.
So again keep in mind that the next middleware
in the stack is of course this one
and the get overview.
So basically the function that it's going to render
our page.
But remember that this url is all of this.
So all this with all this data here.
And so again that's not secure at all.
And so at least let's make it a little bit more secure,
all right?
And so what we can do here is to basically
redirect the application now to only this
url.
And so basically you're removing the query string
from the original url.
And so actually we're now going to use something
we never used before.
So that's great, right?
So we're going to use redirect.
All right?
So now what we want is the entire url,
but without the query string.
So what we could do is to just
kind of cheat and copy
this here.
But let's make it a bit more elegant.
So what we're doing is request
.theoriginalurl,
which we already used before.
And so that's the entire url basically
from which the request came.
And so now what we need to do is to split it
by the question mark.
Right?
Because that's the divider between the
part that we actually want and the query string.
So if we split this by the question mark,
then we will have an array where the first element is this
and the second element is all of the rest.
So the query string itself.
And so here we take the first element
and so that is then our homepage.
So our route url.
And what redirect here does is basically to create
a new request but to this new url that we passed in there.
All right?
So this will now create yet another request
to our route url.
So we're again gonna hit this route.
And so once more we will hit this middleware here.
So the one that we're just creating.
So for the second time we're going to be hitting that
but now the tour, user, and price are no longer defined.
And so then we will go to the next middleware,
which finally is the get overview handler function,
which then we'll just render the homepage, okay?
Made sense?
So this is kind of circular then.
So basically in the beginning we're gonna hit
this route here.
Then a new booking here is created
and we redirect the application again to this route,
this time without the query string.
And so without the query string
and this middleware,
we passed right to the next one.
And so only then we get to is logged in
and get overview.
All right?
And so that's actually it, all right?
Well that's just right here that this is only temporary
because it's
unsecure.
Everyone can make bookings
without paying.
So again that would be terrible for the business.
Okay, now it's time to test this out.
And so actually I want to do it with that other user
that we created which is jonas@mailsac.
And that's because I want to see if we actually get
that email receipt from Stripe.
So let's log in with that user
onto our website.
So
log out.
Well that's not working.
That's weird.
Let's reload.
And that should be working so let's see
if we have some error in our javascript.
Because that is actually client facing
and we get Stripe is not defined.
Let's see if we have the same error here on this page,
which we shouldn't, right?
And actually it's not there,
but back on all tours.
Yeah, it's there.
So the solution to that is to move it from the tour
basically to all of the pages.
All right?
So for some reason the parcel bundler does it so
that it needs to be
here in the main scope for all of them.
So for all the pages, okay?
So actually let's put that at the bottom
right here before our bundle.
All right?
Try that again and so now we're good to go.
So log out and
that worked.
Now log in.
Of course now our copy is gone.
One two three four.
No, that's not correct.
Test one two three four.
So I guess I changed the password at some point,
so let's try a new password,
which is not working either.
Let's try pass one two three four
and that worked.
So it's not test one two three four,
but pass one two three four.
At least here in my case.
So let's try to book the
let's say the sports lover.
All right.
Down here.
Book tour
and that still works
and that's the expensive one.
(laughs)
So four two four two and then four two
all the way to the end.
Then here's some month and here is some number.
Let's say my entire name here
and now let's hit pay.
And I'll take a look at the url bar.
And indeed we get our homepage so our route url
without any of the query string that we specified before.
So that means that something is working.
So let's take a look at compass and click up here to reload
and we get our bookings collection.
And that's a good sign.
And indeed here we go.
Our very first document is created.
So remember that was that price.
Let's also take a look at the user's id
which is this one ending in eight E three B.
So eight E three B, that's correct.
And I'm assuming that the tour is also going to be correct.
So perfect.
That worked as well
and so now we really have a way of creating bookings
whenever a booking happens with Stripe.
Let's also quickly checkout our dashboards here again.
That's really fun.
And I guess I just have to reload here.
So let's see.
Here is jonas at whatever we named that is.
We've got the sports lover
and
perfect.
That's working now.
And the final task.
Let's now check out mailsac.
Mail
sac
.com
and see if I got my
email there.
And well actually I did not,
but that's not a big deal.
I'm not sure maybe it just doesn't work with test data.
And so for now that's all I have to show you
about Stripe integration.
Now again once a website is deployed,
we will then actually use Stripe Webhooks
in order to create bookings in a more secure
and much better way.
All right?
So let's just again take a minute to recap what we did here.
So basically we added
all the variables that we need to create a new booking
to the success url.
Then we added a new middleware function here to the stack
of that exact route.
So this one here.
And so like this whenever this url here is hit
we will attempt to create a new booking.
All right?
But that new booking is of course only created
when the tour, user, and price are specified in the query.
And so in this middleware function,
if they are specified on the query well then we create
a new booking in here.
Then after that is done we remove the query string
from the url in order to make the whole process
a bit less transparent for the user.
Basically so that whole query string doesn't show up
in our browser's url bar.
And then down here we redirect our application
to this new route url here, okay?
And so this way this middleware here will be skipped
and then our normal homepage will simply get rendered.
All right?
Let's just get rid of this app error here
and the factory we will actually need in the next lecture.
So in that next lecture we will actually take care
of implementing one last piece of our website,
which basically is this page here for my bookings.
And what this page will do is to basically display
one tour card for each of the tours that we have booked.
So looking pretty similar to this homepage,
but only with the tours that the currently logged in user
has booked, all right?
So that's a nice feature for a website, right?
And so let's take care of that in the next one.