Hello and welcome back to the course.
My name is Vitale and today I'm going to talk about the Pareto Principle.
It is an exciting topic used by the businesses daily hourly and probably every minute and every second.
Somewhere in the world it's an important principle of prioritization and I am so keen to share some
tips and tricks a bit of a history and some core my whole understanding of this prince.
So let's dig into it.
We'll start with a bit of a history and it's going to tell you how these principle originated.
It's all started from a person called Will Fred-O Perito.
He was the Italian economist and in his study of course the economy politic Berita has observed a very
important correlation.
When he started the ownership of Eataly he realized that roughly 80 percent of all Italian land has
been owned by 20 percent of the population.
Disproportioned surprise Perito and he did a few service on other countries and to his great surprise
these proportions stayed roughly the same.
80:20 80 percent of Whilce land or similar metric has been owned by 20 percent of the population.
That was exciting and lead to later on a big discovery of this principle.
But there was another person who actually was my colleague management consultant.
His name was Joseph Duren he was specializing in quality management systems.
And in his work Joseph Ciaran observed that quite a handful of flaws of the system usually cost the
majority of the issues that happened with that system being being accustomed.
And knowing the work of will for the Perito Joseph jur on has made and has made an observation that
most likely this principle is of a global nature not only applicable to the economy or the quality management
but could be something bigger.
And he was probably right.
These days this principle is used every day in every business and is of very important nature.
Let me give you a few basics of this principle.
So we're on the same page.
If you have a system and some input into the system you obviously get something in return which is outputs.
So as an example I'm going to give you as an input something like tasks your effort in many hours your
investments as a money as outputs you could get something like the benefits or sales or return on your
investment.
So the principal says that majority of the outputs and let's say 80 percent is closely attributed to
the minority to the vital views of the inputs which is roughly 20 percent based on the broader principle
and this disproportion is super important and of big significance.
So I'll probably state it again roughly 80 percent of the outputs are closely associated with 20 percent
of the inputs.
Let me give you a few examples.
So it is crystal clear what we're talking about.
Imagine you own a supermarket and the breeder principle applied to the sales of that supermarket of
your supermarket would say that roughly 80 percent of all the sales come from just a handful 20 percent
of the customers that visit that supermarket.
Why and how could it be.
Well the 20 percent of your customers could be the ones that live nearby and stop in your supermarket
very often.
They could be the ones that have large families and therefore their basket product basket is pretty
big every time they go to the supermarket.
They also could be people who follow the healthy lifestyle and prefer to buy things are getting things
and things that are
more expensive to manufacture healthier and therefore average amount of money that they leave on the
table for the same product is higher than the majority of the rest of the customers.
That's why you're just a handful of customers 20 percent could have a larger impact on your business
on your supermarket sales.
Why is this important you might ask.
Well if you are the owner of the supermarket and you are trying to implement a customer loyalty program
which is effectively aimed at retaining your customers making sure that they are super happy with your
supermarket and are not going to go to your competitor whom would you target would you have a blanket
policy and applied to 100 percent of the customers and make it a uniform average kind of program or
would you try to tailor it to a specific group to the 20 percent of the customers that actually bring
you 80 percent of the benefit.
That's a food for thought and effectively it can shape your policy.
It can make it effective one and it can help protect your majority of your income.
All the sales in that supermarket.
There are a few other examples that I would like to share with you and probably less or less comprehensively
as the one with the supermarket.
But just to give you a flavor of how this principle can be applied in the real life the Baree the principle
states.
If we apply to the traffic on the streets that's 80 percent of all traffic accidents are probably associated
associated with just a handful of drivers roughly 20 percent.
And if we look at the statistics we probably will find that this principle holds truth.
So how does the government and police can use these outputs.
Well if we know the socio demographic characteristics of the these 20 percent of the drivers who usually
offend police could potentially be providing the educational programs for that sort of demographics.
Let it be for example students or if there are people who I'm just speculating so this is not set in
stone or grounded and if for example most of the traffic accidents come from people of the let's say
25 to 30 years of age hypothetically on Friday nights after having business drinks or whatnot then the
police efforts for breathalyzer potentially should be ending.
Exactly that social group and for that specific time.
So privatization is quite important.
And forward to give you another example which can be applied to your real life and to your everyday
life.
If you look at your apartment the one that you're living in at the moment hot whether it's a house you're
renting a room or you sharing something like with your parents.
And if you think of all the area in that habitat the breeder principle states that 80 percent of your
time is probably spent in the 20 percent of the area of that apartment.
How can we use it in the everyday life.
Well imagine you are planning to buy a house whether it's your second house first house first apartment
whether you will be thinking about characteristics or criteria to buy that house.
You might want to consider.
Where do you spend most of your time so you can emphasize and prioritize those features in the house
that you are targeting.
And the principle is your friend in that this were a couple of examples that I wanted to give you.
Let me share a few variations to the principle that could be quite interesting.
First of all 80:20 is not a rule set in stone and always has to be the truth.
The rule could be 70 20 95 1.
The main thing in the break the principle is that there is a disproportion what particular disproportion
and what particular ratio that you will find will depend a lot on the situation you're in one not the
two numbers on the left and right hand side.
They shouldn't add up to 100 percent because we are comparing different types of measures.
Inputs and outputs do not need to be in the same and usually not the same thing that we are comparing.
So it's like comparing apples and oranges.
So 70 20 altogether is 90.
Ken Stillstand and other thing is a specific example I wanted to give this is so-called 1 percent instant
participation rule the rule states that out of all people who are on the Internet 90 percent of the
people usually tend to do the browsing on the collaboration websites.
Nine percent of the people usually leave comments or edit content and only 1 percent actually active
content creators.
So when you think of the Web sites like for example Wikipedia or let me speculate linked in the content
the articles and the things that are being produced are likely to be done by only 1 percent of the visitors
or the users up there.
Why is it important.
I think you can already get the drift and understand that attracting those people to developing content
will be much easier if you don't do it as a broad brush but you do it in a very laser focused way.
Another variation is the 90 90 rule.
It is a quite humorous way of talking about the code development.
So if the way in 99 to rule goes is the first 90 percent of the code developed developed by a developer
or programmer accounts for 90 percent of his or her time.
But the remaining 10 percent of the code will probably require additional 90 percent of the time.
So obviously the time cannot add up to 180 percent.
When you think about it this way but what it says that the if you are to normalized back to 100 percent
the majority of the code is done in an disproportionate amount of time then the remaining bits of the
code 10 percent.
So roughly the same amount of time spent 90 percent and 90 percent as units of time for example.
But the output will be disproportional.
In the first instance it is 90 percent of the code and the second is 10 percent of the code.
So I think you got a drift by now of the period of principle.
I hope you are going to be enjoying this course and see you in the next tutorial by.