You guys welcome back to statistics for business only the Fed is very excited for you to be part of
this course.
Hope you're enjoying the tutorial so far.
Now in this area I'm going to take you on a quick walk through Africa.
How random is that.
So I'm in a small village here and I'm in on my morning walk.
Wanted to show you around while we're here.
I also wanted to give you a quick heads up.
Very soon you do me is going to ask you to leave a review for this course.
Now I know it can be difficult to judge the quality and value of course this already on home of the
Demetri's system has simply changed and they're asking you to leave your views earlier and earlier in
the course.
No we're not going to ask you to leave a five star review here but what I would like to ask is that
if you don't know the course well enough you're not familiar with totals well enough to rate a five
star course.
Then please scroll through the different topics that we cover and have a look at all the exciting things
that you will or
and hopefully once you see that that will give you the confidence to write this course the Passaro course.
If on the other hand you feel something is wrong with the course if you are unsatisfied about something.
If you're unhappy about something then please do let us know before you write.
Of course you can contact the produce and support team directly or you can leave a short message in
the course Q&amp;A.
And if your book is very valuable to us we'll get back to you or we'll fix up whatever the issue is
and then get back to you and hopefully that will give you the confidence right this course by course
now not notes.
If you feel something is wrong please do let us know.
But if you're satisfied of everything if you think that this is a great course and you're having fun
so far enjoying it and looking forward to the things you'll learn you feel that this is a five star
course.
Then please do appropriately so that the rest of the world will also know that this is a five star course
on statistics and they can learn this topic from here.
Thanks so much guys for being with us.
It is a very exciting a journey as you have ahead of you.
Hope you enjoyed this the journey this little walk through Africa.
And I look for seniors inside and be analyzing.