Hello welcome back to the course on statistics.
Today we're talking about the rejection region.
So previously we saw the steps that are involved in hypothesis testing.
And today we're going to see a alternative way of testing hypotheses.
It's just a bit different towards the end.
Otherwise everything is going to be the same.
So let's have a look.
You've probably seen this chart before somewhere online or in other research that you might have been
reading about or maybe when you were doing a stats course back in the day.
So here we've got a rejection region.
And as you saw previously we did the hypothesis testing we followed the rejection region.
So how is this approach different.
So let's have a look here we've got the problem from the previous tutorial where we've got the millennials
who in 2015 used to watch twenty six and a half hours of TV per week.
And now you've surveyed 50 of them or 50 random millennials and you found that 24 like they watch about
24 hours of TV per week.
And we went through the analysis and we showed that we can reject the null hypothesis with at least
a 95 percent confidence.
So now what are we going to do is we're going to do exactly the same thing we've learned even plotted
our distribution.
So this is the sampling distribution and we've done all these calculations.
But now when we proceed we calculate the score just as we did previously.
And it turns out to be one minus one point seventy seven.
And that's why our X bar is actually sitting here not as we thought originally was over there but now
instead of going to the Zad table we're here and finding minus one point seventy seven what are we going
to do.
We're going to reverse engineer the situation we're going to look in this table.
Let's zoom in a little bit.
So now we're going to look for the opposite.
We're going to look for zero.
We're going to look at 5 percent in the state.
We're going to we wants to find Zed such that it is a 5 percent chance of something falling into this
area because we want to reject our hypothesis with a 95 percent confidence.
So therefore we want to see where it is zed which is responsible for 5 percent is sitting.
And so we look for 5 percent in our table.
You can see you at 0.5 375 to six.
So as that increases this primary this value decreases of course because as that gets to that goes more
to the left the percentage decreases.
So as you can see we going down to 0.5 or fives or four point four 9:5.
So therefore you're Zed at which 5 percent will fall into there is about this that so minus 1 6 4.
But to be safe is to take this one because this is just a bit greater than 5 percent.
You want it to be a bit less than 5 percent rather than émigrés.
So the best to go with here is minus 1 point 6 5 1 6 1.6 5.
So this from this value you can tell that the Zehr that you're looking for is minus 1.6 feet and that's
going to be used critical and you might have heard this somewhere that is your.
Zed cret or Zed critical.
So if now we go back here we're going to calculate so pick the critical the p the critical p value that
we're looking for is 5 percent and therefore we've found that Zed critical is minus 1.6 5.
And the beauty about this approach is that Zayd critical is not going to change that table.
Or that said table as its artistic table is never going to change it's always going to be like this.
So if you just remember for yourself that if you're always testing and 5 percent confidence you just
remember for yourself minus 1.6 five years you've said that you are looking for then you don't really
have to use that table you just remember OK this value just compared to minus 1.6 5.
And the way you compare it is like you draw.
So as you go here you draw the Xat critical.
There it is.
So it is about minus 1.6 five standard deviations away from the mean.
So that's one sound deviation that's a half that's about 6 1 0 points 1.6 and there's one point six
five standard deviations away from the mean.
And then you just color the skin.
So there you go that's your rejection region.
That's what we're looking at so that's the rejection region and therefore anything or the likelihood
what it's telling us is that the likelihood of picking of randomly picking a sample size from this rejection
region is always going to be less than 5 percent.
The further you go to the left the lower it will be.
But even if you pick one just right on the rejection region on the borderline It will only be 5 percent
likely.
And that's what's called the rejection region.
As long as you've picked a sample from here randomly You can reject the null hypothesis meaning that
it is so unlikely that this happened that there's probably something fishy going on that this null hypothesis
isn't actually correct that our assumption is incorrect.
We don't live in that universe we live in this universe and therefore that's how it works so that's
two approaches to the same problem.
WALLACE First finalizes that is a critical minus one point sixty five hours it is minus one point seventy
seven.
This is lower than this so we're further away from the mean.
Remember if you're going to be doing on the other side then you want to be.
This has to be greater than this because it's going to be positive.
So you want to be further away from that.
That's why this helps I think is a good idea to always draw this sketch at all just to understand what's
going on so you remember to do the right comparison so we can reject the null hypothesis and there and
we can accept the alternative hypothesis I mean has decreased.
So there we go that's two different approaches slightly different very slightly different.
You can see the whole thing is the same we're still using the sampling distribution.
We're still calculating the sampling mean the sampling standard deviation same formulas we're using
the central and the theorem we're then calculating we know our eggs bar with calking Nozette score and
then only the only difference is off to calculate the score in the first approach that we saw you go
to the table and you find your score that you've calculated.
There it is.
So mine is 1.7 7.
So you know exactly the percentage likelihood of that happening 0.03 8 4 so three point eighty four
percent.
So therefore you could reject this hypothesis even if a 96 percentage confidence because this is lower
than 4 percent then yeah this is a long and 4 percent or whether it was a problem or one that we had
privey in the Prius or Toral in this to trial what we did is we reverse engineered the situation we
looked for Zero Point or five or five or it was a point of 195 that once that's a 5 percent and then
we just looked at the Zed's critical so minus 6 minus 1.6 5.
So and then we calculated well minus 1 some point 6 5 because that Croisette is less than that critical
is like further away from the mean.
Is it critical therefore we just reject this hypothesis.
So in this case we just say that's why it's it's also convenient to say that we reject it for 95 degree
percent confidence instead of always changing it up and saying that all this time is 96 percent degree
confidence stems 97 percent degree confidence.
Just because you always have to use that first approach to find out the exact degree of confidence.
If we set a threshold and say 95 percent degree of confidence is sufficient for us then we can also
use the second approach and it's up to you what you like that or so.
This might be faster if you just remember the minus 1.6 five.
It corresponds to the 95 percent degree of confidence or symmetrically at 1.6 five on this side and
therefore you can just use that without having to look at that table so that can be a bit faster.
So you go other than that these two approaches are identical in their results and methodology that they
are relying on no results at the yield and the methodology that they're relying on.
So I hope you enjoy this Tauriel and hopefully this is starting to make you come all come together and
further down the section of course we're going to have a look at more and more examples of how to apply
hypothesis testing to real world problems.
And I can't wait to see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.