Hello and welcome back to a course in statistics.
Have you ever heard the term normalize.
Let's normalize this data set.
What does that even mean.
Well today you'll find out that and much much more.
So let's get started here.
We're talking about does that score.
All right so this is our normal distribution.
And as we've discussed previously there's our center or the mean right now it's zero.
Then we've got the standard deviations going either way.
And within the first standard deviation left and right you will always have in a normal distribution
you will always have sixty eight point two percent of your observation so that's how many observations
are going to fall between minus 1 center mission and a plus months and duration then within the next
two.
So if you take the total of minus two standard deviations to Tucson which has been in this area you
will always get ninety five point four percent of your observations and then between ministries and
missions these penetrations you will get pretty much all of them you'll get ninety nine point eight
percent of are observations falling inside.
Three three sandwiches or three.
Either way minus three two plus three.
That's that's really interesting.
But what if I want to find out how many observations will fall into for instance one and a half a standard
deviation is just no reason.
We're just curious what will happen if we look at one and a half and deviations or two and a half or
half a standard deviation.
How many observations will fall into that part of the normal distribution.
And this is where the Zed's score comes in and it's also called the standard score and also is called
sometimes the normal score.
Let's have a look at that.
So let's get rid of all of those writings on our standard deviation and more will let's put it at not
at a non-zero mean.
So it's sitting somewhere at a myu.
That's the mean it's not centered around 0 percent or on some other value and it will have a standard
deviation of Sigma.
So just a very general kind of normal distribution.
And now let's have a look at that's one place that we were interested in.
So let's say for instance that's about 1.6.
We're interested in 1.6 standard deviations.
How many observations are going to fall into this part over here.
And that's going to mark that as x.
So what we need to do is we need to calculate the distance First of all first.
Well the point here is we need to get to the score.
And so how we're going to introduce it.
We need to first calculate the distance from the center to X and that's done through just you just check
this line.
So basically that's a representation of that.
And there it is X minus mue that's going to be our distance.
If you just subtract one from the other you'll get the difference and bear in mind that this is a side
difference so if you're x's on the left it'll still be X minus MU and will be negative.
So the distance this way is negative that this was this way is positive that's very important as well.
And the zent score is defined as X minus myu divided by Sigma and that is essentially how many standard
deviations a mile away.
So if that's Sigma that's X minus.
If you divide x my is me by Sigma you will see that it took about 1 second division a ha ok plus about
0.6 So one wanted 1.6 are 1.6 standard deviations away from myu that's where X is residing and that's
what that formula is saying.
And that also explains the name well not the name not the escort name but the standard score or the
normal normal score or name or sometimes are also called these Zad variables it can be called Zed score
standard score normal score or it can be called a normal variable normalized variable as well.
So basically what this this kind of relates back to what we said at the start about normalization when
you hear people say Let's normalize this database are not in our database that's different.
Let's normalize this dataset or Let's normalize these values.
That's exactly what they're saying they're saying.
All right so let's find the mean of these values then let's find the standard deviation of these values
of these set of values and let's just subtract X minus mood to put this whole.
When you do that mue because if you put plug myu in here instead of X ules you'll get a zero.
So that basically moves this whole distribution to zero to the mean of zero.
So if you apply that to all of the values and not just to calculate the set score for x you actually
apply to all the values and you'll get.
You'll move this distribution to a mean of 0 and divide Verstand division.
Basically that means that you will raise there in the end you will get a standard deviation of 1 and
so any distribution with a or any normal suspicion with a mean of zero and deviation one is called a
normalized standard distribution or normalized it is called normalized because now all of the variables
conform to the to the philosophy that if you take the mean you'll get zero and if you've clicked the
send additional be one.
And that's that's essentially what does that square you do and furie have a normalized set of variables.
Then the zeds core will just basically.
So you'll have zero here you'll have one for standard deviation you have to as citizens score will be
just your coordinates you won't and you will no longer need subtract because it's already 0.
You will no longer need to divide by Sigma because it's already once so you'll just have to look at
the coordinates and you'll get.
OK 1.6.
In either case it's not normalized.
So that's why we calculating X minus MU and Sigma and we can see that visually we can say it's about
one point six standard deviations away.
All right well that's great but how do we now find out what is a probability.
Well we.
It is possible and this is how we can do it so we can find the probability of a random variable that
we pick from this distribution of it falling into this shaded area over here on the left.
And how is that done.
Well that is done through a table.
Once you have all of these distributions all these Once you have your distribution normalized then you
have the Zed score or you just calculate the zero score you can go and you can find a table basically
just go to Google and if you look for Zed's score table this is the first one that pops up this sounds
pretty good.
So university of Florida I believe.
Thank you very much and for sharing this on the Internet.
So here if you scroll down you'll see what exactly that saying it's saying.
OK so where does that score if that's your score over here on the left because it's negative.
You can see these negatives scores then.
This is the stable We'll tell you the probability of something being here.
If your score is positive like here you'll see that this table will tell you of the possibility of it
being in that whole area.
So that's fine as score I at core as I remember was about approximately 1.6.
So let's do that.
So there's one 1.6 and then this is the next digit So 1.6 this is your first two digits all the digit
before the column or the digit after the comma after the decimal.
And then you add 1.6 and then you 1 0 0 so you don't want another any more digits.
Although if you are in one point sixty one that's then that's your entry.
You win one point sixty two that's your entry 1.6 that's your entry.
So zero point nine four or five.
OK so that is the probability.
94 percent is a probability that a variable is going to fall 94 percent in the ninety four point ninety
four and a half percent is the probability the variable will fall in this area over here which is looks
plausible just by looking at and looking at the size here.
But if we want this area over here between the center and this then we need to subtract how much.
I'll let you I'll let you guess this one.
How much do we need to subtract from.
So this is 94 and a half percent.
How much is this part on the left of the center.
Oh that's right it's 50 percent so we just need to subtract 50 percent.
So 94 and a half minus 50 makes it 44 and a half cents is 44 and a half percent probability that you
will pick a variable between the center and 1.6 standard deviations to the right or in our case between
the mean and X whenever x may have been in the original data set before we calculate that score.
So there we go.
That's that's how it works and that's how you get those percentages.
You might be wondering yourself why do we even need to do this.
But all of this will become much clearer in the next tutorial when we will.
We're going to be starting to apply the central limit theorem.
In practice definitely we're going to need this knowledge.
And so here just the notes on these ninety four point five percent that's going to happen here is going
to be picked from here.
And also that actually means that there's going to be five point five percent there's going to be pick
from here.
And as a training exercise before the next Tauriel I highly encourage you to double check these values
so just go to the table and find out what's there.
Just verify that this probability is correct.
What is the probability of picking a random variable between 0 and 1 sigma.
So check if you will get thirty four point one percent.
You're going to have to need to do the same process.
You're going to need to take this side subtract 50 percent and see what you get.
Or check one of these and see what you get for the left side of things.
And on that belt top your prejudice Tauriel and I will see you on the next one.
Until then happy analyzing.