Hello and welcome back to Pluralsight and this module,
Gaining Insights via AWS Systems Manager OpsCenter,
where we will discover this service and its potential for Globomantics
to more deeply understand events in the environment and respond to them
much faster than they were ever able to.
My name is David O'Brien, and in this module,
we will cover the following topics.
We will introduce AWS Systems Manager OpsCenter and how it can support
companies like Globomantics that want to leverage as much of AWS's managed
offerings as possible for the operations teams.
We will then discover the process that integrates
our AWS account into OpsCenter, how it works,
and the resources the process creates.
When that is done,
we will understand what role CloudWatch plays in all of this
when creating OpsCenter OpsItems and how we can work with
OpsCenter to create custom rules.
Systems Manager OpsCenter is the one central location
where operations teams can go to view, investigate,
and resolve work items.
Work items are also known as OpsItems in the context of OpsCenter.
OpsCenter aims to reduce the Mean Time To Resolution,
also known as MTTR,
by giving deep insights into what happened leading up to an event.
It leverages other AWS services, mainly CloudWatch and CloudWatch events,
but can also leverage Systems Manager Automation runbooks to help
automatically solve OpsItems and any issues that arose from the
events that caused the creation of an OpsItem.
These OpsItems are based on events that happen on our AWS
platform or even inside our applications and are either
created automatically or manually.
Operations teams can use OpsCenter for investigation and remediation purposes
and integrate into existing case management systems via its public APIs or use OpsCenter for their complete case management.