In this demo,
we will learn about the process to enable Systems
Manager OpsCenter on our AWS account.
Back in the Systems Manager console,
we first navigate to OpsCenter and see that there really isn't too much
to see right now as we haven't enabled OpsCenter yet.
For this to happen, we click on Get Started and,
interestingly enough, we now find ourselves in the Explorer and OpsCenter setup.
AWS created an integrated setup experience for these two
services that makes it easier to get started.
In this integrated setup, two things will happen.
OpsCenter requires IAM roles or permissions to do its job,
which is essentially to interact with other
services and aggregate data from them.
That's what the first role here is for.
And then we need another role, which is used by CloudWatch to create OpsItems.
We can see what the IAM role permission and trust policy will look like.
There's no way to not have these roles created.
But later on we will see that we can always use other
roles that might fit our use case better.
The other thing that will happen is that the setup process
allows us to have default rules created that,
if triggered, automatically create OpsItems.
These rules are going to be CloudWatch event on AWS Config rules and are
really a collection of commonly used rules. This collection of default rules
changes over time and can be viewed in the Systems Manager User Guide. We
want to have those default rules created,
so we keep the box ticked.
One click on Enable OpsCenter here and we are
forwarded to the OpsCenter summary page.
This means the integrated setup experience is done now.
So let's have a look at the IAM roles by first browsing to
IAM and then clicking here on Roles.
We can see the two roles that were created by the setup
experience. If we wanted to, this would be opportunity to
make changes to any of those roles. But for now, the built‑in permissions will be sufficient.