We now know how to create and inspect parameters from the command
line on the console and why it is certainly already very powerful
to be able to get them from PowerShell.
It's also good to understand how Parameter Store integrates with other AWS
services. Out of the box, there's native integration to the EC2 service, ECS,
the Container Service, Lambda, CloudFormation,
the Code Suite, and, of course, the other Systems Manager services.
How? Simple, by referencing the parameter by its key name
and optionally the parameters version.
No need for hard coding values into scripts or using complicated helper
scripts to get secrets out of secret managers and worrying about keeping them
safe at the same time. For unencrypted parameters,
that's all we need to do. For encrypted parameters,
there's usually a bit of coding involved, but not much, as we will see in the next demo.