In this demo, we will discover what working with OpsCenter is like,
from configuring a new CloudWatch event rule to resolving an OpsCenter OpsItem.
As always,
we start in the Systems Manager console and make our way over to OpsCenter.
Right now, the summary isn't showing us anything,
which is expected as our account doesn't have much activity at the moment.
Over on the OpsItems tab, we can configure the sources,
which really means we can configure the CloudWatch event
rules and what they mean in our company's context when it
comes to how we categorize them, their severity,
and if you want them enabled or disabled.
Here we can see all the default rules that we created in our first demo.
Now let's go to CloudWatch to configure a new rule.
Here in the CloudWatch console, we have to go to Events and Rules.
We can see all the same rules here that we just saw
over on the OpsCenter console.
The only difference here is we can click on Create rule to create a new one.
We want to make sure that we get alerted whenever
something or someone stops an EC2 instance.
This shouldn't happen without the operations team knowing about it.
So that's a good scenario.
First off, all we need to configure is the event source.
In the Service Name drop‑down list,
we can see this very extensive list of services we can hook events up to.
For our use case, we search for EC2 and select this one.
In the Event Type drop‑down,
we can now see a list of events that we can be notified on.
The EC2 instance state‑change notification event sounds like the one we need.
We can be notified on any state changes, but that could get very noisy.
So we filter the state for the stopped state.
This means that whenever an EC2 instance's state
changes from whatever it was to stopped,
this rule gets triggered.
Also, for this rule, we want this to be applied to all our EC2 instances.
Down here,
we can see an example of the actual rule to verify that what we
have configured was what we expected to see.
We now have configured what we want to be notified on.
Next, we need to configure what should happen if an event like this occurs.
A very common use case is to invoke a Lambda function to do
certain tasks or to send an event to an SNS topic.
But we want it to create a OpsItem.
There isn't too much to configure now,
apart from which IAM rule we want CloudWatch events
to use to create this OpsItem.
We can have this process create a new role,
or we use the existing rule from the first demo,
which is exactly what we're going to do.
Next step, we configure the rule name and give it a description.
We'll click on Create rule.
Once that is done, we can see our rule now in the list of rules.
Let's now go ahead on get an OpsItem created by forcing this scenario.
We browse over to the EC2 console, check our running instances,
and we're going to select this (there is only one) instance and stop it.
Once the instance is stopped,
we expect this event to trigger the CloudWatch event
rule that we just created and that, in turn,
to create a Systems Manager OpsCenter OpsItem.
Now that the EC2 instance is stopped, let's head back over to OpsCenter.
As expected, we can now see that there's one open or in progress OpsItem.
We can click on it on already see some high‑level information about it.
For example,
we see that the OpsItem is related to the EC2 servers and
the EC2 instance state‑change event, when it was created,
and when it was last updated.
We can click on the event ID to get even more information.
The OpsItem shows us exactly which AWS resource is related to this OpsItem by
displaying the resource ARN and of what type this resource is.
Clicking on the resource, we get even more insights into the resource,
like the instance ID, its IP, DNS name,
and many other details that can help and simplify troubleshooting.
We can also see the instance tags,
which can help further identify what the resource is
being used for or who the owner is.
The CloudTrail logs can also be super helpful in understanding what
APIs were called in relation to the impacted resource.
Here we can see that our user Bob called the StopInstances API.
We can now have a conversation with this user to
understand why they stopped the instance.
Back on the overview, we can see the similar OpsItem menu,
which over time will probably show more OpsItems and will make it
even easier for operations teams to troubleshoot issues based on
past OpsItems and their resolutions.
Under Runbooks,
we can see Systems Manager automation runbooks that can potentially be used
by the service to remediate any of the issues we find.
There's one runbook called AWS‑RestartEC2Instance that we
could use to restart the impacted instance.
This could be an easy fix.
If something stopped an instance, let's just first try to restart it.
For this, however,
we need to go back to the instance and get the instance ID
as that will be an input to the runbook.
Let's search for the runbook again and execute it,
paste the instance ID in here, and say Execute.
The status shows that this runbook is now in progress,
and it is also now associated with this OpsItem.
Future OpsItems that are based on this event will automatically
show this runbook as a recommendation to the user.
Let's refresh this page and skip ahead to the completion of the runbook.
It's now successful, and we can click on the output here.
We can also save the output of the runbook to the
operational data of this OpsItem.
This means that for auditing and also future similar troubleshooting,
administrators can go back and check what was done.
We can easily see the runbook output in the operational data now.
Now that the instance rebooted and is running again,
we can set the OpsItem status to Resolved and can continue
working on our next items resting assured that future events like this will be resolved even faster.