Hello and welcome back to R
programming course and in the previous
tutorial we created this beautiful
visualization and in fact we actually
completed the challenge so we have done
what was expected of us and we created
this scatterplot and now we can
present it, so what's next? So what we're
going to learn in this tutorial?
Well we've so far learned how to import
data frames and how to work with them
and we know how to visualize
them however we haven't yet learned how
to create them. It would be great if we had
an opportunity to practice that,
well luckily our manager has just to run
into the office with an urgent request
for us. Let's have a look at it, you have
received an urgent update from a manager,
you are required to produce a second
scatterplot also illustrating birth rate
and internet usage statistics by country
however this time this scatterplot needs to
be categorized by countries/regions.
Additional data has been supplied in the
form of R vectors, so pretty much the
same thing as we did but instead of
categorizing by income group like we did
last time this time we need to categorize
by region so whether it's Africa, Asia,
Europe and so on and this time, the
additional data so we can continue
working for our existing data but also we're
going to add more data to our analysis
and it's going to be supplied in R
vectors. So let's go ahead and find that
data, that data is of course located at
www.superdatascience.com/rcourse,
one word and if you scroll
down here to section 5 data frames then
you'll find this third data set over
here country-region of vectors on third
link over here, so if we'd go ahead and
download that then what will be will be
a zip file that like you can see over
here and then once you unzip it and open
it in R, it will look like this.
So here we've got three vectors, so this
is like the actual file that you will
see and it's creating three vectors and
putting them into these three objects. All
you have to do is select all the code
and run it
so let's go ahead and do that and what
that will do is it will create these
three vectors squeeze here so cold
countries and regions so we can get rid
of this filter actually but we'll do
that later. So here we've got these three
vectors that we've created ABW, AFG so
what does this look like? This looks like
the codes of the countries, then the
countries themselves and the region's. Ok
so that's that's a good start right so
now we have this information H vector
has a hundred ninety five elements to it
which is the same as our data frame
which is it which is a good good thing
good sign but now the question is why
are the wisest information in vectors.
How do we put into a data frame? And
that's exactly what we're going to learn
today, so let's dive straight into the
tutorial.
Alright so section 5 and here we're
going to create a new section in our
code and we'll call it creating data
frames exciting tutorial ahead. Okay how
do we create a data frame?
Well we've already got the vectors, now
all we have to do is put the vectors
into a data frame and this is going to be
very similar to something we already
know and that something is the C bind
function. So this time, we're going to use a
function called data frame and don't
forget the dot in between. That's how
the function is called and now here you
need to pass the vectors that you want
to bind into a data frame. So let's pass
the vectors that we have, so this one's
going to be codes 2012, no let's start with country. So
countries 2012 data set that's the first
vector then we're going to pass the
codes 2012 data set and then we are going to
pass the region's. There you go, so you
can see I'm even starting to type with a
small letter here not a capital and its
prompting me for a capital so that's a
good thing.
Speeds up your coding as well. Alright so
there's our three vectors, I'm actually
going to put some new line so we can see
all of that. So just like the C bind
function does the data function will put
all of these into a data frame will not
a matrix, data frame this time
and if we run that you'll see that now
we have a mydf so now let's go and
check out mydf which is going to use
the head function to see the top rows.
So let's make some space over here and
let's make some space over here. So there you
can see, now we've got this new data
frame, now we have two data
frame we've got the stats data frame and the mydf data frame.
In the mydf data frame, you've got
the countries, the data set, the culture
for the data set and the region's.
Alright, so what are we doing now?
Well now we want to change these names of
these columns, they're like too long.
How do we change the names? Well it's
exactly the same as with matrices we already
know this and it's a good
opportunity to practice this again. So colnames
mydf and into here, where do you want to put? So by
the way, if you feel confident at any
stage throughout these tutorials just
pause the video and try to complete the
code we're typing in yourself. In this
case, we want to put in C so we want to
add a vector and here we're going to say
country and then what's the second
column code and the third column region.
So if I just run the colnames of mydf,
you'll see that these are the current
comments
therefore on this whole line the call
names have been changed and if I look at
colnames now it's just country called
region and we can confirm that by using
the head function again. You can see that
now it's much neater like compare this
with where it's so spaced out just
because of the names of the columns to
this where it's nice and neat and you
don't have anything extra.
Alright, so it's a good start but I
actually wanted to show you another
great feature of R which we are
finally ready to understand and ready to
learn.
So I'm going to comment this out as if
they never existed and I'm actually
going to remove the mydf data frame.
You'll see why in a second, so I'm going
to remove it completely and now what I'm
going to do is I'm going to recreate it.
So I'm just going to copy this line
again and here instead of just saying
the names of the vectors that I want to
put in my data frame, what I'm going
to do is I'm going to give them names
right away. So I'm going to say country,
and without the quotation marks I'm just
going to take country equals and I'm
gonna say code and a five quotation
marks I'm going to say code equals to
that vector. So let's make some room
here and then instead of region regions
vector I'm going to say region without
quotation marks
equals regions right? So what we're doing
here is it might seem a bit odd
first of all because these you would
think that something that you want as a
name would always have quotation marks
like we have in this case, but what we're
doing is recalling the data frame
function and we're virtually creating
our own parameters that we are passing
to the data frame function and then it
will treat this as the data and this as
the name. So let's go ahead and run this
and see what we get. So right now, we
don't have a mydf data frame right now
in our data, but if I run these two
lines, I've just created mydf and if I
look at it you will see that that's the
whole idea of course we just need the
top part so let's do that again.
So here we can see that right away these
columns have the names that we wanted
right? And we can just like play around
with it let's say ABC right? Let's see
what that would that does. If we do that
and we run that you'll see that now this
column is called ABC and that is a very
powerful tool in R because it allows
you to save time. Instead of time
creating a data frame and then
renaming the columns you can right away
create the data frame with the renamed
columns and the most of the code that you
will see in R if you're looking at the
people's code it will be created like
this so they'll know I want to call them
called country and the data set I want
to put in there is this one or the
Vector and then I want to call them
called code and and this is the data and
so on. So be prepared for that and also
use that use that to your advantage and
moreover I'll tell you this that this
same approach, works in the C bind
function and the R bind function. You
can use exactly the same approach and I
really wanted to tell you about it
back in that section but it was a bit
too early for us we didn't it would have
been a bit of overwhelming to try to
grasp this at that time but now you're
ready for it and you can totally
practice the same approach with the C bind
and R bind functions. So I'm just
going to rerun this so I have the
correct data frame okay and all we
wanted to check here is just check the
head and let's practice the tail
function just to see that it makes sense
right so
that may become check some codes, it's
about what is in Africa, Samoa, Oceania, South
Africa that that looks like it
makes sense that's always a good thing
to check that everything make sense and
finally let's just check our data
set using the summary function mydf
and here you can see that we've got
countries, codes and regions right? So
everything looks okay, it looks like
every country you know is only present
once and every code so if you add this
up it should add up to 195, that's 195 and here
you've got many countries in every per
region.
Alright so that's how you first of all
create data frames using the data frame
function and vectors and second we
learned today is how to specify the
names four your columns in a data frame right
away and also this approach works for
the C bind and R bind functions.
That's great we learn quite a lot today and I look
forward to seeing in the next tutorial,
until then, happy coding.