Hello and welcome back to the course
on R programming and congratulations on
completing this section of the course
devoted to our fundamentals. And today we
have another homework exercise and this
time we're analyzing financial statement.
I know it can be a bit tedious to go through
financials and look at all the revenues
expenses and so on but as a data
scientist depending on your role of
course but sometimes you will be in
encountering financial statements and it's
good to have at least a basic
understanding of what's going on and how
you can apply the tools you know to
analyzing these financial statements and
moreover of course we're going to
analyze the financial statement using
R. So it's going to be an interesting
combination of programming and financial
statement analysis, so without any
further ado let's dive straight into the
challenge. Here we have a scenario, you
are a data scientist working for a
consulting firm, one of your colleagues
from the auditing department has asked
you to help them assess the financial
statement of organization X and by the
way this scenario comes from real life,
when I was working consulting in the
data science division the auditing guys
would often come to us asking for help
because they had lots and lots of data
and they knew that the tools that we
have and the knowledge that we possess
can help them process that data much
faster so it is a very powerful
combination of the two departments
working together, and in this case, you have
been supplied with two vectors of
data monthly revenue and monthly
expenses for the financial year in
question.
Your task is to calculate the following
financial metrics, profit for each month,
profit after tax for each month, the
tax rate is 30 percent, profit margin for each
month in which equals to profit off the
tax divided by revenue, good months where the
profit after tax was greater than the
mean for the year and bad months where
the profit after tax was less than
the mean for the year. Also, the best
month where the profit after tax was
max for the year and the worst month
where the profit after tax was mean for
the year.
Now it sounds serious blood with the
help of R, we can power through this
challenge and also we've got some
additional notes over here, all results
need to be presented as vectors and that
includes the best month and the worst
month they should be presented as true
and false vectors. Results for dollar
values and need to be calculated with
one cent precision but need to be
presented in units of 1,000 dollars meaning
that every unit is a thousand dollars
and there is no decimal point. Results
for the profit margin ratio need to
be presented in units of percentage
terms with no decimal points and also
don't worry about the percentage sign,
just get a number from zero to a hundred
and for those of you curious out there,
note that your colleague has informed
you that it is ok for tax for any given
month to be negative. In accounting terms,
negative tax translates into a deferred
tax asset but we won't get into detail
on DTA's and stuff like that,
just bear in mind that if you do get
attacks that is negative in a given
month that's totally fine and it doesn't
cause any problems. Okay? So where do you
get the data set for this challenge? To
get the data set for this challenge, you
need to go to the website which is
superdatascience.com/rcourse, so let's
zoom in over here and now if you scroll
down to Section three, Fundamentals of
R. Here, you will see more challenge
which is the PDF so the slides that we
just went through and also you'll see
the homework data set so go ahead and
download the homework data set and once
you unzip it and open up in R, what it
look like
is it look like this. So you'll be given
these two vectors, they're already
pre-coated for you so you just have to
run these two lines to create these two
vectors and then you can go ahead and
type in your solution over here. So if
you're comfortable with this challenge
already then please proceed and
attempt it, see how far you can get but if
you'd like some additional hints then
stick around because I'm going to give
out two additional hints and the first
one will just list the functions that
you will need new functions that we
haven't talked to through just to get
you on the right
track. So now I'm going to proceed to the
hints, let me bring up my presentation
and now
hint number one, hint number one is the
new functions that we haven't talked
about yet and that you will need for
this challenge. Here they are, there's
four of them round, mean, max and min and
I specifically have not included any
descriptions or any additional
information on these functions here
because now you have the question mark operator
which you should be quite comfortable
with. Remember, if you put the question
mark before the name of the function and
execute that line then you will get some
additional information. You will get
description of the function and you'll
get some insights on how to use it. So
the mean, max and min functions are
pretty straightforward and you should be
okay with them straight up, but the round
function, you might want to use the question mark
operator to find out some additional
information because it does have a
parameter that you need to pass on to
it.
Ok so there they are, the four functions
now you should be pretty much on the
right track to attempt this challenge
and I invite you to do so, so go ahead and
stop this video and attempt the
challenge. I do understand it's quite a
long task so don't be worried if you
don't get through all of the points that
required in the challenge even if you
get through some of them, that's already a
great accomplishment because it will
allow you to practice these vector's
operations which are so important in R
and once you've attempted the challenge,
come back and I will reveal hint number
two for you.
Ok so now I'm going to proceed with hint
number two. Hint number two is just as
last time a fill-in-the-blanks exercise
and the code was a very long so I didn't
put it in the slides over here,
what I did is I uploaded it on the
website and now we're going to go and
have a look at it.
Ok so if you proceed to the website over
here, superdatascience.com/rcourse
and you scroll down to Section
three fundamentals of R, here at the
end you will see fill-in-the-blanks exercise, so if
you download that file and unzip it
you'll see our code which looks like
this.
Here's the R code that you'll see and
this is our fill in
the blanks exercise, so as you can see,
I've put in a very thorough comments
throughout so you should be pretty
comfortable as in what's going on in
each one of these and you
it's a great exercise to complete
because once again you will learn how to
or you will revise how to do those
vectors operations and by the way even
if you didn't complete the challenge, there's a
bonus for you over here at the end. It's
a preview of what's coming in the next
section, so if you run this code, you will
get a matrix which you'll be able to
print out there once again we haven't
talked about matrices yet but it's
coming in the next section very very
soon so I just wanted to give you a bit
of a taste and a bit of a feel for it. So
there we go, that is hint number two and
this brings us to the end of today's
tutorial. I wish you luck with this
challenge and if you'd like to see how I
solve this problem then go to the end of
this course, there's a section on
homework exercises. The solution is
presented there and I look forward to
seeing you in the next tutorial.
Until then, happy coding.