Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming. In the previous tutorial, we
created our own data frame based on
the vectors that we were supplied. So now
we have two data frames, we've got the
original one, the stats data frame and
we've got the mydf data frame and our
goal today is to transfer some of the
information from the mydf data frame
and specifically we want after the
region's into the status data friend
right? So let me create a new section and
I will explain exactly what we are after, so
there's the new section and this one we're
going to call merging data frames
because that's exactly what we're going
to be doing. Alright, so let's have a look
at the top bits of each one of these
documents, so how do we look at the
documents? We look at them using the head
function and we say stat's that's the
first one and the second one is the top
bits of mydf right? So let's make some
space here and then we can discuss what
the plan is for today, what the plan of
attack is.
Alright so this is the original data
frame that we loaded from a file as you
remember and here we've got countryname,
country code, birthrate, internet uses,
income group and we've already visualize
that so we've got this beautiful
visualization in the right. Now according to
our additional challenge we need to
create the same visualization but
instead of coloring the dots by income
group, we need to color them by region and
country code and region we were supplied
these this information in additional
vectors and in the previous tutorial, we put them
all into a data frame over here which
is called mydf. Now the challenge for
today that we have is how do we combine
all of this because we can't really
visualize this data if the interest,
internet users and birth rate, so this
numeric data is in this data frame but the
categorical variable region is in this
data frame. How do we combine all of
that into one data frame and what
you'll see here is that we have
countries right? So we're looking at each
row is a separate country and same thing
here it shows a separate country so that
is our key
to success in this case. That is the
way we're going to combine these two
data frames or in fact how we're
going to merge them. We're going to say,
everyone just take the rows and match
them by country. So look for instance, with
Aruba in this data frame and then
take these columns to take this whole
row and add it to the row so right over
here on the right which also has Aruba
and then Afghanistan, add it to
Afghanistan, Angola add it to Angola. Now
that's that's the concept behind it,
however personally I find it's always
safer to go with codes because in the
country name and this is kind of like
more of a data analytical tip or
data science tip for you that
sometimes in country name especially
when the data is coming from different
places,
it's very likely, not very like, it's very
simple that they could have been a
mistake. Somebody might have typed in a
country with the wrong letter
somewhere or put in extra space or
forgotten the space like might have
typed in United Arab Emirates is one
word or something like that and that way
your match will not go through.
Whereas country codes are more reliable,
they're universal right? It's always three
letters. They have a format. It's very
unique. It's very hard to make a mistake.
I mean like it could have made a mistake
but probably these weren't typed up
manually probably these codes came from
somewhere. So it's always better to
mention codes and that's what we're
going to do. We're going to see where the
codes match and that way we're going to
add those roads in. Alright, so that's the
plan of attack.
How do we get that to work in R? Ok so
the function that we're going to use is
called merge. So that's what the function
is and we're going to put to the merged
value into a data frame which we will
call merged just for fun and know what
are we going to pass to this function
merge? We need to give it some values so it
knows what it want, what we want to merge.
Well first we want to deposit the name
of the data frame that we want on the
left which will be stats and then the
name of the data frame that we want in
the right which will be mydf. Now it
needs to know how exactly do we want to
match those two data frames.
Well then to explain that you say by dot
x
equals and then you explain which column
you want to use from the first data frame.
The first data frame has a column
called country code and we want to use
that column we have to pass it in
quotation marks. There we put a comma and
we say by dot Y and Y have by Y by X
because X is the data frame on the left and
then by dot y, why is the one on the right.
So just that this function knows exactly
which data frame we are talking about. Here
we want to use the column code in
quotation marks beautiful, so that's all
we have to do and if I run that you'll
see that now we have a new data frame
over here which has seven variables.
Ok let's find out and why it has seven
variables because this one had five, this
one had three, should have age right? So
let's have a look what happened over
here. If we look at merged and let's look
at the just the head, the top part of it
and maybe let's make some room first so
that it fits on one screen, so what
we have here is we've got country code,
country name, birth rate, internet users,
income group, country and region. What
column is missing?
Well the column that's missing is just a
code,
this column from the second data set. Why
is it missing? Well the reason is because
we are matching on this column right? So
we've got country code equals to code
right so R already knows that it will
not make much sense for you to have a
duplicate of this column because it,
that's what it did, it matched on that
column so obviously they're gonna be
the same so that's why R just doesn't
include that column for you and saves you
some space. At the same time, we can also
see that we already have a duplicate
column as well. You see country here and we
see country name and they're going to be
the same right? So how do we fix that up?
Well we're going to remove the column, we're
going to remove this duplicate column
country and how do we remove columns?
Well just as we learned before, we say
merged then country
good good another good opportunity to
practice something we've learned already.
So if we run that and now we look at
let's say instead of head, let's look at
this
str for structure
merged, you will see that we have country
code, country name, birth rate, internet
users, income group and region and we
don't have any duplicate column so what we
have just done is we've transferred this
region column into the merged data frame.
So we have a data frame that has all
the columns from the first data frame and
just that one column that we are after
from the second data frame and if we
want, we can look at let's say last five,
last six variables of rows here. As you
can see, it all makes sense.
Everything is working fine and you can
just confirm South Africa is this, is
actually in Africa and Yemen is in the
Middle East. Alright so everything is
working fine, that's great and we are
ready to proceed with the next step
which would be visualizing this new data
frame and I look for single the next
tutorial,
until then happy coding.