Hello and welcome back to the course on
R programming and slowly but surely
we're making our way to the top
we're at the coordinates layer of our
visualization. Last time we talked about
facets and today we're going to learn a
lot of things we are going to learn about
limits, zooming in, zooming out and things
like that. So let's dive right into it, so
this is what we created last time
beautiful visualization that is nearly
ready. All we have to do is fix up these axes
so that the y-axis is from zero to a
hundred and how do we do that? We need to
learn how to zoom in and zoom out how to
control our coordinates so let's start
talking about that.
So today we're going to cover the
agenda for today. Today we're going to cover limits,
how to limit our axis and zoom, how to
zoom into our axis. Alright what's that
are we on W, U, V, W, X, Y, Z and I don't really
want to use X, Y and Z because that might
come off a bit confusing so let's start
somewhere at M right M was going to
be a letter for today ggplot and data
equals movies aesthetics so what are we
doing? We're going to be recreating this
plot so not exactly this plot without
the fastest for now we'll just say X
equals critic rating, Y equals audience
rating and size you can actually see now
why it's important to give your variable
simple names because you might end up
typing and up a hundred times like we
are. Alright so there's our M. What are we
going to do now? We're going to say m
plus some points, geom point on that
beautiful beautiful beautiful.
Alright so let's say I want to cut out a
piece I want to visualize only this bit,
so this top top corner right? The top
what is this called, the first quadrant or the
the best quadrants at the movies with
the highest ratings that's what I want
to cut out of this plot so 50-100 by
critics and 50-100 by the audience, how do
I do that?
Very very simple and we are in fact very
no we haven't touched on this yet but
we're going to touch on it right now.
So geom point okay and then we're adding
a layer as we always do, add a layer
which is the limit Xlim fifty to a
hundred so if I run this, that cuts it off
so you can see here on the left 50 is the
lowest, hundred is the highest and so
basically cut off all the points on the
left and you can see the warning message
removed 304 rows. So this is going to be
the key going forward that it actually
not just zoomed in it actually removed
the rows. You set a limit to the value of
x and let's do the same for y, y
limb fifty to a hundred so if I run
these three lines now, viola! Now we've got
that quadrant left and so we removed
quite a lot of rows in total right?
Not quite a lot of values ok? So that is
a good method but it doesn't always work,
let's have a look. Won't work always,
won't work, well it will work won't work
well
always, why not? Let's have a look, let's
say M. Let's say M is GGplot but here
we've got data equals movies as always and
then we have aesthetics x equals budget
millions right?
What is that going to be? What we're
creating here? In creating a histogram
because we only have one axis or one of
those variables x and y histogram binwidth
equals 10, aesthetic especially the
one we've already created genre so
that's our histogram with which is the
blurry one and then color equals black
that's a pretty one.
Alright so but let's say I want to cut
it off up to 50. I want to cut it off
over here.
I want to zoom in, let's say I want to
zoom in from 0 to 50 on the y-axis and
I decide to use the Y limb function
so then I say plus ylim fifty to a
hundred and if I run that which you will
see then make some space.
Well huh actually I was going to say 0
to 50 but still, alright let's do that
again. 0 to 50, you can see that it did
zoom in to 0 to 50 but it actually cut
off any data that was supposed to be
above and that's not what we want that's
like not the opposite of what we want
but it's definitely not we want very very bad
looks not like what we were expecting.
We're checking just to zoom in not to
actually cut out the data so how do we
do that? How do we zoom in?
Well let's look at that there's a
different way instead zoom so how do we zoom in?
Well what we need to do is I'm going to
re-type this and just going to copy it
okay that's that's the plot right and
now we want to say plus equals and here
what we want. The layer that we're
looking for is called cord underscore
Cartesian and this is the Cartesian
coordinate system that we are using the
XY and that's why we're using this
function and here we want to say instead
of ylim and then in brackets like
here, here ylim is a parameter. So we
have to say ylim equals and then
pass it the values in a vector of 2, 0 and 50.
So this is our vector of 2, it's got two
values and fifty were passing it to
ylim so now it knows that the limits
are 0 and 50 and that's called cartesian,
that's a new layer which will zoom in
for us and if we run this viola! As you
can see, we've actually zoomed-in
literally zoomed into the chart and then
like it's still there, the data is
still there. Everything is still there
but after this visualization was created,
this first bit that we are well familiar
with then a new layer was applied which
facilitated the zoom on this chart. Once
again that's how layering works in GG
plot.
Ok so now we know how to zoom into our
charts, so let's go ahead and zoom in to
this beautiful plot that we were
creating right? The one that we really
wanted to improve so let's go ahead and
just copy that and we already have the W
letter, so we're not going to
copy the W because we're going to carry
it alone so improve number one and here
so if we run that, what will we see, we will see
that amazing visualization that we like a
lot but it's from minus 50 to 150 which
is not what we want. We're gonna say plus cord
Cartesian and here we want to say y
lim equals C zero to a hundred. Alright
if I run that, give it a second. Viola!  Beautiful!
Exactly what we wanted right? So here now
you can derive so many more insights
from this chart, you can see that you can
see the trends this exactly the CEO was
are asking, remember that little scribble they
were supplied with at the very start. All
this is what he wanted he just didn't
know what he wanted and so like all
these over here at the bottom
statistically probably insignificant
except for probably romance in 2011
really picked up but otherwise not
enough data to make a lot of conclusions
but here we've got some interesting
visualizations so you can see that for
instance or can receive you can see that
action is when the critics rate action
low, the audience tends to rate it pretty low to,
right but when critics rate it high,
audience also rated pretty high whereas
in the what is this comedy in the comedy
genre you can see that the audience
rarely rated across the years. The
audience rarely rates comedies very low
right rates them pretty ok.
Regardless of how the critics rate them
but it's the same time it is also hard
and has been hard for comedies to get
very high ratings of audience like for
instance in 2008, no comedy ever got a
rating over 80 and then improved a
little bit, improved ability and better
so you can see that the tendency for
comedies that the audience ratings are
slowly slowly improving whereas with the
action genre
and even though it's a bit more volatile
so it's a bit riskier to be here because
you can get a bad rating from the
audience but you can also get a very
good rating and a respectable viewer. So if
you want to play it safe, you might
create a comedy if you want to be on the
riskier your side and you want the great
ratings for the audience then you might
create an action film and what else
do we have? Well we've got some information
here on drama as well right so it looks
like especially in the recent years
looks like people like drama a lot so if
you just look at this smoother it's
sitting regardless of the critic rating
it's sitting above 50 for the past three
years of two 2009, 2010, 2011
really actually all the years in all the
years the smoother the middle line is
sitting above 50 regardless of the
critic rating which is also an
interesting insight. So there we go so
quite a few valuable insights from this
one chart and we'll definitely include
it finally ready so let's save it as image.
This one's tricky because it's like if I
just said different proportions it might
squeeze it now it actually looks pretty
alright so let's go ahead and save that
and where is it?
There it is going to be our first chart.
Alright beautiful
so there we go one more to go, one more
chart to go and we already know what that is
that's the bar chart which we wanted to
improve and that's what we're going to
be talking about next time. We're going
to be learning how to further improve
our charts and I hope you enjoyed today's
tutorial. I look forward to seeing you
next time, happy
coding.