Hello and welcome back to the course on
R Programming and today we're going to
recap on what we learned in this section
about data frames. Alright in this
section we learned number 1, we saw how
to import data into R. That was a
very exciting tutorial and for me
personally it's quite exciting because
up until this section has been quite
challenging supplying a data sets
for our learning because we didn't know
how to import data into R and I had to supply
the data sets through R code and
existing vectors and code that you would
have to run, but now that we've learned
how to import data into R we, going
forward we can use csv files and we can
just import the data into R so its
much more convenient and I was very
excited to finally get this topic cut off
because ultimately when you're working
with R in your day-to-day job or in
your hobbies you're going to be
importing data as csv files or other
types of file. So its always important
to know these things and in this
specific case we looked at how to first
of all import data using the read csv
function and then choosing the file that
we want manually and also then we saw how
we can change the working directory, so
whether you're on Windows or Mac now you
know how to change the working directory
of your R studio, so that then you can
actually type in the name of the file
into your code. So that was quite
exciting tutorial, then we moved on to
exploring data sets. So I show you
some of the tricks that I used to
explore data sets because it's always
important to get acquainted with the
data set and also check for errors and
some of the functions that I recommend
using R head to check the top six rows
or whatever number of rows you specify
tail to check the bottom rows, then the
summary to get the summary of all the
columns in your data set and the str for
structure to get the overall structure
of your data set and see what type of
columns it has and some just sample
values from there. So that's what we did
for exploring data sets, then we
learned how to use the dollar sign. So
the dollar sign is very specific to data
frames. It allows you
to its kind of a shortcut to accessing
the columns by their names because
usually in a data frame columns would
have names because that's how data
is normally stored in its source and
then you can just say that data
frames, name dollar sign and then the
column name that way it's a very quick
approach to accessing separate columns
in your data frame. That way it's a
very quick approach to accessing
separate columns in your data frame. Next
we talked about basic operations
with your data frames, so here we saw
that we could look at different columns
we could add them, we could perform
mathematical operations with them, we
could add columns into data frames,  we
could get rid of columns from data
frames by just setting them to null and
things like that. So very simple things
operations of data frames and they
were pretty straightforward and quite
made quite a lot of sense and also by
the way in these tutorials we also
talked about factors so that was all
kind of first encounter with factors and
that they have different levels and
we'll talk more about factors further
down in the course but it was good to
know how R stores categorical
variables because we did have a couple
of those in our data sets. Then we talked
about filtering a data frame it's a
very important topic but at the same
time like even though it may have seemed
to be a bit complicated, it's not at all
and we saw that in that tutorial that
filtering a data frame is you just
create a logical variable which is the
filter and then you use that to filter
out the rows and in fact you can
actually combine the two so all it
all filled, fits in one line and that's
what filtering data frame's all about,
selecting the roads you want based on
some certain criteria and then we had an
introduction to Q plot so it was just
basically a quick tutorial to see what
kind of function it is and what it is
capable of doing. Kind of like a teaser
of what's coming up in the next section
when we'll be talking a lot about the
visualization. Then we actually use Q plot
to solve the challenge. We built a beautiful
scatter plot that told a wonderful
story about internet usage and birth
statistics and that was the deliverable
that we were after. So basically we solve
the challenge but then we got an
additional challenge and some additional
data, so we moved on to the next part
of the section. Where we were building
data frames, we use the data dot frame
function which is kind of very similar
to C bind. So combining a set of
vectors into a matrix using as if they
were columns data frame does a
similar thing but it combines the
vectors into a data frame and also here
we learned how to specify the names of
the columns of the data frame right
away in the data frame function. So a
shortcut that allows us to avoid using
the column names function and that's
something that you will definitely see
in other people's cause just because
that's the normal convention of doing
things. Then we talked about merging
data frames we just emerged function
and that's a way to join to data
frames together based on one column that
they share so one column that they have
in common.
You can merge the two data frames
together to get a bigger data frame with
the data from the two first data
frames. So that that is a very important
thing to know and there is so much more
to emerging in R. So that is just like us
getting introduction to emerging when
you do encounter merging in your
day-to-day work it's always a good idea
to go and learn more about this topic
because you can create inner joins you,
can create outer joins, you can get
different types of joints we just did
the very basic joint and you already saw
that it's very simple. So it's very easy
to get up to speed just depends on what
you will need for your day-to-day row
but it's very good that we have already
covered off the basics of merging in the
section and then we talked about you
Q plot again. So we covered also some
interesting parts of Q plot like we
talked about shapes, we talked about
setting transparency so the Alpha
parameter and we talked about changing
the title of our plot and if you enjoyed
that you'll definitely enjoy the next
section of the course because we'll be
talking about visualization all the time.
It will be all dedicated to building
stunning visualizations that will
captivate your audience. So I hope you
enjoyed this section and you learned a
lot about data frames. Data frames are
indeed our door into the world of
analytics and data science because
that is basically how you store the
data you're analyzing in R and
that's how you work with it in this
programming language and remember to do
the quiz for this section to have a
quick self-assessment and of course as
always I have another interesting
homework challenge prepared for you. I'm
sure you're going to enjoy that and get
some valuable hands-on time with R
programming and I look forward to seeing
you in the next tutorial,
until then happy coding.