Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming. I'm very glad that you
got this far in the course and as you
can already probably tell from my voice
I'm super excited about today's tutorial.
Today we're talking about the grammar of
graphics and in line with the topic I've
got a very vibrant and colourful
presentation prepared for us so let's
dive straight into it because I can't
wait to show you around.
So what is the grammar of graphics and
where did it all start? Well as the story
goes, it all started back in the 19th
century. Here we've got a map, a map which
illustrates the French campaign or
Napoleon's campaign against Russia back
in 1812 and this map was created by a
gentleman named Charles Minar and he
created it around 1869 and what it's
showing is how the French troops started
over here even by just looking at it you
can probably already guess what it's talking
about but just like going to interlude
of detail like the French troops started
over here on the border of Poland and
then they went went went got all the way
to Moscow turned around and went back so
after I told you that,
now you can already even just by looking
at it you can regather so much
information from here. You can see the
how many, how many troops there were so
they started at 422 thousand men by the
time they got to Moscow is a hundred thousand
men and when they got back it was only
4,000 men. You can see how they split, how
the army split at certain points in time. You
can see the direction of travel. You can
see which cities they went past and you
can even see the temperature so on the
way back you've got the temperature here
and here it's it's a bit of a different
scale but in terms of Celsius and
Fahrenheit that it got asks over here
they called this point was around minus
thirty.. 38 degrees Celsius and minus 35
degrees Fahrenheit. So it was very cold
when they were returning and yeah so
that wasn't in their favor at all.
So we can see a lot of information
from this one picture and in fact
Charles Minar was able to depict
six different types of data in a
two-dimensional image so here we can see
the number of troops, the distance they
traveled, the temperature, the latitude
and longitude, the direction of travel
and also the time. So here you've got
some dates over here so you know when
they were there. So that is an incredible
amount of information all-in-one
two-dimensional picture and that's where
it all started that's where of course
you didn't call the grammar of graphics,
grammar of graphics came later and so it's
actually a book that was written in 1999
and if you if you find the original
hardcover it will have this image on top of
it but he started the whole concept of
layering your image so you can see here
that there's lots of different layers
and lots of different not just layers
but also done a different types of
elements to image. There's the data,
there's some aesthetics which we'll talk
about. There's some geometries, there's some
schematics and so on there's lots of
elements to an image and even though you
don't think of it in that way that's
what constitutes an image and that's
exactly what we're going to be talking
about. We're going to be talking about
how to create charts that tell a story
and one of the main components of them.
So let's move on to the next slide, a
chart or a layer on a chart will consist
of the data obviously.
Aesthetics and aesthetics are things we
see, so they can be like you might have
some some information in your data so it
might be a number like the revenue or an
expense or some like the number of
popula, number of people but you can't
see a number on a chart. You might you
might see an x-axis. That's an aesthetic, we
might see a color, a color is an aesthetic
or the size is an aesthetic. Things you can't
actually see. Then there's geometries so
the size of what? Or the color of what?
Is it a circle? Is it a square or is it
is it a dot or is it a line? So those are
geometries, so that's only if those three
elements are absolutely necessary for
you to create a chart. You have to have
data. You have to have a way to translate
the data into things you see which are
aesthetics and you have to also explain
how there's aesthetics which forms the
aesthetics are going to take, what geometries.
Ok on top of that, you can have
additional layers. You can have another
layer which is statistics. So you might
make transformations to a data to
create new variables and visualize them.
They're in charge might have facets and
we'll talk about facets in a bit more
detailed going further down in this
tutorial but basically facets are
multiple of the same chart based on some
category or so like if you have many
different years then you might have the
same chart for every year. Then you might
have coordinates right? So you're is your
chart in normal coordinates like XY
coordinates or is your chart and pull
the coordinates or do you want to zoom
in or do you want to zoom out of your chart and
things like that. So after everything is
built, we'll you actually see it and
finally there's a theme so theme is all
the other stuff that goes in your chart
so things that make your chart pretty
and even like this might all seem very
overwhelming at first like 7 layers of
information on a chart, you never
thought of it this way and personally I
was a bit confused at the first time
when I saw this. But don't get scared
because right now we're going to go
through all of this one all these layers
one by one on the real example and it'll
all make sense. So let's jump straight
into it. Here we've got a chart, a chart
which will actually create in this
section of the course which looks pretty
cool right and it's showing some data on
a movie distribution, movie budget
distribution so you've got a y-axis at
the bottom which shows the budget in the
millions of dollars and then the number
of movies that were produced at that
budget between the years 2007-2011 and
then you've also got genre. So it looks
like a pretty straightforward chart when
you think about it that way, but now
we're going to go through it layer by
layer and see all those things that we
just talked about right? So let's get
started, here are our layers so where's
the data?
Well first of all you can't see the data.
You can see objects on the chart,
you can actually see the numbers you can
see the data that was given to you. The data is
somewhere else, somewhere in the
background. So you've got the data
and the data that was used for this
specific chart is the movie name, the
budget and the genre and notice that we
can't even see the movie name some
anywhere here so this part of the
data was not even used. We can see
the budget and we can see the genre so
that's the data.
Where are the aesthetics? Well aesthetics
again you can't see them. Aesthetics are
things like the
mapping of your data to the chart.
That's like the intermediate step and
how what aesthetics are using? Well we're
using the x-axis over here and the fill,
so the color basically of these bars and
aesthetics basically means how is the
data map? So how's this map to these
values, so in our case budget is x value
and genre is the field we can see over
here and then we get to geometry so
we're what I mean when I say we can't do
the data, we can't see the aesthetics
because up to now we for all we know,
this could be circles or these could be
triangles it could be lines we don't
know what geometry this these objects
would take so that's when the geometries
layer comes in and now yes we can
actually see that their bars or boxes
you can think of them as boxes and that
is all of the basic building block those
three layers are absolutely necessary to
create a chart.
Alright statistics so where can we see
statistics here, that's that's our
geometry and now let's move on to statistics.
Where can we see statistics here? Well in
this case our geometries and statistics
are actually combined because we're
creating a a bar chart which is not just
a bar chart is the distribution right? It's
a histogram and when we're creating this
histogram. We're running a statistic so
we're grouping our data which has
like 500 rows and we're grouping
these 500 rows by some column, by genre
so we're saying how many movies fall into
the genre of action? How many movies fall
into the genre of comedy? So that is
radius statistical transformation of our
data and we're creating a new
variable which is the count variable for
every genre which is basically not even
present in our data, so we creating a new
variable and we're visualizing it and that is
order statistical transformation is all
about. It's about doing something to
existing data to create new variables
that you're going to visualize so in
this case our geometries and statistics
work together to create this bar chart
which is also histogram. Then facets,
we're going to skip facets for now. We're
going to move onto straight to corners
because I'll show facets after we get
through all these just so that
we don't
over complicate the chart. So
coordinates what is that? Well it's the
coordinates that we have. We got an
x-axis and y-axis and also you can see
that this chart is actually zoomed in so
you can see that we we can't see the top
of this chart so obviously it goes
further there somewhere maybe up to a
hundred or even further but we have
zoomed in and so that is part of the
coordinates layer so we're not only we
select that we want XY coordinates we
don't want polar coordinates or we don't
want a world map or something else. We
want just XY coordinates plus we want to
zoom in into this part of the chart so
everything to do with how you observe
your data that is coordinates and
finally the theme, what is the theme?
Well the theme is everything else you
see on the chart, that is not related to the
data. You've got the title over here
right? So we could have done without the
title then we've got the color of the
X&amp;Y axis labels and the size of the text
you've got the size of the text of your
tick marks and you've got the legend so
not just the size of the legend but also
the positioning of the legend, the size
of the text of the legend, the size of
the title of the Legend and all those
things. So all of these things that make
the chart look pretty and in fact they
have a name, they are called non-data ink so
they're completely not related to the
data but they're still present in
the form of ink on your chart.
Alright so those are the six elements
and facets let's just quickly look at
facets that's a facets basically means if
you had instead of this one chart if you
have a chart like that for every year so on
the right here, you can see that there's
multiple years and basically that's what
fascinates means. That's faceting your chart
and that's how all these seven layers
work. It doesn't necessarily have to be
in exactly that order so some, from
some books or from some other sources
you might find that these layers are put
into different orders personally this is
my interpretation of everything. This is how I
best understand it so feel free to look
around and maybe your own understanding
of GGplot2 and a grammar of graphics
will be a bit different but in essence
those are the seven layers that you require or
that are required to create a beautiful
stunning visualization and we're going
to go through them one by one in this
section of the course
and I can't wait to jump into it. I hope
you enjoyed this presentation and I look
forward to seeing you next time, until then
happy coding.