Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming and the first question
you probably have on your mind right now
is, Kirill why is there a huge timer right
in the middle of the screen?
Well I'll tell you, the reason for this
timer is that I'm super-excited about
you taking this course. I don't want to
get you excited about taking this course
completing it and finally mastering R
programming and in order to do that I'm
going to illustrate what a powerful tool
R is and what amazing insights you can
derive with some just some basic
knowledge of R in under seven minutes.
So let's dive straight into it, the first
thing that you'll need is a browser and
in your browser, go to www.superdatascience.com/rcouse
and this is the page where
all the data sets for this course are
stored and if you scroll down you'll
find the one that we need is under
Section 1,
it's called miss price diamonds. So go
ahead and download that and that way
you'll be able to follow along with the
code in your own computer and have the
same insight on your own machine.
Alright so we have just six minutes to
go, let's explore the data set. Here we've
got three columns, one is carat, the next
one is clarity and price and these are
all diamonds. Every row represents a new
diamond and carat is its weight, clarity
is its clarity and price is the price at
which it was sold and if you scroll down
you'll see that this data set has a lot
of transactions, in fact over 50,000
transactions in just this one data set
which makes it pretty big and so what
are we doing today?
Well let's look at this cla.. clarity
over here. We've got some abbreviations
and these abbreviations are explained in
this chart on the right. So you can see
that the eyes mean that there are some
inclusions in the data set and in the
head in the diamond and met it isn't a
pure and then you've got less inclusions
less inclusion and less inclusion and it
would make sense right that diamonds
that are clearer are priced higher,
should be priced higher than diamonds
that are less clear at the same weight
and carats, and what we're going to be
investigating today is does this
relationship between price and clarity
always hold true. Now we won't be looking
at individual diamonds per se, but we're
going to be looking at is the statistical
averages for clarity. So we're going to
want to investigate, does a better
clarity always mean that the diamond is
going to be priced high or does that
relationship sometimes not hold true and
are there miss pricings in the market? It's
going to be pretty exciting and with
50,000 roads, it's going to be pretty
challenging but with the help of R,
we'll get there very quickly. We only have
four and a half minutes to go
let's dive straight into R studio. Now
I'm going to type in some code and just
follow along and I won't explain
everything in this one tutorial but you
will definitely learn all of this
throughout the course. So type in my
data read csv and then file choose
in brackets and run this line by
pressing control enter on windows or
command return on a mac, and then we'll
allow you to select the file that you
downloaded. If you located and selected,
what that does is that it lowers your
data into R. Now we're going to, now
that we've loaded the data. We're going to
install a package and this package will
help us visualize the data set, it's called
GGPlot2, so let's run that line what
you'll see is R studio is going to
start downloading this package from the
internet and installing it on to machine
so it's taking a while to think over
there and there you can see the download
has started its downloading this package
and all of its components to install
into the machine and we're here in the
packages tab, you'll see that now we have
GGPlot2, just appeared over there.
So now we're going to activate the
package by clicking at this check box.
Alright, so three minutes left we're
halfway there already.
Let's call the function called GGPlot,
and we're going to pass it's some variables.
Data equals my data then X we're
going to say aesthetics and for
aesthetics we're going to x equals
carat and y equals price. So we're going
to create a scatterplot and here we're
going to say plus, we want to add points
right? We want to say that we want to
have a scatterplot so we're going to say
geom point. So if you run into these two
lines together now geom pointed toward
the bottom part.
There we go, in a rush alright so if we
run these two together
now you will see that here we've
got the scatterplot for the diamond, so
all of the records are illustrated here
and it already looks pretty interesting
but at this stage it doesn't tell us
much because we don't have our third
variable which is clarity here. So let's
add it in, gonna put this on a new
line to make some space and here I'm
going to say color equals clarity and
now if I run these three lines together
you'll see that the data set, the
plot is going to change. It's going to
include clarity and we have a legend on
the right here so now already we can
see that some diamonds are priced higher,
some diamonds are price low. That's a great
start but the scatterplot is quite
cluttered and we got all these points on
the right that are not statistically
significant.
So first of all, let's make it less clear
have more clear will say alpha for some
transparency equals 0.1 if we run this
and we check the time
one minute 45 seconds alright so we've
made some improvements. We can already
see the where there's a lot of data and
with this little data, and now we're
going to filter out everything to the
right of this line two and a half carats
because it's not statistically
significant. It's not going to help us or what.
So you will learn how to filter inside
the course but for now just type in my
data dollars sign carat less than 2.5
comma nothing and if you run that that
will filter your data set and leave only
the two and a half carats and below.
Alright and the last thing that we need
here is geom smooth, so let's add the
smoothers so that we can see the
averages for these different carats. I'm
going to make some space here so that we
can see the chart very nicely. Alright we won't
need the code that much, so there we go
let's see how much time 57 seconds.
Okay time to derive insights, beautiful!
That's exactly what we're after so here
you can see that the lines should be in
this order. So Brown is the the best
clarity and then this rate is the worst
quality, so they should be in this order
all the time. But whenever they're
crossing each other, that means there is
mispricing. So you've got some mispricing
over here, these lines shouldn't be crossing
like that and then you've got some
mispricing over here right? So some of
the lines are crossing
over there and some of the lines
are crossing over here at the low prices
as well. So as we get to the right, you
can see that the confidence bounce are getting
greater, so that we have less confidence
about what's actually going on because
of the data set but nevertheless we can
already tell where what is going on and
you can see how the diamonds are being
purchased at one carat, one and a half
carat, one and half carat over there, point
seven carats, point five and so on. So there
we go, just on time, time expired.
We have derived some great insights from
this data set it was very very quick and
as you can see R is a super powerful
tools. Just a few a couple of lines of
code we were able to build this
beautiful visualization which we can
then take to the client or to our
managers and explain what exactly what's
going on in the data set.
Alright as you can see, it was all
step-by-step we slowly build this
visualization and that is exactly how
this course is organized you will learn
our step-by-step improving every
tutorial one skill at a time and learning
a lot and I can't wait to see inside the
next section. I look forward to seeing
inside the first tutorial and until then
happy coding.