Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming. Slowly but surely we're
making our way through this first
section of the course.
Previously we spoke about logical
expressions and variables and today that
information will come in handy because
we will be talking about the while loop.
Now the while loop isn't something that
is very commonly used in a programming
language like R and that is because
R has other means of achieving the
same results through functions like S
apply, L apply and so on.
However it is imperative to understand
how the while loop and other loops work
in the background because unless you
know these fundamentals, there's no point
in learning them more sophisticated
tools. So that is why we will spend some
time on understanding the while loop and
further down the other types of loops. So
let's jump straight into it. Here I've
got a new worksheet and we're going to
right away see how the wild loop is structured.
The while loop starts with the keyword
while and you can see that it has been
highlighted in orange or in different
colors that basically means that it's a
keyword. Then it's followed by a standard
normal bracket and then you have curly
brackets that come afterwards. Notice
that everytime I open brackets R
automatically closes them for me and
that's so that we don't forget to close
the bracket. Now the first part over here
is of course the first part is the word
while, the second part is what goes
inside the normal brackets and it is the
logical expression you have to put a
logical and expression in here so let's
say our logical expression is ABC and
then in the curly braces what you have
to put is the body of the loop. So let's
say, the body of the loop is going to be
XYZ, just for argument's sake. So what
will happen here is once you run the
loop, the studio or R will get to this
part. It will check the logical
expression which is inside the bracket
so check ABC and if ABC is true, so if
that logical expression returns true
then R will execute whatever is inside
the body of the loop in this case XYZ.
Then it will go
and instead of continuing on, it will go
back and check this expression again. It
will check it as ABC is true and if it
is still true it will execute XYZ
again and that will continue on and
on and on until ABC becomes false. As
soon as ABC becomes false, the execution
of the loop ceases and that the end of
that loop. So let's give this loop some
substance to see how it works. Let's say
we want to a print out a message. Let's
say we want to print hello
and now here we are using a new function
which is print previously I did mention
that in R you just have to type in the
name of a variable or an expression for
it and then execute it for it to appear in
the console. That is true in all the
cases except for when you're working
inside the loop to print something out
from within a loop you need to use the
word print. So here, we are printing the
word hello and inside this expression
let's for a simplicity type in the word
false. So we know that this expression is
not true, it's just the word false so
therefore it's always false. It's never
true and if we're on this loop
basically we shouldn't see anything up
here in the console. Let's try that,
let's give that a go. Let's highlight
this loop. We need to highlight all of it
because it starts with the keyword and
ends with that lost bracket and let's
execute this now. As you can see, what
happened here is this code was copied in
so this plus means that the line
continues that are is waiting for the
end of this expression or the end of this
loop to before it executes it
completely and basically so that means
that the loop continues over several
lines and as you can see nothing
happened afterwards.
Now let's change this word false to the
word true, so now we know that this
logical expression which is simply the
word true is always true and that means
that this loop will keep going on
forever. So this logical expression
will never be false and the loop will
just become what is called an infinite
loop and it will make our computer to
print this word out on and on and on
just basically forever, so let's go ahead
and run that.
Highlight it and hit run so that we can
see here is our infinite loop in action
basically the computer is constantly
printing this word hello as fast as it
possibly can and we're getting a lots
and lots and lots of them here.
Of course that's not what we want this
was just for illustrational purposes.
Now in order to cancel an infinite loop,
all you have to do is click escape on
your keyboard and that will force a stop
that loop.
Ok so now let's create a loop that has a
bit more sense to it.
Let's say we want to create a counter
loop, counter loop basically just counts
some numbers and then prints them out so
we're going to start with a variable
which we'll call counter, that will be our
key variable that will be triggering the
execution or that will be governing the
execution of the loop. So we'll understand
what that means just in a second and we'll
assign it the value of one. So we'll
start at one, and then we'll say while in
the normal brackets we'll say while
counter is less than 12. We want to count
from one to 11, so that's why we're
saying less than 12. Then we'll put in
the normal bracket and here we'll say
print we want to display the value of
counter and as you can see if we leave
it like this then counter is not
changing so country is equal to 1 and
basically this loop will also be an
infinite loop because this condition
here will always be true. One is always
less than 12, but what we can do is within the
body of the loop within these brackets,
we can increase counter so instead of
counter we can assign the value of
counter +1. So basically we're taking
counter, we're adding one and then we're
reassigning that counter at the end of
the loop and then we go back into the
loop and then the new values checked and
this will continue until counter becomes
12. So let's go ahead and execute that,
first we'll execute the first line and
then we'll highlight the loop and we'll
execute the full loop. As you can see the
computer has counted up to 11 for us
just as we expected. So we're here at the
top and we make some more space for this.
At the top you can see the copied code
over here and then you can see the
printed values 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11 and that
is how loops work. Basically it allows
you to perform certain actions on and on
and on and said your time instead of
printing out 11 times the word print
with the correct values we did it in
basically just four lines by using a
loop. That is what loops are for, they're
for iterating certain operations and
that brings us to the end of this
tutorial. Have a play around with that,
see what other applications of the while
loop you can come up with and I look forward
to seeing you next time. Until then, happy coding.