Hello and welcome back to the course on
R programming. In today's tutorial, we
will be exploring the four loop. Now the
four loop is somewhat similar to the
while loop but in my opinion it can be
more convenient at times. So what we're
going to do is we're going to copy the
code from our tutorial on the while loop
and we'll paste it into a new file over
here and this is where we're going to be
talking about the four loop and having
this while loop code will allow us to
compare the two side-by-side. Alright, so
let's create a four loop. The four loop
starts with the keyword four and then
just like the while loop, it has simple
braces and then curly braces now the
curly braces are indeed for the body of
the loop but the simple braces, they
don't specify a logical expression
instead they specify the iterations of
the loop. So in this case, let's say we
want to print out the words
hello so here I'll add print hello,
let's say hello R, there for a bit of
fun. So we want to print out the world
the phrase hello R, and in the simple
braces we want to specify the iterations,
what are we going to iterate over? So
we're going to have a variable I, which
will be iterated over five values. So it
will print out the phrase five times so
we need I to run across five values and
to specify that we need to type in I in
1 to 5, so this is an interesting construct
which we will discuss just now, but for
now let's just run this code. So for I in
1 to 5 print this phrase - Hello R. Let's select
all of that and hit control enter or
command return, so there we go the phrase
has been printed out four times, so what
exactly happened here?
I know it might be a bit confusing at
the start and also you have experience
with other programming languages in the
four loop in R is a bit different so
you don't have those semicolons, you don't
have those three elements inside the four
loop. It is a bit different and why is
that? Well this is where we are starting
to touch for the
first time ever the concept of vectors.
Now don't get afraid, don't get worried
we won't be digging too much into
vectors in this specific tutorial but
this is our first encounter of a vector
and it's natural because R is all
about vectors and vector as operations and
we'll drill into vectors in a lot of
detail in the next section of the course,
but for now let me show you a quick
intro or show you how we're using a
victory here. So so what this construct
actually is, is it is a vector. So if I
select this 1 to 5 just by itself and now I
run this code so I press command return.
What you'll see is this line of code has
been copied into the console and then
these values appear 1,2,3,4,5,
so basically this expression 1:5
represents a vector of numbers or just
basically if you are used to other
programming languages and it's kind of
like an array of numbers, if you're not
used to programming languages and it's
just a sequence of numbers 1,2,3,4,5 and
this in R is called the vector. Once
again we'll talk about doctors further
down the course but basically what we're
saying in this concert and this is what
we're interested interested in now is
we're saying that I has to iterate
within this construct which is the
vector 1,2,3,4,5 so I has to iterate
through all of these values 1,2,3,4 and
5 so I could create a similar four loop
and I could say for I in let's say from
five to ten right and then I run this
what you'll see is a Hello R has been
printed six times.
Why is that? Because if I select 5 to
10 now and press come in return you'll
see that there are six values here, five,
six, seven, eight, nine, ten,
so I has been iterated. So it doesn't
really matter where you start or what
this vector actually is it could be
characters it could be any type of
numbers basically I is iterating through
them and every time I changes this cycle
or this loop is executed and whatever is
inside the body of the loop is executed
and that's how four loops
work in R and as you can see the four
loop is actually quite short compared to
the while loop, so it takes a bit of space and
because it does use of vectors in that
way it can be a bit more convenient to
use than the while loop. But once again
we'll talk more about vectors throw it down
the course. Just get your head around
this on how the four loop works and try
some experimenting, try putting in
different values in the colons on the
left and the right see what happens and
see how that affects your four loop and
maybe try using the I inside the body so
just like we did with counter over here
we use counter inside the body of the
while loop, try using I inside of the
body of the while loop and see what
happens because ultimately learning a
programming language is about trying
trying trying and practicing practicing
practicing.
Ok so this brings us to the end of this
tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, happy coding.