Hello, and welcome to Deploying Value with Kanban.
I'm Michael Krasowski, and I'll be presenting the module Kanban vs.
Scrum: A Deeper Look.
Here's a quick preface.
Now, since this is an intermediate course,
I will assume that you have some Kanban knowledge and build upon it,
but it's not mandatory.
If you do want to refresh your Kanban knowledge,
check out my class,
Kanban for Agile/Scrum Practitioners, and here's a
little more information on that class.
You might like to consider this companion course,
Kanban for Agile/Scrum Practitioners.
If you find you want to have a better foundation or understanding
of Kanban before you embark on this course,
please check this out.
And if you are relatively new to Kanban,
this course will give you everything you need to accelerate your
learning in this course. Here is the course outcome.
You will learn the knowledge and skills to help you implement
continuous integration and deployment within the context of the
Kanban value stream and DevOps.
I will start by telling you what Kanban is not.
It is not a software development lifecycle methodology.
It is not a project management methodology. Yet, Kanban improves
developing software and managing projects.
Intrigued? So, what is it?
Okay, so just what is Kanban? Kanban is a method to manage workflow.
This is the most basic, simple definition.
I think about every single system that I ever designed,
developed, architected, or managed was built following a workflow,
either formal, informal, or even chaotic.
So, if your team's practices, such as UI design, coding, quality
assurance, to name a few, can be thought of as steps in a workflow or as
conditions of completing steps in your workflow,
then you'd be well served by using Kanban. Kanban is a Lean practice,
as is Agile, Scrum, and others.
Kanban is a highly flexible and adaptable framework to allow you
to create contact‑specific process solutions, rather than
strictly following a more rigid software development lifecycle
process, such as waterfall, and, to some degree,
even Scrum.
So Kanban is not a process in and of itself.
Kanban is a method that can be used to create a process which will
always be unique to the problem and the resources available. And Kanban
is a practice that symbolizes a principle and is flexible and adaptable
based on the challenge at hand, and the necessary resources.
Here's the course overview. In this module, we'll take a
deeper look at Kanban versus Scrum.
So many of you already have a pretty good understanding of Scrum, and
I think by comparing the two, you will more quickly understand and
appreciate the differences between the two.
Next,
we'll explore implementing continuous integration to
increase customer value, and then, of course,
on implementing continuous deployment to also increase customer value.
Then, in the next module,
we'll talk about adapting Kanban within larger organizations.
And what I mean by large is not so much about the size
of the company or your organization,
but instead, the total number of development teams working
together on the same project with the same goals.
Now, this is a very interesting module, indeed. And lastly,
a nice summary of the key objectives of this course, along with my final words and other resources that might be helpful to you.