Areas of Workflow Friction.
That is where in our workflow we may find the greatest
resistance to a smooth flow of work.
There are two big areas of friction within our continuous workflow.
The first is between implement and validate. The pull criteria for an
implement step is if the implement done rules are satisfied,
and only if they are satisfied can the resource, the person, in
the validate step pull the work forward. As an example, a done
rule may be the feature is coded, unit tested, and meets all of
the feature requirements.
The second point of friction is between validate and deliver. The pull
criteria for the validate step is that the validate done rules are
satisfied, and only if they are satisfied can the resource in the
deliver step pull the work forward,
or typical for a deliver step is that the work is simply placed in the
deliver column waiting for our downstream partner to pull forward. As an
example, a done rule is the entire suite of test cases has been completed by
the QA engineer and were 100% successful.
A quick note. Done rules may be much, much more comprehensive.
These are just examples. Though the Kanban done rules are an absolute
requirement of a high‑quality Kanban value stream and they help
mitigate issues and improve quality between the handoff from implement
to validate and from validate to deliver, there can be a lot of
unnecessary churn, issues, bugs, etc. between those two pairs shown.
Therefore, here is where continuous integration will play a pivotal role.
Continuous integration will reduce or eliminate the
friction and will smooth out the value stream,
thus improving quality and throughput.
You may have heard of the term moving left.
Basically, in this example,
it means can we do some validation in the implement step, and can we do some of
the delivery functions in the validate step? So we're moving left, or upstream,
through the value stream and determining things,
finding things,
correcting things earlier rather than later. Deliver to whom?
That is, when you have completed the validate done rules,
where does the completed code go?
In small companies,
the validate or deliver step was where the devs made the
builds, ran any scripts, and directly put into production the
delivery, that is the new release.
Great.
That's how work has been done for many years in many organizations,
including mine.
So in this case, the devs actually deliver, well, to themselves.
In larger companies,
the code is handed off or thrown over the wall to operations for
deployment to production and possibly where operations continues to
maintain the codebase going forward.
But every company is different, so in this case,
the devs deliver to the operations team, or the ops team.
The handoffs consisted of a package of stuff like DLLs and
scripts and databases and ZIP files, instructions, you name
it, and were usually a bit crude,
error‑prone, and resulted in breakage and more bugs and,
worse, unhappy customers.
In several of my consulting engagements,
I saw much breakage, reduced quality, and even animosity between teams.
So if we are just crushing it on the Kanban side of things,
our continuous flow has now been disrupted.
So how do we solve that?
Well, yes, you guessed it, continuous integration.
So whether you are delivering to yourself, or especially
if you are delivering to another team,
you want a rock‑solid continuous integration approach.
So what we need is at least the following features or
capabilities to support continuous integration.
First, you need to support automated testing.
This will find and eliminate bugs from being pushed out to
the customer in the production environment.
When you find them early in the implement step,
the quality is better, and the customer is more satisfied.
You will need a repository for the source code,
a repo for short, but also known as a version control system, like
Git. And developers must be mindful to merge changes down into their
branches and merge their changes back into the target branch of the
codebase as frequently as your team has decided as a group. And for
me and my group, it's daily.
So at the end of every day,
your project could have a perfect build package, whether it's deployed or not.
That is the general idea of continuous integration.
Continuous integration is lean.
Kanban is a fantastic enabler of lean development, and with CI, continuous
integration, we can better continue a lean process further through the
entire development lifecycle. Kanban's core philosophy is providing
continuous value to the customer. Perfect. Prior to making better tools,
making builds could be a lot of work and was error‑prone since it was
mostly a manual process and therefore not done as often and usually done
right before deployment.
So as tools became more sophisticated, it was a perfect match made in heaven.
And how can you make all this happen?
Well, there are a ton of tools out there to help us. So now let's talk about a specific class of tool, a version control system.