Let's explore how we might adapt and change our actions in order
to continue to excel in larger organizations.
Some context first. It is quite difficult, as a Kanban team leader or team
member, to influence or affect large, multi‑team corporate system development
activities that are happening around you and above you.
Therefore,
this module will focus on how you can live and
thrive within that complex structure.
All projects, big or small, need to articulate and
document the expected project outcomes.
For example, what is the vision?
What is the purpose of the project?
What will be the benefits?
What's the architecture?
What's the project plan?
All this will drive deliverables with what features must be completed,
milestones and dates, and what each team's roles and
expected contributions will be.
All this needs to flow clearly and effectively to all the development teams.
I must say, that is a communication challenge. To get
everyone on the same page is not easy.
Lots of teams, lots of development methods,
lots of product owners, it can be a challenge.
So now that we have the expected project outcomes,
let's determine what the work is to do and assign the work to the right teams.
All work items given to each team is, of course, their backlog work items.
I would suggest identifying only the priority 1 items that are in the MVP,
or the minimum viable product items, for them to work on.
The rest,
if any, are just parking lot items for this time. Determine the
work type that makes sense for this project.
I have simplified this into two work types that I'll
recommend. The first, use cases. I like use cases.
They are the best to me for business features.
An example may be users can rideshare as a carpooling feature.
Another work type I like is services or general purpose services or
components that are the underpinnings of your new large project.
An example may be determine the best‑fit GPS
algorithm to pair riders with drivers.
Now you need to assign your use cases and services as backlog
items across all your teams. And with tons of interdependencies,
this could be very complex indeed.
Okay, a note.
You are a team lead or member of one of these teams.
You are likely not to have to do all this planning,
but you need to know how your team fits in into the larger
project and organization so you have the context on why you
are doing, well, what you are doing.
Let's look at three ways we may structure our teams. First, each
use case team owns multiple use cases to deliver.
That is one kind of team.
This team focuses on business features. That is their focus. The
second, each team owns multiple services to deliver.
This team focuses on services or components that
the feature teams would consume.
Now, I have found time and time again that if you split things as
I have shown there is much less understanding by the service teams
to what the use teams really need.
And I have seen much wasted time integrating the
features with back‑end services.
And it's not that this won't work, it can, but I recommend a lot of
communication between these two types of teams.
So another approach to consider is hybrid, that is a little of both.
So teams own multiple use cases and some services too.
The use cases will drive the nature and features of the service,
but since it's on the same team,
much more communication and understanding will happen.
Then the team needs to publish the service and work with the other use case
teams to further enhance each service to meet their needs.
So they have some use cases that initially drive the service offering and
then enhance the service offering to other use case teams.
Just a thought.
Now, there may be other ways you want to slice the pie,
but I have chosen use cases because they describe the outcome in the
user's business terms and expectations, I like that, and services
since, well, everything is a service today,
and it just makes sense. Here is your typical Kanban workflow for a team.
You have your backlog, and you are receiving your backlog items
usually from a product owner or a customer.
Your work flows through your value stream,
and, in this example, it is specify,
build, and validate. And then you deliver to your customer and users.
So you have one upstream partner providing you with work
items and one downstream partner you are delivering to.
This is quite normal and typical, especially in smaller organizations.
Now, let's see what it looks like in larger organizations
with multiple interconnected development teams. With multiple
teams, it gets more complicated.
You have your backlog and your value stream represented by the blue arrow.
As you can see,
there are now multiple sources of upstream partners
delivering new backlog items to you.
And lastly, your value stream is delivering to four other downstream partners.
So does everything coming into your backlog come in just when you need it?
And does everything delivered go to each of the four or just some
deliverables? Or to just some downstream partners?
And did you give it to them just when they needed it?
Yeah, good questions.
Things can get complicated. Let's see how we can make it a little better.