Now that we have a backlog in place,
let's move on to comparing backlog planning and work selection.
Now let's look at a bird's‑eye view of agile project planning. All agile
projects start with agile project planning, of course. This is conducted
with the product owner and the dev lead typically,
and there may be other subject matter experts as well.
Also, the product owner is bringing in product requirements, lists of items,
ideas, concepts, and a draft backlog.
And yes, more times than not, it can be a bit unstructured and fuzzy.
The initial product backlog may contain features,
user stories, and epics of various chunkiness, since we are just starting
out. The backlog features may be broken down to 1, 2 or several releases
that would each describe the feature set to be delivered in business
terminology, so that management and executive leadership can relate and
understand how it will help them.
This is basically the release plan. Along with each release may be target dates,
though optional,
very rough, and certainly would change based on the cadence and delivery.
Yes, pure scrummers will say no dates.
Yes, I get it, but also understand you may have senior leadership wanting dates,
and I will do my best to give them dates, as you should too.
You will now identify the features and stories that
you'll want for each release.
So the releases with their initially assigned features and stories,
along with other project artifacts, will make up the project roadmap
and release goals. Now, nothing's in concrete with agile/scrum, and
features will move around,
be eliminated or brand‑new ones appear, as they should.
Okay, now let's go a little deeper into release plans.
So now you might take all of the features targeted for Release
1 and plan your sprints for that release.
In order to do sprint planning, you need the product owner,
scrum master, the dev lead, and maybe other members of the dev team.
What will feed into sprint planning may be a couple of things.
Here, I am showing that sprint planning is for a sprint within
Release 3 and its associated backlog.
If you are not using the release planning model,
you would have the remaining backlog as input into the sprint planning.
Next, the outcomes of the sprint planning are the sprint plan,
which is focused on the next sprint within this release,
and also what backlog candidates will be in the
subsequent sprints in this release.
Refined user stories, we may need further discussion on a
user story to better understand it.
Refined estimates and priorities, based on those refined user
stories and discussions, we can improve the estimate and reset
the priority we want to assign to it.
Sprint backlogs, in this example we have three sprints and have
determined which user stories are assigned to which sprint. Again, this
may change based on the outcomes of the sprint demos,
reviews, and retrospectives.
For example,
I am showing three planned sprints in this release,
and associated backlogs for each.
Please note, for the next sprint planning, let's say in two
weeks, we will only have Sprint 2 and Sprint 3, since Sprint
1 of this release is complete, and if not,
we will decide what to do with the uncompleted user stories of Sprint 1.
Since we are using timeboxing in this example,
the schedule is set and the scope is fluid.
Each sprint, for example, is going to be two weeks.
Okay, now that's the general approach to sprint planning.
Now let's switch over to Kanban. So you can see there is quite
a bit of work in the agile/scrum approach.
Hey, I'm not knocking it at all.
I think it is one of the best system development approaches around, but to me,
Kanban is more lightweight and more flexible,
so it might be the right fit for you in some circumstances.
Okay, items are pulled from the backlog in the order needed.
The product owner or customer still provides inputs,
of course. And this happens in no particular
frequency, but may be reviewed daily,
and it is not tied to a two or three‑week event.
There are no sprints, simply a continuous flow of work.
So, no sprint planning and no sprints. Now, don't forget the backlog
can contain work items that pertain to planning, requirements
gathering, estimates or whatever you want.
So some high‑level requirements planning must take place to some degree, so
begin with backlog planning work items. That is, items in the backlog could
be project planning, requirements planning,
determining the scope of the project or whatever you need to
prepare and get ready to actually develop software.
The Kanban approach allows you to be extremely flexible.
Does it seem pretty easy and straightforward?
Well, it is. Okay, let's take a look at a Kanban backlog.
Now it may look something like this initially. We're going to
rearrange our work items into priority sections.
Here's our priority items for number 1,
here are our priority 2 items, here are our priority 3
items, and the rest are nice to haves.
Then all the work is pulled from the priority 1 section of the backlog
into the work in progress value stream. At each standup,
the work item cards may be moved between priorities as
the team feels it is appropriate.
Now please note, a Kanban backlog can be by priority as shown, by type of
work item or by any organization of the backlog that works best in the
context of the business problem you are solving.
There are no hard and fast rules.
Be creative.
Let's recap backlog planning and work selection.
Backlog organization is similar,
so the process by which backlogs get populated are similar,
and the process or practices on how to organize a backlog are similar as well.
Backlog planning, though, is very different.
With agile/scrum, you have project planning,
release planning, and sprint planning.
Many shops skip the release planning and just have sprint planning.
And with Kanban, your planning is just done every day during
your standups based on the needs of the business and how best
to add value to the business.
Work selection is a bit different,
since agile/scrum has all of the project, release, and sprint planning as
context for the work selection. And the pulling of work forward is about
the same, but remember, with sprints the work that is pulled forward is
sometimes locked into a sprint, whereas in Kanban we can make much quicker adjustments every single day.