Now that we have our projects moving forward,
that is our work in progress, what are the things that could get in
the way, or another way of saying it, what are the constraints or
issues that would impede our workflow?
So let's compare and contrast how we will handle those with Kanban and Scrum.
Let's first define some terms for what I'm calling the
three Bs of workflow constraints.
A bottleneck in a process flow is anywhere that an accumulation
of work builds up waiting to be processed.
Sometimes you might hear the term constraint as well.
A blocker is a blocked or impassable work item that is restricting the flow
of work, it is the work item itself that is the blocker.
Now it's important to get our terms right, a
bottleneck is not a blocker. And lastly,
a buffer.
Now a buffer has a totally different meaning between Kanban and Scrum. Okay, so we will drill into these and their implications.