I know everyone has heard the real estate phrase,
"It's all about location, location,
location." And in large companies and especially large,
complex development efforts, the phrase is communicate,
communicate, and communicate.
To me, you can never communicate enough.
Here's a quote: "What we've got here is a failure to
communicate." It's a famous line from a classic movie,
Cool Hand Luke.
So even if you think you are communicating,
be sure you can determine if it is, in fact, effective.
And if you have a chance, check out the movie.
It's a classic.
The larger the organization,
the more complex the communication challenges can be.
It's a given, so be ready for that.
You can use many of the same tools listed throughout this course to
manage status information about backlog items,
work in progress, tasks, the order of work,
priorities, and milestones.
If you are using more than one tool in your organization,
say one for Kanban teams and one for enterprise project management,
you will likely have to integrate the data or simply manually update
the enterprise data that relates to your team.
Nonetheless, the better the automated integration of data,
the better quality of project status communication.
Not only is communication skills critical,
but also leadership, so check out my most popular Pluralsight course,
Leadership and Communication Skills for Software Engineers.
You won't regret it.
Communication via push events.
It is important that you as the Kanban team leader or member
communicate significant events of your backlog,
its ordering, and your deliveries to other teams.
Since it will be likely that more than one project management tool is used,
and since the tools tend to be more precise and detailed,
you will need other creative ways of communicating the
events of completion of backlog items, ordering and prioritization,
the breakage of backlog items, bugs, delays,
etc.
Consider using email, text messaging, Twitter,
Facebook, or other ubiquitous tools to push information
about the state, health, milestones,
deliverables, or any breakage by your Kanban team.
Of course,
there should only be one communication process for the entire enterprise
project. That would make life much easier, but don't count on it.
Be proactive and push your status events out to others.
Don't wait for them to ask you.
It's important to note with waterfall or scrum,
for example,
there are distinct events by which you can be reminded to publish
your results and statuses. But with Kanban,
you are continuously delivering, and hence, you need to be
communicating with others probably even daily.
So why not have a status dashboard updated daily?
The bottom line is communicate proactively; push events to others.
People need to know information. Again, this is a complex network problem.
You have your backlog being fed from multiple teams, and
you're delivering to multiple teams.
It can get very complex.
The more information, the better.
With large projects and large organizations,
I strongly recommend a focused project management level of effort.
Why? Dev teams are doing what they do best, and that is develop great systems.
In my experience,
they're not always the best suited to also communicate project activities.
Therefore,
you may need a full‑time and dedicated project management team to manage
all the planning, requirements management, integration,
etc.
Do not shortchange the project.
If you are the lead or a Kanban team member,
this choice will likely be at a higher IT or leadership level.
But trust me, if you can lobby for resources to focus on enterprise planning,
then you'll have more time to do your job,
and that's write great software.
Project management is not just for big companies or projects, either.
Even if you have only three or four teams,
there will be a lot of project activities to handle in coordination,
planning, budgets, resources, issues, customers, and you name it.
Wouldn't you rather have a group of professionals handling that?
I sure would.
I want my team focused on the developing of the best software and not be distracted by project management activities.