Okay, time to merge up.
It's time to get even a little more disciplined.
Let's do a definition of a pull request.
If you have code you want to put back into a source code repository's
mainline or branch, you will issue a pull request.
This is also known as a merge request.
So it got the name pull request because the dev requests that the
owner of the target codebase pull the dev's source code and merge
it back into the target codebase.
And I am also calling this merging up.
Merging your dev branch back to mainline.
Let's do our timeline again so we can see what is happening.
Okay,
so you are the developer, and you have been assigned the branch work item
495.1, and it is branched off of the parent branch release 4,
which, of course, was branched off of the mainline.
Remember,
I mentioned earlier that all dev branches may be best branched off of the
release branches between the mainline and the developer's branch.
That is what I like, and you may like something else as well.
On day two,
the parent branch release 4 was updated by the owner of
release 4 branch. And on day three,
you merged release 4, validated that everything was good,
made a build, and continued coding. Perfect.
Then on day six, your code's complete, and you issue a pull request,
which informs the owner of the parent branch.
In fact,
the pull request may inform many people based on your
pull request policies. On day six,
or sometimes soon thereafter, their parent branch owner then takes the
action and merges your work into the parent branch.
If all is good, you move on and pull new work into your Kanban value stream step.
Or, if there are issues,
the parent branch owner will certainly let you know,
and you'll correct any issues.
Here are a few merging up rules of thumb. When your work item is validated,
that is it has passed all the Kanban done rules for the validation
step, then it is now a candidate to be merged up and back into the
target branch from where it originated.
So you make a pull request from within your tool.
A pull request, of course,
is asking someone, the branch owner, lead, or a PM to merge your completed
work back into the codebase from where you branched from.
It could be the mainline, but it's likely a release branch like in our examples.
A pull request means that you're code files are a candidate. That
is they're all ready to be merged up to the code stream from where
you branched from, the parent branch.
Pull requests are made to the branch owner.
All branches, and especially the mainline,
are major releases, must have an owner.
I think every branch has an owner, end of story.
The owner inspects the changes usually with
highlighting syntax and diffs, you know,
old version and new version side by side,
maybe follows a checklist that must be completed, and only updates the
files such as changes, added files, or deleted files,
and then they are committed to the target branch.
The candidate branch is rejected or approved. And of course, rejected means that
the owner sends it back to the developer to fix and repair.
After the developer repairs the work, they will issue another pull request.
If approved,
you're done, and the pull coordinator or owner does
the merge into the target branch.
If later the merge code is problematic,
some systems allow you to undo or revert with no harm
to the dev stream or parent stream, if you will,
and you might want to be sure that your version control system can in fact do that.