Okay, so let's first look at bottlenecks.
Let's start with bottlenecks for Agile Scrum.
For example, if your velocity slows down for a variety of reasons,
then you are producing less outcomes and work items will build up
in the backlog and can become a bottleneck.
Uncompleted work items may be pushed to the next sprint based on your
sprint planning, but that means some of the work you were planning for must
wait and remain in the backlog furthering the bottleneck. Or uncompleted
work items are simply placed back on the backlog and will be discussed at
future sprint planning meetings.
What can be difficult is looking inside the sprint to see
what is really causing the bottleneck.
Sometimes you don't know until the end of the sprint that you
did not complete some of your story points.
Typically,
if story points are completed, the system will track those
so you can see what you have finished, say,
85% of your story points, but it is difficult to visually see
where the problem is or what caused it.
Could it be testing, maybe more training is needed,
and you won't always know until the sprint review,
retrospective, or even the next sprint planning meeting.
Let's see how we can identify a bottleneck with Kanban.
Here is our value stream.
I have tweaked it a bit and added double columns per step, one for work in
progress, WIP, and one for done, that is the work is complete.
We have six resources applied, two in specify, three
in implement, and one in validate.
I am showing those with boxes.
Now let's overlay our work item cards for some point in time as follows.
Here is our backlog.
This is what's going on in the specify step, two work
items in progress and two are complete.
Next is the implement step.
We have three resources, but only two are busy and
we have five work items complete.
Our validate step has only one resource allocated and they are busy
and we have three work items completed. And lastly,
the work we delivered. Okay, now there is a lot to impact on this slide.
If you need to brush up on this,
please check out my course Kanban for Agile Scrum Practitioners.
Okay.
Can you see where the most significant bottleneck is?
Okay, a quick quiz, we can see that the cards are
stacking up in the done column of implement.
That's where the arrow is showing right now, but that is not the bottleneck.
The bottleneck is the step after the done step where the cards are stacking up.
Therefore, the bottleneck is in the validate step.
So in this case,
we do not have enough resources, the validate step, to pull
the implement done cards forward for a smooth workflow. Now
look again at the implement step.
It is not the bottleneck, in fact,
it is cranking out work very well and even has one free resource.
Let's recap bottlenecks.
Bottlenecks are part of all development approaches,
it's how they're handled that counts. Kanban provides better
visibility with more granularity and Kanban provides more timely identification and remediation.