As I mentioned earlier in this module,
the enterprise level planning and the integrating of multiple development teams,
some Kanban, some Agile Scrum, and some maybe even just
roll your own, can be quite complex.
The remaining sections of this module will address how you can best
focus on handling and dealing with these complexities.
Quite frankly, the enterprise world is likely beyond your control anyway.
Okay, the first is dealing with late dependencies. Late dependencies.
What are they?
Well, it is when a use case or service that your team needs is late, therefore,
making your work late for teams further down the value
stream. You can see the cascading effect.
If the upstream work is late to your team and your work
is late to your downstream teams,
it can affect multiple downstream teams and the whole project's timeline.
Here is an approach on how you can modify your Kanban board
to deal with late dependencies since this is an area that you
do have complete control over.
So let's say you've been informed that a work item you are expected to be
placed in your backlog by an upstream partner is late.
What you can do then is at a late area to your backlog and a late column to
your implement step to track the late dependencies. For each backlog item or
work item that is affected by a late dependency, mark it as blocked with the
reason of the late dependency. As‑is normal for all Kanban standups, the
team reviews each blocked item, and especially, the late dependency items
each and every day.
Now let's go into a little more detail with an example.
Here is our typical Kanban board we have been
using, in general, for this course.
Now let's annotate the board further and add some more visual cues.
The black boxes represent our work in progress resource limits per step,
two in specify, three in implement, and one in validate.
Now let's add some done rules right on the board.
I added them on the bottom in blue.
This is important since you'll want the team to easily see and fully
understand the done rules while the stand up is an action,
or when they view the board,
either in person or online. No one needs to remember anything.
All the information is right on the board.
Now let's fill in the board to complete our initial setup for our
example. So we have our backlog on the left.
Let's say we are using color cards to illustrate the work type.
We have divided our steps into two sub columns, work in progress, WIP, and done.
We have added our done rules to the bottom,
and we have our work in progress limits shown as black boxes.
Now let's see how we will modify a typical Kanban board
to accommodate late dependencies.
Now, let me go through the scenarios here.
So I added an area in our backlog called Late.
Next,
I added a new column in the implement step called Late for late
dependencies and this late column will represent any work item that
was in the implement steps work in progress and was waiting for an
upstream work items such as a service.
Let's say this purple work in progress item is waiting for a dependency.
We will move the card to the late column and mark it blocked with a big L.
The freed resource and implement can now pull new work forward
from the done column of the specify step and try and keep as
much work moving forward as possible.
Let's say two work items arrive late into our backlog.
I want to keep the late ones in a separate area so we can easily identify them.
So when there is an available resource in the implement step,
I can move the block purple one back into the work in
progress and consume the late work item from the backlog
area into my implement work item.
Those two will then match up.
Is this the only way to do this?
Well,
certainly not, but it is certainly a place to start and evolve as you see fit.
Please note you have the freedom to design your board any way you
want as long as it adds value to the business.
That is why Kanban has immense power. You are not constrained like some other software development methodologies are.