So we have seen how we have modified our Kanban value stream
to incorporate a version control system.
Let's further leverage that version control system to
take advantage of automated testing.
Before automated testing the context of continuous integration,
this is how work flowed between the implement step and the validate step.
Dev performs unit testing, ensures the done rules are complete,
places the work in the done column.
Now unit testing may or may not mean automated unit testing,
but let's hope it does.
The QA person pulls the work item forward for the validate step.
The QA typically performs manual tests and runs automated tests,
if any, ensures all the done rules are complete for the validate step,
and then places the done work in the done column.
For the devs, typically the unit tests are few at best,
and sometimes the testing is random.
And for the QA's resources in the validate step,
testing is better since that is their profession,
and it's usually documented and usually repeatable.
So a quick shoutout to all the QA professionals who must
clean up things for the devs sometimes.
No offense devs.
Why should we do automated testing?
Well, yeah, got to.
Continuous integration requires automated testing, no if, ands, or buts.
No automated testing, well, to me, no continuous integration.
It's great for catching errors and bugs early,
or should I say earlier and often.
Manual testing really is obsolete.
Our development stacks are so complex,
we are leveraging a plethora of APIs and other remote services
and trying to integrate everything together.
How often have you or others just click around the
screen hoping to find something wrong.
That is not automated testing.
And I mean earlier.
Why wait for the validate step to better test things?
How about catching more of them in the implement step?
So fail early and often.
Management's support.
So often budgets are allocated for dev work and not testing.
I see it over and over.
Untested systems in the long run do cost more,
period, but it can be hard to convince management otherwise.
So I can sympathize with you if your management says no automated testing.
Well, you either pay now or pay later.
And when you pay later, the customer is even more unhappy,
and you're probably frustrated as well, including your team.
Automated testing enhances lean development.
With lean, you want to reduce or eliminate waste.
So much of the friction points I mentioned before only create waste,
which results in lost time and money.
Committing code.
In version control systems,
a commit adds the latest changes to the source code to the repository.
In our running example,
the dev will commit the changes back to the branch he or she is working on.
Now this is not a merge.
Remember,
merging is either merging down from a parent branch or
merging up into the parent branch.
Let's consider using continuous integration practices in
the implement step and what that means.
Continuous integration requires frequently committing
chunks of code into the shared repository.
When you commit code, that event fires a series of things you need to perform,
automated tests and a whole slew of other things that could be set up
and programmed to exactly meet your requirements.
How frequently should code be committed?
Well,
committing code more often detects errors sooner and
reduces the amount of code a developer needs to debug when
finding the source of an error.
Frequent code updates also make it easier to merge changes from
different members of a software development team.
This is great for developers who can spend more time writing code and
less time debugging errors or resolving merge conflicts.
When you commit code to a repository,
you can continuously build and test the code to make sure that
the commit doesn't introduce new errors.
Your test could include code linters, which check style formatting,
security checks, code coverage, functional checks,
and all sorts of other custom checks that makes sense for you.
Here are some rules of thumb for committing code to your working branch.
Develop automated tests as a matter of normal practice.
Set up rules in your version control systems so that on every
commit the automated tests are run or other scripts or
actions that you need are completed.
Decide how often each developer should commit their code.
I say daily.
Decide is a team what they should commit.
To me, it should only be workable, functioning code.
Handle your automated test code as real code,
not just some add‑on or chore to do.
Heads‑up. This is the heart and soul of continuous integration.