So whenever you're doing your work,
your new mantra should be continuous everything.
Look for all those bottlenecks and blockers that affect
the flow of work and make it better.
As you can see, I'm a big believer in continuous everything.
Kanban is a continuous value stream of deliverables to the customer.
Continuous integration. So our code is committed by developers.
It's merged into the main branch as much as possible.
Tests are triggered automatically to validate the changes.
Events are fired if an issue is detected.
This best practice helps detect problems early upstream and reduce merge
conflicts when compared to a more traditional build release cycle.
Continuous delivery. Changes that have been successfully passed
through the continuous integration phase are automatically
verified and packaged to be made available for deployment to
production at a later time.
Continuous deployment. That is deployment to production
happens automatically, conditional on the successful
completion of the previous steps.
Features and bug fixes go live to the users as soon as
they're ready without manual intervention.
Kanban has been around for a heck of a lot longer than continuous integration,
delivery, or deployment,
so some credit must be given to all of those Kanban practitioners that have come
before us and laid the groundwork. Getting ready for CI/CD.
Here are a few suggestions to help you dive into
continuous integration and deployment.
CI/CD is not for the faint of heart and will challenge
your team and possibly your organization, so I recommend a
strong and disciplined team.
Expect costs and the addition of a few new skills.
Architecting a solid CD pipeline process is essential,
and your code must be extremely testable.
I mean really, how many people's code are that way?
So you may have to change the development processes. So maybe
you need to have adopted test‑driven development first for CI
to work. And again, for CD to work, you need CI to work.
You need good test coverage, thus avoiding manual testing as much as possible.
And of course,
your pipeline must support rollback because you will
find issues and errors. Lastly, you need to have the confidence of management,
your customers, and the team's confidence in the
process and tools to make it happen. Start easy, start light, try a pilot, and see how it goes.