Hello, my name is Michael Hoffman.
In this module,
I'll be demonstrating the next step for adding a new
feature to the JHipster generated project.
We're going to start the actual construction of the new feature.
Just to recap,
the business case is to allow patients to interact
with their physicians in a practice.
Eventually, this is going to be a full functioning portal,
but to start with,
I just want a feature that allows patients to manage their appointments.
In the previous module,
you saw the steps needed to change a security aspect
in the JHipster generated project.
This was a good exercise as it should have warmed you up to some of
the basics of making a change to the code base.
We're going to put that new security role name to use in this module.
To start with,
I want to create a form that allows a patient to request an appointment.
The user will need to be logged in and have the new patient role.
The second task is to provide a view of all the appointments a user has made.
I'm going to keep the data for this form very simple because we want
to maintain focus on what JHipster has provided.
In this module,
I'll be focusing on only the client-side implementation of these tasks.
I'll cover the server-side in the next module.
Let's start by running webpack again, so that you can get some additional details about it.