In this module,
we learned about the decisions that are required to use JHipster
for generating a monolithic web application.
I focused on six of the major decisions that need to be made.
I showed how JHipster can generate projects that can support both
a monolithic and microservice architecture.
For the monolithic architecture,
I talked about what JHipster actually generates for the client,
the server, and the utilities.
I explained the options for authentication in detail.
These options included stateless authentication using JWT or Auth2,
and the more common stateful authentication using HTTP Sessions.
I also covered what JHipster generates for you,
including security configuration, users,
and roles.
I covered the options for database selection.
JHipster supports both SQL and NoSQL database types.
Also,
JHipster allows you to select a different database when
running in a development environment,
and when running in a production environment.
Finally, JHipster supports schema management for the database via Liquibase.
I discussed what JHipster generates when selecting Gradle as
the primary build tool for the application.
This included common tasks like compile and test,
as well as support tasks, like Liquibase for database schema management.
I discussed the options for client-side frameworks,
and why Angular 4 is the recommended choice.
Finally,
I provided detail around additional testing frameworks that are
supported on top of the default unit test frameworks,
JUnit and Karma.
We selected Protractor,
as it provides end to end testing that supports Angular applications.
With the project generated,
the next step is to start developing a feature in order to understand the benefits that we achieved from scaffolding.