In the module on customizing security,
I made a small change to the Liquibase scripts to modify our role name.
Liquibase is a third-party dependency that JHipster brings into the
application for you to manage your database schema.
While I made the change for the role name,
I didn't really go into depth on the structure of the Liquibase configuration.
So let's do that now.
You can see the directory structure where these configurations reside,
which is src/main/resources/config/liquibase.
The sub folder change log is where you define your schemas.
I'm going to add a new file here shortly for our appointment schema.
I already changed the file in this folder,
named with leading 0's, _initial_schema.
xml.
This file defines the base schema from JHipster,
including tables for users, auditing, and security.
At the root Liquibase folder is for our files.
Authorities.
csv contains authority data that will be preloaded into the database.
Master.
xml is the main Changelog file for Liquibase.
I'll be updating this to refer to our new change log for appointments.
Users_authorities.
csv contains relationship data between users and authorities, and finally users.
csv contains user data.
Again, both of these will preload data when we run our script.
I'll be adding an additional file here for preloading a
few appointments for one of the users.
Now that you understand the structure, let's make the changes for appointments.
I'll be walking you through dropping in the new
Liquibase files from a GitHub repository.
If you didn't do so already for the client,
you can download the project from the repository listed.
The URL is github.
com/michaelhoffmantech/patient-portal-resources.
You'll be copying the Liquibase folder under the server/liquibase directory.
The source code is also included as part of the Pluralsight course material.
Once you have this project downloaded, you can continue with the course.
I've opened up Eclipse,
and here we see in the package explorer that I've expanded the
GitHub project called patient-portal-resources.
We're going to copy two of the files.
First, I'm going to copy the file that's under server/liquibase/changelog.
Select that, copy it.
We're going to put it in the corresponding folder of the project.
I'll expand Changelog, and paste it in.
And now we have a second change log on the project for Liquibase.
Let's grab the other file, I'll select appointments.
csv, found under the folder server/liquibase,
copy that, and we'll put it in the corresponding folder of config/liquibase.
So now that we've moved these two files over,
let's explain a little bit about what they are.
There are two files that we added from GitHub.
The first file is the Changelog,
including the schema for a new appointment's database table.
From a naming standard, I used the date only in the prefix of the file,
but you can also go down to the full time stamp.
I then provided a detailed file name to indicate that the
Changelog is for creating the appointment schema.
The second file is a CSV file with appointments data.
The data will be prepopulated into the database for
the purpose of local testing.
In order for Liquibase to process these new files,
we'll also need to add a line to the master.
xml configuration.
Let's look at these new files in some detail.
I'll start with the new Changelog file first.
The first item of note is the definition of the changeSet element.
I've set the ID to use the prefix from the file name,
which was the date and trailing 0s.
I've also appended a -1, in case we had multiple change sets in this file.
I've also set the author to be system.
Let's look at the contents of the changeSet.
First, I've defined a createTable element,
setting the tableName to be appointment.
If you've used SQL before to create tables,
this format should be self-explanatory.
I've defined five columns.
First is the id, which is the primary key and will be set sequentially,
next is the user id, which is a foreign key I'll be touching on again shortly.
This refers specifically to the user id of the currently
logged in user making the appointment.
Then, I have a reason column, which is the reason for the appointment.
Next, I have a Boolean for whether or not the user's insurance has changed,
and finally, I have a phone number for the user to be called back on.
Note that I've added a not null constraint to all of the fields,
as they will all be required for an appointment to be created.
With the table definition in place,
there are two more items that were added in the change set.
The appointments table is going to have a relationship to
the user table provided by JHipster.
Note that I've added a foreign key constraint,
which provides this relationship mapping.
The constraint maps the user id column of the appointments
table to the id column of the jhi_user table.
I've also defined an element to tell Liquibase to preload data into
the appointments table as part of the creation.
The file reference was the one that I downloaded into the project from GitHub.
It contains one line of data using all of the columns,
and a semicolon for the separator.
With this in place, let's make the change to the master Changelog.
I've opened back up Eclipse, let's edit that master.
xml file now.
I'm going to minimize the Package Explorer so we can see the full file,
and here we see the include from JHipster.
This is just a reference to the Changelog for the foundational schema tables.
I'm going to drop in another include.
Save the file, and now we have our new Changelog added into the master.
xml.
Note that sequence is important here.
Liquibase is going to run these Changelogs in order,
so our schema will be added after the JHipster schema.
Now, let's try running the application,
and make sure that this new table is in place.
I've opened up a PowerShell window to the project directory.
If you're already running either the client or server, you should stop them now.
I'm going to run the server command, which is.
\gradlew,
and once the server is started you should see a message
regarding Liquibase loading up our database.
I fast forwarded through the start of the server.
Here we see the line that says Liquibase has updated our database.
So, this has been successful.
But let's verify it through our browser.
I've opened up Chrome to the server homepage at localhost port 8080.
Let's log in with the user and password admin.
Once I'm logged in I can click the Administration menu in the nav bar.
I'm going to select Database.
This opened a new tab to allow for login to the H2 console.
Let's click Connect, and now the H2 console is displayed.
On the left, I can see the appointment database table.
Let's expand it.
I see the columns that I defined in the Changelog,
but let's select everything from the table.
And, here I'm displaying the data that was prepopulated from the appointment.
csv file.
This means I successfully set up Liquibase for my appointment schema change.
With the database in place,
we can start coding the repository and domain entity to support appointment persistence.