The next step for the server-side implementation is to implement persistence of
appointment data into the database table that we defined.
To keep focus on JHipster,
I'll just be showing you how to drop in the code from a GitHub repository.
I'll be displaying the appointment entity class.
This leverages JPA annotations to map the class
members to the database table columns.
As the entity will also be passed up to the service and API layer,
I'll be adding Java validation annotations to some of the columns.
I'll then be displaying the appointment repository class.
This extends Spring's JPA repository interface,
providing access for operations against the appointment table.
Before we see this code,
let's first look at what JHipster generated for you to support database access.
I'm showing the database configuration class that was generated by JHipster.
You'll find this class in the package com.
Pluralsight.
patientportal.
config.
If you've worked with Spring configuration for databases in the past,
most of this should be familiar to you.
If not, let's walk through some of this.
The first line is Spring's annotation to define this as a configuration class.
The next line defines the package to be scanned for JPA repositories.
Our new appointment repository class is going to reside in this package.
Next, you'll see a line defining an annotation for enabling JPA auditing.
JHipster has provided support for you out of the box to audit data,
including created by, modified by, created date,
and updated date.
The springSecurityAuditorAware bean has also been defined to tie the
currently logged in user or system user for audit purposes.
The final annotation in the class enables Spring's
transaction monument capabilities.
Within the class definition, JHipster has two defined beans.
The first allows for TCP connection to the H2
database used in local development.
Note the profile annotation.
JHipster provides several constants for you as predefined Spring profile names.
In this case,
JHipster is using the development profile to restrict the bean's registration.
The second bean defines the Liquibase configuration.
Note that JHipster has brought in another of its
dependencies as part of this definition.
The TaskExecutor pass will support JHipster's custom
implementation of Spring's Liquibase integration.
The reason for extending this integration is that JHipster is providing
asynchronous execution of the Liquibase schema tasks.
This is another case where JHipster is going above and beyond basic
scaffolding to provide a real-world solution to a common problem.
Liquibase can take a long time to load a schema change,
so this feature reduces the overall time to start a server that leverages it.
That covers the database configuration,
so now let's drop in the entity and repository.
I've once again opened up Eclipse,
and I have the patient-portal-resources project from GitHub.
We're going to start by copying over the Appointment.
java file that represents our entity.
I'll select that and Copy it, I'll scroll back up to the project.
Now note here, we already stubbed out appointment,
so I'm just going to replace it.
Great, now we have the appointment dropped in, but we also need the repository.
Let's scroll down.
I'll select AppointmentRepository.
java.
And we'll copy it, let's scroll back up again,
and I'll paste it into the repository package.
Now you might notice that there's an error.
That error is because we've replaced the appointment entity.
We can just resolve that by opening up the web.
rest package, and for now deleting AppointmentResource.
Obviously, we'll be adding that resource in shortly,
but we no longer need the stub.
So, now I have the repository and the entity added,
let's talk about it in a little more detail.
I'm displaying some of the code for the appointment entity class.
This is a straightforward JPA entity.
One thing to note here is that we have a foreign key reference to the userId.
This is the Id of a user defined by JHipster's generated database schema.
The reason we have the userId as a foreign key reference is
that I want to restrict users so that they see only the
appointments that they've created.
Other than the userId, we have the id column configured as a sequence,
the reason column, the insuranceChange flag column,
and the phoneNumber Colum.
Next, let's look at the AppointmentRepository.
I'm displaying here the appointment repository class.
This is simply an extension of the Spring data JpaRepository interface.
Note the first line has the Spring repository annotation.
Also note that I've added an additional method on the repository.
The purpose of this method is to return appointments only
if they are associated to a userId,
which we'll be passing in as the current user's id.
With the addition of this class, everything needed for persistence is in place.
I'll continue building out the server-side so that we can
test it in full when we're complete.
With that in mind,
let's move on to creating a REST controller class and a service class for appointments.