As part of project generation,
JHipster creates two roles and four user accounts for you.
First, let's look at the roles.
The administration role, as you would expect,
is for admin functions in the application.
This includes viewing metrics, managing users,
and managing the database and development.
The user role is for functions that require authentication.
In this module,
we're going to change this role to be something that's less abstract.
We're going to name it ROLE_PATIENT.
It's likely in your application that you may follow similar steps.
Along with roles, JHipster generates four user accounts for you.
The administration user has all of the admin and user authority rights.
It's likely you're going to delete this account in favor of having one
or more operational users with this level of access.
If you do use this account in any deployed environment,
just make sure to change to the default password.
The anonymous user represents an unauthenticated user, or a guest.
JHipster doesn't use this by default,
so it's up to you if you want to keep it or remove it.
The system user is a user that's leveraged for batch jobs and auditing features.
Finally, the user named user,
represents the authenticated account with non-administration access.
Similar to the admin,
you're likely going to delete this account in favor of real user accounts.
Also, similar to the admin account, if you keep this for any reason,
make sure you change the default password.
These users and roles are foundational to the JHipster generated application,
and are going to be mentioned again as we go through the course.
JHipster assumes that you're managing the users and
roles within your own application, but depending on your environment,
it's likely you'll be integrating with some external source for this data,
such as a directory server.
Unfortunately,
integration with these sources is outside of the scope of this course.
For now,
let's just focus on the admin role to understand what JHipster's providing you.
I've opened up the Chrome browser to the server URL of localhost:8080.
Note here that I'm showing the anonymous user's landing page.
At the top I have a navigation bar that includes a ribbon
to tell me what environment I'm in.
Right now we're in dev.
I also have an icon, I have the application name, and I have a release version.
On the right side of the navigation bar I have two menus, Home and Account.
I'll talk about Account menu now.
In the Account menu I have two items.
I'm going to click on the Register menu item,
and we see a Registration page that JHipster generated for you.
This registration page allows you to create a new
user account with the user role.
It's likely you're going to make some customizations to this,
such as allowing for the registration of different user types.
For this course, we're just going to leave the registration view as is,
though,
we're going to need to change the server logic for our new patient role name.
Let's go back to the homepage, and now I'm going to click the Account menu,
and I'm going to select Sign in.
I get prompted with a modle for sign in.
It includes inputs for the Login, the Password,
and the check box for Remember Me.
The Remember Me check box remembers the user's identity after log in.
This functionality is actually a JHipster extensions of
the Spring Security remember me feature.
JHipster also provides you with support for recovering a password.
Let's try to log in.
I'm going to answer in user, for the Login,
and also enter in user for the Password.
As you can see, not very secure.
Let's click Sign in.
And now we can see the user's landing page.
We know that they've logged in because first of all,
the content area tells me that I'm logged in as user.
Also, the navigation bar now has a new menu item called Entities.
What is this Entities menu item?
Well let's try clicking it.
Hmm, there's nothing there.
What's happening here is JHipster's providing you a container,
that container will show menu items if you use a separate generator.
This generator is going to create all of the client and
server code for you around an entity type.
Then, you can perform CRUD operations and the views that get generated.
I'm not going to show you this feature in the course,
but it's pretty cool and I would check it out if you get a chance.
Let's look at the Account menu.
This has also changed.
Instead of just the Sign in and Register,
I now have four more menu items, Settings,
Password, Sessions, and Sign out.
Settings are just general information about the user.
Password allows me to change the password.
Sessions shows the sessions that I have for the user.
And Sign out obviously logs me out.
Let's do that now because I want to log in as an admin.
So we're back to the anonymous page, and I'm going to click Account again,
and I'm going to select Sign in.
Now let's log in as an administrator.
The admin account is a Login of admin, and a password of admin.
Let's click Sign in, and now again I'm logged in as an admin because one,
my content area says that I am, and second of all,
I have a new navigation bar.
I still see the Entities menu.
Note that that Entities menu is accessible both for the user and the admin,
because the admin includes the user role.
Let's look at that Administration menu now.
Under here I have User management,
which lists the available user accounts in the app,
Metrics, which includes basically Spring Boot metric data,
Health, which is also coming from Spring Boot,
the Configuration of my application, Audits,
which is a feature provided by JHipster,
Logs, which shows me the application log levels,
API, which gives me access to Swagger, and Database,
which is where we can see an H2 database console.
Since we're using H2 database I have this menu item,
I'm going to go ahead and check it out.
Here I've opened up the H2 console.
You can see the information about the local database,
including the driver, the URL, and credentials.
Let's click Connect.
Okay great, now I'm in the console.
On the left,
let's note that you have all of the tables that were generated by JHipster.
These are all prefixed with JHI_.
You're going to see this prefix as a common pattern
throughout the generated project.
Let's explore some of these tables.
If I click on the JHI_USER table, I'll be able to run the SQL query.
And I can see all of the information that's being stored about the user.
Is see their unique identifier, their login ID,
a hashed password, their name, and their email.
Now, let's query the JHI_AUTHORITY table.
Here we see the two roles that we discussed earlier.
At this point we see the role named ROLE_USER.
It's a generic role,
and one that we want to change to capture the concept of a patient.
Obviously, updating this value right in the database is not the right approach. Instead, let's look at how JHipster created this data.