In this module,
I showed you the steps needed to customize the client
side of a JHipster generated project.
I went into some depth on how webpack scripts come pre-generated for you.
You saw how Browsersync was also integrated out of the box to
update the browser for client-side code updates.
I gave you an overview of the client-side project structure.
You saw the directories,
and got a high-level overview of the content that they contain.
Finally,
we customized the client-side code by adding a new patient module to
support creating and viewing patient appointments.
The navigation bar was updated to include a new menu and submenu item,
you saw how JHipster provided you out of the box support to show or hide
navigation content based on the authenticated user and their role.
You then saw how a custom module can be built,
which leverages both generated features,
and JHipster dependent libraries.
Then, we added a server-side stub so that we could test out the new UI feature.
With the client-side code in place,
let's build out the server-side API to fully support this new patient appointment feature.