All right,
let's get to building your first note app when I'm working.
I like to keep at least two things open.
First is my text editor so that I can write and edit the program,
and I also sometimes use this to browse through the folders in the directory that I'm
inside of.
And the second is my terminal.
So I can run and test the application and see the deep of messages etcetera.
Later on,
when we're building the Web app front end.
It's also useful toe have a browser open so that you could test it when I'm building an A P
.
I also often have an A p I tester like postman open For now,
these two windows are fine.
For the purpose of this video,
I'm going to collapse these windows into one screen so that you can see the text editor on
the left hand side and the terminal in the right hand side.
Normally,
I wouldn't do that.
I would just kind of toggle between the screens,
but ta,
going back and forth would make this video very dizzying.
So I'm just putting it all in one.
If you're going to court along go ahead and open up your terminal and your text editor,
if you like,
so that we can get rolling.
Now to recap in this section,
we're going to be building a rest ful a p I for an up time monitoring application using no
NPM modules,
no dependencies or anything like that.
We will,
however,
be using a large chunk of the features available in the No Js library,
and I'll point out what each one of these is as we go along several sections from now,
we're going to go back through this code and add some tests and re factor a little bit to
make it better and more robust overall.
But for now,
we're just going to build a quick and dirty application.
As I mentioned,
we're building up time monitoring app.
This is an app that lets you as a user into a U R L that you want monitor,
and it'll send you alerts.
If that euro goes down or comes back up after being down,
you're probably familiar with a lot of uptime monitoring applications available.
We want this app to be usable in the wild,
so let's make sure that our users can sign up signing,
sign out,
then edit their settings in addition to just being able to make up time checks and that
kind of thing.
Also,
we want our users to get their up time alerts their up alerts and they're down alerts by
SMS instead of email.
So we're gonna be integrating that way before we get to coding.
Let's speck out or requirements here.
What is this,
a P I part supposed to do?
We want a rest for a P I.
That one listens on a port and accepts incoming HDP requests for post get put,
delete and head to.
We want the FBI to allow a client to connect to it so that they can create a new user.
Edit that user or delete that user.
Three.
We want users to be able to sign in,
and we want that signing mechanism to give them back a token that they can use for a
subsequent authenticated requests.
If they want to do something that requires being logged in,
they're going to need to provide that token that they got when they signed in the first
Number four.
We want that same user to be able to sign out,
and we want their token to be invalidated,
or you want them to be able to invalidate their token when they sign out.
Number five.
We want a signed in user to be able to use that token to create a new check.
And by check,
we mean a task for the system to check a given your l to see if it's up or down.
We also want the user to be able to define what up or down is.
For example,
for some websites up might mean that you receive a 200 status code,
while other websites might say that for us and up is anything that isn't 500 Number six.
We want a signed in user to be able to edit or delete any of their checks,
and we want to limit their checks to five so we don't want a user to be able to create 1/6
check.
We want them to be able to have zero through five checks and seven in the background.
We want to perform all the checks at the appropriate time and alert the users when a check
changes.
It's state from up to down or vice versa.
We want our checks to run once a minute.
So once a minute we want all the checks created by all of the users to run.
We want to check those euros to see if they're up or down,
given the definition provided by the user and if it is currently down when it had been up,
we want to send them an SMS.
If it is up when it had just been down,
Otherwise,
if it doesn't fit those two conditions,
we just want to do nothing.
Okay,
so that's pretty much our requirements for the A P I.
There's a few other little things that we want to be able to do,
but we'll walk through those as they appear for the majority of these features will use the
plane known AP I.
But to alert users by SMS messages,
we use no to connect to the twilio a p I to send SMS to the user,
though this doesn't mean that will be using 1/3 party library to connect to TWILIO.
We're actually going to craft that http requests by hand,
and I chose this integration because I wanted to be able to show you how it's possible to
interact with AP eyes from plain note itself,
without needing a library from that vendor.
Also,
since it's a fairly simple program,
we will be writing to the file system rather than a traditional data store.
If we were building this program for production,
it would be worth integrating with a true data store,
possibly through a library.
But that's outside the scope of this course for us.
We're just gonna be writing Jason files to the file system and reading them as if the file
system was a key value store.