now,
the next thing we're going to want to get out of this request before we process it are the
headers that the user might have sent.
So in between getting the http method and sending the response,
let's go ahead and insert what we want to do next,
which is get the headers as an object.
Luckily,
this,
like the previous example,
is also very simple.
We want Teoh define a headers variable,
and its value is just going to be request R E Q wreck dot petters wreck dot headers.
Now let's go ahead and log that out.
I'm going to erase the rest of what we had loved previously because we already know that
that's working request received with these headers.
Okay,
so now we're logging out which headers we are receiving.
I'm gonna go ahead and save this file,
start the act back up,
but at this point,
we need to add headers.
This request so curl were kind of outgrowing Carl at this point,
some to close that tab and switch over here to postman.
Postman is an http request library that's really useful for debugging ap eyes.
When you're building them,
it lets you form requests and the headers you want to say and at the body you want to send
really easily.
Okay,
so I'm going to say that we want to send a request to local host 3000 and we want to add
some headers.
Food is gonna equal bar fares,
is gonna equal buzz and apples are going to equal oranges and red is going to equal book.
Okay,
so that's a whole bunch of headers sent at that request and groups we don't want to do
local host 30,000.
We want to do local host 3000 So I'm going to send that request.
We see that down here,
we can see the response that we've got back was still just raw text coming back.
It's hello world,
but if we go back to the terminal,
we can see all of these headers that got sent along with the request.
Some of these we didn't add in Postman,
they were added for us.
But some of these we configured ourselves.
For example,
we set food tow bar.
We set red to blue apples to oranges and fizz toe bus.
So now the application is understanding all the headers that it seeing as part of these
requests,
and it is locking them out for us.
I can kill this app now and move on to the next section.