all right,
The next thing we want to do for the last thing we want to do before we start handling
these requests and routing them somewhere is get the payload that the users sent.
This is going to be a bit more complicated than the others,
but is still fairly straightforward.
So let's go ahead and above this response say what we're trying to do.
Get the payload.
If there is any for this,
we're going to need a another library that's built into node and that is called string
decoder.
So we're going to require appear you're gonna say that bar string decoder equals require
string.
Underscore,
decoder Don't string decoder.
The String Dakota Library contains a number of useful things,
and the string decoder functions that we want are actually available on the string decoder
parameter within that object to now there,
available to us at the variable string decoder.
Now back to getting the payload.
First thing we want is to create a new string decoder.
So we're going to say that this decoder equals new strain decoder.
And when you create a new stream decoder,
you want to tell it what kind of char set or encoding it can expect her.
You know what it should be decoding And for our case is gonna be utf eight.
This is going to be the case with pretty much any.
You know,
Jason ap Either gonna be building unless you're specifically trying to do something other
than utf eight,
which probably very rarely be the case.
So as you might have heard,
no deals heavily with these things called streams.
We don't need to do a deep dive into what streams are right now,
but it's worth knowing that they are pretty much what they sound like.
Their bits of information that are coming in a little bit at a time,
as opposed to all at once.
Payloads that come as part of an HTP.
Requests come in to the HDP server as a stream,
and so we need to collect that stream as it comes in.
And then,
when the stream tells us were at the end,
coalesce that into one coherent thing before we can figure out what that pay low it is
because as we receive little bits of this payload,
we might only know a few characters at a time.
But re are really interested in what the entire payload is in its entirety once it is
finished streaming in.
So in order to do that,
before we start catching the payload as it comes in,
we want to create a new string to hold it.
I was gonna call it Buffer for now,
and I'm gonna initialize it to an empty string itself than as new data comes in.
I'm going to append it to this existing string here.
We do that by binding to an event that the request object emits.
And that event is called data.
So when the request object emits the event,
so on the event called data,
we want this call back to be called and we want the data that is being emitted to be passed
to this call back.
And what we want to do is we want to say that that buffer recreated up here should have the
new data appended to it through a string decoder to the buffer is going to be appended with
decoder doctor,
right?
And then the data that we received.
So what that means is,
as this data is streaming in every time it's dreams in a little piece.
The request object emits the data event that were binding to and it sends us a bunch of un
decoded data.
We know it should be utf eight.
So we decode it to utf eight using this new YouTube UTF eight decoder that we created and
we upend the result onto the buffer that we created a moment ago.
What that means is a large string that streaming in is going to be received by us little
pieces at a time.
But eventually after this data event emits,
you know,
a certain number of times it's all going to be there,
and the buffer is going to have it all as a normal utf eight string.
But there's actually another event that tells us that it's done when it's done and that is
called end.
So when the request object emit so wreck on and we I want to call this callback,
which doesn't take any parameters,
and that's going to tell us,
Okay,
this is the end.
So the buffer is going to be appended with whatever we just ended it with decoder dot end
and now that the request has finished,
we want to do the things that we were doing before,
namely sending the response and logging the request.
So removing the response,
sending and the request,
logging from where they used to live just inside the function body into the handler of the
end event.
Now you might be saying not every request is going to have a payload.
So is this end event going to get called?
The answer is yes.
The end event was yet called.
This data event won't always be called.
So if there is no payload,
the buffer is going to get initialized to an empty string.
It's never going to get anything appended to it.
But then it's going to get ended,
and we're still going to send the response.
And let's go ahead and say that the request was received with this payload and go ahead and
log out whatever the payload.
Waas.
Okay,
so just toe walk back through this one more time to make sure it's totally coming home.
We created a decoder that we're using later on.
The buffer is calling it buffer.
It's really just a placeholder for a string.
As it requests,
payload gets streamed in the request object is going to admit a data event that were
binding on.
So the request on this data object,
we get a new bit of data and then we use the decoder to turn that into a simple string
through utf eight.
And then when it ends,
we cap off the buffer with whatever the request ended with,
we send the response and then lock out what the payload waas.
This is how streams are generally handled in no Js.
You don't simply just grab the value of a stream.
You need to bind to the data events of a stream or the ending event of a stream or whatever
events the stream has defined,
so that you can grab the little pieces of information that the stream is sending along and
then know when the stream has finished.
In this way.
We're actually using another part of the no Js docks right now,
which is called stream streams air built into node.
There are fundamental concept,
especially when it comes to http servers or any kind of servers,
and this is generally how you deal with them.
You can create them or you can read them in.
So let's go ahead and start the server again knowed index dot Js servers listening.
We're gonna go back over the postman here and now we're going to add a body to our request
in order to have a body,
we to switch to something other than get because technically,
according to the definitions of get it shouldn't have any kind of payload there.
So we're going to switch to a post,
and now we're going to add that the body should be a raw body.
That's just text.
And this is the body we are sending.
Let's go ahead and send it.
Send it.
We got hello world back.
Let's see what the application thought it received it received.
This is the body that we are sending.
So that is how you stream in a payload that comes in.
This could be for a giant payload,
like a huge Jason object in our case,
Or this could be for a small bit of text or nothing at all.
Let's send one more request without the body,
the one that we did previously.
Just to make sure that the a p I still working even if there is nobody.
So the request is been received with this payload.
Nothing in our case would be an empty string.
Because that's what we initialized this buffer variable too.
Okay,
so now we can move on to the next lecture.