this course is separated into eight sections.
The first section is the one you're in right now.
The introductions in overviews in this section will introduce the course and myself,
the instructor.
Then we'll get you set up with everything you need to complete the exercises that come
later.
We'll also go over the requirements and prerequisites for the scores to ensure your in the
right place and you're ready to go through it in Section two will give you a conceptual
overview of node and the story behind it.
We'll start with the history of note.
It's quite a story,
and I'm sure you enjoy it after that will walk through the nuts and bolts of what note is
and what via is how they both work,
as well as how they relate to each other.
Well,
then show you a sample note app so we can apply what we just learn to a real world example
to cement our understanding of how a note application really works.
Well,
then talk about a few common note conventions used as well as differences between reading
JavaScript for no Js and writing it for the browser.
We'll also go over the differences between note AP eyes and build in JavaScript functions,
and we'll go over the read evil print loop rebel that comes with note in Section three.
We're going to jump right in and build a rest for a P I together.
Doing this exercise will get you familiar with several key sections of the No Js docks.
Fs the file system.
Http crypto lib string decoder and path to name a few in Section four,
we're going to build a sample Web G Y.
The major purpose of this app will be to consume the A P I we just built,
but also use it as an excuse to show you how you can build complex template ID views within
note.
In Section five,
you're going to build a command line application that takes user inputs from the console,
processes them and writes outputs back out to the console.
This will get you acquainted with nodes,
read line events,
TT,
Y,
V eight and OS modules.
Very feud.
No developers have ever built a command line tool and note.
After this section,
you'll be one of them,
and you'll have done it without a framework.
How about that section six is all about testing.
Did you know that note has a built in assertion library and that writing tests is as easy
as creating file?
No quote unquote test runners or pipelines air needed?
Here in this section,
you're going to write tests for a few of the functions that we wrote in the fever these
projects.
We're going to write unit tests and also show some examples of how you test your new A.
P I over http will also explore how to use the strict JavaScript flag,
Teoh Lynch,
your code for syntax errors and how to use the D bugger to pinpoint issues during execution
.
Section seven Speed and scalability or two of the most popular reasons that Dev's choose to
work in note.
But few know how to profile or benchmark their code or tweak it for performance.
Section seven will be a crash course in performance optimization and all things speed and
scalability here will re factor some of our earlier app so that they're less resource
hungry and then use the performance hooks module to time the execution of certain processes
.
Then we'll dive into nodes,
cluster and child processes modules to explore how any note app can take advantage of all
the cores available to it.
Section eight once you reach Section eight Yobe,
a development force to be reckoned with,
but you'll still be missing experience with a few key no J ASAP eyes that we didn't fit
into the earlier lectures.
Section eight is dedicated to all these loose ends.
In this section,
you'll get experience with HDP two VM,
UDP,
Net TLS and more.
Once this section is done,
you're done.
There really won't be anything left to teach you.
As far as lecture format.
The majority of this course will show a text editor on one side of the screen and a
terminal on the other.
I encourage you to make this video full screen on a full size laptop or desktop so you can
see the text as it might be quite small if you'd like to download the code rather than
write it from scratch along side the video.
Each lectures code base is available to download or clone from our get up or from the
course site.