The next thing we need to do is formalize the fact that we're sending Jason back to the
user.
If you remember from the last lecture,
handlers must send us a object back.
If they don't send us an object,
we default to a empty object,
and we always turn that object or empty object into a Jace on string and then returned it
to the user here.
But we don't actually tell the user that we are returning them,
Jason.
And so we want to formalize that a bit more.
Now.
We're going to do that by sending the header content type with our response.
So we're going to send a headers that says Content type is application slash Jason.
The way that we do that is again a using a built in function that comes on this response.
Object so you to do rez dot set header,
and this can take in anything we want.
Its key value.
It takes two parameters,
a key and a value.
So we're going to say that the key is content type and the value,
which is the next parameter is application slash Jason.
Now it's telling any browser anyone who understands content types that we're sending Jason
,
and it should parse this response as if it was Jason.
So let's go ahead and start up our server again.
Go back to postman,
send the same response.
We can see that this was the response that we got the last time we sent it.
Now we're going to send this response and you can see it changed from just a bit of black
text to a parse Jason object.
That is because this application postman looked at that content type that we just returned
.
See that we returned content type application,
Jason,
and it's going to understand.
Okay,
this is Jason.
I'm gonna go ahead and parse it and show it back to the user in a pretty way.
If we look at the raw response is,
there's no difference.
We're always returning this raw string.
There's nothing changed about the formatting or the coloring or anything like that of what
were returned is just that a browser or a a mobile client.
Or in this case,
Postman understands that when you're sending Jason,
it's a little nicer for the user.
If I format it in a nice way,
so it's doing that is doing this color highlighting for us because we told Postman,
you know,
this is Jason.
All right,
so that's how you specify Jason.
Later on,
we'll deal with specifying different types of payloads.
But for now,
we're building this A p I.
That is purely in Jace.
On every request that we received,
we're going to respond to with Jason,
at least for now.
And so at this point,
we are done.
I'm gonna go ahead and kill the server.
We can move on to the next lecture.