At this point,
the APP has reached sufficient complexity that we need to add some kind of configuration
file to store different configuration variables so we can start the app in different ways
for different environments.
What we like to accomplish is relevant.
Starting the app with node index dot Js we'd like to say no off equals And then what other
environment name?
We want such a stating and then node index dot Js as normal as we went over in an earlier
lecture,
this note arms command line argument becomes available to us within the APP as a global.
In reality,
we could say environment equals staging or known environment.
You could say Jing,
we could have come any command line variable that we want named here knowed underscore e
envy is just a convention that many applications use and so we're going to use it here.
In order to accomplish this,
we're going to create a second file in addition to our index dot gs,
we're gonna call that config dot Js and it's going to live in the same directory just
within the app for then we're going to modify indexed SJs so that it requires that new
convict library and uses thebe configuration defined within it.
Within the configuration file,
we're going to define several different environments and the variables that should exist
within those environments.
And then we're actually going to export Onley,
the environment that has currently been called by the command line,
so that when another file such as index dot Js requires that one,
all it sees is an object interface with the variables defined as they should be for the
specific environment.
That's it.
If that was a little confusing,
don't worry.
It'll make sense as we go along.
As I mentioned,
the first thing we're going to do is create this new file.
So touch,
don't you?
Yes.
And within here,
which is going to note that we're going to create and export configuration variables?
Okay,
the first thing we want to create is just a general container for all the environments.
This is the object is going to hold all of the different environments and their sub keys as
keys on its own object.
But rather than exporting the entire environments object later on,
we're going to have some logic that determines which exact environment should.
It gets exported and then exports Onley that sub object from the environments up For now,
we're going to create two environments.
One is staging that will be using most the time and the next one is production for our
purposes.
Since we don't always want to have note on equal staging passed along,
we're actually going to set staging as the default environment so that if the user has not
defined note off equals anything,
it's going to go ahead and default staging.
So first,
I'm going to create this staging object and next I'm going to create a production.
Okay,
Within both of these objects,
I'm just going to define some pretty straightforward keys.
I'm going to find the port that they should run on if it's in staging or production,
respectively,
and also create a key called off name that will allow anyone using this config object to
know exactly the name of the environment that they're in right now.
Okay,
So as you can see here,
all I did was created port and off name King on both objects.
The only major difference is that staging is running on Port 3000 and production is running
on 5000.
You can choose any numbers.
You want these air just for this example.
Off name.
We've just go ahead and add a key to these objects That is the same as the name of the
environment.
This is because reaction going to end up exporting the inner pieces of these objects.
And so the key,
such as staging up here,
isn't going to be visible.
So we're gonna have to create something like off name in order for the user to know exactly
what environment they're dealing with at the time without having to parse that note off,
uh,
committed my variable again.
Okay,
so now we have these two different environments,
and we want to determine which one should be exploited out.
As I mentioned,
this is easily accomplice with the global called process dot off dot node,
underscore arm.
And so we're going to go ahead and checked to see if that exists.
See if it is not undefined,
and if it is defined,
we're going to push it down to lower case.
We're gonna say the current environment equals type of process.
I don't know equals string,
So if it equals a string and we want it,
so we're going to say process done to lower case.
Otherwise,
this gives us back in a peace treaty.
All right,
now we want to check that the current environment is actually one of the environments that
is defined up here because it's quite possible that someone might have started the APP and
said Node equals local host or note off equals food bar.
And we haven't defined a food bar or a local host environment here.
And so we don't just want to check that the current environment it's set,
but that it's set to one of the keys on our greater environments up yet before,
if the environment that's being passed or the one that we've grabbed right here is not one
of the keys on the environments object,
we're going to go ahead and default to the staging environment instead.
So we're going to say that far the environment to export,
So the one that really needs to get pushed out to anyone who's requiring this library is
going to equal take off environments kind of environment,
which is this variable here equals of it.
If it does,
then that's the one we want environments trying to Otherwise we wanted to folk to
environments,
Doc.
So at this point,
this environment export variable is going to contain this whole object or in this whole
object,
it's always gonna be one of the two because either they define staging defined production
or it defaulted to staging.
It's always going to contain something we don't have to default to staging.
We're choosing to do that in this case just for convenience.
So the last thing that we need to do is actually export market,
and we're going to use the normal convention for that that we talked about earlier.
Montel dot exports equals.
But in this case,
as I mentioned,
rather than exporting,
all the environments were on Lee going to export the one that we walked the require er to
see.
So in module dot exports equals environment to export.
All right,
that's everything that we have to do in the config dot Js file.
But at this point,
it's just a file that exists.
The note APP is going to completely ignore it because we're starting up the index dot Js
file and the index that Js file is making no reference to config dot Js So now we need to
modify index dot Js to use the conflict.
Violence step.
All right,
so let's go ahead and require that file,
but passing a relative path to it.
So we're going to say that the variable can fake equals require.
And remember,
this is in the same directory that we're in right now,
So we're just going to go dot slash can pick.
We could just as easily do dot slash config dot Js.
But remember,
notice smart enough to assume that you mean dot Js and so we don't need to tell it that
part,
so config equals require too thick.
And now this variable is going to equal whatever is being exported from here.
So we can change some of the variables that we're using within this file to use
configuration variables to find there.
There's a lot of things that we could do,
but for our purposes right now,
all we're really caring about is the port and the environment name cause those two
variables that are defined in to convict So let's go down to where we actually start the
server server.
Don't listen.
And rather than hard coating in 3000 were going to say that we're starting to server and
let's just take away.
Haven't listen on 14,000 we're going Teoh dynamically set the pork to whatever is defined
in the config.
So rather than saying 3000 willing to say config dot court just to review where we got that
the object is being exported is going to be the same as one of these two objects here.
In either case,
they both have a port key defined on them.
And so that object docked port was gonna equal 3000 this case or staging in this case if we
started in default mode or if we started instead.
Okay,
so we're listening on CONFIG port.
Now this measures that we log out,
the server is listening on port 3000.
We could go ahead and modify that to include the dynamic variable instead,
config dot port.
Let's go a step further and go ahead and log out exactly which environment that we're in.
Because remember,
the off name is one of the variables available to us in that config object.
So the server is listening on a port can fake port and then we want to say in,
I think name good.
So,
for example,
this would say the servers listening on a port 3000 staging or hopefully will say that.
Okay,
so those are all the modifications we need to make the index dot Js file.
Let's go ahead and start up the as normal and see if the defaulting to staging works.
So no index dot Js The server is listening on a port 3000 in staging mode.
Let's go ahead and pass note on equal staging.
No indexed out.
Yes.
See if he says the same thing it does.
All right,
let's kill the server.
And this time we're going to start up and no equals abduction,
no index statue the services thing on port 5000 in production.
So you can see depending on the note variable that we start the act with.
Now the index dot Js file is going to inherit two completely different sets of
configuration variables because this config library that we just created is only going to
export their variables that are useful for that specific environment.
This is a really simple example of adding configuration.
We're gonna add a few more keys later,
but I just wanted you to see exactly how this works and how we're going to be using it.
So I'm gonna go ahead and clear out this console now and we can move on to the next venture
.