so far in this course,
we've created an http server and listened on the port.
But we haven't done anything with http s At this point,
it's going to be worth it to add on https support to our app.
And so we're going to do that in this lecture.
The first thing we're going to need to do,
though,
is create an SSL certificate that we can use within the app to actually facilitate the SSL
handshake and so forth.
In order to create the SSL certificates,
I'm going to use open SSL.
If you don't already have it installed,
you can download it easily.
I'm going to place these SSL Certs inside of a new directory called https and then CD
inside of it.
All right now,
the commander going to use very long.
I'm going to spell it out here.
But if you want to just copy and paste it.
Go ahead and down the code for this lecture.
Look inside the HDP s folder and there is a text file called key generation dot text.
You can just copy that pasted in your console,
especially if you're on OS X and it will create two different files,
a key dot Pam and a served up.
Okay,
the command is open.
SSL wreck dash nooky R s A.
It is to just 48 dash new dash nodes,
dash x five or nine dash days 36.
50 3650 days And then the key out The key that we want to come out is keyed up him.
And the search that we want to come out,
which is just with the dash out key,
is certain.
So one more time Open.
It's a cell wreck.
Dash nooky R s a 2048 dash New dash nodes dash x five o nine Dash days 3650 dash key out
key dot Pim dash out served up just to clarify Here,
this should not actually be a capital K.
There should be a lucky escape.
All right,
at this point,
you are going to be presented with a bunch of questions.
You could answer them anyway that you want,
especially for this example.
In reality,
if you're building this for production,
go ahead and answer these questions truthfully for the business that you're creating this
app for.
Okay,
So the two letter code for the country.
For us is us the state or province name.
California Locality in San Francisco.
The organization name.
It's purple.
The organization unit Name is purple.
The common name.
This gets a little complicated,
especially when you're working on local host for us,
where it is going to write local host.
But if you're doing a production website,
for example,
you're doing example dot com and you want this SSL certificate to work for www dot example
dot com and normal example dot com.
It will depend on who you're getting as a self certificate from for most SSL certificate
creators.
You can just specify example dot com,
and they'll make sure that the certain works for Www and normal example dot com for us.
Since we're creating a local hosting,
this is a self signed certificate.
It doesn't really matter.
We're just going to write the word local host in there email address.
Hello?
Had,
uh,
come and that's it.
So at this point,
if we look inside this directory that way,
or if we go ahead and explore with Adam,
we can see that we have assert that Pym and a key dot All right.
So what we're going to do is now use thes two files in order to create an https server.
The first file that we want to modify is going to be config dot Js Rather than having one
port that we listen on,
we actually need to now listen on to ports.
As you may be aware of,
Http and https conflict with each other.
And so we are due to separate out the ports on most applications.
HDP is going to happen on Port 80 and HCPs is going to happen on port 443 Don't read too
much into what those numbers mean.
That's just the convention that has evolved over the years that is popular,
and that is what most Web browsers expect.
If you're running a local holds application,
it really doesn't matter which ports you choose.
But on production you might want to choose 80 and 443 if your application is facing the
world.
Okay,
so for us,
we want to.
Now,
instead of having poured 3000 for staging,
we want to have two different variables.
Http Port,
which will leave at 3000 and http s support which we're going to change to 3000 and one
Similarly,
for production,
we wanted to take away this port at 5000 and replace it with HDP port at 5000.
And go ahead and add on HDP s court.
That's going to be as you guessed,
at 5000 and one.
We'll save that file.
And remember,
in the index dot Js file we have used that port variable,
so we needed to go ahead and update the places where reviews that.
But this is also a good time to re factor this file in general because we're going to be
creating two different servers that have the same basic functions.
And so rather than coating up this entire server block twice,
we want to re factor it so that all we have to do is create the server http mode and then
pass wreck and rez to another function that will actually handle the meat of the logic.
And then we can add on https,
don't create server function and also have that one just pass,
wreck and rez to that same function that will handle the meat of the logic.
So rather than having two different create server functions that both have a whole bunch of
logic.
We're going to trim down this,
creates ever function,
create another https,
create server function and have them both past their reckoned rez to 1/3 function that all
make more sense.
In a second,
before we create the H two p s part,
we want to just go ahead and re factor the HDP part.
Then it will make more sense when we want to add on the https.
As I mentioned,
we want to create a function that's going to handle all the unified logic for both the http
and the https server.
So we're going to call that function unified server,
and it's just going to accept a wreck,
and rez is normal.
All right,
now what we want to do is take the entire meat of this function up here,
starting from where it gets the girl all the way down to the end.
Take that out of this function and put it inside of this one.
Now,
this server,
rather than doing all that logic itself,
is just going to pass its reckoned rez to unified server.
Now it's worth pointing out that unified server isn't actually doing anything with the port
.
It is handling the requests that come into the server when they come in,
which is after the point that the server has already started listening on a port and has
logged out which port it's on.
So we don't need to update anything.
A unified server.
We do need to update where we have started Server.
So rather than conflict outpour,
we want to have config dot HDP port.
Then we want to say the server is listening on port config dot http report that we can get
rid of the environment name cause we know that's worth Okay.
Now you can see how this is coming together rather than having a huge function up here.
We have two very small functions.
One that in Stan.
She hates the server and one that starts the server.
So we can change the combat here to simply say we are in Stan Shih ating the HDP sever,
and then we're starting the server.
Okay,
so now we can see what we need.
We need to create a second server and https server that listens on a different port.
Listens on 3001 or 5000 won and then pass it the logic to that same unified server function
.
To do that,
we're going to need a different module than http and,
predictably,
that modules called https.
All right,
now,
I'm just gonna put in comments toe outline,
what we're going to be doing.
We want to stand.
She ate the https server with one function and then another function.
We're going to start the https server.
At this point,
these server names air gonna get confusing.
If we have one server called server and the other one called something else,
it's it's kind of weird.
So let's go ahead and change the HDP server so that it is actually called HDP server
instead of just server and then to start it rather than calling server.
Doubtless.
And we're gonna have to call http server dot Listen,
All right,
now we have a blueprint for how we're going to create the HDP s server.
I'm actually just going to go ahead and copy the start function from http down to ancient
PS because it's going to work almost entirely the same way we're going to change it to
https server dot Listen,
config dot http s support and then console Log out that the server is listening on config
dot HDP s support.
All right.
Now,
of course,
the HDP s server variable doesn't exist yet.
So up here,
we need to create it.
But this is done a little bit differently than the HDP one,
but I'll start with his http version,
and now we will make some modifications to it.
Https server equals 82 p s dot create server.
We're actually going to add in some variables before the call back.
So we're gonna call it HDP s server options and then put in the call back,
and then it's going to call unified server.
But we haven't a fine https server option,
so let's go ahead and work backwards from there.
That's create that object.
Https Server options equals an empty object.
All right,
we're going to want to keys on this object.
The different streams starting http and https server is that the H two Bs server has a
whole bunch of options related to you Guessed it.
Https and SSL.
The two that are important and are required for creating a server are the key and the
certificate the key in the certificate or what?
Allow the https encryption and decryption to actually happen.
So if we don't specify those,
it really can to create an encrypted server.
So we're going to create a key,
and we're going to create a certain we have to find them in something.
We actually want to define these two variables or these two keys.
As the contents of you guessed it.
These two files that live in this htp esf order,
the cert dot pam and the key dot him.
So we want to read those two files and synchronously so that their data can be the value of
this key.
In order to do that,
we're going to require the file system module fs that comes built into note.
So we're going to save our F s equals Require fs and the function that were using on the FS
module is read file sync with much of the note a p I.
You'll notice that there are sink versions of a function and a sink versions of a function
.
For many cases,
you want to use the A sink whenever possible,
since we want these files to be read in synchronously.
The sink version of this function makes sense that we want to call fs don't read file sink
.
And then we're going to specify the path to the file in this case that we're specifying the
path to the key file so dot slash https.
Because remember,
these air is living up a directory inside of https directory keyed up.
And then,
for the certain wanted to the same thing Fs docked,
we'd file sync don't slash h two bs,
sir Don.
Okay,
And that's pretty much it we're now reading in these two files,
so h two b a server options dot key will actually be the contents of this file and Sirte
will be the same.
We're passing these server options to the https server when it starts so that it can
actually create a secure server when it starts up.
Okay,
so I'm gonna go ahead and clear out my terminal.
We have saved these files.
Now we're gonna go ahead and start the app.
I do have a small type of appearance.
I'm gonna change require to make sure it has an e on the end before you start the app.
Make sure you get back out of the https directory.
So seedy up a directory.
Make sure you're in the base directory for your app before you try to start it.
Go ahead and started with node index Doctor.
Yes,
all right.
Now I have to Long's coming to the screen.
The servers listening on Port 3000 and the server is listening on Port 2001 Kill that
started up again with node off equals production and the servers listening on 5000 the
server is listening on 5000 and one.
Now,
we have two different servers,
technically,
that are listening on two different ports,
but passing all the meat of their logic to this unified server function.
So,
in reality,
these two servers are identical.
They're working the same way.
It's just that they need to listen on two different ports.
And the client that wants to connect over http can connect on the first port if they want,
can't https,
which,
for obvious reasons,
is highly recommended.
They can connect on the second Port.
All right,
now we can move on to the next lecture