Okay,
At this point,
we have enough of these scaffolding of the application built up so we can actually start
building on the production routes.
The first round we want to build is super simple.
It is called Ping,
So we're going to add a route to the router called Ping,
and we're going to create a handler for that route that simply calls back 200.
What is this for?
The purpose is so you can monitor your application and easily find out if it is alive or
dot Coincidentally,
this is also really useful for up time monitoring.
If this application was being monitored by another uptime monitor,
the slash ping route is probably the one that we would give when we're setting up the check
.
Because the Ping route doesn't have any actual effect on the server.
All it does is called back 200 say,
Yes,
I'm still alive.
So let's go ahead and create that run within index dot Js.
I'm going to get rid of the sample route entirely and leave the not found handler because
that is still something that we want to invoke.
Anytime a user requests a path,
it doesn't exist,
but we want to define a router rather than sample.
We want to call it pink,
and it needs to go to handlers dot pig.
So I'm gonna recreate a hammer here.
That's a lot like the sample route.
Call it a ping handler.
Handlers dot Ping Just like the others.
It takes a data object and call back,
and all it's going to do is call back 200.
Remember that you can call back a status code and a data object optionally.
And if it doesn't call back a data object,
an empty object gets returned to the user.
So we're just going to call that 200 cause we don't care about the payload.
Really?
I'm going to start up the act.
It's listening.
Now,
I'm gonna go back over to Postman,
make a request to local host 3000 slash king,
and I should just get 200 back with a raw object,
and I do All right,
so that was pretty simple.
Now we have a ping set up that will always call back 200 to any request.
We can kill this application and move on to the next lecture