and the next lecture.
We're going to want to start creating routes that right,
data and manipulated.
But before we do that,
we need to set up a regime to write data to the final system and read it back out.
As I mentioned in previous lecture,
we're going to be using the file system as a bit of a key value store of different Jason
Files.
But we need a library in order to set that all up.
So the first thing that we're going to do is create a couple new directories within our app
.
The first directory is going to be called Docked Data.
Since it starts with a dot by convention,
it is a hidden folder.
And that is just because we want to make it clear to anyone looking at this code that the
things inside of dot data is not logic,
but actually just files that are being written as a part of the apse process of running.
The next directory that we're going to bond is a lip directory,
so I'm creating it there.
This live directory is going to have a number of files inside of it eventually,
but for now we are just going to create a library for working with data specifically the
data inside of the dot data folder.
So inside of the lib directory,
I'm going to create a file called data dot Js.
This fire was going to be the library that we used for storing and editing data.
This file is going to have to dependencies.
The first is the file system,
or FS,
And the second is a module called Path,
which we're going to use to normalize the paths to different directories.
Okay,
as normal,
we're going to create a container for this module and at the bottom of the file,
we're going to export it.
Okay.
Now,
for the meat of the file,
the first thing we want to do is create a function for writing data to a file.
So we're gonna call that function lib dot Create this function is gonna take him three
parameters.
A directory.
We're not going to just write data to the dot data folder.
It's We wanted to be held in something analogous to tables or collections.
And so for us,
subdirectories within the dot data folder is going to be like the table or the collection
of keys.
So,
for example,
within the dot data Ford er there might be a user's directory,
and all the files within that directory are going to be all the users.
There's gonna be a different directory called tokens in all the files with him that's of
directory or the tokens.
So the first thing that we want to know when we're creating ah file or writing data to a
file is what directory or what group?
What collection are we actually reading to the next is going to be the file name that we
want.
This actual file,
to be called the Third parameter,
is going to be called data,
and this is the data that's going to be going to the file toe comprise the file itself.
Lastly,
there's going to be a call back.
All right,
Now,
the first thing that we need to do is try to open the file for writing.
For that,
we're going to use fs the file system dot open,
but now we need to pass in an actual path to the file that we want to create.
So before we fill out the rest of this,
we need some way to know exactly where the data directory lives relative to where we are
now.
For that,
we use path.
So just above this function,
I'm actually going to define the base directory of the data for order on the lib objects so
that all these different functions can use it Live,
Don,
we will call baster equals path join Then we're using a constant that's available in every
node application in every file called directory name,
which is basically where we are right now or specifically,
we are living This file is living inside of the lip directory.
So we want to take the directory name where we are now and normalize it.
Uh,
back up the tree one directory and then into the data folder.
What this functions going to do is take these two locations where we are right now and then
the fact that we want we know we want toe jump back up a directory and then go to the data
folder,
it's going to make this into one nice,
clean path without you know,
slash dot,
dot,
slash Etcetera.
In there.
So now we have the brace directory.
So when we're doing fs dot open always to do is call lib dot based directory and then
append on the directory that the user specified.
So,
for example,
we want this file to live in dot data slash users.
So we depend on the directory and then we need to upend on a slash and the actual file name
that they passed.
They're not going to be passing on the dot Jason that it's going to be implied.
So we're going to add on DOT Jason.
We want to open this file for writing,
so we're passing in a W X flag.
There's a lot of flags in the documentation.
This is just the one that works for this particular case,
and what we're going to get back as a call back are two things error and a file descriptor
.
You can think of a file to skip door as a way to uniquely identify a specific file.
We would use that file descriptor to do,
uh,
the next things.
So once that call that comes back to us,
we want to say,
If there's not an air and there is a file descriptor,
then we want to continue with logic there.
Otherwise,
we want to go ahead and call back an error.
Remember that we're using the air back pattern.
So we're just going to call back a string with the air in it.
And this air would be I could not create new file.
It may already exist.
You end up here.
If you trying to f s dot open with a W X flag,
a file that already existed,
We specifically want to open it and error out if the file already exists.
Before we tried to open a created.
All right,
if we make it here,
everything's good.
We created the file,
it didn't exist.
And so now we want to take the data that we got past to us and convert it to a string so
that we can write it to the file so convert data to strength.
We always going to have to convert to a string because this library is going to be used in
such a way that we're just gonna be throwing Jason at it,
not just on strings,
but just data objects at it.
Jason objects,
and we're going to want that converted to a flat string written to a file.
And then when we read it back out.
We want it converted back to a normal Jason object.
So we want to create string data out of it.
And string data is going to equal Jason dot string if I and then whatever data they sent to
us,
So we're converting that data to a string Now we want to write to file and close it.
So for that,
we're gonna use fs dot right file.
We're going to pass.
It is the first parameter the foul descriptor that we got up here.
The second parameter is going to be in the string data that we want to actually right to
that file.
And that's it.
The call back that is going to send us is just going to have an heir parameter in it.
So we only want to continue if there's no air else.
In other words,
if there isn't here,
we want to call back air writing to new file.
This in theory should never get called,
but you never know.
All right,
so we have written to that file,
but we actually still need to close the file,
So we're gonna call f s dot clothes and all we need to pass.
It is the file descriptor.
It's going to pass us back again in error and we want to continue if there is no error.
Otherwise we call back.
You guessed it air closing new file.
If there is no air,
though we call back false,
We're calling back false.
Because remember this parameter,
this air back pattern expects its parameter to be an error,
so a false error is actually a good thing.
All right,
so that's how you write data to these files.
Let's go ahead and just temporarily modify index dot Js so that we can actually see if this
is working.
We're not gonna leave this code in index dot Js is just a convenient way.
Teoh,
test this out.
So the first thing I'm going to do is make another directory within the dot data directory
and call it dot data slash test.
You can see that it's in there now and we're going to write to that test and then we're
gonna delete it.
So within the index dot Js,
I want to require this file that we just created so far data equals require.
Then I want to go up into the live directory and require data.
I'm just going to throw this test right here at the top because we are going to delete it
in us again.
So to test this,
I'm going to call data and then the function that we just created since it's a dot create,
I'm gonna call that than the directory name is going to be tested.
The subdirectory of the dot data folder that we just created.
The file name that I wanted create,
which is the next parameter is going to be new file.
The next parameter is data that we want.
So I'm just going to say that this data should be passed.
Who bar.
And lastly,
it's a callback that's going to pass us in here,
and I'm gonna log at that area if it comes.
All right.
I'm gonna save the file and go ahead and start up the application again,
making sure I'm in the right directory knowed index dot Yes.
This was the error.
False.
So in other words,
there was no error.
So if I look inside of the dock data directory,
I should see inside of test another file called new file.
Jason inside of it is just the Jason stratified object that I sent.
So that all seems to be working.
Fine.
But what happens to be running again?
This was the air could not create new file.
It may already exist.
So when this app started up the second time,
it did what we expected it to dio It tried to create this new file inside of the tests of
directory,
but it aired out because that file got created last time it already existed.
All right,
that seems to be working.
Well,
I'm gonna leave this here for now and go ahead and go back to our data library and create
the next function.
Now that we've created the create function,
the next thing I want to do is be able to read data from a file from a file.
So I'm gonna call this function lib dot reid and it is going to,
except three parameters a directory,
making a collection file name without the dot Jason on it,
and then a call back.
It's going to read the contents of a file by using fs dot reid file and again it's going to
pass the Lib based directory,
plus the directory that specified plus slash and then file name and then done.
Jason is going to read it in a sooty F eight and it's going to receive to call back
parameters back Air and data.
It's going to call back air and data to whoever called it.
Okay,
so let's go ahead and try this out.
I'm gonna go back to index dot Js and I'm gonna modify this tense that we're doing to say
data don't read.
And I want to read in from the same directory.
I want to read that same file name.
I'm not passing any data to it cause I'm reading from it this time,
and I'm going to get back air and data.
So this was the air air,
and this was the data there.
Okay,
let's go ahead and run.
This.
This was the error.
No.
And this was the data food bar.
All right,
now,
what if we tried to read something that didn't exist?
That's a new file,
one that doesn't exist.
So let's start the f again.
This was the air.
No such file or directory.
And this was the data undefined.
So in that case,
the air came back on the data didn't.
And in the next part of this library that I want to build is the ability to update an
existing file with new data.
So I'm gonna call that function lib dot update.
It's going to take the same things that create it.
It's going to take a directory,
a file name,
data call back.
It's going to work much of the same way that create did accept going to have some extra
logic in there for truncating any existing data.
That's part of the file already before it writes in the new data.
So the first thing is going to do is open the file for writing and again,
we're going to use F s start open,
pass it live baster,
and then all the same things that we did before,
but now is going to open up the file with the switch.
Our plus,
the difference between W.
X and R plus is I'm gonna open it up for writing.
But this time I want it to air out if the file doesn't exist yet,
whereas before it had an air,
if the file already existed,
So I'm gonna open up with the or plus switch,
and it's going to come back with an heir and a file descriptor.
Okay,
I only want to continue if there's no air and there is a file descriptor else I want to
call back.
The fact that there's an error could not open the file for updating.
It may not exist.
You I continue on if there is and no air and there is a file descriptor.
And again,
I pretty much want to do this exact same thing.
I want to convert that data that we got to a string,
so I'm just gonna copy it from above.
But now I don't just want to write to that file because there might already be something
there.
That's what I need to do is truncate the contents of that file before I right on top of it
.
For that,
I'm going to use fs dot truncate and I just need to pass it a file descriptor.
It will go ahead and chunky that file for me and pass back in air once again.
I want to continue if there is no air and if there is an air,
I want to call that back air truncating file okay,
but there is no error.
So the next thing I want to do is write to the file and close it for that.
I'm gonna use fs dot right file,
pass it a file descriptor passes the string data just like we did before.
It's gonna pass me back and air,
as you probably guessed.
And I only want to continue if there is no air.
If there is an air,
I don't call that back air righting to existing file.
Let's say there is no air than I want to close the file.
Fs stop close.
Passing a foul,
descriptor it,
passing me back and air.
If there is no air,
I want to call back False as I did before,
which means I'm not calling back in air.
Otherwise,
I want to call that the fact that there was an air closing the file.
Now let's go back to we were manipulating new file Jason in the index dot u s border and go
ahead and modify this example that we're doing to use this new piece of library.
So we're gonna call underscore data.
Don't update.
I want to call it with directory.
The file and now I want overwrites,
um,
new data instead of what we had before.
So before we had food bar Now I want to override it with theirs.
But so we're gonna be sending that object and said and it's going to call back with only a
single air,
No data.
So I can go back to just saying this was the air.
All right,
let's go ahead and run that,
see what happens.
I just have a small subjects air here.
That's because I separated fizz and buzz with a comma rather than a cold.
Alright,
Fixed that running that this was the air false.
There was no air.
So if he opened up new found out Jason,
we should see it now.
Contains fizz,
Buzz and said a food bar,
so updates working.
All right,
now,
what would you guess is going to be the last thing that we need to add to this library
before we move on?
We did create.
We did read with the update was the last part of crowd delete.
So we need to create a piece of this library for deleting a file.
I'm a call it live dot delete,
and it's going to be a function that accepts in the directory the final name and call back
,
and it's going to call back an error.
It doesn't to call back any data because nothing's getting red.
This is going to be a fairly simple one.
We're going to be doing what's called on linking,
which is removing this file from the file system.
We're going to call FS got a link,
then we need to pass it the full path like we did before.
So live the base directory.
Oh,
that same stuff as we've been doing,
it's gonna passes back in there.
There is no air.
We want to call that close.
Otherwise,
all those we want to call back the error that we are having trouble deleting the file.
All right,
let's go ahead and try to use that in our index dot Js,
We're gonna call data delete Best directory,
new file.
We don't need to pass it.
Any data?
Let's run this.
Have a small syntax air here.
I need to go back and fix.
Jason is supposed to be a string,
so there we go.
Let's try this again.
I'm just gonna clear at this console to make it easier to see.
All right,
one more syntax error.
I said leave instead of lib fixed that.
All right,
this was the air false.
There was no air.
So if we go back into this directory and look for new file dot Jason,
you can see that it's gone.
It has been unlinked,
all right.
It still exists in Adam just because that's how Adam were keeping to lead a flat out.
But until you close the window here,
it won't actually be gone out of your editor.
But as you can see,
it's gone from the file system.
Kill this server and we have a library for doing all the court operations within this dot
date.
Afford that we created,
we have greet.
We have read,
we have update and we have delete.
And so now we can move on to creating another service that actually reads and writes data,
and we are going to be calling this library that we have created before we move on.
I gotta follow this to do delete this thing that we promised to delete get rid of this
dependency that we don't need at this second save it and now we can move on to the next
lecture