Now that we have a library in place for manipulating data,
we can go ahead and create our first real service outside of the ping service,
and that service is going to be users.
Normally,
we would just go ahead and add the handlers down here.
But these handlers air going to be pretty big.
They're going to be creating users,
reading users,
updating them and leading them,
and that's a lot throw into one file.
So I think what it's worth doing at this point is re factoring a bit and moving the
handlers from here within the index diet Js to their own file within the lip directory.
So let's go ahead and create a new file touch lib slash handlers dot Js.
Now that file exists in the lip directory,
and we're going to move all of this stuff into that one.
I'm just gonna paste it here from now,
and we'll clean it up in a second back to the index dot Js file.
We still need the handlers defined because the router is still in this file,
so we need to know what the handlers are.
So up here we are going to require that new file that we just created far handlers equals
require.
And then we're just going to walk up live directory handlers.
Okay,
Now,
let's go back into that file and clean it up a little bit.
So we're going to say with a big comment at the top,
These are the request handlers.
Okay,
Now we're gonna have some dependencies,
which we don't need to you fill in yet,
but that's where they will go.
And we want to define all the handlers as we doing.
And lastly,
we want to export all of the handlers at the very bottom.
Okay,
Now,
everything else works exactly the same.
Now that we re factored,
we can go ahead and start adding on more complicated handlers for this new route called
users.
So in the index dot Js file,
the first thing I'm gonna do is match up a new path called users.
Two handlers dot users.
Now we need to go back to handlers and make sure that this path exists.
Somebody create a new object for users indemnifying handlers that users,
and this is going to be a function that,
just like the other ones,
takes in a data object and call back.
But what this function is going to do is actually figure out which method you're requesting
.
Figure out that's when the acceptable methods and then pass it along to some sub handlers.
So I'm going to list out the acceptable methods for the users route,
and that's going to be post okay,
put and elite for this round.
We don't accept anything else.
So we want to say if the acceptable methods index of the data object that we're getting
method.
So in other words,
if data method exists within the acceptable methods array,
then we want to call handlers don't underscore users.
And we want to call specifically data method that we want to pass along data and call back
.
And if that does not exist,
we just want to call back four or five,
which is the http status code for method not allowed.
Now you're probably saying what is underscore users,
and what do you calling their that stuff?
We have a defined yet by convention.
I'm just going to create this thing called underscore users to denote the fact that these
are kind of private methods that are used by the users,
Handler and it's not really something that someone calling this library would use directly
.
So I'm gonna create a container for the users sub methods,
And that's gonna be handlers underscore you choose.
And that's just an object on that object.
I'm going to create handlers,
users,
post handlers,
users get hamburgers,
users put and delete.
So let's start with post users post.
We're gonna call it handlers,
underscore users dot post,
and it's going to accept in the same thing as anything else that it's getting from appear
data and a call back All right,
before we feel that in,
Let's go ahead and create the scaffolding for the other three users get users put and users
do it so you can see how this works.
The request comes in.
It says this post get put or delete it checks to see that it is one of those four,
and if it is,
it passes it along to the respective place where it needs to go.
If we wanted all posts toe act just like put so we wanted gets Tau AC elect elites.
For some reason,
there would be no reason to separate these out,
but for us,
the logic that happens when you post T users route is gonna be very different than when you
put to the users route.
So we want to make sure that these handlers are all separate.
So now that start filling in these handlers before I do,
I just want to write a note to myself about what I'm doing here.
Specifically,
What are they required?
Fields for us.
It's first name,
last name,
phone password and a 1,000,000,000 code to US agreement.
Is there any optional data pass along?
You know,
all right,
now I have those just to guide me while I'm writing this.
Now,
I got to do some of the tedious sanity checking that you always have to do.
Check that all required fields are filled out.
What we do here is check that the user gave us the payload in the structure that we require
.
And if they didn't,
we need to send the Mac and error.
And if they did,
we can continue on with the logic.
So we want to say that first name is going to be defined to the first name that was that
came in the payload.
As long as it meets certain requirements otherwise going to be defined this false.
We do that by saying first name because type of data payload first name equals string,
and its length is greater than zero.
So we're going to say that this,
like,
greater than zero.
We just move this over a bit.
I'm gonna make sure that it's trimmed.
Length is actually greater than zero.
In other words,
when you get rid of the white space that still has a good length,
go ahead and use it.
Data payload,
first name trim.
Otherwise default.
Divorce gonna go ahead and copy this whole first line down to the next line and basically
just used the exact same logic again for last name because it has the same requirements.
The last name he goes type of data payload.
Last name,
he called string.
Make sure has a trend length grade of zero.
If it does,
go ahead and use the trimmed version of it going to fall to force.
Okay,
Now I want to do a similar thing for the phone number for us.
Even though phone number looks like a number,
we want to accept it as a string in case it starts with a zero or something else that a
that a true integer wouldn't be able to convey.
So we want to say that of our phone equals type of data payload phone.
But then we have stricter requirements about the length here.
So we want to say that data payload,
phone trim length not just greater than zero,
but it is exactly equal to 10 because we're looking for area code plus seven digit number,
then data payload,
phone trim or default.
Divorce.
Now we need Teoh set some requirements for the password field that they're sending.
So we want to say password because type of data payload,
password,
equal string.
Then we want to make sure that the trim length is greater than zero.
If so,
get the trembling.
The only requirement we're putting for passwords right now is that it has a length.
Lastly,
we want to put some requirements for the toss agreement,
Julian.
So we want to say that the toss agreement,
because data payload toss agreement equals Boolean and that that Julian equals true.
If so,
it should be true or should deport a false.
So,
in other words,
that they didn't fill out that toss agreement at all.
If they didn't check the box one way or another,
or if the payload didn't come along for that field,
we're going to devote it to false.
Otherwise,
it'll be true as long as they defined it and they said it to true defaulting into false in
our case,
it's going to set it to an unacceptable field.
And so whether they said it to false manually or they just forgot to include the Toss
Agreement 1,000,000,000 we're going to say this isn't a valid payload.
You have to agree to the terms of service.
So next we want to say,
if first name and last name and phone and password and toss agreement then continue on.
Otherwise we are going to call back and say Raju because you are messing up.
So we want to call back 400 we might as well give them a pay low.
Italian was going on.
We want to say error.
I didn't spell out what the air is missing,
required fields,
Otherwise we continue on with the logic is normal.
So the next thing that we need to do is now that they're trying to create a user.
We want to make sure that that user doesn't already exist.
As you can guess.
Here we're uniquely identifying users with a phone number and a password rather than email
in a password or a user name and password.
That is because,
as I mentioned before,
we're going to be texting users alerts.
And so we don't really care what your email addresses.
We care that you have a unique phone number,
and so if you try to create a user that has a phone number that's already in use,
we're not gonna let you do that.
So we need to make sure that the user doesn't already exist.
The way that we're going to do that is we're going to attempt to read from the user's data
,
and if the user's data comes back with an error,
then we know it doesn't exist.
The reason this makes sense is every time that we create a new user,
we're going to be saving a file called your phone number dot Jason.
So if your phone number is 5555555555 there's going to be inside of the data forger,
a user's directory at inside of that directory,
there's going to be a file called 5555555555 dot Jason.
And so once it reaches this part of the logic,
if someone's trying to create a new user,
we're going to try to read the file.
5555 dot Jason.
And if it comes back with an air,
we know that file doesn't exist,
so we can go ahead and continue trying to create that user.
If it comes back with an error,
that fire already exists,
which means that user already exists.
And we can't allow you to create a new user with that same phone number.
Okay,
so let's go ahead and use that data library that we just created in the last lecture to
start reading from the final system.
So we want to say data dot reid number that function that we created,
we want to read from the user's subdirectory.
We want to look up this user by the phone number,
and we're going to get back an air and data.
Now you might be saying once the data don't read what's data?
Well,
that's gonna be dependency on our end underscored data.
There's going to equal require dot slash data so that's gonna pull in that data library
that we wrote earlier.
Now we want to go back to where we are using this new library to do the read,
and we want to say If it comes back with an air that's good,
we want to continue on with what we were doing.
Otherwise,
we want to call back an error to the requester,
saying a user with that phone number already exists.
Call 400 again,
a data object with a key called Air and an explanation that says a user with that phone
number already exists.
OK,
but if the phone number is valid,
then we want to start the process of creating the new user object.
So the first thing that we're going to need to do to create that user object is hash the
password.
We don't want to store the password as the users send it to us.
That's just a bad practice.
And we don't want to store plain text passwords in your file system or in your database or
every restoring data you want to store in some kind of way that mask the true string of the
password.
So we want to say past the password.
How do we do that for you?
That we were going to use a built in library that comes with node called crypto.
But within this file,
all we need to do is reference a helper function that we're going to create.
So here we're going to say that bar Pash password is just equal to helpers hash,
and then we pass it the password string.
So what is this helpers dot hash function?
That's what we need to create.
But we're going to create it within a separate file that we will call helpers and we'll
reference that helpers file at the top of this handlers file.
So let's make that reference up here with our dependencies Were going to say that far
helpers equals require dot slash helpers.
Remember that this file is living within the live directory,
so referencing dot slash means referencing something within lib.
So within lib,
we just need to create another file and this time,
call it help restart Js and you can see it's been created here.
We're going to say that this file is just helpers for various tasks.
We're going to create a container for all the helpers,
and then we're going to export that container down at the bottom.
And,
as you can guess from what we were a fenced here,
helpers needs to contain a key,
a function called hash that,
except in a string and returns out the hash diversion off that string.
So let's go ahead and create that function within helpers for our purposes.
We're going to use Shah to 56 as our hash,
although you're welcome to use whatever hash you like.
Shock to 36 is one of the few that are built into nodes,
so it doesn't take any external library to hash things that way.
As I mentioned,
this is a function that takes in a string that is all.
It doesn't accept a callback because it's actually going to return the value instead of
calling it back.
So we want to first validate the string that's coming in.
Say,
if the type of this string equals string and it has a length,
then we can continue.
Otherwise we're going Teoh return.
False.
So now we actually need to hash this string and return it in order to do that.
This is where we use the crypto library.
So let's go ahead and add dependencies at the top.
And our first dependency is going to be crypto itself.
Now that we have it included,
we can use it to pash this string.
We want to say that it's hash equals krypton don't create H Mac,
and then we're going to pass it shot to 56 because that's the type of passion that we want
.
And we're going to pass it a hashing secret.
In this case,
we're going to store that hashing secret in our config,
which will get back to in a second,
then docked update passing that string that we want to be hashed.
Don't digest picks.
Okay,
now,
that's really complicated.
But all that basically means is we are hashing this thing with Shaw to 56.
And after it does that,
we want to return to whoever called that function.
Okay,
now,
what is config dot hashing secret.
This is just how this create h mac function works.
It needs a hash secret.
But since it's really shotted 56 it won't have much of an effect but at any rate,
we want to add to our configuration a key called Passion Secret.
And I'm just gonna say this is a secret and the most gonna added to production passion
secret is equal to this is also a secret.
All right,
now those have been added to the CONFIG.
In order to use that,
we're going to need to add another dependency to this helpers file so that it can use
things that are defined in convict.
We're going to say that far config equals require dot slash convict No,
back to our handlers dot Js file where we're actually calling this function and using it,
we're passing in the password that the user sent to us.
We're getting back out a hash password.
And now we need toe continue on creating that user with the data that they sent along with
the hash password.
We want to create the user object say that bar user object equals this big object that
we're gonna add a bunch of keys to one his first name that's gonna equal for his name.
One is last name That's going to Eagle.
You guessed it.
Last name phone is going to equal phone hashed password is going to equal hash password.
We're not including the raw password and the Toss Agreement.
He's going to Eagle.
True,
because it wouldn't have made it past this level of validation if the toss Agreement wasn't
true.
Now we actually need to persist that user to disk.
It's a story.
The user and we're gonna use that create function that we wrote in the last lecture.
We're gonna write it to users,
which means that within this data for her,
we need to first create that users subdirectory.
So what?
We're here.
I'm gonna go into the data for order and then make a new directory called Users.
Okay,
You can see it there.
Get back out.
We're creating it within users.
And we want this file to be named the same as the phone number dot Jason remembered The
create function is going to add on the dot Jason by itself.
So we need to pass in.
Is the phone number the contents of this file?
We want to be this user object that we just created,
and then we're gonna supply the callback and check the air that comes back.
If there is no air.
We want to call back 200 to the requester because everything went fine and we stored the
user disk.
Otherwise,
we need to log out that air and call back 500 a payload That spells out what the Air Waas
could not create the new user.
They're just add some extra safety here.
I just want to add some sanity checking around the hash password so that the logical only
continue if the password got hash successfully.
So before creating the user object,
I'm going to say,
if hashed password.
Do all of this.
Otherwise,
call back 500 and spell out what the air was now before we started up.
We need to make sure that the payload that's coming to the handler isn't just a raw buffer
,
but it's actually the parsed Jason Data.
So I'm going back to the index dot Js and we want to change payload to rev and be buffer.
We wanted to be helpers done Poor's Jason to object and then pass it a buffer pass.
Pass it the variable that we've called buffer.
Now again,
we want to reference helpers as a dependency.
So the top we're going to say that Bar Helper is equal is require dot,
slash lib slash overs.
Now we can go to helpers and actually create that function.
So we want to create a function that takes in an arbitrary string and either returns the
Jason object from that string or returns false.
The reason that we're doing this is because natively Notre Job Skip will just throw an
error if the Jason dot parts function is trying to parse something that isn't valid.
Jace on and we don't want things to throw.
So we want to say course a Jason String to an object and all cases without throwing and
helpers done poorest Jason Object is going to be a function that takes in a string.
It's basically just going to wrap Jason dot parson a try catch.
So we're going to try Catch are Object equals Jason dot parse the string.
If that catch gets called,
we want to return an empty object.
If the catch doesn't get called,
we want to return whatever to Scott,
parse that we want to return object.
All right,
so that is all the logic that we need within this users post method.
Let's go ahead and test it out.
Try to create a new user using postman and see what happens.
So I'm gonna start up the app.
All right?
I'm getting a syntax.
Error just means that I forgot the if.
All right,
try that again.
Ah,
this error is happening because Helpers expects the config file to be within the Libs
directory.
But I haven't actually moved it there yet.
And so I need to move it there.
Se mueve config dot Js to live slash convict up?
Yes.
All right,
now it's living up here since I've moved it,
I need to change index dot Js to reference it up inside the lib directory.
The reason I've moved it is just because now that we have a lot of other libraries going on
configures only one of them,
they might as well all live in the same directory and have just index dot Js living at the
root.
All right,
let's try to start this up again.
We have the server listening on 3000 so I'm going to go over to Postman and create a post
request toe local host slash users.
Let's just send off this request without anybody see what happens?
We have a 400 coming back that says Error missing required fields.
That's what we were hoping would happen.
So now let's construct this request with all the required fields and see if we can get a
200 back.
And we got a 200 back.
We sent in first name John.
Last name Smith phone number was 555 Whatever password is this is a password and toss
agreement is true.
If we tried to send this payload again,
we got 400 back.
ARer user with that phone number already exists if we try to change the phone number a
little bit.
Changes.
7218 We should get back a 200 again because that was valid.
We tried to create yet another user.
Let's change 8 to 9,
But then set,
Let's say toss agreement to false.
We're going to get back error missing.
Required fields that be the same eras if we left off one of the fields entirely.
Okay,
so this post method is working and we can go back and look at our data folder inside of
users.
We have these two new Jason files that both contain the data for the two new users that we
just created.
Now that post is working,
let's move on in the handlers file,
too get.
But before we move on to the get method,
there's one other function within our data library that could benefit from that parts Jason
Toe object helper that we just created this one.
So let's go to the data library.
And rather than simply calling back the raw data,
let's call back the parts Jason Data.
Since we know that we're always going to be storing Jason,
it makes sense that we can just return parsed Jason objects to the requester rather than
the raw Jason string that get stored in the file.
So we're going to say that if it's not air and there is data we want to get parse data and
parse data equals helpers dot parts Jason object and we're gonna pass it in the data that
we got out of whatever file were reading,
and then we're gonna call back False and the coursed data.
Otherwise we're gonna keep it the same.
We're going to call back the air in the data as it came out of that file.
Okay,
now back to what we were doing.
Let's go to the get method in the user's handler.
Is that some commenting here?
That is required.
Data phone optional,
data none.
And we're gonna read a note to ourselves.
But is it to do for later that we should only let authenticated users access their own
object?
We don't want to let people access other people's objects,
so only let and authenticated user access their object.
Don't let them access anyone else's.
Okay,
Now,
within the function,
the first thing that we needed to do is check that the phone number provided is valid since
is a get request.
There is no payload,
so we're actually gonna pull the phone number from the query string.
Object within the data object instead of the payload gets is a reminder number.
When we're forming all these requests and sending them along to the handlers were sending
this whole object along.
The payload is only part of it.
There's also a query string object that contains any key value parameters that would have
been sent and get request.
You're gonna have keys and values in the query string instead of in the payload instead.
So we're going to say that the phone number of our phone equals type of data query,
string,
object phone,
equal strength.
And it is length equals 10.
The same kind of validation that we did on the Post Request.
We're gonna deport False.
And on the next line,
we're going to say if the phone was provided and it was valid that we're gonna continue
otherwise we're going to call back a 400 error to the user saying 400 air missing,
required field.
In this case,
it's missing the fun of her.
But if there is a good phone number,
then we wanna look up,
user.
And to do that,
we're going to call our one of our data methods data dot Reid,
we're gonna read from the user's collection,
and we want to read the phone number provided it's gonna call back an air and some data
when it calls back.
We want to check that.
If there is not a right and there is data,
we can continue with the request.
Otherwise,
we're gonna call back 44 as you are.
No.
44 stands for not found.
So in this case,
you're asking for a user that does not exist before we return this user object and
requester.
We actually want to remove the hashed password from the user object because that's not data
that they will ever need to read or that it would be safe.
Teoh,
show them.
So remove the hashed password from the user object before returning it to the requester.
Okay,
so we do that by just saying delete data hashed password and then we want to call back 200
everything else that was in that data object this case using data too many times it doesn't
really matter,
but just for clarity sick.
That is not this data object that's coming in.
That's the data that's coming back from the,
uh,
don't read function.
So that's all we need to be able to get users.
Let's go ahead and try this out and make sure that we can read a user must startup the
server listening on a port.
I'm to go back to here the postman and do a get requests to local host slash users.
But this time I'm going to say that phone equals 5551234567 Since that is one of the users
that we created click send.
Looks like a crash.
Helpers is not defined.
That is because within the data file,
I'm calling helpers,
but I never required it appear.
And so I need to do that now for helpers equals require,
uh,
slash helpers.
Okay,
so let's try to start it up again.
Send the request again.
All right.
We just did a successful read.
We have the first name,
last name,
phone and toss agreement coming back.
And we do not have the hash password coming back because we're deleting that from the
object prior to returning it to the requester.
If we change this phone to something that doesn't exist,
like 560 instead of 567 we get a 44 If we change it to remove the phone field entirely,
we're gonna get that We're missing a required field.
Okay,
so this get seems to be working.
Fine.
Now that we have get,
we can move on to put for put.
Once again,
the required data is phone.
You must specify which user you want to put to.
So which user you want to update.
And this time there is optional data.
The optional data is everything else.
First name,
last name and password,
and we're just gonna write a note to ourselves that at least one must be specified so
individually,
they are optional fields.
But collectively,
at least one of these optional fields must be specified.
In addition to the required field.
We want to write one more note to ourselves.
That is,
to do only let and authenticated user update their own object.
Don't let them update anyone houses.
So it's the same reasons that's before we for security.
We don't want to let a user with phone number X update the user object for the user for
phone number.
Why you owe me should be able to read and now update your own object.
But we'll get into that later after we have offing mechanism.
All right,
so the first thing we need to do is check for the required field,
which in this case is the same thing as above the differences.
Rather than pulling it from the query string object,
we're gonna pull it from the payload.
So all right,
now we want to check for the optional fields.
These were going to be three of them.
First name,
last name and password.
And they are actually going to be the same as we did for Post.
So I'm going to copy those down from here.
I could have copied phone as well.
Could you just get rid of phone now?
Rather than saying that the request must include all of these things,
We're gonna put in a little logic that says you must have the phone and you must have
either the first name last name or the password.
So we want to air if the phone is invalid in all cases.
So only continue if the phone is good.
Otherwise we're gonna call back 400 air until the air may saying required field.
And we want to say air if nothing is sent to update.
So we want to continue if there is first name or last name or password.
Otherwise,
we want to call that a 400.
Tell the user air missing fields to update.
Now that we have valid strings,
we need to look up this user and actually make sure that they exist prior to trying to
update their object So look up,
user,
and we're gonna use one of our data helpers again.
Data read in the user's collection.
And we're going to read based on this phone number,
give us back and air and user data.
We're going to say that if there is not an air and there is user data,
then we're going to update the fields that are necessary.
Otherwise,
if it came back with an error came back without user data,
we want to call back and Eric to the requester,
saying 400 air the specified user does not exist.
We could also call this back as a 404 Some people prefer not to have four fours on a put.
It's really a personal choice.
As long as you convey what you're doing to whoever is consuming your A P I.
It's up to you to make that distinction.
All right,
Now,
back to updating the fields.
We have the user data here,
so we're actually going to update that user data object as we go if these fields have been
set.
So if first name has been sent,
then we're gonna update user data first name with whatever this new value is let's do the
exact same thing for last name if last name update user data,
last name,
he goes last name.
And lastly,
if password,
we need to do the same thing.
But we need to hash that password the same way we did before.
So user data hashed password equals helpers dot hash,
and we're gonna pass in the past right straight.
Now we've up in his object.
We actually need to store it,
so store the new updates persists them to disk.
For that,
we're going to use our data update function that we created again.
It's gonna be the users collection we're identifying,
which,
while we want to update by the phone number and the data that we want to overwrite into
that file is the user data object that we've been manipulating,
and that's gonna pass us back and air if there is any.
So we only want to continue if there is no air.
Otherwise,
if we get an error back,
we might as well log it for debugging purposes.
But also call it back to the user has a 500 because this is something internally wrong with
us that we couldn't figure out how to up its file.
You want to say air could not update user.
The reason we're saying 500 instead of 400 is there's really nothing necessarily wrong with
the user's request if we're having an issue updating the file,
and so there's no reason for them to retry or reform at the request is just a air on our
server that we're gonna have toe deal with.
But if there is no air,
we want to call back 200 to tell the requester that everything was successful.
So that is,
users put let's start the server back up and see if we can update one of these users that
we created earlier.
So I'm gonna go to this post request that I created before,
and I'm a change it to be a put.
Let me change it so that we're modifying users.
1234567 And I want to change his first name too.
Jim,
instead of John,
I'm gonna leave the rest of these fields off.
Okay?
So when I send this put,
I should get back a 200 with nobody.
And if we go back,
we look inside of the users object.
1234567 We can see that his first name is now Jim,
so the put seems to be working as expected.
Now that puts their we've done,
create,
read and update.
The last thing to do for the users service is delete deletes going to be set up in a
similar way to get so we're going to start with a required field that is just phone,
and we want to have a couple to do notes to herself.
The first is,
as you might guess,
only let on authenticated user.
Delete their object.
Don't let then delete anyone else's.
We also want to have one other to do,
telling us to clean up a delete any other data files but show shaded with this user.
This doesn't relate now,
but later on,
let's say that this user has a bunch of checks associated with them or a bunch of other
kind of files.
When this user gets deleted,
we don't want their checks to keep running,
and so we're going to have to have some logic in here At some point that cleans up
everything associated with this user But for now,
we don't need to have those things in to The first thing we want to do in this function is
check that the phone number is valid.
We're going to do that with this exact same logic we used and get pretty extensively.
And so I'm just going to copy the whole get function and paste it down in here.
That double comment phone equals the phone that's provided in the query string.
If there is a phone,
we want to look up the user.
If the user can't to be found,
we want to call back A 407 for four.
We want to call back with 400.
That says Air.
I could not find the specified user.
And then from here inside of these two brackets,
it's gonna be some new logic.
So we're going to say data delete and we're gonna be deleting something from the user's
collection identified by that phone number,
and it's gonna pass us back and air.
So we're just telling the users collection to delete that user,
and we want to say that if it's not an error,
call back 200 to the user.
Otherwise,
call back 500.
I could not delete the specified user.
Okay,
so that's it.
That's so we needed for the elite logic.
Let's go ahead and start the at back up.
You're going to use this old get request.
We can see if they get still works,
but we're going to change it to a delete request.
Leave it the same and click Send.
We got a 200 back.
If we go over here,
that 567 object is gone.
So if we send the delete again,
we get the 400.
Could not find the specified user because the delete worked the first time.
So that's the user service.
We have post get put and elite or create,
read,
update,
delete.
And now we can move on to the next section.