the next service we wanna build is called checks Checks is really the meat of our
application to review what a check is.
A check is basically a task that tells our system Go check this u R L every X number of
seconds and then tell the user the creator of the check whether the U.
R L.
Is up or down.
We're going to allow users to create up to five checks and later on will go about building
the background processes that need to actually preform the checking.
But for now,
all we need to do is create a check service with post get put and elite that allows a user
who has logged in and got a token to create up to five checks and have those checks listed
in his account.
So let's go ahead and get started by modifying index dot Js to include the new checks route
.
Going to say that checks needs to go to handlers that checks.
Then we'll go ahead and open up the handlers file again and start building out these checks
.
I'm gonna scroll all the way down to where we left off from tokens and start building out
the check service.
We're going to set up the primary checks handler,
just like we did the other ones.
So I'm actually going to copy what we did on tokens and just used that down here.
We're gonna see the hand.
There's checks is a function acceptable?
Methods are all the same.
Post get put,
delete,
and it should relay data and call back on to private methods for checks.
Now,
let's have a container for all the checks methods.
And now we need to build out checks,
post the required data for post Going to be a few parameters protocol,
That is,
http.
Or https,
the euro.
That the user wants us to check a method as in post,
get put or delete that we should use when checking this girl.
The success codes Now,
success codes will basically be an array of numbers that we should treat as meaning success
.
So that could be a 200 or to a one or anything that isn't a 500 etcetera.
And lastly,
the time out seconds.
If the euro takes more than X number of seconds,
the time out,
seconds to respond,
we should consider it to be down.
Optional data is none.
Okay,
no handers underscore checks dot Post going to equal function takes it data and co back.
But one thing that we know is that we are going to have to enforce the five check limit on
this post service.
So before we start voting on this post service completely,
let's add the max checks limit to he can fake dot Js.
So we're going to say in both staging and production that max checks,
meaning the maximum matter checks that any user may have on their account is gonna be five
.
Now,
back to handlers.
Dutch.
Yes,
It wouldn't keep voting out this service.
The first thing that we're gonna need to do within the service is validate all these inputs
.
We're going to do it the same way that we did posts for the other services.
So I mean a copy one of this sanity checking strings that we did before pace that down here
,
but instead,
for us,
that's going to be protocol equals type of data.
Payload protocol equals string.
And rather than checking the length,
we want to say that it should be one of these two options in this array.
So we want to say that within this array,
the index of data,
a load protocol should be greater than one.
In other words,
we don't care of his http or https,
as long is.
It is one of these two,
and if it is,
we'll go ahead and use it or deported falls.
Now we want to set up the URL.
The earl,
excluding the protocol should be a string,
and it should have a length.
We were to say that length of the girl is greater than zero.
If it is,
take it or default to false for method.
We're going to do something similar to protocol.
So I'm going to pace that down here from Method needs to be a string,
and it needs to be one of thes options in disarray.
Post get,
put or delete and the index of data pay.
The method should be greater than one.
If so,
we use it or default.
False success codes is going to be a little bit different,
but will use this as a template.
Success codes needs to equal type of object,
and it needs to be an instance off and Ray,
and it needs to have a length greater than zero.
If so,
we'll go ahead and use it or would have fought divorce time out.
Seconds is the last one we need to do.
I'm going to copy your l Use that again.
Time out seconds is actually going to need to be a number.
And we're going to need it to be a whole number.
And we're going to need it to be greater than or equal to one and less than or equal to
five.
If so,
we'll use it or default.
Divorce.
All right.
We validated all the inputs.
Now we want to only move on with the logic if they're all valid.
So if protocol and you are l and method and success codes and time out seconds,
then we move on.
Otherwise we're going to return an heir to the requester that says 400 air facing required
inputs or inputs are invalid.
Okay,
but assuming that payload is valid,
we'll move on.
The next thing that we need to do is check that the user has provided a token in the
headers and then we need to look up the user by reading that token.
We don't want to allow anonymous users to create checks.
This has to be something that you have to be logged in to do.
So we are going to get the token from the headers.
We're going to use the same logic that we did before this.
Wear it again,
Token because type of data,
headers token,
equal strength data hitters,
Token force.
All right,
now we want to look up the user by reading the token,
so we're going to try to read that token that they provided from the file system.
So we're gonna say that data read we want to read from the tokens collection and the token
i d that we're reading is identified by the token variable they're gonna pass back in here
and token data.
If it exists,
it's possible that it doesn't exist.
So we are only going to continue on if there's not an air and they're in stoking data.
And if there isn't,
they need to call back for all three to the user,
which is the status code for not authorized on the assumption that there is talking data.
We're going to get the user's phone number.
So far,
user phone equals token data dot Now that we know the user's phone,
we can look up the user.
Look,
what user data we're gonna say.
Data read.
We're gonna read from the user service user phone,
and then they're gonna passes back an air and user data.
If that user exists now,
just like in the last step,
we want to make sure that there is no air and there is user data.
Otherwise we're going to call back for three not authorized because they provide us a token
,
But it wasn't really or didn't correspond to a real user.
But if there is good user data,
then we need to identify which checks the user already has.
Now,
if we look at the user data stored here,
there's no checks on.
This object is just first name,
last name,
phone hash,
password and toss agreement.
1,000,000,000.
That's the whole user object.
But now that users are going to be able to create checks,
we are going to need to add another key onto this object called checks,
and we're going to store an array of checks by check I.
D.
S on this user so that to know which checks belong to which user we just need to look up
the user and see which checks are attached to his object.
So when we looking up this user,
we need to just see if the checks key exists and if there's anything to find there.
So we're going to say that the user checks equals type of user data,
don't checks,
equals object and user data.
Dot checks is an instance of Ray.
If so,
user data checks we'll use or we're going to default to an empty array.
We're going to be adding the new check to the users existing array or their brand new empty
array if they don't already have any checks.
Now,
we need to actually verify that the user has less than the number of Max checks per user.
So remember we just configured here that the Max checks is five.
So before we allow this user to create another check,
we need to make sure that he doesn't already have the max.
We're going to say F user checks length is smaller,
then can fig max checks.
You can continue.
So the Max Texas five,
which means if you have less than five right now,
we're going to allow you to create another one.
Otherwise,
we need to stop you here until you delete one of your checks.
So if they already have the max,
then we need to return error to them saying call back 400 Here.
The user already has the maximum number of checks.
And just to remind three Quester what that number is,
we're going to spit that out to them in parentheses.
If they haven't exceeded the max number of checks,
then we can go ahead and create the new Jack.
So the first thing that we need to do is create a random i d for the check.
And this we're going to do the same way that we created random I ds for the tokens were
going to say that the check I d equals helpers create random string and a length of 20.
Now we want to create the Czech object and include the users phone number.
The phone number is how we uniquely identify of user.
So we're going to store each check with a reference to its creator,
and we're also going to make sure that these creators have a reference on their object to
each of their checks.
This is a no sequel way of story things.
This is how you generally might want to do things with key value stores.
This is not the way that you would use a relational database,
but if you're using something like readiness or Mongo or any kind of no sequel than this
pattern will probably be familiar to you.
So we're going to say that the check object is this big object with a bunch of keys on it.
The I d of this check is gonna be check.
I d Use your phone is going to be used from protocol is going to be protocol.
You're always you're ill.
Method is method success codes,
his access codes and time out.
Seconds.
It is time out.
Seconds later on.
There will be more keys added to these objects as our background workers start to process
them.
But for now,
they're just the keys that it got.
Start with.
No,
we need to persist.
This new object to disk,
we're going to save data create.
We don't want to create something in the checks collection.
And before I continue with this,
let me just make that directory because our data border does not include that.
So I want to make the directory data checks,
and there it is.
So that's where these things would get stored.
So when a story in the Czechs collection and all be storing it by check,
I d.
Since that'll be unique and I will be storing the check object and that's just gonna pass
me back an error,
I only want to continue if there is no air.
If there is an air,
I want to call back and air to the requester,
saying 500 I could not create the new check.
So now that check has been created.
But before we return response to the user,
there's another step that we need to take.
We actually need to add this.
Do check i d to the users object and then update The users object with this new array of
their checks,
so we want to say,
Add the check i d.
To the users.
Object already have the users object.
So we're going to say that user data chicks equals user checks because remember that we
have their existing checks or possibly this new empty array saved as a variable user checks
,
so we just want to sync up that variable to the user object dot checks.
Now that sink tup we can do the addition of our new check I d So we want to say user data
dot checks push.
So I'm adding to their array Were pushing on the check i d.
So now that user data dot checks contains possibly just an array with one check I d or all
of their old check I.
D.
S with this new one added.
And now we actually need to save the new user data.
So we're gonna call data update users.
We're gonna update it by user phone.
We're going to be updating with user data,
which is all of their new data.
They're gonna passes back and error,
and if there's not an error will continue Otherwise,
Well,
we turn that air to the user saying air could update the user with the new check if
everything was fine.
We want to return the data about the new check to the requester.
So we're going to call back,
not just a 200.
What?
We're gonna call back the whole check object this one back to the requester.
So they create something they don't know what that new check I d is unless we tell them.
So we're going to send back this check,
object to them to let them know what this whole object looks like now that it's getting
stored.
All right,
so that is handlers checks dot Post we can save that.
Now I'm going to try to start up this server and we can test out the service.
Testing this out is going to be a little bit more complicated because this service is
authenticated.
So I'm going to need to recreate a token.
The same way that I did before just created a token for this user one of the frog 68 And
this new token is that so Now I'm going to create another request,
but this is going to be going to the check service,
and it's going to have a header,
which includes the token that I just got.
Now I need to form the payload that I want,
and we're going to use all of these same things that we expected to use you to say protocol
.
You are all methods,
success codes and time out.
Seconds.
So we're gonna say protocol is,
Http,
your l is google dot com method is get success codes 200 or to a one time out seconds is
three.
All right,
so I'm gonna send this off.
I was hoping to get a 200 back,
but I got a 400 back,
which means something's not quite right.
And if we look at it,
we can see this is likely the issue here.
I'm spelling success wrong.
So let me add a c here.
Make sure that these are all correct.
And now when we go down to success codes,
we need to spell it right over there as well.
Okay,
so that should be everywhere.
Start this back up,
send it again and looks like it crashed because config is not defined.
Which means we need to make sure that handlers has a reference to the config file,
which it doesn't so far,
so config equals can thick.
All right,
let's try to start this up again.
We got another crash that says check.
I d.
Is not defined.
Let's go down there.
That is because check i d has a capital I but this one does not.
Okay.
Had a few bugs here that started up again.
See what we can get.
All right,
Now we're getting a 200 back so we can see that this is a new I.
D.
That was automatically created.
And this is the phone number of the user who created this check.
It's with protocol.
Http.
It's to that girl is a get these air.
The optional success codes and time out seconds is three.
So let's send this again on certain again.
This user should have three checks on their account now.
So if we go look at this user,
we should see checks is an array of three.
Now,
let's create 1/4 1 and the 5th 1 Now it shouldn't let us create this.
61 Let's see what happens.
Alright,
400 bad requests.
User already has the maximum number of checks.
We go back to the user object,
we can see he has 12345 checks on account.
And that is all the checks that you see here.
So this post service seems to be working correctly.
Let's move on to the get service.
So forget we're going to say that they require data is just the i d similar to the other
services.
Optional data?
None.
Now we want to form this,
but we can use a lot from some of the previous ones that we created.
I'll grab the one from users since that had a similar level of validation happening.
All right,
so now we want to say handlers checks get takes data in a callback,
and the first thing we need to do is check that the i d is valid.
So we're going to say that i d equals query string object.
I d equals string that the length should equal 20 and if it does,
will use it or deported false.
If it isn't valid,
i d String will continue.
Otherwise,
we will call back.
That is missing required field.
Now we are going to want to get the token from the headers.
But first we need to figure out which user created this check and if the check exists So
before we do that,
we want to look up check.
So we're going to say data read checks,
I d.
So we're looking in the Czechs collection by the idea that the user just sent and they're
going to send us back error and checked it.
So if there is no air and there is check data,
we want to continue,
Otherwise we're going to call back before four to the user.
Now,
we can move this stuff up inside here,
but we are going to modify a bunch of it.
So we do want to get the token that sent the request.
So it's token getting from the headers object.
And now we want to verify that the given token is valid and belongs to the user who created
the check.
So we're gonna use that same tokens.
Verify token helper that we created before.
So handlers tokens verify Token.
We're gonna pass it token.
And then,
rather than passing it,
phone variable,
we're passing it.
Check data dot user phone.
Remember,
each check is storing a key called user phone that tells us which user created that check.
So we are verifying that the token in the headers belongs to the same user who created the
check that we're looking up right now and we're gonna pass us back whether or not the token
is valid.
So then we're going to say if the token is valid,
the next thing we need to do is just return that check data to the user who is trying to
look it up.
So we don't need to do any of this stuff here.
We're just going to say if token is valid,
return the cheque data.
So we're going to call back 200 and the check data that the user asked for.
If the token isn't valid,
we're gonna call back just 403 All right,
clean this up a little bit.
Well,
hadn't saved that.
Restart the app and see if I can use this same token to do it get request and get one of
the checks that we created a moment ago.
So I'm going to turn this into a get request,
and I am going to say that I want to look up one of thes ideas.
Let's grab one of the ideas here.
I want to look a check.
I d ending in fl two.
There we go.
I got a 200 back.
If I left off this token and try to send the request,
I get a four or three back.
If I leave on the token,
but change it to something that doesn't exist.
I get a four or four.
Otherwise,
everything's fine.
All right.
Now that they get is working,
we can move on to put back to the handlers file.
Now,
as far as put goes,
we're going to allow the user to change any of the things that they set when they created
the check in the first place.
The protocol you are l method success,
coz,
or time out seconds.
But all of those will be optional.
The only required data will be the i D.
But one of the optional things must be sent as well.
So checks put required data.
His i.
D.
Optional data protocol.
You are ill.
Method six s codes.
Time out.
Seconds one must be sent.
All right,
now let's create this Put service handlers.
Checks put is a function that takes data call back.
Now we want to check for the required field and then check for the optional fields.
This feels a lot like the put that we did above.
So I'm going to grab the put that we did too.
Users and copy some stuff from there.
So first we want to check for the required field is going to be the I D.
So type of data payload string data payload I d tram length equals 20.
Take it or we deported to false and then the optional fields are going to be the same.
Actually,
rather than using this first name that I copied down,
I'm going to grab the same validation that we did for Post because these are all the same.
And it's still occurring within the payload,
not within the query string object.
So there we go.
We've gotten all those and now we want to make sure that the I d is valid.
So if I d continual otherwise callback of 400 to the user saying missing required field.
Now we want to make sure that they have included one of the optional fields or more.
So we're going to say,
if protocol or euro or method,
we're success codes four time out seconds it's sent,
then continue.
Otherwise,
we're gonna call back another 400 telling the user missing fields to update.
If they did include at least one field update,
then we'll continue by looking up the check.
So we're going to dio data read to the Czechs collection by I D.
They're gonna passes back and air and check data.
If there is no air and there is checked,
data will continue.
Otherwise we're gonna call back and heir to the requester,
saying there check I d did not exist.
Now we need to do similar token checking that we did on the last one.
So we're going to get the token that sent the requests.
We can pretty much copy this logic from here.
We're getting the token from the headers,
and then we're verifying that the given token is valid and belongs to the user who created
the check by comparing the token to check data that we got from here dot user phone.
Now,
I just need to close some of these brackets.
So if the token data is not valid,
we're going to call that four or three.
If the token data is valid,
then we need to update the check where necessary.
So we'll start with protocol.
If they sent protocol,
then what date?
That check data protocol equals.
Now let's do the oriole.
If you're out,
check data.
Euro equals euro.
If method then check data method equals method.
Now,
if success codes check data success codes equals success codes.
Leslie,
if time out seconds,
then check data time out.
Seconds.
You guessed it equals time out seconds.
Now we need a story.
The updates.
So we're gonna say data update the Czechs collection.
By this I d remember the I d is what we originally started with that the user sent in,
and we're going to update it with this new updated check data and expect an error back.
If there is no air,
then we'll continue.
And we just need to call back 200 to the user if there is an error.
Me to call back 500 or fault and say air could not update the check.
All right,
that is the checks dot put method.
Let's go ahead and start silver back up and trying to use it.
So I'm gonna use the same token since it hasn't been an hour yet,
so it hasn't expired.
Climate change.
This to be a put.
I'm going to move this.
I d down into the payload and let's just modify each thing.
I'm a change.
Http to https.
Change this to yahoo dot com with a put and the success codes are going to be 200 to 1 and
403 and the time out seconds,
they're going to be to said,
that looks like it hit an issue.
It's the same issue as before success codes.
It's not something that I seem to be able to spell correctly consistently,
so I'm just going to update those wherever I did it.
All right,
All of those have been updated.
Let's start it Back up.
Send this Put.
We got a 200 back.
This is the check ending in fl two f l two we look at it.
Https.
Yahoo!
Put these new success codes time out.
Seconds is too.
So all of these updates seem to be working.
Now that puts working,
we can go ahead and write the delete method to require data is just going to be I d.
And there won't be any optional data.
We're going to start with the scaffolding from the last elite that we wrote.
But this delete is going to be a bit more complicated because not only do we need to delete
the check,
but then we need to go into the user's object and delete any record of that.
Check being on the user's object as well,
some copying the delete function from users.
Since it has some off validation that we can use,
we're going to say handlers checks delete.
Here is a function,
and the first thing we need to do is check that the I.
D.
Is valid.
Same modifications.
I mean last time.
And if it's an I D,
then we're going to continue.
Otherwise,
we're going to call back an error to the user.
Now,
before we move on,
we actually want to look up the check that they want to delete.
So we're going to say data read from the checks collection by I D and passes back in air
and check data.
If there's not an air and there is check,
data will continue.
Otherwise we will call that 400 and heir to the user,
saying air the specified check I D.
Does not exist,
but if the check data it was good,
then we need to get the token and verify that it belongs to the same user who created the
check.
So let's move all of this up here.
Okay,
so we're getting the token than we want to do.
Handlers tokens verify,
token and compare it to check data,
user phone,
just like we did before.
And it's gonna passes back of Boolean saying that the token is or is not valid.
If the token is not valid,
then we're going to return a 403 to the user.
But if it is valid,
then we can immediately delete that check that they're asking us to delete.
So we're gonna say,
delete the check data.
We're gonna call data,
delete the Czechs collection by i d passes back and air.
It's not an air.
Continue.
If there is an air call back to the user of 500 saying air could really the check data,
But if there is no air now we need to use this section that we copied down.
We need to look up that user and then modify their object to get rid of any reference to
that check.
So we want to look up the users in the user collection,
and we're gonna look them up by check data.
Use your phone.
It's going to pass us back air and user data.
If there is no air and there is user data will continue here.
If we hit an error or there wasn't any data,
then we're going to call back a 500 say could not find the user who created check so could
not remove the check from the list of checks on the user.
Clean this up a bit,
right?
But back to hear.
If we did get the user data out,
then we need to figure out what the users checks are.
So we're going to take the logic from before,
and we're going to use that down here.
So now we have the list of the user checks and we need to remove the deleted check from
their list of checks.
The way that we're going to do that,
it's figure out what position in that array the user checks is so check position is going
to equal user checks.
The index of i D.
Maybe that's the I d.
From up here.
Now we have the position of the check.
We want to say,
if check position greater than negative one,
then there's something for us to do if for some reason is not greater than negative one,
which had never happened.
But just in case we want to call back an error here.
I could not find the check on the user's object so could not remove it.
But if the check does exist on the user's object,
then we need to remove it with this place.
So use your checks.
This place check position one.
Now that has been removed.
We can re save the users data.
So we're going to just copy this.
Move that up here,
but it's going to be data update.
The users identified by check data,
user phone.
We're going to be updating them with this new user data and they're gonna pass back in air
if there's not an error.
Gonna call back 200.
If there isn't a right that we're gonna say 500 air could not update the user.
Okay,
so that is how we delete a check.
Let's try and start this server back up,
see if we can do it.
So I'm going to change this.
Put to a delete since is a delete.
I do need to move this into the query string.
Get rid of this body.
I'm going to leave the token in the headers and send it off.
I got a 200 back,
so the check ending in f 02 shouldn't exist in here.
And if I open up the users object his array should be missing it.
It should have 1234 So now that that's gone,
I would be able as this user to create my fifth check again since my fifth check has been
deleted.
So Delete seemed to be working fine.
But before we move on to the next lecture,
there is one other modification that we need to make to the handlers file.
But that is in reference to the to do that we made a very long time ago in the user's dot
delete method here.
We told ourselves to clean up any other data files associated with the user when the user
gets deleted.
So let's go ahead and get rid of this to do,
because that's what we are addressing now.
And now,
instead of just calling back 200 we're gonna call back 200 bottom to get rid of that for
now,
because we're gonna put a whole bunch more logic in here.
We're gonna say if the user was deleted successfully.
Now we need to delete each of the checks,
Associate ID with the user.
So let's figure out what the user checks are.
We're going to use that same logic that we did a moment ago.
So now we have the user checks to find,
and we're going to say that that checks to delete is equal to user checks.
Dark length.
So that's the total number of checks that we need to get rid of.
If checks to delete is greater than zero,
we want to do one thing.
If it's not ready than zero,
we want to do another.
If it's not greater than zero,
then we just want to call back 200 to the user because there's really nothing left for us
to do.
If it is greater than zero,
then there's some work that we need to do,
deleting some checks.
So we're gonna continue on with the logic.
We want to start counting the checks.
It we have deleted,
so we're going to say checks deleted.
It is a new variable.
You got a zero and we also want to count.
If we have any delish in errors.
So right now deletion airs are false.
We're basically going to look through all of the checks and delete them one by one.
Keep track of how many we've done and keep track if any of the relations have hit in air.
So we want to loop through checks.
We want to say user checks for each.
Let us use the check I D.
So for each pass of this loop,
we want to delete the check by calling Data docked elite.
We're gonna delete it by i d passes back in air.
And if there is an air deletion airs,
gets set to true.
So we can keep track at some point over this looping process and error happened,
but at any rate,
rather,
an air happened during the deletion process or not,
the checks deleted,
gets increment ID and once checks deleted is equal to checks to delete.
In other words,
once we have passed through the same number of things that we have to do,
then if there's no delusion errors,
we'll just call back 200 to the user because everything went fine.
If there are any heirs,
then we want to call back 500 because we messed something up.
We want to say Air Air is encountered while attempting to delete all of the users checks
Paul checks may not have being deleted from the system successfully.
Let's start the silver back up and tried to delete this user and then make sure that all of
his checks got deleted when he did.
So I'm going to do a delete,
but I need to figure out what this user is called.
So I'm going to do another delete request,
but this time it's to users by phone number.
I'm going to keep the same token and send it off.
Looks like we hit air user data is not defined.
And that is because I'm referencing the user data as user data here when it's really coming
back as data.
So I'm just gonna make it so it comes back is user data and then change it where it needs
to be changed.
Now,
since I'm in Adam,
I can actually re save this file to make the user reappear and restart the so the user's
back in there,
and so are his checks.
So I'm gonna send us off again All right,
We got a 200 back.
That one user is gone.
All the checks were gone,
so that's working as we wanted it to.
Now,
I am actually going to re save this user again just because we wouldn't want to use him
again later.
All right,
I'm gonna kill this app.
That is the modification that we need to make to users dot elite and all of the services
that we needed to build for checks.
So now we can move on to the next lecture.