Now that we have much of the A P I in place,
we have a way for users to be created,
to sign in,
to create checks and to be alerted by SMS.
Now we need to actually go about performing the checks that they create.
And for that we need background workers.
We need background processes.
So at this point,
the nature of our application is fundamentally changing.
We're going from a server that simply starts up and listens on a port to an application
that starts up a server and starts up background workers and needs to be able to do both
things at the same time.
So this old structure we have,
where the index stuck,
Js just starts up the server itself and has all the servers logic contained.
That doesn't really work anymore.
We need to start re factoring so that this index dot Js file will be much smaller and we'll
simply call a server file to start up the server and then we'll call a workers file to
start up the new workers that we're gonna right.
So in other words,
there's a whole bunch of re factoring that we need to do right now,
let's start with this index dot Js.
As I mentioned,
much of the logic here is going to need to move to a server file,
so I'm just going to cut all of it out,
then go to my terminal and create a new file called lib slash server dot Js and I'm gonna
paste it all in there.
We are gonna have to re factor this file so that it exports a lot of what it's doing.
But let's just leave it there for now,
and we'll come back to it.
I take this comment back,
though,
because I do want that to stay in the index file.
And now the index file is just going to do a few simple things.
It's going to have some dependencies,
namely the server file and a new workers file.
So I'm gonna say that far server equals require dot,
slash lib slash server So that's gonna pull in that new server file that we just created.
Now I'm going to create another file called live workers dot Js.
So that lives there now,
and I'm in a reference that here as well workers equals require that's last lid slash
workers.
Now we're gonna want to declare the app just say that for after equals an empty object.
And the only function that we need for now is an initialization function.
Call it an innit function.
So we're gonna say that in it equals a function,
and we're going to within this function,
call the server and workers file.
Then we're going to execute that function.
We're gonna say it.
Lastly,
we're going to export the app.
That's not something that we had done before,
but it will be useful later on when it comes to testings.
Were going to say that module exports equals in the APP.
Innit?
File.
We want to start with the server and we want to start the workers.
We're gonna call them in similar ways.
Server in it.
That means back in that server file,
we need to make sure to create a function called in it.
And we want to start the workers once they exist.
So we're gonna call workers that in it.
So,
as you can see,
the index file is much more streamlined now.
Now,
let's go back over to our server file and start re factoring that we do want to comment up
here.
Just be different than index dot gs.
We want to say that these are server related tasks.
Oliver dependencies are going to stay the same,
except that now that server is living within the lib file.
We don't need to have our require statements walking into the lib file.
So config consider the be referenced dot,
slash config.
Same with handlers and same with helpers later on.
We are also going to need the path module.
And so I'm just going to require that now,
since they know what need it later,
we want to change this so that we in Stan she a several module object.
In other words,
we want to just save our server equals an empty object,
and later on,
we are going to export the whole server.
So we're going to say at modelled on exports equals server.
As you can tell router and all these other functions,
unified server etcetera are declared as local variables.
So they all need to be changed now so that they are keys on this server block so that when
server gets exported,
they do too.
So let's start with the HDP server rather than saying,
Bar http Server were going to say server http server But rather than making the server dot
Listen,
be another key.
I'm gonna cut it out of here,
and I'm going to move it down inside of a new unit function which,
as remember,
gets called here.
So we're gonna call server in it.
So anything that needs to get called when the server should start up,
it's going to move down into this innit function.
I mean,
it's a server that in it equals function,
and it's gonna do two things.
It's going to start the http server,
which is what it's doing here.
But this is no longer valid reference.
So now I want to say server dot http server dot Listen,
Then it's going to start the h g.
P s server.
So let me go up and find where we were starting that.
Move that down here.
So we want to say server dot https server dot Listen,
all right,
now that we have that in its grip,
we could go back to modifying things up here instead of saying https server options,
I want to say server dot https server options and instead of saying var issue to P s server
.
I want to say server https server.
When I referenced the server options here,
I want to say server dot h two b A server options.
Otherwise,
it wouldn't be a valid reference.
And now,
within the silver options,
we need to modify these paths because thes air no longer valid paths to the key and assert
for that we're going to use the path module as we did before.
So we want to cut this out of here for now.
And we want to say path join and the two things rejoining our your name and then pasted
when I just copied out.
Except that I want to back it up one directory.
So I'm gonna save changing from dot,
slash to slash,
dot,
slash So that it backs out of the lib directory,
goes into the HDP s directory and then gets the key.
I'm gonna modify this the same way I'm gonna say path join,
join it with the current directory,
your name pasting when I just copied out and change it to back out of this directory.
All right,
All these modifications air going well instead of Hvar Unified server.
We want to say server dot unified server.
The rest of these references look fine,
because while they are local variables there within server dot unified server,
so we don't need to change any of that.
Now we're going to modify router so that it is server dot router,
which means that we need to modify where router gets reference,
namely,
routed its reference when we're choosing the correct handler.
So instead of type of router,
etcetera,
we want to say,
server dot router in all of these places,
Lastly,
we want to go back up to where the unified service getting called and make sure that we
reference that correctly.
Okay,
Now,
before we move on to anything else,
let's make sure that this part is working.
So I'm gonna comment out what we're doing with workers because workers don't exist yet.
And I'm start up the app and make sure that everything is fine.
All right?
The server is working just as it was before,
so everything is fine so far.
We could kill the act.
A NCAA meant what we just commented.
And now we can go to create the workers library to reiterate the workers are going to
actually perform all of the checking that has been configured by all the users.
So one of the things that workers are going to have to do is gather up all the checks.
As you know,
we're storing all of our checks as separate files within a checks directory.
So one of the things that the workers is going to do is list all of the available checks in
that directory.
Unfortunately,
our Datafile only handles creating,
reading,
updating and deleting files.
It doesn't currently allow you to list all the files in a collection or in a directory.
And so,
before restore writing the workers we actually need to modify our data file.
Add on a function called lib dot list,
which will allow a user to list all the files in a directory,
which,
for our case,
is listing every key in a collection.
So within the data for order,
I want to say list all the items in a directory.
I'm to call this lib dot list,
and he's going to be a function that takes it directory and call back.
We want to call the function reactor or however you pronounce it r e a d D I r.
Which is nodes built in FS function for listing things in a directory.
We need to pass it the base directory as we did before,
whatever directory they're asking about,
and then a slash.
And it's going to pass us back an air and data,
and that data will contain all of the files in the directory.
So we want to say,
if it's not an error,
we'll continue.
Otherwise,
we are going to call back air and data to whoever called us.
But if there is no air and there is data and the data which will be an array has a length
greater than zero,
we'll continue on,
and we're want to get an array of file names that have been trimmed.
So we want to say trimmed file names is an empty array for now.
Now we are going to look through so data for each look through each of the things that they
gave us.
Get the file name,
and we want to just trim off the word dot Jason because we want to know all of the keys,
not with the dot Jason on it so trimmed file names push.
So we're adding things to that array,
and before we add it,
we want to say Found name,
replace dot Jason within every strip.
So again we're looping through the array of file names that we're getting.
We're taking dot Jason off,
and then we're pushing it onto a direct,
and now we just need to call back that array.
So we're not gonna call back an air and we are going to call that Jim found things.
We don't need to test this right now because we're going to be using it extensively within
workers.
And if there's any issue here,
we'll catch it then.
So now we can actually move on to writing these workers.
So let's go into the new workers dot Js file.
Let's set it up with a comment saying that these are worker related tasks.
This file is going to have some dependencies,
and I might as well just list them all out now rather than coming back to them later.
We're going to be using path,
which is required path.
We're going to be using the file system which is require fs.
We're going to be using our data library that we wrote.
So underscore data is require dot slash data because,
remember,
we're already in the liver directory,
so we don't need to do slash lib.
We're going to be using the https module.
We're gonna require https.
We're gonna be using HDP.
We're gonna require it should be.
That is because these workers need to perform https Post get put,
delete or http,
depending on the nature of the check.
So if the check is an https check will use this one.
If it's an HDP check will use that one.
We are going to be using the helpers that we've been reading.
So helpers equals require dot,
slash helpers.
And lastly,
the URL equals require.
You're you'll see how we're using these different note modules as we go.
We want to instead initiate the worker object.
We're just gonna say that workers is an empty object and down at the bottom,
we're gonna export it.
Now what do we need to write?
As you remember in the index dot Js file,
We are starting up the app and immediately calling workers dot in it.
So we know that workers needs to at least have an in its grip,
just like server does.
I'm gonna say workers dot in it is a function and we want to call two functions that don't
exist yet.
We want to execute all the checks as soon as it starts up,
and then we want to call a loop so that the checks continue to execute on their own.
This is because we're going to be initiating this loop with a set interval.
And the set interval,
for example,
of a set interval is every five seconds when it starts,
is not going to execute the first time until after the 1st 5 seconds.
So we want to execute.
As soon as we start up,
we want to perform all the checks and then let the loop takeover.
So these two functions are going to be called workers don't gather all checks,
and the loop is going to be called workers dot loop.
We go ahead and write that loop.
Now we're going to say that this is a timer to execute the worker process once per minute,
as I may have mentioned earlier,
No matter what kind of check the user has set up,
we are just going to execute it once per minute and so once permitted,
all of the checks need to be gathered up way to read all the current checks in the system
and then perform them.
So workers dot Liu is going to be a function.
But it is just immediately going to call a set interval,
and it's going to execute everything in here once.
So we're going to say 1000 milliseconds times 60 seconds.
We could just as easily put this in our config file,
but we don't need to for now.
So once a minute it's going to perform the same thing that we executed immediately upon
Start,
which is workers dot gather all checks and this you work there is not.
We're calling to functions here.
This one is calling the same function,
and this function is that function.
And so the only thing left to do is build out this worker dot gather all checks and any
supporting functions that it would need.
Workers gather all checks.
It's going to do a few things.
It's going to look up all the checks,
get their data and then send all that data to what we're calling a validator,
which is going to make sure that the checks are valid.
So we're gonna say that workers dot gather all checks is a function,
and the first thing that that function wants to do is get all the checks that exist in the
system.
In order to do that,
we're going to use that new data list function that we just made so called data list,
and we want to the list everything in the checks to four order.
Right now,
there's nothing in there,
but we'll fix that in a moment.
It's gonna pass us back an air and an array of checks if there are any or just in India.
Rey.
So we want to say if there's not an air and if checks is valid and checks has a length
created zero,
then we want to continue.
Otherwise,
we just want to log out to ourselves air.
I could not find any checks to process.
Remember,
this is a background worker.
There is no requester here,
so there's no one to call back a response to.
So we're just going to log things out on the assumption that at some point we will want to
look at the terminal or looking a log file which will create later and see what these
process was doing when it was trying to gather all the checks.
So if it did find checks to process,
then we're gonna call checks for each and we're gonna loop through this.
It's gonna give us one check at a time.
And remember,
this is the name of the Czech file without the dot Jason,
So we can just read in the Czech data by passing the Czech name to data dot reid.
And we don't need to strip off that Jason because that's already gone.
So we're just gonna say data read from the checks collection,
this check and that will pass back an error and what we're gonna call original check data.
Remember,
we are going to do stuff with this check,
and so we want to keep track of the state.
The check was in before we performed the check itself and the state afterwards of the
original state that we pull it from the database before actually performing the check is
the original check data.
Now we want to say if there is not an air and there's original check data,
then we want to continue.
Otherwise,
if we've encountered in air with one of these checks,
we want to just log that out so that we could take note of it air reading one of the checks
data.
But if there is check data,
then we want to pass the data to what we're calling the check validator and let that
function continue or log air is as needed once again.
Since we are not dealing with a request that's coming in,
we don't need to worry about the status of any particular operation being called back to
this original calling function.
We don't care about returning any status to someone who initiated this process.
All we care about is that certain processes take place,
and if they air out,
we don't need to call back an error.
We just log out that air.
So rather than doing the structure that we had before,
where we invoke different functions,
get the call backs and then call back the status of those functions to the requester were
actually just going to pass around the data that we need two different functions.
They don't need to call back to each other.
They just need to pass it where it needs to go.
And if they encounter any issue,
they just need to log it out on their own.
There's no master requester who needs to get the status of these processes sent back to
them.
So we want to pass this on to workers Validate,
check data,
and we want to pass them original check data.
So it should be clear what we need to do next.
Now that this function is filled out,
we need to validate check data,
right that function.
So let's do that.
Now.
We're going to say that the purpose of this function is sanity.
Checking the check data.
Remember,
this is Chuck data that we're pulling out of the database.
We still need to make sure that it has everything that we are expecting you to have.
If we're going to perform the check,
for example,
we need to know that there's a girl we need to know that there's a methods era.
So we're gonna say workers validate check data is function and we know what it accepts.
It accepts original check data,
and it doesn't need a callback because this,
for each loop,
is going to pass things to it,
but it's not expecting anything to be called back or even return to it.
It's just going to pass it to this function.
This function is going to log out.
Errors is needed,
so we just need to start by making sure that the original check data exists as a object
with pass keys on it.
Say original check data type of is an object and original check data is not know still
would deal with it or defaulted to an empty object.
Now we want to say that original tech data I D.
Is a strength,
and it has a length of 20 for the fourth.
That would force we want to do basically the same thing with user phone,
except that the length should be ted.
We want to do a similar thing with protocol,
except remember that protocol must be either http or H.
Two p s.
We want to say that protocol is a string and is one of those two things,
just like we did in post checks and put checks.
You are l is going to be just like I d or user found was,
except we just want to make sure that it has any length.
So any length above zero method is going to be set up similar to the way we did protocol.
Except it must be one of post get put.
Delete success code should be an array,
and it should have a length greater than zero.
And if you remember,
time out seconds used to be a number,
it needs to be inter jer.
It is to be greater than or equal to one and needs to be less than or equal to five.
-
Now
,
if you'll remember.
We said that this object that was originally created was not going to be the final state of
the checks once the workers got a hold of it.
And so we actually need to check to see if the new keys that workers would be added have
been added.
And if not,
we should add them to the copy of the object that we're working with.
We want to set the keys that may not be set.
If the workers have never seen this check before,
lamely there to new keys when it's called state,
there's gonna hold whether the check is currently up or currently down.
and the next key is called Last Checked,
which is a timestamp indicating the last time that this check waas performed.
We want to say that original check data a state is a string and it's literally going to be
a string called up or down.
So we want Teoh set it up just like we did protocol.
Except with those two strings instead or down.
And instead of defaulting toe false,
we want to default to down.
So what this means is if a cheque has never been performed If a u.
R l has never been checked,
we want to assume that it is down.
And so the first time we check it,
if we find out that it is up,
it is now going to switch from a downstate to an upstate.
If it is down the first time we check it,
its state will stay down.
The last check.
Timestamp is going to be the result of calling date now,
so it is a number.
So we're gonna copy what we did for time out seconds.
Say that last checked should be a number and it should be greater than zero.
We can get rid of the rest of this,
but we still want to devote it to false.
And that is so we can know by looking at an object whether or not it is in a downstate,
because it has never been checked.
Last check this folks,
or if it's a downstate and that downstate is the result of a check.
If that's the case,
the state will be down and last checked will be a time stamp.
So now we want to do some checking.
We want to say if all the checks pass,
pass the data along to the next step in the process.
This is why this function is called validate Check data.
This is really all it's doing.
Its checking that this thing that we just pull it off of the file system is sane.
And if so,
it's going to pass it along to the workhorse functions that actually preform these checks.
And if it's not,
is just gonna do nothing or just log out an error.
So we're gonna say if original check data I D.
And going to start working on another line now because this is going to be a very long if
original check data user phone and original check data protocol and you are ill and method
and success codes and time out seconds.
Then we want to pass it along.
Otherwise we just want to log out.
But the issue air one of the checks is not properly formatted.
Skipping it.
So that would just let us know when we're looking at the console.
It encountered a check that did not contain the keys for some reason.
And so it's just not even attempting to perform that one.
If everything was fine,
we want to call workers,
don't perform,
check and pass it the original check data because we know all the original check data is
good.
So workers perform check is going to be exactly what it sounds like.
This is going to perform the check,
send the original check data and the outcome of the Czech process to the next step in the
process.
And so this is going to actually look at the euro,
make the http request to that your hell,
Then it's going to record an outcome and then send this original check data and the outcome
to the next step in the process.
So we're gonna call this workers that perform check and it's going to be a function that
takes in original check data from this previous step in the process.
So the first thing it wants to do is prepare the initial check outcome by default.
We are going to just set a outcome that will most likely get overridden as the check gets
performed.
We want to say that check outcome is an object that contains two keys.
One is air.
Did it encountered in air so far in the process?
No,
it didn't.
So that's false.
And the response code that it received well,
it didn't even make the request yet.
So the response code is going to be false.
In the next step of the process,
we want to mark that the outcome has not been sent yet.
In other words,
this outcome object has not been relate to the next phase in the process yet,
and the reason we need this variable will make sense as we go through this function.
Now we need to figure out who were making this request to.
So we want toe parse the host name and the path out of the original check data.
So we want to say that the parsed U R l is going to be your l that parts we're using the
URL module that we required above We want to pass it original check data dot protocol and
then add on colon slash last cause original check dated up protocol is either http or https
So we're adding on colon slash slash and then we're adding on the original check data dot
your l's and we say true.
Now why do we need to this if you remember in the last lecture when we were sending the HDP
requested twilio ap I you remember that part of that payload that we need to send when
crafting htp requests is the hosting.
But when we asked the users to tell us the URL,
we didn't ask them to split the host name off from the path or off from any query string.
We just gave them a taco http or https and we give them a Eurail tefillin that you are l is
gonna contain host name plus a path and a query string.
So we need to reconstruct the full Earl and then parse it into its different parts.
So that we can craft the HDP request accordingly.
So now that we have the parts,
you are Oh,
we know that the host name equals par Sharell dot host name.
This is exactly what we did when we were parsing incoming requests earlier on when we were
first Setting up the server and warpath equals parsed your l dot path.
And I was gonna put a note here that we are using path and not path name,
which are both available because we want the query string.
We want the full query string that they entered there.
And so if we had only used path name,
we wouldn't have had that query string,
but it might be important to the check.
So we do want it now.
We can go about constructing the request.
We're going to say request details is set up much like we set up the request to twilio in
the last lecture.
So request details is a big object.
Protocol needs to be set to original check data dot protocol and remember that it needs to
include a colon on there.
So we're gonna add on the colon host name equals what we have set to the host name Variable
.
Right now the method needs to be set to original check data dot method.
But since this function wants all methods in upper case,
we need to now call the to upper case function.
Teoh,
switch it to that.
So the path is going to be the path and we're including the query string in there.
And lastly,
the time out is going to be set to original check data time out seconds times 1000 because
this key is expecting milliseconds.
But we asked the user how many seconds before it should time out.
And so if it's three,
for example,
we actually need to enter 3000 so we're just gonna multiply it there.
That's all the request details we need to fill out.
Now we're about to perform an http request in the manner that the user asked us to.
So the next thing that we need to do is just like last time in Stan.
She ate the request object using either the HDP or a GPS module as we went over earlier.
If you're doing a shitty P stuff,
you were making requests to HDP colon slash last.
Something you want to use the HDP module.
If you're making a request to http s cones,
that's something you want to use the https module.
And so the first thing we need to determine is what module to use and risk going to assign
that module to this variable and use this variable instead.
So we're going to say that the module to use equals the original check data's protocol in
model form.
So,
in other words,
if the original check data's protocol is http used the http module This variable http is
assigned to that module up here otherwise used the HDP s Marshall.
So now we have the module to use and we can craft the request.
So we're going to say that the requests the rec equals martyr to use dot request.
Then we're gonna pass in the request details.
It's gonna pass us back a response object.
And just like last time,
we're going to grab the status of the sent A request.
So the status equals rez status code.
They should all look familiar because this is what we did when making the request to twilio
.
Now we want to update the check outcome and pass the data along.
So we want to say that they check outcome dot response code number.
This thing up here equals whatever status we just got back.
Now we want to check if the outcome has not been sent already and if it hasn't will pass it
off the next phase in the process.
In a moment,
you'll understand why,
in some cases,
the outcome would have already been sent by the time we reached this part.
So we want to say if the outcome has not been sent,
then we want to call workers process check outcome,
which is the next phase in the process.
And then we want to pass it original check data on the original thing we were working with
and the Czech outcome.
Then we want to say outcome sent Too true.
That's all we need to do here.
But in the next section of the function,
we're going to bind to an air,
and that error is also going to pass things along to process check outcome if the outcome
hasn't been set yet.
So we're going to say bind to the air event so it doesn't get thrown,
just like last night.
So we're gonna say a request on air.
So if the request throws the air event and give us the air and we want to say update just
like above the check outcome and pass the data along.
So I'm just gonna copy that here,
we're going to say check outcome dot Air needs to be sent.
Rumor.
This field here and that's going to equal an object because it has some data we need.
Teoh said air true value is going to be whatever this air is that got passed to us.
Now that we have filled out the error,
we want to say if outcome has not been sent,
then do the same thing that we did above.
Send the original check data and this new filled out check out.
Come here.
Now,
The next thing that we need to do is something we didn't do on the last request,
which is bind to the time out.
So behind to the time out event,
I'm just copying the whole error thing cause it's very similar and we want to say request
on time out.
So,
in other words,
if they exceed the time out seconds,
If we said three seconds and it passes three seconds.
Then we want to throw this event and we want to say there is an air,
the air is true and the value this time is going to be time out.
So now when the process check outcome function receives payloads,
it can tell the difference between an air that is thrown and an error that is the result of
a time out So the outcomes not sent.
We're going to send that along here,
so these are all set up.
So that process chat outcome will only receive the original check data and check outcome
once for each check.
Because every time it's about descended in these three different places is checking if
anyone else has ever ascended,
and it's only going to send it if no one else has.
Lastly,
we want to,
And the request,
which is the same thing,
is sending the request correct.
And so now it'll get sent off.
At this point,
we need this function,
so let's go ahead and write it.
It's going to be the one that takes in these process checks after they've been performed.
They might be in an air estate or they might have a status code,
who knows?
So we want to say that the purpose of this function is to process the check outcome an
update,
check data as needed and then trigger an alert to the user if needed.
And we're going to include special logic here for accommodating a check that has never been
tested before.
And we want to say that we don't want to alert on that one.
So,
in other words,
if the state is switching from down to up,
but that's only because the state was set to down by default.
We don't want to send a SMS to the user saying that the check went from down to up.
We only want to alert the user that the status has changed if this status has truly changed
from something that we read wants to something that we read now,
so that's craft dysfunction were fished out.
Process check outcome is,
they function takes in the original check data and the check outcome.
Like the others,
it doesn't need to call back.
It's going to handle whatever it needs to do and log out errors accordingly.
First thing it needs to do is decide if the check is considered up or down in this current
state,
we're gonna say this state equals that there is no check outcome dot there and there is a
check outcome dot response code.
And that response code is one of the response codes that the user told us should be
considered up.
So we want to say that the original check data success codes index of check outcome
response code is greater than negative one.
If so,
the check is up.
Otherwise the check is down.
So to say that one more time,
we're considering the check the euro to be up.
If when we went to process it,
we didn't find an error,
we did get a response code back,
which means we didn't time out or in country and the other kind of there.
And the response code that we got back was one of the codes in the array that the user set
when he or she said that these were the allowable response codes that should be considered
.
Okay,
Now we need to decide if an alert is warranted.
Remember,
we are texting users when the status of their check changes,
and so we only want to text a user if it was previously down and went toe up or is
previously up and went down.
So we're going to save our alert.
Warranted equals original.
Check data dot last checked and original check data State does not equal state that we just
set there.
If so true,
otherwise false.
Let me explain what this means.
We're trying to figure out if it's worth texting.
User.
The first thing we need to know is that they really did have a state before,
so that if the check was down,
it really was down.
It wasn't just defaulted to down because he had never been checked before.
And so we want to check that the last checked field is set.
Any number is going to be Truth E and so checking it this way,
it's fine,
because if it was false,
it would fail this job.
And so if it said is a number and not said it's false,
it'll pass here.
And then we're checking that the original check data states of the last recorded state is
different than the state that we just noted that the Ural currently is in.
So we're saying that if it was down and is now up and the largest warranted,
or if it was up and is now down,
then it alert is warranted.
And in the other case alert is not wanted.
So now it's time to update the check data,
regardless of whether or not it's worth texting.
User,
We do want to update the check in the database with this new data that we just got the last
check time and the new state.
So we want to say that new check data equals original check data and that new check data,
uh,
state equals state and new check data dot Last checked equals right now.
Now we want to save the updates to disk.
You want to say data update the Czechs collection with the I.
D of the check that we're dealing with,
we update it with new check data.
They passes back and air.
If there is no air,
we want to continue.
Otherwise,
we want to just log out the fact that we're having issues we want to say air trying to save
updates to one of the checks.
But if everything's fine,
we want to send the new check data to the next phase in the process,
if needed.
And the next phase of the process is actually sending the alert to the user.
So we want to say if alert warranted,
go ahead and send that alert.
Otherwise we're not gonna do anything.
So we're going to say check.
Outcome has not changed.
No alert needed,
but it looked alert is warranted.
We're gonna say workers that alert user to status change which is not a function that
exists yet,
but it will in a second workers that alert user to status change and then passed in new
check day.
Now,
the last function that we need to build is you guessed it alert user to status change.
And this is one that's going to send the actual SMS using the library that we made in the
last lecture.
So alert the user has to a change in their check status.
As we can see above,
workers got alert.
User to status change is a function accepts in the new check data only,
and at this point,
we're going to craft the message.
So we're going to get the message is equal to alert your check for new check data method to
upper case and then new check Data protocol.
Colts Last lash new Jeff data Your l is currently new check data State.
So what this would say,
for example,
is alert.
Your check for post http s colon slash slash google dot com is currently up or something
like that.
So now we have the messaging taken care of.
We want to call the helpers using the helpless library we included up there.
So we want to say helpers don't send twilio sms new check data dot Use your phone.
Remember,
we first need to say the phone number that we need to alert and we're storing the user's
phone number on the check data so we don't need to look up the user.
We already know who the user is that needs to be alerted.
We need to send them that message and then we're gonna expect back an air in the car back.
So we're going to say if there's not an air then bringing the log out Success user was
alerted to a status change in their check via SMS.
And then why don't we just also log out the message that we send them.
But if there was an error,
we want to log out.
Air could not send SMS alert to user who had a state change in their check.
So that is all we need to do for these workers.
You should have a pretty good idea of how they work.
But of course there are no checks in our system.
So now when we start up this,
besides a few errors that we might need to fix,
we should see this error get logged out,
could not find any checks to process.
And then,
since this is running once a minute,
a minute later,
we would see the same thing.
So let's see what happens.
There we have it.
And just for illustrative purposes,
I'm to speed this up to run every five seconds instead,
just so we can see the loop work.
I could not find any checks.
The process.
That's the run.
This running initially now five seconds later,
could not find the checks to process.
Five seconds after that,
could not find any checks to process.
It's so it's just going to continue to try over and over again.
Let me set this back to 60 and we might encounter some other heirs when we I actually have
some checks in there.
But let's see.
So let's go to postman and create a few checks with our user and then start the at back up
and see if the checks are getting processed normally when a start up the app And now let
before I need to get a token,
This the token I'm gonna use and my subsequent requests.
I'm gonna go create a new check just like I did before.
But this time you use this new token and this same one that we were creating with the user
before we deleted him,
I think would be fine.
Except let's say that this https protocol all right,
you've created that that's create another one,
too yahoo dot com Oh,
I'm hitting this issue because I just manually save this user without updating Hiss array
of checks.
And so I'm going to delete this guy's checks and re save his user.
Start the backup.
Most are gonna delete this check since it's now and orphan.
All right,
created one for Yahoo.
Let's create one for Google.
All right,
Now,
this user has these two checks on his object.
let's go ahead and restart the server,
See what it does.
Could not find any checks to process,
so that's not right.
Let's go ahead and check this out and see what's going on.
Looks like it might be an error with this listing function that we did.
We said there was a strength when it is supposed to be the variable start the workers back