in this lecture,
we're going to show a few different tricks that you can do with console logging.
We already went over the basics of logging to files,
but there's still many different reasons that you'll want to lock the console.
But the more that you look to the console,
the harder it is to see or pinpoint any given mind that you might be looking for.
And so these tricks we're going to allow you to separate out different things and also tell
node when toe log certain strings versus others.
So we're going to go to our workers file and log out the fact that it has started right now
.
As you know,
when you start up the application,
a few different logs happen.
It says the server is listening on a Port 3000.
It's listening for 2001 And then there's a bunch of logs happening from log file truncation
,
new logs big sent to log files and then the workers telling us that they did not need to
send new alerts to users.
That's a lot to happen.
And if you're just trying to glance at this and figure out whether or not the workers have
started whether or not the server has started,
it might be a little difficult.
So in this initial ation script,
let's log out the fact that the workers have started.
But let's log it in yellow so that we can see it really easily when the at boots up.
So we're going to say,
said to console in yellow,
we're going to do a normal console dot log.
But this time we're going to send a code that tells Node to do everything in yellow instead
.
And that code looks like this.
Then we're going to put in the string that we actually wanted to send.
Background workers are running now to explain this a little bit more consul dot log When it
comes to node doesn't just take simple strings,
but it actually takes in string interpolation or allows you to put in variables.
Now,
this whole string is actually a command telling console to put it in yellow.
But this percent s is actually telling it that whatever the next parameter is that you send
in,
go ahead and insert that in here and then make this whole thing to come out.
And so when we start this up,
you can see background workers or running,
and that's coming out in yellow.
We can actually modify these numbers 33 34 32 etcetera to get different colors.
There's not that many colors available,
but there are a few.
So now that that's working,
let's change the server listening imported 5001 to be a different color because there's two
things that we really need to know when we glance at the AP after it starts.
One is that the workers were running and then the other that the server is listening.
So let's copy what we did here and then move over to server.
Go down to the initial Asian script,
and we're actually going to modify these two functions to be different.
So I'm pasting in what I just got from over there.
I'm moving them into the second parameter of the log.
So now if we start this up,
we'll see a whole lot of yellow.
That's kind of hard to grok.
So let's change the two colors of these two messages.
Let's change this 1 to 36 this 1 to 35 see what happens now when we started up background
workers air running still in yellow.
The server is listening of Port 3000 is coming through in light blue,
and the server is listening.
Import 1000.
What is coming through and pick.
I like the way that looks.
So let's just leave that there now.
Despite all these other messages that are coming through weaken glance at this app when it
starts and see yellow,
light blue and pink and no.
Okay,
everything is at least started up.
So that's how you make the console long strings of different colors.
That's very useful,
especially if you want to make errors very pronounced to the user.
May come out and read or success messages come out in green etcetera.
But the issue that were going to run into with this app,
especially when there are lots and lots of checks,
is that there's gonna be lots and lots of logs happening as well.
And someone looking at this console is just going to be inundated with success and error
messages so quickly that they can't really grok was going on,
especially if there is a lot of requests coming to the A P.
I and a lot of background workers happening at the same time.
So the next thing that we need to do is figure out how to modify the AB so that not all
these logs need to be coming through all the time.
The way that we do that is actually with nodes debug command line argument now to see what
I mean by that,
we can start this app up with node debug equals any built in module into note.
So one of the ones that were using his http,
so let's just say no debug equals http and then start up is normal node index dot Js c o
this extra stuff coming through.
We have our yellow,
blue and pink,
but then we have all these debug messages coming through from this HDP module does
identifying itself as its module.
And then it's process I d.
If we go over to postman and just send a random post,
you're going to see that there's even more information coming through the socket opening
and closing.
And so every time the http module does something,
there's going to be mawr and Mawr messages here,
and that is true of any node package that sends out deep of messages,
which many of the modules do.
But you can also use the node debug command line argument to specify your own packages or
specify your own bits and pieces of console locking that you might be doing in different
places.
The way that you do that is with the utilities package.
So let's go over to workers and we're going to include the utilities package.
So far,
you till equals,
require you,
too.
And then we're going to say that debug in other words,
what we're going to be using instead of consul dot log.
So debug equals you tail dot debug log and then we have to give it a name.
So this name is the same thing that we will pass as a startup argument.
So in our case,
we're gonna call this workers because we're in the workers file and when we want to only
see debug messages from the workers file,
we're going to start the app up with node debug equals workers knowed index Js Right now
that would not have much of an effect.
But once we modify the consul logging here to use debug instead it will have effect.
So I am actually just going to find replace most of the console logging that happens in
this file.
Just replace it with D book.
That is true for most of them except this last one where we are using the colored console
logging to make the background.
Workers are running come out as yellow,
and we want that to come out whether or not we've started it with no debug equals workers.
So now that we've switched all the console,
don't log to be called with the debug function.
Instead,
let's start this up.
Now you can see all the same logs that were coming out before yellow,
blue,
pink and then a bunch of workers related logging.
But you can see that now workers are coming out specifying that they're coming from the
workers in this realization of this debug blogger and also a process i d.
That also means that if we start this up without no debunk equals workers,
we don't have that locking happen at all.
So now that logging has gone from something that happens all the time,
every time we start the app to log in,
that happens conditionally on Lee if we start the application with a certain flat,
so that will make it a lot easier for us to grok what's going on now.
Let's go over to server dot Js and do something similar.
So I'm gonna copy this here,
move it over to server.
But this time I want the debug log flag to be called server instead.
Now that we have that debug function defined,
we can go ahead and replace most of the console log in this file as well.
So I'm gonna do,
ah,
find,
replace and start replacing things.
But I actually still don't want to replace Thies,
too,
because I don't want the server is listening messages to be conditional.
I want them toe happen every time we start up the app while we're here,
let's go ahead and get rid of this old console log that we just replaced and let's make it
a little bit more robust.
So let's say instead of just logging the request path that came in when a user makes a
request or a P,
I,
let's say if the response is 200 print green,
otherwise print red,
so we're gonna add some coloring here,
but we still only want these red or green messages to happen if the application is started
with no deep of equal server.
So we're going to keep this within debug instead of console dot log.
So we're going to say if status code equals 200 we want to look something out.
Otherwise,
we want to log it out in red.
So what we want to log out in Green is going to be the method that the user requested,
and we're gonna push it up to upper case and then the path that they requested,
and then the status code that we sent back.
And this first parameter is going to become the green coloration.
If it's not a status equals 200 it's gonna come out with the same message is just going to
come out red.
So let's go down here.
Copy this string pasted in here.
But instead of it coming out with that color,
let's change the 201 to 32 which will make it come out green,
and let's change the else to 31 which will make it come out red.
So,
in other words,
good requests are coming out with green.
Bad requests are coming out with red,
so I'm gonna start this server backup with no debug equals server.
There's nothing there yet,
cause remember,
these debug messages only come when requests hit the a p I.
So I'm gonna go back to Postman said off a random request that was a 200 so that messages
coming out is great.
Now I want to modify this to be something that doesn't exist.
Send that often,
get a 404 That's not a 200.
So the message should be read.
So now every request that comes into the a P I is going to be law green or red if it's 200
or not.
And so when you're debugging issues and you're trying to figure out what happened when that
user got a 500 back to track down that request,
you congest visually scan for red marks as opposed to trying to figure out exactly which
request you need based on text alone.
But once again,
if we hadn't started this up with the no debug equal server flag,
none of these messages would have appeared at all right,
so I can clear out the terminal.
That's all the fancy console logging that we really need to go over here.
All the modifications that we need to make to are apt to make these messages a little clear
for us so we can move on to the next lecture.