Let's begin re factoring our application so that it can support a Web interface and not
just a Jace on a P I.
I've gone ahead and opened up the server dot Js file inside of the lip directory on the
scroll all the way down to where we have defined this router.
The pass on this rather were fine for a Jason a p I.
We didn't need any prefixes to any of these services because we didn't have anything else
going on in this application.
Now that's starting to change,
and we actually are going to want to move a lot of these services up into their own AP I
directory with their own AP I prefix just to get out of the way off any other new user
facing rows that we will need for the Web app.
So I'm going to modify these three services users tokens and checks so that they exist off
of an A p I prefix.
So rather than making requests to local host slash users,
a client would now make a request to local host slash AP I slash users.
For example,
I'm gonna leave Ping as its own path because that might be useful,
and it's not really part of our A P I.
It's just the app itself,
telling anyone who might ping it that it is alive.
What we're here in anticipation of the routes we're going to build.
We might a swell fill out this router with everything that's going to need to be there in
the coming lectures.
So at the top,
we're going to add a path of a nature we haven't seen before.
And that is an empty string.
And that empty string will route to Handler called handlers dot Index,
which,
of course,
doesn't exist yet.
If you look at this,
you can probably guess what this means.
Until now,
any path that a user might hit has had a string of a length.
It's always had something in it.
But now,
like any normal Web app,
we're going to have users who request the base directory who requests no path at all,
and that will mean that we need to serve them the index file of this new website.
So for them,
we're going to say that if you request no path,
you should be served by the index handler.
Now that's built out a few of the other ones.
Before a user can do anything,
the user first needs to exist.
And so the first route that we want besides the index is account slash create.
This is the path in the browser that the user will actually visit if they visit local host
2000 or whatever at the base directory is where this app is hosted,
and then they click on Sign Up.
They'll be taken to the domaine dot com slash account slash create and this handler called
handlers dot account create.
We'll need to serve them in HTML page,
showing them a sign up form where they can fill out information and sign up for an account
.
Once they're inside of their account,
they're going to be able to edit their settings.
So I'm gonna create a path called account Slash Edit that will route to a handler called
handlers dot account at it.
Once their account exists,
they also need the ability to delete it,
and that is going to be a button that exists on the account edit page.
But once they have deleted their account,
they need to be taken to a your account has been deleted page,
and so we're going to set up that route at account slash deleted that will be served by
Handler called handlers dot account deleted in order to do anything on the edit path or in
order to reach the deleted path they will have needed to sign it.
Or in our parliaments,
they need to create a session.
And so we're going to create a route called Session Slash create.
If they visit the home page and then they click a button that says Sinan,
they'll be taken to a log in form,
and that log in form is going to be served at the earl slash session slash create,
and it's going to be served by Handler called handlers dot session create.
Similarly,
they need to be able to log out,
which is deleting a session,
and after a session is deleted,
they need to be taken to a page that says you have deleted your session or in user speak.
You have logged out,
so we're going to create a route called Session Slash deleted that they'll be taken to
after logging out,
and that will be served by handlers DOT Session deleted when they're signed in and they
want to create checks.
The first thing they're going to need to see is a dashboard of their existing checks,
where they can click on them and reach more details or click a button and to be taken to a
page where they can create a new check.
This dashboard page is going to be called checks.
Slash all,
and this,
like many of these other routes,
is going to be a protected route that you can only reach if you're signed in Check slash
all is going to be served by handlers dot checks list.
As I mentioned,
they're also going to want to be able to create a check on a special page that gives them a
form that they can fill out in order to create a check and that path that they're on when
they're doing that will be checks Slash create that we served by Handler called handlers
dot checks create.
They're also going to want to be able to edit and delete a check.
If they delete a check will simply be taken back to a checks list page,
but if they edit it,
they will simply need to see a message on that same editing page saying that they're
changes have been saved.
That page is going to be called checks slash edit checks slash ed.
It will be served by handlers dot checks.
Edit.
That's all the new routes that we need.
And now we can actually go about modifying the server a little bit more so that it can
support HTML content types.
Right now it serves Jason,
and it only serves Jason,
so we're going to need to modify that behavior.
So we're going to go off inside of the unified server function and look for where we are
passing the incoming request to the chosen handler to review.
We expect all handlers to call back to optional fields a status code which will default to
200 if they don't send it back.
A payload which will default to an empty object,
and that's it.
But now we actually want to add 1/3 optional parameter to this function callback,
which will allow anyone who is calling back as a handler to send 1/3 variable to us and
that variable is going to be content type now,
since no existing handler is calling this back there on Lee ever calling back status,
code or payload,
we're going to have to create a sensible default for content type that won't change the
behavior of any of the existing routes or handlers for our case.
We're going to make sure that the content type,
if it's not specified,
defaults to Jason.
So here we want to determined the type of response fall back to Jason.
So we want to say that the content type should equal strength and if it does,
use whatever it is otherwise default to a strain called Jason.
Up until now,
in all cases,
we have simply sent back the content type header,
as always,
set to applications last Jason and we have written the payload string to the body,
defaulting it to an empty Jason object.
Now we need to re factor this section of it to check if the content type being served
should be Jason,
in which case this behavior should stay the same.
Or if the content type is going to be HTML,
in which case a different header should be sent out.
And rather than defaulting to a empty object issued default to an empty strength So rather
than simply saying we want to return the response,
we say that we want to return the response parts that are content specific,
and then we want to return the response parts that are common to all content types.
Let's start with what are common writing.
This status code is going to be common to all requests and writing.
Something that is defined as payload string is going to be common to all requests.
It's just that what that payload string is will vary depending on the content type.
So first we need to default the payload strength to an empty strength.
Then we want to say,
if the content type equals Jason,
we want to do certain behavior.
Otherwise,
if the content type equals H t mail,
we want to perform other set of behaviors.
The behavior that we want to do if the content type is Jason is much of this behavior that
exists up here.
We want to set the headers to content type application.
Jason,
we want to default the payload to an empty object,
and then we want to override this payload string variable with the Jason string of five
payload.
Alternatively,
if the content type is HTML.
I'm just going to copy this header from here.
We want to say that content type instead of equals.
Application slash Jason that's going to equal text slash html.
Secondly,
we want to say that the payload string it's going to be set to type of payload equals
string payload or empty strength.
In other words,
if the existing payload that's being called back by the handler is already a string,
then that's a string we need to use.
Otherwise,
we're going to use an empty string of our own For these HTML handlers.
Calling back an object is not going to work.
We're expecting these handlers to call back strings so that we can write them to the body
of an HTML document.
Now that we have this set up,
I'd like to create a simple hello world route on the index handler that we defined in the
router down here.
So let's open up our handlers file,
and we want to first note that everything below this point it's going to be considered
Jason ap I peddlers and we're going to create a section up here that is just going to be
dedicated to the new HD mail handlers that we're creating.
The first handler is going to be the index handler,
and it's going to be set up initially,
just like the Jase on a P I handlers were going to say that handlers dot index,
it's going to equal function,
takes in data and to call back.
And initially,
let's just make it Colback Nothing at all.
This will make the status code default to 200 the body default to an empty HTML string.
But this is also going to make it default to Jason.
So we actually want to make sure that the third parameter says html So rather than having
nothing at all,
we're going to say undefined,
undefined,
and then html.
Now let's start the app up and then view the index page in a Web browser so we can see that
this page is rendered.
Okay,
Now I'm gonna open up chrome and try to view this page.
Now we can actually see that this page is at local host 3000 which is the index of this
site.
I'm gonna refresh it,
and I'm actually switching to view source,
which you can see here,
you can see that there is nothing coming out.
I'm gonna open up the inspector and then reload this so that we can actually just make sure
that anything is happening at all.
As we can see,
local host 3000 was fetched with a get and the response headers were pretty minimal.
We said content type,
text slash html the date the transfer encoding and keep alive,
which is stuff that note put on automatically.
So so far,
so good.
We're able to serve an empty HTML file to the browser to make this a little bit easier.
Let's view it in postman as well.
I mean,
to make a get request to local host 3000 and we see that we got back nothing at all except
a 200 and content type text html as well as those other headers that I mentioned a moment
ago to debug this front and application will use a combination of the browser when it's
useful and postman,
when we need to do simple things that don't require actually rendering the HTML objects or
viewing the CSS or anything like that.
Now let's go back and modify this new route so that it can serve some real HTML,
such as a hello world message.
I'll get rid of this.
You can see I've added this comment that we want to reject any request that isn't a get so
we want to say that if the data dot method equals,
get will continue.
Otherwise we want to call back four or five undefined and in html,
strength.
Simply saying four or five.
That method is not allowed.
What?
We're going to tell you that by serving in HTML content type and the four or five status
code.
If the data method is get,
then we want to read in the index template,
which we haven't created yet as a strength.
And though this function doesn't exist yet,
I'm just going to use it in anticipation.
We want to call helpers that get template and then pass it the word index because we want
the index template and we want it to give us back and air and a string that string should
contain the actual template data.
So if there is no air and there is a string,
we want to continue and simply called back 200 then the content of that template and then
note that this is HTML that we're calling back.
So,
as you can anticipate,
the template is going to hold with a bunch of HTML,
and our handlers will simply fetch those templates from the file system and then serve them
within HTML content type.
If there was an air or there wasn't any template string,
we want to call back 500 because something is wrong with the app Now that we've set that up
.
Obviously we need to go defined this helpers dot get template function.
Let's open up the helpers.
And the first thing that we're going to need to do in this helpers file is add some
dependencies because in anticipation what's coming,
we know that we're going to need the path module.
So we're going to require path and we're going to need the file system.
We're gonna require fs now.
That's right,
that get template function that we just referenced a moment ago.
So down at the bottom,
I'm to create this new function that should get the string content of a template,
and it will be called helpers.
Don't get template,
as we saw a moment ago it's going to accept in a template name and a callback.
The first thing that's going to need to do is sanity.
Check the template name.
So what?
We will set the template name equals type of template.
Name equals string and template.
Name length is greater than zero.
Then whatever template name is defined as or false then we only want to continue if
template name Issa good variable.
Otherwise,
we're not gonna try to read a file of that name,
so we will call back A valid template name was not specified.
But if a valid string came through,
then we want to read in the template file.
So the first thing we're gonna do is define a templates directory as path Don't join.
This should look familiar from the data folder underscore under store directory name and
then slash,
dot,
slash Templates slash.
So,
as you can see,
we now need a new directory to exist in the roof order.
We need to create directory.
So I'm going to make directory templates.
And there it is.
Now that we've referenced that templates directory,
we can try to use fs read file to pull in whatever the user is asking for.
So we're gonna say Read file templates directory plus template name plus dot html Because
all these templates are going to be named something dot html.
Then we're gonna read it in as utf eight and expect back in air or a string.
As you can guess.
If there's not an air and there is a string and the string has a length of greater than
zero,
then we're just going to call back.
No error and a string to the requester.
Otherwise,
we're going to call back.
No template could be found.
So now we have the basic scaffolding set up to read in in html template and then pass it
back to a caller so that they can render it to the browser.
But we don't have any templates yet,
so let's go ahead and create this index template so that it can be rendered when someone
requests the base directory.
So within the templates for order,
I'm going to create a new file called index dot html.
Open that up and it's going to be very simple.
HTML document.
It's gonna have an HTML opening and closing tag.
It's going to have a head opening and closing tag as well as one for the body and in the
head.
There's just going to be a title tag saying in the World and similarly in the body and H
one saying Hello,
world exclamation point.
Now that we've set that up,
we've created this template that's living in the templates for her.
When the handler gets called,
we're going to use this get template function to find here in order to read in the content
of this template and serve it back to the browser.
So when we go to postman now,
we start up the APP and make this request to the base directory.
Again.
We'll see that a body is returned and it is an HTML document.
Similarly,
when we refresh the page in the browser,
we can see Hello world.
When I view source,
we see the same HTML document that we created in the template photo.
So that's our little hello world Proof of concept of rendering HTML for the browser R A p I
should still be working as normal is just that the paths have been moved up to live inside
of another directory called slash AP.
I and now our APP is ready to get a bit more complicated.
So in the following lectures,
we are going to add on some more features that let us serve more complicated content such
as photos and CSS files.
And then we're just going to start building out these HTML templates and the client side,
JavaScript and CSS that we need to exist for Our users toe have a fully functional Web app
.
But this basic concept of serving hte email to the browser has been accomplished.
Here.
It's now we can kill the APP and move on to the next lecture.