Now that we have basic template ing working,
we want to add a universal header and footer that will be used on every HTML page.
And then we want to modify our get template helpers so that they pull in those universal
header and footers and wrap them around every HTML template that gets called.
So the first thing we want to do is create a couple more templates.
This time we're gonna call them Underscore Footer and underscore header dot html.
But they're going to be living in this same templates directory,
so I'm gonna call,
touch,
depletes underscore footer html and touch templates underscore header dot html.
So I'm gonna open up the header and begin composing this first.
As I mentioned in a previous lecture.
Since this course is not about front end,
each team l or C s s are front and JavaScript or don manipulation or anything like that.
I'm going to breeze very quickly through composing these templates and all of this front
and stuff that it doesn't directly have to do with serving files or writing handlers in
note.
And so,
if you want to look at these files in more detail,
feel free to browse to get hub.
Otherwise,
don't worry about memorizing or keeping up with everything that we're saying here.
When we originally wrote this index Hello,
world.
We wrote the opening and closing HTML tags,
the head tags and the body tags all here.
But we want to be able to modify this index dot html so that the only thing it needs is
just the content that makes it different from every other page,
namely an H one with hello world it.
I'm gonna modify index dot html to only have an H one.
Then we're gonna build out these header and footers so that they provide the rest of the
tags that used to be there.
They're just going to do it in a more complex or fully featured way.
So within the header,
I'm gonna have the opening HTML tag fathered by an opening head tag.
I'm also going to include the closing head tag,
an opening body tag,
and then what?
I'm calling a page rapper.
Now you'll notice that I'm reading these comments as HTML comments,
not as JavaScript comments.
And so I'm using the HTML comments syntax instead of the one that we were doing earlier.
So this is going to be the page rapper and it's just going to be a div called Class Rapper
That's going to be opened within the header.
But as you'll see there are that and another element called content that don't get closed
within the header.
They will get closed within the footer.
So within the rapper,
when other thing that's going to be included on every page is a header,
But by header,
I don't mean this whole file.
I mean the head of the document,
the top of the HTML page of the browser users are going to see.
So I'm gonna say that the header is going here and that is going to be a Dave with the
class header and I'll fill that in and details in a moment.
This one actually is going to get closed because the header lives entirely within the
header dot html and then as I mentioned,
we're going to have the page specific content,
pretended with the opening tag called content.
So I'm going to create a death.
Call it class content,
but I'm not going to close it before we fill in the header and the rest of the head.
Let's go to the footer so that we can close thes tags so that it's not so hard to keep
track of them later on within the footer.
I'm going to close that content,
Div.
Then I'm going to actually have a footer and HTML footer,
though,
didn't here.
So I'm gonna created Dave with a class called Footer.
That itself is going to be closed.
Then I'm going to have another closing Dave here and to look back of what we're doing.
We're actually closing the page Rapper.
Then I'm going to have a closing body tag since the body was still open.
And finally a closing HTML tag to make this all seem a little prettier.
I'm just going to space thes out a little bit,
so the body's indented.
The closing Dev is indebted from the body.
The footer is indebted from that closing Div,
and then the content closure is intended as well.
I could get rid of these empty spaces here,
but I am going to fill in some content in the footer now while we're here,
and that's just going to be a Dave with a class called copyright and we're going to say
that copyright equals global dot year created,
followed by Global,
that company named and a pipe and all rights reserved with a closing def.
Now you might be saying,
What on earth is global dot your created what is global?
A company name.
And what is this syntax that you're using?
Right now we are inserting a variable into this template.
All of our templates and these are no exception are going to accept variables that are
global or specific to the page that's being rendered.
These two variables,
your created and company name are just two of the global is that we're going to make
available.
Where did these come from?
Well,
as you know,
before these templates are ever presented to a browser,
they need to go through helper functions such as get template.
So in a moment after we finish writing this header and footer,
we're going to modify those helpers so that they can dynamically insert any global's that
we want or any of the data specific to the page.
So if you were wondering in the header how we're going to get paid specific titles,
meta descriptions,
all of that in the head.
If this is a universal header,
that is how the helpers were going to be able to pull in paid specific metadata and global
meta data about the app the global metadata were using.
Here is the year that this application was created and the company name that created the
application so that we can render a copyright correctly back to the header.
We have a whole bunch to fill in here within the head.
We want to have some general purpose settings at the top.
The first is the char set.
So we're going to say that meta charset equals utf eight.
Then we're going to say that the content language is English,
So e n dash us made a H two b equipped equals content.
Language content equals e n dash us.
Now we want to include a base tag.
This is not an HTML tag that very many people use,
but I am quite fond of it.
It allows all of your links to be relative to a base directory that you specify.
So I'm going to say that the base directory that every HTML link on the page should be
relative to is going to be global.
Don base,
you are out.
This is another use of these global variables that will be inserted when these pages air
getting rendered.
Now we want to put in some Met attacks.
As you can expect,
these meta tags are going to be mostly placeholder variables that will be modified on the
fly.
Something include the title tag and that's going to be a very well called head title,
followed by pipe and then global dot happening.
So,
for example,
we're going to want this title to say,
you know,
home page pipe and then the name of the app.
Now we want a meta description.
Use a meta name equals description,
but the content of the description is going to be a variable head description.
Since we're doing this string and interpellation or this find,
replace,
if you will on our own,
we don't need to worry about play saying variables within quotes or outside of quotes
doesn't matter will be able to find it ourselves.
Now we want to list the static assets.
The first is a fabric all which most browsers will pull in from the right place
automatically.
But we might as well,
tell them where it lives.
That type is image slash X icon rail is icon and H ref is Colin dot ceo.
We don't need to put a slash there because even the H ref within the fabric con link tag is
going to be relative to the base directory.
We're gonna have a script tag whose type is going to be text slash job script char set is
going to equal utf Dash eight and whose source is going to be a public route that we didn't
define yet.
It's going to be called public slash ap dot Js In the future,
lecture will go about rendering static assets like app dot Js on a public path.
But for now,
we're just going to put that reference in there on the assumption that it will exist at
some point and then we want to close that script tag.
Now we want to reference a style sheet,
so we're gonna say link rail equals style sheet type equals text slash CSS and a draft
equals public slash ap dot CSS and then this could be a self closed link.
Then we'll have the head closed and we can move on to the body.
The body tag itself is something that we're going to change.
We're going to add a optional class to it,
which has the variable body don't class.
This will be really important for enforcing page specific styles in our CSS.
Now within the header,
we actually want to add a logo and then a menu.
We say that logo goes here logo is going to be a link back to the index page with a basic
or rail in effect in order reference index page.
We still do want a slash there.
We're gonna add the class called logo.
Now we want to add a menu.
Someone say the navigation goes here.
The menu is going to be an a Norden list with a class of millions.
Each link in the menu is going to be a list item that has an a tag inside.
So I mean,
write a blank one here and then copy it down six times 12 three for five six.
This top link is going to be the home,
so it'll just be a slash The next one is going to be to sign up,
and for now I'll just put a slash him for that one,
and all the others will for them out later.
After sign up,
we want log in,
then dashboard,
then account settings,
then log out.
Now you might be saying it be very strange to visit a website looking the menu and sea.
They sign up in the large in but in the larger out band and then dashboard in settings that
you really should only be able to get to if you are logged in.
So we are going to add classes to some of these menu items,
saying that they should really only be visible if the user is logged out,
such as the log in button.
Or they should only be visible if the user is logged in,
such as the log out button.
So sign up and log in.
Are both going to have a class code logged out.
Only logged out.
People should be able to see this thing now.
Dashboard account settings and log out should have a class called Log in because only
logged in people should be able to see any of those links.
The home button should always be visible to everybody,
so it doesn't need a class.
Now we have the HTML for the Universal Header,
the Universal Footer and are modified index that's going to our helpers file.
Now let's add some new logic that's going to let us wrap these new header and footer around
any existing template to create a full page out of it and what we're here.
Let's also add some logic that's going to let us perform string interpolation or,
in other words,
that variable replacement for any of the variables that we have put inside of our templates
,
whether inside of page templates inside of the header or inside the Footer.
So we're going to modify or get template function.
We're also going to add some new functions for adding the universal templates and doing
string interpolation.
Why don't we start with TheStreet interpellation?
We want to take a given string and a data object and find slash Replace all the keys within
it.
So this helper is gonna be called helpers that interpolate,
and it's going to take a string and an object with keys on values.
First thing is going to need to do is sanity.
Check both of these things,
so we're going to say that string type of strange egos string and has a length otherwise
before to an empty string data object.
It's going to be type of data equals object,
and it's not.
No.
Use the data object or default to an empty object.
Now that we've created these defaults,
we need to at the template Global's to the data object PRA,
pending their key name with Global.
So what this means is,
in our configuration file,
we're going to add a bunch of global's that can be used anywhere in any templates.
For example,
if you remember in The Footer,
we have a global called year created and another one called company name.
But notice how they are reference by saying global dot here created.
That is because here in the interpolation function,
we are going to grab those global's out of our CONFIG file,
add them to the data object that is going to be paid specific or template specific.
Add the global's in,
and then we'll go about performing the find and replace.
So we are just making sure that any time finding and replacing is happening,
we are inserting the global's so that they are available for finding,
replacing on any template at any time.
So we want to say that four for key name in config dot template Global's.
So we're just gonna loop through it.
If config template Global's has own property key name,
then we're gonna add it to the data object.
So we're going to say global dot key day equals config template Global's key name because
to clarify,
we're not adding a global object to the data and then adding these keys as sub keys on the
object were actually adding top level keys called global Doctor something.
So now that we've added those in for each key in the data object,
we want to insert its value into the string at the corresponding place order.
So what we're going to do is cycle through all the keys and the data object and then find
and replace those key names in the template string.
So we're going to say for of our key and data,
remember,
Data now holds all the global's as well as whatever it started with.
We're going to say if data has own property key and type of data key equals strain,
then do the replacement.
So we're going to get the value.
That's what's going to be inserted.
We need to find Is that part in the template where that key is referenced and within the
templates?
We reference these keys by just saying the key name and wrapping it in brackets.
So we're going to look for a string that looks like that.
So it's going to be an opening bracket,
plus the key name and then a closing bracket so you can see what we're doing here.
We're finding that and we're replacing it with that.
So now we're saying that the string equals straying.
Replace,
find,
replace.
Lastly,
we need to return the new string now that all the find replacing the interpellation has
taken place.
Now that we have this general function that's useful for fighting replacing data,
we want to modify this helpers that get template function to actually use this
interrelation function any time that it is returning a template to a user who is requesting
it.
So we're actually going to modify,
get template to not just taking a template name anymore,
but it taken template name and a data object and then the call back,
and that will allow this function to pass the data object to the interpolation function so
that the find replacing can happen.
So we already sanity checking the template name.
Now we want to sanity check the data object and we're going to do that the same way that we
did down here.
Now,
instead of calling back the string that we pulled from the template,
we now want to do the inter relation on this string before returning it.
So we want to say that the final string is going to Eagle helpers Interpol,
eight string data.
So take the strain of this template.
We just pull it out and insert,
find,
replace any of the data there.
Now we want to call back False and this final strength.
So that's all the variable finding and replacing that we need.
But we still don't have an easy way to wrap these templates that will be getting with the
header and footer that we created.
So we're gonna add a new function for that.
And this function is going to let us add the universal header and footer to a string and
passed the provided data object to the header and footer for interpellation So we are going
to say that helpers that ad universal templates is a function it takes in a string data
object.
And Colback we want a sanity check the 1st 2 parameters the same way we've been doing it.
Now we want to get the header and then we're going to get the footer.
Nothing.
We're going to wrap those around the string that we're starting with.
So we're going to call helpers that Get template.
We're gonna tell it that we need Header.
We're going to provide it the data object that were started with,
and it's gonna pass us back air or the new header straight.
So if there is no air and we got the header strength,
we'll continue.
Otherwise,
we're gonna call back the error that we could not find the head,
our template.
Everything's fine for you to get the footer.
So we're gonna call coppers,
get template,
tell it we need the footer,
passes the data object and expect back and air and a flare straight.
And if there's no air and there is a foot or strength,
we're gonna continue.
Otherwise,
we would call back,
could not find the footer template.
Now we need to add these three strings together.
So we're going to say that the full strength,
all the HTML is going to be equal.
Header string plus the string we started with plus the footer strength.
Then we're going to call back No error and the full strength.
So the way that this function will get used is our handlers will get the template they want
.
Then they'll pass that new string to this helper to have that string wrapped with the
header and footer templates.
Now that that exists,
we should go to our config object and add in the global's that we will need in order for
the interpolation to work.
Sit down below Twilio.
I'm gonna add a new key called Template Global's That's going to be an object that has a
few keys.
It's gonna have happening.
We're just gonna call this app up time checker.
It's gonna have a company name on it will be not a rial company incorporated year created.
That will be 2018 and then a bass euro and in staging mode,
that base your l is going to be http clones last last local host,
then whatever port we're using up here in our case 3000 and then a slash.
We can copy the template Global's down to production as well.
You just want to fill in the base your l to be whatever your production,
your l is for us.
It will be local host 5000.
Now let's go back to our handlers.
Look at that index handler that we wrote and modify it to,
rather than just returning.
The contents of the index dot html template actually get indexed html wrapped with the new
header and footer.
So we still want to reject any method that isn't get.
But now we want to start preparing some data for that string interpolation.
It's gonna happen.
So prepare data for inter poor relation.
Remember that the header is expecting some page specific content to be passed to it.
So the global dot base you're always going to come from the convict.
But the title and the description as well as the body class and some others,
whatever we define within index dot html are going to need to come paid specifically so
they don't need to be defined in the handler for us.
We're just gonna use a few examples and save our template.
Data is an object Head title is this is the title had description is this is the meta
description Body title is going to equal Hello,
Template ID World and body class is going to equal index.
So let's go use this new body title that we just added We're gonna go to index dot html and
instead of saying hello,
world,
let's just say body title.
Just as we used this new variable,
we can use any variables that we define.
If we define food in template data,
it will be made available as food here by convention and just to keep things organized.
I am doing dot notation so that we can keep track of which things are data that should be
inserted similar in the head and which things are going to be inserted somewhere in the
body.
But it doesn't really matter.
You can name them anything that you want.
Now that we've named them,
we want to read the template as a string as we have already done.
So we're gonna go helpers don't get template index.
But then,
instead of just calling back the string,
we want to call that ad.
Universal templates function toe Add the header and footer We're gonna call helpers,
add universal templates.
We're going to pass it this string that we just got from the get template function and then
we're gonna pass it All this template data that we just created And remember,
our interpolation function is going to be smart enoughto add in the global's automatically
.
So we don't need to worry about redefining the global is from the configure object back
here.
They're gonna be inserted,
always available in any of these templates.
So this template could use one of the global variables if it wanted to.
So after we pass in the template data,
we want to expect back in air or the new full string of the whole page So then,
if there's no air and there is a strength,
we want to return that page as html.
And so we'll just call back 200 the string and HTML.
Otherwise,
I want to call back the same error as below 500 undefined Ph.
D mail.
So let's start our at back up and see if these headers and footers are being added and all
the variable replacement is happening Going to make you get to the base.
You,
Earl,
this is what we saw last time.
This time through an air says call back is not a function in the helpers file.
So I'm gonna go to the line that they're talking about 1 30 And as you can see,
we're getting tripped up right now because the get template function is being called in the
old way.
It's being called with template name call back where we've actually now inserted this data
object.
So we need to make sure that anyone who's calling get template is actually calling template
name data and then call back.
So back in our handler,
when we're calling,
get template to get the index from before,
we need to make sure that we're passing in template data there as well and then stating the
callback.
So let's try that again.
I'll send the request and there we go.
You can see the source that is coming back here.
We have ahead.
You can see that this is the title and then the APP name is getting inserted dynamically
using that find replace.
There's all those static assets that don't exist yet.
Then,
as we scroll down,
we can see that the footer has 2018 not a real company,
Inc and that the body has Hello,
template ID world.
So all the find replaces happening.
And also this whole header and this whole footer are being wrapped around the template
content.
The template is only this one line.
Hello,
template ID World,
Let's go ahead and viewed in the browser.
And here we are.
Look,
a host 3000.
We have these links,
we have Hello Template world.
And then we have a footer.
Obviously,
we're gonna make this look a bit better as time goes on.
But we know that the string in population and general use of templates is working fine now
.
So now we can move on to the next lecture.