in this lecture,
we're going to set up the ability for the users to log out after they've locked in.
Unlike creating an account,
logging Out doesn't need a page of its own.
But we do need to create a page to send users to after they've successfully logged out.
And so,
rather than being a log out page is going to be a you have been locked out page that is
going to be called session deleted,
as you can see in our server router session slash deleted his handlers dot session deleted
so we can go to our handlers and create that new one using the last one as a base.
So we're going to say that session has been deleted.
That's going to be handlers.
Session deleted.
Still,
only going to accept to get the title was going to be logged out.
The description is going to be You have been logged out of your account and the body class
session deleted the template.
We want to get his session deleted and everything else could be the same.
Now we can create that template.
Templates slash session deleted dot html,
like the others are just walking through what we written here.
Title was logged out.
We tell them you've been logged out of your account and there's just a call to action but
saying Log in again.
Now we have to make some modifications app dot Js To bind any log out button so that it can
trigger an actual log out and buy logged out.
We need to send a request with the http method delete to a P I slash tokens to actually get
rid of that token,
and then we want to delete it from our local storage and front and library.
But first we need to update our header so that the law go but and has a specific I D that
we can bind to.
Now that that set up,
we can update this file.
It's walking through what's happening here.
A session delish Inform Handler has been created.
A log user out function has been created apt out,
log user out,
which actually sends the delete that I mentioned a moment ago and then redirects users to
the session slash deleted page that we just created.
We also have added a app dot bind log out button function,
which is going to automatically bind the log up and in the menu so that any time it's
clicked,
the app dot love user out function gets called now that logging in and logging out should
be working.
We can also demo the fact that the menu should be expanding and contracting based on the
state of the user.
So let's go ahead and start the app up and try this all out,
going to refresh the log in page,
get rid of this console and then log in like I did a moment ago.
As you can see now,
I am logged out and the only things that I can see on the menu are home.
Sign up and log in.
That's what we want.
I'm looking in with four and 51234569 and this is a password.
Now I'm logged in and I'm taken to the checks all page.
But if I return to the home page,
I'm still logged in the checks.
All page doesn't exist,
and so we can't see much there.
But the home page exists,
and we can see that my links appear have changed.
I now have home dashboard account settings and log out the log out.
But it's something I can click.
So I click it and I'm sent to the You have been logged out page,
which means that I clicked the log out but in a post was made to delete my token,
and my token was actually deleted from the server.
And then I got rid of a client side as well.
If we try to log out the active token,
you can see that it doesn't exist.
So logging out and logging in as well as the disappearing in reappearing menu items all
seem to be working fine so we can move on to the next lecture.