now that we have users creating checks through the G Y.
We want to set up the dashboard page,
also known as the check slash all page,
so that we can list out all of their existing checks.
After we do this,
we're going to allow users to edit their existing checks and delete their existing checks.
But for now,
we first need to list them out so that they can click on them so we can see that check
slash all make a the dashboard page matched to handlers dot checklist.
And that is a slight typo I should have said checks list.
So we're going to go to the handlers file and create that hammer.
Now this is the dashboard view checks.
I'm going to copy this down.
Call it checks Missed.
Again.
The data method is get the title.
This time is just going to be dashboard and the body classes checks list.
The template it should be fetching is checks.
Let's everything else can remain the same.
Now let's create that template Touch templates slash checks list html Open it up.
We're gonna pay set in here.
You can see this is pretty bare bones This is a title and a message telling them that they
can create up to five checks.
But then there is the beginnings of a table,
which list out in Table Header is the method protocol,
your L estate in details of checks.
But then we don't actually see the checks listed.
That is because in the clients,
I.
J.
S,
we are going to write some JavaScript that allows us to programmatically add rose to this
table If the user has checks and will write that in a function that will load after the
specific page loads,
that start of function will also hide this.
Create a check blurb.
If the user already has five checks,
if they have no checks,
it will show them this blurb.
You have no checks.
Please create one.
Let's go ahead and update that APB Js file and we can go to the checks list functions.
And here we see the logic that is Onley loaded on the checks list page.
There is a whole bunch of logic in here about pulling in the existing checks of the user
has using a get to a P I slash checks and then programmatically adding rose Tr's and sells
TDs to the table to list out all the checks that the user might have.
And here we see the logic that if they have less than five checks,
we can go ahead and show them he created check call to action button,
and if they don't have any checks,
we can show them the You don't have any checks message.
And he created Check Goto action.
Now that all that logic is in place and the CSS has been updated as well,
we can go ahead and restart the application and navigate to that page to see if our
currently logged in user has any checks so well,
we load this and there we see the check that we created earlier.
It's a put to twitter dot com with HDP its current status up,
and we can click here to view,
edit or delete it.
But that won't lead to a working page yet because we haven't created the edit a check page
yet.
We can,
however,
create a new check which will take us back to the form,
and I'll create one for facebook dot com with some random parameters.
Create that check and as you can see I was now sent back to the dashboard,
and the check that I just created is included in this list here,
since it was just created and no one has checked it yet.
The state is currently unknown.
After its check.
The first time,
the state will either be up or down.
So this dashboard,
which is where you're taking to immediately upon walking in,
seems to be working fine.
If we didn't have any checks here,
we would see the message here saying you don't have any checks.
Please create one.
We can still navigate to the account settings page and all that.
But the dashboard is the main launching point for the real meat of the application.
So now we can move on to next lecture and finish up that last template.