Now we've reached the lecture for the last template that we have to create.
As you can see,
throwing together these templates does take some time,
but thankfully,
we've reached the end.
The last thing that we need to do is create a new template that will allow us to edit a
check.
We can see that this route already exists on our about er.
It is called checks slash ed it and it maps to handlers dot checks edit so we can go to our
handlers,
copy down one that we already have and now edit it for checks at it.
So trains this comment to edit a check the title.
It's going to be checked details,
and the body class will be checks at it.
The template that should be fetched is checks.
Edit.
So now I'm going to go and touch templates.
Checks.
Edit html Great that Open it up and now we can paste in form or get huh?
This full template,
as you can see it,
is just as big and complicated as the template that allows us to create a new check.
It's much the same,
except that it also includes the ability to delete a check as part of another form.
As you can imagine,
this template needs to be loaded with data when it's presented to the user.
We don't just want to show them an empty form.
And so we need to add logic to Apthe Js that will determine which check the users trying to
view by reading the U R L.
That they're trying to access and then make it request to a P I slash checks using a get in
order to get data about that particular check if the user has access to it and then load
that checks details into this actual form.
So let's go ahead and update after Js.
And as you can see,
there is now a load Checks Edit Page function,
which makes a request to a P I slacks,
checks and then fills this form up with all the data about that check so that the user can
view what's there before they edit it.
This includes checking all the boxes programmatically that need to be checked for success
codes and selecting all the right options within the drop downs that are on the page.
Now that this exists,
we can go ahead and we start the app.
We're going to refresh the pace that were on.
It looks like I need to log in again now.
I'm logged in.
I want to view the check we created for Twitter and we can see all the details.
The check I D.
Was programmatically created and it's not edible.
The current state is listed here,
and it's not edible,
But everything else is.
For example,
let's add on 400 that's changed a protocol to https.
Now we're going to save.
The changes have been saved and we can go back to the dashboard and see that those changes
have pushed her.
So now all the checks exist.
They're all being checked.
That's why even the newly created Facebook one from the last lecture now has a state of up
instead of unknown.
So all the background workers are actually performing the checks as they're supposed to.
The users,
if we had any would really beginning SMS alerts and our application as a whole is working.
But before you would go live with an application like this,
you would want to build yourself some kind of admin interface so that you can cheap track
of how many users you have and the different logs for the different checks,
and generally keep tabs on your system without having to parse through all your data files
manually.
So in the next section of this course,
we are going to create a command line interface that is actually an admin tool that will
let us walk around inside of the data and view different metrics about our server and about
the application as a whole.
So we can kill this lecture now,
and after the section review,
we will move on to a whole new section.