All right,
We've reached the end of the front end part of this course.
Hopefully for all you back end Dev's that wasn't too tedious and lengthy.
I try to move pretty quickly through the things that I don't think would matter very much
to a no Js Dev like the CSS and much of the Front and JavaScript.
Although we did a bunch of no Js work setting up the new handlers,
modifying the server to be able to serve static assets like images and CSS and JavaScript
files and fabric cons from the file system,
we actually didn't use any new modules in this section.
We just continue to use a lot of the modules that we were already doing things like console
things like file system.
We used FS a lot when we were reading in the content of the templates.
We use it again when we were reading in the content of static assets in order to serve them
.
And reading in these assets meant we were in some ways using buffers.
And so although we didn't need to require the buffer module,
we were creating and using buffers quite a bit,
and we were also using path quite a bit in order to normalize the paths to our public
directories in order to figure out how to read and those static assets and normalize paths
to our templates for dinner,
etcetera.
And,
of course,
we used many Global's and some other modules that we didnt explicitly need to require in
the next section,
in which will be building a command line application were actually going to jump in to a
bunch of new node modules that we haven't seen yet in order to build out that command line
interface.
So without further do,
we can move on to the next section,
which is building a CLI.