in this lecture,
we'd like to build out the responder for the man or help commands.
If you remember,
when the user asks for man a manual or help,
both of those event binds are going to call the same responder cli dot responders dot help
.
And so we want to fill out this function with a typical man page that you'd see in any
terminal base advocation.
When the user asked this question,
they asked man or they ask help.
We want to list out all the commands they're allowed to ask,
as well as a semi thorough description off that question so that they can see it in more
detail.
Remember,
the only time of user is going to be saying man or saying help is if they really don't know
what commands they should be entering or if they're unclear of the syntax.
And so let's define all the commands that they are allowed to ask.
I'm going to go down to where we codify the inputs earlier,
and we're going to base this new object on that order,
Ray,
I'm gonna pay set in here,
and then we're gonna have to modify it because that was the contents of an array,
and now it's going to need to be the contents of an object.
The let's take out these commas and entering some empty strings so each key of this object
is going to be a command.
And then the value of that key is going to be a description of that command.
We're also going to rearrange this border a little bit so that the order representing it to
the user is most relevant to them.
So the exit command we're going to say,
kill the CLI and the rest of the application for the man page.
We're going to say that this is just what you did right now show this help.
Page Help is an alias of the man.
Command stats is get statistics on the underlying operating system and resource utilization
list users is going to show a list of all the registered Take a UN deleted users in the
system.
More user info is actually going to need to be modified in its key because the command
they're entering isn't simply more user info.
It's more user info,
dash,
dash and then a user i d were using these brackets to represent a variable that the user
should put in Any admin looking at this should understand that this command needs them to
modify the bracketed portion with their own variable.
So more user info dash dash user i D.
It's going to show details of a specific user.
Let's checks is going to need to be modified in its key to list checks up dash dash down
either.
Or so we want that to show a list of all the active checks in the system,
including their state.
The dash dash up and the dash dash down flags are both optional.
For more check info,
we want to modify the key to be dash dash check I D and we'll say,
show details of a specified check for list logs.
We can leave that key as it is.
Show a list of all the log files available to be read,
compressed and un compressed.
For more log info.
We want to change the key so that the user knows they need to specify Dash dash file name
and we'll say the value is show details of a specified log file.
So that's all the commands and their descriptions now that we have that prior to presenting
this to the user.
We actually want to do a little bit of formatting.
Typically,
when you see a man page or a help page,
you see horizontal lines all the way across the screen.
A bit of a title section saying This is the man page,
etcetera.
And so we want to include that kind of thing.
So we're going to call some functions that will let us build a header.
We want to show Header for the help page that is as wide as the screen.
So we're gonna build a function called cli dot horizontal line.
And that's just going to draw a horizontal line across the console in whatever with the
console currently is so recalling that,
and then later on,
we're gonna build that.
Next we want to write a title called CLI Manual,
but we wanted to be centered on the screen,
so we want to skull cli centered and then pass it the string cli manual.
Then we want to call another horizontal line and then some vertical spaces,
so cli vertical space and we want to pass it to because we want to vertical spaces now you
should be getting an idea of how these functions work or is on the line.
Draws a line centered,
should center some text on the screen and then vertical space adds some returns.
We will go back to actually writing those functions in just a moment.
But for now let's assume that they're doing what they should.
Now that we have the header in place,
we want to show each command,
in other words,
looked through this object and right out each thing that the user is allowed to dio.
So show each command,
followed by its explanation and wait and yellow,
respectively.
So let's start looping through this object four fr key in commands.
So we're looping through up here.
If commands has Owen property key,
then we want to continue.
We want to say that the value equals commands keep.
So now we've simply got in,
whatever the value of that he was,
and we want to build the line that we're about to write to the console.
So we want to say that the line equals some text that makes it yellow,
which will fill in a second plus the key,
plus the end of that expression.
If you remember.
We are writing colorful things to the console down here.
So I am actually just going to copy what we're doing here all the way up to the M after the
number.
And I'm going to pace that here,
but change the 34 to 33.
Now.
I want to go get the rest of that string after the percent s because wherever the percent s
is what allows console log to take whatever is here and put it between these two escape
coats.
So I'm just going to take the end of this escape code and paste it in here.
Remember,
you can simply right this way to the console log.
You don't need to have escaped codes and then follow that up with the string.
You can just wrap the string in the actual bits and pieces of the escape codes,
and that's what we're doing here.
Now we want to define how much padding that we need.
So we want to say padding is going to equal 60 minus the length of the line that we just
defined here because we want to say that Boren line equals that and the padding equals 60
minus line.
The length.
You know,
there was a little bit confusing that we just repeat here we're defining a key.
We're wrapping it in escape codes to make it colorful.
That is defined as line.
We're getting the length of that line and we're subtracting it from 60.
So we know how much padding to put after this key,
so that everything that we right after this key ends up vertically aligned.
And this will make more sense when you see this all right,
into the console.
So we want to do a four loop now.
So for I equals zero,
I was going to be less than padding I plus Plus,
we're going to add a space onto this line until it equals 60.
So all of these lines,
once we get through with this loop,
are going to have a length of 60 so everything that comes after them is going to be aligned
.
So we have line plus equals value,
So we're actually adding the value on to the end.
Now we're going to log out the line and we're going to enter a vertical space after all of
this is done after the four loop is complete and we've logged everything out.
We want to enter another vertical space,
and then we want to end with another horizontal line.
Before any of this is going toe work,
we're actually going to need to write these functions that we used appear horizontal line
centered and vertical space.
So let's create the vertical space first.
CLI vertical space is a function,
and it takes in the number of lines that it should write to.
The console lines should be a number,
and it should be greater than zero if not,
is going to default toe one.
So now we're going to do another four Luke for I equals zero.
I is less than the number of lines I plus.
Plus,
we went to console Log an empty string,
which will,
in effect include a carriage return and move on to the next line.
Right now,
we want to create a horizontal line across the screen,
so we want to say CLI horizontal line is a function doesn't take in any inputs.
Before we write dashes across the screen.
We're going to do figure out how big the screen is.
We want to get the available screen size.
For that,
we're going to say that the whiff is equal to process standard out,
not columns.
Now we're going to build a line which starts,
is an empty string and then do yet another four loop,
adding on dashes to that string into them.
It's the same with as the number of columns of the screen.
So for equal,
zero eyes less than with I plus plus,
we want to upend a dash to the line string.
And then,
after the four loop is done,
we want to just log it out so console dot log the line.
Lastly,
let's create the function that lets us create centered text on the screen.
You can probably anticipate how we're going to do this.
We're going to need to get the width of the screen just like we did before.
Calculate how much padding we should have on the left side of whatever we're writing.
Put in the padding,
using a for loop and then write the text and it'll be centered.
So Seelye dot centered is going to take in a string which we're going to have to sanity,
check straying equals type of string,
equal string and has a leg.
If so,
we'll take it.
It's trimmed version so that spaces on either side of it.
Don't mess us up when we're trying to center thinks or we're gonna default it to an empty
string and go ahead and write it anyway.
So just like before,
we need to get the available screen size.
So I was gonna copy that from here.
Now we need to calculate the left padding there should be.
So you are left.
Patty is going to equal math dot floor.
So we're gonna round down the with of the screen minus the length of the string that were
writing to the screen.
So everything that's left when you subtract the text from the with that's already there,
then divided by two and rounded down.
Obviously,
this won't be exactly centred if there aren't the correct number of otter,
even pixels and we're rounding down.
But this will be pretty close,
just entered every time.
So then we actually want to put in left padded spaces before the string itself.
So again,
I'm going to start with an empty line.
That's just an empty string.
Then I'm gonna do a four loop.
I equals zero eyes less than left padding because that's the amount of padding we're
putting in I plus plus.
And then for each path of this loop I wanted to add on plus equals another space.
And after the loop completes,
then at the very end,
I want to add on the street.
So the patty comes first and then the string and then I want a log out the line.
So now that all that is in place,
let's go ahead and start this up.
But I'm going to make the screen bigger so that you can really see starting up the
application.
I'm gonna ask for help and it wrote out what we wanted it to.
We have a dash line going all the way across screen.
We have sent her a text telling us that this is the CLI manual.
We have another dash line and then we have keys and values the keys in yellow.
The values in white key value,
key value,
key value and we terminate by adding another space at the end and then a dash line all the
way across the screen.
And so anyone who needs help figuring out how to use this application can simply type man
or help and get this output and the next lecture.
We're going to move on to writing the response two stats,
which will be another pretty output like this that will give users stats of the current
operating system usage and all that kind of stuff so we could move on to the next lecture.