in this lecture,
we're going to fill in the responder for the stats command.
There a number of stats that might be useful for an admin,
but we've chosen a few common metrics related to resource utilization memory,
CPU,
etcetera.
When user enters the stats command,
we want to build something similar to what we did for the help command that is,
create an object and then cycle through the keys in that object,
printing out one stat at a time.
We're going to fill in this section sealed.
I don't responders dot stats.
The first thing that we're gonna want to do is compile and object,
Uh,
stats that objects just going to be called var stance and that will go ahead and fill in.
The keys will come back to the values in just a moment.
First key is load average,
and then we're going to do a CPU count free memory.
Current Medlock memory pique My locked memory allocated keep used as a percentage available
.
He allocated also as a percentage and finally up time.
That is the number of seconds that the system has been up.
Now imagine that we have filled in all these keys with corresponding values after we do so
we actually want to create a header the same way that we did for the man page.
So I'm just going to copy what we did up there and paste it down here to create a header
for the stats.
I'm pasting that in.
And rather than having the title cli manual,
we're going to say system statistics.
Now we're gonna log out each stat,
but this,
too,
is going to be very similar to what we did in the last section.
So I'm going to grab the four loop from here,
as well as the vertical space and horizontal line that we did afterwards.
I'm gonna use it down in dysfunction rather than for Barkey.
And commands were going to do for Barkey in stats the object above.
If stats has own property key,
then we'll continue.
We're getting the value the same.
We're creating a line that's also a 33 to make it yellow.
We're creating padding that is 60 minus the line length,
and then we're going through each line and adding that panning and at the very end,
we add the value after the padding and log out the line,
followed by a vertical space.
When we're completely done,
we add a vertical space and then end with another horizontal line.
So before we move on and actually start filling out these stats,
let's just see what this looks like.
I'm gonna start the at backup when asked the question stats and you can see it through an
error.
And that is due to the fact that we're still getting the value as commands key when really
it should be stats key.
Let's try that again.
Just gonna make this a little bit bigger so you can see the center header start up.
Ask it the stats question and there you have it.
You can see the keys,
and now we just need to fill in the values.
I'll kill this.
Move this back over to make some room.
Now that's fill in each one of these In order to get the load average of the underlying
operating system as well as the CPU,
count the free memory and the up time seconds,
we're going to have to use a module called OS.
We haven't actually required that at the top yet,
and so let's go do that now BAR O.
S,
which stands for operating system equals require OS.
Now that we required that module,
we can go back down and use some of the built in functions for that module to get this data
that we want.
The load average is going to be available at os dot load a V G.
That's a function that you have to call,
and then we actually want to join the resulting array with a space.
That is because this load average that comes back as a return value of this function is an
array which would then need to be joined to make it into a consistent strength.
The CPU count is going to be available to us at os dot CPUs CP use and that's gonna come
back.
It is an array as well,
specifying details about each CPU.
We want to just get the length of that array,
which would tell us how many CP use are in the system.
Free memory is available to us at OS Don't free mammoth,
and that's a function as well.
Lastly,
the up time is available to us at os dot up time,
and that is a function that we call and then for convenience.
We're just going to add on the word seconds so we can start the at back up,
see the results of this OS module.
I'm gonna ask you the stats question and you can see this is the load.
This is the CPU.
Count the amount of free memory and the number of seconds that the system has been up.
Of course,
the results will vary for whatever system you're building on.
The rest of these metrics are going to be available to us in a different package.
A different no Js module called V eight.
As you know from the early lectures note is built on top of V eight,
but it also provides aviate module that gives you some low level metrics about the runtime
itself.
We can access these metrics with far V eight equals require V eight.
We're gonna go back down.
The current Matlock memory is going to be available to us at V eight dot get heap
statistics and then a key of the resultant object that gets returned from that function.
The key is my locked memory.
Similarly,
we can just copy this down to the next section The peak.
My lost memory is going to be available at V eight dot get Keep statistics peak underscore
Mel Locked Underscore memory.
Now the allocated heap used is actually going to be a metric that we create as a percentage
of the total keep size available,
so we are going to use the same metric scaffolding.
V eight dot get keep statistics dot used heap size,
But then we actually want to divide that by another metric,
which is v eight dot get heaps statistics dot total heat size,
then wrap this,
multiply it by 100 then round the result.
So math dot ground and what math is rounding is 100 times the used heap size divided by the
total heap size.
So what that's going to end up with is a rounded percentage of the allocated heap used.
We can take this same basic scaffolding of one thing divided by another times 100 then
rounded and paste it down below.
We're just going to change the metrics involved for available heave allocated.
We actually want to use the total keep size as the numerator and divide that by heap size
limit,
then we'll multiply by 100 round it.
So that's going to give you the percentage of the total heap size limit that has been
allocated.
Both of these metrics,
the allocated heap used as a percentage and the available heave allocated as a percentage
will be important to understanding the usage of the heap.
So those air all our statistics,
let's go ahead and start the at backup and asked the stats question and we can see all of
these metrics coming through.
So now our Stats command is working fine,
and we can move on to the next lecture.