in this lecture,
we're going to build out the more user info command now to review the syntax of this
command.
Let's look at the man page that we built.
I'm gonna start the app up and call help.
We can see that the more user info command is supposed to be specified by the admin as more
user info and then two dashes and then a user I d on the assumption that they are using
this syntax correctly.
We can actually look at the text that they sent in.
Split this string in half on the two dash is and then we'll know that everything to the
right of the two dashes is the user I d.
So let's build out command responder.
That way I'm going to scroll down to where we fill it in the placeholder.
For more user info,
get rid of this console dot log.
Now the first thing we need to do as I mentioned is get the I.
D from the string that's being provided to us in the str variable.
So the first thing we'll do is split this string into an array,
so the array equals string split,
and we want to split on Dash Dash.
So we're going to say that user I d equals the second element in the array as long as the
second element in the array,
as long as the second element in the array is a string with a length greater than zero.
So we're going to say that our one should equal a string and are one train length.
It's greater than zero.
If so,
we will use it.
We'll just trim it.
First order for two.
False Now,
of course,
we only want to continue if we have a truth.
E variable defined otherwise will just ignore it.
Now that we have a user,
i d.
Let's look these air up using the data library,
we're going to do data read,
read from the user's collection by this use radi and then we're gonna expect back an air
and user data.
If there isn't in there and there is user data will continue.
Otherwise,
we will do nothing to the first thing that we need to do before returning the user.
Data to the console is removed the hashed password because in our scenario,
even the admin using the CLI tool doesn't really have a good reason for needing to see the
hash password of the user,
and so we're going to delete that from the user data object before locking it out.
Then we want to print the Jason object of that user with text highlighting by default.
When you log out a Jason object,
it's just going to come out whatever text color your console has set,
and it won't be pretty printed in any way.
When you log out large objects,
they're very hard to grok.
And so,
rather than do that,
we want to print out a vertical space.
And then,
rather than use consul dot log,
we're gonna use consul dot de IR and passed that the user data object and then also passed
consul dot the i r a configuration object telling it colors are true.
Then another vertical space to see how this logged out Object looks that start up the APP.
First,
we're gonna ask it to list users.
Now that we have a user,
I d make a phone number.
We can ask it a follow up question.
More user info,
dash dash,
this phone number and it just printed out this object As you can see,
it's not just a long Jason String.
It's actually the Js object with text highlighting now that the more user info command is
working,
we can move on to the next lecture.