in this lecture,
we're gonna build out the responder for the list checks,
command.
Now let's checks actually takes in two optional flags.
So let's review the syntax by looking at the man page going to start up the f and then say
help.
Let's checks allows you to state dash,
dash up or dash dash down,
but both are optional.
If you don't include either flag,
it would just show you all of the checks.
So let's go ahead and start building this out.
I'm gonna remove the default Consul look.
And now the first thing we want to do is just list out the checks.
So we're gonna use our data library list checks.
It'll pass this back in here and an array of check i d.
S.
If there's no error and check,
I DS is truth E and check.
I d.
S has a length greater than zero.
Then we're going to continue.
The first thing that would do is enter a vertical space before we start running through
each of these checks to separate out this response from any other previous responses.
Now,
for each of the check I d.
S,
we want to run through a loop that will give us the check I d.
Individually and then we want to read the data for that check I d.
So I want to read checks and pass it.
Check I D and expect back in error and check data.
Now,
this point,
we need to decide whether or not this is a check that should be included in our response to
the user we wanted to fall to false.
So I'm gonna say include check.
It's going to default to false.
Now this push the string down to lower case.
They said that lower string equals str to lower case if they included dash,
dash up or dash dash down with upper case,
we don't want to miss it.
So we're gonna push everything down to a lower case before we go looking for those strings
and we want to get the state of the check,
but default two down.
So the state of the check is tape of check data.
State equals strength.
If so,
we'll use it.
Four will consider it down.
If it doesn't have a state yet then the state is unknown.
But for the purposes of this admin tool,
we will consider that state to be down,
and then that is the state that we're going to filter on to know whether or not to include
this check.
But when we write out the checks,
we want to lump in unknowns with the downs.
So we also want to get the state in a way that will default to unknown if there is no state
.
So we're gonna save our state over unknown is going to equal this same logic,
but defaulting to unknown.
I was gonna add a comment here,
Get the state default to unknown,
and you'll see the way that we use these two different variables in this next section.
So if the user has specified the state or hasn't specified any state,
include the current check accordingly.
So we're going to say that if the lower string index of dash dash state over the state that
we defined here can only either be up or down,
the word unknown isn't there were trying to find out if when the user specified to list
checks,
they included the straying dash,
dash up or dash dash down.
So if lower string includes dash dash state,
pour the lower string doesn't include the words down or up.
So we're going to say or lower string index of dash dash down equals negative one and lower
string index of dash dash up equals negative one.
Then we want to log this out.
So in other words,
if the state that we read from this check when we were defaulting to down is included in
the flags that the user set in the console as an input,
then we want to continue.
The only other case in which want to continue is if the user didn't specify dash,
dash down or dash dash up,
in which case all things should be included.
So now we want to create the line that we're gonna lock out so far line equals is going to
start with I D and then check data I d.
Then we're going to spell out the method and the u.
R l and the state of the check.
So we're going to say check data method to upper case and then check data protocol.
Then we're going to add on colon slash,
slash and in the U.
R.
L.
Lastly,
we want to include the state and for that,
we will use state or unknown because we were writing these out.
We do want a lump in unknown things with the down checks,
but we do want to specify that they were actually unknown not down.
So now we're going to log out this line and then include a vertical space afterwards.
So that's the whole this checks function that started up and try it out.
It's a list checks,
and I'm not gonna specify a flag.
You can see we're hitting an error that checks.
I DS is not defined at 2 37 That is because this array is returning.
Check I.
D.
S and I am calling it checks I ds.
So we need to correct that.
Start the at backup,
try again list checks with no flag,
and you see that we have a number of checks.
They're all spelled out with their i d method protocol colon slash,
slash and then the or L and their current state.
You can see that some of them are down and some of them are up.
So let's ask again,
List checks dash,
dash up.
Now we're just getting these three that are up.
Let's try a list checks dash,
dash down and we're just getting the three that are down.
So everything seems to be working fine.
We can kill this application and move on to the next lecture.