in this lecture,
we're going to fill out the responder for the more log info command.
Let's take a look at the man page for that command.
We can see the more log info works just like more check info and more user info.
One of the main differences,
though,
is that more log info allows you to put in the file name of an existing compressed log,
and then it will decompress it for you and spit out the Jason.
Since we know we're going to be dealing with parsing these Jason strings,
we're going to need the help for library that we created a while back.
So let's include it up in our dependencies.
Far helpers equals require dot,
slash helpers.
Now,
let's go back and fill out this responder.
We're going to start by using the more check info function as a base.
So we're gonna pace that in here.
The first thing we're going to do is get the log file name from the string.
What?
We're still going to split on dash dash.
So rather than check,
I d.
We're going to get log file.
Name is the second element in the array after the split,
and we're going to continue if there is a log file name,
but the rest of this is going to be different so we can get rid of everything in here.
We want to start by putting in a vertical space,
and then we want to decompress the log file.
So we want to say logs decompress.
Remember the decompression function that we wrote here?
But we never really tried out.
We're trying it out now,
so we're gonna call logs,
decompress,
and they were gonna pass it a log file name and expect back an error and string data,
which should just be the string of the log.
If there is no air and there is string data we want to continue otherwise will ignore it.
The first thing we need to do he's realized that the log is a whole bunch of individual
Jason lines upended after each other,
went after the other with new line characters.
And so,
in order to read out the output of this file,
we need to first split it up line by line.
So we're going to split into lines which will put it into an array.
We're going to say that this array are are is string data split and we're going to split on
this slash n new line character that's going to give us an array of strings.
So we're going to say array for each Jason String because these air still individual Jason
strings Now,
for each one we want to create an object from that string line.
So far,
log object equals helpers.
This is where the help is.
Class comes in,
parse Jason toe object,
and we're going to pass it the Jason String if we got an object back from that line.
So if log object and the string of five version of that object does not equal an empty
object,
then we want to continue.
Now we want to use console dot de ir because we want to pretty print out this object.
We're gonna pass it log object and the configuration object telling it that colors car True
.
Lastly,
we wanted to add a cli vertical space.
You know this test out this function,
which will in away test out this decompression function at the same time,
we're gonna start the at backup.
We're gonna first list blog's.
Then we're going to take one of these log file names was gonna take the one at the top,
and I'm going to say more glogg info,
Dash dash and then that file name.
As you can see,
it spat out the UN compressed data from that walk.
If we look up this log file name in our file system,
this is a base 64 G zip file.
So our decompression function must be working fine because it's getting the Jason out of
here now.
In this case,
there was only one line inside of this compressed log,
so let's pick a larger log to use.
I'm going to use this file name,
which I happen to know is a much larger file.
I'm gonna enter the command again,
More log info,
dash,
this file name and we can see that it has three separate lines which represent the three
different lines inside of that file.
We can see that it was,
of course,
for the same check getting checked over and over again.
And each time the state was up and there was no need for an alert.
So that is the complete functionality for our cli tool.
We've created several different commands that an admin might use in order to find out more
information about the system or about the users or about the checks or any of the events
that have happened in the past through the logs.
And now we can move on to the section review to talk about all the different modules that
we used in this section.