No,
J s,
as you may have heard,
is built on top of the chrome V eight JavaScript engine.
So to properly understand what no Js is and what it does,
we must first take some time to understand what V eight is,
how it works and what JavaScript engines are in general.
To do that,
it's worth taking a step back and defining a few key concepts around this topic.
First.
First,
it's worth understanding that modern day computers Onley understand machine code,
and that machine code looks nothing like the programming languages you may write.
Machine code looks more like a string of ones and zeros than it does a Java script or C
plus plus or PHP your ruby.
So most programmers never attempt to write raw machine code instructions.
Instead,
the right quote unquote high level programming languages.
High level languages are those that abstract away the close to the metal operations that
the CPU is doing,
like loading,
adding,
comparing and storing numbers to and from RAM and let the programmer create variables,
perform operations,
execute functions and the like.
The terms high level and low level are ambiguous and relative,
though if you ask a visual basic programmer.
Ruby might be low level if you ask a ruby programmer,
C might be low level and to those who work closely to the metal in assembly in machine code
.
All of these are high level languages.
In reality,
languages lie on a spectrum,
and there's no clear point where low level ends in high level begins.
But one thing is for certain JavaScript C plus plus ruby and all the other popular
languages are completely foreign to the computer itself.
It doesn't understand them.
So broadly speaking,
one or more things need to happen before a computer can execute.
Run ah program.
Written in a modern programming languages,
this is the work of three main groups of software.
Compilers,
transpire Eilers and interpreters.
There are also others,
such as assemblers,
but those air outside the scope of this course compilers.
They take source code that is code written in a programming languages and turn it into
machine code or assembly or by code or object code or something else.
Low level so that the computer can run the program easily,
or only has to take a few short steps to run it.
Compilers create,
execute a bles.
These are programs that are ready to be run,
transpire,
alors,
take source code and generate more source code of another type.
Common examples of trance filing include turning coffee script into JavaScript or turning
Less or SAS into CSS interpreters.
They take source code and directly executed themselves.
They do this by performing real time intermediate steps,
such as compiling pieces of the code as it goes and optimizing aspects of it for
performance.
So you can think of interpreting as compiling,
plus executing.
Except interpreters.
Don't leave behind any artifacts.
Any executed will programs like the compilers dio.
So what is V eight?
Well,
via is what we call a JavaScript engine and JavaScript engines are interpreters for
JavaScript.
V eight compiles JavaScript down to native machine code and executes it.
It also optimizes the code at runtime to make it faster.
V eight is a standalone application,
but people rarely interact with it directly.
However,
if you've used the chrome Web browser,
you've already used V eight.
If you've opened up the console and debug JavaScript on the client side,
the rebel you're interacting with is V eight.
There are a couple other job Skip engines you're probably familiar with if you've ever
built an app in react native or if you've ever used the Safari Web browser you've been
interacting with.
A JavaScript engine called JavaScript Core V eight was written by the folks at Google in
order to power Chrome,
while Java script core is written by the folks at Apple largely to Power Safari.
There's another popular engine called Spider Monkey,
which is developed by Mozilla and is used inside of the Firefox Web browser.
Spider Monkey and V eight have alternately both been used inside of Mongo DB so that Mongo
can understand that Jason commands you send to it.
Interestingly enough,
Spider Monkey was actually the first ever JavaScript engine,
and it was written by Brendan Eich,
the same guy who invented Java script.
He was working at Netscape,
and he wrote Spider Monkey in 1996 to be used inside off the Netscape Navigator Web browser
.
In 1998 Netscape created Mozilla,
the current parent of Firefox.
There's also a JavaScript engine called Chakra,
and if you've ever using Microsoft's Internet Explorer or Edge Web browsers,
you've used chocolate before.
Modern Web browsers perform a lot of tasks,
but many of them include parsing and executing JavaScript.
So in a way,
you can think of a Web browser as an application that looks at JavaScript files and sends
them to an embedded JavaScript engine like V eight so that the job script can be executed.
So in this way,
browsers are built on top of a job script engine.
Now that you've got that concept down,
weaken,
turn to look at know J s a different type of application that is also built on top of a
JavaScript engine and functions much the same way.
No Js looks at JavaScript files and then sends those files to an embedded JavaScript engine
V eight so that the JavaScript can be executed.