congratulations.
You've reached the end of the section on building a CLI command line application.
In this section,
we used a few modules that we had never used before.
The first was events.
Obviously,
we built this command my tool very differently than we had built the A p I,
rather than passing information around functionally when the user interest texts as an
input in the command line that ends up emitting an event that we need to bind to.
All of that was done through the event a meter through the event class.
One of the other modules that we introduced here was the OS module.
This is the one that we used in order to get information such as CP use and load averages
when the user's asked the question stats in order to respond with specific metrics,
we pulled in this module and we also put in the eight module to get information like keep
statistics.
Lastly,
to read input from the console,
we implemented our CLI using the read line module,
and this allowed us to read in text from the console one man at a time and then send that
text to an input processor off our own design.
These four new modules were introduced here,
and there will be several more modules introduced in the coming sections.
Coming up,
we're going to turn to a section on debugging and adding stability with test coverage.
So without further ado,
let's move on to the next section.