in this lecture,
we're going to add on a number of unit tests so that we can show the different type of
testing that you could do,
or at least the different kinds of assertions that you can make in your unit tests.
The first thing that we need to do is push these unit tests into their own file because
this file that were using to run the test is getting a little bit too crowded.
And if we added in a whole bunch of unit tests here,
is just gonna be too big.
So let's go ahead and create a separate file to hold these tests.
We're going to say touch test slash unit dot Js and let's just cut these out and paste them
here for now,
and we'll come back and clean that up in a bit later.
But we want this file to work much in the same way.
And so,
rather than defining these unit tests as an empty object here,
we can actually just coal at tests set up is an object and then add on the unit tests as a
dependency.
So at Tess unit going to equal require dot,
slash unit because we're in the same directory now.
We can actually move both of these dependencies to that new file as well,
because our test runner is of our own creation and we're not using any dependencies here,
So all the rest of this should work the same way.
It's now going back to this new file recreated.
Just gonna add a comment at the top saying that this is the unit tests and we have our
dependencies.
For now,
we have helpers and assert we're actually going to need a few more.
We're going to write some unit tests that deal with the libraries and here,
particularly logs and the example debugging problem and helpers,
which we've already included.
So let's include the logs bar logs equals require.
Then once again,
we need to back out and up into the live directory toe logs and now far example debugging
problem.
It's going to equal require once again into the live directory example of debugging problem
.
Now that we have all these dependencies,
let's go ahead and create a holder for these tests.
So we're gonna call it for unit,
and then when we defined these tests,
we don't need to call AP Test unit.
We just call unit the richest,
adding on keys to this unit object when their time and at the bottom of file.
As you would expect,
we just need to export the tests to the runner.
Marjo dot exports equals unit.
I'm gonna leave these three tests that we've defined already here and then add on some new
ones That's ready Test that says that logs dot list I should call back and array and a
false air.
Remember that logs dot list should go through the logs directory here and give us back in
array of file names.
And since we're doing their back pattern,
it should give us false as the first parameter that calls back.
So we're going to create this test with name logs,
got list,
should call back a false air and and a ray of log names.
And this is a function that,
of course,
take done.
And within it,
we're gonna call logs that list just as we would normally we're gonna pass it true,
telling it to include the compressed files and it's going to pass us back an air and log
file names within this call back we want to assert that the air is false.
So we're calling assert dot equal are asserting that two things are equal air and false.
Next,
we want to assert that something is truth e.
We want to assert that log file names being an instance of an array is Truth E.
And so for that you can call assert dot OK,
by okay,
they mean truth e.
So log file names instance of array should be a true the assertion.
Next,
we can add on as many assertions as we want,
but we want to call one more.
That is also asserting that log file names length greater than one should be true.
Thea's Well,
if all these pass will call the done,
if any of them don't pass it,
they'll throw.
That will get caught by our test runner,
and it will come back as an air.
Next.
Let's call another function within the Logs library That's called truncate,
and we should say that truncate should not throw,
even if the i d that we send to truncate doesn't exist to remind you what truncate is.
This is a simple function that truncate,
say log file.
It takes in the log i d.
It tries to truncate that file on the assumption that it lives in the Logs directory and
then calls back either no air or an error.
But it should not throw if there's an error because the log file didn't exist,
it should call it back,
but it shouldn't ever throw.
So we're going to write this unit tests to assert that that's true.
So logs truncate should not throw if the log I d.
Doesn't exist.
So let's say that this is a unit test name logs truncate should not throw.
If the log i d.
Does not exist,
it should call back and air instead.
Now you can see having these comments up here and having the names of the test in plain
English is a bit redundant.
When you're reading your tests,
you should certainly feel free to leave off the comments.
So this is going to be a function that takes in done like the others,
and within it,
we are actually going to call an assertion first,
and that assertion is going to be assert dot does not throw,
and within it,
we're going to define a function and within it.
We're going to place logic that were asserting will not throw.
But when you call does not throw,
you actually need to assert that it does not throw a specific thing.
And so we're asserting that it does not throw a type air.
So we're going to call logs truncate.
And this idea is going to be I do not exist because that doesn't exist and we expect back
an air within it.
We can actually assert more.
We can assert that the air is okay because the air should be truth EOC this point and then
we can call done.
If any of this throws,
it'll be caught by this does not throw,
which will itself thrown air,
which will be caught by the test runner.
Now,
this is something that does not throw.
Now let's do an example of something that actually does throw.
So I'm gonna copy this down.
Change the description,
too.
Example.
Debugging problem dot in it should not throw,
but it does.
We know that example.
Any button problem from nearly lecture does nothing except throw because it tries to use
the value of bar which doesn't exist.
Let's change the test name to example,
debugging problem in it should not throw when cold.
We're going to wrap it and it does not throw.
But then call example debugging problem in it and then done afterwards.
Let's run these tests and see what happens knowed test.
And there we have it.
We have to failures get a number,
should return to which we already knew was failing.
And then example.
The problem in it should not throw.
When called.
The first details that we could look at is the same as before.
We were expecting the number to,
but it was actually number one.
But then an example bucking problem dot in it.
It's actually going to show us the error that got thrown that caused the issue in the first
place.
So for us,
bar is not defined,
which is the root of the issue.
In example,
T button problem.
This is also an example of how errors can bubble up through many different tries and
catches within.
No Js.
This is one of the reasons that debunking issues in node can be extremely complicated and
tiresome because you think you're dealing with one file,
but an issue is actually buried deep within another and is bubbling all the way up through
the try catch that you put somewhere else.
So those are some examples of different ways that you can assert things to be true.
You can assert things to be truth EU concert things to have a certain value.
You can assert that logic should not throw.
There are many other ways to use the Assertion Library as well.
In the next lecture,
we're going to go on to writing some integration tests to actually test the outcome off our
A p I that we built so we can move on to the next lecture.