in this lecture,
we're going to create some A P I tests.
And by that I mean we're actually going to start up our application and then make http
requests to the application and check the responses.
For example,
will want to verify that the Ping route really does return a 200.
And by doing that over,
http,
this kind of integration test or and toe end test is testing that all the intermediary
steps like processing the user's request and being able to spit out Jason.
Those must be working if the A p I.
Itself is returning the expected result.
So we're going to start by creating another file next to the unit dot Js file.
But we're gonna call it a p i dot Js So I'm going to say touch test ap i dot Js open this
up and say that this file is going to contain the A P I tests.
This is going to have a number of dependencies.
The first is going to be the app itself.
Like I said,
we need to start up the app which is not something that we've done from a test before.
So we actually need to require the index file from the root of our directory.
We need the assertion library as before,
we're going to need the HDP module in order to craft these HTP requests and we're going to
need our config object.
The config object is going to tell us which port that we should actually make our htp
requests to Before we fill out the rest of this file,
Let's actually go to that config object and create a separate configuration block just for
testing.
So I'm gonna copy or a staging environment and say that this is going to be the testing
environment when it paste it down here.
And the only difference that we want to make is that we want when in testing mode.
Http port to be 4000 https to be 4000 and what the armed name is then going to be testing,
But everything else can stay the same.
So now when we start our app in testing mode,
it's gonna be running on 4000.
Or to put it another way,
if we see the application running on 4000 we know that it's in testing mode,
not staging we Of course,
though need to change this key to be testing as well.
Okay,
now we actually need a way to tell the application to run in testing mode.
When we started up,
we could do note off equals testing,
but we want to just be able to call no test that having to remember anything else from the
command line.
So I'm going to goto our test runner here,
and the first thing I'm going to do is override the node off variable.
We do this by just saying process that,
um dot note off equals testing.
Now,
no matter what somebody said when they did note on and then node test,
we would be overriding it to testing we.
So we are enforcing the fact that when these tests run is going to be starting that
vacation up with note off equals testing.
Which means anyone using the config is going to inherit this configuration object as
opposed to the staging or production ones.
Okay,
Now,
let's go back to a P I.
D.
J s.
We want to,
as before,
create a holder for the test.
This one,
we're gonna call ap I instead of unit,
and it's just going to be an object and down at the bottom we're going to export the tests
to the runner.
So Marjo dot exports equals a P I.
Now let's write some tests.
All of these tests are going to include making requests over http.
So rather than crafting http requests by hand each time,
let's just make ourselves a little helper.
We're gonna call this our helpers equals an object,
and then this function is going to be helpers.
Make get request,
and that's going to be a function that takes in a path and a callback.
We want to configure the request details and then if you remember,
send the request afterwards.
So let's configure these details.
This is just going to be for simple get requests.
And so we don't really need to do anything fancy here,
since they're always coming to our a p I on local host,
the protocol is always going to be http post name.
It's local host port comes from the config file Port is config.
Http port the method it's going to be get the path is going to be the path that gets passed
its function when the headers are going to be content type application slash J saw.
That's all the configuration we need to do.
Then when we actually send the request,
we're gonna call rec equals http module request,
Pass it the request details and expect back in response object which we can simply call
back to whoever called us.
Then we call wreck end,
which ends it off.
And we're done.
So that helper will allow us to write these tests a lot easier before we make that first
http requests We actually need to include the app and started up.
So we want to say that the main in it function should be able to run without throwing.
So we're gonna write this like we did those other does not throw functions before we want
to call a p i bath in.
It should start without throwing.
It's going to be a function that takes done.
We're going to call.
Assert does not throw,
and within that does not throw of type there.
We are going to just call app in it and expect to Colback after in it is done booting up
after in it is done.
We want to call that done the one thing you might be remembering from our index dot Js file
.
Is that app in?
It doesn't call back anything at all.
It does three different things.
One of them is set off by 50 milliseconds.
So in order for this test to ever reach the done,
we're going to need to add a callback toe apthe in it.
Let's do that now.
Within the function declaration,
we're gonna include call back and then within the set time out,
we're going to call callback because that should be the last thing that happens out of
these procedures.
Lastly,
when we call the execute,
we can't just invoke up in it because it is expecting a call backs.
We have to call app in it and then pass it a callback that doesn't do anything,
but one of the other things you'll notice is that we are requiring the application here and
then asking it to start up,
which means we don't expect it to start up the moment that we require it.
We don't expect this file to self execute.
We expect it to simply export itself and wait for us some third party to call the minute
function.
That's not how this primary index file works.
This index file defines its own in it and then calls itself,
which means our tests would never reach this point.
It would never be able to call in it because the moment that it included of our at this
logic would run through and self execute.
So we need to use a trick that's built into node to tell this file on Lee to self execute
under certain conditions.
And those conditions are that someone is invoking the file directly,
such as going to the command line and calling node index dot Js.
If they're invoking that directly,
that means they're trying to run the application.
If this file,
on the other hand,
is being invoked in directly,
which means some other file is including it,
our test runner is including it and then trying to invoke it.
It should not self execute.
So let's change this comment to self invoking only if required directly.
So let's say if require dot main equals,
equals equals module,
then we want itself execute.
Now this is just a quirk of the syntax built into knowed.
What this is saying is,
if you're invoking me directly my module is going to equal required at Main.
If this file is being invoked from another file and that other file is the one that's being
called from the command line,
these two are not going to equal each other.
And so this initialization function will never happen.
So let's go back to a p i dot Js.
We've modified in it and told in it not to start unless we tell it to when we're invoking
it from a separate file,
such as we're doing here now that we've started the application up and we've waited for it
to start all the way up,
we can make a request to Pink.
So let's say that this test name is slash Ping should respond to get with 200 and this is
going to accept a done and it's going to call our helper.
So it's going to say helpers that make get request,
the path we're going to tell it to hit it slash ping,
and we're going to expect back a response when the response comes back.
We're going to assert the equality between the Status code,
which is available at Rez Status code and the number 200 which is the same as saying status
code should equal 200 during assertion error.
If that's not true and they were gonna call it done,
let's make another request.
Let's copy this down.
Let's make a request to a P I slash users.
Since we're making a ball,
http,
get request.
With none of the required fields,
this should call back of 400 to us.
So make a request to a P I slash users.
We want to say that a P I slash users should respond to get with a 400.
So I'm gonna modify this path a p I slash users and assert equality between the status code
and the number 400 to hammer this example home.
Let's make a request to a random path,
and we want to say a random path should respond to get with 404 We want to make a get
request to this,
uh,
shouldn't exist.
And then we want to assert the equality between the status code we get back and 404 Okay,
so those are all the integration tests that we need.
As you can see,
it's very easy to get the status code.
It would be just as easy to get the body text or the response headers or anything else from
these requests.
And if you did so you could validate all kinds of things.
If you want to validate that,
the payload that the AP eyes returning should include certain keys or should have certain
values.
You could do that there.
If you wanted to scrape HTML pages and assert,
you know there should be a head or there should be a body or there should be this Dave or
this span inside of this HTML.
You could parsi html and do that there.
In this way,
these kind of a P I or integration or end to end test can be used to validate your HTML
pages there,
Jason responses and everything else that you're a P I or your user facing Web app is doing
.
Before we call this,
though,
we actually need to modify our test runner just a bit more because we're not including the
A P I test.
So we want to say that AP tests a p I equals require a P I and then,
at the very end of the test,
report after we console log that we're ending the test report.
We want to kill the process by calling process exit zero.
This is because within the A P I test,
we have started up the application and there's no where else in the code that is explicitly
stopping it.
So this will explicitly stop the app from continuing on in any form after the test report
runs.
Let's go ahead and run these tests and see what happens.
I'm calling node test and you can see that we have a number of issues here.
We have the areas that we expected in get a number and the debugging problem in it.
But we're also getting that there's an issue with the get request to paying which there
shouldn't be.
And it looks like that is a similar error that we've hit before.
Http is not a supported type.
We actually need to make it.
Http Colon.
So I'm gonna edit that here.
We're gonna clear out these tests and run it again.
Okay,
Now,
this is looking good.
We're seeing a lot of green,
and we're also still seeing the blues and pinks and yellows that we're locking out when
we're booting up the application.
That is because the application is being started up by the test runner.
It runs through all these tests and is telling us that there are two failures and it's the
same two failures that we experience before.
Get a number,
an example debugging problem.
And so all of these seem to be running fine,
and that's all we need to go over.
A Sfar is adding tests and debugging and glinting to our application.
If this was a production application,
you obviously want to go through all of your files,
all of your library's all your functionality and write tests all over the place for
everything that you can.
The more test that you write,
the more solid your application is going to be and the more easily and quickly you'll be
able to tell if and when you do accidentally break some functionality in the future because
your test will start failing,
so now we can move on to the section review