in this section on stabilizing your application,
we used a few new node modules that we hadn't before.
The first is the D bugger,
the debunker we used when we wanted to step through our application to be able to pinpoint
exactly where an issue was occurring.
We used break points to be able to walk from point to point,
using the continue flags.
And we also stepped into the rebel that lives inside of the debunker and used it to inspect
the current value of variables at the moment of execution.
The bugger is very useful when you're diagnosing difficult problems,
especially raise conditions or anything related to that.
The next module that we used extensively was errors as we went over.
There are many different types of errors in No Js,
grouped into different categories like evil,
heiress in tax range,
reference type in your eye,
and then a whole host of system errors and user specified errors that we triggered
ourselves as well as airs from the Assertion module,
all those taking together or a lot to deal with.
But we went over some ways that you can try and catch different errors so that they don't
kill your thread and take down your app.
But then,
as mentioned,
you can use the bugger to jump deeper into any issues that you're experiencing to try to
figure out where that execution is hitting a problem.
The last module that we introduced here was assert,
assert is the Assertion library built into know J s.
A lot of people include third party libraries when it really isn't necessary.
Assert includes a whole bunch of functionality out of the box.
We use the ability to assert equality between different values,
assert that things should not throw when they're called and assert that things or truth e
using a certain Okay.
As you can see,
there are a number of other assertions that you can make,
and these taken together wrap up much of what you need to be able to do to right robust
unit and integration tests.
Most unit and integration tests are simply asserting equality or asserting that thing
shouldn't or should throw.
Now that we've gone over these,
we could move on to the next section in this course,
which is all about performance,
and the next section we're going to go through how to tweak your application to make it
faster.
How to diagnosis performance issues and have to get the most out of your underlying CPU and
memory resource is so without further ado,
we can move on to the next section.