in this lecture,
we're going to talk about how to use no Js cluster module to spread the work of your
application across all the CPI use available on whatever system you're running on.
Doing that is going to make some major changes to the way index dot Js works.
So I'm actually going to create an alternative index dot Js again and I'm gonna call this
one index dash cluster dot Js.
So I'm going to copy index dot Js to index dash cluster dot Js,
and that will make the modifications to this new file.
And when we started up,
well started with this one.
In order to use the cluster module properly,
we actually need to require to new modules cluster and Os OS is something we used before to
get information about the underlying Cebu resource is and we're gonna use that again to let
us know how much of a cluster we can build.
So let's require cluster equals require cluster and let's require us bridge equals require
os.
When you start up your app on multiple cores,
it is the same thing as starting multiple versions of your app.
So there's certain things we don't want to be running multiple times even though we're
spreading this application across multiple cores.
We don't want our CLI to be running across multiple cores.
We don't need to give inputs to for different See ELISA for running on a four core system.
Similarly,
we don't want our workers to run four times as much.
We set our workers to run at the interval that we thought was appropriate.
We don't want those to run any faster,
so starting four of them on a forecourt system would actually get four times as many
workers running so four times as much stuff happening as we intended.
Instead,
the only thing we really want spread across all of our course is what our server is doing,
which is taking in requests As the server takes in requests.
We want the load to be spread across as many courses possible so as many Htp requests could
be processed per minute as our whole system resource is will allow.
So I'm just going to reorganize this section here a little bit.
I'm going to move the cli and the workers to the top of this innit function,
and I'm gonna put the server at the bottom.
So when node starts up,
it's going to start up in the normal way.
And that first thread that starts is what the cluster module is going to call master.
Everything else that the cluster module creates all the other threads.
We're gonna be called Forks.
We're forking the process to another corvus CPU.
So we need to write logic in here that can tell if I am the master.
I need to perform this behavior.
If I am one of the forked clusters,
actually perform some other behavior.
So what we're going to say is that the workers and the CLI should start on the master
threat and then all these other forks that get created All these other threads,
though,
should be the ones that startup the server,
which my moved it down here.
So the first thing we're gonna say is,
if cluster is master,
then we want to do these two things here.
So I'm gonna place thes inside of this f so these will get started on this first master
threat that get started up when you boot up the application.
But then I'm gonna put in an else and here we're going to paste in server dot in it and
severed in.
It is actually going to start the HDP server.
I'm gonna change his comment to say if we're not on the master thread,
start the http server up here.
We're going to say if we're on the master thread,
start the background workers and the CLI.
Now,
the changes we've made so far aren't going to work because we haven't actually forked this
thread the master thread at all.
And so this else is never going to get called.
There isn't ever going to be a fork started,
so we have to manually fork this process when it's in Master Boat.
So we're going to say for the process and for that,
we're going to call a four loop and we're going to cycle through this four loop the same
number of times as the number.
Of course on the CPU,
that is where the OS module comes in.
So we're gonna say for Hvar,
I equals zero.
I is less than os dot c p use dot length,
remember?
Oh,
SCP use retardants an array with information about all the CPI use.
So getting the length of that array gives you the number of sea pews in the system.
This is similar to what we did in the stats module.
They were gonna call I plus Plus.
So this four loop is going to get called once for each of the number of CP use in the
system.
And so,
for each of the CPI use,
we're gonna call cluster dot fork as this gets called,
this is going to start the app up again and call this primary file our entry file again.
But when it gets called the second time,
it's going to be a fork,
and it will know that it's a fork.
So when it hits,
cluster is master.
This will not be truth e.
And you'll end up in the else where all they will do is start this server dot in it.
You can see this in effect if we start this up because of the logging that we have in place
for the different parts of the system.
So if I start the app up the normal way with index dot yes,
we can see background workers are running servers,
listening servers listening.
See allies running.
What if I started up with this new file we created Node Index dash cluster dot Js
background workers,
air running.
The CLI is running and now we actually have four of each type of server log the servers
listening on 2000 again again again,
Again,
again,
you might be thinking,
How can these different threads lol,
listen on the same port without having a poor conflict?
That is something node is smart enough to resolve on its own.
These different threads are going to share listening on the same port.
But as requests come in,
they'll be delegated to each of the cores,
and they'll each be able to handle some of the load.
If we go back to postman and sent a request to this a p I.
We see it works,
is normal.
We got a 200 back where it would create a token,
and the FBI is functioning as normal.
Except that all these cores air running.
The one issue with this is being able to test or create tests or created test runner.
When your a p I is taking over,
all the cores can be somewhat tricky.
And so if you're going to implement it.
If you have a good reason to implement cluster module and you have some good functionality
that you want to push over two different forks,
two different CP use go ahead and do it.
But be prepared to re factor the way that you're testing.
So with that,
we can kill this and move on to the next lecture.