in this lecture and the lectures that follow were going to be creating some for lack of a
better term Hello world applications with some of those modules that we mentioned earlier.
But since we're just wrapping up here and these modules aren't necessarily going to provide
value to our existing application,
we're gonna leave our code based as it is,
and then just create a separate photo where you can run these examples on their own in a
standalone way.
So I'm going to create a new directory and call it miscellaneous M I s e within the
miscellaneous border.
The first thing that we're going to demo is HDP two module.
The primary thing that H two B two is able to accomplish out of the box is streaming Web
sockets,
which is something you'd have to implement manually in earlier versions of H two b,
but initially be too.
That's just a built in part of the protocol.
And so we're going to create HDB to client and http do server and show how they can
interact.
So within Miss,
I am going to create touch miscellaneous HDP two,
client dot Js and touch miscellaneous H two B two dash server dot Js.
Let's start by creating the server.
So I'm gonna open up these files and I was gonna add a comment at the top.
Example HDP two server.
As you can imagine,
this is only gonna have one dependency HDP two.
Because that's the only thing we need to demo here,
and that's going to be require HDP two.
The first thing that we would need to do is initialized server.
So in it,
the server we're going to save our server equals http to create server.
And that's just a function that you call on its own.
Just like the other service that we've created in this lecture.
We need to give the servers some behavior that happens when events occur,
then tell it to start listening.
So the behavior that we want to configure is that on a stream,
this is what I was referring to as a Web socket earlier.
But they refer to as a stream we want to send back some hello world H t m l.
So when someone connects on a stream,
we want to send this payload in response.
So we want to call a server on stream and then provide a callback where we're expecting
back the stream and the headers.
Now that we were within the function that's going to get called when a new stream gets
connected,
we can configure what the response should be.
So we should say stream don't respond with status were responding with his 200 and the
content type is going to be text html.
Then we want to end the stream.
So stream and and we'll end it by providing the html text payload that we want the user to
see in the browser or whatever the client is.
So I'm gonna have an HTML opening and closing tag within their I'm just gonna put a body
opening and closing tag and within the body,
I'm gonna put a paragraph,
and inside that paragraph,
I'm gonna say hello,
world.
So,
in response to any of these new stream connections,
we're gonna write 200 status code.
We're going to tell them that it's text html and we're gonna give him this HTML.
Now we need to tell the server to listen on what is pick a port will say port 6000.
So we're gonna call server.
Don't listen 6000.
That's a pretty simple http server that responds with some HTML.
Now,
let's create a client that can interact with this silver.
I'm just going to note that this is an example Http to client.
And again,
this is gonna have one dependency http two equals Require http two to create an HDP
connection as if we were a browser or some other kind of client.
We want to create a client.
The calling of our client is equal to http to dot connect.
And then we'll need to specify the euro that we want to connect to.
In our case,
that's going to be local host 6000 because that's the silver in the port that we've
configured this server to.
Listen on.
Now let's create the request.
If you remember from creating htp requests earlier in this series,
you always have to have some kind of configuration there to tell it what to do.
This is no exception.
So we're gonna call that the request is client dot request and then pass it.
This configuration object.
But we need to configure.
Is that the path which is going to be specified with a colon first?
so calling path is going to be slash because we're just requesting the base directory.
Now we want to tell it that when a message is received,
add the pieces of it together until you reach the end.
So if you remember,
parsing HDP payloads from incoming requests when we're building a P I data that's coming in
is going to stream,
and HDP two is no different.
And in fact,
HDP two is enforcing this kind of streaming thing.
Previously,
when we were creating http,
servers were thinking of the client as something that sent a payload,
and the server is something that received a payload.
Remember,
Now we're configuring the client were telling the client to stream in data from the server
.
That is because HDP to like Web sockets,
opens up a full duplex connection where both client and server can send data back and forth
to each other in these open streams.
So we need to allow the client to read in payloads from the server,
just as we would have the server do from the client.
So we're going to say that the request on data it's going to expect a choke to come in and
it's going to need to start assembling those chunks into a coherent strength.
So we're going to start by saying string is empty and then as thes chunks come in,
we append them to the end of this strength.
Then when the message ends,
log it out.
So we want to say that on end.
So when we know we reached the end of the message,
we can stop assembling this string and just log out the results.
Lastly,
for this request to actually fire,
we need to do what they call end the request.
So call wreck.
And now let's go back to the terminal.
And this time I'm going to create two separate times so that you can see both the client
and the server in action.
In this first tab,
I'm going to start up the HDP two server,
so I'm gonna call it node misc slash HDP two server dot Js.
As you can see,
we get experimental warning that the HDP two module is experimental.
But now we can go to our client and call node MISC.
Http two client dot Js And as soon as I call this,
this client should run through and make a connection to that server.
All right,
so we can see that the client received back this payload from the server.
The server.
We don't have anything logged out because we didn't send any payload from the client.
This HTML,
as you can see,
is the exact same HTML that we told it to send out here.
So if this client was a Web browser or something,
it could make this connection to this server,
open up the stream,
receive this body coming down the stream,
and then render this Web page for the user.
So that is a brief overview of H two B two HB two streams and how you can use no to create
both in age to be to server or an HDP to client,
if you wish.
So now let's move on to the next lecture.