in this lecture,
we're going to go over how to run arbitrary JavaScript inside of a virtual machine using no
Js.
So I'm gonna start by creating a new file in this miscellaneous voter called vm dot Js So
I'm gonna go touch misc v m dot Js Open up this file within here.
I'm going to read a comment that this is an example VM running some arbitrary commands.
We're only gonna have one dependency.
And that is that for VM is going to equal require VM,
which gives us access to the virtual machine built into note.
The first thing we need to do is define a context.
Employed this script to run in a context allows you to find a whole bunch of variables that
will become available within the executing script when it runs out.
So the context for us is just going to include a global called food that equals 25.
Now we want to define the script that should execute.
So we're going to say script equals new vm dot capital script.
No,
everything within here is arbitrary JavaScript and this should be encapsulated by tick
marks.
So I'm gonna put a tick mark at the beginning and at the end of this script,
no one in here we can just write whatever you want.
I'm gonna write that food equals food Times two and that far far equals food plus one.
And that for phase equals 52.
Now we can actually tell the script to run.
And after we run the script,
we can log out the context again to see the results of that script having been run.
So we want to run the script,
which is going to say Script that we defined above don't run in new context and then we
pass it.
This context that we created above remember script is a new instance of V m DOT script,
so it includes a bunch of functions that a normal string would not so script running new
contacts.
We pass it the context,
and then we can simply log out console,
log,
whatever the context is.
Now let's go ahead and run this script.
Note miscellaneous slash v m dot Js You can see it ran,
and then it logged out The context.
The context now is that food equals 50.
That bar equals 51 fizz equals 52.
White is full legal 50 because the context started with Fu equaling 25.
But as soon as we ran the script,
we multiplied food times two to make it 50 bar we got from the existing value of food.
But we added one and phase.
We define statically to 52.
So that is a brief overview of how use the VM.
If you have any reason to run arbitrary JavaScript code either because you got it from a
user,
someone put it in and ask you to run it or because you're trying to run your code in
isolation to debug some issues or what have you A VM might be a good choice.
Obviously,
you need to be very careful when you're running arbitrary JavaScript if you've got it from
an untrusted user,
someone who wasn't part of your team.
But if you're building your own C I c D tool to run your code or prepared for production,
maybe that would be a good use case.
But just again,
be very,
very careful.
If you're allowing users to specify JavaScript that should be executed on your machine if
you want to,
then this is how you would go about doing it.
With that,
we can move on to the next lecture