one of the things that node is very useful for,
but it's not commonly used for is building low level and networking applications.
And that is because it exposes the TCP stack to you So you do not need to build HDP
applications if you don't want to,
you can drop down to the level of TCP and buying two sockets and write messages back and
forth all you want.
In this example,
we're going to create a simple TCP server,
any TCP client,
so that you can see how you would go about building that kind of low level networking
application in the miscellaneous Ford.
I'm gonna create two files again.
Touch Miscellaneous Net dash server dot Js and touch Miscellaneous net dash client dot Js
I've been open up server and note at the top that this is a example TCP make a net,
which is the package that node calls the TCP ap eyes server.
I'm also gonna know that this listens to port 6000 and sends the word poem to clients.
You can guess what the clients are going to send to the server.
They're going to send the word pain now,
as far as dependencies.
We only need the one we need.
Barnett equals require net again.
When you see net in no Js parlance,
you can just think of TCP Now we want to create server we're gonna call of our server
equals net that create server.
The syntax should start to seem familiar to you now,
as the different ways of creating servers all seem to have familiar traits.
And then we're gonna expect back a connection object in the callback.
Now that we have the connection,
we can send the word Paul.
So we want to say that the outbound message the one leaving the server is just a string
called Paul.
And on this connection,
we want to write the outbound message.
But now when the client write something,
we want to log it out.
So connection on data.
So we didn't receive something from a client.
We want to get past the inbound message.
Now that we have it,
we want to get it as a string.
So message string is going to equal inbound message to string.
And then we want to log it out so console log is going to equal.
I wrote How about message and they said message straight.
So it is going to say that the outbound message that it wrote and then it's going to tell
the inbound message that it received.
Finally,
we have to do what we always do.
We just tell the server to listen a port.
So server Listen,
Now let's go over to the client.
That's,
um,
comments at the top here.
We're going to say that this is an example TCP client make a net and that it connects to
port 6000 and sends the word ping to the servers.
It,
too,
is just gonna have the one dependency for net equals require net.
Now we want to define the message that they should send.
So the outbound message again this time is going to be pig.
That's it.
A pop.
Now we want to create the client by saying that bar client equals net.
Create connection.
This is creating connection to a server on Port 6000.
We're going expect back a call back,
and when it does call back,
we want to send the message because that means this connection is open and it's ready for
us to write stuff so kind right outbound message.
Now,
what we've done so far is opened up the connection to this server and wrote a message.
What we can expect is that the server is configured to write back a message as soon as it
receives a message from the client.
So now we need to configure the client to parse out this message from the server when it
receives it in response to what it said to the server.
So we want to say when the server writes back,
look what it says then kill the client so claimed on data we're gonna expect and inbound
message.
And we're going to do just like we did before.
Message string equals inbound message to string.
Now we can take the console log that we did here and really just paste it in.
It's the same log,
except it should say different things.
It's going to say I wrote the outbound message and they said the message string.
But what the client is logging,
and with the servers,
logging should be two different messages.
Lastly,
we need to kill the client.
So we're gonna call client and I'm gonna open up two different tabs and this one.
I'm gonna start up to server,
so I'm gonna call node Miscellaneous net server dot Js.
Now that that's running,
going to go to the other tab and call node miscellaneous net client dot Js and this is
going to create the connection and set it off.
Now we see that the client has logged something out.
The client has said I wrote Ping,
we could see they did and they said Palm,
Now let's go to the server.
The server says I wrote Pong and they said,
Ping,
that is exactly what we were hoping it would do.
So this is how you set up a raw TCP client and server,
and at this point,
we can move on to the next lecture.