in this lecture,
we're going to be going over the basic anatomy of a small node application.
This is not a building exercise.
There's no need for you to write this small application yourself,
but if you want the code,
you can download it from the link on your screen.
This application is just a super small example to familiarize yourself passively with the
structure of a note,
app will be going over all this stuff again as you build your own APS in the following
lectures.
First,
let's start with an empty directory.
This is where the APP is going to live.
This is where we're going to put the primary job script file for this application,
whose name we will pass to know J.
S in order to start the APP,
we can call it anything we want.
In this example,
we've called it index dot Js.
So when we run,
this application would do so by calling node index dot Js from within the base directory.
In other words,
within our terminal will CD change directory until we are inside of the base directory and
then we'll enter that command.
If we entered that command within a different directory,
we would likely need to provide a relative or absolute path to index dot Js so node would
know which file we're actually talking about when we're inside of the base directory.
Note is going to look for the file called index dot Js.
In that directory automatically inside of this index dot Js file,
We can see a few sections comments,
dependencies,
module scaffolding and configuration function declarations and function.
Invocation.
We're going to take a round about way,
but will eventually look at each of these sections in more detail.
First upper comment Block these air pretty self explanatory.
I'm giving the file a title as well as a lengthier description,
and I'm also using one of the much derided conventions of stating the author and date
within the comments as well.
You'll find a lot of developers who hate this tradition today and find get commits to be a
much more expressive way of conveying who was added what to which file and when.
But for this example of just hard coded in my name and the date dependencies,
the logic contained further down in the file is based on having certain variables such as
math,
lib and certain functions such as math lib dot get random number defined.
We don't define these ourselves instead require or import and external file and assigned
the contents of that file to a variable or more accurately,
That imported module has exported a certain object or interface,
and the interface it is exporting becomes available to us at the variable we assigned to it
.
So in our example,
we require a library that lives at dot slash lib slash math dot Js and we assign it to the
variable math lib.
At this point,
everything that the math dot Js library has decided to export has become available to us
within that math lib variable before we move on,
let's open up lib slash math dot Js and see what's going on inside.
This file is very small.
There are some comments that an object is created.
Ah,
function is added as a key to the object and finally that object is exported using the
module dot exports convention.
To put it another way,
an object is defined and then exported to whatever file has decided to require or import
this module.
This includes the get random number key that was on the object.
So back to index dot Js.
We import the math library,
assign it to the math lib variable than further down.
You can see that we use math dot Js is get random number function and that we do it by
calling the get random number key on the math lib variable we assigned to the object when
we imported it.
Note,
however,
that the top variable name to which get random number is a key is arbitrary.
We could have just as easily imported the math dot Js library and assigned it to a variable
called coconut.
And then,
in that case,
we would call get random number by invoking coca dot get random number instead of math lib
dot get random number.
The keys that Matha Js defined are always available to us as they were defined in that file
.
But the variable object that contains them can be named anything we want.
But hold on.
You might be saying we didn't import lib slash math dot Js We only imported lib slash math
without any file extension.
So how come math dot Js with the dot Js extension got imported well That's just a
convenience that no,
it provides us.
When you try to import something,
it assumes that you're either importing that file name with dot Js at the end or that
importing a folder of that name and that folder contains a file called index dot Js.
In that case,
we will import the index dot Js file within that Ford ER.
This is exactly how the next slide works.
You'll see it's importing,
slash lib slash jokes and assigning it to the variable jokes lip.
But if you open up the lib directory,
you won't see a joke.
Start Js file.
You'll see a Jokes directory,
which has an index dot Js file inside of it.
Notice smart enough to know that you intend to import the index dot Js file within the
Jokes directory,
and all you have to specify is the location of the directory itself.
Let's open up the index dot Js file within the lib slash jokes directory and see what's
inside.
The first thing you'll notice after the obligatory comments is that this module is also
requiring something else.
It's important to point out,
though,
that variables such as fs that are defined within this module are scoped to this module and
this module alone.
You notice that the jokes object gets created,
a key gets added to it,
and then it gets exported.
But FS is not defined as a key on that object.
So it's not one of the things that gets exported.
But if you look closely,
you'll see that a function defined within F S.
It gets used within the all jokes function on this module.
So you might be asking if f s never gets exported.
Won't this function break?
If another file requires this one and then tries to call the all jokes function?
No,
it won't break.
This is another quirk of how node scopes variables you don't need to export FS.
It's the know J s equivalent of a private object or function within the module and is only
used internally to that module.
If,
however,
the file that requires this one wants to use FS,
then that file would need to require it on its own.
Either that or this file will need to export it directly to that one.
I'm sure all of this consume a bit confusing,
but it will make more and more intuitive sense over time and with repetition,
will be dealing with this issue a lot.
Now let's browse through the repo and try to find this FS library that this file is
importing and using.
Oops,
it's not there.
Is this an oversight?
No,
it's not there because F S is a module that comes standard with no Js as part of their A P
I.
You don't need to download FS or write it yourself,
but you do still need to require or imported and assign it to a variable.
If you want to use it.
Over the course of this lecture series will be building our applications with many native
no Js modules as opposed to 1/3 party NPM modules,
so you'll become very acquainted with these over time.
Now,
what does this node application do before we look in detail?
Let's just run it and see if you've downloaded the code earlier.
Just CD into the directory and type node index dot Js,
then press return.
At this point,
you should be seeing a new joke printed to your console once every second.
Now you can kill the program in OS X.
Just hold down the control key impressed the letters C.
Other platforms will differ so we can see that this is a pretty ridiculous program.
It just tells us random,
terrible jokes one at a time and sometimes due to random chance,
it repeats jokes twice in a row.
Now that we understand the purpose,
let's go back to the primary index dot Js file in the base directory.
We've covered what the comments in dependencies do,
so let's move down from there.
We can see that this file is also built as an object and has keys added to it.
This isn't for any particular reason,
but I find that using this kind of object literal notation OLN,
for all my files,
keeps things cleaner and makes testing easier later on.
The first sub key that gets defined is a config key,
and within that object,
we define a time between jokes variable that we can use later by accessing the app dot
config dot time between jokes.
Keep it.
We keep scrolling down.
We can see that we define two functions.
One that prints of random joked to the console and one that loops indefinitely.
Calling the first function over and over and over.
Let's look at the first function.
First,
it invokes the all jokes function that is part of the Jokes Library and assigns the return
value to a variable.
What's the return value?
Let's look at Libs last jokes slash index dot Js again.
Here we can see that this function simply reads in the content of a joke.
Stop text file from the file system,
splits the content into an array and then returns the result to the caller.
If he opened up the jokes directory,
we can see the jokes dot text files that it reads in.
Now back to the main index dot Js file in the Root directory.
At this point,
the function we were looking at has imported that array of jokes and assigned it to an all
jokes variable.
Then it gets the length of that array and a signs that length to the variable number of
jokes.
Now it needs to pick a random joke out of this array of jokes,
so it gets a random number between one.
And however many jokes were in that array.
It does that by passing one and the number of jokes variable to the get random number
function that is defined within the math dot Js library,
which has been assigned to the math lib variable.
So it calls math lib dot get random number between one and the length of the joke array,
and the resulting random number gets assigned to the variable random number.
Now we can see that this script wants to get the joke of the joke array,
effectively getting a random joke.
But since a raise in JavaScript start with the position called zero,
not one,
we would need to actually get the joke at the end minus one position,
not the position.
That way we have a chance of getting the zeroth joke,
and we don't run the risk of asking for a joke at a position that is one greater than the
maximum position in the Erect.
We select the random joke and assigned it to the variable selected joke,
and then we log selected joke to the console.
So in a nutshell,
this function uses the two libraries required at the top.
To get all the available jokes,
select a random item from the set of jokes and then log that joke to the console Now let's
look at the other function app dot indefinite loop.
This one seems simple enough.
All that does is create an interval that calls the first function above and does that after
every X milliseconds,
where X is what every number ISS set in the config object to find at the top of the file.
Once this function is called,
the printed joke function will be called over and over again indefinitely.
And as we learned earlier in this example at all times,
the No Js event loop will always have something left to do on its to do list.
In this case,
it will always have another printer joke function to call in the future and therefore this
note app will never exit unless some kind of error occurs.
Now,
at this point,
all we've done is defined to functions.
So when no Js starts and reads this file,
it was see those functions defined,
but it won't call them.
It will read in the dependencies,
since they are defined in the tree.
But the apple actually start running because nothing explicitly started the app that is
left up to the final line that actually invokes the looping function.
All it does is call that function,
which in turn calls the other one once every x milliseconds,
1000 milliseconds,
a k a.
One second in this case to illustrate this,
let's comment out the last line so that nobody explicitly calls any functions.
Now let's start the APP.
As you can see,
it returns you right back to the command prompt and doesn't seem to have done anything at
all.
In fact,
it did do something it read in the dependencies.
It pulled the function definitions into memory.
It started up the event loop,
but then there wasn't any asynchronous code to actually invoke these functions.
So nobody lit the proverbial match.
Nothing got the ball rolling after starting the event loop.
It's all ahead.
Nothing left to do and nothing to do in the future.
So it exited all within a split second.
All right.
That,
in a nutshell,
is a node application.
Really?
It's more complicated than it needs to be,
but I want to show you how require statements work in practice.
However,
practically every know J s application you encounter in the wild is going to be more
complicated in this most will contain more files like it package dot Jason that we didn't
include here.
So in the next section we're going to go over many of the common no Js conventions.
You'll find out in the wild from file structure to coding patterns.
We may or may not be using these conventions later on to this chorus,
but it'll be worth it to go over them,
so you can better understand any random no tap that you may encounter.