In the last lecture,
we used the net module to create raw TCP client and server.
In this lecture,
we are going to do the same thing.
But with the TLS module,
which is actually just a subset of the net module that adds on SSL TLS encryption to those
existing AP eyes and so we don't need to write a whole bunch of new things from scratch
here.
I'm just going to copy what we wrote from Net client and Net server to two new files and
then we can modify those files just a little bit toe add in the SSL certificates.
It's era.
So I'm going to copy miscellaneous net server that Js and in a copy it to miscellaneous TLS
dash server dot Js Likewise,
I'm going to copy miscellaneous net client dot Js and I'm a copied over to miscellaneous
TLS client dot Js.
Now that these to exist,
I'm gonna open up TLS server first and we can start making some modifications here.
I'm to say that this is an example TLS server listens to port 6000 and sends the word poem
to clients rather than having the dependency of net.
I'm gonna have the dependency of TLS and require TLS.
This is gonna be very similar to what we did when we're using both http and https servers.
When we created the a p I,
we did very similar things with both servers except at https added on the ability to use
SL's,
TLS and NET have the same relationship as the HTT,
PS and HDP modules.
Since we need to pull in the certificates we need to use.
These modules were familiar with FS the final system and we're gonna need path to resolve
these paths.
So now,
before recreate the server just like we did with https,
we need to add some server options in our case options.
We're going to equal a route to the key and a route to this certificate.
This is just like we didn't https,
so I'm actually going to go back to lib slash server.
Look up where we got the certificates last time and we're going to use the same
certificates.
So I'm just going to pace that in here key insert.
And since,
like last time,
we are inside of a directory inside of the root folder,
we can leave these paths untouched last time.
We need to leave the lib directory to get the certificates.
Now we need to leave the miscellaneous directory to get the certificates.
But the past that we right here that we resolve with the path module are the same.
So I'm gonna leave those options as is Now we can create the server.
We're gonna call of our server,
but instead of net create server,
it's TLS create server and we need to pass it.
These options before we expect the call back to come back and that is it.
Everything else about this server can remain the same.
It has the same exact behavior as the Nets server.
It's just that since we in Stan,
she hated it with the key and certificate it's going to allow for TLS as a cell connections
.
Now,
I'm gonna go over to the TLS client now and modify this file.
One thing to note,
though,
is since in this example we created thes certificates.
Locally,
they're considered a self signed certificate and when you have a self signed certificate,
it doesn't have the authority of a normal SSL certificate that you would get.
And so because of that we need to include the certificate with our connections when we're
creating our client.
This is only the case with self signed certificates.
If you're using a real SSL,
you're not gonna need to do this.
But for us,
we do.
So I'm actually going to go back to the TLS server,
grab the same dependencies that we just did and paste them here instead of net at the top.
I'm going to say that this is an example.
TLS client connects 2.6000 sends the word Ping.
Now back to the server.
I'm gonna grab these options that we used and paste them inside the client.
We don't need to know the key.
We just need to know the certificate.
So within options,
I'm going to define the certificate,
but I'm going to label it s C A certificate authority and next to here,
I'm just going to read it.
No,
this is only required because we're using a self signed certificate.
Now that we have the options in place,
we can create the client instead of calling net create connection.
We're gonna call TLS connect and,
rather than passing Port 6000 were first going to write the port.
So we're gonna call 6000 and then we're going to pass in the object full of options that we
defined above after that,
sending the message is the same client dot right and in the outbound message.
When the server writes back,
everything else is the same,
so we can leave that there.
Now.
Let's open up two tabs in the console Startup.
The server with node Miscellaneous T.
Alas,
staff server dot Js Now that it's listening,
let's start at the client and have it make that request.
So we're gonna call node Miscellaneous D a last dash client dot Js Again we see the same
output that we got when we created the Net client and the Nets server I roping and they
said Pong in the TLS server.
I wrote Pong and they said,
Pig.
So that's how you create the same thing that you would do with net.
But you created with TLS.
So now we can close this out and move on to the next lecture