In this LTs release of node,
there is an experimental but interesting module called a sink hooks.
A sink hooks is designed to let you track the life cycle of asynchronous operations.
So whereas before we use performance hooks to be able to log out at what time certain
procedures were happening,
a sink hooks lets you automatically understand when an asynchronous function is initialized
,
it will tell you right before it gets called right after he gets called,
when it gets destroyed,
or if it's a promise when the promise gets resolved.
So if you're trying to debug and figure out exactly when certain things are happening,
or you just are unsure if some random library is calling some other function,
you can use a sink hooks to track whether or not a certain function is getting called.
When is getting initialize,
etcetera.
When you're debugging,
a sink hooks can help you pinpoint where an issue might be.
So in our example,
we're going to create a new file and then create an asynchronous resource in this case,
a function that just has a set interval in it,
and then add on a whole bunch of hooks that tracked the life cycle of that function.
Let's go ahead and create that new file I'm gonna call touch miscellaneous a sink hooks dot
Js.
And in this file at the top,
I'm going to say this is an a sink hook example we're going to need to dependencies here.
The first is a sink hooks so we can call a sink hooks equals require a sink underscore
hooks.
But then we're also going to need a file system.
And that is because,
as you'll see when you're tracking the life cycle of a synchronous operations,
you shouldn't use asynchronous operations to track them.
And so,
for us,
using console log is technically a synchronous.
Although it happens really quickly,
it is an asynchronous operation,
so we don't want to log out the data using consul dot log.
We want to use fs dot right sink,
which will write to standard out in a synchronous way,
basically do the same thing is console logging,
but it will block the thread and stop anything else from executing.
So the first thing that we need to do is to find a target execution context for us.
We don't need one.
We're gonna define as false.
If we wanted to use the current contact,
we could pull it from the A six module there.
But for right now,
we don't really need an execution context.
Now,
I'm just going to write and arbitrary a sink function.
So this function is going to be called.
What time is it?
And it's going to take a call back I was going to do is define a set interval.
And when the interval runs,
it's gonna call sf right to sink one,
which is just this in tax of right sink.
And then we're going to say that when the set interval runs the execution context.
So the train execution context that were in when we were writing this message is,
then we can state whatever it iss a sink hooks don't execution a sink.
I d We need to upend a new line on the end.
Then we're gonna call back,
and the thing we're gonna call back is the current date.
We're gonna call this set Interval 1000 so it'll execute once a second.
Now we want to call that function.
So we're just gonna call what time is it?
And pass it a call back and expect back time because once every second this function is
going to call back to us over and over and over again.
So we're gonna call XF right Sink one,
and then we're gonna say that time is time and then do like,
basically,
we're just creating something that will have a whole bunch of asynchronous operations
happening over and over and over again,
and we'll log out what they're doing.
We also just out of curiosity,
want to see what the execution context is at the moment in time.
If you're confused earlier about defining an execution context that will let you know what
those are now,
we actually need to do find the ace in cooks.
So we're going to say that Hooks is equal to an object that it has a whole bunch of sub
functions on it.
So in it,
which takes in a sink,
I d tight trigger a sick I d and resource.
And within here we just want to call fs right sink one and then say that the hook
initialization happened,
Or rather,
the initialization hook got called and we're gonna attach the a sick I d that we got past
and then a new line.
So that is when whatever function were tracking gets initialized now before gets called,
it's only going to get past a sink I d.
So we want to say hook before basic,
i d These are gonna end up in the console just so we can see which order things happen
again After is also going to get a think i d.
So we want to say,
Look after a sick I d destroy is going to get the same thing so hooked,
destroy and then promise resolve which for our case,
we can log it out if it happens.
But it really shouldn't happen because we're not using promises in this case.
Lastly,
we need to create a new instance of the A sink hooks module.
So we're going to we're going to call a sink.
Hook equals a sink.
Hooks create hook hooks a sink dot enabled.
You might be wondering,
Why are we using fs dot Rite's ink all over the place?
Well,
that is because,
as you've seen,
we haven't actually specified which asynchronous resource is supposed to get tracked.
All we've done is set up tracking for asynchronous resource is we need to minimize the
amount of asynchronous functions that are happening in this file.
Otherwise,
we're gonna get locking all over the place because a sink hooks is going to track the life
cycle of all the asynchronous operations happening.
So had we used console doubt log anywhere every time console dot log got called.
It would automatically track the initialization of it that before event the after event the
destroy event and the promise resolve.
But since we would be writing the results of those events using consul dot log,
the act of writing console dot log would trigger more life cycle events.
And so we quickly end up in this spiral of events that trigger events that trigger events,
and our system would soon crash.
So I would advise to avoid using concert out log anywhere in your file when you're using a
sink hooks,
but particularly within the hooks themselves.
Because if the hooks themselves trigger in a sink operation,
you're going to end up in this recursive loop that will quickly run out of memory.
So now that we have all of this set up,
we can go ahead and start up this application,
which is a fairly simple advocation and should just log out what the time is.
But we'll also see the life cycle of this asynchronous function as it happens.
So I'm gonna call node miscellaneous a sink hooks dot Js Looks like we just have a small
syntax error here,
and that is because we didn't actually close any of these open parentheses.
So let's just close those quit this out and try again a sink enable as little typo.
So I'm gonna clear that out and replace it with a sink hook enable one more time.
All right,
now we can see a whole bunch of things coming to the console went after another.
When we stop this and we can look more closely at it,
we can see that during this set interval the execution context is number six.
We have a whole bunch of hooks being fired because of various asynchronous things that
might be happening elsewhere in this file.
But we are particularly concerned about the execution context.
Six because we're trying to,
for example,
a debug what's happening with this set interval for our purposes.
We're just going to follow what is happening with six.
We're getting the before event,
firing the after event,
firing that before again,
the after again,
the before again,
the after again and every time the execution runs is in the context of six.
So that is how you go about debugging and asynchronous operation.
Had we been actually destroying the operation or using a promise,
these other hooks would have been called as well.
The A sink hooks module is fairly complex.
If you're interested in using it,
you definitely want to read through the documentation in detail.
It is also still an experimental module,
and so your mileage will vary in a few versions of note.
From now,
it should be a bit more stable.