in this section,
we went over all of the node modules that we hadn't previously talked about in the earlier
sections.
We began by talking about some deprecating ones that you really shouldn't use.
Or you should at least avoid puny code domain and everything happening in the deprecating
AP I section.
Then we talked about T.
T y.
And how,
while it does have interesting events that you combined two,
you'd be unlikely to have a reason to use it directly.
And we talked about GSM modules,
how they're currently experimental and not yet supporting import,
which kind of makes them illogical to use at this point.
We talked about the tracing module and the inspector module and how you'll need third party
tools to use those.
And we talked about internationalisation as well as C plus plus add ons and c++ adults and
a P I,
and how you'll need to compile a new version of node to make use out of those modules in
any significant way.
After that,
we moved on to case studies of a few specific modules.
Http.
Two were recreated a client and server VM were.
We ran arbitrary code inside of a virtual machine and modify the global execution context.
And we did you DP data Graham were recreated a kind and server and then net and TLS where
we did the same.
We then moved on to the rebel module,
where we showed how easy it was to create a rappel,
and we used a sink hooks to show how you contract the life cycle of a synchronous processes
.
So this point,
that is all the modules.
If you choose to do a deeper dive on any of the modules that we explored here,
just make sure you're using ones that aren't too experimental.
And if you are interested in using experimental modules like a sink cooks,
that might be a good reason to start exploring something beyond the current LTs of node.
The LTs is going to be stable,
but the newer versions of know that are currently under active development might have
resolved some issues that you will encounter when you use the experimental modules.
With that,
we could move on to the final lecture