As you browse through existing node applications and libraries,
you're likely to encounter a number of conventions that many projects use for one reason or
another.
Some of these air prescribed by node itself or in PM while others have been developed in an
ad hoc way.
Others still are only one of many competing conventions you may encounter for the same
topic or issue in this section.
We're going to go over a few of the most popular conventions in use today.
This is by no means an exhaustive list,
nor is it a prescriptive list.
I'm by no means recommending the conventions we go over here.
In fact,
many of them,
like packaged up Jason Files or NPM,
won't be in use at all during these lectures.
Nevertheless,
as you are likely to bruise many node applications in the near future,
I feel your no Js education would be woefully incomplete if we didn't at least peruse the
conventions that many developers use and have used to date.
Let us start with the convention mentioned a moment ago.
The package dot Jason file to illustrate this and the other conventions,
we're going to return to the same sample application whose structure we reviewed in the
previous lecture.
Again,
it currently consists of just a few files and index dot Js and two separate library files
within a lib directory.
As an aside,
this lib directory is a bit of a convention itself,
though you may also frequently see a vendor directory or a note underscore modules
directory as we'll discuss in a moment dependency management.
The package dot Jason file.
If this application had,
one would live in this directory like this,
just sitting in the root of the project inside.
It contains metadata about the project very similar to the data,
such as this description that we've already included in the index that Js file in our
example.
This includes the name,
version and description of the project.
But many types of information may be included in the package that Jason File.
We're not going to deep dive into this because this course isn't about NPM.
But let's look briefly at one of the more important payloads.
Many projects,
including their packaged at Jason,
a list of dependencies.
If we add a list of dependencies to the package dot Jason like so and then run the NPM
install command.
Those projects are going to be installed inside of a directory called Node Underscore
Modules in the root of our directory.
Let's say that,
for example,
I've gotten sick of our jokes.
And so I've decided to find 1/3 party joke module on NPM.
I find the module called jokes,
review its current version and want to add it to my project.
In that case,
I add the name and version Number two are packaged Jason file here and then run NPM install
on the command line now that projects code has been added inside of a subdirectory called
node underscore modules and I can require or import that library,
as I would any other node module that I had written myself.
But note actually provides a helper for this.
Since that module has now been installed in the directory called node modules,
I can require it by just stating the name of the module.
I don't need to write the relative or absolute path to the node modules.
Forger note is automatically going to look for packages in that folder name by convention.
After I run in PM,
install you notice I now have a package dash lock dot Jason file.
This is the feature available on later versions of NPM,
which locks down the exact versions of the node modules you have installed since your
package that Jason File may have specified you dependencies in such a way that they don't
actually specify an exact version for each dependency but less things dollar choose the
newest from a range of possible dependency versions.
Getting node modules installed into a note project is one of the primary purposes of NPM,
which is why it's named as such.
The Node Package Manager.
The package dot Jason file is a primary artifact of NPM and has a number of features and
capabilities that we haven't gone into here.
If a project has a package dot Jason file,
you may also notice a hidden file called dot N P M R C.
This file is pretty simple inside and just contains a token that lets her local NPM
installation authenticate as a given user against the NPM Cloud.
This enables NPM to do things such as download private NPM modules that the user has access
to,
but that an anonymous user would not have access to as far as using these private and
public dependencies.
We've already gone over a few conventions in the last lecture that you require,
or import module is genuinely at the top of the file and that each no Js file generally
requires Onley,
the modules that it individually needs to perform its tasks rather than some master file.
Importing all the dependencies for a project and then passing those modules to other
scripts.
Testing and task ready testing in task running are both quite popular in the note.
Community testing scripts are commonly contained in a slash test directory and are often
triggered or ran by a quote unquote test runner such as Mocha.
If the project you're reviewing has a complex testing C I or deployment CD configuration
and is using a C I C D Runner such as Travis See,
I you may also notice a dot Travis dot yeah mo file in the root directory as well,
which tells Travis C.
I all the configuration that the project needs for the test to pass as well as other
related settings.
Similarly,
if the project is using a JavaScript,
letters such as Js hint,
you may see another hidden file a dot Js hint RC file,
which configures the Java script.
Linder in various ways all of the kinds of tasks JavaScript lending test running C I.
C D operations are often controlled by a general purpose task runner.
The two most popular task runners are a grant and gulp accordingly.
It's quite common to see grunt files and hope files inside of no Js projects,
documentation and source control get into a lesser extent.
Get hub is by far the defacto source control.
Implementation for note get is the underlying protocol in application.
While Get Hub is a SAS provider of cloud based get repositories,
which facilitates easy collaboration among and between teams as resort,
you're very commonly see a doctor get hidden file within no Js applications and modules.
You also see a dot get ignore file,
which,
as its name implies,
hide specified files and directories from source control.
In addition,
since get Hub has fantastic built in support for markdown formatting,
you often fighting,
read me dot MD file in the root of a project.
This file,
which should contain markdown syntax,
is automatically highlighted on the primary project page for a repository,
so project descriptions in human readable metadata about the project often goes in this
file.
The NPM Cloud and PMG s dot org's has adopted this convention as well and automatically
displays the parsed markdown Read me for repositories modules on each packages home page.
Technically,
there can be many different markdown files in any given directory of a repository as well
as subdirectories.
But in practice you're likely to only encounter one.
Read me dot m d file in the root of the project,
and this file is likely to contain the vast majority of the documentation for the project.
Documentation often also takes the form of code comments within JavaScript files,
and a common convention is to use code comments above each function and the at Program
string to spell out a description of each parameter being passed to that function.
This convention plays well and may very well have been born from the use of comment parses
that generate automatic documentation for projects.
You're likely to encounter other code comments of various formats in many places.
Within a note app.
Some developers up to use the at to do line to indicate a feature they're currently working
on or need to work on some also up to use the at author tag to indicate who wrote a certain
line or section.
It's worth noting,
though,
that many other Debs vehemently opposed.
The use of such comments as Gipp commits are a much more robust and reliable way to
indicate who authored what within a given file.
Environments and configuration.
When it comes to application configuration,
no provides woefully few conventions,
if any,
when configuring an application to run on local host.
This issue is of trivial importance.
But once you've gotten application that needs to run in different ways within different
environments on a staging site versus a production site,
for example,
configuration is used can come into focus.
Unfortunately,
there's no given solution that works in all cases,
because much of the configuration of an APP is dependent on the features available within
the environment,
the apple eventually be running in,
and the continuous integration and deployment systems that will ship the app to those
environments here will go over a few of the most popular options.
The first option,
and likely the most popular,
is to start your application with the node underscore arm equals environment name such as
node underscore on equals,
staging or note off equals production.
The command line variable will become accessible within your note application at process
dot um dot node.
Underscore off.
Really any command line arguments set will be available at process dot on dot that variable
name,
but note arm is a particularly popular convention.
You could just as easily call it Food bar equals production to the same effect.
At any rate,
since the environment variable is available within your application,
many developers will create a single configuration file with a switch inside of it.
This configuration file will export on Lee the variables configured for the environment in
question.
Any of the other node files can require that config file,
and the variables they'll see will be specific to the environment they're in.
This is the convention will be using later on in the course,
so we'll dive into how this works in detail much more later.
Don't worry if there's still a bit confused right now.
Another convention that we won't be using but it's still popular is to pass every single
configuration variable to the note app when it starts,
for example,
rather than having a config file that states What DB password is in different environments
.
You would simply pass the DB password to the node app when you issue the start command.
This convention sounds unwieldy and hard to manage,
but it's actually a fairly elegant solution and has a number of benefits.
First for a large project or an open source project.
None of your configuration gets committed to source control.
Second,
you write your code in a much more function away,
and this makes it much easier to write tests.
Third,
when you configuration needs to change,
you just stop the app and restart it with the other variables.
No code changes needed.
Another convention is to use a dot arm file.
This a file whose name is predictably dot e envy and sits in your repo but gets ignored by
source control using a get ignore file.
The idea is you put all your configuration inside of the dot arm file whose format is
similar to Yam.
Oh,
and then your application reads that file.
Ideally,
you're testing and build systems would insert dot arm files into the code base before they
test and deploy it,
and developers would have their own dot arm files living in the repo for their local host
work styles in patterns like PHP,
ruby and python.
No developers tend to code with certain styles.
By far the most ubiquitous and popular style guide is published by Airbnb and is worth
reviewing here.
This is a general purpose JavaScript style guide,
but is very popular with no Js Debs in particular.
Another influence on style comes from the letters that are popular in no Js projects,
namely Js,
hint and Js lint.
These lenders will catch many style issues that aren't of major consequence to the function
of the application.
But our common conventions used,
rather than going over all the styles and patterns here.
Now,
just pay attention to the way applications in this course are written.
Later on,
I'll try to adhere to popular patterns whenever possible.
Error handling,
as you'll see in the coming lectures,
are functions and libraries will take a common approach to error.
Handling this approach has three components.
One air back this another convention popularized by express with the air back pattern.
Every callbacks,
first parameter is an error parameter,
which should come back is no undefined or false.
If There's no error to when writing functions.
We avoid throwing exceptions most of the time,
opting instead to return the encountered error to the collar,
such as through the air bath parameter.
Since no Js is single,
threaded,
thrown exceptions kill the entire application.
So if we request comes sin to your node rest API I,
for example,
and you encounter an errant throw.
An exception,
the entire application will die,
not just the process that's handling that particular request,
but the entire application handling all requests.
If you encounter an error that truly should kill the whole advocation,
it's fine to throw.
But these cases are pretty rare.
Three.
As in browser based JavaScript,
avoid using Global's and polluting the global name space whenever possible.
Many note applications have dozens or even hundreds of dependencies and libraries.
If every library at its own global variables and polluted the global name space,
it would be very difficult to avoid collisions when your application is defining variables
of its own.
So rather than risk collisions,
each module or library should scope there variables to its own module and to its own
functions,
thus avoiding any names based pollution.
You'll see how we accomplish this and other conventions in the coming lectures