[Autogenerated] hello.
Welcome to this model about spring aspect oriented programming after having
been introduced to the main concepts that are used by a.
Opie will move now to effectively demonstrate how to
write code that uses Spring A or B.
So let me further what we're going to do to demonstrate
the effective usage of Spring A or B.
First,
we'll show how spring GOP aspect are implemented using
regular classes and XML based configuration,
then will show how to use aspect.
Yeah,
notations to declare a regular gela classes as aspects will effectively use
the mainspring GOP annotations toe build clear examples.
Our examples will implement or diagonal behavior for normal execution,
or they will implement or tonal behavior.
For exceptions,
we moved to the code and show a few starting spring applications
examples on which we're going to add the spring.
A Opie functionality.
The spring application contains a passenger class having an I.
D.
A constructor, a getter and the two string method.
We would like to simulate the implementation of the dowel,
or data access object design pattern.
The passenger dollar interface declares a get passenger method that
is receiving as argument the I D of the passenger.
We implement this interface through the passenger doll in class.
This one will contain the map of the passengers that have already been retreat.
If the passenger already exists inside the map, we take it from there.
Otherwise we constructed and put it in the map.
For the moment,
we are content to create the passenger with the help of the constructor.
Instead of effectively introducing persistence layer,
we will do this at a later time.
The current approach is enough to demonstrate the spring a Opie
cassettes In order to work with the spring application,
we added This spring dash contact dependency into the poem XML dependency file.
It is enough for the moment will add more specific spring a
Opie dependencies at a later time looking in the AARP dot
xml beings definition file.
We see that for the moment there is one single been introducing the
container passenger doll of type passenger now empty.
The current functionality will only create the context.
Get the best singer that old bean get the passenger with its help,
then close the context.
Let's see how this works.
So we are getting the best singer having i d one and we
would like to introduce the spring.
It'll be functionality with the help of XML scheme are
based with great aspect implementing using regular
classes and configured through XML.
First, we'll add the needed spring A O.
P and spring aspects.
Dependencies to the prom dot xml file will greet the logging aspect class that
will contain a longer as a private field and two methods the before method to
be executed before calling some other method and the after method to be
executed after having called some other method.
What remains to be done in the aspects configuration through XML we need
to add have been corresponding to the looking aspect.
It belongs to the logging aspect class.
We need to add the GOP name space and the corresponding X s d XML is Kmart
definition where we'll find the definition of the a o.
P.
Name space and we add this a Opie configuration.
We declare that we have a new aspect with the i d looking aspect referencing
to the previously defined logging aspect being the point Got has I D passenger
method and its corresponding expression is the execution of any method
matching this pattern a method corresponding.
Tow the com dot parasite dot spring GOP dot example one package.
The metal may have any arguments and may return anything,
and before this point got reference.
Passenger method we execute before method.
After this point cut reference passenger method, we execute the aftermath.
Let's see now how the application works and we're getting the
orthogonal functionality provided by the lower aspect with the help of XML scheme I based configuration.