[Autogenerated] and we'll move now to presenting the aspect oriented
programming key terms To start the introduction of the key A.
Opie Terms will show this code example where we may say that the logging
itself as orthogonal functional T may be considered an aspect.
The action executed before the main function is called
before advice and the action executed after the main
functionality is called after advice, we summarize with the help of this picture.
The main key, a Hopi Terms on aspect,
represents the model Aries ation of a concern that cuts across multiple classes.
Longing is a very good example of an orthogonal or
crosscutting concern in Java applications.
We'll see in the next model that spring GOP
implements aspect Using regular classes,
the scheme are based approach or regular classes and
outdated with the aspect annotation.
The Aspect J Approach ah Joint Point represents the effective execution of
a method where the aspect will be applied on advice.
Is the action taking by an aspect at the particular joint point would see
that there are different types of advice is as before,
after around,
after returning after throwing spring A or B may create chains
of advice is for one single joint point,
and a point cut is a predicated that matches join points on
advice is associate ID with a point cut expression and runs at
any joint point matching that point cut,
for example, the execution of a method with a 13 name and more key GOP terms.
The target object is the object being advised by one or
more aspects would see that spring GOP will create a
runtime proxy for the target object.
In orderto add the aspects to the execution.
Our introduction is used to declare additional methods
or fields for a given class spring.
GOP allows that the advised object receives new interfaces to implement.
You can have a given class that receives additional behavior
at runtime with the help of introductions.
The GOP proxy is the object created by the GOP framework so
that it can add the aspects in the execution.
Springer be provides two ways to create the GOP proxy.
The standard mechanism of proxy creation called J D.
K Dynamic Proxy and AH see Jilib, or cogeneration.
Library proxy will show how both of them act during the next model With ink is
the operation of program transformation that applies the aspect to the target
object in order to create the advised object.
Spring, eh?
Oh peeper.
First weaving at runtime, this picture summarizes the runtime living operation.
The aspect Weaver puts had tohave the base code of the target object
and the program transformation defined by the aspect.
And we'll get the modified coat to conclude the first
model of our journey with spring GOP.
We take a brief look at what we're covered so far.
We demonstrated the need for aspect oriented
programming and how we arrived to it.
We explain the GOP use cases for orthogonal functionality,
including here logging, exception, handling user writes checks,
cashing transactions and tweaking a legacy application.
We define the terms of aspects join points,
advices, point cuts that are, get objects,
introductions.
And we explained the functionality of a Opie Processes and a Opie weaving.
Our next goal will be to put all these terms and
notions in action through code examples. This is to follow in the next model