[Autogenerated] we'll continue now the code demonstration and will show how
to effectively cash the results of current operations.
In order to do this will first demonstrate the execution without cashing.
Then I will introduce cashing through ah crosscutting
functionality more exactly through an aspect and then will
demonstrate the execution with gashing.
We go back to our flights management,
main class and first to retreat the passenger don't improve
bean from inside the spring container.
We retrieved the best singer with the I D one once and
retrieve the passenger was the I.
D one for the second time will debunk the application
and we see how things are going.
We have inserted a break point to see if any passengers is retrieved from the
passengers map and another break point to see if they get by.
The method is called Leslie back the application.
Remember, we are trying to retrieve twice the passenger having the i.
D.
One.
When the method is first cold,
we see that the execution stops where recall get by i d.
So at the first call of the get passenger method,
the passenger is not yet in the passenger's map.
We have retrieved passenger Jim from United States.
We resume the program and we see that for the second time the
passenger hasn't been retreats from the map.
It is the same passenger Jim from United States.
So there is no cashing.
Of course, this is because nobody's inserting anything.
So the already defined passengers map Remember,
we have promised to go back to this problem.
Who should do this, of course,
across cutting functionality more exactly on aspect.
And this is what we're going to do next.
We introduced this new cashing aspic class and we'll provide to
it order three meaning it will have the highest importance in
order to speed up the application.
Winter.
Just hear the get passengers map method In order to make the passengers map
field accessible from outside the passengers that are in class,
we go back to the cashing aspect class We annotated with aspect.
We introduced this cash passenger method and we annotated with the around
annotation Toby executed around the execution of the method.
Calm the parasite.
The spring GOP dot flies management dr DAO dot passenger,
dollar imp dot Yet passenger In this method,
we are first getting the metal Arguments were
effectively running the original method then,
as the I D.
Is the first argument of the original method,
we check if it already exists inside the map.
And if this does not happen, we are putting it into the passengers map.
This is how we are effectively making the cashing into
the AARP dot xml configuration file.
We're inserting this being with the name cashing aspect
belonging to the class calm dot pearl site.
Hot Spring Europea Thought Flights management dot aspect dot cashing aspect.
This way, the aspect will arrive under the control of the spring container.
We kept the same break points, so let's run the application.
This is the first execution of the get passenger method,
having one as argument The passenger was the I.
D one is not yet inside the passengers map.
So it is retreats from the database with the help of the get by de matter.
It is passenger Jim from United States.
We resume the program and look at the second execution of the
get passenger method with the same idea.
One, the messenger is retrieved from the passengers map.
Why?
Because the cashing aspect has inserted it here and we may resume the program.
So we have demonstrated how to introduce the cashing crosscutting functionality with the help of the spring Air Opie facilities.