Welcome back to the advanced course on
Tableau. Today is finally the day when we
get to derive insights from our analysis.
What a journey we learned so many new
techniques and skills in relation to
table calculations in order to get to
this stage and what do we have in front
of us here?
Well we have the five machines that
we're analyzing and we've got the
average idle capacity expressed in
percentage of the nominal capacity for
every machine and the average is taken
for the eight hours preceding to the
hour visualized on this timeline and as
per the criteria in the assignment what
we're looking for is times when the
average spikes over the 10% line.
So as you can see here we're looking for
situations like that which tell us that
the machine has been underperforming for
a substantial period of time and perhaps
that it requires maintenance so these,
these are the observations that we need
to report to the management or to the
client. So let's go ahead and proceed
with this analysis at first glance you
can see right away that this machine
definitely needs to be red flagged, it does
have times and quite often times when the
average spikes above the 10% line.
This machine looks good looks like it's
always under the 10% line. This
machine looks good, this machine looks
good and then this machine has a spike over
here. So that's what you would probably
report off the bat or off, if you're
told to give an inside very quickly but
because we have a bit more time we're
going to go over and above and we're
going to investigate exactly what's
going on.
So first thing that you notice is that
this looks very different to this, right?
So this spike is not just a spike it's
actually a plateau up over here or why
does that happen?
What, what
can the data tell us about this? What
else can we see from here? Is there
anything else we can tell the client or
the management in relation to the
specific spike that might change their
opinion about servicing this machine?
Well what we can see here is very
similar to what we can see here, right?
How does that happen? Why, why are they
and why do they happen at the same time?
So basically what this means is that the
idle capacity here is 0. Meaning that
this machine was working at full
capacity while this machine had to work
at a lower capacity. Interesting,
ok so how about we go and investigate and this
is where you'll see that domain
knowledge or knowledge about the
business which we developed in the first
tutorial of this section is important,
right? So what can we tell about these
two machines?
Let's go ahead and bring up an image so
there's our map right and if I zoom into
the stockyard you'll see that here these
machines which machines are we looking
at?
We're looking at RL2 and SR6.
You'll see that these machines RL2
and SR6 they actually
work on one line right so it's not like
this one works here in this one actually
they actually work on one line and so
what can happen two machines that work
on one line very logically is that
sometimes they might end up in conflict
especially when they're when they come
to this bit in the middle here when they
come to service or coal here so reclaim
coal in this case they were both
reclaiming call because let's not forget
this is a reclaimer. This is a stacker
reclaimer can also stack coal, so when they
get come to work on the coal here in the
middle there might be a conflict they
might not be able to share or might both
not be able to reach the stack that they
need to at the same time and looks like
that's exactly what happened. Looks like
this machine there was a decision made
for this machine to go ahead and work at
full capacity while this machine had to
sacrifice some of its capacity so maybe
work on a different pile of coal
or maybe leave some room for this other
machine because this doesn't look like
it was a random period of time when this
happened this looks like it was planned
this was a planned sacrifice of capacity
how this machine to achieve higher
capacity on this machine with this
machine and we can also confirm that by
looking not at the average but just look at
the idle capacity. So let's for a moment
duplicate this tab and here I'm going to
instead of doing the moving average, I'm
going to just look at the idle capacity
pause and so everywhere it spikes but
here you can see that not only does the
average plateau but also the actual idle
capacity plateaus for both of these
machines right? So you can even look at
the good tons and you'll see that you
see the same situation here. So it's not
cause just by the average it is an
actual observation in the data set so
let's delete this sheet so that is
something that you would include in your
report of course because your assignment
tells you to you would definitely report
this machine but you would also say that
by the looks of it this was a planned
sacrifice of capacity in order to assist
this machine. So kind of cross
a correlation here between the two
machines.
Good, good to see good to observe this as
you can take as you can imagine you
can't just see this from excel from just
lots and lots of numbers but you can see
it when it's visually represented like
this. So that's one of the first things
that we want to mention about the data
something that's you know
we're going over and above.
Now let's move on to the second thing,
and the second thing is even more
interesting than that.
The second thing is we're going to add
trend lines, now we haven't talked about
trend lines yet but it's going to it's a
very good time to introduce them now.
What we're going to do is we're going to
right click the chart and all going to
do is select trend lines show trend
lines
and what this brings up is Tableau
automatically fits a trendline and
basically a linear regression line to
your data and to tell you what where
this whole trend is going what each
one of these charts is looking like. So
I'm going to right click and edit trend
lines and I don't want the confidence
bands you can see here that it's
actually showing you not one single line
but showing confidence line so let's get
rid of the confidence bands we don't
need them and we click OK and right away
what is this trend lines, what are these
trend lines telling us? Well if you look at
the orange machine you can see that the
trend lines pretty flat and if you put
your mouse over, it it will tell you
quite a few things. It tell you the
trend line formula so the coefficient
times hour what what is basically telling
is, it's telling you
whoops, so let's do that again. It's
telling you a linear formula. A linear
regression formula here,
so what's the coefficient for our hours
are x-axis and what is the constant so
where does the line cross the vertical
axis? There's got a p-value here and we're
not going to talk about p-values too much.
It's a more advanced statistics
topic but we're going to say is that
just look out for p-values and
compare them to 0.05 so if your p-value
is less than 0.05 like in this case the
trendline is pretty, like the
result of statistical significant. In
this case, it's a statistically
significant result and basically even if
I look at the formula you can say that
this trend lines pretty flat if anything
it's actually going down means that if
everything else is held constant
everything's progress the way they're
progressing now then by the looks of it
this average is not going to start
increasing at all of a sudden. Here on
the other hand, you can see that the
trend line is sloping upwards and if I
click on the trendline the p-value is
less than
0.0001 so it's definitely, definitely
passes the test statistically
significant result and this upward
sloping trendline what it's doing is
it's telling us that if things continue
their continuing now, they're
happening now then this average or this
chart for this average will continue
increasing and you can actually see that
here you can see that cut is it is
slowly increasing and what that means is
it will keep getting close and close to
ten percent line so the machine will
just keep the will underperform more and
more and more. Then for the green chart
here you can see that the trend line is
pretty flat but we can't it doesn't even
tell us anything just because we can see
here that the p-value is quite high, it's
nowhere near 0.05 so that means this is
not a statistically significant result
so we shouldn't take into account. So
basically we can't add in information
based on this trend line here and then
we're looking at the red chart this is
an interesting bid. We can see that even
though we're not reporting this machine
hasn't spike the moving average hasn't
spiked anywhere above the 10-percent
line so this machine is good to go,
what you can see from the trendline is
it is drastically very quickly
approaching a ten percent mark. In fact,
it is definitely statistically
significant result based on the p-value
but also you can see from the formula
that the coefficient here is 0.0012
times hour of daytime plus some constant.
So what this means is that every for,
with every hour that this machine will
work if everything else continues the
same way it is now, with every hour that
this machine operates the idle capacity
the moving average of the idle capacity
in expressing percentage, in percentages
will increase by 0.12 or  0.13 percentages.
So for every hour,
this machine's idle moving
average idle capacity is increasing by
0.1 percent, so approximately in 10 hours
every 10 hours this moving average will
increase by 1%
like in the long run of course is going
to have its ups and downs going to have
the fluctuations but in the long run is
going to keep increasing at that rate
and that what that means is that within
a couple of days but literally within a
couple of days this line will be crossed
so even though we're performing this
analysis for September we can already
say what's going to happen in the future
and that is very powerful. That is
extremely powerful so we're not only
reporting on the analysis that we were
contracted to do that is fighting
machines that require maintenance
according to the criteria specified by
the company we're actually going above
and beyond we're saying that this
machine looks like this machine will
require maintenance soon sometime in
October it will cross this line if
everything else continues the same way
it is happening right now and what that
we can help the company of course they
can choose to ignore this inside but
another had its better to have the
inside and ignore it then not to have it
all right? So what they can do is they
can say okay well instead of revisiting
this machine at the end of the month
because perhaps they're only conducting
this in type of analysis once a month if,
if ..if they're lucky so if they're likely
conducting this analysis once a month
the end of every month and only at the
end of October will they pick up this
machine cross this line at the start of
October. Instead from your insight what they
can say okay we're going to do some
preventive maintenance right now we're
going to look into this machine right
now or they can say we're going to visit
the specific machine after the first
week of October and see if that
line it did cross the 10% mark and
that is extremely powerful. That is just
by looking at the data we don't like
you and I we don't know anything about
these reclaimers and stackers and so on
but just by looking at the data and
adding a trendline, we're able to tell
that something's going to happen to this
reclaimer or SR4A machine
Sacker Reclaimer 4A and if you look at
the trend line this one is it is
increasing but it's not as steep as
this one. This trend line is pretty steep
and that means that something's wrong
with the machine, maybe the oil's old, maybe
some nuts and bolts fell out but
something is going on there and we can
see it turning into a disaster very soon
so you guys better get up and do
something about it.
So that's the power of data and the
every time I form analysis something
like this I, you should be proud of
yourselves right now it's
incredible what we can see and every
time I just like this I just have this
smile on my face because it is
impossible to see something like this
like coming without looking at the
data you can't just look at the
machine and say that our something's
wrong with it, it's, it's only the data
can tell you something like this it's, it's
incredible what data science and data
visualization can help you achieve. So
there we go that those are power
insights we report on what we see, we
report on these plateaus which look like
planned sacrifice of
productivity and utilization and finally
we will report on this anomalous
trendline and what it might lead to at
the start of the following month. That's
all for today, in the next tutorial I
will show you how to put all of these
insights into a storyline to present to
the stakeholders. I look forward to you next
time and until then, happy analyzing!