Section recap.
Alright so what did we learn this
section was saturated with knowledge we
had lots and lots of different topics
let's recap on them very quickly.
First, we learned how to create groups.
It's a useful feature if you want to
affect the metadata that Tableau will be
working with and in a way merge the
two categories or multiple categories
within one field and we understood
exactly how groups work and that how
this affects segregation and that you
are safe to proceed with things like
averages and sums and so on when you're
using groups. And then we talked about
groups versus sets and the main key
difference here was that groups allow
you to control metadata of your data set
and sets are like filters which you can
put in your pocket and carry around with
you and use as your convenience in
different scenarios for different
purposes. Then we talked about static
set so there are two types of sets
generics, static and dynamic sets. Static
sets are very quick. You can create them in
your visualization right on the chart
but they do have the disadvantage that
they don't adapt to changes in your
data or changes in the requirements
of your analysis. Dynamic sets on the
other hand don't have those
disadvantages and that makes them so
much more powerful as you could see. Well
for most of this section we were working
with dynamic sets and they allowed us to
create some fantastic visuals. Then we
learned about combining sets, if you have
two sets that are based on the same
dimension then you can use them together
to combine and create a third set and
you can put some rules around whether it
includes everything that's in both the
set includes the overlap of the two sets
or other scenarios. Then we looked at
controlling sets with parameters and as
you can see this combination of sets
and parameters is extremely powerful if
sets by themselves are like fire than
adding parameters to set is like pouring
gasoline over the fire and allows you to
create
such powerful visuals and such
responsive dashboards. It's truly amazing.
Then we talked about creating assets
using formulas so which is also an
advanced tool in your arsenal now, you
can specify exactly what's that you want
using formulas and different fields of
your data set. So those are the main
things that we learned in this section
that was what section was focused on but
along the way we actually learned quite
a lot of other things and here's a quick
list of those things.
Additionally we learned number one, how
to create folders. Folders value to clean
up your workspace. Number two is how to
set default properties for fields and
that is also a star here because I think
that that is a very useful technique
that will help you in your future
dashboards and visualizations because it
saves time you don't have to format that
field every single time you just
format it once and we saw that on the
example of a growth which had to be a
percentage every single time we used it.
Then we learned how to use two
dimensions or sets in color. Another star
here because it's a very very useful
feature and not many people use it, not
many people know about it.
You now know about it and it will
definitely help you out sometimes so we
saw how we could add three colors into
our dashboard gray, blue and red, using
two different sets that we dragged into
the the color button. Next we saw how to
add reference lines so probably another
star should have been here, reference
lines are very useful and we actually
saw how to control reference lines with
parameters. Then we talked about how to
add a drop lines, so drop lines allow you
to help the user remember we're always
thinking about the user help the user
see where on the axis a certain element
of the scatterplot actually lies and not
only scatterplots you can also apply
drop lines to other visualizations. Then
we saw how to create useful tool tips so
not just tooltips that give real like
random information to these and we saw
how to customize our tool tips so that
they provide the very insightful
information the user is looking for and
they also look fantastic. And finally we
talked a lot about aesthetics and best
practices and off the top of my head I
can remember two stars being in there. We
talked about how to fix up your color
range so that it doesn't start from a
certain value actually starts from zero
working nonstop from a negative value so
you adjust your color range to what you
want to see and we talked about dynamic
text in your dashboard which also helps
the user understand what's going on
because that text is affected by the
parameter that he is changing. So there
we go that's everything we learned, as
you can see very very saturated section.
I hope you truly enjoyed it and had fun
along the way. We did create a beautiful
visualization towards the end and thank
you for your attention.
I look forward to seeing you on the next
section of the course. Until then, happy
analyzing.