Hello and welcome back to the advanced
course in Tableau. We've already discussed
two out of the three types of the LOD
calculations, we've talked about the
include type and the exclude type and
we've only got the fixed type left but
before we proceed I'd like to quickly
recap on what we've learned so far and
also discuss again what we will learn
today. Just so that we're on the right
track and that we don't get lost.
Alright so we talked about the include
level of detail calculation and what we
did is we started at the level of
granularity of state. Once again, it
doesn't have to be geographical data or
geographical dimensions it can be any
type of dimensions but in our case they
are geographical so we started at the
level of state so this was our
visualization and then we included a new
dimension which was city. We went down to
a more granular level what we did here
is we aggregated our orders or actually
aggregated our items in our orders for
every city so here would sum up all the
profit for this city, sum up all the
profit for this city, for this city, for
this city so we'd find the profit for
every single city then we would take
those sums of profits that we've attributed
to every city and we would bring that
value back into our visualization and
what we would do if it is we would take
the average remember because you have
once you're going to a more to a less
granular level two more aggregate level
you have to aggregate the measures that
you have created so we've created a
measure which is the sum of profit for
every city but now we're talking about
things at the level of state so what we
did is we took the average of the city
profits for every single state so that's
how we use that level of detail include
in our visualization. Next we used
exclude and what we did is we created a
visualization at the city level and we
needed to get the a value from a
higher level of aggregation so what we
did is we used exclude and we excluded
city and that brought us in the
background again, our visualization
didn't change in the background and
brought us to the level of granularity
of state from here we quickly grabbed
the profit for every single state and
brought it back to our city and here in
this arrow we don't need to we do we
still need to aggregate but we don't
need to apply some more average or
anything because we're actually bringing
a measure, measure from a higher level of
aggregation so from the state level so
that's where the ATTR function came into
play and that way we were able to bring
down the profit for the states to the
level of the city and then we use that
in the calculation of what proportion or
what portion of profit does each city
contribute to its state and we create
that very powerful visualization that we
have now and finally the lost type of
level of detail calculation we still
have to discuss is the fixed type of
calculation and what it does here is we
set our aggregation that we want to work
with as an absolute. So think of that
little hack that we talked about with
relative and absolute pathways on a hard
drive so the include and exclude they're
like relative pathways, you have, you have
your starting point in your ID exclude
something so you go to a high level of
aggregation or you include stuff so you
go to a lower of all level of
aggregation but the fixed level of
detail calculation what it does is it
doesn't mind or doesn't take into
account of inspiration where you are
starting doesn't take that experience so
you could start at the country level at
the city level you can start at the
state level doesn't matter. What we'll do
is always take your absolute
specified level of detail and from there
perform the calculation and all
bring the same result to your
visualization regardless of where you're
starting from. So that's our quick recap
and the fixed level of detail
calculation is what we're
going to discuss today, so let's dive straight
into it. Alright so what we're going to
do is we're going to actually recreate
the level of detail calculations that we
have created but this time we're going
to use fixed and the reason for that is
because our visualizations is pretty much
ready all we have to do is we just need
to take this chart and this chart and
overlay them but we'll do that further
down in this section. For now we're just
going to learn and practice how to use a
fixed level of detail calculation and
we're just going to create the same
chart but with fixed and then this chart
as well hopefully if we have enough time.
So let's quickly duplicate this sheet
and bring it over here, there we go
and so we're going to say LOD fixed
and then we'll say a and here we're
going to just duplicate LOD include
going to duplicate this and we're going
to edit it and here we'll say LOD. This
is why I included this word the key word
here so that we can quickly change it
and here I'm going to say fixed and
instead of so let's just let's just
think this through, what we're doing is
we're we're applying into this this
chart only and we're ready in this chart
when we open up we have 1, 2 dimensions, we
don't have any other dimensions so we're
saying take these two dimensions and add
the dimension city to these dimensions
and then perform the calculations at
that level. So basically it's a take city
add it here and then perform the
calculations and then bring the result
back here. So let's just quickly bring
city again in here so once city is added
right how many dimensions we have? We
have country, state, city. We have three
dimensions so those are exactly the
three dimensions that we need to specify
here so that's what we're going to say
we're going to say country and then
we're going to say state we're going to
say city and we're going to click ok so
let's just take this out from here and
if LOD fix and instead of include
this time we're going to say fixed right so
because previously we already had
country and state we only needed to add
city but now because we're saying fixed
we don't have a relative pathway where
we have to specify the absolute pathway
in those terms that we discussed but
in Tableau terms we just have to specify
all the dimensions that we want in our
aggregation that's going to happen in
this aggregation is going to happen we
want to specify at which level of
dimensions it should happen.
There we go LOD fixed, click ok, LOD
fixed and now I'm just going to replace
it here.
Of course we need an aggregation, we're
going to say measure average and just
replace it here to hold down control so
there's our new result
let's compare it to our old result, as you can
see same exact result and moreover now
if something changes with our
visualization the result won't change so
the this calculation will still be
performed so if I for instance take
state out you know we're seeing
307.8 here that is the average
this this calculation is still being
performed so if I click LOD fixed right
edit the calculation this is the average
that is applied to this calculation so
the sum of profit is still calculated at
the city level and then the average is
applied and you can make sure to confirm
that is true by just going to the second
chart and if I remove state here you'll
see that the average here is 35.42.
35.42 probably what I'll do is just make
this label much bigger so that we can or
maybe make it white that should be
better to see so 35.42 is the average
across all items that were sold ever in
any state any city, any postal code
across any time from, whereas 307.8 is
the average in the US across all the
cities right so that you can see that
this works. It works fine, even though our
aggregation has changed.
Ok so that's just return that back to
where it was. Ok so that's LOD fixed a and
now we're going to recreate this more
difficult one.
Let's duplicate sheet and here let's
start with this year we'll put it here
to say fixed be, right so let's see what
do we need to recreate, it's actually not
that difficult,
what we need to recreate is just as LOD
exclude say profit and then we're going
to have to replace it in these measures
ok so I'm going to duplicate LOD exclude
and I'm going to rename it, I'm going to
edit it,
alright so this is what do we want? We
want, once we exclude city and postal
code, what we'll have is country and say we
don't even need to look at the
visualization. All we need to look at
and count and register is the
dimensions that we have, so we have
country and state just two dimensions
that's what we'll have official city and
postal code are excluded so that's
exactly what we're going to do and let's
change it up here, so here we're going to
say fixed and here I'm going to say
fixed as well but now this is not what I
want to exclude this is actually a level
of detail which I want to perform the
calculation so fixed this is going to be
country and this is going to be state so
I'm specifying exactly the same to that
we have here and that's the calculation
one perform. So I'm just going to return
everything back to normal,
city but now this is our LOD fixed, going
to click ok. Alright so there it is,
LOD fixed a state profit that's the
one we're going to be using so we're at
the city level we're going to the state
level and let's just rename this so we
can copy the name and let's apply it
everywhere so we're just going to double
click here and in this case it's used
twice in this calculation so we're going
to put it here and we're going to put it
here just as a press ENTER just check
the map that nothing changes nothing
change that's good, then again
double-click here,
there we go
this and this one is only used once
again nothing changed in the map some
profit stays LOD exclude let's change
this, okay.
Again nothing changed and finally this
one. Let's look
yep it's only used once, alright did
something changed nothing changed good
and now basically even if we add the
postal code it will still work as
expected it works totally fine.
So there we go we have successfully
replaced LOD include and exclude with
LOD fixed as you can see you can
achieve the exactly same results you
just specifying explicitly we're at
which level of granularity you want your
calculations to be performed and I hope
you enjoyed this tutorial I look forward
to seeing you next time and until then,
happy analyzing!