Hello and welcome back to the advanced course on our in this tutorial we're going to import the data
set into our studio.
So as you can see we've got our studio open in front of me and I encourage you to follow along so that
you can have the same code on your screen as well.
All right.
So let's get started.
First things first we're going to get the working directory for our our studio as we can see the working
directory here is users curial Eremenko.
So that's not where I have stored the file.
I stored the file in a folder on my desktop so I'm going to set the working directory to that so that
I can all work in that folder right away.
I'll show you how to do it both on Mac and Windows so we'll start with Mac.
I meant to say set working directory.
And here in quotation marks I'm going to say users are so similar to what we see here.
Actually this copy that users curagh slash curial Eremenko then desktop then our programming and bonds
.
All right so that's how you set the word inertia on a Mac.
Let's run the slide.
As you can see the working directory has been run and let's just check it out.
It has been set to the correct folder.
That's good.
So this is for Mac users.
And if you're watching and doing these tutorials on Windows then the procedure is a bit different.
You need to type in set working directory.
And here the path should be specified instead of using forward slashes.
You need double backslashes.
So for instance A B C double backslash users double backslash curial double backslash desktop double
backslash our programming advanced.
So depending on where your file folder is stored so in this case it's on the C drive in the user's folder
in the folder of my name then desktop and then our programming and once.
So I'm just going to come in this hour so it's not in the way but if you're using Windows then that
is a format on Mac that is the format.
All right so then just make sure to run good working directly to confirm that the word integrity has
been changed.
And now we're going to import our data set so as you can see we have nothing in our global environment
here.
And let's go ahead and use the read dot CSV function which we are well familiar with.
Now now we're going to type in the name of our data set which is future $500 CACP in quotation marks
and we're going to assign what Reid says period turns to an object right.
So we're going to store our data set in this doorframe which is called fin stands for financial because
we're dealing with financial data is going to use the name of the data set as been.
So we're on this line as you can see we've got an object we've got a data frame of 500 observations
11 variables.
So it's got some information there but we don't need that because we have other ways of exploring this
data set.
Now in our.
So let's proceed to that.
The first way we know is to just run the name of this data set and that'll bring it all out here as
I guess it is a lot of lines way too many for us to look at in this way.
So we're going to use some tricks that we know when dealing with data sets.
We're going to look at the top a certain number of rows so we just look at ahead thin.
And let me expand this.
We won't be needing this window much in this section of the course so we're just going to keep it close
like that.
So if I run ahead fin there you can see we've got the top six rows of our data set and it's got all
the Call them so it kind of gives you a good understanding of what's going on.
Also we can look at the tail of fin then we get the bottom row so we can see indeed this 500.
And there hasn't been any road shifts or column shifts.
Everything looks okay.
It's always good to check.
And if you want to check a few more rows and 6 and just say here just pass a parameter let's say 10
then I'll give you Moroz.
Same with hedgie you can check more rows that way.
And now let's have a look at the structure of our data set.
So as you are fin there we go.
We've got a quick description of every column what it is that's an integer that's a factor that's factors
and integer factors integer factor.
And finally let's look at summary fin.
So there we go.
We've got some stats on every single one of these Kolbe's.
So all of this should be already familiar to you from our basic course on our programming and today
what we wanted to focus on is that we've got a lot of factors here.
So we've got a lot of factors that we're dealing with and factors are going to be quite important for
us in this section of the course on a door operation.
So in the upcoming tutorial we're going to have a quick refresher on factors because we really do need
one just so that we're all on the same page when we're dealing with factors.
But other than that the data set has been imported into our end if you would like to start playing around
with it you can do so and I look forward to seeing the next tutorial.
Until then happy coding.