Hello.
Welcome back to the advanced course in our programming.
Today we're finally going to get to the fun stuff.
We're going to build the time series plot.
So let's dive straight into it.
If you do not have G-G plot 2 installed on your machine then please run this line.
Install packages and then in quotation marks G-G plot 2.
If you do have it no need to run the Slyne.
Just make sure that you connect this package just by running this line of the library.
So if you don't have Did you plot to first try this and then run this line.
If you do then just run this line.
There we go.
Now we've connected G-G plot 2 and now we can start building our plot.
So once again if you haven't done the basic course on our programming then I hope you're familiar with
the plot too.
If you have then this is all going to be very simple stuff that we have discussed in the basic course
so p is going to be G-G plot and we are going to specify the data as you tell because we want all of
the machines right in our plot not just the one.
And here we go to say maybe let's make some more room right away because it's going to be quite big
.
OK we can say P plus genome point.
Actually not we don't want to point to on line.
Jim line.
And now we are going to create some statics aesthetics on the X-axis we want POSIX time and this is
how you create a time series plot.
It's that simple and why is utilization common.
Well it's just start of that so let's see what how that looks while right.
That's a lot of.
Can't see anything there.
Let's see if we can make it a bit prettier.
OK let's say we want color equals machine.
Let's try that.
OK very very thin.
And they're kind of covering each other up so first this make them a bit thicker so we going to add
size.
But just a quick reminder this inside aesthetics are really doing is where a mapping variables.
So when or we're mapping aesthetics when we have an aesthetic like X Y and color we're mapping them
to variables inside odorata or frame.
Now we want to add size.
It's not going to be mapped.
It's going to be actually just set to a certain value.
That's why it has to be outside of this static function.
So here we can say size equals one point two.
Let's have a look at that fire on that.
OK so it's a bit thicker now but there still overlapping What do we do in stuff like this happens.
What do we remember from the basic course.
We add a facet grid.
Right.
We want to separate all of these colors into separate charts.
Facit grid.
And what are we separated by a machine.
Tilda Daut ants run this.
OK.
Looks much better now right.
Looks much better and by the way if you've done that bonce course on Tablo you might be quite familiar
with this chart already.
And now we're going to say plus here we're going to go over and above a little bit.
We like this chart is pretty much ready but what are we going to do is we going to add a horizontal
line at zero at the 90 percent mark over here.
Why.
Well that is because that is our threshold right.
The low threshold and we just want kind of highlighted for the user.
So we'll just say Jorm underscore horizontal line and then here what we need is y intercept and that's
going to be nine t commom colorless.
Give it some color.
Oh well let's let's forget about the color for now.
Let's just run this and see how this goes.
Since it's very dark is black Let's make it a bit lighter color gray and then we'll say size as well
.
Equals one point two.
All right let's run that before I show you the next shrink.
So far on that is yoga is looking better right but now so that it doesn't look like so important because
he can even confuse it with the bottom of the axis here as opposed to like these white lines which are
separated which are the actual separators.
What I would do is say a line type equals three.
You can look up line time for G.G. plot and you'll see that here it tells you one is solid.
Zero is blank one assaulters dash three started on we're going to be using for his dot dash fives long
dash to six to dash and plus then you can use other combinations if you like specify quotation marks
.
We won't get into that we'll just say a line type 3.
So let's run that.
So here you can see that now it's a bit more subtle.
It's a subtle line and right away like somebody who is analyzing the report will be able to see.
OK so this machine has dropped below 90 percent utilization.
This machine hasn't this machine hasn't this machine kind of.
Hasn't this machine has tried so very very easy to quickly analyze it and all we had to do is just altogether
that's you know six seven seven lines and lines of code to bring this beautiful plot to life and to
finish off what we're going to do is we're going to save this plot so we'll just say take this and put
it into a object.
Let's say my plot like that and you will see why we're doing it right.
Just in a second.
So there we go.
So that's the plot.
Now we've saved this actual plot into my plot so if I run that that creates my plot object.
And now we want to add this to a list.
So if I go a list on the score of.
And yes we can add even a picture into a list or a plot.
So I'm creating a new component which is going to be called plot and I'm going to add my plot into the
list if I run that and I look at list and the score of one is going to be interesting so if I run that
all right let's just look at that again.
See like it's printing out everything.
It's printing out all component 1 2 3 4 5 which is our daughter frame and even our plot six.
But the plot is kind of like empty here why.
Well that's because actually printing this blood so I can prove that to you I'm just going to delete
all the applause from my our studio and if I run just this last line you'll see that the plot appears
again.
Right.
So that means that when you actually print the plot it prints a plot here.
And moreover if I look at a summary of list underscore all one you'll see that here it's added the plot
line nine and that is because when we look at the next item you'll see why it's length 9 Klaas's G.G.
and it's it's actually plots are stored as lists them selfs or the mode of this is a list so let's just
quickly look at the SDR faade going into too much detail on that.
Let's look at it as C-R.
You'll see that we've got this new item added over here which is just huge.
So there's that machine component that's low threshold.
Unknown hours then our daughter component and it ends and so we're here.
So this is everything we had before.
Once we've added the plot as it gets it's actually also a list of nine but we won't go into detail on
that because that's the inner workings of G-G plot how it stores its plots.
And that's that's something you can explore on your own if you're interested in that.
But basically this is all the information about the plot.
It's stored here so basically anybody who gets access to this list that we've created will be able to
recreate the plot and that's exactly what we wanted right so now we have this beautiful list which is
called list.
Underscore are all one and if we want to pass it on to anybody then they'll be able to extract all of
the information all the insights that they have been after or they were after which are Allium the sheet
name the stats for that machine that are a low threshold test the unknown hours the data for that specific
machine.
And moreover they'll even get the plot for all of the machines everything is included in this one list
as you can see lists are extremely convenient in terms of even just arranging your analysis just organizing
your workspace and how you analyze your data.
Very very convenient tool to have.
There we go.
That's how you add a beautiful plot into your list.
And I look forward see you next time.
Until then happy coding
.