We've accomplished a lot in this module.
We've touched and worked with a variety of Spring
architectural concepts in the Spring Boot environment and
have a working backend conference app.
Just keep in mind that we went really fast through this.
To get a deeper understanding,
you will need to dive into each portion of Spring that we
covered and worth through the details.
So let's recap what we've built.
Once we've determined what our conference app would do,
we installed and got a Postgres relational database
running as the foundation of our app.
I provided the schema and data files from a Git repo to bootstrap the database.
Next,
we worked our way up and built out some JPA models and repositories that
comprised the persistence tier of our architecture.
This included connecting to the database and setting up model relationships.
We then built out the API endpoints that would be needed for
basic CRUD operations on sessions and speakers.
This utilized the Spring MVC framework,
which relied on REST controllers and the Jackson library for JSON serialization.
We did deal with a few other nuances,
like working binary data and serialization issues.
You'll always find one-offs like that when building an application
that you will have to work through eventually.
App development tends to follow the 80/20 rule, like most things in life.
Eighty percent will build out easily, and 20% will give you more headache.
And that's it.
Take a break and regroup.
Because coming up in the next section of the course, we'll dive deep into all the ways Spring Boot can be configured and managed.