If you were a Java developer back in 2005 and you
wanted to deploy your application,
you'd become very familiar with containers like Tomcat,
Glassfish, or Websphere.
These were all containers that complied with the JEE specification at that time.
And when you deployed a Java application,
you created a WAR file and then installed them on these containers.
Now with Spring Boot, apps are standalone.
Instead of installing your app into a container,
Spring has embedded a container inside of the framework.
This allows you to run the app in standalone mode now.
The default container Spring Boot uses is Tomcat out of the box.
You can switch that out to Jetty or Undertow if you
prefer a different embedded container.
Let's see what it actually takes to switch out an embedded container for our conference application.