For this next clip,
I'm going to show you an alternative way to create a Spring Boot application.
If you aren't interested in this or you don't have
a licensed version of IntelliJ, you can go ahead and skip ahead to the next clip.
If you do happen to have an IntelliJ Ultimate edition and a paid license,
you can also easily create a Spring Boot project right from the IDE.
This time, instead of importing the project,
we're just going to go ahead and create a new
project by clicking on that button.
On the left-hand-side menu,
find the Spring Initializr item and click on it and
then select your Project SDK version.
I'm simply going to use the default recommendation of
version 12 and then click Next.
At this point, IntelliJ has communicated with the Spring Initializr site,
and it wraps it in a nice IntelliJ dialog.
I can now set up the group and artifact IDs,
select my Maven, pom.xml, and Java version.
So I'll go ahead and customize those quickly.
I've set the Group to com.pluralsight and the artifact to conference-demo.
I'll leave it as a Maven project with the Java language,
and I'm going to bump up the Java version to something a little newer.
And when I'm happy with my settings, I'll go ahead and click Next.
At this point,
I can select my dependencies and integrations that I want
to bring into my Spring Boot project, and I want to use the Web,
so I'll select that and click Next.
I'll leave the Project name and Project location as is and just click Finish.
IntelliJ will go ahead and download from the Spring
Initializr site and pull that into the app,
and you're ready to get started.
I'm going to simply just rearrange some things,
close the Maven dialog, open up the Project tab,
and this should look pretty much exactly like the
community edition at this point.
There's one other way that you can work with Spring Boot
that's a little different than any type of Java development
that you might have done before.
Coming up next, we'll take a look at the Spring Boot CLI, command line interface.