We'll start by making a couple of changes in the Maven pom.xml file,
so I'll go ahead and get that open.
The first thing that needs to happen is we need to flag
the embedded containers as provided, so I'll need to do a few things here.
First, we have a dependency for our spring-boot-starter-jetty.
I'm going to go ahead and remove that dependency.
And we've also excluded the spring-boot-starter-tomcat in
the spring-boot-starter-web dependency,
so I'm going to go ahead and remove that as well.
Next, I'm going to re-add the spring-boot-starter-tomcat dependency,
but I'm going to give it a scope of provided.
That means that Maven won't package the Tomcat starter in the build.
It expects something externally to provide it.
With these changes in place,
you won't have an embedded container inside of your application anymore.
And the final thing that we need to do is to change the
packaging type of the Maven artifact to a WAR.
We can do that by adding the following line.
I'm going to do that near the top of the file underneath the description area,
and that will be packaging tag with a value of war.
That now will produce a WAR file rather than a JAR file.
Go ahead and save those changes, and IntelliJ is wanting us to import those.
We'll do that.
Once that's done, we need to make one small Java change,
so I'm going to go ahead and close this build section,
and I'm going to jump back to src, main,
java, jump into my packages,
and I want to find the ConferenceDemoApplication class.
If you remember,
this is our bootstrap class that has the public static void
main where everything gets kicked off.
The change I want to add in here is I need to have
this class extend the following.
We want it to extend SpringBootServletInitializer.
We'll go ahead and import that class and save the file.
When you deploy a WAR file to an external container,
it expects a context to be available.
It also expects a web.xml file, which defines how the app will get deployed.
Since the Spring Boot does not have a web.xml file in it,
this class provides that value and information to the external container.
Without this,
you won't be able to access you app properly via a
context when you go to access it.
With these changes in place,
we can go ahead and open up the Maven pop-out and run mvn package again by
going to the little m and running the mvn package command.
At this point, you'll notice that we get an error,
and I wanted to point this out because this can cause people to run into a
lot of issues if you're not familiar with what's happening.
So, ultimately,
what happens when the test runs is it's looking for
everything to be set up correctly.
We're currently set up to use our database by using an environment variable.
So I'm going to go ahead and close this Run thing here,
and I want to go over to the resources, application.properties.
In here, the app is expecting this.
Well, this is not provided when we run our test.
And if you think about it,
this environment variable won't be provided when we go out to
run our app inside of a Tomcat container,
for example.
We could end up setting that as a value on there,
but just to make things simpler, I'm going to go back into the config,
PersistenceConfiguration,
and I'm going to reenable the bean that we set up
because we've hard coded our URL in here.
I'm going to save that file.
Now also, keep in mind,
you don't want to end up doing this for your production app.
You do want to end up using some kind of external configuration source,
and a lot of times,
the best way to do that in an external container is using JNDI.
So you could set these up as JNDI values so you don't have your URL
and credentials hard coded into your application.
Since we don't have enough time to go into that depth,
we'll go ahead and just reenable this and run the mvn package again.
This time, the app has built successfully,
and if we go look in the target folder,
you'll now see that the artifact is a WAR file rather than a JAR file.
We still have our old JAR file in there from an earlier build,
but we also now have this conference-demo- 0.0 .1 - SNAPSHOT.war file,
and this is the file that we'll go ahead and deploy to a Tomcat container.
So to deploy my WAR file to a Tomcat instance,
I need to go find that WAR file, which is in my target folder,
and I'm going to copy this.
I'm going to go over to my apache deploy,
and you're going to push this into the webapps folder for apache-tomcat.
So we'll simply paste that WAR file in here,
and then you'll notice that Tomcat will extract that
out into an expanded application.
By default, Tomcat runs on port 8080, so I'm here at the root of my Tomcat,
and I have the Tomcat documentation.
To run and access my app, I need to enter the context.
Now the context was the name of the folder that I just deployed.
That folder name is this big, long thing here,
so I'm simply going to copy that and paste that in
as my context for my application.
So that would be forward-slash and the name of my conference-demo-SNAPSHOT.
And when I go to that page now,
you'll see that my app is responding to the home or the root endpoint,
which is our app-version of 1.0 .0,
and the app is now running on a container using the external
Tomcat instead of the internal embedded Tomcat.
And again, we can go ahead and test out the speakers or the sessions,
and I still get my sessions endpoint back.
So this is how you can run a Spring Boot application on an external container,
and there's only a few changes that you need to make
to your app to get that working.
Finally,
keep in mind that the changes that we've made in this clip
will prevent your app from running as a JAR file or a
standalone executable JAR file.
You can pick one way, or you can pick the other,
but you can't have both a JAR and a WAR at the same time.
If you want to go back to running your app as a standalone JAR, you'll need to revert the changes that were made in this clip.