Whilst it might not seem like it at first glance,
traditional query creation can involve lots of boilerplate.
Let's demonstrate this with an example.
The method we have here is called findByName,
and it will return our customers in the database with the given name.
Although the signature straightforward is making it previous
obvious to us what the method should do,
we still have to implement the code to execute it.
In our case, we're using JPA,
so that means creating a native query using the EntityManager,
setting the parameters, and then returning the result as a list.
And this doesn't even include the code required to convert our
results into a list of the customer type.
Now if we take a step back and look at this code,
it's definitely filled with boilerplate because regardless
of whatever read query we'd be doing,
our code here would always look more or less the same apart
from the query string and parameters.
And actually, although the query string is unique,
doesn't the method name already look similar to it?
Spring Data aims to solve these problems of query
boilerplate for derived queries.
In a nutshell,
a derived query is a query generated by Spring Data for
you based on the method signature.
So when we declare a method like this one on a Spring Data repository,
Spring will be smart enough to generate an implementation of the method for us.
Let's step through to see how Spring Data might do this.
Spring Data first looks at the method name and maps
the word find to the word SELECT.
It then sees the word ByName and maps it to WHERE NAME =.
Then the value of name is pulled out of the name query parameter.
Finally, by looking at the return type,
Spring Data knows what to map the result set into.
And for this example, that would be it.
The specific details of how Spring Data does this is
beyond the scope of this course.
But an oversimplified explanation is that it will generate an implementation
of the interface at runtime based on the method signature,
and then this implementation would be what you get when you
wire in an instance of the repository.
Derived queries are arguably one of Spring Data's most powerful features,
and really there's a bunch of different things that can be achieved with them.
Let's take a look.
We can derive queries that use logical operators,
such as and and or, by simply putting the word into the method name.
Our queries can also be made case-insensitive by putting
terms like IgnoreCase into the method.
We can order the results of the query by putting OrderBy,
delete elements by column name, in this case the value of name,
and even use operators like less than or greater than.
If for some reason you think this is overkill and feel that it's
fine to query your database with your ORM directly,
then first try to think about some of these advantages.
In the case of Spring Data derived queries,
there's no boilerplate for it at all.
All the plumbing that could be done is done for us.
Our queries are generated for us based on the method signature,
so we don't need to implement them.
The queries are also executed for us within the generated code.
And finally,
the result set is automatically mapped for us into
the return type of our methods.
The removal of the boilerplate isn't the only advantage
though because doing things this way also dramatically
reduces the learning curve for developers.
This is because the underlying query language is abstracted,
letting you work with human readable method names whilst
counting on Spring to do the rest for you.
So if you are inexperienced with SQL,
then derived queries would help you get a quick start.
As well as this,
we should consider how advantageous interoperability of derived queries are.
This is because whilst the examples we've given were
of SQL queries being generated,
the exact method signatures are convertible into all
sorts of different query languages.
For example, if you don't know Cassandra in SQL,
but you do know Spring Data,
then Spring Data Cassandra would be a great way to
generate those queries for you.
It's only when you run into more complicated,
advanced, and database-specific concepts that derived queries won't be enough. But in the basic use cases, they are.