Sometimes, but rarely,
the Spring Data Repository interface as in derived queries
might not be enough for our use case.
If this is the case,
we can implement a repository method ourselves rather than
leaving Spring Data to do it for us.
A common gotcha when trying to do this is thinking you can
implement the Spring Data Repository method and that Spring Data
will use that implementation by default.
Without getting into the finer details,
this won't work as when Spring generates a repository implementation,
it will ignore the existing implementations.
To get it to work, we need to generate an additional repository interface,
which does not inherit from the Spring Data repository.
Any method we put there, we can, of course, implement.
We then use composition with our original repository
to write our custom method to it.
So if we want to implement a method with our own code,
we put it in a separate interface, implement that interface, and then make our repository inherit from that interface.