In our final demo for this module,
we're going to create a custom repository interface.
We'll then implement the interface with our own custom code,
after which we'll make our Spring Data repository extend it.
And finally, we'll verify our custom implementation functions with a test.
Okay, let's get started by creating a new test called CustomImplTest.
We'll run it with the SpringRunner and make it a JPA test just like before,
also wiring in our FlightRepository.
We'll then create a test named shouldSaveCustomImpl and then save a flight
to London whilst creating a helper method in the process.
We'll call this flight toDelete and then create a second flight called toKeep,
which will be to Paris.
Following this, we'll save them, delete the one to London by origin,
and assert that the only flight in the database is the one to Paris.
Notice how we didn't generate the deleteByOrigin method yet as in this case,
we're going to create a custom implementation to perform our query
rather than relying on Spring Data to generate it for us.
First, let's create a new interface called DeleteByOriginRepository.
We'll define our method deleteByOrigin here,
navigate to our existing FlightRepository,
and make it implement this interface.
It's important we do it this way as putting a method on a separate
interface allows us to create a custom implementation of it.
Let's do this by creating a subclass called DeleteByOriginRepositoryImpl.
Now we can literally put any code we want here,
even code that wasn't data access code.
But for this example,
we'll just use the JPA EntityManager to perform the delete query.
We'll inject the EntityManager by making it a constructor
argument and then create a native delete query,
DELETE from flight WHERE origin is equal to our provided parameter.
Now that's done,
let's switch back to our test and run it to see if it goes green.
It does meaning our query has worked.
Now we could stop here.
But to prove that it really was our code that was executed,
let's navigate back to it and add a breakpoint.
We can then rerun our test and confirm that the breakpoint was hit,
proving that it's indeed our custom code that's getting executed.
And that covers it for this demo.
This last step hopefully proves that there's no limit
to the extensibility of Spring Data, even though in the majority of use cases, the base abstractions are still probably enough.