Imagine we had an application that allows a customer
to book a ticket for an event.
When the customer books a ticket,
we will first allocate a seat within the venue to them and
also take a payment for the transaction.
Once both these things have taken place,
then the customer's booking will be completed,
and we can send them their ticket.
However, if the payment request failed without transactions,
we would have a problem.
This is because the first step, seat allocation,
would still be successful,
meaning the seat would be taken up when there's no ticket associated with it.
If we wrapped queries in a transaction, then things would be different.
This is because a single transaction contains multiple queries,
which either all take place or do not take place at all.
So if our payment request failed, the whole transaction would fail,
rolling back the seat's allocation so there's no longer one allocated in error.
We describe a transaction as having asset guarantees,
meaning it's atomic so it either all happens or does not happen at all,
it's consistent,
meaning the data written is valid according to the various constraints,
isolated,
meaning another transaction cannot see the results of
the transaction until it's committed,
and it's durable meaning the results of the transaction are written to disk.
We won't go into much more detail about this as this course is not
for learning the inner workings of a transaction.
But what's important to understand here is that the majority of
enterprise applications will be dependent on transactions at some
point in order to function as they need to.
Okay,
let's take a look at how we might execute our code
in a transaction without Spring.
Here's our method, bookTicket, which will allocate the seat and make the payment.
Wrapping it in a transaction, first of all, introduces a ton of boilerplate.
In this case, the boilerplate is Hibernate.
We need to start the transaction, commit the transaction,
remember to wrap it in a try-catch block so we can roll the
transaction back if there's an exception,
and also add a finally block so we always close the
session after our transaction completes.
Now wouldn't it be great if we could make our bookTicket method
transactional without having to write any of that code.
Well,
with Core Spring we can do this simply by annotating
our method with @Transactional.
This declarative annotation does all of the boilerplate for us.
The exact specifics of how this works by leveraging AOP
is beyond the scope of this course.
But an oversimplified explanation is that at runtime,
Spring will create a proxy,
which intercepts calls to @Transactional methods and executes
the transaction boilerplate for us eventually calling the real
method during this transaction.
So you can be confident that declaring something is @Transactional will
mean that transaction will be started before the method is called and
then committed a row back after the method is called as long as the
annotation is on a Spring managed bean.
It's also important to note that Spring transaction
management technically comes from Core Spring,
not from Spring Data.
However, as transactions and Spring Data are so heavily used together,
it makes logical sense to cover them both in an overview course.
So just to be clear about the benefits of transaction
management with Spring or Spring Data,
the first is that we remove a ton of boilerplate.
What was once rings of code is now a simple annotation on a method,
which means developers can focus on writing their queries
instead of the scaffolding for those queries.
It's also declarative and non-invasive.
The annotation isn't even part of the code.
It's metadata meaning the code will contain only query logic.
In turn,
this makes bugs a lot less likely because the transaction
code is now managed for us by Spring.
And the main advantage from the point of view of Spring
Data is that it's data-store agnostic.
If you're working with a database that supports transactions,
the corresponding Spring Data module will know how to
generate the corresponding transaction code.
If you're working with a non-transactional database, like Cassandra, then this annotation will do nothing.