Okay, before we get started with our first demo,
let's go through what this course will and won't be focusing on.
We need to do this simply because the scope of Spring Data is so broad,
and we'll only be taking a high-level slice throughout the framework.
The main focus will be Spring Data Commons.
This parent project is used throughout all of Spring Data,
and understanding it is key to being able to use any of the other modules.
The core interface we'll be working with is a repository interface,
providing an abstraction for writing and querying data.
As we can't use Spring Data Commons independently,
we'll be using the JPA and MongoDB modules.
This, however, is just for demonstrating Commons,
and we're not going to touch on the details of either of these implementations.
Finally, we're looking at transactions in Spring.
Whilst not technically part of Spring Data,
Spring transaction management is extremely powerful
and directly related to data access.
This thin slice through Spring Data will also touch on other concepts.
So let's list which of them we'll not be focusing on during the course.
The first is Hibernate, JPA, or any other ORM.
It's assumed that you already have some knowledge of object
relational mapping before starting the course.
This only needs to be the basics though as Spring Data Commons does a
really good job of abstracting away most of the complexity.
We'll also be using Core Spring and Spring Boot during this course,
and it's expected you already know the basics of these.
Again, if you don't, you'll still be able to get by,
but it might be worth covering them in another Pluralsight course.
Finally, it's worth mentioning that Spring Data is not for batch processing.
Spring Data Batch is a framework independent of Spring
Data specifically for that purpose. So if you want to do batch processing, please don't use Spring Data.