Hello welcome back to the course on computer vision we talk about the horror like features the name
Haar comes from Alfred Haar who was a Hungarian mathematician in the 19th century and he developed a
mathematical concept called the haar wavelet which is a basis of way for functions which act similar
to the four year transformation but we're not going to get into detail on that right now because we
don't really need that we just need the horror like features which have since been derived from the
hard wavelet and our that's why they called Horo like features they just kind of like the descendants
of the haar wavelet and so we're going to look at the HARLICK features straight away.
So what are these features.
They are.
Let's first look at them.
They are the edge features the line features and the four rectangle features these are the Horlick features
that Viola Jones male and Jones identified in their research in their paper.
And so what are they.
What does it mean to be a feature.
Basically what we have is pixels.
So on an image you might have somewhere for example like a edge.
Right so an edge of feature like for instance an edge of an image for example just imagine like a photo
of a table or something.
Then part of the table where you can see the table top might be light and or lighter than the part where
the table ends might be darker because it's further away it's the floor or the carpet might be a different
color or something.
And so you can identify that that's the end of the table because you know there's a line of pixels which
are brighter line of pixels which are dark in terms of the age in terms of line features you might you
know might identify some objects and it doesn't have to be just like one line of pixel this could be
like three columns of pixels and then you know 15 rows of pixels.
So these are scalable.
They can be longer or they can be wider and so on.
So let's have a look at how all of these work out in the in terms of a face.
Right.
So here we've got our friend J.D. and let's see if we can identify some Horlick features here and that
will help us understand better why exactly they were picked.
What's a role what purpose they serve.
So have a look here.
So if you look at his mouth you can see here there is a tiny tiny tiny blackline then.
So that line that part is darker than the lips.
So that's a horror like feature.
You can see that that's a feature that's a line feature because that part is darker than that.
Those two parts bottom and top.
And this is all very rough very very very kind of rough approach to this image but nevertheless it works.
And you will see why it works.
Further down as we talk about things like the integral image and so on.
But for now let's just let's just stick to this bar so we kind of like breaking out these features we're
trying to see them in this image.
So what else can we see here.
Can you see any other of the features that we discussed.
If you if we go back we've got the edge features.
So we just identified this one we just identified a line feature.
Can we find maybe an age feature in several There's a line feature they'll look at the eyebrow you can
see that the eyebrow is darker than the forehead so let's put a feature there so you can see that that
signifies the edge of the forehead that line that eyebrow.
And so therefore the hard feature of an edge can serve a as a concern to show where this break this
division happens.
And that's normally going to be the case for in most photos that you process.
Most of the time the eyebrow is going to be darker in the face.
So for you know some some rare instances or some non frequent instances in most cases are going to be
like this and we'll I will talk about how all of these features were together.
So it doesn't have to be like every single time it's is like this but they're going to have a kind of
like a voting system that the more features the more likely it is a face.
Let's have a look at some more.
What can we see on for example on the nose.
Can we see that part of the nose is brighter than the other part.
So you can see here.
Let's see on the left here.
The nose is brighter.
The bridge of the nose is brighter than this part.
And that's normally going to be the case.
So if you look at pretty much any photo in grayscale you will often find that the bridge of the nose
is brighter than either just one side or even both sides.
It depends on the lighting.
Sometimes you might find here like a line type of feature so this part is wide and then you've got dark
and dark.
That's just how the human face reflects light in this case the lights coming from the left.
And that's why the left part is a bit brighter overall.
The right parts are.
But nevertheless you can see this edge.
So here you are nobody have a line or an edge feature.
That's exactly what we're drawing here.
There's our edge feature.
And then let's have a look another one.
You can see the eye for instance because though the outside outside of the outer part of the eye is
white and the inner part is not white.
It means it's dark or so it doesn't have to be like black and white it's black and white would be ideal.
So for instance the eyebrow in the forehead in this case are very very close to black and white and
because of the eye it's less close.
But nevertheless it still works you can see that you can identify that feature inside the eye as you
could could go keep going like that you could find another one for the other eye than eyebrow.
You could you just keep finding these features and some of them would be dependent on the lighting some
of them would be dependent on the person inside.
But overall you'd have kind of like a set of features that are predominantly present on most human faces
or like you have like a set of features most of which are present on any face meaning that if you you
have to have like at least 80 or 90 percent of the features like speaking roughly of course we'll get
into more detail about this further down.
But you'd have a speaker after you'd have to have like 80 or 90 percent of those features actually and
fight for it something to be a face would be very rare that you would have a face that would have only
half of those.
So now let's see how exactly this works in terms of the pixels.
So let's talk about the nose bridge featured or identified this age feature over here.
So if we zoom in a little bit you can see it is a feature.
Now I'm going to draw.
I'm going to show the nose without the feature overlaid but instead we're going to have the pixels so
of course this is a very simplified representation because there are many more pixels in this space.
But just for argument's sake let's say that there's four pixels by eight pixels thirty two pixels in
total and this nose.
And now we're going to understand how the algorithm works.
So let's ride out these pixels and here I've given them values between 0 and 10 there is 0 and 1 0 means
very white.
So 100 percent white 10 mean and 1 means 100 percent black and anywhere in between is greyscale.
And of course greyscale is from 0 to 255 because it's like 256 values and so on.
But we're not going to bother with writing them a lot.
We're just going to normalize them two from 0 to 1 and just keep it that way.
So it will be easy just for us to discuss.
And so here you can look at this image and you can see that this is not 100 percent white.
This would be 100 percent white.
But this is close to white.
So in an image like for argument's sake again this could be like 0.1 this pixel could have like a 0.1
intensity given that zeros and white and one is 100 percent like this pixel is a bit darker.
So is there a point to this pixel is about the same brightness or upon one's report ones or report one
0.2 it's a bit darker over here.
0.3 it's even darker if you compare to that one.
This one is 0.1.
This is a point and so on and so on so you can see that these are they're not all zeros but they're
close.
They're on the side you can see that this one is about 0.4 or somewhere on their 0.5.
This gets darker 0.8 3.6 this was a bit brighter sort of potent force similar to that.
Closer to that than to that and then to that for instance the reported fires are pretty high.
So you can see kind of the values here.
Now what's the algorithm will do what the algorithm will do is now that we've identified all of this
so this is this is where we see the feature we can see that kind of like white and black but this is
what is happening in reality not actually 100 percent black and Harmsen white that somewhere greyscale.
So what the Belgians algorithm will do is it will compare.
How close is this real world tonight or what is happening in the real world to the ideal Haar like feature
that it's looking for the white and black.
How close is it.
So how would it do that.
Well it will take the average of these Vaso First of all it will calculate the sum.
That's the first thing it does it calculates the sum of all these pixels and then divide by the number
of pixels it takes the average intensity of the white pixels and 0.1 6:06 takes the same thing for the
black pixels takes the sum of all of these values and now takes the average.
So as devised by whatever 16 here adds them up to as 16 gets average and this is the average intensity
of all of these pixels Fizer 0.06.
And now it's simply subtract one from the other subtracts this from that.
So the black minus the white is 0.4 02.
So these pixels and minus these pixels are the average minus averages 0.4.
Now so the question is what would this difference be in the ideal scenario.
Kind of the ideal scenario that where you would find exactly this feature where this would be all black
and this will be all white.
Well exactly right.
If it is all black this is all one.
If so why this is all zeros.
So it'd be one minus zero the average be one the average here would be 0 1 0 would be 1.
So basically in this in the in this approach the closer it is to one the closer the real world scenario.
This one is to what is being looked for.
Now of course we understand that we're humans we're not robots we don't have black and white delimited
parts like that so when we're And you know it depends on the lighting depends on on all these different
things.
So of course you're never going to have an exact one here or an exact zero.
This is always going to be some sort of gradients some sort of different colors shades and so on.
That's why the bell Jones has some thresholds and through the training which we'll discuss further down
through the training these thresholds identified.
And for instance for this specific feature in this position it's identified that the minimum threshold
might be 0.3.
And so whenever you get a result a calculated value here that is greater than 0.3 that means that indeed
this is somewhat similar to this HARLICK feature which we're looking for and we're going to say that
yes this Harlech feature is present in the image where in that position where we were looking for it
if on the other hand you get like 0.1 or basically a value that's less than your threshold then is the
difference between the two colorings for instance here.
For answers if you just basically applied looked for this feature because the algorithm doesn't know
that it needs to look for it here it will just look for it everywhere and look for it here or look for
a hero.
It's looking for the nose and at the end all it knows about the nose is that the nose looks like this
like this like this feature.
So it's going to look for it everywhere.
So if for instance algorithm were to apply this exact HARLICK feature some over here in the top left
corner then the difference between the real world of whites and the real or black would be nothing right
because it would be zero.
In this case because it's exactly the same it's just looking at the wall in the white and the wall in
the black.
So it would look for the nose in many different places and then it might find a nose somewhere else.
But then through other features it will understand that that's not the face.
But for now what will it find here in.
Once it gets to the actual nose it will see that yes.
In this case it it surpasses the three threshold that exceeds the threshold so this we're going to say
that there is this potentially or knows over here that might be a potential nose over there that might
be a potential nose or here but it's definitely going to say that there is no nose in many other places
and then through the other features and we'll learn more about this throughout the section.
It will be able to identify where exactly the nose is where exactly the faces but that's that's the
starting point.
And so that's where the threshold comes in.
The threshold is very useful to understand if this feature is actually present or if this is or we should
move on and there is this feature is not present in that location we're looking.
So that's how the Horlick features work.
Very important.
They lie in the foundation of this algorithm.
They're kind of like once those features that were identified in the face the like for eyebrows and
so on.
Once you once the Aluf you don't have to do this by your algorithm identifies through training a a number
of features quite a large number of features then that is kind of like forms the basis for to understand
what elements roughly a face is constructed from and then it will be able to use those to detect the
face.
But in the in a nutshell this is how it works through the pixels through the white and black regions
which it calculates averages for and then subtract.
So there we go.
Hope you enjoyed today said Tauriel and I'll look for see in the next one.
And until then enjoy computer vision.