On March 3rd, 2021, Flutter 2 was released.
And in this lecture and video
I'm going to explain what this means for Flutter,
for your code and for discourse.
And of course I'll also show you how you can upgrade Flutter
and your apps to Flutter 2.
Now, let me start with
the most important piece of information first.
Flutter 2 sounds like a big change
like a totally new version
that introduces a lot of new features or changes a lot.
And indeed it is labeled a major upgrade
but if we take a closer look,
we learn that actually not much changes.
Indeed the biggest new feature,
which is also advertised and emphasized
by the Flutter team itself
is that now we can build Flutter apps for any platform.
And that's the biggest new thing.
Flutter historically, was a framework using dart
to allow you to build cross-platform mobile apps
iOS and Android apps.
Now over the last months and years even
the flutter team worked towards the goal
of making Flutter a framework
which you can use to build apps for any platform,
including web apps.
So websites, which you open in the browser
and also desktop apps for Mac iOS, windows, and Linux.
And this sounds big and it indeed has to potential
of becoming a big major thing for Flutter
but at the moment, I'd say we're not there yet.
It turns out that support for windows macOS and Linux
at this moment at this time is still in beta
so it's not production ready yet.
So whilst you might be able to build windows,
macOS and Linux apps with Flutter,
it's not really at the point
where these apps could really be distributed to your users.
Now, when it comes to Flutter for web apps.
So for websites,
that feature is actually labeled production ready
by the flutter team,
but I don't fully agree there yet.
You can use Flutter and one code base
to build an app that runs on iOS, Android, and the web,
but when it comes to web development,
I don't feel that the apps Flutter spits out
are on the same level performance wise, for example
than native web apps built with native web technologies.
So yeah, this might become better in the future
but at this point of time
I personally don't plan on using Flutter for web apps.
Whereas I absolutely do think that building mobile apps
with Flutter is more than production ready.
So that's the first big feature
having this better cross-platform support
and with all the explanations
I gave you over the last minutes
it's hopefully clear that the impact of that
is not that big.
You can experiment with those new platforms
but the code you'll write is not impacted by that
and it also doesn't shift the main focus
and the main selling point of Flutter,
which is the mobile app part.
Now, if you dig a bit deeper into Flutter 2,
you will actually all defined very long release notes
with tons of information in there.
But it turns out that even though those notes along,
we mostly have fixes and small improvements here
nothing that would really impact your code
and change the way you write code with Flutter.
Now, there is one exception
and I updated some lectures in the course already
to reflect that.
And that would be Buttons.
With Flutter prior to version two,
you use the RaisedButtons, FlatButtons
and ElevatedButtons in your code
to bring some buttons onto the screen.
With Flutter version two,
those buttons are actually marked as deprecated now.
And in visuals duo code you might see
that they are having this strike through effect.
Now deprecated
does not mean that you can't use them anymore.
They will stick around for many months to come
and actually I would argue that in most projects that exist
and in most examples and other resources like Abra tutorials
you will still see those old buttons.
And this course also uses those old buttons
because of course,
this course was not recorded with Flutter 2.
Now you can switch to the new buttons
and in the lecture after this one,
I will quickly walk you through the migration path
from old buttons to new buttons
and I did also update some lectures in the course
where I first introduce a RaisedButton and FlatButton
to make you aware of these new buttons there as well.
But for going through that course,
I do strongly recommend
that you do stick to RaisedButton, FlatButton and so on
since that will make the course experience a bit smoother.
And if you wanna get rid of that warning
that strike through effect,
you can always go to your settings in visual studio code
search for deprecated there
and disable this "show deprecated" feature.
You can of course always migrate to the newer buttons
thereafter if you feel like it.
It will just make going through that course of it's smoother
because you don't have to adjust that code all the time.
Now, if you do want to migrate
from the old buttons to the new ones though,
check out the lecture after this one,
because dare I will show how you do migrate
and how you do change your code.
Now, before you can migrate any code
and before you can use Flutter 2 though,
you need to upgrade.
And that's very easy,
you just need to open up your terminal or a command prompt.
And in there, if you run flutter upgrade
that will simply download
and install you the latest version will Flutter
globally on your system
as you see, I already did update,
which is why it's telling me that I well,
have the latest version
and that will then upgrade for you as well.
And thereafter all your projects
will automatically use the Flutter 2 if you want to.
Now, of course, with such a long list of fixes
and minor and new features
there're of course are more features.
And that's why I also linked
the official announcement blog post here,
and also the more technical Flutter specific
insightful blog post.
Yeah, they basically just have two block posts
for announcing Flutter 2,
one marketing overview block posts
and one word technical block post both are linked.
Now in this blog post, you also find more details
about this update, more technical details
and for example, you also learn about new iOS features
and new widgets that were added.
You can of course, look into those
and play around with those as well.
But overall,
there really just aren't any code breaking changes.
Nonetheless, I also wanna point out a special tool
which the Flutter team now added.
And that's the the Flutter fixed tool.
It is a tool which you actually invoke
by calling dart fix in the command line of your projects.
And if you run that command,
if you run dart fix in your command prompt in your terminal
navigated into a project folder that will analyze your code
and make any changes that might need to be made.
Now at the moment, there aren't a lot of changes
that would need to be made, but nonetheless
it is worth knowing about dis tool as well
especially also for future Flutter updates
which then again might break more things.
And therefore, there are only two last questions.
What does Flutter 2 mean for you, your code and your apps
and what does it mean for this course
and your course progress.
Now, as I mentioned, despite his long list,
the only real feature or change that will impact your code
is that new buttons thing, which I mentioned
and which I'll dive in in the next lecture.
Besides that, the code will stay the way you'll learned it
and hence there aren't any major changes needed
to your code.
And even that change is technically optional as you learned.
You can stick to the old buttons,
deprecated does not mean that you can't use them anymore.
So even that change is optional
and hence there aren't any major code changes needed.
You can upgrade to Flutter 2, and you should be fine.
Now you can explore those new platforms if you want to
but of course you don't have to do that either.
You can stay focused on iOS and Android apps if you want to.
And for example,
that is what I will keep on using Flutter for personally,
Android and iOS development, at least for now.
And what does it mean for discourse?
I don't plan any big changes to this course right now.
Yes, I'm of course using those old buttons,
but I hope with the next lecture
and those minor adjustments
which I made to some of the lectures in the course,
I can make it clear how you can change to those new buttons
but that you don't have to change.
And other than that, there really aren't any major changes
that would impact this course.
Of course, those new operating systems are interesting,
but since three of them are still in beta
and the web support doesn't fully convince me yet,
I don't plan any near term additions or changes
related to that as well.
Now I will keep this course overall updated
and I won't rule out more major course upgrades
in the future
maybe I'll even redo the course entirely again
in the future, but for the very near term,
there are no such changes planned
simply because Flutter 2 despite its name,
doesn't change that much.