Now of course we could deploy any app,
I picked these great places app where we worked with the native device features, camera, maps and so on
to show you these different steps
and let's start with the testing and code optimization step.
Now testing simply means that you should run your app on as many devices as possible, so you should make
sure that you test your app on different device screens, on older devices, smaller devices, bigger devices,
of course on Android and iOS devices if you want to target both platforms and as much as you can, on
real devices to really see if your app works correctly,
if there are any bugs, if it looks good, if it's fast enough. Regarding the performance, you can always
go back to be Flutter internals module in this course where I explain how Flutter rebuilds and what
you can do to optimize your app,
for example split your bigger widgets which are rebuilding into smaller widgets, so that smaller parts
of your app rebuild or use const constructors, for example in places where you have const values like
this text widget here which should effectively never rebuild,
you can add const in front of this to tell Flutter that when this widget rebuilds, this widget, this text
widget doesn't need to rebuild because it will never change, things like that.
Now you will always find certain improvements, optimizations and maybe also some bugs after you deployed,
after you published your app
and that is absolutely normal.
Of course you should really rule out as many bugs as possible but for performance optimizations like
this one here, if you tested your app on a broad variety of devices, also on older devices and it worked
fine everywhere, then this is not the end of the world
and you can always and you should of course update your already published app, publish a new version
and your users will automatically download and use it.
So highest priority really is that you ship an error free application and thereafter, performance
improvements or other tiny improvements, you will always find new ways of improving your app
and that's a normal part of development.
So don't worry about overlooking some step,
testing is the important thing, with your tested app,
you can always publish updated versions thereafter.