- [Instructor] Now, with
the course introduction
and all the basics out of the way,
and with Flutter and
Android Studio and so on
installed on our system,
it's now finally time to
dive into Flutter development
and to learn Flutter and Dart.
And for that, we're going to
create a new project here.
So for that, again, use the cd command
to navigate into some
folder on your system
where you want to create that project.
And then once you navigated there
in your terminal or command prompt,
you run "flutter create"
to create a new project
and give it any name you want.
And I'll name it "flutter_complete_guide."
The project name is up to you,
but it should not contain
any dots or dashes
or white spaces.
Instead, if you have multiple words,
separate them with underscores.
And the convention also is
to use an all lowercase name
like I'm using it here.
And then simply hit
enter, and as you learn,
this will now create a new folder
in that path where you
navigated to before,
and stored these initial
Flutter project files
in that folder.
And then we can again
use Visual Studio Code
or Android Studio to open that folder.
And that's what I did here.
So then, be get our Flutter project here.
Now, this Flutter
project, which I got here
has a web folder,
and I'll delete that folder
since we're not going to build
for the web here.
So I'll just move that to trash.
But I'll keep all the
other folders and files
which I have in there.
Now, I'll walk you through
these folders and files
and what they do in the next lecture.
For the moment, I just want to make sure
that we have to same
kind of starting project.
And to ensure this, attached
you find my "pubspec.yaml" file
and a "main.dart" file.
And you should replace your
"main.dart" file with mine
and delete any other files
or folders you might have
in your lib folder with mine,
and replace your
"pubspec.yaml" file with mine.
This is really important.
Now one important
note regarding my pubspec.yaml file:
I named my project flutter_complete_guide,
and if you chose a different
name for your project, you might get an error.
What you
should do in that case is take your project name.
So the name of your project folder,
which in my case is "flutter_complete_guide".
But if you had a different name
here, if you chose a different name when creating
the project with
"flutter create", you should plug that name here
into the "pubspec.yaml" file instead of
"flutter_complete_guide".
In addition, you might get an error in this widget_test.dart file.
widget_test.dart file here.
After adding my main.dart file to the project.
Now you can ignore this.
Ever since this test file is there for
automated tests,
and that's not something we'll do in this course.
But to get
rid of that problem, you can simply delete the test
folder or that test file because we won't need it.
We will instead
work in the lib folder because that's where
we put the code we write for our application.
You then also might want
to open this terminal,
and in that terminal, run
"flutter packages get."
Typically this should not
be required because Flutter
should run it behind the
scenes automatically,
but this is important to
ensure that Flutter picks up
that "pubspec.yaml" file,
which I provided to you.
And this is really just
important to ensure
that we're all starting on the same page
and you can follow along smoothly.
Now, as I said, in the next lecture,
I'll walk you through
these folders and files.
For the moment, I just want to make sure
that we can start this project here
as an application on an emulator,
and you can use either the
iOS or Android emulator,
but since everyone,
including Windows users
will be able to use Android emulators,
I'll go for that.
So just as in the previous core section,
I'll quickly spin up an emulator again.
Of course, you might still have one
from the last section and then
you can absolutely use that.
So, here I'll just quickly
set up that emulator.
And once that emulator
is up and running here,
we can run our Flutter
app on that emulator,
either by using that terminal,
which you can open with
terminal, new terminal,
and running "flutter run".
Or better, as you learned in
the previous core section,
by going to "run," "run
without debugging."
And then this should automatically run it.
Now you might get this
dropdown where you have
to choose how you want
to run your project.
And here, I will choose Dart and Flutter.
And then this will run your
application on Android,
on the Android emulator and build it
as an Android app automatically since we
do have this Android
emulator up and running here.
Now, the first time you run this,
as you saw in the previous core section
can take a bit longer.
But once this is finished,
we should have this counter app running
on the Android emulator again.
And then we can use this
control panel up here
to reload this app whenever
we need to do that.
But as I showed you in
the last core section,
whenever you change your code
and you save your code changes,
the great thing about this
way of running the Flutter app
is that it will automatically reload
whenever you change your code.
So, let's now wait for this to start up.
And here we go, here's this application.
And again, if it just started,
it might still be a bit slow,
but it should get more responsive quickly.
And then you can play around with it here,
and edit your code here.
And therefore that's now what we're going
to do for all the discourse section.
In the next lecture,
we'll explore the files
and folders we got here
and what they do.