So how does authentication work then?
We have our server, Firebase in this example but can be any server and we have our Flutter app and of
course, the goal is that these two communicate and that we might have certain requests we're sending
from the Flutter app to the server which actually should be protected,
for example placing a order or creating a new product might be something that should only be possible
for logged in users or maybe any action should only be possible for logged in users,
that of course depends on your use case and which kind of app you're building.
So the goal will be that we present some login screen to our users and on that screen, users can enter
their credentials and authenticate themselves with the server.
So we'll send a password and an e-mail to the server and the server will then either create a new entry
for that user and store it in a database or if that already happened and the user tries to login, the
server will check and validate the password and if it's correct and matches the e-mail, then the
user is treated as authenticated but now the interesting part happens, how does that work?
How does the server treat a user as authenticated
and how do we manage that?
If you have a web development background, and if you don't it's no problem, but if you have that background,
you might be aware of the concept of sessions. In web development,
you could create sessions on a server to basically store an entry on the server in a database for example
that basically logs that a user with a given ID is currently logged in and in your front-end,
so in the browser basically, you would also store a cookie which identifies that session, so which has
the ID of the entry in the database which in turn knows that this user is logged in and then browser
and server can communicate to find out hey the user using this app in this browser is currently
logged in.
This is how this would work and I'll not go into more details here because this is actually not how
this works in Flutter because in Flutter and also in many web apps
but here we're building a Flutter app,
you work with RESTful APIs and these APIs are stateless. Now
this has nothing to do with stateless widgets of course,
instead it means that the server,
the API does not care about the individual client that connected,
we don't store anything in the database that tells us that a certain user of a certain app or website
or anything is authenticated,
that's not how it works.
Instead the job of the API is to provide certain endpoints to which you can send requests and then
we simply return an answer,
we don't want to take care about managing who's authenticated and who's not.
So using a session is not the idea,
instead you use a token.
The idea behind the token is that once the user logged in, such a token is generated on the server with
a certain algorithm and a certain private key that's only known to the server so that the token can't
be faked and that token is the end a very long string which is sent back to the Flutter mobile app.
Now in the Flutter app, you then go ahead and store that token on the device, not on a server, not in the
database in a web but on the device,
so in this module, we'll also have a look at on device storage. That token is stored on device because
this allows us to read it from there
when the app restarts for example because that will clear all the memory we had,
so storing the token in a variable would not suffice,
that would be lost when the app restarts but storing it on the device storage, on the device hard drive
so to say makes sure that we can fetch that token even when the app restarted.
But of course the question is yes,
what's the idea behind that token?
The server now works such that for endpoints which should actually be protected and only be available
for logged in users,
it requires us to add such a token to the incoming request.
So if we send a request to an endpoint which is actually locked down, let's say the endpoint to create
a new user,
so a post request to a certain URL, then that request will be declined and an error will be sent back
if no valid token is attached to the request
and of course in this module, you will learn how that attachment of the token works.
So only if we have a token and it has to be a valid token created by that server, with that algorithm,
with that private key which only the server knows,
so only if we attach that token to the request, the server knows
OK you got that token,
the only source where you could have gotten that token from is me, the server and therefore, you are logged
in because you clearly proved that earlier.
So the server doesn't have to store that we're logged in, the token tells the server that we are logged
in and because of that private key which is used for generating that token which is only known by the
server, the server can also tell that that token is not faked or some random string but that that
token was created by this server.
This is how authentication works, that's a rough idea
and that is what we will implement now in this module. We'll not focus on that server side, on the token
generation part because this is no server side course.
If you want to learn more about that, you could use a language like NodeJS and I do cover all that
behind the scenes server side stuff there in my NodeJS, The Complete Guide Course for example, from
Flutter side, we'll only have to take care about storing and managing and attaching that token,
so that's what we'll focus on in this module.
Thankfully, Firebase has this token creation mechanism built-in and we can easily enable authentication
there and lock down our endpoints in Firebase,
so we'll have a server that supports all of that automatically.
With that, let's dive in.