Now let's briefly plan what we're going to build and where we're going to add which feature in our application.
We're essentially have two main screens.
We'll have this authentication part where you enter email, username and password and where you can
also pick and upload an image.
And once a user is authenticated, we'll also have this chat screen where you can send messages and
also see messages by our users always combined with their image and all the user name.
We'll also implement push notifications there at the end to make sure that if our app is closed, we
actually get a notification about a new message and we can then tap this message to, well, bring this
app back up.
Now in this module we're going to use Firebase.
And Firebase is a fully managed backend service.
It's by Google, just like Flutter, but it's totally independent from Flutter.
You don't have to use Firebase with Flutter.
It works without Flutter as well.
Now, we actually already did use Firebase in this course.
We used it as a dummy backend API in the HTTP section and so on.
Firebase is not just that though.
I used it there because that allowed me to show you how you can connect flutter to any backend without
having to write any backend code here because this is a flutter course.
So therefore I wanted to focus on flutter, but that's the only reason why I used Firebase there.
We didn't really utilize any amazing Firebase features in those sections.
Well, now we're going to do that and I will show you that if you use Firebase, not just because it's
a nice dummy backend, but because you want to use it and you want to build a complete app where Firebase
runs your backend that Firebase ships with a lot of cool features that make building a powerful app
a breeze and integrating Firebase into Flutter is actually also pretty straightforward.
But what do I mean when I say fully managed backend service?
What is Firebase all about in the end?
Well, Firebase consists of a bunch of cool services.
For example, it comes with data storage with a database, and it comes with an API that makes talking
through that database easy.
To be precise, it also comes with a bunch of sticks.
So with a bunch of packages which you can install in, for example, flutter apps to make working with
Firebase Extra Simple.
Now, besides the database for storing data, Firebase, for example, also has a file storage for,
you guessed it, storing files and uploading files with the Firebase SDK, which we're going to do in
this module, will also be extra simple.
Firebase also comes with built in authentication services so that you can easily add authentication
to your app without having to write your own logic for that, which can be fairly difficult and which
of course also has to be done right to avoid security issues.
Now, Firebase also comes with a push notification service, which makes sending push notifications
to both Android as well as iOS apps very, very easy.
And we're going to utilize this in this module as well.
And Firebase also has more than that.
It comes with analytics services.
You can run server side code with a feature called Cloud Functions if you need to do that so that you
can run your own code and not just talk to their preconfigured database and it has much, much more.
We're not going to explore everything here because this, of course, is a flatter course, not a firebase
course, but we'll use some of the coolest feature in detail in this module, to be precise.
We're going to work with the data storage and database, with the file storage and authentication,
and we'll also see some on demand server side code in action with help of those cloud functions.
So a lot of stuff to do.
Let's get started with an app and let's start building that app and that's then step by step, add cool
Firebase features to it.