Now to build an app.
I have a brand new Flutter app here.
A basic app as it comes created by Flutter Create.
And you find this snapshot, this main dart and this pops backdoored yaml file attached in case you
want to start with the exact same app.
And I also already launched it here on an Android emulator.
And as you can see, this is really our standard starting app here.
So now let's turn it into the app we actually want.
And for that, of course, I'm going to utilize all that knowledge we gathered throughout that course,
though the app we build will not be too fancy because I rather want to focus on those Firebase features
and how to utilize those features in a Flutter app in this module.
Nonetheless, we'll need a bunch of different elements here, to be precise, will at least need to
screens because we'll definitely have those two screens, login and authentication screen and the chat
screen.
And of course we'll also need a couple of widgets.
Now for that I'll add a screens folder where we can add those screens and a widgets folder which will
hold any other widgets which are not standalone screens in the screens folder.
I'll add my auth underscore screen start file which will hold the authentication screen and I'll also
add the chat screen which you guessed it will hold the chat.
And for widgets, we'll add them as we go and as we need them.
Now, I will actually start with a basic chat screen here.
We will actually need authentication before we can chat, but I want to show you how Firebase works,
and that is best shown with the database feature.
And therefore we'll start with the chat and we'll turn it into a real chat with users later.
So on the chat screen, let's create a new stateless widget actually, which will name chat screen and
make sure that in this file you import material dart from the flutter package.
And here I will not just return such a container, but I actually want to return a list view of chat
messages.
Now for that, I'll use that builder mode here to have that item builder and you'll learn about that
in the course.
The item builder here takes a function, essentially, which gets the context and the index of the item
that is being built.
And then here in this arrow function, for example, we return the item, the widget that should be
built for every item we have in the list view.
So here we could build a simple, let's say, container where we have some padding with edge insets,
all of eight to have a padding of eight in all directions, and then a child, which is simply some
text.
This works like that.
Now the list view builder also needs the item count so that we know how many items should be created.
And I'm just going to build ten items here soon.
We'll build this dynamically.
Now the chat screen, of course, should be visible.
So let's go back to the main dart file and here I'll rename this title to flutter chat and get rid of
that comment.
Here, get rid of this comment here.
And here under home, I will not render my home page here.
Instead, I'll delete all that code down there.
And instead I will just render my chart screen here.
So make sure you add that import here to the chat screen dart file from your own package.
This import is also fine to use from the screen's folder and the chat screen dart file.
And with that, we have our chat screen being rendered here.
Now, if we save everything and you have a running emulator and you run your application on that emulator,
you should see this works here.
Now, this looks ugly because we're missing a scaffold.
So let's go back to the chat screen and we can refactor this to wrap the list view with the widget and
wrap it with a scaffold here.
Now, the scaffold does not have a child, but a body instead.
And if we do just that and we save this, this already looks a bit nicer.
Now, that's, of course, just some dummy static data.
So therefore, let's now explore Firebase and see how that works.