For this module, I'll start with a brand new project and you can therefore simply create a brand new project
with Flutter create, attached
you'll find the main.dart file here which will actually get you started or which will give you the content
I have here in the main.dart file,
it's only one simple widget where we're currently missing a home screen where I just added some theme
set up here to have some nice colors
and that's basically all for now, we'll add the rest together. Now as already mentioned,
I will add all these screens and widgets together with you but it will not be the main focus of this
module and I'll pretty much only use features there which we already learned about in this course,
so I'll walk through that relatively quick and instead focus on how to work with native device features.
So let's jump right in and let's add a screens folder here because we will have a couple of screens
of course, to be precise,
we'll have a screen for our places list, so all the places we have,
that's our starting screen basically.
We'll then have a place detail screen, so I'll just create all these files for now and then we'll add
content to them later,
so places list screen, place detail screen, we'll also need an add place screen which is that screen
we open when we click the plus icon in the appBar to add a new place and that will be it for now. We'll
add more later but these are the three main screens we'll have in our application.
Now let's start with the places list screen because that should be our starting screen.
That can be a stateless widget because in there, we don't really change the screen from inside,
there is no data in there that would change from inside,
so I'll just name this here places list screen, like that
and as you already are used to, I'll of course import material.dart from the Flutter package.
Now in this places list screen, I want to have a scaffold of course because I want to render an entire
page there
and in the scaffold, I'll add an appBar with a title which is a text widget where we could
say your places, anything like that because in the end, on the screen here, we'll display all the places
of this user. Now in the appBar,
I also want to have some actions because there, we certainly need an icon button in the actions list
here which shows a plus,
so an add icon here that allows us to add new places or to switch to that new places screen.
So on pressing this, we'll soon navigate,
for now I'll just have an empty anonymous function here because I'll add the navigation logic later.
This is the add button here though, besides that in our scaffold, of course we need a body and in the
body here,
I want to output my list of places obviously. For the moment, I'll add a center widget here
with a child in there where I just show a CircularProgressIndicator but of course we'll soon add some
real data. For that
however, we'll need a place to manage data and I'll again do this with the provider package,
so let's add providers folder there and in there, I'll add a great_places.dart file simply
because we're managing all the great places we collected, you could name it just places or user places
or whatever you want of course. Now in addition, I want to define how a place looks like and that will
actually be a definition which won't change internally, to which I don't want to listen,
so I'll create a separate models folder to again have that separation between data models which
will be provided and to which changes I want to listen and to also have models like here in the models
folder to which changes
I won't listen because I'm not interested or because the data won't really change.
So in there, I'll just add a place.dart file to define how a place should look like. So let's start in
that place.dart file maybe and let's think about how a place should look like
and for that, we can create a place
class of course to have a blueprint for how a place should look like in this application
and I'd say each place should have an ID,
so that will be an ID which is a string. Each place should have a title
and these are all the things I already mentioned in the planning lecture.
Each place should have a location and we'll worry about the data type in a second
and each place should have an image
and we'll worry about that data type in a second too. Now of course, I want to have a constructor where
we assign values to these properties and I'll use named arguments here
by wrapping them in curly braces and I always want to require them all,
so let's also import foundation.dart from the Flutter package so that we can use the @required decorator
here and then I want to require the ID,
I also want to require the title,
I also want to require the location and unsurprisingly, I also want to require the image.
Now back to location and image, which data types do I want to use there?
Well since we'll now work with images that are stored on the device, I'll actually use the file data type
here.
Now file is not a data type built into Flutter but actually into Dart, to unlock it,
you need to import dart:io.
This gives you access to methods and to types that help you work with files and the file system
and that's something Flutter is able to leverage.
So here we'll work with files,
each image is a file on our device, not a string, not a URL to some image stored in the web but instead
a file on our device. Now for location, a location should actually be a combination of things.
Locations are typically expressed as coordinates which are defined with a latitude and a longitude which
are geographic measures basically
and I also want to store an address. So I'll create another class in here which I'll name place location
and a place location is, as I just said, made up of a latitude which actually should be a double because
that's just a number, latitude and longitude are just numbers,
they're basically coordinates and also a longitude.
So we've these two coordinates which are used to describe a place on earth and that's a common way
of measuring or of locating things on the planet because latitude and longitude together
allow you to identify a unique place on the world
and in addition to that as I mentioned, I'll store the address which is simply a human readable address
and therefore, it should be a string.
Now just as with the place, here I want to add a constructor, again maybe with named arguments where we
expect the latitude, where we expect the longitude and where we expect the address and the latitude
should certainly be required,
so should be the longitude and for the address,
I actually don't require this here because we will be able to work without that since latitude
and longitude are the key things when it comes to finding a location on the planet.
The address is just the human readable part and we don't need that in all parts of the app we're building.
So latitude and longitude and therefore here, location in the place model, in the place class should
be of type place location, so of our own class here and as you learned, every class you defined also automatically
creates a type you can use.
So this is how places should look like in the application and in great places, we'll manage these places.
So great places is just another class here which will use the ChangeNotifier mixin though, which
you can also import from foundation.dart and ChangeNotifier, as you learned, is a mixin that allows you
to call notifyListeners which then is used by the provider package to update all places where
you listen to that provided object thereafter. In the great places, I want to use the place model, so I'll import
that from the models folder, from the place.dart file, so that in there, we can have a list of places in
the end and I'll name that items and initially, it will be an empty list.
Now just as we did it in earlier modules, I also want to provide a getter which allows us to retrieve
a copy of our items, so I'll name this just items without an underscore and here, I'll return a copy of items,
again so that we can always get access to the items from anywhere in the app
but we get access to a copy of the items, so if we change that list from the place where we're getting
access to it, then we won't change the list here
in this class which is certainly something we want to avoid,
so we want to make sure that this can't be changed from outside because if you would change it from
outside, you wouldn't trigger notifyListeners and therefore you would change data without updating
the app which would be bad
and that's it for now, we'll add more methods here, like a method for adding a place when we need it.
With that, we have our data model here set up,
now we need to provide it so that we can listen to it. Now
the place to provide it unsurprisingly is again the main.dart file.
There, I'll basically wrap the entire MaterialApp with a new widget and that will be the
ChangeNotifierProvider widget to provide this class with the provider package.
But one thing is missing, in order to do that, we need to install the provider package
and since this is a brand new project, we'll actually have to add the provider package before we can use
it.
For this, you can again visit pub.dev and there search for provider and find that provider package
there and it's the exact same package we used before.
So there, under installing,
copy that entry here with that version, the latest version of course you're having when you're viewing
this video and then go to your pubspec.yaml file and under dependencies, below Flutter here, on
the right level,
so on the same level as Flutter, add this package. Simply save this and it should be installed automatically,
in case it's not, as always you can go to the terminal and there, run Flutter packages get to install
all the packages for this project.
Now with that, we got the provider package installed, in main.dart
we can therefore now import it. So import package/provider/provider.dart
and now the ChangeNotifierProvider is available there.
Now here, I'll use the value constructor and therefore, we have to provide a value argument and that
should be an instance of my great places class.
So let's go to the providers folder and there to great places
and let's instantiate great places here. Now besides the value, we of course also have the child argument
here for the value constructor and therefore with that, we should be all set to provide this data.
Now we just have to make sure that we use the places list screen here as our home screen,
so let's actually import this as well,
the places list screen here and let's render it here or add it here as a value for the home argument
in the MaterialApp, places list screen, like that.
With this, the content in the main.dart file is finished for now,
we're providing an instance of great places by instantiating it here and providing it with
ChangeNotifierProvider value and therefore now in the places lists screen which is a child of this widget and of this
widget because we're passing it as the argument to home, in the places list screen, we can start consuming
our places and of course, I want to consume the places here in the body.
However, I only want to do this once we have places and for now, we don't have any, so we'll add this later.
Let's next work on this add place screen because that is the screen where we then will start working
with native device features like the camera of course.