Now which application will we build in this module?
We'll build an expense planner
and that means that users should be able to add their expenses, like what you bought yesterday,
bottle of milk, maybe some new shoes. You can add them and we keep track of those expenses in a list and
then we also show a little chart
that basically sums up what we spend over the last week.
So our application will look something like this and now come my awesome drawing skills.
This is our iPhone or our Android phone
and in there, in this application here, we'll therefore have a couple of things. We'll have our little chart
up there which we'll build which will basically have little bars that indicate how much we spend on each
day over the last week.
Below the chart, I want to have a list of the transactions which we registered and for each transaction,
we kind of save the price let's say, so what we spend and then a little title here, something like that.
I also want to make sure that we can of course add new items here
and for that, we'll have a little plus button here in the app bar and I also want to have a so-called
floating action button here at the bottom, which also has a plus and both buttons, because this of course
still is also a course where I want to show you something, will trigger in the end not a new page
but a new mode on the existing page.
So we're still on the same page where we have that chart and so on
but once we press one of these plus buttons, a little bottom sheet should slide in,
so this is a little sheet coming in from the bottom overlaying the rest of this application,
so behind that would be our list of transactions here
and in that bottom sheet, we'll have some inputs for the title and for the price and also a date picker
so that we can pick a date and then of course, a button to confirm this.
Now I can certainly draw nicer than that or maybe I can't but we can certainly build this app and we'll
build this app with some of the widgets Flutter gives us, with more than just the basic widgets we
use thus far and we'll then also use the various theming and styling features Flutter gives us to
make this application look good.
With that, let's get started.