So that was Android emulator and the real device.
Now what about iOS?
Now important to build an iOS app, you need the Mac OS operating system.
That is a restriction applied by Apple.
You can't build your Flutter app for iOS on Windows or Linux.
You need Mac OS.
If you are on Mac OS, then you can of course also test the app on a simulator or also on a real device.
Now for that you need Xcode and I showed you how to install Xcode in the first module of this course.
So you should be able to launch Xcode and see that welcome screen there.
Now in there, open another project.
Click that button.
And then navigate to your Flutter project folder and there to the iOS folder and choose that runner
Xcode Project file.
Open that as a project in Xcode.
Now here you could write code, but that's not what we'll do.
We'll stick to Visual Studio code for that.
But here we can also configure this so that we can run it on a simulator.
And there's one important thing you need to set up.
Click on this project icon here on this route, icon here, this route element in the left bar here
where you can get by clicking this folder icon here.
So click on that so that you have this view.
And then here you might see that signing for Runner requires a development team for that.
Here in this dropdown, you should choose a team and normally you should have one.
If you don't have a team here, click on add an account and add your Apple account with your apple ID
here to Xcode.
So here you can either create a new one if you don't have one, or you log in with an existing account.
Now important for developing iOS apps, you need an Apple developer account and you can activate one
for your Apple ID, which you probably already have by going to developer Apple.com.
And their click on account.
Now here you now have to log in with your apple ID and the process should start, which turns you into
an apple developer.
Whilst you need to agree to some terms, what you don't need to do to develop apps is pay.
You will have to pay a fee to really publish your app to the Apple App Store.
But for developing and testing your app, you don't need a paid account, so no need to pay.
You just need a normal apple developer account.
Once you have that, you should be able to select your team here in Xcode and use that for this project.
Now, once you did this, once, you should be fine.
And now you can run your project either through Xcode by selecting a simulator here and clicking the
run button or select a real connected device if you have one.
But you can also do it here from within which due to code, by going to the terminal and there in your
normal system terminal.
You can run open.
Dash a simulator app.
And what this will do is it will bring up an iOS simulator.
Here it is.
Let me close.
Xcode.
We don't need that anymore.
Let me move the Android simulator over there.
And now here.
And now here is the ice simulator.
And again, you could have launched that through Xcode as well if you wanted to.
Now, this is booting up and as soon as this simulator is done booting up, we can select it down here.
Well, actually, I can already do that.
So you can select your simulator here in the bottom right corner of Visual Studio code by clicking on
that bar here.
Then select the iOS device or as before, shut down all our simulators, disconnect all our devices
from your machine, and it should automatically pick this one.
And once you did all of that, just as before, you can again run your app there with the flutter run
command or through the debug menu here in Visual Studio code and start without debugging, for example.
And now this will also build the app, but it will now build it with the help of Xcode because now in
iOS app is built and once it's done building the app, it will ship it onto the simulator.
So let's wait for Dad to finish.
Here's the app running on iOS now, and one thing you might notice is that it looks exactly the same
as it looks on an Android device.
The reason for that is that Flutter does not automatically adjust the styles to the iOS.
Look, it does not automatically give you that iOS look.
Remember that with flutter you in the end use a framework that controls every pixel.
It's not using native device or native platform user interface elements.
So a button here is not compiled to an iOS button for iOS and to an Android button for Android instead
of button always looks the same because Flutter draws it onto the screen.
It's not using some platform primitive, not a built in UI element, and therefore these apps look similar.
Now, later in the course you will indeed learn how to adjust your look though other than the font,
the font family is actually different automatically, but you will learn how you can adjust your app
to look like an Android app on Android and an iOS app on iOS.
If you want that or you create your own, look for all platforms, whatever you need.
All that is possible with Flutter and well of course, have a look at all these options throughout the
course.
Now, more important than the look is, of course, that it works correctly and that is the case here.
So now we can also test the app here on the iOS simulator and we're just fine.
Everything is working correctly now.
What about a real iOS device then?