Obviously before we can start using the various tools for passing data around and so on, we need to build
a couple of these screens which we need.
So here I am in a blank project again and you'll find this blank setup attached to this lecture here,
it's an empty Flutter project just as the default main.dart file, slightly edited, I changed the text in
the appBar here and right now if I start this application here on my Android emulator again, it will
only have a center text where I say navigation time. I also haven't added any specific theme here,
I'm just going with the default settings of having a blue theme here, though these are all things which
we'll adjust throughout
this module, so we'll primarily of course work on making sure that we have navigation and so on but we'll
also of course make sure that we build a pretty application.
So here's the dummy application,
pretty empty right now
and the thing I want to start with is that starting page which shows us various categories of meals
like Italian, veggie and so on and then the detail page for each category, which then in turn shows us
the recipes for that category,
that's the idea here.
So in the code, I think it makes sense to start with that categories page where we see all the available
categories, where we then can tap on one to see the meals, the dishes for that category.
So it would make sense that this is our first new widget we add and this will not only be a widget,
it will also be a screen of our app.
Now technically, there is absolutely no difference between a screen and a widget,
every widget can be used as a screen,
it only is a term that describes a widget which we use to control an entire page on our app,
like my home page widget which we get out of the box, it controls the entire page
we have here. Typically, any widget that uses scaffold is a page, is a screen widget.
Again, not technically or as a hard rule but since scaffold sets up the configuration for the entire
screen, for the entire page, by adding an appBar and setting a body,
this typically is a widget used in a screen widget.
So let's add a new file which should hold this new widget and I'll name this
categories_screen.dart.
The _screen part is absolutely not required,
it's a personal preference so that we can quickly see that in this file, we have a widget which we use
as a screen.
It's not a must use but I personally like it a lot.
Now what should go into these categories screen then? Well I'll create a stateless widget in here because
right now, the plan is to only output a list of categories and I'll name this categories screen.
So that's the name of my widget here, again to make it really clear that this widget is not getting used
as part of another widget but really to control the entire content of a screen,
so the entire content on our device here in this app.
Now as always when we create a widget, we have to import flutter/material.dart to get access to the stateless
widget, the BuildContext, the container widget class and so on
and now the question of course is what do we return in this CategoriesScreen widget. Well the idea here
is to return a grid with all our categories.
So a grid is basically like a list but the difference is that in a grid, we have multiple items sit
next to each other,
so side by side instead of just from top to bottom above each other. We can simply build a grid in Flutter
with the GridView.
So we have the ListView for a simple list where we have no items side by side and the GridView
if we want to have items side by side. Now just as to the ListView,
you can pass
children
and by the way just as the ListView,
the GridView also has a builder mode which you can use if you want to build a dynamic amount of items,
if you don't know in advance how many items you'll have or if it's a very long grid and therefore, you
want that performance optimization where only items that are on the screen are getting rendered.
For our purposes here however, we can definitely use the GridView with a fixed amount of children because
we'll not have that many categories,
they'll also not change dynamically and hence we also should have no performance problems.
Now I'll take care about the children here and the category items we're going to render in a second,
let's first focus on setting up the general look and structure of this grid and we do that with another
argument we have to pass, which also is mentioned here in this warning, we have to pass the gridDelegate
argument or parameter. So gridDelegate is another named argument we have to provide and the value for this
looks really strange,
it's a
SliverGridDelegateWithMaxCrossAxisExtent. That is a horribly long name,
what does that do however? Now slivers in Flutter are really just scrollable areas on the screen and
of course, our grid just like the ListView, is scrollable as a default.
Grid delegate, that simply means that for the grid,
this takes care about structuring, layouting the grid, so this task of providing a layout is delegated away
to this class here so to say. Well and WithMaxCrossAxisExtent simply means that this is a
preconfigured class which allows us to define a maximum width for each grid item and then it will automatically
create as many columns as we can fit items with that provided width next to each other.
So therefore here, we pass a MaxCrossAxisExtent, so the maximum extent or width of the tiles, so of
the grid items
and here I'll use 200 pixels and now it really depends on the device size how many columns we'll get
in that grid. If we have a device with 300 pixels width,
then we'll only have one item per row and hence it will look like a list. If we have a device with 500
pixels width,
well then we'll have two items sit side by side.
Besides this MaxCrossAxisExtent,
we can also define a child aspect ratio to define how the items should be sized regarding their height
and width relation
and here I want to have a 3 by 2 relation,
so of course you could just pass 1.5 but this expresses my extent way clearer.
So for 200 width, I want to have 300 height in the end and you can add some spacing, some
crossAxisSpacing of 20 and some mainAxisSpacing of 20 which simply means how much distance is between
our columns and rows in that grid.
So with that, we are designing the look of our grid,
now we have to provide some children here and that of course will be our categories. For that,
I'll give you some dummy data but first of all, I want to define how a category should look like.
So now, we'll add a definition of how the data we work with in this app will look like
and we did this earlier,
if you remember in an earlier course section, for the transaction. There we provided a so-called model
and we'll do the exact same here.
I'll add a new folder, models and in there, I'll add my category.dart file,
so there I will define how a category looks like in this application. In the category.dart file,
I'll create a class named category and this will now not be a widget, so I don't extend stateless or
stateful widget,
it'll just be a normal Dart class which I can instantiate.
Now how should a category look like? Each category, each category item should have an ID which is a
string, so a unique identifier.
I want to have a title, so the name of the category like Asian or Italian and then also a color which
will be used as a background color. Now just as we did it before in this course as well, I'll provide a
constructor, category
here,
where we can pass data for all these different properties and color is a type that's not baked into
Dart, instead
this is provided by Flutter,
so we have to import material.dart from Flutter.
Now in the constructor here, I'll use named arguments but of course you could use positional arguments
as well
and then here, I'll expect an ID,
I'll expect a title and I also expect to get a color, though for the color, I'll provide a default of colors
orange,
also to practice this again, this is how you would provide default values for named arguments in case
no value is provided for this named argument.
I want to make sure that we always get an ID and a title though and we can do this by adding @required
which is a decorator provided by Flutter and it is for example included in the material.dart file.
So since we have that import, we get access to this decorator and now we would get a warning or an error
if we tried to create a category without an ID or title.
So this is how a category should look like
and with that defined, I'll add a new file, dummy_data.dart, which you find attached
which you can simply add to your project
and this contains a const variable here, which holds a const and therefore unchangeable list with some
default categories following our model.
Now one thing which I need to do here, I need to import material.dart from the Flutter package so that
colors is available here, should already be part of the attached file though so you will not have to
add this. And now also important,
we're getting an error here because I'm actually creating a const list here which means this can't
change, the values in the list can't change
and this is only accepted if each category object is also immutable.
So if we can't go to a created object and after its creation, change its color to a different value
and therefore we should go back to the model and add const in front of the constructor here and now
this means since all these properties are final, the properties of an object can't be changed after the
object has been created and therefore, we now really have a list where the values will never change.
So that's just some dummy data which I provide right now since we have no server or database where
we could get that data from and you'll find this finished file attached. This file has all the data I
want to load into this categories screen now to render the categories.