So now that we know that storing data in the web or on the server can make sense, another question which
I see quite a lot is how can I connect Flutter or the same is true for web apps
actually to a database?
So how can I connect Flutter to a MySQL or NoSQL or whatever
in this database
and with that, I mean a database that runs in the web on a server, not some on device database.
The answer here is, you don't directly connect Flutter to your database because that's technically complex
and also insecure
and because it's insecure, it's technically complex because it's basically not a scenario which people
want you to use and therefore, there are no easy solutions to set up such a connection.
Now why is it insecure? If you're connecting your Flutter app directly to a database, that means that
in your Flutter app code, you need to include your database credentials, your username and your password
to give you read and write access to the database.
Now when you ship your Flutter app to the app stores and users download the app from there, of course
your source code is not easily available,
users can't read your source code when they install your app from the App Store but you can't rule out
100% that some users might get around that and might be able to get your app bundle and kind
of uncompile it and find out your credentials.
It is definitely very challenging and unlikely but you can't totally rule out that this could happen
and then if people have your credentials for your database, they can access all your data of all your
users.
They can delete everything, they can copy everything,
it's a nightmare,
so you definitely don't want your database credentials in your source code.
You want to have these credentials in a place which your users have no direct access to
and that would be a web server.
Therefore, you typically connect Flutter to a web server by sending HTTP requests there and then
the web server in turn reaches out to a database. The source code of the web server is stored on that
server
and yes of course theoretically, servers can get hacked but there are protection mechanisms against that.
Unlike your app, people can't just download it and then do their best to crack your code,
instead they have to crack your server first and if it's well protected, that will be almost impossible
or entirely impossible
and therefore having a web server which actually stores your credentials and interacts with a database
is way more secure and this is hence the approach which you want to use, you have a web server in-between
which establishes the connection to the database and your Flutter app only communicates with that web
server.
It's the same by the way if you are building a web app for the exact same reasons.
So this is the approach we'll also follow in this module, now we'll not write a web server from scratch
though because this is not a web development course and we don't use Flutter or Dart to create a web
server,
instead we'll use a service which is free to use, Firebase, which gives us a web server out of the box
where we don't have to write any code which just works and which also gives us a database attached to
that web server, to which it automatically communicates, so that we have an easy way of interacting
with that server and learn how Flutter talks to web servers.