This module is based on an article in the official docs which you will of course find linked to this
lecture and also in the last lecture of
this module. So definitely read that article to have a written form of this module
basically in order to find alternative examples for writing native code with Kotlin or with Swift because
I will cover Android with Java and then also iOS code with Objective C in this module. So check out this
article for sure but of course, I'll walk you through it and explain step-by-step how to make that all
work in this module.
Now one important concept of Flutter is that it's actually possible for you to run native code, so
code written in Objective C or Android Java, that you run such code from inside your Flutter app because
Flutter gives you a bridge
so to say
which lets you talk from your Flutter app to your iOS or Android app.
Here on this picture, it's named iOS host and Android host.
So in the end, Flutter can send a message to these hosts and for example tell iOS hey I want to get
the battery level and then some iOS code can run
which then in turn returns that battery level or whichever information was requested back to Flutter
where you can then use that and the heavy lifting of sending that message and transforming the type and so on,
that's all made very simple and handled by Flutter and actually in this module here, we'll have a look
at this example where we request the battery level from our native platforms by adding some native code
there and we'll then use that information in the Flutter app and for this, you find this very simple
dummy project here
attached to this lecture, this main.dart file.
This leads to this application here where I want to output the battery level here in the middle
as soon as our app loads let's say. So
right now, here I just got ... and now I want to fetch the battery level by adding some native
code for Android and iOS.
Now of course, it's worth mentioning that you probably will find plugins that allow you to get the battery
level,
so for this concrete example you typically don't need to write your own code but it's just an example
to explain how you could talk to Android and iOS
in case you need to and therefore a simple example makes sense to show the base concepts.
Now let's start here on Flutter side before we dive into the native code
and here in my MyHomePage stateful widget or in the state class here to be precise, I want to ensure
that when this loads, so in initState, we reach out to the native code, so to the native hosts and fetch
the battery level
and for that, I'll actually add a new method here in MyHomePage state which I'll name
_getBatteryLevel and that should return a future and that will be a future which eventually will yield
nothing though and it just returns a future because I'll use async await in here,
you saw that before in the course and I'm using async await because the way we communicate with the
native platform, with the native hosts, that will be handled by futures because sending that message from
the Flutter app to iOS or to Android and then using the response is really fast,
you won't really feel or see a delay but technically, it's still an operation which doesn't finish instantly.
It's an asynchronous operation, so the other code shouldn't get blocked whilst you're waiting for that
response from the platform host and therefore a future is getting used here by Flutter.
So how do we send such a message then? You first of all create a platform const and you can name this
however you want of course by using the MethodChannel
class and MethodChannel is provided by Flutter but there, from the services.dart file, so you
need to add that import to the file where you want to use the method
channel. So you create a new instance of that MethodChannel and you do so by giving this a unique identifier
and that should be a string.
The convention here is to use an identifier that looks like a URL, something like
course.flutter.dev/battery and you don't have to own that URL,
this doesn't really have to exist,
this is not a website we'll visit, it's just a unique identifier
and this domain
URL look is simply a convention established by the Flutter team and therefore, we will follow it.
Now this should be a unique identifier in your application, so if you are building multiple applications,
you can definitely reuse these identifiers but in one and the same application, if you have different messages,
different channels you want to set up to your native host,
then each channel needs its own unique identifier, so you must not repeat this identifier in the same
app.
So with the platform created with that, we can now go ahead and use the platform object we got here to
call invoke method. Invoke method basically sends a message through that MethodChannel and that method
channel here automatically is established by Flutter between Flutter and iOS or Android, the platform
the app is running on in the end.
So now we can send a message through that channel and the message we send here simply is a name, is the
name of the method,
so a function we want to execute in our native device code, for example getBatteryLevel
but of course you could use any name you want here.
Now invoke method now returns a future as you can see here and that makes sense because as I said, sending
this message and waiting for the response can take some time.
By the way, it's also worth noting that if you had a method you want invoke which needs arguments,
you can send these arguments here as a second argument, a list of arguments like one, you could send this
to this method you'd want to invoke in your native code, getBatteryLevel needs
no arguments though.
So this returns a future and therefore, we want to await it to then store the response which should
be the battery level in a variable or like in this case here, in a constant. Now important, when working
with this, things can go wrong so you should add try catch here because if the communication with the
platform fails for whatever reason, you want to be prepared to handle that error.
So here I want to add a try catch block and wait for the platform exception which is made available
by the Flutter package and then catch any potential error
we might be getting and then here
we can handle that error and
for example set our battery level to a dummy value.
And speaking of that, we need a property in the MyHomePage state which we then can also use in our widget
tree to output the battery level.
So here, I want to have let's say a _batteryLevel property which should be an integer like this,
then here we could set battery level to null to make sure it really reset back to normal because we've
failed fetching it and here in the try block on the other hand, we could set battery level to the real
battery level.
Now since we're in a stateful widget, I will actually call set state in here to set my battery level
property to the battery level I'm fetching here, so that we do rerun the build method and update the
UI
and it's the same here.
I'll put that into a set
state call here, so inside of the function we pass to set state, I'll set battery level to null in that
case.
So we're managing the battery level here, we are sending a request to get the battery level to the native
platform.
Now of course, we can try using the battery level here in our UI, in our widget tree,
in the text widget where I want to output battery level with the string interpolation and therefore with
all of that out of the way, we can now try to get the battery level in our native code and I'll
start with Android.