So let's start with this and let's now actually calculate the height of this list container and therefore
also of the chart container dynamically. To calculate that height dynamically, we need to know how much
height we have available
and for that let's go into the transaction list where we have that fixed height
and let's find out which tool Flutter gives us to calculate the height dynamically.
How can we find out how much height we have available,
what the general device height is? For this, there is a specific class we can use, the media query class.
If you have a web development background and specifically you know some CSS there, which is the styling
language in web development, then you know that there you also have a feature called media query which
also allows you to write styles that behave differently on different device sizes or on different screen
sizes.
The media query class here is exposed by the Flutter material package,
so we need to have that imported
and then here, just as with the theme, we have to connect it to our context with .of context because
the context, as you know, is this metadata object with some information about our widget and its position
in the tree
and as it turns out, this connection also allows us to find out which general device size we have available
because that's something which Flutter managers behind the scenes for us
and with media query of context, we can tap into that.
Now that alone however doesn't help us
but with that now, we get an object where we can get all kinds of interesting information about our device.
We can get the device pixel ratio, if we would be interested in that, to find out which screen density
we have
there, more modern devices have higher screen densities, that could maybe be useful for loading images
or whatever you would want to do.
You can find out whether the user opted that animations should be disabled, which you might want to respect
in your application to not play a certain animation if that's disabled
but we haven't had a look at animations yet, so let's ignore that.
We can find a couple of other pieces of information, about settings the user setup but most importantly
here, you have a size property and the size property gives you access to an object where you have a height
and a width property and that gives you the device height and width you have available.
So here we could take the device height like this
and now this would of course be the full device height we have available, obviously in this case here,
our container with the transactions should only take a fraction of that height which is why we can simply
multiply this height with a value between 0 and 1, 1 to take the full height, 0 to take 0 height.
So here we could say we want to take let's say 60% of the available height of the screen. So
we can multiply the available height with 60% and if we do that, then you see I can no longer scroll
this and you see here the boundaries,
this indeed only takes 60% of the available height which is why now this container of transactions
does no longer overflow our screen at the bottom.
And if I shrink this further to let's say 0.2, well then we see we get problems with our
image here because this image isn't resized, we could configure that but right now it's not resized and
therefore here, we're running out of space for that image.
But 0.2 is a bit too small anyway, so for now, let's bring this back to 0.6.
So this is not too bad,
now at least this bottom container has a fixed height of only 60%.
We haven't restricted the height of this container at the top here though and obviously, that is something
we could also do. If we go to our chart.dart file here,
we can wrap this card here let's say with another container with the help of the refactoring tool and
assign a height here which is also calculated based on the available height with media query of context
size height and then we had 60% on the list with the transactions, here we could assign the remaining
40%.
Of course you don't have to make sure that the amounts add up to 1 if you want to leave some space unoccupied
but here if we do match them, we see 40% seems to be a bit too much for the chart here,
we have some empty space here at the bottom but now we have that a line up and yet we can scroll that
page and that is really strange because if you think about it, we have 40% here on the chart,
we have 60% here on the list
and if we have a look at the main.dart file, then these are the only two widgets we have here, chart
and list.
So why can we still scroll here,
shouldn't they add up to
the entire height and therefore this should not be scrollable? Well that's not the case because
we also have the appBar here and we're not considering the appBar in our calculations here. To do so,
we can go to the main.dart file which is where we create that appBar and we can create that appBar
in a variable, in a final variable because I don't plan on changing it and there, I simply store my appBar
widget. With that stored in a variable, we can simply assign that variable here to the appBar argument
so that we still create the appBar. Now why am I storing it in a variable? Because the appBar object, which
I can now access anywhere since it's stored in that variable, has information about the height of the
appBar.
So now here in main.dart, we can go down to the places where we create the chart and the transaction
list
and now let's wrap both with a container here inside of the main.dart file.
So I wrap my chart and I assign a height here of MediaQuery.of(context) size height times let's
say 40% just as before but I want to deduct the appBar height from that. So I'll actually wrap
my height here,
the height calculation into parentheses and deduct
appBar.preferredSize.height. preferredSize is a property we can access on the appBar to get the height
that is reserved there or the dimensions that are reserved.
So now here, we have an adjusted height where we deduct the appBar and then we calculate 40%
of that adjusted height and we should now do exactly the same down there on the transaction list.
So I'll wrap it here with a container, still in the main.dart file and then I will copy that height calculation,
add it down there but here, I'll use 60%.
Now important, you have to deduct the height of the appBar on both calculations because we then use a
fraction of that and we want to use a fraction of the available space and the available space is always
full height minus appBar height
in both cases. Now since we calculate the height here in the main.dart file, we should not do it here
in the chart and in the transaction list widget anymore.
So let's remove our container here in the chart widget file and remove the closing parentheses and the
same down here in transaction list.
I'll not do that here, instead I'll just return my ternary expression here without the container because
we have the container in the main.dart file.
Now if we save this and maybe do a full restart with the green arrow here to make sure that this really
is all taken into account, we can see that here, I still have a little bit of scrolling available and
this now comes from the status bar which is another element we have
here that takes up some space. So we should also take that into account in our calculations.
To do that, let's go back to the main.dart file and in here, let's deduct something else, that's now a
piece of information we can again get from the media query with of(context) and there access
the padding. This, as the information here also tells us, gives us the padding which Flutter automatically
adds around a wrap for typical UI interfaces or typical UI elements, like the system status bar.
So here we can get the padding and we want to get the padding from the top which is for the status
bar. Let's deduct it here from the available height for our chart and also for the available height of our
list
and if we saved this and do a full restart with the green arrow here again and we go back, now
this really isn't scrollable anymore because now, we have the full height of the device minus the
appBar minus the status bar and then we split that available space.