Now for this module and for this course, we'll use Firebase which is a Google service.
You can visit firebase.google.com to learn more about it
and whilst it sounds like the name of a database, it actually is a server-side solution offered by Google
which gives you a lot of services,
we only need a few of those and amongst these services is a web server with an attached database.
So you basically get a database and a server that talks to the database as one service
and that's exactly what we need here because we can then use this web server to communicate with it
and automatically have that server then communicate to a database out of the box without us writing
any server-side code.
You can also use it for free,
all you need is a Google account
and once you did login with your Google account, you can simply go to that Firebase console there to
then create a new project here.
Now I already did create one, if
you're creating a new one
you simply need to check these boxes here and then create a new project with any name you like
and once you're in the project,
you should see a starting screen that looks something like this.
Now in here as I said, you have a bunch of options, Firebase has a lot of services and this is not a course
about Firebase and I will not turn it into one,
so we'll not cover Firebase here,
I'm only using this as a dummy back-end because it gives us a web server where we don't have to write
any code and which we can then use to learn how Flutter talks to such a web server
and the knowledge you learned in this course therefore is applicable to any back-end, to any server
you use, not just Firebase and that's important by the way. If you search for Firebase Flutter, you actually
find out that there is an official documentation on how to add Firebase to your Flutter app and they
do this through the Firebase SDK for Flutter which is essentially a Flutter plugin you install.
Now you can do this if you really want to use Firebase and all its services it offers,
so also things like analytics, machine learning and all the stuff this service offers and a lot of that
will then also be a paid service, if you want to use that then of course the official SDK, the Firebase
SDK or the Firebase plugin for Flutter is a great idea because it makes working with these Firebase
services easier.
I don't use the Firebase plugins here because I don't want to teach you Firebase plus Flutter which
won't help you much if you ever build a Flutter app that needs a different back-end but instead, I want
to teach you Flutter with any back-end and therefore we'll just use the generic parts of Firebase which
you can easily replace with other back ends,
so I hope that's clear.
So in the Firebase console, the interesting part for us right now is the database.
Now it might look here like we're setting up a database to then talk directly but always keep in
mind, Firebase abstracts away a lot of the complexity and therefore, it looks like we send requests directly
to a database,
we will send requests to a Firebase server which then simply translates that into instructions, into
query statements it sends to the database.
Now for that, we need to create a database and we'll not use Cloud Firestore because that's a bit of
a more complex database,
we'll use the real-time database which you should find if you scroll down a bit.
There, you simply can create a database and start in test mode,
that's important, because this ensures that everyone can read and write
and for this module, that's what we need.
Later in the authentication module, we'll lock that down and I will show you how authentication could
work in such an application.
This is the screen you should then see
and this is in the end your web interface where you can see the data which will be stored in database
and where you also get a URL, which is at least a part of the URL to which you have to send
your requests so that they are automatically translated into database queries
and that's really important.
You don't directly talk to a database here,
you talk to a web server which has this URL or which has different URLs which will always
start with this one and then that web server knows how to interpret certain HTTP requests to
then interact with your database,
that's how that works.
So with that setup, let's now dive back into our Flutter code and make sure that there, we can now add
products which are stored in the cloud on a web server and that we can then also load the data from
there and so on.