You can visit Firebase Google.com to create new Firebase projects and also to learn more about Firebase.
Now, Firebase is a service by Google and it consists of a lot of different products.
As you can see, if you click on products, a lot of features built in.
We'll see some of those features.
We'll see those most important features, so to say, in action here.
And if you click on pricing, you will see that you can start for free, but depending on which features
you're going to use, you might need a paid plan which also initially is free, but where you can occur
costs if you then use certain services to a certain extent and you can see all the details here on the
pricing page there, you'll learn what's free and what costs money and if there is any free tier.
For example, for authentication, you see that some services cost money, but you also have a certain
free tier so you can use them for free.
And only if you exceed this, you pay basically.
And that's true for all those services.
There are certain free tiers and from a certain point on you're going to pay and you should definitely
check this pricing page before you build any real app.
Therefore, now what we're going to do in this module should be covered by the free tier.
But of course if you are already using some other Firebase projects altogether, they might be exceeding
those free tiers.
So they are free.
You should definitely check your usage and make sure that you don't occur any unexpected costs.
With that, let's go to the Firebase console and for that you will need a Google account.
So make sure that you do create one or that you sign in with your existing one.
Now, once you logged in, you can add a new project.
And first of all, you need to pick a name here and I will name it flutter chat, but the name is totally
up to you.
Next click Continue and here you can choose if you want to add Google Analytics to your project and
I will leave it turned on though technically we won't really need it here, so let's click continue.
Select an account if you are getting prompted for.
We're a Google Analytics account.
So I did that here and I will now create that project.
Now this can take a few seconds or maybe even minutes, but it should be fairly quick.
And this will now set up a Firebase Project and then forward us to a web console where we can manage
that project and where you will be able to manage and monitor those different services you might be
using.
So let's wait for that to finish up.
Here it is.
Let's continue.
And here we are in this Web console.
Now, here you see your Firebase project.
And on the left you see the different services that are offered by Firebase.
Now, in this module, we're going to have a look at authentication and database and storage, and we'll
also have a look at the cloud functions and add push notifications, which we don't see here, but which
also are included.
You see them here with cloud messaging?
Now you can manage your plan down there and switch to a paid plan, which you might need to do if you
exceed certain limits.
And here under the gear icon, you can also manage your project and views on configuration data.
We might need and in general manage your project, though we will do that together as the need arises.
Now, what we need to do right away here to get started is we want to add our Flutter app to this Firebase
Project so that we can tap into Firebase with help of our Flutter app.
And for that we either add an iOS or Android app here, depending on which kind of app you're building.
Of course, you can also add both.
Now, I'm currently previewing this here on Android, so I will click on Android here to start with
that and connect my Firebase Project here to this Flutter app.
Now we get this wizard here and I will show you iOS in a second, by the way.
But let's start with that.
So we get this wizard and first of all, we need to enter our Android package name here.
Now you see that this is the application ID you find in your build gradle file.
So we can go to the Android folder and there go into the app folder and there this build gradle file.
Here.
It's this application ID which you should find in this file.
Now you can also change this project right in your Flutter project and then choose any identifier of
your choice.
Here I will go for the default one.
You can assign a nickname if you want to, which you then see in the Firebase console.
But I will not do that here.
We don't need that signing certificate here.
And therefore we can just click register app now.
Next, we should download this Google Services JSON file and then drag it into your Android app folder.
So next to that build gradle file we just had a look at.
So let's download this and here I'm in the Android folder and in that app folder there I will download
that Google Services dot Jason file.
Let's move on to the next step and now add the Firebase SDK.
Now for that, you should actually follow the steps that are shown here.
Go to your project level, build on Gradle file, which is this one here, and make sure that you have
Google here in your repositories node.
So here in build script repositories, you should have Google and we already have that here but verify
that it is there.
Also under all projects repositories dear you should always make sure that you have Google.
You can have more than that, but make sure you have Google at least.
Now, all to make sure you add this line here and you can just click that copy button here.
This line here to the dependencies in your build script node.
So here's the build script.
Here are the dependencies.
And make sure you add this class path here, which I just copied and save the file thereafter.
Next in the app level builds gradle file.
So the build gradle file in your app folder.
There you should make sure that all those entries are added.
So under build gradle here.
If you scroll down a bit, you should already see this plugin com android application, so that should
already be there.
But you should also add this Google Services plugin.
You can add it right below there.
And of course, make sure that you have this line added to your dependencies.
So if you scroll down.
Here's the dependencies.
And there at the end we can add this service or this line, save that file and you're done.
You can skip that step here.
You're done already.
So now here it's going to check whether that works.
But it should work.
And this kennel reports that it doesn't work because you might need to uninstall and reinstall Europe.
But we'll see if it works soon because we're soon going to add the Flutter Firebase SDK, which is going
to communicate with Firebase.
And there we will see whether it works or not.
Now, that was the Android setup.
Now, if you develop on a Linux or Windows machine, you can now jump ahead to the next lecture.
But if you're on a mac OS system, you can of course also configure Firebase to work with iOS.
So let's do that next.
So therefore I'll skip this step.
I'm back here in the console and I will click Add app here to also add the iOS app.
Now here we need the iOS bundle ID and we can find this bundle identifier in the general tab of our
apps, primary target and Xcode as we see.
So therefore I opened the iOS folder of my project here with Xcode and if I click on Runner here under
General.
It's this panel identifier which we now need.
And I'll change to actually to.
Flatter chattier.
We're actually.
I'll change it to the same identifier I had in the android folder.
So app build gradle there.
I had.
This identifier and I'll use this in Xcode too.
You might already have the same if you don't.
Maybe make sure that you do have the same identifiers.
Now this is the bundle identifier, which I now also add here on Firebase.
However, for iOS, of course it doesn't like underscores.
I keep forgetting that.
So let's make sure we remove all those underscores here so that we have this identifier and we have
the same identifier here on Firebase.
Now, just as before, we can add a nickname if we want to.
We can add an app store ID if we want to.
I don't want to do either of that here, so I'll just register this app.
And as a next step, we have to download the Google Service Info List file here.
So I'll download this.
And I'll add it in this runner folder in my iOS project.
So next to App Delegate and so on.
I'll add this file and save it there.
And now you can click next.
But because we're going to use the Flutter Firebase SDK, you should not add this Firebase SDK like
this, so you should not follow the instructions here.
You should also not follow the instructions here in ad initialization code.
Instead.
We're already done with adding our project here and therefore we can go back.
And now here we have our iOS project, we have our Android project set up in our Firebase Project.
So we connected this Firebase Project to our iOS and Android app, and now we're going to use the Firebase
Flutter SDK and get started with that in the next lecture to finish up this connection and to be able
to communicate between our Flutter app and this Firebase backend.