So in our application, we want to send HTTP requests and I think a good place to start with that
is actually to allow us to add new products and actually store products where we then click on that
save
icon here, not just locally in memory but actually on a server, so that in the next steps thereafter,
we can start fetching the data from the server, for example for this list
but of course also for our shop, that we can then store the favorite status on the server when we change
it, that we can store our orders on the server
and of course, we also store edits or updates to our products on the server and that when we delete a
product here, we obviously delete it on a server, that would be the plan.
So it all starts with enabling us to add new products and to send HTTP requests in Flutter,
we need a specific package, the HTTP package which you can easily find if you search for Flutter
HTTP or on pub.dev,
you simply search for HTTP there,
this is a package which makes it easy for you to send HTTP requests from inside your Flutter app.
You install it like all other packages, under the installing tab,
you copy that dependencies entry you find here and you add that to your pupspec.yaml file below
your other dependencies
and once you save that file, Flutter should automatically go ahead or the Flutter extension in Visual Studio Code
should automatically go ahead and fetch that package. If it doesn't, then you can go into a terminal and
there, run Flutter packages get. So with the package added to the project and installed,
we can now start sending HTTP requests and with the Firebase back and we want to send them to this
URL or to a URL that's based on that URL and for that, let's first of all understand how we actually
send HTTP requests to such a back-end like this one and I say like this one because it's really representative
of any back-end you could be using. When sending HTTP requests from inside your Flutter app, you
have various options and typically, it always depends on the server you're talking to, the server you're
talking to decides which kind of requests it's able to handle, so you always need to check out the documentation
of the back-end you're working with,
unless you're of course the developer who wrote the code for the back-end, then you should know how it
works.
Typically, you will communicate with a so-called REST API when working with a back-end from your Flutter
app,
that's the most common web server you use for front-end or for front-end applications, so for user
interfaces like Flutter app. It's the most common scenario you'll talk to and for such REST APIs, the
idea is that you send a HTTP request that's made up of an endpoint which in the end is the
URL and a HTTP
verb to a server and on that server, depending on that combination of URL and verb you
chose, a certain action is executed.
Now you can only use combinations the server knows of course,
that's why you have to read the docs or you write your own web server which accepts certain combinations.
You'll of course see concrete examples throughout this course.
Now as I said, the endpoint is really just the URL you target and for different URLs, different
things could happen, for example with myserver.com/posts,
if you send a request to that, you might want to load all posts or add a new post to the list of posts
and that action is also determined by the HTTP verb
you choose therefore because you can send different kinds of HTTP requests,
the most common request which we all know when we open a page in a browser is a get request. When you
open a page in a browser,
a get request is sent to get the data that should be displayed in the browser.
You can also send such get requests to such RESTful APIs or REST APIs which is a short form and
the idea here always is that this should get you some data,
a single piece of data a list of data, really depends on the server you're working with and the app you're
building but get this not the only HTTP verb you can use.
You can also post data, you can send post requests to a server. If you send a post request,
you typically want to store data, append some data to an existing list of data.
Again, what actually happens is always decided by the server,
it's the server-side code that runs but the convention is when writing such a server, that post requests
to a certain URL are handled in a way that adds data to an existing list or whatever your server, your
application does.
So this adds data and of course with that, I typically mean that this also at some point gets added, gets
written into a database, get on the other hand returns data from a database typically. Now besides adding new
data,
you might also want to update existing data and this can be done with the patch requests which updates
data or as alternative,
you can send a put request which replaces data.
The difference is that patch typically just edits the fields or the pieces of data that changed whereas
put take some new data block and replaces an existing one with it,
again it depends on your web server which type of requests it accepts and what it does in detail then,
the official documentation is always the place to go of course, the official documentation of your
web service
I mean. Delete requests can also be sent and as the name suggests, you typically would choose those
if you want to delete some data,
some resource on the server.
So these are the different kinds of HTTP requests you can send
if your server supports them for the URL, for the endpoint you are sending them to and we'll now work
with these HTTP verbs and also with different endpoints throughout this module.