Now that we animate this overall container here, I think it would also be nice that if this increases
in size, this confirm password text field also wouldn't just pop in but also slowly animate and
maybe slide down and fade in, so that it looks like it's coming from behind the password field so to
say
and for that, Flutter has us covered.
We have another built-in widget we can use to get that look and feel,
actually we'll have two widgets that help us with that. Here's the text form field which I want to
animate when we're entering sign up mode and currently, we use that if condition to let pop in or instantly
remove it. Instead of doing that,
so I remove that if statement, I want to wrap that with a new widget and there, to fade it in, we can
use the fade transition widget.
I think that's also good point of time to let you know where you'll find all these built-in animation
widgets,
it's of course in the Flutter widget catalog in case you forgot about that.
There you have that animation and motion part and if you click on that, you find all these widgets that
are built into a Flutter that help you with animating something,
so definitely feel free to play around with these and dive into the docs about these to learn more about
how to use them,
you can also dive into the animations documentation here in the official docs if you want to learn way
more about animations there as well.
So fade transition is such a built-in widget,
it takes a child which it will fade in but fade transition then, unlike the animated container, does not
take a duration and a curve, instead
this needs an opacity and you need to change that opacity dynamically with the help of an animation
or an animation controller. With that, we're of course back to where we were before,
we need a controller, we need an animation. We have an animation controller and I'm fine with that duration,
I just want to add a new animation, an animation where I animate the opacity and in the end, the opacity
is just a double right,
it's a value between 0 and 1, so 0.1, 0.2, 0.3 and so on,
that's a double.
So here, we can have our opacity animation or whatever you want to name that and set that animation up
here in initState. Opacity animation is again set up with the tween class because I want to animate
between two values and I want to start at zero which is fully invisible, 0.0 and I want to end
at 1.0 which is fully visible.
Now here, I call animate and pass in my curved animation to basically configure how that should look and
feel, the parent of the curved animation is my controller, _controller and the curve here is
let's say curves ease in and as I mentioned, feel free to play around with these different values.
So with that, the opacity animation is set up, we can now use that down there and fade transition will
automatically register a listener and so on for us.
So all we have to do here is we have to use opacity animation as an argument for opacity because
opacity actually wants an animation object, it doesn't want the double, it wants animation object because
as I just said, fade transition will then take this animation object and add a listener and adjust the
opacity of the child widget for us. All we need to do is we need to make sure that we do start the controller
or the animation with controller forward and then we also do control playing it back and with that, we
should have everything we need. If we go back to our application here
and I do go to sign up, you see this fades in.
Now we have a problem however, as you can see the space for this text form field is now always reserved
and hence we have these empty ugly space and need to scroll when we're in login mode.
The good thing is that our fade animation works but of course, it makes sense that this space is reserved
because if you have a look at your widget tree where we just changed our fade transition in the text form
field, this is now always part of the widget tree, it's never added or removed.
So a solution here would be to also wrap the fade transition here into another animated container
which we actually shrink to a height of zero when it should not be visible, so when the space should
not be reserved and give it a more appropriate height that leaves enough space for the text form field
when it should be visible. So here on the animate container, the fade transition is the child and I want
to have a duration of let's say 300 milliseconds, just as on the fade transition
and now I want to control my constraints and set up some box constraints there to control the min height
and the max height of this container because it should have some room for change.
Now the min height of course depends on the auth mode,
if the auth mode is equal to AuthMode.signUp, then that should be let's say 60 pixels and you can
experiment with that value to see when it looks good and otherwise, it's zero.
So if we are in login mode, I don't want to have some space reserved here and so I set the height of this
container to zero. The max height
also of course depends on the auth mode and if the auth mode is sign up, then I'll set this to 120, otherwise
to zero.
So in the end, this container can be anything between 60 and 120 pixels high
if we're in sign up mode and it is always zero
if we're in login mode. With that changed, we also can of course give this a curve here with
curves easeIn and then do a full restart here to see that animation in practice.
So now you see the space is not reserved,
then it fades nicely and smoothly in as we animate this and this I'd say is a much nicer look.
Now if you also want a more detailed sliding animation for the confirm password text field, you can also
go into the fade transition and add yet another transition here by wrapping the text form field with another
widget,
the slide transition which just like the fade transition is also built into Flutter. We can use that
to let that widget slide and for that again,
I crawl up to initState and above that and I'll recycle the old height animation and name it slide
animation because we don't need the height animation anymore,
we're using animated container for that and the slide animation here will actually get an offset value,
not a size value, offset is also a class provided by Flutter and then here,
we set up slide animation with a tween that controls offsets and we start at an offset where we can
to set different values and offset, if you have a look at it, takes an offset on the x and on the y-xis,
I never want to offset this on the x-axis so I'll set that to zero
but on the y-axis to have it slide in from the top, I'll offset this by 1.5 pixels here in the
end, -1.5
and I want to end, add an offset of 0.0, so add the position it should have in the end. That's an offset
tween and we can now use that on the slide transition because slide transition wants an animation
that uses an offset tween and of course that's also something you simply find in the official docs
in case you're wondering how I know this. So on slide transition, you add a position and here you see this
wants an animation which gives us an offset in the end, so here, I point at slide animation and we should be
good to go. If we now do a full restart again,
we have a look at that,
now you see that slides in from above.
Now of course be aware that the more animations you nest into each other, the more inefficient this gets
or the more performance heavy your app gets. This here should be absolutely fine
but if you start animating everything on the screen all the time, your app will slow down.
So use these widgets, no matter if they're built-in or if you're building your own animation from scratch,
use that with care and do careful testing
also on older devices to make sure that your app runs smooth because the best application with the best
animations isn't worth much if it's just slow and people can't use it.