To let users sign up, we need to send a request to Firebase and I'll manage that through a new provider
in the auth.dart file which should be there to manage all our user logic,
signing up, logging in, logging out and also making sure that when the app restarts, we try logging in
the user again.
So let's create a new class in there, an auth class
and here I will add the change notifier mixin from flutter/widgets.dart so that we can call notify
listeners to make sure that all places in the UI that depend on our auth logic here are updated
when that changes. So in here, what do we need?
We will definitely manage a token in there later to attach it to requests
that reach endpoints which do need authentication.
This token, haven't mentioned this before but I'll mention it now,
this token expires at some point of time,
that's a security mechanism.
This token doesn't live on forever,
typically it expires after one hour,
for example the token Firebase generates expires after one hour, so one hour after you got it, it will
be treated as invalid.
So therefore, I'll also store a datetime object here, the expiry date of that token
essentially. Now an additional piece of information that will be helpful is the ID of the logged in
user,
so I'll also store the userId here which should be a string.
None of that is final
by the way because all of that will be able to change across the lifetime of our application, we can
logout for example and then all these fields would be cleared.
Now with these properties set up there,
let's start simple and let's add a method that allows us to sign the user up.
So for that, I'll add a new method and that will return a future which eventually will yield nothing
which I'll call sign up and there, I use the async keyword so that we can work with async await.
Now sign up will need two pieces of information - the e-mail and the password, the confirm password is not
required here,
I only use this in the AuthScreen in my form here in the validation already.
It's just there to validate the input, I don't need to submit this to the server.
So these are two pieces of information that do need to reach the server.
Now the question is of course which URL is the right URL to send that data to? To get an answer
to this question,
you can simply google for Firebase Auth REST API and you should find an article from the official Firebase
docs and there you can learn how to authenticate with the help of the Firebase or with a certain Firebase
REST API, not the same API we used before but a different API also provided by Firebase. On the right,
you have shortcuts to the different parts of the documentation and relevant for us is right now
sign up with e-mail and password because that's exactly what we're trying to do.
There, you learned that you'll need to send a post request with some JSON data
to this endpoint, to this URL. So unlike before in the last course module, now you can't build any
URL you want,
instead you have a fixed URL to which you need to send your request
and that's actually the default when working with APIs. Typically you don't construct your own path
and that is then reflected back in a database,
typically you have hardcoded endpoints to which you can send your data,
so that's the case here. As a payload to the request, so as a body you attach,
you need to send the e-mail, the password and then also an extra field which has that returnSecureToken
name, written like this which holds a boolean and as you learned, this should always be true,
so we just add that. And you'll get back a response which basically gives you the token,
so here, you already get a token after signing up, you don't even need to login,
we still need to implement a login because of a user comes back after the token expired,
then that user can't sign up again because a user for that e-mail already exists,
so then we'll need a login but for the first time sign up, you already get back such a token there
You get back the e-mail,
well you sent that there, so not really information you need but still, you get it back.
You get a refresh token which is an advanced concept which we'll not use in this module,
this would allow you to prolong that token which expires after an hour so that the user doesn't have
to login again after an hour.
I'll not cover using it here because if you really want to use Firebase, you can look into its SDK
which manages this for you anyways
and I just want to show the general flow for which the normal token and with the expiry date will suffice.
You also get information when this will expire.
It's a string but in there, you actually have the number of seconds until the ID token,
so your main token here expires and local ID is the userId which Firebase automatically generates
when you sign up a user.
So that's the data you get back,
this is the URL you need to send a request to.
So back in the auth.dart file here in the providers folder, let's import the HTTP package because
we'll of course send our request with that and again, I'll import it as HTTP to have it all bundled
up in this HTTP prefix here.
So in here, we need a URL and that URL is the URL I just copied from the docs
and please note that it has one dynamic segment in there,
the API key. That is a key you get from your Firebase project, there if you click on that gear icon under
project settings, you find this Web API key and that's the key we use here
even though we're not in a web project. So take that key here and enter it here instead of the square bracket
API key thing.
So with that, you have that URL with your API key at the end and that's the URL to which the request
should be sent.
So here we send a post request with the post method to that URL and for the body, you need to, as you learned,
send JSON data which contains this information.
So here, I'll again import
my good old dart:convert package which is built into Dart to call json.encode here, pass in a map
and in that map, we need to have these three key-value pairs. So we have e-mail, we have password and we
have that
let me copy it to not mistype it,
returnSecureToken value.
The value for that is true, for the password the value of course is the password we're getting here as
an argument and for the e-mail, the value also is the e-mail we're getting here as an argument.
So with that here, a couple of commas to reformat this,
we have our map set up, now of course the key values here actually have to be between quotes, so
let's make sure that's the case
and now this can be sent as a post request.
Right now, we're not waiting for the response though, so let's throw in an await here and actually store
that in a variable.
Now we should add error handling here and I'll do so in a second to make sure that we actually handle
errors which could occur if you try to sign up for an e-mail address that already is signed up,
so that's something I'll take care about in a second.
For the moment, let's simply print json.decode response body to see what's in the body we get back,
I mean we already see it here
but to really see that this also works and that that we have that data here. Now we just have to call sign
up and for that, we first of all have to provide this auth class or an object based on this auth class. The question
as always is where and the
AuthScreen would be the right place, if you really only want to send that request, then we could definitely
just wrap our main widget here,
let's say this stack here or the scaffold here, we could wrap this with a widget, with our change notifier
provider widget, we could do that, that would be correct then but actually, we'll need AuthData in different
parts of the app as well as it turns out, for example soon we'll have to decide what our home screen
should be, should it be the AuthScreen or if the user is logged in, it should actually be our products overview
screen.
So we'll need information about the login status and also about the token and so on basically in our entire
app and therefore, we will provide it as so often here in main.dart. There in the multi provider list here,
I'll add another change notifier provider with a value and the value I provide here of course is my
instantiated auth object. Now for this to work
however, we need to import that auth object,
so let me go here and import from the providers folder,
the auth.dart file so that we can create such an object based on the auth class here and provide that.
Now with that, we can tap into this to send our sign up request here in the
auth_screen.dart, there in the submit method, in our AuthCard state, I have login and sign up.
So here in the sign up place, we want to use the provider package,
so let's import it, import
package/provider and then provider.dart to use that auth object and send such a request.
So now down there, we can use provider of for our auth object here of course, for our auth class and then
pass in the context.
Now obviously, we need to import the auth.dart file from the providers folder to unlock the auth class
here,
so let's do that too and
let's add another import here at the top where we point at the providers folder and there, the auth.dart
file and with that imported,
let's go down again to that sign up logic,
now this works
and now here we can call sign up and forward e-mail and password which we can get from our form data
because please remember that in the end all data is stored here in this AuthData map,
that's where the data gets stored by our form fields
when save is called.
So here we can forward AuthData
and then for the e-mail key and here, for the password key, these are the values we want to forward here.
Now also important, here
we can also set listen to false because I don't really want to set up a listener to the auth state here in
this widget,
I don't care about the concrete auth state in this widget,
I just want to dispatch my sign up action here.
The auth state will then be important in other widgets but not in this one actually because if I'm on the
AuthScreen, I'm always unauthenticated.
If that changes, I'll replace the entire screen,
so inside of that screen, I don't care about changes. Also important, sign up of course returns a future
because we're using async await in there and hence we can also await here,
you just have to make sure that you add async here on the submit method and therefore this of course
returns a future which eventually yields nothing and then we can call await here which is important
to make sure that we also show the loading spinner in between.
Now you can do a full refresh here and give this a try. For that, go to sign up mode and then enter an e-mail
address and it should be a valid one because whilst you can trick our local validation here, the Firebase
server also has its own validation and will deny invalid emails and also enter a password which is at
least six characters long. Enter the same password here for confirming
and with that, click sign up, you see the spinner and then for now nothing
but here in your debug console, you should see the response by Firebase which looks pretty good. ID
token is a pretty long string, that is this token string that is generated.
You also see the e-mail you entered again, you see the refresh token and then the rest of the response
is cut off because the token is so long
but this clearly proves that it in general worked.
So now we're sending a sign up request,
we can also see that it worked in the Firebase web console, there if you go to the authentication area
again under users, click refresh if you don't see your user yet and then you should see the user you
just created. Here by the way, you always can delete the user in case you want to test that creation
flow again with the same e-mail.
This is how we sign a user up, the next step of course is that we also enable sign in before we then
make sure that we change what we see on the screen based on the authentication flow and of course we
also want to handle errors,
that's also important because there is a lot that can go wrong when sending the sign up and login
requests.