So let's work on adding and editing products and for that, we need a new screen which presents all the
text inputs where the user can enter the title, the price, the description and of course then also an imageUrl
and so on.
Hence let's create a new file in the screens folder
and as always, you can name this however you want,
I'll name it edit_product_screen.dart and I'll use that same screen for both editing a product
and for adding a new product because the inputs will be the same
and the only difference will be the data we load and how we load the data to prepopulate these inputs.
So in here, in the edit product screen, we have to create a new widget
and now this will actually be a stateful widget here. Stateful because we'll have to manage all that
user input and that also if you remember that earlier slide I showed you in the course, in the bottom right
corner,
I mentioned form input as a good candidate for a widget only or a local state
and the reason for that of course is that what the user entered is important for this widget because
you want to validate it, you want to temporarily store it there and once the user submits that, presses
some submit button,
you typically want to save that into your app-wide state,
create a new product, sign up a user, whatever you're doing but until that submit button pressing, you
want to only manage that data in your widget because the user might cancel adding this, might close the
app or do anything like that,
so your general app is not affected by the user input until it is really submitted.
So therefore, we want to manage the user input and validate it and so on locally in this widget and hence
a stateful widget is the right solution, instead of using the provider package and a more globally
configured object. The name I'll use here is edit product screen and this, automatically thanks to this
shortcut, got added here as a name for the state object and so on as well
and of course, you know that we then have to import material.dart from the Flutter package.
So now this sets up a stateful widget and now the question is, what do we want to render here in the
build method?
Well, it will still be a standalone page, so it makes sense to then render a scaffold widget here and
on the scaffold widget, we can add an appBar and there, present a title where we say edit product.
You could also show a different title depending on whether you are editing or adding,
you'll soon learn how to find out what's the case
but I think edit product is also a title we could keep for all circumstances.
I don't want to add a drawer or anything like this because my goal is to go to this page by pushing it
so that we have a back button and can simply go back to the previous page,
so the next thing I'll add here is a body and that body should display all the text inputs that allow
the user to enter a title, enter a description and so on.
Now earlier in the course when we worked on that personal expenses planner, we already work with inputs
if you remember. You were able to add new transactions,
we used the text editing controllers and in the end, we rendered some text fields, widgets built into
Flutter which you connect it to our text editing controllers and then these text editing controllers
saved the user input automatically and we could then call submit data, either when a button was pressed
or when the keyboard, the soft keyboard was closed,
to then basically read the values from our controllers here with title controller text. So put in other
words, what we did here is we handled all the user input manually,
we manually created the controllers, connected them to our inputs, got the values from there when the
data was submitted and then we added some basic validation here by simply throwing in an if check where
we checked all the inputs the user entered. For
simple forms, for simple inputs that is fine but it misses a couple of convenience features
you might want to have in more complex forms. Handling the input would be nice if that would be done automatically
and you don't have to assign text editing controllers to all your inputs,
that would definitely be a nice thing.
In addition, this kind of validation is not too good,
it allows us to prevent the submission of this but the downside simply is that we don't really show
error messages.
It would be nice if we could color the text fields which do have problems read, maybe show some error
message as well that gives the user some hints on how to improve the input to make it through the validation,
so in short, this is not the best way of handling more complex input data and we'll now dive into the
best way though.