Now storing that image in a variable is a nice first step, but of course doesn't help us that much.
Right.
So the first thing we can do, though, is, of course, we can call set state here because we're in
a stateful widget and set our stored image.
So this property up there, which is a file equal to the image file we took from the camera.
Now, again, a little addition here at this point, if you are using that newer version of the image
picker and you're using that alternative approach of picking the image, which is optional, as I mentioned.
But if you are doing that, so if your code looks like this here with get image.
Then what you're getting back here from the get image method is not a file you can use like this.
It's not a file as you get it from dart io.
It's instead pict file, which is a specific type provided by the image picker package.
And in order to use that and convert it to a regular file, you should simply wrap the image file here
with the file constructor and access the path on it.
So this converts depict file to a regular file, and with that you get the update syntax with the latest
version.
Alternatively, as mentioned multiple times, you can stick to the code shown in the video.
This is simply the more futureproof code which will work with future versions of image picker as well.
This should at least allow us to see it here in our preview.
Right?
Because once stored image is set, we're trying to display that file here with the image widget, which
has a file provider basically.
Let's give that a try before we continue with saving the image on the device.
So if I save this and I go back to take picture, let's take a picture here with that emulator camera
preview.
And indeed, here is my picture.
So that is looking good.
That is working.
But still, it's of course not that useful if we can only manage our image here in a variable and in
memory, basically, because that means that we're not adding a place here.
When we go back, it's lost.
And when we restart the app, it's all the lost.
And that's of course not the idea.
Instead, we want to store that file somewhere permanently on our device harddrive, so that we can
then work with this image whenever we restart the app and so on.
Now to store it on our hard drive, we need more packages that help us with that because interacting
with the hard drive can be challenging, to be precise.
Actually, it starts in a pretty straightforward way.
Maybe here.
After updating our preview image, you can use the image file which you got up there, which is a file.
And on that you can call copy to copy this file in a new location.
So that's great.
Now we need to enter a path on our device where we want to copy this to.
And this is the very tricky part because of course, as you can imagine on iOS and Android, you can't
write files to any place on the hard drive.
Instead, there are a lot of restrictions regarding where you can write data to so that you don't clutter
up the hard drive of the mobile device or start writing files into folders where you really shouldn't
have access.
So down for both iOS and Android typically gave you a certain path where you can store your app related
data.
And that's a good thing because since such a path is clearly defined by both operating systems, that
means that whenever you delete your app, these operating systems can erase all the data from that path.
And they know that all your app specific data is gone to gather with the app, and that keeps your device
hard, drive clean, and avoids that you save files anywhere, and when you uninstall the app, these
files are still there, and therefore your hard drive would well reach its capacity at some point of
time.
So it's good that you have clearly defined paths where you can store your data, but of course that
also means that you need to find out which paths that are.
And for that we can use a certain package which we can search for on pop def and its path underscore
provider has nothing to do with the provider package.
Instead, this is a package which helps you get access to the paths iOS and Android give you to store
data in.
So as always, let's go to the installing tab here and add this entry to the pops.
Back to the YAML file below our image picker here like this.
And before I hit save I need yet another package.
And that's the path.
Package, just path.
This helps us with constructing paths.
So one package helps us with finding paths.
This package helps us with combining paths basically.
And you'll see why we need this in a second.
So let's also install this at this entry here to the pop spectral YAML file and now save this.
And again if it doesn't work run flutter packages get.
So now with these two packages back in the image input widget here, we can import them both.
We can import our package path.
A dare to puff dart fowl and maybe gift us a puff prefix so that we can use all the methods it provides
on the path thing here with path dot and then the method name and lets all the import a package, the
path provider package and data path provider dart file.
And I'll give this a prefix of source paths for system paths, but you don't need to assign these prefixes.
I just do this so that it's really clear which functionality is coming from which package.
So now down there where I want to copy this, we need to find out where we're allowed to copy it to
and therefore we first of all need to find our app dir, our app directory where we can store data and
we can do this with the help of the SIS paths.
Object here.
So in the end, with the help of the POV provider package.
A deer, we can use lobsters, puffs and there we can use the get application documents directory method.
You see you have a couple of methods there for example also for getting access to the external storage
which only works on Android though.
So not really an option if you build an app that should work for iOS two, this would give you access
to an external SD card if available or the temporary directory.
But as the name suggests, this is a temporary directory and it will regularly be cleaned up by the
operating system.
So don't store anything in there which should be living a bit longer, at least as long as your app.
The images we're taking right now with the camera, for example, also are stored in a temporary directory
and therefore they get deleted at some point of time.
So we need access to the applications documents directory.
That's a directory on the device which is reserved for app data.
And that sounds just about right now.
This here actually gives us a future which then yields the directory.
So I will wait for this and therefore now we'll have a handle to this directory stored in after.
So that's one thing.
But here for copy we need a path which is actually just a string, not a directory handle.
But the good thing is that our app directory has a path property which gives us the path as a string,
but I don't want to copy my image like this.
Instead you also have to provide the name of the image it should have.
And for that I'm fine with the name that was automatically assigned by the camera, by the image picker.
And to get that, we can use.
Poff And that's now using this prefix and therefore referring to the path package.
POF dot based name which gives you.
The part of a path after the last separator, which is a complex name for saying the file name.
So here we can enter.
Image file dot path.
That's the file.
That's the path to where our image file is currently stored.
So this temporary directory I just mentioned and there the path does not just contain the folders where
it's stored in, but also it includes the name of the file.
And with base name we get that file name, including the file extension.
So I'll store this in a file name, variable or constant here.
And therefore now we can copy this into this path and then also add the file name.
And therefore here I'll enter a string and then use string interpolation to get my.
After a pause here and then a slash to basically tell flutter or dart that you want to navigate into
this path, so to say into the folder here.
And then I'll use more string interpolation and output my file name here.
So that means I basically copy the file into this path and I keep the file name.
That's what we're doing here.
Now copy also is returning a future because this can take a while.
Not too long, of course, but still you don't want to block your other code.
So here I will await for this because we're using async await to work with these futures and here I
therefore have my saved image in the end and this is now the image as it's saved in its final destination.
Now it's this safe image which we then can work with in other parts of our application, for example,
to store it to on device database so that we can combine it with a title and have a permanent entry
on our device.
But before we do that, let's make sure we work with this in memory first.