Well as a first step, it would probably make sense to have a new widget and new screen to which we can
navigate because the idea of course is to fully replace the content on this screen with the content
of a brand new screen, the screen that shows us the recipes for that category.
Hence, it's time for a new widget and therefore, a new file and you can name this however you want,
I'll name it category_meals.dart or category_meals_screen to be consistent with my other
file here, the category screen.
So this will be the screen which shows us the meals for a chosen category. In there,
let's add a stateless widget which should have a name of CategoryMealsScreen to basically fit our
file name and as always, import material.dart in there. Now for the moment, to simply see something
and work on that transition, let's just output a centered text here which should display the recipes
for the category
and we'll learn how to go there and how to pass data like the title of the selected category in a second.
So now we've got this new screen,
how can we reach it from our categories screen?
Well actually there's one more thing we should do here,
we should of course use a scaffold and put the centered widget into the body of the scaffold and also
maybe add an appBar where we can show a title and that title here will be the recipes
but of course maybe, we want to actually soon show the category name here instead of the recipes.
So how can we now go to that category meal screen? In the end,
we want to make sure that in the categories screen, we can tap a category item.
So inside of the category item, we need to be able to tap these items, that I guess makes sense.
To make them tappable, container doesn't have an onTap argument or anything like that
but we can wrap container with a new widget, so let's use the refactoring tool to wrap it with a new widget
and there we could use a GestureDetector because a GestureDetector allows us to add onTap,
onDoubleTap and many other listeners so that we can execute functions when a user taps or double taps or whatever,
our elements.
But it would be nice to also have some visual feedback,
so instead of a GestureDetector, I'll use an InkWell. InkWell is a widget which I briefly mentioned
earlier in the course, it's basically a GestureDetector which also fires off a ripple effect,
so this Material Design effect you have when you tap something, where you have these waves coming out
of the point where you tapped it.
You can also add onTap here but now you can also configure the ripple effect,
for example you can set the splash color, so the color of these waves
and for that, I'll use my theme color and there, the primary color theme simply by tapping into the
theme with theme of context and also set a border radius, maybe of BorderRadius.circular 15, actually
not maybe but it should match the border radius of your card, of your container, so that these waves nicely
follow the shape of the container.
So the border radius up here for the InkWell should match the border radius down there for the container
and you can simply set a different border radius to see the difference and why you might want to align
them. Well and with that, we just have to make sure that something happens onTap and that something is
of course that we want to go to a different page. How can we do this?
Well we can add a method here, which you can give any name you want,
I'll name it select category and in there, we can now use a tool Flutter gives us to change the page.
So let's hook up onTap here to select category, without parentheses,
we don't want to call this when this gets parsed but when the user taps here and in select category, we
now use a feature which I also mentioned earlier before but which we only have briefly used and that's
the navigator. The navigator is a class or a navigator
here is a class built into Flutter which helps you with navigating between your screens,
that's the core idea. Like theme or media query,
it needs to be connected to the context because you might remember that context is this object which
has information about this widget and its position in the widget tree
and of course something like that is super important for the navigator to know because it needs to know
what the current screen is so that it can add this page you want to go to as a screen on top of it.
And what do I mean with as a screen on top of it though? In mobile apps and therefore also in Flutter
apps but not just there, when we navigate between pages, like a product and a product page,
we typically do this by managing these pages as a stack of pages. Now what's a stack? A stack basically is
a list
you could say. The idea here simply is that when we go to the product page, we actually add this product
page to the list
and when we go back from it, we remove it from the list
and you can imagine this list as being in a three-dimensional space where you always see the last or
the topmost item of that stack,
so the topmost page is visible.
So if we add the product page on the stack and the products page was already there, the product page
is now visible because it's the latest and therefore the topmost page.
Therefore we also speak of pushing and popping pages,
we push a new page onto the stack so that it's the topmost page
and if we want to go back, we pop it off there. So in our code,
this means that we now use the navigator here to push a new page.
Now before we do that, we need to make sure that we have context available here,
so we should accept it here as an argument and I'll name it ctx here to avoid confusion with
this context.
You wouldn't have to rename it,
it's only there to, as I said, avoid confusion
and since I need the context here, we need to bind onTap to an anonymous function
and now forward the context we get here by Flutter to select category when this anonymous function
is triggered.
So now back to the navigator,
now with the navigator set up and connected to the context, we can use push and pop on it.
Now pop doesn't make sense here because we don't want to remove a page from the stack, instead we want
to add a new one.
Now you have various versions of pushing, you can pushNamed pages,
that's a feature I'll come back to later.
You can also push and replace pages,
that means that instead of adding a page on the stack or on top of the stack, you add it but you remove
the page below it,
so you still only have one page in your list then instead of two and that means that you won't be able
to go back from that new page because you deleted the page you were coming from. We'll see use cases for
this later too.
Here however, I'll push and keep the page
we were on
and now what do we push here though?
You don't push your widget you want to go to, so you don't add your CategoryMealsScreen here,
that's not what you add here,
instead you add a MaterialPageRoute and yes, there also is a CupertinoPageRoute if you want to handle
both.
For now, I'll focus on the MaterialPageRoute, though the Cupertino route will work in the same way. The
MaterialPageRoute is a class but you have to instantiate by adding parentheses,
so by calling its constructor and of course it's available because we have that flutter/material.dart
import at the top.
Now as you see, we can configure four things here, important for us is the builder which defines which
widget should be built with the help of MaterialPageRoute.
We need MaterialPageRoute as a wrapper so to say, to handle things like the animation from the old
page to the new page and so on. Full screen dialog is a boolean which you can set to control whether
you want to have that default animation where the new page kind of slides in or if it should basically
be a full screen overlay rather and settings will become important later, we can ignore it for now,
same is true for maintain state, we don't need that at the moment.
So let's add a builder and the builder here gets a context passed in automatically because again the
function you would provide for builder here is now executed by Flutter and here, I'll name the context
just c or actually use an underscore since I won't need it
and now in here, we have to return the widget which should be used as a new page now
and here, the idea of course is to return our CategoryMealsScreen.
So for that, we now need to import it with a relative import path here from our
category_meals_screen.dart file
and of course we instantiate it here. So with this, we are creating our new screen as part of this
MaterialPageRoute
and with the help of push on a navigator, we should be able to go there.
So with that, let's do a full refresh here with the green arrow and go back to our application,
back here in our application, click a category.
Now what you see is that you now get this transition to this recipes page, of course to the same page
for all categories but still
and you automatically get a back button up there
and of course on Android devices, you can always use this back button.
So that's now of course really nice because now we can switch to a brand new page and we automatically
got this back functionality managed by Flutter so that we can also go back to the categories page here.