If you search for flutter provider, you should end up on this page here on pop dot death with the provider
package and there you find some documentation about how to use it.
Definitely interesting.
But of course there's now also what I will do together with you.
We will start using it.
And for that you first of all have to install it, which you do by simply copying this entry here and
installing tap on the package page.
Now go back to your project and they're in the pop spectral YAML file at this entry below your flutter
dependency here and make sure the annotation is correct because indentation matters.
Once you save that file, flutter should automatically go ahead and fetch these packages.
If it doesn't do that, you can run flutter packages, get in your terminal, navigate it into this
project folder.
With that the provider package is installed.
And of course the question is now how do we use it?
Now a provider in the end needs to be defined with the help of a class, and you then build a new provider
based on that class definition.
Now, a provider or this class you create is also often referred to as a model because you all the kind
of model, your data, they're the data in your app, which then changes.
Now I'm already using the term model here though, and I'm using it here to define my my data classes,
my data types, which I have like a product here.
And that is not really something I want to provide because a single product is just a single object
I use.
What I want to manage here with this state management solution is something bigger.
A list of all my products, not just a single product.
Now, therefore, I will create a new subfolder here and name it providers to set up my classes that
define these bigger state management definitions, these bigger data definitions for my app.
So to say the data, which also changes over time and which I want to reflect.
So here in providers, I'll add a new file.
And named at.
Products Dot Dart you can also name it products underscore provider if you want to make that differentiation
really clear now in the products dot dart file.
You to find a new class and I'll name that class products.
However, now here you don't just have a class like this.
Instead, you need to add a mix in.
I mentioned mix ins earlier in the course already you add make sense by adding the width keyword and
then the name of the mix in a mix in is a bit like extending never class.
The core difference is that you simply merge some properties or it's a methods into your existing class,
but you don't really turn your class into an instance of that inherited class.
It's a bit like inheritance lite, so to say.
And class we need to mix in here is to change notifier class, which is built into flutter and which
you enable by importing the flutter material dart package here.
Change Notifier is basically kind of related to the inherited widget which the provider package uses
behind the scenes and inherited widget, whilst we won't work with it directly is simply a widget in
Flutter which allows us to establish behind the scenes communication tunnels with the help of the context
object, which we're getting in every widget.
So this product class now mixes in the change notifier here and you'll see why we add this mix in in
a second.
Now, you can define whatever you want at this class.
And here I want to define a list of products.
So I'll, first of all, import.
My product model loops only with one slash here and I'll store a list of products here in the product
class.
So I'll have a list which will hold product data in the end and I'll name this underscore items.
You could also just name it items.
I just want to make it really clear that this property here should never be directly accessible from
outside.
And I'll also show why I do this in a second.
So I have my underscore items in there, and that's not a final list because it will change over time.
And with that, I mean the value here in the items property, not just the items in the list, because
as you learned, you can also change items in the list that is final.
But here I really want to change the value that's stored in the property itself.
Before we change anything, however, let's actually make sure we can fetch these items.
And since I turned this into a private property by adding the underscore, which means it can't be accessed
from outside, I'll add a getter here which will return a list of products, and then it's a getter
by adding to get keyword, which is named items without the underscore.
And in there I return my items, but not like this.
Instead I return a copy of them, which I do by wrapping items here into square brackets and then by
using the spread operator.
Now, why am I doing this?
You have to remember that all these objects in flutter were entered are reference types.
If I would return my items list here, then I would return a pointer at this object and memory.
Right.
That's what you learned earlier in the course.
And that means that anywhere in the code where I get access to my product class here and where I then
get access to the items, I get that address and therefore I get direct access to this list of items
itself in memory.
And hence I could start editing this list of items from anywhere else in the app where I tap into this
product class.
I don't want to do that and I don't want to do that because when my products change, I actually have
to call a certain method.
To tell all the listeners of this provider, remember the slide.
You have the provider and you have listeners that new data is available.
So let's say we had an add product method here which returns nothing and which for the moment doesn't
take an argument.
And then here we would simply add something to our items.
Then, of course, we typically would have the problem that if we change data here in this class, how
would we let all our widgets or the widgets that are interested know about this?
And that's why we add this change notifier because that gives us access to a notify listeners method,
because always keep in mind this class will soon be used by the provider package which uses inherited
widget behind the scenes and therefore it will establish a communication channel between this class
and widgets that are interested for us.
And we need to let those widgets know about updates that we did with not notify listeners.
So that in these widgets which are listening to this class and to changes in this class are then rebuilt
and do actually get the latest data we have in there.
And that's why I return a copy so that we can't directly edit our items here from anywhere else in the
app.
Because if we would do that, we could not call notify listeners because we can only do this from inside
this class because there we added this mix in and hence our widgets that depend on the data in here
would not rebuild correctly because they wouldn't know about the change.
So we have to make sure that we only change data from inside the class because then we can trigger notify
listeners and all the other parts of the app that are listening to this class will then get rebuilt.
Now, this might not be entirely clear yet because we're not listening yet, but that's the general
idea here of why I do it like this.
And for the moment, I'll comment this out because for the moment we don't really know how to add products,
but that's the idea why we have change notifier and why we need this set up and why I return a copy
here.
But we've said, let's start listening.
And before we can start listening, we first of all need to provide this.
Thus far we have the class, but now we need to turn this class here into a data container, into a
provider which we can use in our app and in the different parts of our app.
And there the products are important.
A couple of places of this app, of course they are important.
In the product detail and the product overview screen for the moment.
That means that I want to provide this in the main dart file because that's important and that's something
you have to know with the provider package.
You need to provide a class which you then want to use from different widgets in your app at the highest
possible point of all these widgets which will be interested, which means that if the product overview
and the product detail screen are interested in the data, I have to provide the class in a widget that
is above them, which in my case is this my app widget, my root widget.
If I had data which is only important to the product item widget, then I could provide that data in
the products overview widget because that is where I create the product item.
No need to then manage it in the main dart file.
But here, since I have widgets which are registered on the root level, I need to also provide my data
on the root level.
By the way, that will not mean that the entire app will rebuild whenever something changes in the data
though, but more on that in a second.
So I want to provide my data here and therefore let's import our provider or this class we just worked
on from providers and they are from the products dot dart file.
And now we can set up a provider here.
Now how do we register a provider in our app then?
To register a provider, you need to import something from that provider package because there is a
reason why we added it after all.
Right, so import provider start from the provider package and now here in your my app widget.
Instead of returning material app, we'll actually wrap this into another widget.
So wrap with new widget and that new widget.
Is now a provider.
And there you've got a couple of providers available.
The most common provider, which I would recommend using, is to change notifier.
Provider.
And that's a clause provided by that provider package which we installed.
It allows us to register a class to which you can then listen in child widgets.
And whenever that class updates the widgets which are listening and only these not all child widgets.
Only child widgets which are listening will rebuild.
So here.
You then have to provide a builder method.
That builder method will receive a build context and it should return a new instance of your provided
class.
So not a widget.
A new instance of your provider class.
So in our case of the products class here.
So here I simply return products like this.
Now, one important note at this point, though, the builder method here is the right method to choose
if you are using version free of the provider package.
So if you have, for example, this dependency in your pop backdoored YAML file, if you are using the
latest version or specifically a version greater than or equal to four.
So if you for example, have this entry in your perspective YAML file, then this will not work with
builder instead then it's create.
And just like that you simply have create instead of builder in that case.
Now, I did record this course with version three, which is why you will see Bilder in this video and
the next videos, and you can absolutely use version free of the provider package.
All you need to do is have this entry here in your perspective YAML file, for example.
If you have this, you can just follow along with builder, but if you want to use the latest version,
then you have to use create here.
So if you have version four or higher, then you need to create here.
So don't be confused if you see something different in the next lectures, that's just because I use
the different version.
Now, one thing that does not change is how the provider package works, what it does, and so on.
So that's all the same.
Only this part here needs adjustment.
Just wanted to point this out here.
Now we set up a provider which provides an instance and one at the same instance of this product class
to all child widgets.
So material app and all its children which are interested.
So all child widgets can now set up a listener to this instance of this class, to this same instance,
the same object of this class.
And whenever we change something in the class and we then call notify listeners, the widgets which
are listening will be rebuilt.
And that's really important only to widgets which are listening, not behold material app.
So just because something changes in here will not rebuild material app, it will only rebuild widgets
which are listening.
Nowhere is a place where we could be interested.
Well, the products overview there.
Here in the products overview.
I have my great view builder, so I need my product here now.
Actually, you could even argue to not unnecessarily rebuild the app bar which doesn't need any products
data that we outsource this great you builder into a separate widget so we can wrap this use the refactoring
tool and use extract widget here and gives us a name of products grid.
Maybe now we have that new widget which is created for us.
And that should actually not receive the product as an argument, but get it itself by actually using
our provider.
Now, first of all, I'll move my products right here into a new file.
Technically, you don't need to do that, but I rather follow that convention.
So my products grid dot dart file in there.
Of course you need to import your material dart file from Flutter and also import the product model
because we're referring to it here.
And that's important, the product model.
So our normal model in the models folder, not the products file we just worked on, but the normal
model here.
I also need to reference product item in here because I'm using it.
So let's import.
Product item.
In the products overview screen.
We now don't need that product item import anymore.
I also want to grab the dummy product we have in here and move them away out of that widget into the
product.
Start file in the providers folder because there we have these products and I want to start with some
dummy products for now so that in the product's overview screen, we don't need that anymore.
We don't need the product model import anymore, therefore we just need to import that new.
Products grid from the widgets folder.
So products grid start.
And we don't need a new keyword.
So products grid.
Products.
Great is what I should import.
And now product create is created here in the products grid widget.
Don't need that constructor or anything of that.
I want to fetch all my data in here instead by setting up such a listener.
And for that in the build method, we can now use another feature from the provider package and hence
let's import package.
Provider provider dart here and that our feature is provider of context.
Now we've seen that off context thing a couple of times throughout the course already with the theme
with the navigator and so on.
I'll already explain there that this sets up a direct communication channel behind the scenes.
And this here, the provider package, allows us to set up a connection to one of the provided classes
and therefore you can only use provider off in a widget which has some direct or indirect parent widget
which set up a provider, which we did here.
So that needs to be set up first, that provider, but then we can listen with provider off to changes
in that provided class or in that provided object to be precise.
And this build method of this widget where I'm using provider off and only this build method and of
course all the child widgets will rebuild whenever the object I'm listening to changes the build method
of a parent widget of products grid like the products overview here will not rerun because we're not
setting up a listener here.
And that's of course important not the entire widget tree does rebuild of data changes only the widget
where I'm listening and of course then because this build method runs all the child widgets are rebuilt
too.
That's the normal behavior.
The question now is how do we set up a connection between this widget and then this specific provider?
Right now we only have one provider, but actually, as you will later also see, you can have more
than one provider in your app.
So I want to set up a listener to my provider, which actually provides me an instance of my product
class.
You tell Flutter or the provider package that you're interested in an instance of that product class
by taking advantage of the fact that the off method here on the provider class provided by the provider
package is a generic method, which means you can add these angle brackets to let it know to which type
of data you actually want to listen to.
So here I want to listen to changes in products and now that's important.
That now has to be products.
So here we import.
From the providers folder and there from the product start file.
With this piece of information.
We're telling the provider package that we want to establish a direct communication channel to the provided
instance of the product class.
And now the provider package goes ahead and looks at the parent of products grid, the products overview
screen, and there it finds no provider.
So it goes ahead and has a look at the parent of the products overview screen.
And that's of course our my app widget because that's where I'm instantiating the products overview
screen and there if it goes up the widget tree it indeed it finds a provider and in that provider thankfully
it finds a provider which thankfully provides an instance of type products.
If we would create a different class here, then setting up this listener, of course would fail.
But since we do provide a new product object here, we can tap into it and listen to it here with provider
of products context.
So this here gives us access to this products object.
So name this product data and that's not our list of products, but to the object based on this class.
And this will then have a items getter because we added it here.
So the products we actually work with are then.
Simply fetched from product data.
By accessing items like this.
And this now gives us a list of products.
And since type inference works here, we actually don't need the product model import because we don't
need the product class itself.
Here in the product grid with dad, we now get our products here and we can now use the products here
to determine the length and then forward that data to the product item.
In the product item, as I explained earlier in this module, I'm fine with getting this data as an
argument because this is data which this widget itself needs, which we don't just get to forwarded,
but which we want to output in that widget.
And therefore it's fine to accept it like this.
It's actually recommended to get it like it is because then it's very clear to see which configuration
this widget needs to work correctly.
And you can drop this widget anywhere into your app where you know you get this data no matter if you
have a provider above it or not.
So with that was a lot of talking but very important.
Let's do a full restart now and in our app we now still see our items here, but now we're actually
loading them with the help of our provider class and the advantage, if not already evident, will become
more and more clear the more complex our application gets.