- [Maximilian] In this lecture,
we'll install Flutter on a Windows machine
and we'll set up Windows and
install all the tools we need
to develop Flutter apps on Windows.
If you are not following along on Windows,
you can therefore of course,
skip this lecture and
the next lecture as well,
because in the next lecture,
we'll set up the
environment for writing code
with for Flutter on Windows.
Now the best way to start
installing Flutter and everything
we need is to go to Flutter.dev,
which is the official website
of the Flutter project.
And there you can go to
docs and then click on,
get started and find instructions
for different operating systems.
And here we are, of course,
interested in Windows.
Now the official docs are a
great place to also dive in
and get written instructions
in case you should get
stuck at some point,
we will go through all the
important steps to gather here,
but definitely also dive
into this stocks here
if you are facing any problems
or if you may be just also
wanna get some written instructions,
in addition to this video,
Now it all starts with the
system requirements here.
So you need to meet these requirements
if you wanna use Flutter,
there's no way around that.
Especially the Git requirement
might not be met yet,
but Git is an extra tool
which you normally use
for controlling source code
and saving source code snapshots,
which is getting used by
Flutter under the hood,
and which we therefore need to install
before we can install and use Flutter.
You can just follow this
link here to download
an installer for Windows,
so for Git for Windows.
And I'll do that here,
download this installer.
And then once this download finished,
we can simply walk through that installer
and we'll do that
together in just a second.
Here we go.
And basically just keep the defaults here.
So I'll keep all these defaults,
which will make working
with Flutter easier
since everything will just work
if you use the defaults and you wanna keep
all the defaults here
on this page as well.
Continue, you can keep
this default here as well
if you want to.
Click next, click next here as well.
And now very important
on this screen here,
where it's about adjusting
your path environment
we find on the Flutter page,
that we should ensure that we can use Git
from the Windows Command Prompt
and therefore this middle
option should be checked here.
It's the default typically,
it's recommended here
and we should make sure that
we use this option here.
And then click next.
We can leave that as well,
leave all these defaults here
and just click through all
these options here and then
click install at the end.
And this will now install this git tool
which we could use for
managing our source code
and for creating snapshots,
you can explore a standalone
courses and talks on that,
but that's not a must do,
but Flutter we'll use
this tool under the hood
and therefore we need to know install it.
So let's wait for this
installation to finish here.
Once this did finish,
I'm not going to read the
release notes, but click finish.
And now we can move on
to installing Flutter.
For this we can download it here.
And of course the exact
version you are seeing here
when you are following along
will very likely be a different one than
I see here,
but you will still learn
Flutter in the correct way
through out this course no worries.
So here I'll just download Flutter
and that's a around big download.
So it can take a while
until it's finished.
And once this is finished, we
will extract that Zip file,
which is downloaded here
and we can see that in step two here,
we can place that Flutter folder,
which we'll get by
extracting that Zip file
in any desired installation
location on our system.
And typically you wanna use
some global location there are
somewhere on your root drive.
However, not in C program
files, as you see here,
and also not in any other folder
that might have restricted access.
For example, not the system 32 folder,
but instead some root folder
where your Windows user
has full unrestricted
read and write access.
So for example,
the documents folder and your
user folder, as you see here,
but you can use any root folder.
So the download finished for
me here and hence all extract
that file here, that Zip file.
And in there you find this Flutter folder,
I'll now move that Flutter
folders to some our destination
on my system to be precise
here, I'm in my a user folder.
And in there I'm going
to create a new folder.
I do apologize for this being German here,
but I'll just create a new folder,
which I'll name development.
And in that development folder,
I'll create a new sub folder,
which I'll name SDKs, and
then in this SDKs folder,
which is my root user folder
and then in that development folder there,
I'll direct that Flutter folder into.
So this extracted Flutter folder
goes into that SDKs folder
in my development folder,
in my user folder.
And you should store your Flutter STK,
this extracted Flutter folder
in some global location like this,
so that you can easily
work with it from anywhere
on your system later on,
because that's what
we'll need to do there.
Now, since this is big,
this can take a couple of
seconds if you do it like this,
and I'll we'll therefore be back ones this
has been copied over.
Now moving that folder
finished for me here.
And that means that now we did
download and install Flutter,
but Flutter is not a
tool that we then opened
by double clicking on it
instead it is a tool
which we typically invoke
through the command prompt,
which is installed on every Windows system
and therefore what
we need to do next is we
need to update our path,
which means that we make
this Flutter command,
this Flutter tool that we
installed globally available
inside of the command prompt,
no matter where on our system,
we then execute this.
And this will be super important.
Now for that what we have to do is
we have to add it to our
environment variables.
For this, you can type env here
into this quick-start area.
And for me again, it's German,
but this is added our
environment variables.
And here you wanna click on user variables
or environment variables here.
And then these are some global variables,
which in the end all is the control,
which commands can be invoked
from inside your command prompt.
And there you should have a path variable.
If you don't have it, you can create it
but very often you will have one already.
And then you should add
it to this path variable
by clicking on edit.
And here you can now add new entries
to this environment variable.
And here what you wanna do is you want
to add an entry that points
at this Flutter folder,
which we moved into a global
destination on our system.
So for this here and
back in the STKs folder,
I'll go into that Flutter folder
and they're into the bin folder.
And then I click in here to
grab this path to the bin folder
on my system, this entire path
that's what I need here.
And in there, we have that
Flutter and that dart command,
and these are the commands
which we wanna invoke
from the Command-Line later
and therefore we need to add the path
to this tools to our path
environment variable.
So here, where I'm editing
this path environment variable,
I'll add a new entry to it and just paste
in this path I selected
so that it's part of this
path environment variable
and then we can click OK
And now this was added here
and we can now click OK again,
close all these settings,
and now you should be able
to invoke the Flutter command
from inside your command prompt.
And that's what we'll try it right away.
I'll open my default command prompt.
You can find it by simply typing command
into your quick start menu.
Use this command prompt here
and then here in this command prompt,
you can type Flutter like that.
And this should then work.
It should show you a list
of available commands
in the end here which it does for me,
it should not show any error.
And that proves that we
did successfully add it
as an environment variable.
Now in here, what you can do is
you can run Flutter doctor,
which is a little analysis command,
which will analyze your
system and see if it's ready
to build Flutter apps.
And this will therefore for first of all,
download some extra software
and then run this check.
And right now it will probably
fail because for example,
we have not set up everything
for Android development yet,
You might
also see
a message regarding Visual Studio here and here.
It's important to note that
this would only be required if you plan to build
desktop applications for Windows.
And since this is not the focus of this course,
you don't need to install Visual Studio.
It's totally fine to have this red
cross here in your "flutter doctor"
output for this visual Studio option,
because
we won't work with Visual Studio and we won't
build desktop
apps with Flutter in this course, by the way.
Visual
Studio here should also not be confused with
Visual Studio
Code, which is the code editor we'll soon install.
We definitely
will install Visual Studio Code, but we
don't need
Visual Studio, so we'll ignore Visual Studio.
But we do need the Android toolchain on our system.
We want to be able to build our Flutter apps for
Android and therefore
that's the next thing we'll proceed with.
we have not set up everything
for Android development yet,
and that's important because
that will be the next step.
We can use Flutter as a tool
to build cross-platform applications,
but we actually need
to install extra tools,
which will be used by
Flutter under the hood
to then really build for iOS or Android.
And that's always important
on Windows you unfortunately,
can't build for iOS.
That's a restriction by Apple,
not by Flutter.
You can't build iOS apps on Windows
you can only build Android apps there.
You need a Mac to build iOS
apps there it is what it is,
but we can build Android apps
by going for the Android setup,
which we also find here
in the official docs.
And what we need to do
here in the Android set up
is we need to install Android Studio,
which is the official
development environment
by Google for building
Android applications.
So for that
we can follow this link
and open the Android studio website here,
then simply download Android Studio.
Accept the terms here, I guess,
and then start this download,
which is also big and therefore can
take a couple of seconds or minutes.
Now I'll be back once
this download finished
so that we can then walk
through this installer,
which we'll get there together.
So here we go, download finished.
I'll now start this installer
that we downloaded here
to install Android studio.
And here we can now walk through
that installation wizard,
which for some reason is
a bit blurry for me here,
but anyways,
we can walk through it and basically keep
all these default settings,
especially also make
sure you're installing
the Android virtual device here.
We'll need dev for
running Emulators later,
which are virtual Android
phones on our computer
to test and review our Flutter apps.
So we definitely want that click next,
keep that default location
if there is any way of doing that.
So unless you really have to
install it somewhere else,
don't install it somewhere else.
Instead, keep that default
it will make working with
Android so much easier
because everything will just work
and Flutter we'll find Android studio
without issues and so on.
So keep that default possible,
click next and install.
And this will now install
Android Studio onto our system.
So let's wait for this installation
process to finish here.
And once this is finished, we
can also start it immediately.
So keep that checkbox checked
here and start Android studio
like this.
And by default,
when you started for the first time,
you should get this wizard
here, this setup wizard.
And we'll definitely go
through that wizard here
because we need certain settings
and tools to be set up
and we can set them up
through that wizard.
So here I'll choose custom
so that I can customize everything.
And the first thing I'll do
is I'll keep that default path
here for this Java Development Kit,
which is required under the hood.
And as always try to
keep that default path,
if double click next,
then you can chose the
theme of the editor.
It's not too important because
I won't use Android studio
for writing code here anyways,
we just use it under
the hood or a Flutter.
We'll use it under the hood
for building our Android apps,
but still I'll choose that
dark mode here, click next.
And then here very important,
make sure you do install
an Android version year.
In my case,
I'll install API 30 that you
do install the Android SDK
and that you do install the
Android virtual device here.
And if you have the option
also install into HAXM.
Now you might not be able to select this
and that's fine as well.
You don't need it, but
if you can install it
definitely do because this
will speed up this virtual Emulator later
and simply make it run a bit smoother.
So basically here,
you wanna check all these
options and click next.
Then here you can leave these
defaults for allocating memory
to the Emulator.
So to this virtual Android device,
which we will soon run on our system,
click next and click finish,
and the this will now download
and install more tools
under the hood.
So therefore again,
this can take a couple
of minutes to finish
and I'll be back once it did finish.
No set up this finished for me here.
So I'll finish this here
and now what we can do
on this opening or this welcome
screen here is first of all,
we can go to the STK Manager
by clicking on configure STK Manager.
And there you can install
any missing pieces
that you might still need
though, with that default setup,
we chosen the wizard we should be fine.
The only thing I do recommend here
is that you go to SDK tools
and you choose the Android
SDK Command-Line Tools here.
You should install those as well since
that can actually a wide some
unnecessary errors later,
but that should be all you
need to install right now.
So I'll choose that here
and click, OK, again,
click here and accept the
license and click next.
And this will now again,
download and install this
extra utility software,
which we need.
So let's wait for this to finish.
And once this did finish,
we can click finish.
And then again, on this welcome screen,
click on configure AVD
Manager, by the way,
you should get this welcome screen
whenever you start Android studio.
So that's how you can get back there
if you don't see it.
And then there click on
configure AVD Manager,
that is where you can
manage the virtual devices.
So the virtual Android Emulators,
you can run on your system.
And these are basically virtual
Android phones or tablets,
which you can run on your computer
to test Android apps on them,
so that you don't need a real
Android phone for testing
and also so that
you can easily configure
different virtual phones
on which you can test your Android apps.
So that's a very useful tool
which we'll use during
development to preview
our Flutter app on Android.
Now you might have a default
phone already, if not,
you can click on create virtual device
and choose any device blueprint you want.
Like the pixel free here.
That's what I'll use click on next.
And then choose an Android version
you wanna install there
and I'll use the latest
stable version at the moment
and click download here to install
that well operating
system for this Emulator,
which again can take a short while
since it's big.
So let's wait for this to finish.
Here we go.
Now that's finished and now
I can choose this Android version,
click next and then finish
setting up this blueprint.
And now I can start this phone by clicking
on this play button here to launch
this virtual Android device and will need
such a virtual Android
device to simply preview
and test the Flutter app that
we're building on Android.
Now this can take a while
until this started up,
but for the moment,
we can already go back
to the official docs
and continue here.
By the way,
we can also connect a real Android device
to our system
and run our Flutter app on that.
But we'll not do that right now instead
we will do that later in the course.
So we'll ignore this set
up your Android device part
for now and we did already
set up our Emulator here.
So that should already all be fine
though you can also go through
these written steps again,
if you want to.
Now the Emulator is up
and running for me here,
and now it's time to go
back to the command prompt
and in there run Flutter doctor again,
now that we did set up
Android a bit more and so on,
and this now looks better though
we still got a warning
regarding the Android toolchain
and that warning tells us that we need
to accept some extra Android licenses.
It also shows us the command
we have to run for that
and that's the convenient
thing about Flutter doctor
it very often shows you fix this
you can use if certain
issues are detected,
we can see that we, for example,
get a connected device now though.
So now here I will simply
run Flutter doctor --Android - licenses
as recommended here and hit enter.
And then this will now
automatically accept
all those Android
licenses to be precise it,
asks me whether I wanna accept
and I'll type y here for yes,
all the time,
every time I'm prompted to
accept all those licenses.
And now with that finished.
If you did get an error here
make sure you installed
those Android Command-Line
Tools I showed you
a couple of minutes ago
through the SDK Manager
inside of Android Studio.
And now by doing that, if we
now run Flutter doctor again,
we now finally should have
a working Android setup.
That looks good.
So we now went through this step here
and we won't continue with Windows setups
since we will focus on
building mobile apps
with Flutter in this course
and therefore now we installed
Flutter and Android studio,
we've got all these tools set up.
In the next lecture we'll now create
a new Flutter project
and set up our development environment
and run this Flutter app on our Emulator.