Besides using navigator push like this and creating our MaterialPageRoute here, we can also set up
so-called named routes.
Now what's the idea behind named routes though? The bigger your app gets, the more difficult it can get
to manage all these manual route transitions where you then create your own widgets and so on.
This can be very cumbersome and it can be hard to see where in your app people can navigate to which
page and most importantly, it can be difficult to see which routes and which screens your page generally
supports and for that in the main.dart file,
you also have more options than just setting home and then taking it from there.
Instead, you can set up a so-called routes table with the help of the routes argument. The routes table
takes a map and therefore, you need curly braces to create that map, where you have string keys which
identify a route and a route is really just a screen and then the value after the colon is in the end
your creation function for that screen. So in there, you could for example say that you want to have an
identifier of /categories and you could have any text here,
it's just a convention which also is taken from web development, that you have paths with slash at the
beginning, because in web development, you would have yourpage.com/categories
as a URL and we kind of took this and borrowed this for mobile apps but in the end, this path here
is totally up to you,
you could also name this ABC. But I'll go with /categories
and now on the right side, you have your builder method where you get some context created automatically
by Flutter as an argument,
the context of this builder function and on the right side for example, you create your category meals
screen and therefore maybe here as an identifier category meals, category-meals is a better identifier. So then
we create the CategoryMealsScreen here and that means that we also should import it here of course,
so make sure you add your relative import at the top of the main.dart file and with that, you can quickly
see that you seem to have that route available in your app besides that default categories route. The problem
of course is that CategoryMealsScreen wants some data. There we want to get the ID and the title of the
category we're loading
and this isn't really available anymore now because we expected to get this through the constructor, the
constructor now however is called in the main.dart file and here where it's called, we have no idea about
which ID or title the element we selected has.
Thankfully though, Flutter also has a different mechanism of passing data between routes. Besides using
the constructor of the screen we're loading,
it also has its own messaging system you could say, its own system for passing data.
So in the CategoryMealsScreen here, we can actually comment out this part,
you could also remove it,
I'll just leave it here for reference and instead when we load this page,
so here in the category item, we now do two things.
We now will not push but pushNamed instead and pushNamed does not take a MaterialPageRoute
but it takes the path,
so this string identifier to which you want to push
and that would be /category-meals and hence we should use that here inside of pushNamed but push
named also takes
arguments. We can provide some arguments here which we want to pass along. Arguments here can be anything,
it could be some text, it could be a number, it could be a map, it could be an object. In our case here,
we could pass a map with maybe ID and that will hold as a value our ID here and then also our title, like
this.
So now we pass this map as arguments to the new route, to the new screen which is loaded for this route
identifier which is leading to the CategoryMealsScreen.
The question is, how could we now extract the data in a CategoryMealsScreen? Well in there, in the build
method, you can extract your route arguments and store them in a variable, maybe routeArgs, by using modal
route, another class provided by Flutter material which you also connect to your context with of
context
and then there, you can get information about the route
that was loaded to display this widget so to say. You have a settings object there and there, you have
an arguments object or your arguments key and that gives you the arguments as you pass them here
when you pushed that named route.
So in this case, we pushed arguments which are a map of strings.
So here, we can also inform Flutter and Dart that whatever we get here as arguments will be of type map
where we have string keys and string values.
So this is how we extract the route arguments,
now we can also get our category title here by accessing routeArgs and then as you always do it on
maps, by using the key here in square brackets, that however should be the title of course since I
name that category title
and here I have the category ID, which I get with routeArgs ID, like this.
So this is also how we can pass data around and therefore now if we do a full refresh with the green
arrow, we should again be able to navigate and we are and we see the right title. Now of course, you might
be wondering why you would use this more complex approach of passing data around and why you would use
these named routes
and the answer simply is that for bigger apps, this can be easier to manage because you have your clear
list of available routes here in the main.dart file and it's easy to see which different areas your app
has, which different screens can be loaded and how you may get there.
So it's really just one option you can use to have a cleaner app which is easier to understand and to
get into.