Whilst it is nice that we can see our messages here, it would be nice if the plus button would at least
add some dummy message.
So that's what we're going to do.
Now we have the plus button already.
We get the on press handler for the plus button.
So now all we need to do is we need to make sure that a new message is added.
And for that we can again use fire, stalked instance and reach out to the collection where we want
to add a document.
And that's this same collection to which we're listening here in The Stream Builder.
So let's add it here.
But now we don't call snapshots because I'm not interested in the snapshots.
Instead, we can call add and add will do what the name sounds like.
It adds a new document.
Now, on the flatter side, a new document is represented by a map, and you create maps in dart by
using opening and closing curly braces like this.
And then you can add key value pairs, which will be the key value pairs in your document.
And there we can add a text key because we're using text in the other documents as well.
And add any text of your choice like this was added by clicking the button.
And for now, it's hard coded.
Later will, of course, fetch some user input here.
So if you saved us again, we'll see two entries.
But if I now click the plus, you see, this was added by clicking the button.
You see, the order is a bit strange.
The order jumps around, but you see that's getting added here.
And you also see that's getting added here on the back end.
And if you click through here, you'll see the order we have here actually is the same order as in the
Flutter app we got.
This is the number entry as to bottom most and that's the case here as well.
Now, don't worry about that order thing right now.
We'll take care about this later and we'll make sure that everything is ordered correctly.
With that, however, we have this basic introduction to Firebase.
We saw how we can connect Firebase to the Flutter app, and we see how that data base flutter communication
generally works.
Now, of course, that's not everything we're going to do in this module.
Actually, it is quite a bit away from the final result, but this is a super important first step.
With that, however, we're going to take a step back.
We're going to work on the styling a little bit.
We're going to add the authentication screen and we're going to start from scratch and make sure that
we have some users before we then work on allowing those users to send messages.