Sometimes you don't want to extract something into a new widget but maybe you want to clean up your
widget tree down there and that can be shown in the main.dart file.
There we have a relatively long widget tree,
also because we have these checks for if is landscape, is not landscape, is not landscape, is landscape.
So essentially, you could say the content of our widget tree here, of the MyHomePageState, basically only
depends on the question whether we're in landscape mode or not.
We always have the SingleChildScrollView and the column but what's inside of the column is totally different.
In such a case, of course you could either put the landscape mode into a separate widget and the non-landscape
mode in the separate widget but you could also argue that these are not really separate widgets,
they're all part of one and the same widget, it's just a different alignment or a difference regarding how
they are displayed.
Still if you want to clean up your widget tree down there, you can add a so-called builder method.
With that, I'm not meaning functions or arguments, like here on showModalBottomSheet which also are
builder functions here
but I mean a method you add to your own widget, which is only called internally, which returns a widget
in the end,
that's important, it does not return void,
it returns a widget and you give it a name like
buildLandscapeContent and maybe also a second widget, a widget which builds the portrait content
like this.
The idea with these methods is that you can simply call these methods from inside your build method
down there and you simply outsource content you had in your build method down there into these methods,
so that the widget tree that is created is exactly the same.
It's exactly the same result but your code hopefully is a bit more readable. So what you can do here
is you can grab this row for is landscape, cut it here
so that we don't have it here in the build method and instead, return this here for build landscape
content. So in buildLandscapeContent, I'm returning exactly the same thing I had in my build method
down there but down there, now instead of having all the content here, I just call
_buildLandscapeContent and important, you need to execute this by calling or by adding parentheses here because when
Dart parses this, this should be executed,
this then returns a widget and that's the widget which is inserted here into the widget tree.
So same result as before
but of course now, easier to read. The same here if we don't have landscape mode,
so if we are in portrait mode.
Let's grab that and return this here in buildPortraitContent.
Now important, here we rely on the media query and on the appBar,
so we should accept both here as input.
Now media query here is actually of type MediaQueryData,
so here we have MediaQueryData media query which we're getting and appBar is of type appBar, so here
we should accept this argument too.
So these are arguments which are now passed to buildPortraitContent
and now again, you use this method to call it down there, like this and now forward media query and app
bar.
This is now way more readable.
Now of course we have two other checks for not is landscape and is landscape and we might want to
merge the content for this into our builder methods
we just added. Before we do that,
let me first of all point at txListWidget.
This is another improvement
we're already using, here
we're outsourcing the content for a widget into a variable
and this makes sense if you need to same widget, the exact same widget with the exact same configuration
in different places of your widget tree, often in places which are rendered in an either or condition.
That's something we're already doing to avoid code duplication and that's a good thing.
But now back to merging the content we have for portrait mode here into this builder method here and
our landscape content we have here into the builder method here for landscape content.
Now you might think that you simply take that transaction list widget, which is for portrait mode
and then you go to your build method for portrait content and there, we are returning the container,
so let's add a comma after it and also return
this widget here, this variable.
Now this has two problems, for one, this variable isn't defined here.
So we would have to accept it as an argument,
that's certainly something we can do.
The more important problem is that you can't return two values,
you can always only return one value in a method, in Dart
in general, in basically any programming language in general, so this does not work.
Of course, you could return a list by wrapping this into square brackets because then you return one
value, a list and the list then has multiple values
but now a list is not a widget,
so that would not work.
However what you can do is of course here, you could return a list of widgets,
now this would be correct
and now if you also accept this argument here which is of course of type widget, then you can use your
builder method down there, forward the txListWidget variable which we defined in the build method
and pass this to buildPortraitContent which will then indeed return a list of widgets.
But now we have a new problem, a list of widgets is not accepted as a widget by Flutter.
Of course here in the children of our column, it wants a list of widgets, of single widgets, it does not
want a list of list of widgets but that's what we're creating here.
This builder method returns a list of widgets and not a single widget.
Now when we call it here, it therefore enters or adds this list of widgets into this list of widgets
and that's not what Flutter wants, it wants a single widget.
Now a good solution here is another modern syntax Dart supports, the so-called spread operator, the
spread operator is also available in JavaScript for example and it's simply three dots.
Now this looks strange.
You add these three dots in front of a list,
so in front of square brackets or like here, in front of a function or a method that returns a list
and of course, buildPortraitContent does return the list.
Now what do these three dots do with the list in front of which you add it? These three dots
tell Dart that you want to pull all the elements out of that list and merge them as single elements
into that surrounding list which we have here,
the children list for our column.
So now instead of adding a list to a list, we're adding all the elements of this list as single items
next to each other in this list,
we're flattening the list so to say. Instead of creating a nested list, we pull out the items and add
them as normal items to the outer list.
So now we only have a list of widgets because this here, these three dots, transform our list of widgets
into just widgets, into two widgets.
Now of course, you can use the spread operator not just with lists of widgets,
you can also use the spread operator with lists of numbers
if you have another scenario where you want to add a list of numbers as single numbers into an outer
list and so on. And with that pattern, we can also of course do the same down there for our ternary
expression, where we show either our chart or the transaction list. We can simply go up to our builder method
for the landscape content here and also wrap this into square brackets and return a list of widgets
here as well, return square brackets here and add a comma after the closing row and then add our ternary
expression.
And here now, we also need the media query, the appBar and transaction list widget,
so the same arguments we needed here for buildPortraitContent.
Hence I'll copy the argument list from there and add it to buildLandscapeContent here.
With that in the place where we call buildLandscapeContent, we have to parse the same arguments we
passed to buildPortraitContent just like this and since this now also returns a list of widgets, add
three dots in front of it to use the spread operator to convert the list of widgets into just widgets
that are added to the outer list
and now this if statement down there can be removed
So with that, the advantage is not that we have less code in this file,
we just moved the code into a different position but we have a more readable build method down there
now.
We have basically just a column down there and then we can clearly see that we seem to have two alternative
conditions and that we call different methods for each condition.
We can see that we seem to get back a list where we pull out elements and if we want to find out what's
in a method, well then we can simply control or command click on it and then change our code for that
content in this place here.
So it's not helping performance, it's not making the file shorter,
it even added a few lines but it makes our build method down there more readable.
So that's why using builder methods, not build but builder methods that build you parts of your widget
tree can be very helpful for improving code readability.
They don't have to return lists of widgets, if you only need to return one widget, you can do that too
but you can always return lists of widgets here with the help of the spread
operator.