To save the place here not just in memory where it's lost when we restart the app but instead in a database,
we need to get access to an on-device database.
Now the good thing is there is a database system, an engine which is supported by both iOS and Android and
that's SQLite. As the name suggests, this uses the SQL query language basically,
so the SQL approach of structuring and saving data and in case that doesn't tell you anything, attached
you find a link to a video where I dive into that and where I compare SQL to NoSQL as well
and SQL, SQLite specifically is supported on both Android and iOS, to work with such database,
we need a special package though. So let's search for SQL here on pub.dev and what you should
find is the SQFLite package here,
the SQFLite package helps you work with the SQL database on both Android and iOS. You
install it as always by grabbing this dependency and going to your pubspec.yaml file and adding
it there, like this and once you do this, you can also already quit the running process where this is
running on your real device or whatever it was because we need to rebuild and restart this anyways since
we again add a package that taps into native device features.
Now I want to store a new place in a database here in add place and later, I also want to add a fetch
place method to fetch data from the database.
We could have all the logic for working with the database in this file but I want to keep that file
focused on creating and storing places and the database access,
I'll put this into a separate folder, in the lib folder here and I'll name this helpers and in there, I want
to have a db_helper.dart file and in the end, that's just a file which will have
all the functionality to interact with the database.
Using that extra file is totally optional,
it's just keeping that other file leaner and more focused.
So here in db_helper, we can import that package which we just added, the SQFLite package and there
the sqflite.dart file and also, because we'll also need that, add the path package,
the path.dart file which we added earlier already.
I'll give this a prefix of path and this here, a prefix of SQL and using these prefixes as always
is totally optional.
Now my helper file here should include a class which I'll name db helper like this
and in there, I'll have static methods
so that we never need to instantiate that class but that we can simply work with these static methods
and the class therefore simply acts as a group around all these methods.
We could also just define a couple of functions in that file and therefore use these functions
in any other file which imports this file but I'm a fan of having a class as a wrapper around that.
Now in here, we'll need a function that allows us to insert something into the database, so I'll name
that insert but the name is up to you,
it's a static method so it should be available without the need to instantiate that class first and
it will actually return a future which in the end will yield nothing, a future because as you can imagine
such a database operation can take a bit longer and therefore is asynchronous. So in here,
I expect to get a couple of pieces of information, two pieces of information to be precise,
I want to get a string which is the table in the database where this should be added to, so that this
is actually a pretty flexible insert method, not really just aimed at inserting places but inserting
anything into any table.
Of course you could also write this in a less generic way, in a more specific way therefore
but here I'll make this really flexible and I'll get to the table to which I want to write as the first
argument and the second argument should be the data we want to write into the table and that should be a map
with string keys and then object value, so different kinds of values possibly.
Then I'll use async await because as I already mentioned, we'll work with futures in there because writing
to the database takes a while and now to write to the database, we need to get access to the database
and for that, we
first of all need to create a database
if we don't have one. The first step for that actually is to use the SQL package, so that SQL prefix
up there and then call get database path,
that's the path where you may store your database which you're about to create because that database
doesn't come together with your app,
you have to create such a database basically in your app folder or on the hard drive in a folder reserved
for your app and the SQL package gives you this convenience method which gives you the right path
for both iOS and Android.
So here, we'll get the db path and we have to await this because get database path returns a future which
then yields a string which is that path
in the end. So now we know where to store that, the next step is to actually call sql.openDatabase,
another method provided by that SQFLite package which allows us to open the database and it
either opens an existing one if it finds one in that path we specify here or it creates a new one.
Now the path is not just the db path because that's just a folder where we should store the database, it
instead has to be the path which includes the database name and for that, I'll use something from the path
package here because there, I can use the join method to create a new path made up of the db path and
then the second segment here should be places.db, .db is the extension of our database file.
So I'll create a new file which is named places and has the db extension in that path which we may use
to store our database.
Now when open database finds a database here, it will open that so that we can read and write to it.
If it doesn't find that file, which is the case when we execute the code for the first time ever in the
lifetime of our app,
so when it doesn't find that file, it will create the database and therefore, open database gives us
another argument which we can specify, the onCreate argument.
This takes a function and you can use a named or an anonymous function, a function which will execute
when SQL, so SQFLite tries to open the database and doesn't find the file.
Then it goes ahead and creates the file
and now you can run some code to initialize to database when it's created the first time.
Here, you get access to your database which was created for you by SQFLite and to the current
version of the database because that's already a third argument which we can pass to open database,
you can specify a version there to make clear that you want to open the file with that version and you
could theoretically change that version to override the existing database in the future if you want
to open that in a different version than it currently exists. Here,
I'll always work with the same version because I only want to have one database and we'll add and fetch
data to and from there
and when this is first created, I get access to the database here in this anonymous function we pass
to onCreate and in there, we now can call db.execute to run SQL query against our database. Now
actually, we should return the result of that, so that SQFLite knows when this is done because
this returns a future which basically tells SQFLite that it is done but for SQFLite to
digest that information, we need to return that future
and in there, you pass in a SQL statement.
Now if you're not fluent with SQL, the official docs here are a great place to learn more about the
basic commands and how it generally works
and there, you can also learn more than what I cover here in this course,
so definitely dive into that if you want to work with SQLite in your app and in general, you can
take any SQL course to learn a lot about how SQL works because SQLite basically works like
MySQL for example
regarding most of the queries at least. So here, you can now run create table which is a command to create
a new table in that database which you can give any name you want, like user_places for example
and then between brackets, between parentheses, you define which fields you want to have in the table
and there, I want to have an ID which will be of type text and which is the primary key,
that's a special instruction here, of that table and then separated with a comma, the next
field you want to specify which could be the title here which is also of type text but which of course
now is not our primary key.
You can have only one primary key, one primary identifier per table,
so here, the title and then maybe the image which here should be text and not a file because here, I
want to store the path to the image on our device and now with that, we get all the setup we need for
the moment. So let's save this here and
with that, we have an insert method which we should be able to use.
So in great_places.dart,
we can now import our helper,
so let's go to the helpers folder and import the db_helper.dart file there and in add place, I now want
to call that after adding it here in memory because we can certainly show the place in our app before
we reach out to the database and do the stuff there
and now we can use the db helper class here because we imported the db_helper.dart file, call insert
and I want to insert something in a table and the table name is totally up to you, I'll simply name it
places but again, up to you. The data here should be a map though and in the map, you want to have your
key-value pairs and there,
I'll have my ID which is of course the ID of my new place.
So here, I'll use newPlace.id, then I'll have the title and that's of course
newPlace.title
and I also want to have my image here and that's now a newPlace.image.path and the
.path of course is important because you want to store the path to the image on your local hard drive
in the device so to say and not the image file,
you can't store the image file in the database.
Now one thing we're not doing right now though is if you go back to the db helper, there we are certainly
opening the database but we're not inserting anything there,
instead we're just executing this command to create our database. Well indeed, open database returns a
future which yields you a handle to the database, so access to the database. So you can store that in
a new variable or a constant, maybe named sqlDB for SQL database
and of course here, we need to add await so that we wait for this future which open database yields
to resolve
which then gives us this database
and now we can use sqlDB here to run commands against it, for example the insert command. This now
takes a table where it should insert something and that's the table argument we're getting here,
so I'll use that in here and the values which we want to enter and the values that should be entered
here,
well that should be a map. Now we're getting such a map here,
so here I'll simply forward the data I'm getting as argument. Now I'll pass the third argument and that's
the conflictAlgorithm named argument and I'll set this to conflictAlgorithm.replace and this means
that if we're trying to insert data for an ID which already is in the database table, then we'll override
the existing entry, the existing record with the new data. Shouldn't really happen but that is how we
would do that.
With that, we're now really inserting something here and if we await that, then we make sure that this
overall method only finishes. So resolves void in the end because I'm not returning anything then thereafter,
so resolves void
once this is done.
So now we're actually also inserting something and now create places insert can fully do its job.
So with that, we're inserting
but of course it would also be interesting to fetch data from there and that's the next thing we'll
do.