So now that we saw the real time functionality of Firebase in Action, and now that we saw how we can
connect our Flutter app with help of the Firebase SDK to Firebase, the service, which just make this
clear again is totally decoupled from Flutter.
It works with web apps, with native Android apps, it works with a bunch of other apps as well.
But we can also use it with Flutter through that SDK.
So now that we made this to work, let's take a step back.
We don't need to chat screen right now.
We need to off screen instead because we want to build an application where users have to authenticate
before they can chat.
So let's go to the off screen dart file and let's create a new widget in there.
And that should be a state full widget now.
So make sure you create that stateful widget class here and the state class that belongs to it.
And here I'm using the shortcut where I can type stuff in visual pseudocode and then I get this suggestion
and by clicking tab or by hitting tab, this is generated and here I'll name this off screen and you
see it enters this in all the relevant places.
And I will also import material, material dot dart from the flutter package.
And now here I want to render my well guess what my off screen.
For that.
Here.
Instead of rendering a container, I'll render a scaffold because I want to have a nice background and
so on.
And I will set the background color of this page, not to the default to this grayish white look, but
instead I want to use my primary color here and with theme of context, primary color, we get access
to that as you learn from the course.
Now for the body of the scaffold here.
Of course I want to display some form.
So in the end, a form where the user can enter the email, the password and the username, and later
also pick an image.
That's the goal here.
For that form, I'll use the center widget to have a well centered widget, and the child of that center
widget could be a card, and that's another widget that comes with Flutter.
And on that card, I'll set the margin on the Card constructor here to Edge Insets all 20 to have a
little bit of margin around the cards, a little bit of empty space and the child of the card.
So the content inside of the card should be a single child.
Scroll view, whoops, a single child scroll view so that we can scroll if the form elements should
take up too much space so that we never have a situation where one of the elements is unreachable.
And inside of that single child scroll view.
On the other hand, I want to have some padding, so I'll use the padding widget here and set the padding
to edge insets all 16.
And these are just some values that I picked in advance that should look nice.
Of course, you can use different values here and play around with different values.
I'll take 16 as a pattern here, and then the child of the padding widget here is the actual form widget,
which will soon include all the form fields.
Now I'll just restructure this to make this a bit easier to read.
And this is the widget tree we have thus far.
Now, I can already tell that this form will be a bit longer.
We'll have multiple form elements in there, and therefore I'll do one thing.
I'll actually grab this entire center widget here and cut it.
And in the widgets folder I'll add a new off folder and in that new off folder I will add my auth.
Form the dart file.
So did I basically outsource this off form into a separate widget just to make each widget on its own
a little bit more manageable and a little bit smaller.
Now, the off form widget will also manage the different input states of the user, and therefore this
actually also will be a stateful widget.
For example, we will need to be able to switch between, log in and sign up mode and update the UI
respectively.
So we need to manage some state in here.
Hence this is the auth form and we need to import material to start from flutter again.
And here instead of returning a container, I will return my center widget.
So the content I just cut from the off screen and therefore here in the off screen file as a body,
I can render this off form.
Now again, I just split this into two widgets to make each widget a bit more manageable.
Will of course, all to add some logic to have those widgets communicate with each other.
So make sure you add this input to the off form DART file and let's go back to the off form and work
on that form.
Now the form itself will have a couple of children.
Of course it can only have one child, but this child can be a column.
And now we are able to define a couple of children, which are all part of that form.
Now I want to make sure that this column actually takes only as little space as it needs so that it
doesn't take all available space, but that it basically just takes the space its children need.
So I'll set the main axis size of this column widget to main axis size dot min.
And this makes sure that the column does not take as much height as possible, but only as much as needed.
Now to define how much space is needed and to have all the inputs we need in the children here in this
list, inside of the column, I now want to render all the text form fields we need.
So here we can add the first text firm field for, let's say our email and a second text firm field
thereafter for the username and a third text form field for the password.
Now we'll not always need all of them, but that will generally be the fields we need.
Of course, we'll also add image upload later though.
Now let's start with that first text form field here.
We want to take the email address of the user.
So I'll set the keyboard type here to text input, type, dot email whoops, type email address so that
we present the right keyboard.
We can also set the decoration of this text form field because as you'll learn in this course with the
decoration configuration here, you are able to set the label.
For example, decoration takes an object of type input decoration, hence will use this constructor
to create such an object.
And there we can now set the label text to email address and if we want also the label style, for example,
to be bold.
I'll not do that here though, but of course you could.
And in general you can, of course, style this entirely in the way you want.
This year is the first text form field.
It's missing a bunch of things, of course, and will soon add more logic.
But this is the base configuration, the minimal configuration I want.
Now on the next text firm field in line here I want to get the username.
So therefore here I'm fine with the default keyboard type.
We don't need to set a different type, but I want to set a decoration so that we can actually set the
label.
So here the label text is username to make it clear which kind of input we're expecting here.
And then the third text from Field also takes a declaration where we can set the label text to password.
And now important since this is a password, I also want to make sure that the input of the user is
hidden and we can do that by setting the obscure text configuration or argument on the text form field
constructor to true.
And this will hide the text entered by the user.
Now below all these text form fields, I'll add a sized box, which is a box that we can use to insert
some space, and I'll set the height here to 12.
I'm doing this because below that I want to add a raised button, which in the end allows the user to
submit this form.
So the child of this button is a text widget where we can simply say, log in, though we will also
set this text dynamically soon.
We also should add on pressed here to define the function that should execute when the button is pressed
and right now this is just an empty dummy function because we don't have the final logic yet.
And with that, I'm done with this button right below it.
I will also add a flat button.
This should be the button we use for switching between.
Log in and sign up mode.
So here the child is actually a text where I say, for example, create new account.
This text will also soon be set dynamically.
And I want to also add on pressed here and do nothing at the moment.
Okay.
Cool.
So that's the basic off for him, which does nothing but which we should be able to see.
So let's go to the main dart file and instead of the chat screen here on home, let's load the off screen
and make sure you therefore also add the import to the off screen here.
We can also keep the chat screen important because we will need that later again.
If you now save everything, you should see that log in screen here and that doesn't look too shabby,
but I want to use different colours here, so let's work on the theming in the next lecture.