Now the price and the title are not all,
we also of course need an input for the description. So I'll copy the title input here and move that after
the price input and on there, I'll say description as a label text and the text input
action here should still be next because I still want to go to a different input thereafter but now
the special thing about the description input here will be that it actually should be suited for longer
inputs because the description of a product potentially is longer.
For that I'll add a maxLines argument here and set this to three to determine how long this may be, how
many lines should be rendered on the screen so to say, the user can always enter more by scrolling
in the text field but that determines how big the text field container is in the end. I will also set
a special keyboard type with text input type as we did it for the price
and here to multiline which gives us a keyboard that is particularly suited for multiline text input.
Now with that actually, I do remove the next text input action because multiline will automatically
give us an enter symbol in the bottom right corner of the soft keyboard so that we can enter a new line
there, hence we also don't need onFieldSubmitted there because the user will have to move to the next
input on his own because we can't tell when he's done because we'll have an enter symbol to simply add
a new line but let's simply see that.
So if I save this, we go back,
you see this is now bigger than the other inputs because we set maxLines to three
and now if I tap in here, this is this new line button which I meant, you see the cursor here jumps
into different lines
if I press that and that's why we can't go to a new text input or go to the next input because we don't
know when the user wants to add a new line or when the user wants to quit editing this,
so we'll leave that to the user and always create a new line
and if the user wants to go to a different input, he simply has to tap it.
So now with that, we have the description input here as well
now let's make sure we can go there from the price input by also assigning a focus node to it.
So just as before, we can create another focus node,
now it's the descriptionFocusNode like this and we now assign this here as a focus node to the description
input and on the price input where we have that next button in the soft keyboard, we also use on field
submitted as we did it on the title input and of course here, we request focus for the description focus
node. With that if we save that and we're in the price, if I hit next, I go to description.
Now one other important note about focus nodes by the way, you have to dispose them when your state gets
cleared,
so when this object gets removed, when you'll leave that screen because the focus nodes otherwise will
stick around in memory and will lead to a memory leak.
So when working with focus nodes as we're doing it here, you should add a dispose method to your state
object where you're using them and then in there, call price focus node dispose and do the same for the
description focus
node to be sure that you clear up that memory, free up that memory which they occupy and avoid memory
leaks.
That's an important side note here,
if you're working with your own focus nodes, you need to dispose of them in the dispose method in your
state.
And with that, we added some core inputs here which allow us to enter a couple of important pieces of
information about a product.
One missing piece if we have a look at the definition of a product of course is the imageUrl
because that is something we also need,
ID can be automatically generated,
favourite is set to false but the imageUrl is something the user needs to enter.
So let's make sure we have an input for that as well.