Were you successful?
Let's do it together.
So let's start by positioning the items and for that
let's go to our column here which holds the title and the date
and there, you learned that you can adjust the alignment with main axis and cross axis alignment
but what do we need here?
Remember in a column, main axis is top to bottom, cross axis is left to right.
Since I want to change the positioning on the left to right, so on the cross axis from center which is
the default to start, I need to target the cross axis alignment here.
So let's set cross axis alignment to cross axis alignment.start
and this will move the items to the left.
Now let's work on the text style of the title.
So here's our title and as you learned, you can add the style argument and instantiate a text style object
to control the style of this text.
There, you can set the font size let's say to 18 and the font weight here, maybe to FontWeight.bold,
just like we did it for the amount. This looks better,
a little bit of a smaller font size, maybe 16, so that's looking good. For the date,
I want to give this a gray color, so therefore I'll give this a style as well,
text style because in there, in this object we can set a color property and I'll set this to colors gray,
like this.
Okay, now with that, our transaction items here are taking shape,
certainly not the final form in which I want to have them
but a good start.
Let's now see with what we can continue.