So we added a loading spinner.
That's nice and certainly helpful to our users.
But what if things go wrong?
If things go wrong, for example, when adding a product, then currently we're not doing anything.
Now here in this application, there is little that could go wrong.
To be honest, I have a good internet connection here.
Firebase is a stable service.
Errors are unlikely, but of course, in reality, errors will happen.
Your users lose the internet connection.
There is an error on the server or invalid data is sent somehow and here I can simulate an error by
removing dot jason at the end.
Firebase will not like this and will actually throw an error.
Now let me demonstrate this.
If I now go to manage products and I try to add a new product, a book for 1299, this is an awesome.
Book.
If I now try to add this with my.
Dummy image here.
And I should say, if we see the spinner and now the spinner will not go away, simply because if we
go back, we see that there is an error.
There is an error thrown by firebase or returned by firebase, and that then is automatically caught
by the HTTP package we're using and thrown as an error in our app.
And the error we're getting here in the end is giving us an error message which is quite helpful, which
is actually nice and would help us fix that error since this of course is an error I introduced as a
developer.
We see it's of type format exception in DART there are different exception base classes which are built
into DART which describe errors that can happen.
And here we're having such an error.
So this request here is in the end now following an error and it's bubbling up and becomes a real error
in our app which is thrown here in the debug console and crashes our app because we're not handling
that error.
We should handle such errors not only because we then avoid the app crashing, but also because this
of course, is not a great user experience showing that spinner and not telling the user anything.
That's not that great.
How can you handle errors?
Well, we use them here on our future to define the function, the code that should run when this future
succeeds.
Now, similarly, you can also define a method that should run when that fails, and you can simply
add this after.
Then here you can add it after then, because then itself returns a new future.
And therefore whatever I call after dat.
So with a dot on the result of then is effectively called on the future return by then.
Right.
So I'm calling this on that future object then returns.
I could also call catch error here in front of then and then I would also handle errors thrown by this
post method, which is the method that yields these this error here in the end.
But if I call catch error here before I have my then block, then the logic in this then block will
also execute once my logic and catch error is done.
I don't want that.
Instead, by adding catch error here, I can now define a function which will be called whenever an
error is thrown either here or here.
And if an error is thrown here while sending the post request, the then block will be skipped and we
immediately reach this function here in catch error.
So here in catch error you do indeed the final function which receives the error data, the error object
which was thrown, which describes the error, which here in this case, as I mentioned, is an object
based on the built in format exception class and it contains an error message which is automatically
printed here.
And we can now interact with that error.
For example, with print error here, I can also print that error message.
And now here we could do all kinds of things with that error that you want to do.
The core thing is that now our app will not crash anymore because with this we're already handling the
error.
So we're telling Dart, it's fine, I got you covered, I'm doing something on that error and that's
already an improvement because the app does not crash technically anymore.
Again, as I mentioned, the code in here in the then block will be skipped if the error is thrown instead
of our post method there, which is the case for this error I added here and therefore we make it straight
to catch error.
Now of course here we could do all kinds of error handling, for example, also send this to our custom
analytics server to store this error message there and get notified about that error in one of our apps
or just log it here, which isn't too useful because the user will not see that.
So what we might want to do here is either not use catch error here at all or simply use the flow keyword
which is built into dart to throw that error we're getting here again.
So fro takes an error object and we're getting an error object here and it will now create a new error.
So we're handling the error here and now I'm creating a new one.
I'm only doing this because I have catch error here and I want to be able to add a never catch error
clause in another place.
And that I replace is the edit product screen.
That's of course the screen where we send that request right here we call ad product there we handle
the success case and there we now have the problem that we have no success case but that we have an
error.
So what we can do here is we can add catch error here as well.
And now this will be reached because I'm throwing my error here again.
Alternatively, if we would leave out catch error here altogether, we would also reach catch error
here.
So catch error is reached if there is an error, but only the first catch error in line will execute
then and that will then handle the error.
So here we now also get that error object and here we can now also do with what we want.
But.
Here.
Of course, the great thing is we're now in the widget, so here we can now do something which the user
sees to inform the user about the error.
So here we could send or show a dialogue with show dialogue.
And show dialogue takes a context.
And there we can use the context property which is available everywhere in your state object when and
your state class.
And we're in the state class here, of course.
And besides the context, show dialogue also takes a builder which is used to build this dialogue.
It takes a function which gets its own context generated by Flutter.
And then here we typically return an alert dialog which allows us to configure such a dialog box which
is presented to the user in that dialog box.
Here I'll set a title and error occurred.
Sounds like a fitting title.
Whoops, that should be a text widget though.
Not just plain text.
And besides the title, we also want to have a content here and there.
I'll have another text widget where I say something.
Went wrong, though, if we wanted to.
Instead of having our generic text here, we could also simply use the error here.
Error is an object which will have a message inside of it and it's configured all exception.
Classes in DART are configured to have a two string method.
That's actually a method which every object in DART has.
So every custom object has to string as well because DART basically gives you this object based class
on which every class in Dart invisibly depends.
So to string is available on every value in DART, but to string on error objects is specifically configured
to simply print a readable error message.
And that's why here in our error log, for example, you see this nice message that's coming from two
string being called on the error and then gives us the error message, which in this case Firebase gave
us.
Now we could print this, but often these error messages are really technical, or you don't even want
to show them to your users because they might contain confidential information.
So here I'll go with something went wrong for the moment.
Later in the authentication section, we'll see more fine grained error handling in action.
With that, I'm building that dialogue now.
I also want to add an action to close it.
For that I add a flat button here where the child is a text widget, where I say, okay, and upon pressing,
I just want to close this dialog.
And we can close a dialog simply by calling navigator off context pop as you learned.
So we close overlays of any kind and dialogues are such overlays with pop and just like removing the
current screen of the stack, this removes the current overlay which is on that same stack, so to say.
And here we can actually use the context we're getting here.
So with that, I'm closing that.
I'm showing my dialogue when I get an error.
The missing thing, though, is that I actually do want to remove the loading spinner and maybe all
the close to page if we are done, no matter if we got an error or not.
Because even with an error, we're downloading and I want to give control back to the user.
I just want to let the user know about that error.
Now that let the user know part is finished here.
We now also want to ensure that we reach then.
And the good thing is, that's what I mentioned earlier already.
Catch error catches the error, but then you see catch error actually returns a new future.
So then after catch error will also execute because we're calling this on a future which is automatically
created by catch error and therefore here we're actually fine.
Here we actually will trigger this code in there automatically because since then comes after catch
error, it will be triggered once that error is handled.
I just want to wait until the user made his choice and right now we would immediately pop and actually
change that state here instead of want to wait until the user answered the dialog.
And the good thing is that the dialog also returns a future out of the box.
That's how Flutter configure instead.
So here we can actually return to result of show dialog, which is just that future.
And that future will be resolved with the value we chose here for popping the dialog.
Right.
That's also something we did earlier in the course.
So only as soon as the user click the button and this is popped, this future will be resolved.
Since I returned the future here in this function, that will be the future return by catch error and
therefore it is then block will only execute.
Once this dialog was closed to once this button was pressed and we popped the dialog.
So with that we now have an error handling logic in place which should allow us to successfully handle
that error.
So now if I try this again with some dummy data here, maybe.
This is some test.
And I add my image here.
Now you see that spinner.
Now we get that overlay, that dialog.
But if I press, okay, we actually close that page still and here we only see that shorter output instead
of that crashing error message because our app now didn't crash.
And that output here is only printed because I'm printing the error here and that prints the error message,
which happens to be that.
So this is how that works and how we can handle errors in DART.
A very useful tool of course, because that helps us ensure that we provide a pleasant user experience.
And with that back in product start, I'll re ad dot JSON here because of course here I want to make
sure that we have a successful request again.
Now in the off section, by the way, I will also show you a different way or a way of throwing your
own custom exceptions in case you don't have a technical error.
In case Firebase doesn't report back an error with an error status code and you are still not happy
with the result in the off section.
I'll have a good example for that.
So there will also come back to this.
For now we have all the error handling in place that we need.