In the first app, you already saw it and throughout this course, you will see it, Flutter by default embraces
the material design system, the material design language. Material design looks like this as an example.
and it's a design system created and heavily used by Google.
Now it's not Google's style for everyone though, it it's highly customizable and works on iOS devices
too, so you can also use it in your iOS apps
and whilst material design is built into Flutter, you also find Apple styled widgets in the Flutter
framework which you can use
and in this course, I will show you both.
I will show you how to build apps that look like the typical material design application,
I will show you how to set up your own look,
so neither material design, not iOS style
and I will also show you how you can get that iOS look with the so-called Cupertino widgets which
Flutter also offers.
So here again, Flutter gives you full flexibility regarding how your app should look like
and in this course, I'll cover all the different options and show you how you build different kinds of
apps. For the majority,
I'll use the built-in material design widgets but you will learn how you could deviate from this as
well.