So let's make sure we can use the token everywhere and for that,
let's go to the products.dart file first of all where we already have the token added and in there, we're
using it for fetching the products,
now of course we also need it for adding a product and we add it in exactly the same way,
?auth at the end and then here, point at authToken with string interpolation and this is
no longer a const but
now a runtime constant value with final. Now of course, we also need it for updating a product
so in there, let's add auth and set that equal to the authToken as well and also here for deleting a product,
so here also auth equal to auth token, like this.
Now there's one place that's a bit more tricky and that's inside of a single product. There we also send
a HTTP request to update the favorite status of that product,
we also need the token in here. Now for a single product,
that means that we also need to kind of get the token right. Now you could also add the token
here as a property and then simply pass the token in from inside products which is where you do create
a single product here and there of course, you could also forward your authToken if you wanted that
in product
but there also is another route you could take
and either way is ok in my opinion. You can go to the place where you in the end trigger that HTTP request
and that's from inside the
product_item.dart file here, there we have the toggle favorite status call and in there, we could also say that
this method simply accepts the token,
then we just have to make sure that we have the token available here and we can of course make it available
here in this widget if we want to.
So both ways are OK,
I just want to show this alternative. In product.dart in the providers folder,
we can say that we expect the token as an argument to toggle favorite status, so that here we can also
add it with string interpolation, that token we're getting here and now in product_item where we need
that token, we can get our AuthData or whatever you want to name it with provider of and then point at
the auth class because of course we are providing that here in our main.dart file,
right,
so of course we can get access to that, for that we just need to import the auth provider class here
into this file, like this and now here we forward the context.
I don't want to set up a listener, I just want to get the token one time and now with AuthData available
here, of course we can forward AuthData.token and that's it,
this also now passes the token and we can use it here,
so this is one possible approach.
Now we always need the token for our orders, not in the cart but in the orders and there, I will use the
same approach as my products.
So besides having my orders here, I want to have my authToken in here which actually should be final
and for that, I expect to get that through the constructor and I also want to set my orders here though
and with that, we can go to the main.dart file where we provide the orders and use the same approach as
for products, instead of this provider here, we use the ChangeNotifierProxyProvider like that, instead
of having value here, we have a builder. We need to set the generic types here for this constructor and
that is our dependency and then the value we're about to provide, the dependencies of and we're about
to provide orders,
so we need to set this and the builder now is a function that receives a context, receives our auth
object and our previous orders object and returns a new orders object here and in that new orders object,
we want to pass that token, like this here and our previous orders,
so here we'll have the previous orders, check if it's equal to null in which case I want
to pass in an empty array, empty list and otherwise if it's not null, we can access the orders here and
initialize the orders in the newly built orders object with our old orders. With that, we should actually
be able to send all requests in authenticated state.
So let's do a full refresh and login again and we'll of course also work on making sure that we don't
always have to login.
So let's login here and let's try favoriting this, seems to work,
let's reload that page, still there.
Let's place an order, order now seems to work,
let's go to orders and here, I get an error actually.
Let's quickly check,
yes,
makes sense,
getting the token in orders is nice,
you also have to use it for the requests.
So here for fetch and select orders, we want to use auth and then use our authToken
and of course this therefore is a final
URL not a const
URL and do the same for adding an order
and by the way, there
I didn't get an error when we tried to add the order in the cart because we haven't implemented error
handling simply to save time,
obviously that was a good proof for why you might want to do that if you're building a real application
to make sure that you actually show an error if something goes wrong.
Now however, I do use my authToken for orders too,
so let's retry that all,
let's do a full refresh here and then log back in here with our data, like this
and now actually add this again to the cart, place that order
and now go to the orders screen
and now here are the orders, here's our latest order.
Let's also try to manage our products, add a new product here. So we add some book for example,
29.99,
this is a book
and then here, use the same image I use before
and then save this. So this seemed to work, let's also check it on Firebase to be super safe.
There, if we have a look at our data, in products,
there is a third element and that is the element I just added.
Let's now also edit it to see whether that also works,
maybe the title and the price and add a couple of exclamation marks here, that's looking good.
Let's go to the shop real quick and view it there as well,
I see the price, I see the exclamation marks down there.
Back to managing,
let's delete it and this also worked, it's gone here.
So this all works. Now missing pieces are that we automatically logged the user in when there is a valid
token and the user just closed the app or reloaded the app somehow,
we also want to make sure that the user is able to logout and of course, we also want to make sure
that we scope orders and favorite status to a user, so that if you hit favorite, you don't change the
overall configuration of that product but instead you just change it for your user, for this product
and that you also have your own orders instead of having a generic global pool of orders which everyone
can access, that makes no sense.
In addition, it also makes sense that we add our userId here to the products so that when we try to
manage the products here, we actually only load products for our ID,
so for our user and not all products, all products should only be loaded here on the shop page.
So the next steps will be on scoping data to our user, making sure it belongs to our user before we then
work on the auto login and logout functionality.