Besides the lifecycle of a widget and the state of a widget, the overall app also has a lifecycle.
There's a couple of different lifecycle states and of course, the important question then always is when
is this state reached,
when can you execute code based on that state,
for example you have the inactive state. Inactive means that your app is not even running in background,
it's inactive, the user can't see it, it can't receive user input,
it's not fully cleared from memory yet but it's definitely not too active. A state that can be reached
on both operating systems is paused
however, this is when the app is not visible and when it's running in background,
so when you can reach it through the task manager of your application for example. This is available on
both Android and iOS and you can react to the app transitioning into that mode in your code, for example
to do some last minute cleanup,
clear some connection to a server or anything like that.
Now of course, since you have paused, you also have resumed.
This state is reached when your app is coming back from the background mode
if it's again visible and again responding to user input
and this is also available both on Android and iOS.
So this would be a good place to then again set up a live connection to a server, check whether you want
to change something in your app, fetch new data, anything like that and there also is a suspending
state which is reached when the app is about to be suspended, so when it's almost gone but still there
but when it's about to be cleared by the operating system, when it's about to be removed from memory.
Now for all these states, it's important that you never have a 100% guarantee that
your listeners to these states are executed, especially for suspending and so on,
for example if a battery suddenly goes off or a user removes the battery from the phone, then your app
might not reach that state because it's not a clean exit as initialized by the operating system but
a hard exit
due to some external factor, that's something to keep in mind.
Now in most cases however, you can listen to these lifecycles and therefore let's do just that.
So how can we listen to these app lifecycle events?
Let's do it here in the main.dart file on our
MyHomePageState,
there you can add a so-called mix in.
We haven't used that before,
it's a bit like a class and it's a bit like extending a class but your class is now not
based on that class but it adds a certain feature from that class you're mixing into your class, so you're
adding certain properties, certain methods
this other class has without fully inheriting this other class. It has some technical differences
you also only can inherit from one class, so if you want to bring in features from multiple classes, you
would use a mix in. You use a mix in by adding a with keyword after your class and after all your
extensions or the one class you're extending from possibly and then the name of the class you want to extend
and here,
that's that WidgetsBindingObserver class. WidgetsBindingObserver is something you import here and
or you add here as a mix in and once you did that, you can add a new method,
maybe here after our properties. The new method you can add
now is didChangeAppLifecycleState, that actually is a method added by the mix in and therefore we
add @Override here to make clear that we deliberately override this. You return nothing here, hence
you have to add void and this method receives an argument of type AppLifeCycleState which you can
give any name you want
and this is the state the app now transition too.
So this method will be called whenever your lifecycles state changes, whenever the app reaches a new
state in lifecycle.
Now here already important and hence you should always add this mix in on a state object, on a class
extending state, you also want to clear that listener to lifecycle changes when that widget, when
that state object is not required anymore.
So let's add dispose here with @Override and in there, call super.dispose and clear listeners to
lifecycle changes,
otherwise you keep that listener up and running even if that state class, that state object should be
deleted.
Of course here for our main state, that can't happen because when that gets removed, the entire app is
shut down
but if you have a bigger app and you add your app lifecycle listeners in just one child widget somewhere
down the widget tree of your app because in that child widget you're interested in changes to the lifecycle
of the app,
well then when that child widget gets removed, you certainly also want to clear your lifecycle listeners
to avoid memory leaks.
So here in dispose, you clear all listeners you have to the app lifecycle by referring to widgets binding
and then there, the instance property and there you call remove observer
this. Now before you can remove it however, you also need to set up a listener, so for this method to be
triggered,
you need to add a listener and you do this by adding initState
and there you now use widgets binding instance add observer this.
So with this line, you're saying or you're telling Flutter hey whenever my lifecycle state changes, I
want you to go to a certain observer and call the didChangeAppLifeCycleState method,
that's what widgets binding tells Flutter. We then tell Flutter that the observer is this,
so this class itself and therefore this class of course needs to have a didChangeAppLifeCycleState.
With that now available, this will get triggered whenever the app lifecycle changes and as explained,
we have to clear our listener,
we have to clear our observer here to avoid memory leaks
when this state object should be removed.
And now in this method here, didChangeAppLifecycleState,
you can react to changes in your app lifecycle and for now, I'll simply print state here so that we can
see what the new state is.
For that, let's restart the app, let's maybe even do a full rebuild here. So close the running emulator and
restart without debugging so that this gets rebuilt and launched on the emulator or on the real device
and let's see what's happening there, which logs we see. The app restarted
and if we go back to the debug console now, we see no lifecycle states here,
right,
we see just the build methods running, constructors running and so on, we see no lifecycle, app lifecycle
methods here. That will change if we go back and we press that home screen button here on Android.
So we're back on the home screen but our app is still running,
we could access it here through the task manager.
Now what you see is that here, we entered inactive,
so this was briefly entered on Android but then immediately after that, we actually entered paused.
So it first gets inactive but then Android kind of detects hey this is actually just paused, it's running
in background
and now if I open the task manager and I go back into this application,
we see that there,
here is where we were, it briefly goes back into inactive,
so basically during this switch, it goes into inactive but then it enters resume because now it's getting
back from paused to running again.
Now if I kill the app now by swiping up here in the task manager, we see it enters inactive and paused and
what we don't see here is suspended,
so this is not getting printed here. In theory, suspended should be reached here
but since we clear the app here, also the connection, the debugging connection here is cleared and hence
the suspended state whilst reached might not make it into our console here because we already cleared
our listener here to our app.
So this all happens in a very short amount of time and therefore, suspended should run,
as I mentioned on the slide, you can't always rely on it but it should run
but here for example, we don't get our log being printed because we already cleared the connection,
the debugging connection to that app
basically at the same point of time suspended would run. But we can clearly see inactive and paused and
resumed which are the most important lifecycle hooks because you would use that to, as I said, for example
a refetch data when it's coming back into foreground or to clear listeners when the app is getting
paused.