Let's get there step-by-step.
The first step which I want to take is that we make sure that when we favorite a product, we actually
only do that for ourselves and not for everyone.
So therefore in the product.dart file where we send a request to mark a product as a favorite, here
I actually will send this to a different URL and that different URL could be user favorites,
whatever you want to name it, then I want to have a dynamic segment here with the userId so that we
have a subfolder for that userId only and then in there, yet another folder or another entry so to say
with the product ID. So actually I need two IDs now,
this here is the product ID but I also need the userId. Now since I get the token here as an argument,
it makes sense to also get the userId as an argument here and then this would be the thing I want
to use here.
So this is the userId, we now need to ensure that this reaches this method here in the product_item.dart
file as a second argument
and of course we can go to our auth.dart file in the providers folder because in there, we have the
userId and we're setting that ID when a user is logged in, we're setting it here,
so all we have to do is add a getter. Let's add a getter here, userId and here, I'll not really add a
long check,
we could check if the user is authenticated and otherwise return null
but it's kind of redundant here,
so I'll just return userId, like this. Let's go back to the product_item.dart file and therefore now we can
access authData.userId here now.
So I'm now sending this into toggle favorite status and here, this request should now be sent somewhere
else.
Let's give this a try, let's again login here like this and let's ignore what we see here as a status
with the hearts,
let's press the favorite button here and on Firebase,
you should see that you now have a new user favorites folder, the new entry and that actually should
be the ID of your user.
Let's kind of remember it starts with vtf0,
let's go to authentication, yes
vtf0
that looks pretty good to me,
so that clearly is our userId
So back to the database data, in that folder,
we have another entry, for that product,
we set isFavorite to true.
Now actually, this is kind of a redundant entry, sending a post request there is not really what I want
to do, I don't want to append new values there all the time when we switch our status,
instead I want to override the existing status.
So now instead of sending a patch request here which was good for the old approach where we stored this
together with the other product data, now we can send a put request here because now I really just want
to send
true or false as a value.
So I will just send isFavorite
which is true or false and not in curly braces but just as a standalone value still encoded to JSON
but other than that as a standalone value.
So now let me actually clear that entry and let's save that and let's see what this now generates when
we use put and just send true or false.
So again real quick, let's login here and yes this is annoying, we'll fix it later and let's press this
heart again
and now you see we have a new entry where we simply have that ID which is the product ID here if
you want to compare it and set to true.
If I press that heart again, it's updated to false.
This now works
but of course we now also have to take this into account when we fetch our products because now the
favorite status will not be included in the product anymore
and I will already delete it from there because it simply shouldn't be part of our product data anymore,
the favorite status is not part of the products anymore.
So back in our code,
that means that when we add a product,
here in products.dart when we add a product, of course I'll no longer add isFavorite to the data we submit
because a new product on the server should no longer have a favorite status
and it also means that when we fetch products, we of course also want to fetch data for the favorite
status
and we haven't done this thus far. So here in fetch and set products, besides fetching a list of products,
we also want to fetch the favorite statuses and I want to do that before I transform my product data.
So actually here, I don't want to do that
if we have no product, so I'll wait for this check
but after this check, it's time for another request where we get our favorite response or whatever you
want to call it, where we await another HTTP get request
but now the URL here will be this URL of course which we have in the product.dart
file where we sent that favorite status to. So we can copy it from there, the token is now named auth
token here and we're not looking for a specific product ID but instead, I want to fetch all favorite
information for the logged in user.
Now the userId is not an information I have in here but just like the authToken, we can of course
expect to get this here.
So we can expect to have the user ID here and maybe get this as a second argument if you will
and then we just have to go to the main.dart file again and ensure that we receive the userId here.
So now here for the product's constructor, we also forward auth.userId as a second argument.
Now we have the userID here and therefore we can also use it here in this request and I shouldn't
name this URL because this is final, I'm overriding it.
Let me turn this into a var up there,
remove final down there and simply overwrite the URL because we only need it for this request and
then we can assign a new value for this request.
So now I get all the favorite data for all products that this user favorited or marked as a favorite,
this should of course be
response.
So now for creating our products here which we then store locally, we have to take that data into account
which we get back here and what we will get back of course will be in the end a map where we have key
value pairs, where the key should be product ID and values should be true or false,
so a pretty trivial map which we get back. So I'll create my favorite data here and there, I will JSON
decode the favorite response body and that will be the map I just described. Here where we create the products,
when I assign the favorite status, we no longer get that from the prodData but from the favorites data
and there I just explained, we'll have keys which match our product IDs and then the value will be false
or true.
So I just have to access the prodId here and I should be good to go. Now a check is required
though, for one I want to check if favorite data is equal to null, if that is the case, then this user
has never favorited anything,
so then obviously every product will just be not a favorite,
so we set this to false,
only if the user has some favorite data we can check for that productId
but that product ID still might not exist. If we find no entry for prodId, this here will be null.
Now if it is null, I want to use an alternative value.
We can do this with a double question mark
operator which simply checks whether that is null.
If it's not null, it will use that value and if it is null, it will fallback to the value after the double
question marks
and that would be false as well. So if favorite data is null or if we find no entry for that ID, we'll
set it to false,
otherwise we'll use that entry which we find and that should now actually load our products such that it
takes the favorite data we store here into account. So with that all saved, we can reload the app
and log back in here and
now let's see, this reloads and none of that is a favorite
and that makes sense because we only have one entry and that is set to false.
So even though we have an entry for one product, it's false.
Let's switch this to a favorite here and it's true therefore and then let's reload that page here by simply
revisiting it
and now this is loaded correctly.
If I switch both to a favorite and I reload, it should load and fill out both hearts right from the start
and if I clear that and I reload, only the book should be a favorite.
So this seems to work and we're now storing our favorites on a per user basis, so that if a different
user logs in which I can demonstrate by refreshing the app and logging in with that second user I also
created earlier,
if we now login here with test2@test.com which is my other user, then here we should also be
able to load all the products of course but if we do so, we see two empty hearts, even though one product
is a favorite but it's a favorite of the other user. So that's how we scope the favorite mode or status
to our user,
let's now make sure that the products themselves also belong to users and that on the managed products
page, we really only find the products that we own.