So when this button is pressed, the current location button, I want to go ahead and fetch the user location.
For that, in the location input widget, we can add a new method which will eventually return a future
that will then resolve to nothing though, I named this _getCurrentUserLocation or anything like
that, the name is up to you, doesn't take any arguments but will work with async code and I want to use that
async await syntax, hence the async keyword here and hence this returns a future.
Now here, we can use the location package. So for that,
let's import package location and then location.dart,
this package we installed and we can now instantiate location here, like that
and then call get location on that instance. Now get location yields a future which then eventually
will give us the location data, since that data is probably what we're interested in,
I'll store it in a constant, locData and await this future here.
So with that, we got the location data,
let me now simply print locData and there, we'll have a latitude and also a longitude field and that's
of course exactly what we need because as I mentioned at the beginning of this module, with the latitude
and longitude, we can perfectly describe any location on the world.
So let's now take this method here and connect it to this button here, to the current location button by
pointing at it,
so don't execute it here, just point at the method.
Save this
and now let's go back here and click current location, this button and I'm asked here whether I want
to grant access and I do so I click allow here and in your debug log, you should see these coordinates.
Now side note, that is not where I sit, on the Android emulator, you by default get the location of the Google
headquarters in Silicon Valley, so or of the Googleplex there.
So these are the two location pieces
and now of course, we can use that to display that location on a map with the help of that map image
which I mentioned could be generated by Google.
So that's the next step,
turn that pair of coordinates here into a map preview.