So we added one provider, our product provider, which we use in the products grid.
In the end we use it there because we're setting up a subscription and that subscription or that listener
here with Provider Off Works because we're providing our products object which manages our list of products
here with changed notifier provider.
Now I want to make sure that we can mark products as favorites.
Now, if we have a look at the product model, which is not yet usable by our provider because we're
not implementing with Change Notifier, which, which means we couldn't trigger our listeners from inside
it.
This model has the favorite boolean here and it's also not a final boolean, so we could change that.
Now.
I think it would be pretty neat if the products we had here in our providers package which do use this
product model, could use that product model such that if we change the favorite status of a product,
we automatically notify all places in the app that require a single product and are interested.
You always have to specify that you are interested with the help of provider of so that the widgets
that depend on a single product and are interested are rebuilt whenever that single product changes,
which in our case here means whenever there is favorite status changes because that's the only thing
which can change.
Now.
Therefore, I'll move product here over into providers.
Alternatively, we could now both rename two models if we want to choose.
So rename that folder to models, but I'll simply move the product art file over into providers and
add width change notifier here as well, which is available.
Also thanks to the foundation for import.
So you can use either the foundation art import or the material art import.
Now here in the products DART file, I'm referring to that product.
So through that single product dart file and it's now in the same folder.
So the import path should change to dot slash product dart.
With that, I'm still trading products here, but these products now actually can notify listeners when
they changed.
Now, what would be a place where I'm interested in a changing product?
Now, you might think that would be the product detail page, but that's actually not the case.
There I load a single product based on the ID, which I got, and thereafter I don't really care whether
that changes or not.
I'm not displaying the favorite status on this screen, and I also can't change it from on this screen.
Well, right now it is the screen is pretty empty, to be honest.
Will add more, but will not add anything that would allow us to change the favorite status on the screen.
So the product details screen here is not really a place where I want to reactively listen to changes
in a single product.
The product item, DART file is a different file.
They are the product item widget, which is that Great Tile we're creating there.
I do have this button which represents the the favorite status of a product here and I actually want
to switch that I can based on whether this product already is a favorite or not.
So therefore here of course, I need product data and I need specific data about whether this product
now is a favorite or not.
So I'm interested in hearing about changes in that product.
What does this mean for us?
It means that here I want to set up a listener to a single product.
And that's not important to a single product, not to all products, but to my single product.
Here in that product class, we also need a way of manipulating this Boolean here in a way that also
allows us to call, notify listeners.
And of course, what else is missing?
We have a listener, we have a class.
We need to set up a provider.
What we're doing in main part here for products.
We also need to do that for all our single products.
Now let's start by setting up a provider in the products grid widget.
I'm listening to all my products and then for every product we have, we're creating a product item
here in the end tile in our grid.
So in the end, it's here where I need to provide my product object based on the product class.
Now, in the main dart file, we're doing that here right at the top so that the entire app can in the
end listen to changes in products because we need products in different places.
Now, my single product here is actually really only needed in every product item list style.
So therefore here, where I get all my products, I want to set up a new provider here above my product
item so that inside of the product item we can then listen to changes in that product.
And since this runs, this builder here runs for every product in our products list.
That's perfect because then we can set up different providers for our different product objects.
Because for products, we really only have one object for the entire app defined here in main dart for
a single product.
So for the individual product items, that's a bit different.
We have multiple products there, multiple product items, so we can't set up a single provider.
We need multiple providers one for each product.
Now we're not setting up the provider here inside of the products class because that won't really work.
Instead, we have to do that in our which a tree.
But that's no problem because here we have access to all our products, to the product items stored
in the product class.
And therefore here we can set up a new change notifier provider just as we did in the main dart file.
This is what I'm now returning in my item builder.
This takes a child and the child still is the product item here in the end, so we can still keep that
code.
But now I also want to set up a builder where I build my product object.
Now, the thing, of course, here is I already have my product objects right there built here.
Here I instantiate my product objects.
I do this inside of the product class.
So I don't want to re instantiate product objects now.
I don't want to build a new product object.
But that's no problem in our builder here, where I get a new context passed in automatically, where
I simply have to return the value which I want to provide.
I can simply return.
Products.
I.
This will return a single product item as it's stored in the product class, and it will do this multiple
times because it's inside of the item builder for all the products they have.
Now, since I'm providing a single product here, that also means we could, but we don't have to receive
our product data as arguments here in product item.
Instead here, I'm not passing anything because instead of product item, we could now get rid of all
of that and it wouldn't have been a problem to receive this before.
But now, since I'm interested in some dynamic value in a single product, it makes sense to use a provider
here.
So now in here.
I can again use provider off.
And for that of course you need to import the provider package here in the product item DARD File.
So provider off and now off product because I'm interested in a single product.
So let's import that provider now from the providers folder there from the product dart file, not products
but product.
And it will now look for the nearest product which is provided, which simply happens here in the product
script where I'm providing a product for this product item and a new product, a different product is
provided for every different product item which is rendered.
So for every grid tile because we're repeating this code for all the products.
So this reruns for all the products we have and hence we provide a brand new product for every product
item, which of course is exactly what we want.
We want to provide the correct product item or the correct product element for every product item widget.
Now, there is actually one little problem you should be aware of when working with nested providers
as we're doing it here, when you're using it in a list or in a grid, as we're doing it here where
Flutter removes items when they leave the screen and reads them when they re-enter the screen.
In such situations, what actually happens is that the widget itself is reused by flutter and just the
data that's attached to it changes.
So Flutter recycles the same widget.
It doesn't destroy it and recreate it, which would work fine with our nested provider, but it recycles
it, which means that we are actually attaching a provider to a widget here which content changes over
time and our provider won't pick this up.
Therefore, the more items you have in your list, as soon as you have items that are not visible all
the time, you will run into strange errors and bugs.
But we'll fix this in the next lecture.
This is a good first step and this is an approach you can always use if you're not using a list or a
grid.
So in product item, I can now listen to that.
Past in my context, of course, which is this important communication channel and in here.
I get my product or whatever you want to name it.
So I have my product variable here.
Which won't change in this build run here.
Hence it's final.
And then I can use product ID here to forward that.
I can use product image URL here and I can use product title down there.
If we save that.
You see, this still renders as before, but now we're actually using a different pattern.
The question, of course, is why are we using that pattern?
Because I now, of course, want to make sure that when we tap that favorite button, we switch to favorite
status of a single product for that.
In our product provider file up there in the providers folder, let's add a new method which doesn't
return anything, which I'll name toggle favorite.
Status.
You can name this whatever you want.
The idea here is simply is that we invert the value of is favorite.
So if it's currently true, I want to set it to false.
If it's set to false, I want to set it to true.
So here I'll set is favorite equal to not is favorite and the exclamation mark here simply inverts the
value.
So if it is true, then this here will return false and therefore it a new value will be false.
If it was false, then this year will return true and the new value true.
Now again, to let all listeners know, we need to call notify listeners.
So you could kind of say that's like set state in the provider package.
You let listening widgets know that something changed and they should rebuild.
It's the equivalent to set state and stateful which which we now don't really need here when we're managing
something with the provider package.
Though you don't have to manage everything with the provider package, but I'll come back to this later.
So we're notifying our listeners that this model changed, that we changed something in this object.
We change the favorite status.
We can now use that favorite status in the product item for one here when we press this button, of
course I want to use my product.
Which I'm getting here with my listener.
And call toggle favorite status because that's one thing that should always happen.
And I wanted to reflect the current favorite status here with the icon so we can simply check product
is favorite.
And if it is true, then I want to show that favorite icon which is that filled out hard and otherwise
I'll show favorite border, which is that hard where we got no filling.
If we now save this or maybe do a full refresh here to make sure that this really gets used, you now
see we have empty hearts everywhere, but if I tap it, it gets filled out and I can then also toggle
it off.
And that's correctly reflected on my different items.
And this happens and this works thanks to the provider pattern where we are informed about changes here
in product.
When we tap a heart, by the way, that's a nice use case or a nice place to show.
What happens if I said listen?
Two falls here.
Now, for every product item that gets rendered in our grid, we only fetch the product data.
But then we don't set up an ongoing listener.
That means that when is favorite changes here?
It will still change behind the scenes.
But notify listeners will not reach this build method in this widget because we opted out of updates.
We're not listening.
So this product here will not receive this updated is favorite status.
Therefore a build will not rerun and therefore will not see the new icon.
So if we now do a full hot refresh here.
You see, I can tap these icons as long as I want.
Nothing changes there because we're not listening to updates.
Of course, here, that's not what we want.
So I'll remove that.
But it's important to understand what listen false does.
So now with this changed, you see now this updates again.