So now that you know what's inside of the course,
let's dive into how you can get the most out of it.
So of course, you should watch the videos,
it's a video on-demand
course after all.
Watch them at your speed,
pause and rewind if I'm going too fast.
I try to find the right balance for everyone but if you feel like I'm too fast, slow me down or pause
and go back to the start of the video again because you should also code along and do the exercises
and sometimes, that means that you have to pause the video so that you can code along,
that's okay.
Some students don't code along, which is why I don't have super long pauses in my video since I want
to create a good course for these students as well but my recommendation really would be that you do
code along
because that's how you learn the most. And also, do the quizzes you'll find in the course,
some exercises I have in there.
Do all of that, build your apps, build your own versions of my apps because that's how you ultimately
learn the most.
Use all the course resources you find attached,
that's my source code which you can compare to yours if you're facing any errors
and also of course, check out the different slides and cheat sheets I attach to various lectures in the
course since that can be really helpful
or it can be really helpful resources if you are coming back to this course after a while or if you
are working on your own projects.
Now if you're getting stuck and you did compare my code to yours, which you should always do first,
you can of course also ask in the Q & A section.
I'm trying my best to help you there but I really can only help on questions that are directly related
to the course and to the course code
and I urge you to compare your code to mine first before you ask because most errors can simply be fixed
by comparing code and you'll learn much more if you can find and fix an error on your own
than when I tell you and you maybe don't fully understand what was wrong. And besides asking in the Q
& A section, also help others because you learn the most if you dig into problems, be that your own
problems or the problems of others and you solve them and you have to write down an answer and you have
to think about the problem
and if your answer is correct. Of course, you might answer in a wrong way but that's not a problem, you'll
get corrected and you'll learn again
but if you try solving problems, be that your own ones or the problems of other students, you will learn
so much more because you really have to think about a problem and find a solution
and that is what makes you a great developer in the end. So definitely take this opportunity to get the
most out of this course.