To have a text
and below that text a couple of buttons,
we now need an invisible, a layout widget.
And there we can use the Column widget.
Column, as the name suggests,
is there to render widgets in a column
because difference to text and so on
is that this has a children named argument,
which actually takes a list of widgets.
Now, there are a couple of new things.
This thing here between the angled brackets, that's new.
And the square brackets here are also new.
What does this all mean?
Let's start with the square brackets.
Dart, like many other programming languages,
has the concept of lists.
Thus far, we learned about strings,
about integers, doubles and objects
and everything is an object in the end.
Now, lists are another type of data.
A list is basically a group of data.
So you can have a list of strings.
For example, here we could add a variable, questions,
and that could now be a list of text,
a list of text questions,
like what is your favorite color?
By the way, if you would want to write what's here,
and you use single quotes to enclose the string,
then this single quote would quit the string,
which is an error,
and you can escape this by adding a backwards slash
in front of this.
Now what happens is that this single quote here
is not treated as a quote that ends the string
but instead as the quote character
that should be part of the string.
So that backward slash in front of it achieves that.
So now we would have a question what's your favorite color?
And also, what's
your favorite animal, for example.
Let's also add a trialing comma here.
And now questions actually would be a list of string data.
Now, the idea behind lists
is simply that we can group related data together
because in so many scenarios of programming
but also in real-life actually,
you work with lists of data.
You have on your phone, on your real phone,
if we take a real-life example,
you have a list of contacts.
Your friends, that's a list of persons, a list of people.
And therefore, lists are also something
that exist in programming
and basically in any programming language,
you can find and of course, also in Dart therefore.
Lists are created with square brackets.
What's also what I did up here.
I created it with square brackets
and therefore, lists are also created down there
where we have a list of widgets
and that's the angle bracket widget thing.
This is a so-called generic type
and so a little annotation,
which we could also drop here
because of type inference,
this tells Dart that this list here
will hold a list of widgets
because a list can, of course, hold anything.
This, for example, is a list of strings.
If I hover over questions,
we see that Dart was able
to automatically infer this.
List, and then again, this angle bracket thing
but here with string.
A generic type is basically an annotation,
which you can have on some types
that allow Dart to understand that this is not just a list
but a list of a specific data type here, for example.
It's the same thing down there.
This is a list of widgets.
Now, because of type inference,
we can remove that as soon as we start adding widgets here.
And there, I would want to have my text widget
with the question,
and I'll add some real text soon,
and below that, a couple of buttons.
Now, there are different kinds of buttons in Flutter.
One of them is the RaisedButton,
which is a button with a background color
and a little hover effect.
Now, depending on the Flutter version you're using,
the RaisedButton might have this strike through effect here
as it does here for me in this example.
The reason for this is that the RaisedButton
has been deprecated with Flutter version two.
Now, that sounds big, but it doesn't mean that much.
You can still use RaisedButton.
It's not insecure, not bad to use it.
You can stick to it
and to follow along smoothly with this course,
I do recommended that you stick to RaisedButton.
Alternatively, you could switch to ElevatedButton,
which in the end is the alternative to RaisedButton,
the replacement for RaisedButton.
And for the moment, for the next minutes,
you would use ElevatedButton
just as I use RaisedButton here.
So you add the same arguments
to the constructor then.
Nonetheless, as mentioned,
I would recommend that you stick
to RaisedButton for now for the moment
to follow along smoothly.
I will migrate to the newer buttons
in future Flutter upgrades
but since you will find a lot of projects out there,
which use these deprecated buttons
and since these deprecated buttons
will stay around for quite a long time,
I do recommend that you follow along with them for now.
However, attached, you also find a link
with more information about the new buttons
replacing those old buttons,
why they exist and what they do.
But here, I will stick to RaisedButton for now.
If you wanna get rid of that strike through effect,
you can do that in your settings here
in the Visual Studio Code settings.
There if you search for deprecated,
you can disable this Show Deprecated setting here
and if it is disabled,
you will not have this strike through effect here anymore.
Now, the RaisedButton here is again a widget,
which we create by instantiating our class here
and it typically has a child,
which is basically the content inside of the button
that could be an image, that could be an icon
but often it's also just some text.
So the text which is displayed on the button.
Again, this is a widget, not just some string.
The child here is a widget instead
and therefore, here we could have Answer 1.
And then I can copy that line and add it again
so that we also have Answer 2
and maybe also Answer 3.
Now, each button, besides having a child
also needs an onPressed argument
and onPressed will be a function that should be executed
when this button is well, pressed.
For the moment, since we haven't really learned
how to wire that up,
let's add null here.
Null is a special value in Dart.
It basically means nothing.
The difference to void is that void is a type.
So here we say the type of data main returns
is empty, it's nothing.
And null is not a type but a concrete value,
just like one is a value, the number one,
or like this here is a value, null is a value,
which says nothing.
But we need to add that to avoid errors.
So here I add onPressed to all my buttons
and for all buttons, I then add null.
And with that again, I hit my code formatting shortcut
so that this gets formatted in a bit of a nicer way.
And again, if we add trailing commas, like here,
after null in my first button,
then this gets formatted in a bit
of a more readable way.
So now I added my Column widget,
which has a couple of child widgets
where we have the Text widget and then the RaisedButton.
And if we save that,
now we see our text up here
and then we see the three buttons
and they are currently all disabled
because onPressed is null
and that means if we press this button right now,
nothing happens and Flutter automatically detects this
and then disables the button,
which sometimes can be nice
if you have a user input form
where you gather the email address
and the password of the user.
Then you would want to disable the button
as long as nothing valid has been entered.
Here, however, of course, I want to enable them.
And for that, we have to understand
how we wire up the button here
to some function that does something
or how we make sure that something happens
when the button is tapped.
Of course, we can also improve the styling
and how this is laid out here on the screen
but we'll do this in a second step.
For now, it was important to understand
how we can have more than one widget next to each other
with the help of Column for ordering widgets
from top to bottom.
If you would want to say have them sit next
to each other left to right,
you would have used Row instead
but we'll see Column and Row
and all these other invisible
and visible widgets throughout the course.