So back to navigation,
we now need a new screen.
We need the screen that shows the details about a single recipe.
So in the screens folder, we can add a new file and that could be the meal_detail_screen.dart
file.
The meal_detail_screen.dart file will unsurprisingly display the details about a single meal
and just as before, I'll create a stateless widget in here which I'll name meal detail screen
and as always, you know the game, we import material.dart from the Flutter package
and just to see something on the screen,
I'll again use a center text here where I say the meal, just to see whether we can navigate to that.
So the MealDetailScreen should now be loaded when we tap on a meal item.
So here in the select meal method, I want to go to that other screen and you learned that for going there,
we can use navigator of context and then push our new screen on top of the stack.
Now it's up to you whether you want to use a named route and register it in the main.dart file or if
you want to use a route that you create here on the fly,
I will go for a named route, so I will use pushNamed here
but of course for that, we need to give this route a path and I'll do this here with a static const property.
I explained this earlier in the module,
this is an approach that makes sure that we don't accidentally mistype our route identifier in one part
of our application and I'll give this a name of, what did I choose here,
routeName, so I'll use routeName as a name for this constant here too, just to be consistent regarding
that naming and then you can use any identifier you want, should be a string and I'll use meal-detail
here as an identifier, /meal-detail. Let's now register this in main.dart by referring to the meal
detail screen here and there to the routeName, for MealDetailScreen, for this class to be available
here,
you also need to import it and my IDE added the import but not in the format I want to have it in,
so I'll use the relative import here pointing at the screens folder and the meal_detail_screen.dart
file and now here, I use the routeName as a key in this map of routes and the value is this builder which
gets the context and which should build the MealDetailScreen, like this. So with the meal detail
screen registered as a route here, in meal item, we should be able to go there. Now first of all, we need
the context here, so select meal should actually receive our build context.
So when we register it here for onTap, we should actually use an anonymous function so that we can pass
context as an argument to select meal
and then here for pushNamed, we need to refer to the routeName,
so here we use the meal detail screen class and for that, you need to import it into this
meal_item.dart file too, again with the right
import going to the screens folder and then the meal_detail_screen.dart file and with that import added,
here I am pushing to MealDetailScreen.routeName because that's the identifier of this route.
Of course, it would also be good to pass some data along, data about which meal was selected, so that we
know which meal to display on the MealDetailScreen
and for that, you learned that you can set the arguments key or argument parameter here on pushNamed
and the argument here can be anything, can be a map, can be a string.
Here I think it's enough if we forward the ID of the selected meal because we can then fetch all the
data for that meal on the MealDetailScreen.
So we should expect to get these ID here in meal item,
so ID is another property I want to get,
I also add it as a required property in the constructor therefore and now in the place where we use meal
item, which is of course in the CategoryMealsScreen widget, we also have to provide the ID by accessing
category meals for the given index and then ID and setting this as a value for the ID argument.
Now the ID is available in the meal item and therefore now, we can use it as an argument here
and simply forward that with pushNamed. Inside of the meal detail screen,
we can then get this argument just as you learned it before, here in the build method, there you can
get your arguments or your meal ID because this is the only argument we get here with modal route
of context,
so connecting this to the context, settings arguments and again, this gives you the arguments object which
is attached to the incoming route, to the incoming navigation and in our case since we set it here, that's
only the ID,
so that's only this string here. Hence in the MealDetailScreen, we can tell Dart that this will be
a string in the end
with the help of as string and then maybe, also output this down there with string interpolation so
we can see that this differs from meal to meal which we select. Let's give it a try,
let's click on the classic hamburger now and we load that, we display this
but what is missing on this screen, why do we have the output we have here? Because we are missing a scaffold.
You learned that every widget which you use as a standalone page, which occupies the entire content
of the page, so which you don't include just into other widgets, every standalone widget which you load
through routing, which you navigate to with the navigator needs a scaffold widget because that adds the background,
the appBar and also in general, connects the widget to our material app and to the theme set up there,
to the fonts and so on.
So we should return scaffold here and our body will be this centered item and besides the body, of course
I want to have an appBar where we can set a title and for now, the title will just be the meal ID,
we can later of course, should be a text widget though, we can later of course use the meal title there
instead of the ID which is not that great for us humans.
Now if we go back, that looks way better and if I select the salad, it has a different ID than the hamburgers,
so passing the data also seems to work. And now we have a really nice navigation across multiple layers
where we can go forth multiple times and back multiple times and where we're passing data around. The next
step of course is to display more information about a selected meal. Before we do that however, let's
have a look at another feature Flutter offers you when it comes to loading pages.