So with this quick look at onGenerateRoute and onUnknownRoute which can be useful depending
on which app you're building,
let's go back to this app we're building here and
let's make sure that for a selected meal, we show more details.
This of course again has no direct connection to navigation but practicing to combine widgets with each
other and build nice user interfaces certainly also isn't too bad I guess.
So let's go to the MealDetailScreen and now work on that. In there, instead of the centered widget,
I want to have a column because we'll have a couple of pieces of information or a couple of different elements
on top of each other. At the very top
for example, I want to display the image of the recipe,
then I also want to show the ingredients and then the steps it takes to build this or to make this
dish. Hence at the very top, I'll first of all add a container which should hold the image, where I'll give
this a height of 300 and a width of double infinity to be as broad as possible, to basically
span the full width of the device screen and the child of that container will be the image.
So here, we can use Image.network
and now we need to find out which meal the user selected.
Keep in mind that we do extract the meal ID here,
we can of course now use the meal ID to find the full meal here in our dummy data source.
So in the MealDetailScreen, we can now import from that dummy_data.dart file
so that we have access to the dummy meals
and now we can get the selected meal here by having a look at all our meals, all our dummy meals stored
in this dummy meals constant
and before we used where to filter a couple of fitting elements,
now we want to have only one fitting element
and for that, we can use first where. This gives us one meal for which the condition in this function
returns true.
So again, this runs on every meal in the list
and when this function, this anonymous function returns true, it stops looking for more and gives us that
item, that meal.
And of course the condition I want to check here, here with this shortcut syntax where I use the arrow
function, where I don't need curly braces here and the value of my expression here is immediately
returned,
I will compare meal ID to my meal ID up here.
So meal.id, the ID for the meal we're looking at in dummy meals, compared to meal ID, this variable
name here, which is the meal ID we got from our route arguments. Again as I mentioned, this expression
here, the value of that,
so true or false is immediately returned thanks to this shortcut here with the arrow function and therefore
we return true if the IDs match
and then we found our meal.
So selected meal is the meal which the user picked and therefore for the image down there, we can use
selectedMeal.imageUrl down there.
Now on the image, I'll also set a fit to again fit it nicely into the surrounding container with
BoxFit.cover,
of course you can also play around with different values here to see how the image is sized and cropped
and squeezed differently based on the setting you choose here.
With that if you save it, you should see the image here already.
Now by the way since we now have the selected meal, we can also show the title of the recipe here in the
appBar,
so instead of saying meal ID like this, let's add curly braces and use selectedMeal.title, the
curly braces are required because we don't just refer to a single variable but we have a little
bit more complex expression, we use a dot notation here and that only works with curly braces around it
after the dollar sign.
So now we're outputting the title and the image of the meal, of course
that's by no means all. Besides the title and the image,
I also want to show the ingredients of a meal.
So after this container with the image, I'll add another container and that container should hold
some text where I simply say ingredients, basically as a caption for this or as a title for the next
list which is a list of the available ingredients.
Now that text should have a certain style and that's a style we can probably set up globally in our
theme. If
we have a look at the theme,
we have a title style already
and actually that is the style I want to use.
So we can use that theme title style by referring to the theme here with of context and then text
theme title, just like that. This will style this text nicely, if we save this, we see ingredients here.
Now it would be nice to have some margin between the image and the text,
so therefore here on the container, I'll add margin and set this to
EdgeInsets.symmetric and only target the vertical margin, so top and bottom
and set this to 10 maybe.
Now we have some spacing between the title and the image and this looks better in my opinion. Below that
container which really is just there so that we have a text, just a title for the upcoming list,
so below that container here, I want to have a list of the various steps you have to execute.
Now if I would add a ListView like this here,
we would run into a problem because adding a ListView which by default has an infinite height in
a column which also tries to get as much height as possible would throw an error.
So instead we have to use a container here which has a fixed height and then add a ListView as a child
of that container.
The fixed height here is of course totally up to you,
I'll use a height of let's say 200 here and maybe also only a width of 300 here and you could use a media
query to adjust this to different device sizes,
I'll not do it here,
also to save some time
because that's not the main focus of this app
but of course you can refine these values by using a media query as you learned it in the responsive
and adaptive apps module in this course.
Here, I'll just use 300 and if that doesn't really work on small, very small devices, it's okay for me
here,
obviously you can fine tune it with media query.
So we have a height and a width, let's now add the ListView as the child here and that ListView can
be created with a builder or with this constructor in children,
ultimately it's totally up to you.
Theoretically we don't know how many ingredients we have and it could be very many,
so I will use builder which gives us better performance for very long lists. Here for builder as you
learned it,
you need the item count and the item count of course is selectedMeal.ingredient.length
because we want output all the ingredients here. Besides the item count, we also need the item builder
of course and that gets the context created dynamically here for every list item and then also the index
of that list item
and we should return a widget here and that widget for me will be a card which I'll give a background
color of our accent color
and that's just the style I want to use,
as always you can fine tune this to your requirements and play around with different values.
And the child and the card will be a text
let's say and that text of course should, for the ingredient with that index, output the name of that
ingredient
and since ingredients for us is just a list of strings, the ingredient for a specific index is already
the name of that ingredient. Let's save that and this doesn't look too bad,
looks nice but the problem I have with that is that if this would be smaller, let's say it has a height
of 100, it would be not that obvious that you can scroll it, right?
So the overall box here, the container which holds the ListView should probably have some decoration
that clearly shows its boundaries and makes it more likely for the user to guess that you can scroll.
So there, I'll add a BoxDecoration and give this a color of white,
so a white background color and a border with border.all in all directions which should be grey
with colors grey.
So this adds a border around the container with the border argument and the BoxDecoration object we
pass to the decoration argument of the container and maybe also give that box rounded corners with
border radius and then BorderRadius.circular 10. Now let's also add some margin here with EdgeInsets.all
of 10 around the entire container and also some padding of EdgeInsets.all of 10, that should
be insets.
And now every item here,
so every card in the ListView builder also should have a little bit of padding inside of it I'd say.
So let's wrap the text which is the content of the card in another widget and here we can just use
the padding widget because I only want to add some padding and the padding here can be EdgeInsets.symmetric
to have different padding for left and right and top and bottom of let's say vertical 5
and horizontal 10 and
now we have some padding around the text inside of the ingredient as well.
If we save that and we go back, this now looks better and I think it's way clearer that you can scroll
this and I'll now increase the height to 150, that looks like a good solution.
So now these are my ingredients here,
the next part which I want to output of course are the steps you need to follow to make this dish with
these ingredients here.
For that, I will repeat this title here
and since I will repeat it, we could move that into a separate widget or at least move it into a builder
method
and that's what I will do.
I'll add a new method here to the MealDetailScreen widget which I'll name buildSectionTitle,
the name is up to you
and I expect to get the text, you can name it title, text, whatever you want, as an input, as an argument and
I return this container, which in the end outputs this text here which will now be dynamic and which
also needs the context,
so let's also accept BuildContext context here and now we can call buildSectionTitle down there and
pass in the context and the title which here was ingredients and do the very same below our container
there and do the same for steps because then I also want to output the steps and now we avoided code
duplication and have also a leaner widget tree down there,
thanks to that avoided code duplication.
Now another piece which I want to replicate is this container with the ListView, the ListView itself
will then work differently, there
I will use different list items for the steps but that surrounding container should be the same.
So we can also move that into a builder method and again creating a separate widget, maybe one which
you store in the same file if you only use it here would also be fine
but I will add a builder method again, name this build container
and in there, create my container with a certain child. That child is some input I expect to get,
so that should be of type widget and that's what I pass on to the container here and then I can return
it
and now the child is something we can pass in dynamically, so that we can now use the build container
method down there to build this container
and pass child here as an argument, not a named argument though but just like this
and of course you could turn it into a named argument as well.
And now we have build container,
we can now also use build container down there
and now my child which I want to pass down there will also still be a ListView,
also still be a ListView with the builder method but with a different list item in there,
so it's not a perfect copy. Just as before,
builder method takes an item count
and now we're talking about the steps it takes to create that meal.
So for the selected meal, I now will have the steps length that defined the count for this ListView builder
because I want to output all the steps here and therefore the item builder as before receives the context
and the index
and again we can use the arrow function shortcut here, we return the widget we want to build for every
list item. And here I'll use ListTile, not card but ListTile
and in that ListTile, I'll set leading to a CircleAvatar and
we saw that before if you remember in our personal expenses app and CircleAvatar will have a child
and that should be text which is the number of this step and we can derive that number based on the index because
the index starts at zero and then counts up all the way to the length of the steps -1 because
it starts at zero.
So here, we can output maybe # and then string interpolation, use index plus 1 because it starts at
zero
but we want to start at step one of course, to us humans
step one makes more sense than step zero and output that here.
So now, we output the number of the steps in a CircleAvatar
at the beginning of our ListTile. The title then is the step text,
so here we have a text widget which can be selectedMeal.steps for the given index. And steps
again is just a list of strings,
so this already is the text I want to output.
And with that if we save this and reload and we go to Italian, click on that, I'm getting an error which
has a cryptic error message unfortunately but which in the end is related to me not returning my container
here in build container. Of course we have to return it here,
even state it here, otherwise build container here will not render or not return a widget that
can be rendered.
So now this works and now we have a different problem though, we go beyond the boundaries of our device
and you learned what we can do about that earlier.
We can wrap our column which we have here in the end into a SingleChildScrollView. So can wrap this
with a new widget and that's the SingleChildScrollView which ensures that this column now is scrollable
and that's already it.
Now we have that and down there, we have our steps which are pretty nice to read and hopefully pretty
clear. Now as a tiny tweak,
I also want to add a divider between these steps and that can be acheived down there where we
create these list tiles by not returning just a ListTile but actually a column because I want I have two
items on top of each other, where the ListTile is the topmost item but then besides the ListTile or below
the ListTile,
I use the divider widget which is also built into Flutter, should be here
however and the divider widget will simply draw a horizontal line. So divider is provided by the Flutter
framework and it's added below the ListTile, it's this tiny grey horizontal line you see here.
So with that, I'd say this doesn't look too bad, it is a nice detail page.
Of course you can tweak this to your likings, change the look if you want a different look,
I think for this app, this is more than fine but now with that, I of course
also want to go back to more navigation features because whilst we can go forth and back which is
nice,
what we haven't really learned is how we can also use tabs or a side drawer for example
and that's what we'll focus on next.