Auto login is an important feature and for auto login to work, we now need to store some data on
the device and not just in variables because that just means we store it in memory and memory is the
thing we lose or this memory is the thing we lose if the app gets closed.
So storing that data in memory doesn't help us, if the user closes the app after logging in, the data
will be lost,
so we need to persist the information that the user has a token on the device so that we can check the
device storage when the app launches, then see if that token we might have found there is still valid
and then maybe automatically treat the user as logged in. Now to store something on the device, we can
use a special plugin, the shared preferences plugin. You can find it if you google for Flutter's shared
preferences or on pub.dev, you can simply search for shared preferences up there and you will find
that shared preferences package. As always, check the installing tab here for information, it's straightforward
you copy that entry, go to your pubspec.yaml file and add it here below your other dependencies,
save that and Flutter should automatically fetch that, if it doesn't fetch it automatically, as always
you can open up your terminal in your project folder and run Flutter packages get and this will also install
all packages.
So with that, shared preferences are installed and shared preferences allows you to tap into a simple key
value store on your device which is perfect for storing information like that. If you need an on device
database like SQLite,
there are dedicated packages for that too but for this information and for a lot of configuration information
like this is in the end, shared preferences is perfect,
it's available on both Android and iOS.
So now we can use that and the first step is that we store data in shared preferences when the user
is logged in. So in auth.dart in the providers folder here when we treat the user as logged in,
after doing the auto logout and all of that or after setting this up I should say, I want to store
my login data on the device in the shared preferences and for that first of all, let's import that shared
preferences package here, package/shared_preferences and there, the shared_preferences.dart file. With
that import added here at the top of the file,
let's go back to the _authenticate method and in here,
after notifying listeners, we can now start setting up our shared preferences.
Now actually, this is some async code and
therefore you should make sure you're using async await which we are already doing because working with
shared preferences also involves working with futures.
The first step is to get access to the shared preferences and I'll store that access
so to say in a constant named prefs, name is obviously up to you.
We get access by calling shared preferences,
this is now available things to the import
we just added, .getInstance.
Now this here actually returns a future which eventually will return a shared preferences instance
and that is then basically your tunnel to that on device storage.
So we should await that so that we don't store the future in here
but the real access to shared preferences and now we can use prefs to write and read data to and from
the shared preferences device storage. We write data with set methods and we can write booleans, doubles,
ints or strings as we want to do it here
and if you had more complex data by the way, you can always use json.encode and encode a map into JSON
because JSON is always a string.
JSON is a data format which in the end is wrapped by double quotes
so to say, so JSON data is a string,
so if you had a map you want to store, you can convert it to a string with json.encode
and that's exactly what I'll do here.
So here, I have my user data and I'll create that with json.encode, have a map here
and now the data I want to store is my token,
so the token key and here, I'll point at _token, the userId and here I'll point at
_userId
and very important, the expiry date of course.
So the expiry date
and here I'll use _expiryDate.toISO8601String to have that standardized date format.
Now we can store user data here and give that a key by which we can retrieve it and that key is totally
up to you, should be a string and I'll just
name it user data
but again, that name is totally up to you.
So here, I now store my serialized, my converted data here,
this map which is converted to JSON which is a string as I just said, I store that string here in my
preferences and there, we can later retrieve it. Now to retrieve it,
we need a new method and I'll add that method
maybe here, doesn't matter. It will return a future and actually that is not a future which will in the
end return nothing
but here I want to have a future which returns a boolean because this method will be the
tryAutoLogin method.
The name is up to you,
it will be an async method and it will return a boolean because it should signal whether we were successful
when we try to automatically log the user in,
so we are successful if we find a token and that token is still valid or if we were not successful because
we'll need that information later to render different content on the screen based on whether we were
successful or not.
So here, tryAutoLogin should now of course access the shared preferences,
so let's again get access to shared preferences here with getInstance and await that and store that
in prefs
and now in prefs, I want to extract that user data on the user data key here. So let's first of all
check if prefs contains a key, user data,
if it does not contain that, hence the exclamation mark at the beginning, then we know there is no data
stored on the user data key so we certainly won't have a valid token and then we can return false
and this return false value will automatically be wrapped in a future because of the async keyword and
we want a future that returns a boolean, right?
So here we return a future in the end which yields false
once it's done.
If we do have that user data key, we know that we can at least get a token
and so on from there.
It might still be an invalid token which already expired
in the meantime but we can get some data.
So here, we can get our extracted user data by simply using prefs
and there we can use the get string method and get the user data string, so user data
here because I used user data as a key up there,
if you used a different key up there, you need to use different keys down there of course.
Now please remember that this of course is a string,
I want to convert it to a map, so I can use json.decode here and I know that this will then be a map
with string keys and object values, mixed values,
we will have a datetime in there, we'll have a string in there, different kinds of values. So that's the
extracted user data, now from that extracted user data, we can get the expiry date because we want to
check that date and see whether it still is valid,
so whether that date still is in the future because if the expiry date is in the past, then we know
that the token has expired.
So let's create our expiry date here
by using datetime.parse which thankfully works because I stored the date as an ISO8601String
in there,
so here I get my extracted user data for the expiry date key which I used up there,
so let's use that down there too, that is that string that is parsed into a datetime object now
and now we can simply check if expiry date is after datetime.now.
If it's after, the token is valid, if it's not, the token is invalid.
So if we check the opposite here, isBefore, we know the token is not valid and we can return false here,
we don't need to continue, we return false and therefore our future is done and returns false because
then we know we're done,
we don't need to continue, we certainly have no valid token because the expiry date is in the past.
If we make it past this if check,
we do have a valid token because the expiry date now is in the future and this is now when we want to
reinitialize all our properties up there - token, userId and so on and also set auto logout again
because now we basically want to do the same
we did in authenticate when we logged the user in for the first time because now we know we have valid
data and we therefore want to auto login the user.
So here, I'll set token equal to extracted user data and then token because I used the token here,
userId has the userId key, so let's use that for setting userId, extracted user data userId.
Let's also set the expiry date again of course, that is the expiry date
I stored up there and let's then of course also notify all listeners, also call auto logout to set
that timer again and important, return true because we need to have a future which returns a boolean
in the end so we return false
whenever we fail but here when we succeed, we of course should return true.
Now that was a lot of work on that
auto login function, where do we use that function now?
We can use that function in the main.dart file because that is in the end where our app starts. In there,
here where I have that consumer, where I render my MaterialApp, we render a home screen and the home
screen right now depends on the question whether we're authenticated or not.
Now actually here, if we're not authenticated, I don't automatically want to show the AuthScreen,
I instead want to try logging in and we can do that with the good old future builder here.
Let's use a future builder here in the else case
if we're not logged in and the future I want to use here is taken from my auth object.
So here from auth, I'll try tryAutoLogin, that returns a future right and that future will in the end
yield
true or false. The builder of my future builder here gets a context, gets the authResultSnapshot
so to say and then should return maybe the AuthScreen but that will depend.
So now we can check the authResultSnapshot here and check the connection state
and if that is equal to ConnectionState.waiting, then I want to show a different screen and I want to
show the AuthScreen only for not waiting.
Now you might wonder and what do I do with the result whether we were successful or not?
Well there we have two options.
We can check the data the authResultSnapshot will give us in case we're not waiting anymore
to add yet another nested if condition here and then either show the AuthScreen if the result we're
getting,
so here in authResultSnapshot data, if that is equal to false, in that case we would return the AuthScreen
otherwise we could return our products overview screen.
This is something you could do here but this would be a bit redundant because please note that automatically
will rebuild when auth changes and it does change because in auth.dart, we call notify listeners after
auto logging the user in.
So this will automatically rebuild and we'll go to this check and then we will be authenticated,
so then we will render the products overview screen anyways.
So now I just want to present some waiting screen as an alternative to the AuthScreen for the short
period where we're not yet decided whether we're logged in or not because it's not the best user experience
if we show the AuthScreen where the user might start entering data and then suddenly we see oh the
user is logged in and we present a totally different screen. For that attached, you find another widget
and that's the splash_screen.dart file which you can move into your screens folder.
It's a very simple widget,
it simply shows a centered loading text.
Of course there, you could show your logo, some image, whatever you want but I just showed a text
and that's the widget I want to render instead.
So here, I'll render my splash screen widget and for that, add an import at the top, not the one that was
added automatically here but manually go to the screens folder,
import splash_screen.dart and down there in this complex nesting of if statements which you can
simplify by the way by using a couple of builder methods here if you want to have a clearer structure
but in the end here, I'm checking
are we authenticated?
If yes, products overview screen, if not, future builder
tryAutoLogin, whilst we're waiting for a result, show the splash screen,
if we're done waiting, show the AuthScreen.
Now with that, do a full restart of your application and then try logging in there,
like this,
login, here we are and now do a full refresh again which will restart the app
and you see, I'm still ending up here,
I'm not on that AuthScreen.
If you close the app here through the drawer and you then go to your general app drawer down there and you try
launching your app here,
it also goes right into the shop and it's loading so fast and finding out that we're authenticated so
fast that I don't even see the splash screen.
Still, it's better to have that in place and see that splash screen in case there is some waiting delay
instead of that screen which is obsolete by the time you view it.
So this is how you can implement auto login which obviously is also quite a nice feature in your
application to ensure that you're providing a good user experience and with that, we're almost done
but you'll notice a strange behavior when you logout,
I'm not logged out. The reason for that is yes we're logging out, then this rebuilds here and then we're
automatically logged back in because the future builder runs again when this rebuilds and it sees hey I
still have data stored here,
so you probably want to be back in again.
So I'll relaunch my app here,
this was quit because I quit the app through the task manager here and in the meantime, let's go to auth.dart
and do something important.
When you logout, you of course want to clear all data you have in your shared preferences.
You have to clear all data there to make sure that any data you had in there is gone and is not getting
used in the auto login thereafter.
So here in logout, I'll also get access to my prefs by awaiting and for that, we have to turn this into an async
function with the async keyword which means it will return a future that yields nothing.
So here I want to await,
SharedPreferences.getInstance just as before
and then here we can call prefs and then either remove and pass in the key what we want to remove which
would be perfectly fine and would be good if you're storing multiple things in the shared preferences
which you don't all want to delete if you're logging out
but if you know you only store the user data there, you can also just call prefs.clear
but this will purge all your apps data from the shared preferences,
so if you're storing other data as well which should survive the logout, then you should not use clear
but remove.
Here we can use clear because I'm only storing user data.
So now if I refresh this, we should also be reloading that but now if I press logout, that should actually
work because we clear the preferences, here we saw the splash screen and now here I am back
and of course now we can also log back in if we want to and this should
now in general work just fine.
I also recommend that in the app drawer on the logout list tile, besides popping the app drawer, you also
add another navigation action with pushReplacementNamed
and that we simply always go to slash, slash nothing and that is the home route. Since you always go there,
you ensure that this logic here will always run whenever the logout button is pressed and since this
always runs and since this home route is always loaded,
we will always end up on the AuthScreen when we clear our data in the logout method of the auth provider.
So simply add this additional line here and go to your home route to ensure that you never have unexpected
behaviors when logging out.