So we want to load that chart screen if we are authenticated and therefore in main art, we need to
swap this off screen for the chat screen.
If we do find out that we have a valid token.
Now in the off section we did something similar, but there you saw that there are a couple of steps
you need to to do or you need to take care about when you're managing the token on your own.
The cool thing is with Firebase and Firebase off that entire token, management is done for you and
therefore swapping pages based on the off status is extremely easy.
We can replace our home widget here with a stream builder.
I showed you the stream builder early already.
Now this takes a stream and then a builder argument.
Now for the stream, I'll here not take my cloud firestorm, but instead my Firebase auth package or
a feature from the package.
So I'll import package firebase off firebase auth dart.
And then with that imported here we can use firebase auth dot instance dot on off state changed and
this gives us a stream and this stream will emit a new value whenever the off state changes and the
off state changes when we sign up, when we log in, when we log out, but also when the app is loading,
it will check if there is a cached token and the DAT caching and storage will be managed entirely by
Firebase here by the Firebase Flutter package.
And if it finds such a token, it will validate the token.
And if token is valid, it will even use that token even after a new app startup.
So that entire token storage and manage it across app restarts stuff is fully managed by Firebase here,
which is extremely convenient.
So we just need to listen to that stream.
And then the builder here will fire.
Whenever our off status changes here, we get the context and we get that user snapshot.
And in this function we then can return different widgets based on the user snapshot.
We can check if the user snapshot has data, which means that we did find a token essentially.
And in that case we can return the chat screen.
Whoops, the chat screen here.
Haas data is a field that is available on the snapshot to, well, indicate whether we've found some
valid data.
If we didn't find data, we'll return the off screen because then we need to authenticate.
And if I now save this, you will see that the chat screen is here because I did sign up earlier.
Firebase, as I explained multiple times, did take and store that token and manage it behind the scenes.
And therefore, just by adding this code, Firebase checked if it had a token, it does, and therefore
it logs us in and it renders the chat screen just like that all managed behind the scenes.
So that's why Firebase Authentication is really amazing.
Here now to see it fully in action, log out functionality might also be nice and therefore I'll go
to the chat screen and here on the scaffold.
I'll add an app bar.
The default app bar.
And this app bar will get a title.
Which can be a text widget where I say flutter, chat, anything like that.
And more importantly than that, it will get some actions.
Actions is an array of widgets.
And there I want to add a dropdown button which is a default widget that comes with Flutter.
The dropdown button is able to render an icon which is displayed in the action bar and there I'll use
the icon widget and then the more vert icon which basically gives us three vertical dots.
I'll also set the.
Color.
Here of the icon to theme of context primary color.
Sorry.
Not primary, but primary.
I can theme dot color.
Like this.
Notice we'll render a nice dropdown button, which we see here.
But this button doesn't do anything right now.
So to make sure that it does.
On the drop down button.
But outside of the icon, we set some items which are the items that are shown when we click the dropdown
button.
And that again is a list of widgets.
And here we typically render dropdown menu items.
And that is a single item in that dropdown.
And here I want to have one item.
It has a child where I will use a container and that container has a child where I will use a row because
I want to render two widgets next to each other here as a child in that dropdown.
The two widgets next to each other should be an icon.
So a regular icon widget where I use the exit to app icon and then a text widget where I say.
Logout and for some extra spacing I'll add a third widget here.
A sized box where I set the width to eight.
Now we also need to give this dropdown menu item value which will act as an identifier and I'll just
use log out here.
The value is up to you.
With that back on the entire dropdown button here you can add on changed.
Argument.
And that should be a function which gets the item identifier.
So the value you specified here, if you had multiple items, you could find out which item was pressed
by looking at the identifier here.
Of course we have only one item.
Still, for completeness sake, I'll check if item identifier is equal to logout, which of course should
be here since that's our only item.
And if that's the case, I want to log out for this.
I'll again use the firebase off package.
So package firebase off firebase auth dot dart.
And here we can then call firebase off dot instance dot sign out and this will log the user out.
With all of that.
Now we can open this and if I click logout, I'm back here because this science user out it will automatically
destroy the token and it will emit a new event here on the off state changed stream.
And there we will find out that we no longer have a token so we won't make it into this if statement
and instead this off screen is returned again.
And therefore now if I log in again here.
You, of course, see that we go back to the chat screen so that works that log in and log out part
works.
So that was a lot of progress.
Let me now talk briefly about some Firebase database rules which are important when we talk about security
on Firebase before we then start working on the actual chat here.