Now to throw your own error, you can use the throw keyword and there is a class in Dart,
the exception class which you can use to build your own exception.
However, the Dart team discourages that you directly use that,
instead you should build your own exception based on that exception class here.
For that, let me add a new folder, the models folder,
we saw that before in this course and in there, I'll add a http_exception.dart file and you can
name this however you want of course.
I'll add a class here and I want to name it HTTP exception because in the end, I'll throw that exception when
we have some problems with our HTTP request.
Now this is a class and exception classes which you plan on throwing should do something which we haven't
done before,
they should implement exception.
Now what does implements mean? We saw with, we saw extends, what's implements? Implements uses a class, exception
here is a class,
it's an abstract class though. Abstract means we can't directly instantiate this and in the end when we
implement a class, we are signing a contract, we're forced to implement all functions
this class has. Now exception itself has no class but in the end, this is just some complex syntax for saying
the exception class essentially looks like this and there, we have a to string method.
Now actually, every class in Dart has a to string method automatically because every class invisibly
extends object, object is the base class in Dart which every object is based on.
So to string is a method you can always call on any object,
for example here, on this exception here, we can call to string on our own product here, on the existing
product I have here,
I can call to string
even though we never added that because to string is available on every class.
But now we're signing a contract that will override this because normally to string for your own
classes just for instance of HTTP exception thing, so it just tells you of which type of class
your object is.
Here however, we want to instead print the error message because exceptions typically store a message.
So here, I'll add a final string message and a constructor to set this error message
and then here, I'll override to string with @Override to make it really clear that I'm adding this
deliberately and instead of returning super to string, which would yield us this instance of HTTP exception
thing, instead of doing this, I will return my custom string and here, I want to return message.
So my own HTTP exception class is now configured to always print the message here when we call our
exception which would be a concrete instance of this class to string or when we do print our exception,
in all these cases, it will trigger to string
and now it will simply print that message.
So with that, we have our own exception class added, back in products,
we can now throw our own exception class. So let's use HTTP exception here and for that of course,
add an import to our own class here from the models folder, from the http_exception.dart file. With that import
added,
I'm throwing my own HTTP exception,
add a message here, could not delete product, something like this. I'm never using that message here in
this program but you could use it anywhere if you want to
and now with that, we're throwing that, since I'm throwing
then, we should now make it into catch error and therefore now we should restore that.
So if we try that again and I delete this, it's gone and it's back, it's gone and it's back because now,
we're really using that optimistic updating here. Now we can also take this to the next level and even
add some error handling and actually to always use the same syntax,
I will now add async await, we wouldn't have to do that here but I don't want to makes the different
future syntaxes.
So here, I use async, hence we get back a future and therefore now I await here
and hence I get my response here and store this in this final constant. In the next line,
I then check this and I throw an error
if we have a problem
Now let's just clean this all up correctly,
so here I check if we have a problem with the status code,
if we do, I can already do the roll back in here of course because that's in the end what I had in catch
before, else
if we have no problem and actually, we will only reach it if we're not making it in here because if we
make it in here, throw is basically like return and it cancels the function execution,
the other code will not execute.
So if we don't make it in here, then this code will run and we do reset the product.
Now since I'm not using a promise with then and catch anymore however, I should execute this of course
to have optimistic updating before we actually start sending the request before we wait, so
otherwise we would wait for the request to finish before we delete this,
I want to delete it before the response is there and now, we have a setup where we immediately delete,
then we wait for the response,
then we check the response and possibly roll back and throw an error if it is an error response and
otherwise, we just reset that existing product which we cached.
And now we can actually handle that error in the user products screen, there in the user product item.
When we delete here,
this now may fail so we can now wrap this with try catch here and catch a potential error we might
be getting. For that,
let's just turn this into an async function here, so that this can work with this future which this is
behind the scenes
and then here in catch, we could show a snack bar for example if we wanted to.
So there, we could use scaffold of context,
show snack bar, you learned about that in the user interaction module, to create and use snack bar and there,
show a content of deleting failed for example and content of course takes a widget,
so let's use a text widget there.
So with that, I'm just showing that extra information, besides restoring the data,
I now also give the user some visual feedback that this failed
and of course now we also have the await here,
otherwise we'll not handle this appropriately. So now with async await and try catch here in user product
item, we should now see a scaffold
if we reload here,
if we delete this and it's re-added. However, there is no snack bar and we got an error here that's
causing this or that's explaining this behavior.
Basically, the problem here is with scaffold of, I'm doing this here inside of a future right, I'm doing
this here inside of a future because async is used here and therefore everything in there is wrapped
into a future and therefore of context can't actually be resolved anymore due to how Flutter works internally.
It's already updating the widget tree at this point of time and therefore it's not sure whether a context
still refers to the same context it did before. Solution for that is to go to the build method and
get our scaffold here, store that in a constant variable with scaffold of context and then down there, I just
use this scaffold variable instead of refetching access. If I do that and I now delete this,
now you see this works and now we have deleting failed here at the bottom. So now showing that scaffold
works because now we're getting access to that scaffold outside of our future here
earlier when we built this already and therefore, we already have access to our scaffold no matter if
this rebuilds or not and hence we can now use that down there.
Now let me also align the text here with textAlign.center, just a tiny improvement which I'll
like to have here but with that, we have a decent setup I'd say and we give the user some feedback and
we have some optimistic updating in place and of course, we're also now able to delete our products if
I fix this error and I add JSON again.
So let me demonstrate this as well because of course, that is also not that unimportant,
yes
now it's gone and it stays gone
and even if I reload, it's still gone.