To start using that card here.
Let's first of all think about where we need it later.
We'll need it in the products overview screen because they're in the app bar next to the pop up menu
button.
Here in the app bar, I want to add a card icon which is displayed up there which we can click or tap
to go to the card screen where we see all the card entries.
And on that card I can.
I also want to show a label that shows us how many items are in the card.
So we'll need information about the card here in the product's overview screen.
We also need access to the card from inside the product item start file because there we have that shopping
cart button here, this one which allows us to add items to the card.
And that, of course means that we need access to our card provider.
And we'll later also have a separate card screen which shows us or which allows us to see what's in
the card.
So we also need to access the card from there.
Hence the card is another thing that makes sense to be provided in our root widget because we need it
in a couple of screens which are defined up there as well.
Now the problem is we already have a provider here.
Now, of course we could have a nested change notifier provider in here and simply provide our card
here as a value would be possible, wouldn't be wrong, wouldn't hurt performance, but gets pretty
ugly the more and more providers we add because we have a deeper and deeper nesting, thankfully.
The provider package has us covered.
It gives us a special type of provider which allows us to group multiple providers together, and that's
the multi provider.
Multi provider is a class you can create a few import from the provider provider package and multi provider
takes a provider's argument, which is a list of providers.
Now to.
That providers list you simply add your providers like this change notifier provider value.
Of course, close that extra parentheses.
And at a parentheses here after providers.
And you're good.
So you simply have providers and next to that, then your child, which will simply receive all these
providers.
So in child here, you can tap into all providers you set up up there.
So now you have one change notified provider here with no child here, it will simply get this child
and we can add another one here now which receives our card.
And for Dad, we just have to make sure that we import the card model or the card class.
So from the provider's file, from card start, we need to import this.
And with that import added, we can set up this change, notify provider at the closing parentheses
and we're good.
So now we're adding these to providers to the entire child widget tree down there.
And that means we can now listen to card anywhere in the application.
Now, again, stepping in here from the future.
As I mentioned earlier, the recommended way of solving this here when you provide a brand new object
is that you don't use the value constructor, but instead the create function in the default constructor
of change notifier provider which simply looks like this.
And you should do this for products and also for the cart.
So that would be the recommended, the best practice approach.
The other approach, all the works fine here.
But again, as mentioned earlier, that is the current best practice of doing it.
Hence, of course, I want to show this here.