With our cart provider set up here as well, we can start using it
and a good way to start using it is to add items, here in product item.
That means I want to get access to my cart containers so to say and I can do this by using provider
of
and now of course with the angled brackets, I refer to cart and not products
and this gives us access to the nearest provided object of type cart, which is this one here in the
main.dart file. Now to use the cart
class here in products
item, we need to import it as always,
so we import from providers cart.dart and with that import added, here
we just have to add the context argument and now we get access to the cart container.
Now in the product item here, I'm not interested in changes to the cart,
so here I'll said listen to false so that this widget does not rebuild if the cart changes
because here I only want to dispatch actions so to say, I only want to tell the cart that I added a new
item, I'm not interested in changes to the cart. So down there on our button, we can now call cart add
item and we need to forward some information about the product which we thankfully have here, product.id,
product.price and product.title. All of that is available here
and so we can forward it. Now to see whether that works, it would be nice to output some information about
the cart somewhere
and as I mentioned, I want to do that in the ProductsOverviewScreen. There next to my PopUpMenuButton,
I want to have an icon button which shows the cart icon, takes us to the cart screen and also shows a small
label that tells us how many items are in the cart.
So here, I want to add an icon button with that cart icon and an extra badge.
Now this badge on the icon button is not a widget that would be built into Flutter.
Now to save some time, I'm providing you with one. You find it attached, it's a badge.dart file and
you can simply drag and drop it into your widgets folder. The badge.dart file creates a stateless
widget
and in this stateless widget here, let me add a comma here so that this is structured a bit nicer. There
in the end, we get three things we can configure - child, a value and a color which you can set and then
down there, I have a stack widget which is built into Flutter where I have a couple of children and essentially
there, I render a container with a little box decoration, some rounded corners,
then if a color is set, I use that color
otherwise I use the default accent color of the theme. Some box constraints to make sure that this
label, this badge doesn't grow too big if you have a large value in it
and then here I have my child which is simply text where I output the value which is received as an
argument,
right? So this is passed in from outside, align this in the center, set a certain font size and
yes,
so that's essentially my badge and please note that in this stack here, it does not just have this positioned
label,
it also adds child in here which also is a required argument.
So it basically is wrapped around some other child which you define and we can now use this badge widget
here in ProductsOverview by simply importing it from the widgets folder, there from badge.dart.
Here in the place where you want to have that cart IconButton, we can use our badge and as a child,
I define what this label should be placed on and that's my IconButton which receives an icon widget
of type icons shopping cart, then we also need to define which value we want to output on the badge and
that of course should be the amount of items we have in the cart and that's
now some information which we need to derive from our cart provider, from this cart
class. In the cart class,
we of course have our list of items, now we can also add another getter which returns us an integer which
tells us how many items are in there,
again to move the logic of counting that into our cart class here and not into our widgets.
So here, I get item count and now here, you have two different ways, two different approaches of counting.
You can either count the amount of entries in this map, then that means if you have one product with
quantity five in there, you still only return a count of one or you count the sum of all quantities,
so if you have one product in the cart but that has a quantity of five, you return five.
Now I want to return the amount of products, not the sum of quantities but of course, you can tweak this
to your likings. Here
however, I will simply return _items.length and that's all
and don't add parentheses here for getters.
So this gives us the item count. Back in the ProductsOverview,
this means that here in badge, to provide my value, I need to get access to my provided cart class.
Now we do provide in the main.dart file,
now we need to set up a listener.
We could set up the listener up here at the beginning of build, here in ProductsOverview, we could
get access to the cart with provider of cart and so on right
but that means the entire build method here would rerun whenever something changes in the cart.
Now most parts of this ProductsOverviewScreen don't care about that,
it's only this little button that cares about it.
So the better approach here is to use consumer and for that, you need to import provider.dart from the
provider package into this file and with consumer, you now define the class you want to listen to,
so here we're looking for the next provided object of type cart and for that, to use this class
here, we need to import from the providers folder
the cart.dart file and now we're setting up a listener to cart here
and in consumer, you now get your builder with your context if you should need it
which I don't, with your cart
object or data then
and also with that extra child.
Now it's here where I return this badge, so let's add this here and value, since I'm now in that builder,
can now be retrieved from the cart data or maybe name it just cart because that is what it is
and then on that cart, we simply can get the item count.
Now that's an integer, value
however wants a string, so we can simply call to string here. Now on the IconButton, we also should
add onPressed and for now, I'll not do anything in here and up there since I already used the underscore
for the context,
you could name this _2 or anything like that.
However, I want to use the child here because if you watch closely, what do I do?
I change the value here, that depends on the cart,
the icon button itself and the icon does not depend on it,
so rebuilding this just because the cart changed is actually a bit of a waste. So I can cut this out
of my badge here and on consumer, so next to that builder argument, I now add the child argument there
and provide my icon button as a child. This is then passed in here as a child in the builder and to avoid
naming confusion, I'll just name this ch
and now this is what I forward to the child of my badge.
Now these are a lot of child elements right
but child here on the consumer is my IconButton. This automatically gets passed into the builder by
Flutter and the provider package as the ch argument,
so this is the end what I defined here.
The important thing is that it won't be rebuilt when my cart changes because it's defined outside of
cart.
I then receive it in here in the builder and I can refer to it here and badge
also as a child argument to which I then pass this static child I defined out here which simply is done
this way so that it doesn't rebuild when the cart changes.
Now if we do a full restart here, I actually get an error and
if we have a look at that error by scrolling up to the beginning, we see that the problem is that the
getter length was called on null. So that can only come from one place and that's in the cart.dart file
where I return items length. Of course the problem is items here initially is undefined and therefore
it has no length property. The solution is simple,
you can check whether items is equal to null and if that's the case, you return 0 here and otherwise, you
return items length. That is one simple solution here around this problem.
Now this rebuilds,
now you see here the debug badge is slightly above it
but you see that icon here or the cart icon with that badge and if I click on Add to Cart here,
nothing changes, why is that? Because we forgot something important.
You always need to call notifyListeners when you change something in your provided classes to which
your listeners should react.
So here if I update my cart, of course at the end of this add item function here, I have to call
notifyListeners, otherwise my changes won't be reflected in user interface.
So now if I save this, if I tap this shopping cart
icon here, still nothing.
Well we see that we have an error here and
the error is that contains key was called on null.
The problem here simply is that all my nice methods here on items don't work
if items is uninitialized as it is here. Simple workaround is to simply initialize this as an empty
map which of course also means that this work around here isn't really needed anymore. So make sure that
items is an empty map here initially and now if you reload with that and with notifyListeners added,
now
if I click on my cart icons, you see the number in the badge now changes. If I click on the same
icon multiple times, it doesn't change because in my implementation here, I'm counting the amount of products
in the cart, not the sum of quantities
but if I click on different products, then it increases.
So this shows how we can now manage the cart in our provided class here,
how we do this efficiently and how we can use that information in different widgets. Now as a next step,
let's actually make sure we can click that cart
icon here and go to a separate screen where we can see all the content of our cart.