Deleting products isn't too hard actually,
we first of all need to add a method in our products provider file where we have add and update product.
There we now need a delete product method
and of course it makes sense that we get the ID of the product which should be deleted as an input.
And then deleting here is really straightforward,
we can reach out to our items, so to all the products we stored here and call remove where
to execute a function on every product there
and if it returns true, it's a product that should be removed
and of course we will return true if the ID of the product we're looking at in our list of products
is equal to the ID we're getting here
as an argument. In that case, this will be removed from the list, all other items will be kept
and of course we should call notify listeners to update all places in the app that would care.
Now we can call delete product from inside user products, from the user products screen. There,
we set up a listener to our products and this should be a listener because I want to rebuild my list
if products change and with that here on the user product item, we can now get rid of the product.
So in user product item, here when this trash button is clicked, I want to clear my product and for that,
we have actually two options,
either we receive a callback function, so a function which we store in a variable which is passed in
through the constructor, which we pass in therefore through this constructor here and therefore we
have to function for deleting the product in the user products screen.
We could do that because we already have access to the products data through the provider here,
so it would be super easy to call delete product here but it's also not too hard to use a different
approach and in the user product item widget, we can of course also use the provider package, so use package
provider/provider.dart and also get access to our products.dart file here and then here on the delete
button, we can use provider of, get access to products, forward the context and then call delete product
for the product ID which we already have as a property in this widget because we're already getting
it as an argument.
Now one important note, here of course I don't want to listen to changes, so I'll set listen to false
here,
I only use this place to dispatch this action. And with that if we save this and do a full refresh and
go back to our products,
if I delete the yellow scarf, indeed it's gone and it's still gone
if I go to the shop and I go back because I really removed it from my list of products. Now of course,
it's only temporarily gone,
as soon as we restart the app it's back because we're not saving our data on any server or anything
like that
but this proves that this generally works
and with that we have a setup where we are able to interact with user input, we're able to validate the
user input, create new products, edit products, delete products and also show some helpful messages, like
for example the messages we're showing here when we add something to the cart where we can also undo
this or if we have something in the cart and we want to delete this or we can stop that. These hopefully
are all things that are helpful to you in your next steps.