So we added a couple of nice HTTP related features to this application,
now let's see what's missing.
For example on the shop, when I switch the favorite status here,
currently that's not saved,
if I reload the page, this is simply gone because we're not saving this on the server and of course we're
also not saving any orders. When I place something in a cart and I order this,
obviously it gets added to that orders screen here for all the orders which I do add but the orders
thereafter are lost if the app restarts because we're not saving the orders on a server. So that would
be something I want to do, save the orders and of course fetch the orders from a server and also save changes
in the favorite status to the server.
Now definitely feel free to try to do this on your own.
I will implement that favorite thing with optimistic updating, where you immediately update this here
and you only roll it back if it failed,
that's just a little hint and for the orders you can just store and fetch them as we basically did it
also with product, so add an order, fetch orders, the patterns there should be similar to how we did that for
adding products.
One note about adding orders, here
you might want to go to the cart and make sure that the order now button is disabled
if we can't place an order and that whilst we are placing that order,
so whilst the HTTP request is on its way,
you maybe show some loading spinner here inside of the disabled button then because the button should
also be disabled whilst the request is on its way,
so that you give the user some feedback on when the button may be used and when the progress is in transit.
These are the things I'll implement in the next lectures,
here's your chance to first try it on your own and then do it together with me of course.