So were you successful?
Let's start with the favorite feature. We manage that in the product.dart file, here we have to toggle
favorite status method and in the end, it's here where I want to send a HTTP request to also save that
new status for the product we're updating and of course, we have the ID of the product available in
here to the server. So let's import the HTTP package here because we'll need that send HTTP requests
and whilst technically not required because it exposes so many features, I'll bundle them all again under
the HTTP prefix.
Now we can send a request and as I mentioned, I want to employ optimistic updating here which means
that I first change this
and then I roll it back if it fails.
Hence, I'll first of all store the old status, so old status is isFavorite and this copies the old status
here,
it makes sure that we keep that old status before we then change it.
So here, we then change the favoriting status and we update the UI,
that's that optimistic updating part,
we do that before to request is sent and then we do send a request
and now here, I want to send a patch request because the goal of course is to update our products or a specific
product
here of course with the new favorite status. I want to keep all the existing data there as it and just
exchange the favorite status.
So therefore here, I patch and the URL I want to target is the same URL I used here for updating
or for deleting a product because we need a URL that includes the ID.
The ID here is available because it is a property of this class and since this of course always
will execute for concrete instances of this class right,
the ID will be set and therefore, we'll target a specific ID and send our request to that ID. Now
the body is the data which I want to change or describes the change
and here, we want to json.encode and for that, I need to import dart:convert here,
that's important,
add that import. With that import added here, we can call json.encode and encode a map where I only
want to set the isFavorite key
and again that should match the name you have here on your server,
so that isFavorite name you have there as well
and the new value here is the new value we have here,
so isFavorite, after it was switched because of course I want to store that new value which we also
use locally on the server.
Now normally, that should succeed of course but it might fail. So we can use async await here and wrap
this into a try catch block to roll this back.
So let's add catch error here and return a future in here and I have one curly brace,
too much, should have it here.
So now we have that block and in here, I would want to roll this back,
so here what I set isFavorite which refers to my isFavorite property up there and set this equal to
the old status which I saved, so I set this equal to old status here. If we do that and we reload this,
let's see whether it works,
so first of all without an error here. If I do that, here for example I already mark this as a favorite
on the server by setting it to true there,
if I switch this, it's updated here and also here, it's now false,
so this works
and if I do this multiple times, this also works, it's false here,
it's false here,
so that works.
Now let's simulate an error, again with the good old trick of removing the JSON thing here,
let's do a hot refresh because we lose our local state when we do a hot reload here
and let's try this again, whether the updating works. If I set this,
it gets checked and it's not reverted. Now it doesn't end up on a server because we have an error
of course but we don't revert the value.
Now for one, I'm not calling NotifyListeners here,
I should do that here because otherwise the UI can't update,
you have to call that to update UI, just as we're doing it up here
but that's actually not the reason or the problem here,
instead the problem really is what we had before that the HTTP package only throws its own error for
get and post requests if the server returns an error status code. For patch, put, delete, it doesn't
do that.
Now we still might want to leave try catch here because for example if we have a network error, we still
might want to run that logic and we still might get a normal exception
but I also want to manually extract my response here and store it in that final variable and then check
if response status code is greater or equal than 400, which means we have an error
and in that case, also do that roll back logic and since I have some code duplication here of course,
you could also add an extra method which doesn't return anything, with an underscore because it should be private
and only be callable from inside this file and class which I'll name set fav value
and there I expect to get the new value as a boolean and in there, I simply set isFavorite equal to
the new value and call NotifyListeners
and now we can simply call set fav value to old status here
and this saves us one extra line of code and avoids a bit of code duplication.
Now with that changed,
so now that we manually check the status code,
we should have a setup where we have successful optimistic updating.
So I try to change this and I reflect the new status in the UI but then this should get rolled back
and it does as soon as we have that error.
So now we have proper optimistic updating in place
and with that of course, let me fix that error to again check whether it still works, if we are able to
send that request.
So let's do a reload here,
mark this and now it stays marked and we also see that here on the back-end that it's true.
So this works,
now we are able to update our favorite status and also store that on a server.