Of course, we need to be able to send new messages and therefore I'll add a new widget in the chat
folder.
New message to start.
Now this can also be a state less widget, but it should be a stateful widget because I actually want
to be able to validate the user input and disable the send button if nothing was entered.
So here I'll name this new message and then of course import material.
Start from the flutter package.
And what should we return here?
Well, we can return a container actually should work fine with a little bit of margin, which I only
want to have on the top, though.
So we'll add some top margin here on this container so that there is some spacing between our text field
and the message list.
And I'll also add some padding with edge insets, all of eight as well, so that we also have some space
inside of this text input box widget.
And then the child here is a row because I actually want to have two items next to each other, the
actual text input field and the button to send the message.
So here we need children.
And the first child is a text field.
Now here, a regular text field, because I'm not wrapping this in a form, I'll just validate it on
the go, so to say, without a big forum, because we don't need this here for this very basic input
field.
Now you would get an error like this.
You actually need to wrap this into expand it as well.
Otherwise, a text field in a row will cause an error because it tries to take up too much space with
expanded around it.
This will work, however.
Now on the text field I'll add a declaration.
Input declaration where I set a label of.
Send.
Message.
To make it clear what this text field does in case it wasn't clear.
And I want to listen on every keystroke with the unchanged event here, with the unchanged function
where we get the user input and where we then can do something, for example, validate it and unlock
the button to send it, which is the item I'll add next to the expanded widget here I can button and
this should be the send icon.
So here I'll add a color of theme of context.
Primary color pops.
Primary color.
And I'll add an icon, which should be the send icon here.
Now, of course, this button also needs an own press handler so that something happens or can happen
when we click it.
The button should also only be enabled if a message was entered.
They offer a new message state.
We can manage that state.
We can have a variable entered message, which initially is an empty string.
And here in on changed we call set state and set entered message equal to the value we got here.
Now this will run on every keystroke so we update the stored entered message with every keystroke and
now we can use entered message to lock or unlock the icon button by only conditionally adding this function.
So on the icon button on pressed here we can check if entered.
Message trimmed is empty.
If it is empty, we know we have no valid message even after removing all x's whitespace with trim.
And if that's the case all set on pressed to null, which means it has no function attached and this
will automatically disable the button.
That's how Flutter works.
If the message is not empty, I will set this function here as a value for on pressed.
So now there is a function to execute when the button is pressed and therefore the button will be enabled.
Now.
Right now, we're not sending any message, but this should work already.
So let's go to the chat screen and there we have a column with our messages now below the messages here.
We can therefore now simply add our new message widget.
And of course, you need to import new message.
Start from the respective path here.
So if you save this, we have this message here at the bottom and this annoying floating action button,
we can entirely delete this.
We don't need the floating action button anymore.
So let's get rid of it.
Like that.
And now here.
Here is the sent message button.
It's disabled.
But if I enter a valid message, it's enabled and I can press it.
But of course, nothing happens right now.
So we need to change this.
We need to make sure that when we press this, we may be also unfocused this field so that the keyboard
goes away automatically, but then also that this message is being sent.
Now we'll start with focusing here.
Dysfunction should be triggered and I don't want to write everything here in this anonymous function.
So instead I'll.
Robert add a function up here.
Send a message.
And in there I'll first of all, use focus, scope of context and call unfocused to close the keyboard,
which might be open.
And it's sent a message which therefore is connected here like this, without parentheses, just pointing
at it.
And instead of sent message, we now want to use our store to create this new message.
So for this, we import package cloud, fire store, cloud, fire store, dart.
And then here we can use far store dot instance and target the chat collection.
And here we now want to add a new document, which we do with the ADD method.
Now this takes a map which describes the new document, and we want to have a text field here because
every chat message should have a text field.
Our dummy message has one to.
So here text and the value should of course be the entered message.
So what's stored in this variable?
And that should be all we need to do to send a new message.
Now, this gives us a future, and we could wait for it to complete.
We could show a loading spinner.
But I think in a chat application we don't really need this.
So that should really be all we need.
And please note that we also don't need to add any authentication token or anything like that.
This is all managed behind the scenes by Firebase here.
So if we simply save this, we should be able to send a new message.
If I enter a one, does this work and I click send you see, here's my message.
Now, of course, the formatting is not final, but this is my message.
So that works.
Now two improvements.
I think it would be nice if the message input field would be cleared thereafter.
And I also want to make sure that the messages are ordered in the opposite direction so that the most
recent message is here at the bottom and not at the top.
To make sure that this happens, to make sure that the ordering is correct.
We can go to message start and there on the list view there is a little extra field you can set.
You can set reverse to true.
And this will do just what the name implies.
It will order the messages or the fields differently.
It will scroll from the bottom to the top.
Now you see how low still is ordered below.
Does this work simply because of how the auto ID was created when I manually edit this document?
But if I delete this document with hello.
So if I enter.
Hello here.
You see now this is at the bottom, so that's nice.
Now for clearing the input here in new message, I want to clear the message or the input whenever we
send a new message.
And to do that, we can add a controller to the text field here and create a new controller in our state
here.
A final.
Controller.
New text editing controller like this.
And use this controller here and send a message.
To call controller clear and now bind this controller to the text field simply by pointing at it here
on the controller argument.
We now safeties and I type does this clear.
You see, it clears and this is also closed.
Now, one thing you also see, however, is the ordering here is still is not working entirely as it
should.
And you see that also here in Firebase by default, the oldest document is the topmost one and the most
recent one is the bottom most one.
And since we reverse this here, it's the opposite.
Now, one way of ordering this correctly and making sure that we have a consistent order is that we
also store timestamp along with the text when a document is being created and we then order by that
timestamp.
So here on New Message, we can then go to the place where we add a new document and besides text,
we can also add a created add field.
The name is up to you doesn't have to be created at and you can then use stamped now to create a new
timestamp.
Now Timestamp is a class that is available, made available by the Cloud File Store package.
Now with this, we create a time stamp which will be part of the document that's being stored and it's
stored in a created add field.
So now when we retrieve the messages here before we actually set up that listener or that stream, before
we get access to the stream on the collection we can actually call order by.
And this allows us to order the documents we're about to fetch by a certain field.
And we can order by created at so by that new field, I just add it.
Now, of course, my existing messages don't have that field, so I will quickly delete all those messages.
If you have a lot of messages, you can also delete the entire chat collection.
Instead, it will be recreated automatically as soon as you start adding messages again.
But once it's empty, I'll save this.
Go back and send a new message.
Hello.
Does this work?
And you see it's still ordered correctly, but simply because we have to specify how we want to order
this.
And by default, it's ordered in ascending way.
I want to order in a descending way, though, so I'll set descending to true here.
That's the second argument you can pass to order by.
And if you set descending to Drew, you'll see.
Now that's this work is the second message here.
So this message, which I submitted a little bit later and in the first one.
And if I add another new message, another new message, you will see that now this is the bottom of
that message.
And even if I restart the app here, if I completely reload it, you see, this order is kept.
So now we finally have the correct order here, which is of course super important and which is what
we ultimately want here.
With that out of the way, let's work on those chat messages.
They look a bit ugly like this.
And of course, we also want to make sure that we can quickly tell whether this message is by us or
by a number of user.