Let's now work on the orders and there,
let's start with the logic for adding an order.
Obviously, when you add an order, that should also be stored on the server.
Now the logic for that will be pretty similar to what we used for adding a product, so you can definitely
have a look at the add product method to learn how to add an order
and actually, I'll copy a bit of that, so I'll copy that URL for example, go to the orders.dart
file and add it here.
Also, I'll turn this into an async function which will therefore return a future which yields void in the
end
and now I want to use the HTTP package in here,
so we should import it of course.
So let's import package:http and there http.dart and again, I'll bundle this all with the HTTP prefix to
access all the features from that package with http. With that, here
I want to send the request and that should be a post request because I want to add a new order on the
server.
Send it to that URL and of course, we need to append a body here. Now that body needs to be in JSON
format, so let's also import dart:convert here to create some JSON, to convert our map to JSON.
So here, we can then call json.encode, pass in a map and in that map, I want to store all the data which
should be stored on the server in the end.
So what makes up an order? An order looks like this.
We have an ID, well that will be generated by Firebase so we don't need to store that but we'll have
an amount, a datetime and then also, we'll have some products and the products in turn are cart products.
Now we find the definition for that in the cart.dart file, a cart item in turn has an ID, a title, a quantity
and a price.
So we'll need to convert all of that into maps,
So actually here we'll have a map with then a list of nested maps inside of it.
So let's start working on that,
We'll have our amount and the amount is simply the total we get here,
That's simple.
Now for the datetime, for the timestamp, we can use DateTime.now and convert this to an Iso8601String
which is simply a uniform string representation of dates, which we can later easily convert back into
a datetime object when we load this into Dart again because we can't just send a datetime object like this,
We don't want to send its normal string representation,
instead we want to send this special string representation which is easily recreatable as a datetime
later then.
So that's fine but actually, that's already the first thing which you could mess up.
We're using that timestamp also down there in the order item which we create for our local memory.
That of course should be exactly the same timestamp as up there but if we execute a HTTP request in between,
there will be some difference in the timestamps.
So actually, I'll first create my timestamp here with DateTime.now and then use that timestamp that
is created at the beginning of this function execution here to send it to a server
and here, to then use it locally, so that we have exactly the same timestamp. And then here for the data we
do send to a server, we of course also have our products and now products is actually a list that can
be encoded to JSON just like a map
but that list here now needs to have our cartProducts.
Now cartProducts is a list but a list of cart items and we need to map these cart items into maps and
not have objects.
So here, I will use cartProducts.map and then you call to list to get a list again and in map, we get
a function which runs on every cp, on every cart product and there, I want to now return a new map, so
convert my objects here based on cart item into maps. And there, every map will have an ID,
so basically the same fields I have here for the cart item - ID, title, quantity and price, so I will
have an ID here which is cp.id and I'll have a title which is cp.title and I'll have a quantity
which is cp.quantity here
and I'll have a price, which is cp.price. So that's how the product should look like here in that
map and with that, we now have an order representation, a representation of an order item which we can
send to the server.
Now we already added async, so we can now use await here to wait for a response
and indeed, I will use the response then. We could add error handling by the way, wrap try catch around
that or wrap try catch around the place where you call add order later if you want to,
again I will leave out error handling here to save some time but I still want to use the response here
because that response will hold an ID which is generated by Firebase, which I want to use here instead
of this dummy ID.
So here, I want to decode my response body and that will be that map which has that name key which is
that autogenerated ID. It's the same pattern we used in products, here in add product, we also got the
autogenerated ID like this and I'm using the same pattern now to get that autogenerated ID for
the order and that should be all. We add our order locally
once this is done, with await, we're waiting for this to be done before this executes and again, always
remember, technically this gets wrapped into a then block,
we're not really stopping code execution but now with that, we can go to the place where we call add order
and see if everything is good there and maybe show a loading spinner because we call add order
in our cart screen. There we have that FlatButton, order now and there, I call add order. Now there, I of
course want to show a loading spinner
instead of that text and also disable the button whilst we're loading
and I also by the way want to disable the button if we have nothing to order.
So we have nothing to order
if cart here has a total amount that is equal to or smaller than zero.
So the first thing we can do here actually
and we could have done that before
is that we check cart total amount and if that's smaller or equal than zero,
then onPressed should point at null
instead of that function
and if onPressed points at null instead of a function, Flutter automatically disables the button,
that's a nice feature.
So the button is automatically disabled if onPressed has no function to point at
and that's the case if the total amount is smaller or equal to zero.
But now I also want to manage some loading state to show a spinner and also disable the button there
and for that, we can turn this into a stateful widget or to avoid rebuilding everything just because
we're switching this here to show a loading spinner,
we can of course also extract that FlatButton into a separate widget which might be more elegant here.
So we can use the refactoring tool to extract the widget here and I'll name this order button and by
default, that's placed in the same file
and here I'll actually leave it in that file because the order button is really only used by that widget,
by that cart screen widget,
so whilst you could absolutely move the order button into a separate file and it would not be wrong,
whilst you could do that,
you can also leave it here because we'll never use it anywhere else. Now order button is already configured
to receive the cart which is good because we need the cart
total amount here, however we now need to convert this into a stateful widget, which you again can do
with the refactoring tool because now here, we can add the isLoading property which initially is false
and I want to set this to true in here and inside of set state of course to update this UI when we
start loading.
So I'll set this to true and now that's why I put this into a separate widget,
with set state, we now only re-execute this build method instead of that entire build method up there.
So we rebuild less which is of course not bad
and here by the way, you can remove new which was added,
this is not required as of Dart 2 anymore.
So now here on the order button, we call set state when we start loading,
now of course this here returns a future,
so actually I'll add async here between the parameter list and the body of this anonymous function,
you can use async on anonymous functions as well because of course I want to await this now,
I don't care about the result because the result will be void anyways
but I want to await this before I clear the cart and also before I reset my loading state of course.
So here, I'll set loading back to false once we're done. So with that,
the last thing is that I also want to disable the button whilst we're loading,
so here I'll not just check for the cart amount but this should also be disabled.
So I also want to set onPressed to null if we either have this condition or if isLoading is true and now
with that, let's do a full restart and let's see whether that works.
Let's add a couple of items to the cart here and now here if I click order now,
it gets disabled and after a while, the items are gone, they end up here in orders and
I also have my order here. Now incorrectly in products,
so I'll actually clear that here,
that's a mistake,
in orders.dart, of course I don't want to target products.json but a new node like orders.json,
the name is up to you because of course, this should be not stored in the same list as the products
but in a separate list,
that's a mistake.
So make sure to clear that here on Firebase and remove the order from the products and update the URL
and the other missing thing is that I'm not showing a spinner. I do disable the button,
that's good
but actually I want to show a spinner instead of order
now if we're loading. So here, I'll check isLoading and if we are loading, then I'll show a
CircularProgressIndicator and only if we're not loading, I'll show that text here.
So these are the two things which need to be changed and with that, let's do a hot refresh again to reload
the app, add a couple of items here to the cart and now click order now and here's the spinner
and after a while, it's gone
and now on Firebase, we also see that this item was added to the orders node
and there we have all the data we wanted to send.
So this is looking good
and with that, we're storing the orders,
let's next make sure that we can also fetch them.