With the orders getting stored, now it's time to fetch them when we visit the order screen and for that,
let's go to the orders.dart file because here, I want to add,
just as I had in the products.dart file, I want to add a fetch and set method here to fetch and
set the orders.
It will eventually yield a future which will then yield nothing,
I'll call it fetch and set orders
but the name is up to you and of course, I want to use the async keyword here so that we can work with
async await.
Now for the URL, the URL of course is that URL where we stored our orders and now we
can use a get request here to send it to that URL to get these orders. So that gets us a response
and for the moment, I simply print the decoded version of the response body so that we can see what's
in there and here we should await to wait for that to resolve to really have the response object in
there. So that's a basic setup and we'll of course fine tune this to really extract and store the data,
let's now fire this fetch and set orders method from inside the orders screen. Now this is a stateless widget,
so we can't use initState or didChangeDependencies,
so the first thing I'll actually have to do here is we have to convert this to a stateful widget. With
a stateful widget,
now we can go ahead and either use initState with that future delayed
hack if you remember, I showed it earlier or use that didChangeDependencies.
Now I'll use the future delayed hack here because in the past, I used the different approach and I want
to show both and in there, we use future delayed which is a constructor that gives us a new future and
we pass in a duration that should pass until this future automatically resolves and here, duration
zero is a special value which instantly resolves this but the way Dart works, this still only executes
after this initialization is done here because that all happened simultaneously but this is queued at
the end so to say. So now here, we can add then and we should add
then, don't turn this into an async function here.
It's not something you should do because by default it's not async, by default it doesn't return a future,
you shouldn't turn it into a function that does. So instead use then here, you get a value which is void
but you still need to accept it and then in here, you can go ahead and send that request to fetch orders.
So for that, you need the provider and you need your orders from the orders.dart file,
so that here, we can say provider of orders context and listen: false because I only want to dispatch this
fetching action, I don't want to listen to updates here because of that.
So here, I just want to call fetch and set orders and be done with it
and then down there of course, we do set up a listener to orders and that is all fine but here, I don't
want to set up another one so to say. If we now do a full refresh and we visit this orders page, we should
actually make that request and that's looking good,
here's the output and again, you see we get a map where we have that autogenerated ID as a key and
then a nested map with our order data and that data also then happens to have a nested list with our
cart item maps.
So a couple of nested elements and now we'll have to extract this to then rebuild an order item that
looks like this which has a list of nested cart items and all these values so that in the end, we have
a list of these order items which we can use to override this list with it.
So let's get started with that. Here,
I'll create a little helper list which will be full of order items which I'll name loaded orders which
initially is empty
and then I want to go through my extracted response body.
So here, I'll have my extracted data and that's in the end josn.decode response body,
so what we just printed.
Now we should let Dart know that this will be of type map with string keys and dynamic values, just
as we did it the products.dart file
and with that, we can use the extracted data with forEach to go through all our keys and values in
that map or we of course know that the keys are the order IDs and the values, that's our order
data in the end and now we add items to our loaded orders with add and now in there,
let's create an order item and that order item will have an ID which is our order ID we're getting
here,
so
that key in that map
and besides that, we of course have an amount and we get that from the order data which is a map as we
know which will have an amount key, we can see it here.
We'll also need the datetime
and here we want to create a new datetime, we can do that with DateTime.parse and parse now takes a string
which has to have that ISO 8601 format,
that's why I save that as such a string here before we sent it to the web.
Now we're retrieving such a string and therefore here, we can parse order data and then here, datetime,
so this key and this value and this can now be passed into a datetime object again,
let me restructure this
and now of course, the products.
Now for the products, we know that we have a list in here,
so order data
product,
so for the products key, for this key is a list,
we know that,
so that's a list of dynamic values in the end. So let's wrap this into parentheses because now we can
call map on this to convert it into a list of cart items.
As always, you need to call to list here at the end to convert it into a list
but now in the map function here, you get your items or whatever you want to name that
and here I'll return my new cart items, like this and now every cart item has an ID but item here is the
end just a map,
right,
we know that it is a map
and it has an ID here.
So we can use that ID
and that's still my custom dummy ID because we never save cart items to the server, hence we have only
these IDs, doesn't matter too much though because we never work with these IDs,
so here, I access item ID. Besides that, our cart items also have a price and we get that from item for
the price key,
right,
because we have that price key in there. We also of course have a quantity,
hence here I access item for the quantity key,
so this key and last but not least, we also have the title in there, so let's add title here and access item
for the title key.
So this now creates cart items, to be precise, a list of cart items based on the items we find here
and then we use this as a value for the products here and this recreates in the end our loaded orders.
So down here,
we're done with that and we can now set our orders here equal to the loaded orders
and then of course call NotifyListeners to make sure that our UI updates in all places and this
should be all.
If we now save that, if we revisit this orders page, it should actually load our orders from the web and
display them and it does.
Now what if we have no orders,
so if I delete that orders node here on Firebase? What if I now go back and I revisit this page? Still has
the old orders in memory but we now also have an error here and the error is that forEach was called
on null.
The problem is that I'm calling forEach here on the extracted data, even though we got no extracted
data because we didn't return anything from the back and from the server because no orders were
stored there.
So actually as an improvement, you should check if extracted data is equal to null and if it is, return
here
so that this code does not run if extracted data is null
and by the way, you want to do the same for products if we have no products. There, before we call extracted
data forEach,
we should check if extracted data is equal to null
and if it is return and don't execute any other code, so return here to avoid that you run code which
would fail if you have no data.
So do that in the products.dart file and also in the orders.dart file and with that if we now do a full
refresh,
now we should be able to revisit the orders screen here without errors.
Now let's actually place another order here by ordering that maybe, let's go here to the order screen
and see it
and let's now actually add a loading spinner because of course when we're in the app, the data is immediately
there because it's then already stored here in our orders.dart file
but let's make sure we show a loading spinner
when we first load that page. For that in the orders screen here, we have a stateful widget, I'll add the
isLoading property and set this to false initially. Here, I'll call set state and set isLoading to true,
set state to update the UI because this will actually run after build was called, even though it's delayed
by nothing,
the whole other flow of initState finishing up and build being called will have finished when this runs.
So we need to run set state here to
do this, then also turn this into an async method here and await fetch and set orders
This now maybe async because it's just a function we pass to then, not initState, setting this to
async is not something I would recommend
and then also of course after you waited for the response, set this back to false here.
So now with that, we can display a loading spinner here instead of the list by checking isLoading and
if we are loading, again I'll have that centered CircularProgressIndicator all built into Flutter and
only show the ListView if we're not loading.
So now if we do a full refresh, let's visit the orders page
and we see the loading spinner. If we now revisit this, it again gets loaded again and we see the loading
spinner again
therefore. So with that, we're also fetching our orders,
let's now place one other order maybe for this here for the book to see whether that also works, we
should have two orders now
and one thing you'll see now however is that the order is wrong, it's now ordered with the oldest order
on top.
Now previously, we had a different order and that can easily be fixed by going through the orders.dart
file and here where we set orders equal to loaded orders,
you can call reversed and then to list and this will reverse the list and simply store the reversed
list here.
So now this is also up to date and shows the newest order first,
that's just a tiny thing. But with that, I'd say we have a decent application here which has all the features
we would want of it and we're able to add items, edit items, view items, change the favorite status,
place orders and view our orders now.