Navigation works,
let's now also go to the FiltersScreen and add a scaffold again, so that we have our centered widget
here on the body and in the appBar,
I have an appBar where I say your filters,
something like that
and with that, that looks way better
and now we have a problem here.
I have a back button here
and with that, I can go back to the previous page.
Now maybe that's actually what you want but I would like to have a hamburger icon up here, so that I can
open the same drawer which I have here.
Now the solution is relatively simple,
all we have to do is in the FiltersScreen, we have to add the drawer again and reference our main drawer
and of course also add the import to that drawer here by going up one level and then to the widgets folder
and now we have that drawer icon here.
But there's one behavior which I'm not liking, I'm always pushing my page which I'm loading on top of
that stack of pages.
We're not seeing it here because we have no back button in the top left corner,
thanks to the drawer but actually over time, we accumulate quite a big stack of pages because we never
delete the page we're coming from,
so we're not deleting the meals page or the tabs page here
when I go to filters
but then if I go back to meals, I also haven't deleted filters and the previous categories page.
So the problem is that we get a stack of pages that's bigger and bigger over time because we never clear
the existing pages.
Now that's no problem
if we just go into a category, into a recipe and then we have to go back at some time,
so we will clear that stack at some point of time
and we want that forward backward navigation there but here for the drawer, just like for the tabs, I essentially
don't want to have a infinitely growing stack,
instead I want to clear my stack and simply push the new page as the only stack page here onto my stack
so to say. So if I go to meals, the filters page should be deleted,
if I go to filters, the meals page, the tabs page here should be deleted automatically.
Now it's easy to do that in Flutter, inside of the drawer, instead of using pushNamed,
you can use pushReplacementNamed or if you have no named route but you create it in place,
you also have pushReplacement and then you would pass a MaterialPageRoute here.
But for our named route, we have pushReplacementNamed and the difference to pushNamed without replacement
is that now you will replace the existing page on the stack with the new page.
So you don't add the new page on top of it in that stack of pages but you replace the existing page
and hence you would also not get a back button.
So with that, if I go to meals and filters, we have the same effect as before
but now we avoid that our stack gets bigger and bigger and we can clearly see that effect if I temporarily
comment out the drawer in my FiltersScreen. If I do so and I then full restart the app with the green arrow
here
and I then go to filters here, you see now we have no back button here
and the reason for that is that Flutter recognizes that nothing is on the stack, that there are no pages
to go back to because we didn't keep the old page and push the new one on top of it,
instead we replaced the old page, we deleted it and then added the new page and hence we can't go back
and this is sometimes what you want. Sometimes you don't want the user to go back but instead you want
to replace the existing page, for example also when you add user authentication, when you entered your
login data and you hit login and you then reach your main app, typically you don't want to provide
a back button to go back to the login because you already are logged in,
that would be another scenario where you would typically use pushReplacement instead of just push.
Well and here with the drawer, it's just another example to avoid an infinitely growing stack of pages
behind the scenes which could lead to memory problems at some point of time.