Now with our stateful widget added, it's important to have a brief first look. I'll later to have
a more detailed look but a brief first look at what Flutter actually does when set state is executed
here. Set state is a function that forces Flutter to re-render the user interface, however not the entire
user interface of the entire app,
instead what set state does in the end is it calls build again of this widget where you call set
state.
Now in our case, that is almost the entire app, MyApp,
this widget here with this build method that is basically our entire app
but later in this course, we'll have bigger applications with more widgets where we split that into more
custom widgets and therefore, it will really make a difference if you update the entire app or just that
widget with set state,
so set state updates this widget by calling its build method again.
Now the build method goes ahead and rebuilds this widget tree,
it basically goes through all these instructions again.
Now that might sound very inefficient because the majority of this user interface didn't change right,
all the buttons are still the same,
the appBar is the same,
only this text changed and therefore Flutter,
no worries, is pretty efficient about that. Internally, it has a lot of mechanism to go through that build
method again but to not really render the entire UI again, so it does not redraw every pixel again.
In the end, it just has its tools and its mechanisms to find out what changed on the screen and what
needs to be redrawn and therefore it will find out that text here changed, that this widget changed because
the text we passed to it changed and it will only update this text here
in the end. Now again, I'll dive deeper into how that works and how we can find out what Flutter changed
and so on, I'll dive into that throughout the course
once we are a bit more proficient with Flutter, it's just a brief first look which I wanted to give you
at this point, that build is getting called when you call set state and that is why you see the change
then and that is also why you didn't see anything without set state because then you changed the data
which is nice but Flutter never executed build again and therefore this widget tree never got rebuilt
and therefore this text with the updated text never made it onto what the user sees.