So this is taking shape,
we have our input area,
we can add transactions like new shoes for $12.
Now there are a couple of things I want to change though,
for example when I enter my amount here, it would be nice to have a keyboard where we can only enter
numbers and where we can't even enter text here.
In addition, it would be nice that when I hit this button here, this confirm button on my inputs,
I do actually trigger add transaction if a value for title and for amount is provided. And last but not
least, here when I output my amount, it would be nice to always see two digits, not more than that and
not less because right now I can also enter something like this and of course that looks super ugly.
So to fix or to change this, let's first of all go to new_transaction.dart which is where we have these
inputs and to make sure that we can only enter numbers on the second input here and there, you can change
the keyboard type and that takes a text input type which in the end is a class and there you have a
couple of static properties again,
again static properties on classes, that's a bit like enums, just having more complex values than just
numbers
and there you can set this to datetime which is a perfect input if user should enter date, email address
which is great for entering email addresses because the @ sign is easily available and so on.
But here I want number
and with that
if we now save this, if I tap in here, we now get a number keyboard which is of course good. In addition,
to make sure that we also submit our form when we press the done button, we can add the onSubmitted
listener here.
Now I want to do the same as I do down here, so I can of course simply copy that function
but if you find yourself copying a lot of code, it is always a good idea to refactor it into a single
named function which you then can call from all these places
so that when you ever change something in that function,
you don't have to change it in three different places but only in one place.
So let's grab this logic here where we call addTx and let's add a new function here in our new transaction
widget, a new method to be precise.
It will not return anything, I'll name it submit data, the name is up to you though and in there, I will
call addTx and forward the title controller and the parsed amount.
Now down there, I call submit data
therefore or I point at it without parentheses because I don't want to execute it in line, I only want to
pass a pointer at this method so that it is executed when the button is pressed.
However here, onSubmitted actually gives us the value the user entered thus far as a value,
so here we have to use a slightly different syntax, provide an anonymous function where we get that value
and I don't really use it but still I need to accept it
otherwise Flutter will complain.
An alternative would have been to not use an anonymous function here but accept that value up here,
then this would also be fine,
you just need to have a function that in the end reacts to onSubmitted,
that does take that value even if you don't use it
but since I don't plan on using it, the approach I like more is to not take the argument up here but
instead use an anonymous function down there and add a underscore here which is kind of a convention,
not a hard rule but a convention to signal
I get an argument but I don't care about it here,
I have to accept it but I don't plan on using it,
so instead of giving it a more meaningful name, I add an underscore here to indicate
that yes, I don't use it.
So now this is the code I can use for onSubmitted, on all my or on both of my text fields here and
also when the button is pressed down there,
I want to call submit data. Another advantage of not accepting a value in submit data is that here for
the button, I wouldn't get one,
so here I would have had to manually provide one
by calling this with something like this, if we edited submit data to accept a string.
So that's why this approach of not accepting a string in submit data but instead, dumping the value
here is preferable.
So now we submit that whenever one of these buttons is pressed,
of course the button could be pressed before both a title and an amount have been entered.
So what I'll do first is I'll extract that data, entered
title is titleController.text and here I'll have my entered
amount which is amountController.text and I'll do the double conversion right here already, so
double.parse,
I'll call it here, down there
I will therefore just refer to my entered title and then here to the entered amount.
But first of all I want to check whether we do have values in here,
so I'll add if entered
title is empty,
so if the user did not enter anything there or if entered amount is smaller or equal to zero which also
would be invalid,
I also don't want negative amounts, then I'll just return here and if I just return here, then this code
will not execute because return also stops the function execution,
it means the code after return is not reached.
That's also something important,
return stops the function execution,
this code is not reached
if this here is called, so if we make it into the if block, we'll not try to add a new transaction. So
therefore here if I hit add transaction with no values entered,
I actually get an error because I try to convert something to a double which is not convertible
but if I try to for example submit -1 here and I hit add transaction, I don't get an extra error
but we also don't get the transaction,
so stopping this works. The same is true if I enter a valid amount for my amount here but not for my
transaction,
if I hit this done button or add transaction, this also doesn't get added,
so our little dummy validation here works. Now with that little dummy validation added here, we can almost
test this. One mistake I just spotted is, of course here when I use this approach of using an anonymous
function, here inside of the function body, we then have to call submit data like this,
otherwise this will not execute because now this anonymous function is passed as a reference to onSubmitted,
the reference to this anonymous function to be precise, inside of that anonymous function, when it
executes, we have to manually trigger our function. Only here for onPressed where we don't have a wrapping
anonymous function,
we just pass the reference to our own function. And with that if we save that and we go back to our page here,
if I enter something valid here
but let's say I have -10 down there and I hit this button,
you see it doesn't get added but if I enter something valid here and I use this confirm button, it
does get added.
So now we can use this as well
and we have some basic validation in place. Now regarding the output of our prices here,
for that we can go to our transaction list which is where we do output all these transactions and therefore
the transaction amount.
In the end what I want to do here, on amount we can call to string
but I mentioned that we don't have to do that
if we use this interpolation
but there is a special kind of to string, you can use to string as fixed and then define how many decimal
places you want to show,
for example 2 and if you use this, if you use to string as fixed 2, then every value has exactly two
decimal places,
no matter if you only entered one or none or if you possibly entered a lot, then you see this gets rounded.
So this is really convenient to have a nice user interface where we don't have too long numbers or too
short numbers.