So it's username time and for that back in the message bubble, we can make sure that besides outputting
the main message, we also output the user name of the user who wrote the message.
For this.
I'll actually wrap text here into a column because I now want to have another text above it.
So let's add this text and this should now be the username.
So here.
I expect a new property, a string, which is the username, and that should also be passed to the message
bubble as an argument.
So this username should be output here and we can also set some text style here.
And for a start.
Let's simply set the font weight here to font weight.
Bold.
So very simple style that should show the username above the main text.
Now the problem is that at the moment we're not getting this username in messages.
Here we are forwarding the text and the check, whether it's us or not, but we're not forwarding the
username because we don't have the username of the user who created a message.
The only thing we have on Firebase for a given message is the idea of the user.
We got the dummy IDs and we got the real IDs.
Now, actually, to avoid any problems, let's delete all documents with that dummy user ID of a.
So quickly delete those free documents so that they only have documents.
Only have messages by real users.
So that's the second one.
And here's the third one.
Still, we only have two user IDs here, not the user names.
And of course I want to output the real user name here and not the ID.
Having this here in the chat app would probably not be that useful.
Now of course we can use the ID to get the username that belongs to it.
This is certainly something we can do.
And for that, we can forward.
Let's say the user ID here to message bubble as a second argument and in message bubble change that
name to user ID to make it clear that we're actually not getting the user name route right now, but
the user ID.
So now we have the user ID here and in the message bubble, we could now utilize this user ID to fetch
the actual user name.
We could say that we wrap this text here where we want to output the username with a stream builder.
And then we reach out to the users collection and look for the document with that ID.
Now I'll do that, but I'll actually replace Stream Builder here with Future Builder because I don't
want to set up an ongoing stream.
Instead, I'll just want to fetch that username once.
There is no need to set up a live listener.
It's not going to change because we don't even have a functionality to change our username here.
Now, the future here is that we reach out to fire store and for that you need to add the import to
cloud file store.
So we reach out to fires, the word dot incense, and then we reach out to the users collection for
a certain user ID.
So on that collection, I now use document to point at a certain document and I want to point at the
document with that user ID.
Keep in mind that in Firebase we have a user's collection and we have documents where the names or the
IDs indeed are our user IDs.
So we can look for such a document and document on its own does not give us a future yet.
But we can call, get on this and get we'll simply get the data off this document and it will do this
through a future.
Now.
Then we have our builder where we have our data snapshot here, and that snapshot will eventually hold
data about that user.
So here we can, of course, check the snapshot connection state.
And if we're still waiting, so if our connection status waiting, we could return some dummy text where
we say loading something like this.
And once we get the actual data here, we output snapshot data and that will give us access to this
document.
And there it's the username field.
We're interested.
So snapshot data and then this is a map where we access username like this if we do this and we saved
as indeed we see the username here.
Now let's make sure we can also read the text if it's on the x and color background.
So for that I'll set the colour of the user name to the same colour as the message text.
Like this.
And now it is this readable.
And now maybe all the for some alignment to make sure this is not centered like it currently seems to
be.
We can control this on the column with the cross axis alignment.
And the alignment actually should depend on whether it's by us or not.
If it's by us, it should be on the right.
So alignment.
And if it's by the other user, it should be on the left.
So alignment start.
So here on the cross axis alignment of the column, we can check if it's us.
And if it is us, I'll set cross axis alignment and to move it to the right and otherwise cross axis
alignment.
Start to move it to the left.
We now save that this looks pretty good.
Now the text should also be aligned to the right.
So on the message text we can add, text, align and all.
Check if it's me and if it's me, I'll set text align here to end and otherwise text align to start.
And now the message text itself also should be aligned correctly.
So that's good.
Now we see the username, but this approach has a flaw.
And by the way, you don't see it on the left because this is not connected to our development server.
This is an old snapshot of the app which is still running here, but this approach has a flaw here.
And do you know which flaw that is?
The flaw is that I'm fetching that username here in the message bubble.
I'm fetching it with my future builder, which I added here this one.
And that means that for every new message bubble that's being rendered, I reach out to Firebase and
I fetch that data.
This can be good or bad.
This can hammer this API quite a bit.
Now, the good news is, since this isn't a list, it should only fetch the username for the messages
that are actually being rendered.
And in addition, fire store also caches data locally.
So it's not going to make a million requests here probably.
Instead, it should cache data and not send too many requests.
Still, this is not something you might want here.
You maybe don't want to send a new request for every message bubble that's being rendered.
Therefore we could argue that we don't want to fetch this here, but that instead when we create a message.
So when we create a new message here in a new message widget, we want to store the username next to
the user ID so that we already have the username here and we don't need to fetch it again.
This would mean that we only need to fetch it once when we send this message instead of every time when
we render a message and we could even simplify this more.
Theoretically, we could also fetch it once when our application starts up and then store this in some
app wide state or anywhere else, wherever you want.
So you can really optimize this quite a bit if you want to.
Here.
I will fetch it whenever we create a new message.
So for that, I'll.
Get my user data by a waiting for fire store instance.
And then reaching out to the users collection for the document with my user ID here, which I get from
the user I fetched.
And then get and that's the same I did here in the message bubble.
It's the same future.
But now I get this here for the user who is sending a message and all the user data I resolve for which
I wait, I'll be able to get.
That user name because that is that user document in the user's collection.
And now the username is also being stored in every new message which we store in our store.
Now that means that when we fetch all messages here in the messages widget with the Stream Builder,
those messages will already include the user names which are fetched because they will be part of the
messages themselves.
So that means that now we can just forward username here.
To our message bubble because we add such a username field here when we send a message and therefore
in the message bubble I can rename this back to username also here and we can assume that this already
is the final username.
So now in the message bubble we can get rid of that future builder here.
Can get rid of all of that.
And instead we just have our text here.
Just like this and we don't have snapshot data.
Username.
But we use the username property which we now have in the message bubble.
Now, of course, this won't work with our existing messages, which is why I'm getting an error here,
because all those existing chat messages don't have the username field.
That's well, delete this entire chat collection so that it's going to be recreated.
Let's restart the app now.
And let's now send a message test.
And also send one here.
And of course, from the left device, I'm still getting an error because I'm running an old version
of the app here, so that version doesn't attach the username yet.
So I'm quickly going to do this manually.
Here in the chat collection.
On that document which doesn't have the username field.
I will manually add this field for now to fix this error and set this to Maximilian.
For example.
Added Reload the app and you see that this now works correctly.
So that works.
We're going to run a more recent version of the app on Android soon, too.
And with that, we should have a relatively efficient way of storing and fetching the username and displaying
the username.
Now later we'll all show an image of the user, but for the moment, this is good enough.
This is fine like that.
So with all of that, we got that finished chat functionality.
We can send messages, we can receive messages.
This list is updating.
Whenever we get a new message, we got our authentication in place.
I would say it is now time to move on to image upload with the Firebase Cloud Storage.