So we got our basic chat going on.
We see the usernames.
Now how about some user images?
It would be nice if, besides the username, we would also see some image of the user who sent a message.
And for that, we of course, need a way of adding a profile picture, to be precise, during the signup
process here.
Besides providing a username, it would be great if we would also have to provide an image.
So that's what I'm going to work on right now for this.
Let's go back to the off screen or to the form, to be precise.
And in that off form, we now also want to fetch an image if the user is signing up.
Of course not during login, but only during sign up.
So for that, maybe at the very top of this entire column, which I have here, in the form, we can
add a new widget and that new widget could be the the image preview which you want to use.
And there's a specific widget that could be helpful here, and that's the Circle Avatar.
We can add this on top of the email text from Field, and this gives us such a nice circle here in which
we later can preview the image.
Now it's a bit small, but we can set the radius here to change that and set it to a double.
And if we set this to 30, you see this is already getting bigger and you can play around with that
value.
I'll go with 40 here, I think.
Let me save that.
Yeah, that looks nice to me.
And there I want to preview the image of the user.
Now, of course, the user also needs a way of taking and setting that image, and therefore we need
a button below that circle avatar.
And you can, of course, go for different buttons here.
I'll go for a flat button where I want to combine text and a camera icon.
And there is a special constructor of this flat button which we can use for this, the dot icon constructor.
This generates a flat button that has both some text as well as an icon.
So here on press, I'll just provide a dummy function right now, and for the icon, I'll set an icon.
And there we can use the image icon, for example.
And for the label we can specify a text widget and set this to.
Add image or any text you want.
Now on this flat button, we can then also set the text color.
Whoops, the text.
Color to theme.
Off context.
Primary color.
And with all that added, you should have this nice add image button below this circular avatar.
Now, of course, we need to hook this button up so that when we click it, we actually do allow the
user to take or pick an image.
And for this, we can use the good old image picker package, which we can use for flutter.
This is very straightforward to use.
We just need to go to installing here, grab this dependency and add this to our back to the YAML file.
So in there below firebase off, I'll add the image picker.
And this will then, of course, automatically download this package and add it to our project.
Now, regarding extra setup steps, there's nothing you need to do on Android, but there are some extra
steps you want to do on iOS.
You want to add these three strings or items to your info list.
And for that, if you are building for iOS, you should go to the iOS folder.
Then to the runner folder and they are in info list.
Make sure that you do have those items and I currently don't have them here.
So I'll grab this nice photo library usage description.
And we can simply add this here at the bottom and add a key field opening and closing.
And between the opening and closing key, you add this identifier and below that you just add a string
field like this.
And between the string tags, you now put the options which belong to this description, and that is
the text that will be shown to the user if your app wants access to the photo library.
We need access to lets you pick an image, something like this.
Now we can replicate this twice so that we have three items because we also need the NFS camera.
Use such description where I will show the same message and the microphone.
We shouldn't need this here, but to avoid errors we can also add it.
But since we're not going to access the microphone, you might not need this depending on what you do
in your app.
So now with these keys added here, we should now be fine.
And we should now have all the setup.
We need to use the image picker so we can then go back to the off form and make sure that we do pick
an image if this button is pressed.
Now to keep this off forum, Leon, I will actually grab this circle, avatar and the flat button,
though.
Cut it from there and add a new widget.
And I'll add it in a picker's subfolder.
And in there I'm going to create a user underscore image, underscore picker, dot dot file, which
holds a stateful widget.
Stateful because this widget will actually need to update some state since we're going to manage a preview
of the image the user chose and we'll need to store that chosen image and then re render the UI to show
a preview.
So here I have my user image picker widget and I import material dot dot of course.
And now in there I want to render these two widgets which I cut.
Now, rendering them side by side.
Like this won't work though, so I'll wrap them in an extra column which has some children into.
Some children are my circle avatar and my flat button.
And now we can use this user image picker in the form and therefore the auth form stays lean.
So here I just have my user image picker like this.
And of course in order to use the user image picker here, you also need to add this import.
So with that we have the same UI as before, but now we have a separate component that manages the image
picking process, and that is always a good practice.
So now here with that, with that image picker component, we want to make sure that when this flat
button is pressed, we do open up that image picker that allows the user to use the camera or to use
the image library.
Produce.
I'll add a new function here.
Pic image.
And on the image picker package, we also see how this works, how this package works, and that picking
an image is as easy as calling pick image on this image picker object, which we get from that image
picker library, we add it.
So therefore we need to add this import here as well.
Import this image.
Picker start file from the image picker package.
And then here in pick image, we can call image picker dot pick image.
Like this.
And now we need to wire up pig image, of course, to the Spartans.
So here on Presque Isle Point at pig image without parentheses, so that this function, this method
gets executed whenever a user presses this button.
Now we can define the source here, the image source, and here we get the image source enum which actually
allows us to specify the source.
And here we can choose whether we want to use the camera or the gallery for taking that image.
Now, if you would want to allow the user to go for either of the two, you could also open up a separate
dialog before you call pick image.
And in that separate dialog you could get that user choice.
Now I will simply assume that we always want to use the camera here, let's say.
But of course that is totally up to you and what you want to build in your application.
So now here we call pick image and this should open up the camera.
Now pick image then returns a future which resolves to depict file.
So here, I'll turn this into a async function so that we can conveniently await this future and in
the end get depict image file here and store this in this constant in this variable here.
And it's this pict image file which we then can use to show a preview for that.
Here in this state, we just need to add a new variable which will be of type file and that's the PICT
image.
Underscore picked image actually.
And file is a type which you need to import.
From Dart io.
So you can add this dart io import here and this will unlock this file type.
And then this is the pict image.
And here we can therefore then call set state and set pict image equal to this pict image file we got
from our future here and that stores depict image file in this pict image property.
And it's this property which we now can use to show the preview because of course we have access to
that property down there in our widget tree and it's here in this circle avatar where you can now actually
set a background image to, well, show a image in this avatar.
And this background image argument here should be of type image provider.
And there are various providers in flutter.
There are providers for images that come from the web.
So where you have a link to the image, but there also is a file image provider and file image simply
takes the file which holds the image and will then basically create a connection and load that image.
So here we just pass in our pict image and that should do the trick.
With that we should be able to open the camera, save, depict image and show it as a preview here in
the circle.
Avatar.
Now, you see, when I save this, I get an error though, because initially, of course, my file here
is null.
The Pict image initially is not set.
So therefore here background image actually initially shouldn't be set to anything.
I will rather check if pict image is not null and only if it is not null.
I'll set it to this file image.
Otherwise I will set background image as a whole to null so I will not pass null to file image.
This would cause this error, but instead I only load file image for this image if we have it and otherwise
set the entire background image argument here to null.
And with that it now saves and reloads without errors.
And we have this empty preview here and you could set a different background color if you wanted to.
We can do this in a second and now choose an image.
And as you can tell, nothing happens here when I click this button.
But instead I get an error here.
I get the error that.
The plug in is missing in the end and we know it is error.
We can fix it by closing this emulator and simply restarting it entirely.
If you add a brand new package, you often have to do this to make sure that the package is loaded correctly.
So let's restart it entirely.
And let's then try again.
And now it looks better.
It opens up this camera simulator on my emulator and we can take a picture here, save this, and we
see it here as a preview.
Now, if you're trying this on iOS, you won't be able to do this on the emulator there.
You would need to test it on a real device, and we'll do that in a second as well once we added the
upload functionality.
So here's my image.
Now I will set a different background color here for the case that we don't have an image yet and background
color simply, well, once a value of type color and here I will just use this gray color as a default
so that if we save this.
And they reload this app.
So we have no pict image.
We start with this gray color, but then we can pick an image.
Confirmed us and now we have our image.
So that's great.
We're able to pick an image now.
Now, one problem we have here is that, of course, I only want to be able to pick an image if we're
signing up, not if we're logging in.
And currently this is showing up on the login screen here.
Now, fixing this is easy.
However, on the off form we just need to make sure that just like the username field, for example,
this user image picker is only getting added if we're not in login mode.
And for this we can use this in error if statement where we check if we're not in logging mode.
So if is log in is false and only then this user image picker will be added.
So if we do that, you see there is no image picker here and only if I create a new account that's there.
And then, of course, I can pick that image and it should work just fine.
And of course, we also, thanks to the scroll ability we added earlier, can add our our fields.
So this is not working.
That's step number one.
Step number two is that this image should get uploaded.
Of course.