So what's up with TextAlign.center and EdgeInsets.all? These are certain Dart features, not Flutter
specific and they're not exactly the same.
This here is a special constructor, EdgeInsets has multiple constructors and you can see them here
if you add a dot after the class type, so without parentheses, then you see all these constructors here.
Now these features exist to allow you to create an object in different variants.
Now it can always be nice to look into the raw source code to understand what's going on and you can
always do that by holding command on MacOS or control on Windows and then you hover over the thing
you want to learn more about and it now turns into a link which you can click and if you do click it,
you're taken to the framework code. We see that enum
I was talking about, you create it with the enum keyword here as you can see and we'll do that manually,
later we'll create our own enums, for the moment let's basically ignore that, these are just different
options we have for alignment here which are then picked up by Flutter once we assigned a value to align
our text per the option we chose here.
What's more helpful is diving into EdgeInsets here.
So if we dive into this, we now see it's a class that extends EdgeInsetsGeometry, which is interesting
because you might remember that if you hover over margin,
this takes EdgeInsetsGeometry value,
So it's good that EdgeInsets extends this,
this means that if we instantiate EdgeInsets, we automatically get an object of type EdgeInsetsGeometry
because if you extend, if you have a class that extends another class, that class that does extend always
has its own type as well as the type of the class it did extend, that's also a default behavior of Dart.
Now in here, we see that there are a couple of special constructors here,
we repeat the class name, which always means it's an instructor
but then instead of directly adding parentheses thereafter, we add dot some name and that is a Dart feature
which allows you to define multiple constructors per class.
Now without diving too much into the internals here, in the end that just means that each constructor
creates a new instance of this class but with different configurations, with different settings and that
all is just done to make it easy for you to create different EdgeInsets, which is basically a settings
container setting up spaces. Setting up different EdgeInsets containers with different configurations
with these utility functions here, with these utility constructors. If I go back to DartPad, we could
have created that for person as well, we could have added our own constructor by adding the name and
then dot and then any name of your choice, for example veryOld and in there, we could have accepted
the name and then said that this constructor by default sets age equal to 60.
So here, we can't set the age in the constructor, it's always set to 60 and
we can only set the name.
Now this would be a helpful constructor if we wanted to create a person, p3
that always is 60 where we only want to set the name.
So we could use the veryOld constructor and set this to Max again,
so my name again and now if I print p3.name and I then also print p3.age, if I run this
now, you will see that here we actually get Max and then 60 being printed and that is the output for
our p3 object.
So these special or these extra constructors are really just there to give you the same type of object
you would get with the normal constructor but with some predefined settings, some different behaviour
they run inside of the constructor.