That's happening because when you have an item here in favorites like this schnitzel,
and you then go into the detail page and you now uncheck this as a favorite,
if you now go back, you go back to basically a cached version of that page.
This was not reached by the rebuild of the Flutter apps so to say because it was cached away. Only if
you go to a different page and then come back, Flutter recreates that page and now updates this based
on the most recent state where this indeed isn't favorite anymore.
Now what can we do to avoid showing outdated data on our favoritesScreen therefore? For the moment,
this is the way it is and there's no super simple or clean way of solving this,
however it will be super clean and easy to solve once we have learned more about state management which
will generally help us with managing global data, like we're managing it here in our main.dart file. When
we use the main.dart file for managing that, we run into problems like this and we also have the problem
of always rebuilding the entire app with every change.
These are all problems that will be solved with a better state management tool, which is why we'll have
a look at such a tool in the next course
section. Dirty fixes which you could apply right now would for example be that you turn your favoritesScreen
into a stateful widget, you handle the pushing of a meal item here in that favorites screen widget
instead of the meal item widget,
so you would have to have a function here and pass a handle to that function, to meal item and then with
the then listener on your push or pushNamed call, you could run some code when that recipe detail page
we're on that meal detail page is popped off and in that code you then run, since this would be a stateful
widget here,
you could call set state with no content in it to force an update of this screen but this would be a
really dirty work around which is why I won't cover it here,
instead we'll learn about a way cleaner approach in the next section.
This section here however now is done and you learned a lot about navigation, passing data back and forth
and as a side note, about building a beautiful application.