So for iOS setup, we can go back to the Firebase messaging package page and there you got the iOS integration
steps.
Now it looks short, but actually you've got a few steps that you need to perform here.
For example, you need to generate certificates required by Apple for receiving push notifications.
Again, for that ID part where you're basically telling Apple, Hey, that's me, I am the creator of
the app and here is my proof.
Now you can follow this guide, as you can see, to configure that.
And that takes us to the official Firebase Cloud Messaging Docs.
Now here you should go through the first two steps, but you can skip the create the provisioning profile
step, as is also mentioned here.
So let's go through the obvious steps then.
And the first step is that we create an authentication key.
For that, we need to have an Apple developer account and log into that so you can search for apple
developer or apple developer account and find their apple developer page and log in there with your
apple ID.
Now, once you did, log in.
You should go to certificates, identifiers and profiles and under the keys, select all.
As you can tell.
Let's go there.
Go to keys and there's simply click on plus that all part is not required for me.
At least here I can just click on plus to create a new key.
Now I did that, therefore.
And now we should enter a description for the aprns off key.
And under a key services, select the APN checkbox and click continue.
So here in the end we want to check this Apms checkbox, which basically says that we want to generate
a key which we can use to send push notifications and we should give this a name like flutter chat example,
something like this.
And once you did all of that, you can click, confirm and then download and then save this key in a
secure place because that will be a key which we will soon provide through Firebase Cloud messaging
to Apple for every message we want to send to send that message.
So anyone with that key could cause harm to your application and could abuse it.
So store it in a secure place.
Don't just put it onto your desktop, don't upload it to a GitHub repository, store it in a place where
only you have access to.
Also note that it's a one time download and you can't retrieve the key later, so make sure you don't
lose it.
So let's click on Continue Here Register.
And here we get the same warning that we can only download in once.
So let me now download this key and I'm storing this in some folder on my system now where no one else
has access to.
So that's the key download it.
The next step now is that we create an app ID, so that is basically an identifier that uniquely identifies
our application.
And there we use this reverse domain notation here, which we also use for our bundle identifier.
For that, go to the Apple Developer Member Center and login.
You should already be logged in by now and then click on certificates, identifiers and profiles.
So where we just were essentially.
And in their.
Navigate to identifiers, app IDs.
So identifiers.
And then here we got app IDs, as you can tell.
And we want to add a new identifier here.
So the plus button was clicked.
Now that new app ID has a name.
Which is basically a human readable name and a team ID.
So let's generate this app ID here.
Continue.
Give it your description.
Like flutter.
Chat example your team ID should already be selected here and now choose a bundle ID here and choose
explicit as it also says here and then input your bundle ID which you also have in your application.
And that's important.
It has to be the same one.
So in your iOS runner folder you have the info list file, and in there that bundle ID is inserted by
flutter in the end.
Now, if you're not sure what your actual ID is, therefore you can simply open your project in Xcode.
So that iOS folder of your Flutter project in Xcode and they are under general.
It's this bundle identifier I'm talking about.
Grab this bundle identifier.
Now important before you continue.
You should scroll down here and check push notifications to make it clear that this app intends to use
push notifications.
That's also what you find here in the docs that you should check push notifications.
Thereafter, we can continue and verify our inputs.
And Click Register.
Now as mentioned, you can skip the create provisioning profile part here.
All the worth a note.
Of course, your bundle identifier should be one that's not already taken.
For example, I changed mine to calm academy in the latter complete guide academy and is my company
because com example flatter complete guide was already taken.
If that happens for you, you have to change it here to something unique.
So to your company name and then sub identifier for example, and then all the re add your project on
firebase.
So remove your existing iOS project here and read it as shown at the beginning of the module.
It's super simple and not the end of the world, so once all of that is done, we can skip that, create
the provisioning profile step, and therefore now we're done with step one here in the iOS integration.
No worries.
The other steps will be faster.
For example, we already finished.
Step two, we linked our project to Firebase already, so we don't need to do this again.
Now, here in Xcode, we now need to configure something though.
We need to select Runner in the project navigator and then in the Capabilities tab.
We should turn on push notifications and background modes and enable background fetch and remote notifications.
So here in Xcode, click on Runner and under signing and capabilities, click on plus capability and
choose push notifications here.
Double click on it.
Now all to click on that again.
And choose background modes and.
On background modes.
Then enable remote notifications and background fetch.
These are the two things you should enable here.
Next, let's follow the steps here under upload your app and certificate in the Firebase Docs.
This is required because the Firebase Cloud Messaging Service in the end just talks to Apple's push
notification service.
And therefore, we need to make sure that FCM Firebase Cloud Messaging is able to talk to those servers
and is able to provide our ID criteria.
So our key to those servers.
So we already set up our iOS client.
We already added Firebase to our iOS project.
We registered our app with Firebase, so that all happened.
Hence now our next step is that we upload our API and S authentication key.
So that key we generated a few minutes ago.
And for that, go to your Firebase console and under project settings, go to cloud messaging.
So here.
Click on project settings on that gear icon and then project settings and then go to the cloud messaging
tab and scroll down to your iOS app configuration.
And there you need that app.
And as off key click on upload here.
Well to upload it and browse for that key file you downloaded a few minutes ago.
So here is my key and I will open it here.
And then in order to upload it, you need to enter your key ID and your team ID.
Now you'll find both under certificates, identifiers and profiles.
Here is the key ID, which of course is different for you, but you can grab it from that page.
This was not deleted after your download, so you can still access this and your team ID.
This is the ID you'll find here in the top right corner.
So insert both here and click on upload and it should store your key here.
So that were the steps two and three here in that documentation we're currently going through.
Now we need to initialize Firebase in our app, but that's something we can skip because we're using
the Firebase Flutter sticks.
We can skip all of that, and we can also skip that entire part for handling the messages because we're
going to do all of that with help of that flutter package here.
Indeed, as it says here, we just needed to upload our APIs certificate.
Only that part need to be completed and that is that part we just had a look at.
So therefore we're done with step four.
We can ignore step five here.
And with that, we're therefore done with the iOS setup here, though now we also need to do something
in our flutter code because whilst we are able to just start sending messages on Android and we didn't
need any flutter code, that's not the case here for iOS.
We need to request permissions first and therefore we need to write some code to do that before we'll
be able to send notifications to our iOS device and see them there.
So to do that, let's pick a good place and I will just go for, let's say, the chat screen.
I could ask on the main dart file, but if a user hasn't even logged in, it doesn't make much sense
to start sending messages to that user.
So instead here in the chat screen, I want to ask the user whether he's fine with me sending push notifications
to him or her.
Now to ask for permissions, I will convert chat screen here to a state full widget simply because now
I have this extra lifecycle hook which I can use here the init state function.
So here we can now write our own extra code and that's where I want to ask for permission.
So that will ask whenever this comes up, whenever that opens up.
For that, let's import this package, which we added earlier, the Firebase messaging package, and
there the Firebase messaging dart file.
And in in its state here we can now access firebase messaging.
And instantiated like this.
There is no instance property as on the other firebase flutter packages here we have to instantiate
it like this.
And we can store this in a variable or in a constant to be precise.
I'll name it FPM for firebase messaging and on FPM we can now call request notification permissions.
Now on Android, this will do nothing, but on iOS it will well ask for permission.
And thereafter in the next line I call FPM configure.
Now let's save this and let's rerun this updated app here on the real iOS device, because as mentioned
earlier, you need a real iOS device to test and use push notifications.
So here is the app running on my real iOS device, and I will now switch to a different app so that
the main app is not in the foreground anymore.
And now let's try sending a message for that here in the cloud messaging area.
All duplicate my last notification here this test notification and under target.
I will now also target another app.
I will also target that iOS app here.
Click on next, click on next and click on review.
Now don't publish it yet because at the moment this would not work.
I could send it.
But actually keep in mind that we need to grant our permission first.
That's while actually switched back to my Flutter app and instead log in real quick so that I reach
this chat screen where I am being asked for permission.
Here I am.
Now I will grant this permission and now I will switch away to a different app.
So now with the permission grant that we can click publish here.
And I do get this push notification here.
Does this work?
This now is one of the notifications I have here, and if I tap on it, it opens up the Flutter chat
app.
So this is how we can send push notifications with help of the Firebase Cloud Messaging SDK and Service
to flutter apps both on Android and iOS.
Now let's see how we can handle those messages inside of the app.