So we get the Firebase Admin and the Firebase Functions package available here in this Functions folder
for our JavaScript code to interact with.
So this is now really all just JavaScript world has nothing to do with Flutter because this function's
code will later run on one of Firebase servers so that in the end we can run some code there when something
changes in the database, for example.
So how could this function now look like if we dive into the official Firebase stocks, which is always
a great idea for that.
So if you search for Firebase Cloud functions.
You find, of course, plenty of documentation.
And what you will find here under trigger background functions is that you can use cloud fire store
triggers so that you can basically run a function as a response to some event that happened in your
cloud file store database.
And as you can see, there are other triggers as well.
You could also run a function because some file was uploaded, for example, with cloud storage triggers.
But I care about a function that I want to run because something changed in the database and here we
got four triggers on create an update on delete and on right on right runs whenever on create on update
or delete is triggered well, and our trigger is only run for the respective operation since I want
to run some code whenever a new message is stored.
So whenever a new message was sent, I'm interested in the on create trigger and you can see how that
works in the examples below.
In the end, we need to import this Firebase functions package into our code file with this line of
code.
This is already happening here at the very top and there after we need to export such a function here
which is set up with functions dot fire store.
Then dot document and then a path to the document to which you want to listen.
So where you want to listen to the creative end and then on write or in our case on create.
So I will copy this code here and move it here into my function code.
Like this and replace this with on create.
And here the path is a different one.
I'm interested in the chat collection, but there in any message now you can name this however you want,
but you need the curly braces to signal to Firebase that this is a placeholder, that you don't know
the exact document ID, but that instead you care about any document in there.
So whenever a new document is added, no matter which I did, has this on create function should run.
That is what we're writing here.
And that means that, well, whenever something new is added in our chat collection, whenever a new
document is added here, so whenever a new message is added, our function will run.
So maybe to see how that works, let's just console.log, which is the JavaScript equivalent to print
in flutter.
Let's just console.log the data we're getting upon this event and the data we are getting.
Is the scribe down there.
You can get the data after the operation completed.
So after the creation of the document finished with change after data.
As you can learn here.
And this is all just JavaScript code.
In case you're wondering what it is.
As you can see, it's not too far away from flutter, but for example, const works differently, so
don't be confused about that.
It's all JavaScript code here.
So I'm interested in the data after the write finished.
So I will copy this change that after dot data function call here.
And log the result here with console log.
So I have passed a value that is returned by calling data to console log so that we can output it here.
So now that we finished writing this function, we have to deploy it, which means we have to upload
it to Firebase servers because it's not going to run on our local machine.
It's going to run on Firebase servers.
So here in your project where you previously ran Firebase in it, now run, Firebase, deploy, and
this will take your function and upload it and initialize it to and on Firebase servers.
So you can see this process here.
It can take a couple of seconds.
And it will let you know once it's finished.
Now, what you actually see is that I'm getting an error here of 403 unknown error.
Now, 403.
Looks like I was denied access.
So you can try running firebase log in if you're getting this.
And thereafter I reran firebase deploy.
And now this looks better.
Looks like it's being uploaded.
And with the deploy complete message, it gets what completed.
So now our function is running on Firebase servers.
And now whenever we have a new message in the database, the function should trigger there.
Now, to monitor our function and its output in our Firebase Web console, we can go back to functions.
And reload this page.
And you should see your function here.
If you don't see it immediately, wait a few minutes and then try reloading.
So that should be your function.
And you can also view the logs of this function to see what's going on there.
Now, as always, by the way, when you're working with Firebase Features, check their pricing.
For example, here in the case of cloud functions, you got a certain free tier, a certain free usage
amount, and if you exceed that, you would be charged.
So make sure you check that.
So here we see some logs from this function now and now let's see if something changes there.
If I send a new message, does this work?
If I send this message, it shows up here, of course, and it should show up in our database there.
If we have a look at the chat collection, we should see this does this work message here?
And what about our function?
Now the logs can always take some time until they update.
So you might want to reload, wait a bit and come back at a later point of time.
But eventually you should see something here.
And I actually do see something I see an error cannot read property data of undefined so our function
executed but something went wrong there.
We were not able to retrieve some data here, so it looks like calling data on change after did not
work.
Now.
This was simply a little mistake from my side in the on create case.
We actually don't have to do this change after thing.
Instead we get a snapshot of the data anyways so we can just call snapshot.
DOT data.
As you can see here, I was in the on update case where you, of course have two states before and after
the update.
But if you create something, you just have to snapshot.
So I decided to leave this in because this is easy to overlook.
And therefore now if we access the snapshot here, we should be able to really get the data we're interested
in.
So just to double check this, let's redeploy this.
Whenever you make a change locally, you have to redeploy.
So let's redeploy this and let's now validate this again.
So let's wait for the redeployment to finish.
And now that it finished, let me send another message.
Like that.
And let's then go back to our logs here.
And again, you might want to reload here, wait a little bit.
Reload again until the new log shows up here.
And eventually you should get your data.
Now, we still have a warning here or an error.
We'll take care about this later.
But what we see here is this piece of data.
So we see that's the data we got and that's exactly the data that was stored in the database.
So we get our username here, we get the text that is pretty cool.
And that's the data which I now want to send as part of my notification.
Now one extra note.
We also see that we got an error that the function returned undefined and that it should return a value
or a promise.
Instead, a promise is essentially the same as a future in Dart.
So in JavaScript that's called a promise and our function does never.
Now that's not a huge problem.
We can simply return anything here at the moment.
This will soon change anyways, because now of course I don't want to return anything.
Instead now I want to send my message and for this we'll use that Firebase Admin SDK, which we also
have.