So in this module, we built our first little application.
Now as I said, of course we can certainly build more beautiful applications
and that is something we will of course do throughout this course.
No worries, we'll dive a lot into how you can style and layout your apps, how you can change colors, how
you can adjust all these widgets to your needs and preferences.
What we did in this module though is we covered a lot of important things,
we covered what widgets are, that there are stateful and stateless widgets, that you typically use
more stateless than stateful widgets and that they are both important and how they split work.
You learned how to work with built-in widgets and where to find them in the official widget catalog,
that you can also build your own widgets that actually compose more complex user interface building
blocks from these Flutter primitives you get, from these core basic widgets Flutter gives you. You
learned how to manage some data, how to pass it around as arguments to constructors and you also learned
a lot about Dart and some of its core fundamentals.
If you haven't done it already,
definitely dive into the attached resources and text lectures which you'll also find in this module,
also in the attachments to the last lecture of this module, especially also to compare code because
this will then allow you to dive deeper into certain things you struggled with or which might not be
entirely clear yet. With all these resources, you should have a first understanding of what Flutter is,
how it works and how you work with it and how you build widgets.
Now we'll of course continue doing that throughout the course and dive even deeper into other features and other
things you can do with Dart and Flutter.
So let's move on.