So now that the application is finished and all the features are integrated, it's time for some final
polishing.
For example, there's one mistake I made in the chat screen dart file.
Super in its state should go to the beginning of that function.
To the beginning of that method.
I should say.
It's not super bad.
As you saw, everything works.
But it is a better practice to call this first, so make sure to put super in it state at the beginning
in every in its state method you might have.
So that's the first thing.
Now, in addition here on the chat screen, it's hard to see here, but you might see it in your local
app.
There is a little gray bar at the bottom of this dropdown button here.
Now, if I go to the chat screen there, I have this dropdown button.
There is an underline option and underlined argument which we can set.
And you might think that this takes a number to define the width of the line at the bottom, but actually
it wants a widget that will be rendered as a underline, and you see that by default that's a 0.0 width
bottom border with in the end, grayish color.
Now, even though it has this width, it seems like we're seeing it here.
So let's try setting this to an empty container.
If a now safe test, this is entirely gone.
So now we don't have this ugly border anymore.
So that's another fix that makes sense here.
Now, if we do log out, we also get some issues or some potential improvements here on this.
Log in or sign up for them.
So let's go to that off form here.
The the form generally works, but these text fields could be configured a bit differently, for example,
on the email field here.
I'm not too happy with how it behaves with a real keyboard.
To be precise, I want to turn off autocorrect here.
I always find this annoying on email addresses when it tries to fix what you entered.
I always want to control the text capitalization, which means how it tries to turn certain characters
to uppercase characters.
And there I want to set this to text capitalization non, which means it's not going to capitalize anything.
And with enable suggestions faults.
I'll also turn off any suggestions here because I also find this annoying on email addresses.
Now on the user name here, that's a bit different there.
I want auto correction, I want capitalization on a word level so that words are capitalized, let's
say.
And I still don't want suggestions though.
And of course you can pick different settings, but these are the settings I'm going to choose.
Now for the password.
Everything seemed to work correctly for me, so I won't change anything there.
Now with that, let me log in real quick here.
And all to work on that message field down there, because by default this will only produce lowercase
words.
So we'll go to that chat screen now to the new message widget.
I mean, and there we have that text field.
And on that text field, all set.
Text capitalization to text capitalization.
Let's say.
Sentences, I'll turn on auto corrections.
And I will also turn on the suggestions.
So enable suggestions set to true.
And with that, if that rebuilds and I reload this app, if I tap into this again, you'll see.
Now it starts with a capital character and then I can type and only if I end a sentence.
It starts with a new capital character, so that looks better to me as well.
And then there is one last thing which is hard to see.
If you restart the app entirely.
So if I kill this here.
And I restart the app.
We briefly see the login screen before we are forwarded to the chat screen and the reason for that simply
is that the Firebase authentication package needs a couple of milliseconds to find out whether we have
a valid token or not.
So of course, that's also not ideal.
And therefore I add a new screen, I'll add a splash screen, which is essentially a loading screen
I want to show whilst the authentication package is figuring out what's going on.
So that can be a simple stateless widget which will name splash screen and where we need to import material
to start.
And here I simply want to render a scaffold so that we have a nice background and so on, where as a
body I simply have some centered text, let's say, so simply some centered text where we say loading.
And of course you could also show a loading spinner instead or do whatever you want.
You can show whatever you want here and now.
The idea is that we can show this splash screen instead of the chat or off screen if we don't know yet
if the user is authenticated.
So we can simply go to Main Dart.
And here before we check whether we have data, we can check on our user snapshot if the connection
state is equal to connection state waiting, which means we're still figuring out whether the user is
authenticated or not.
And if it is waiting, we just return the splash screen here.
And of course, for that you need to import the splash screen into that main dart file.
So now with that, I'm going to rerun this application.
And kill it first.
And now when it launches this application here, we hopefully now see the splash screen instead of the
flickering off screen.
So let's see what we get here.
And that looks better to me.
There was the loading text for a fraction of a second before we were forwarded here.
Now, I think another tiny improvement is that on the splash screen on this scaffold, we may be able
to set the background color to our main theme color, to our primary color, so that we have like this
pinkish background color there as well.
So if I now kill this.
And rebuild and rerun this year.
We should now see that this splash screen actually has this pinkish background color.
Now, that will not be our main application start up launch screen.
I show how to configure that in the deployment section.
This really is just the in app screen which is shown whilst we are waiting for the Firebase off package
to figure out if the user is authenticated or not.
So that's something different.
Yeah.
And you can find you this however you want.
But I would say with that we got all those improvements in place that really make this a great app with
a lot of nice features.