The application is really taking shape,
besides some styling or layout things like that keyboard thing here or maybe on different device sizes
where we might want to change the look and feel of our app a little bit,
besides that, the app is really looking and working good and decent
and the missing feature I want to add here is a feature that allows us to delete transactions. For that,
LEt's go to our ListTile here in the transaction_list.dart file and there on the ListTile,
I did mention that on the ListTile, you can add a trailing widget as well. So if you add trailing here,
you can add a widget there which you want to show at the end of the ListTile and the trailing widget
I want to show here is an icon button with an icon of
delete, which is a trashcan trash icon.
So I'm creating that
icon button because when we press this button, the element on which we triggered it should be removed.
I'll give this a color, that icon and the color here will be received or taken from my theme and there,
I'll take the error color.
Now we haven't set the error color and of course you could do that in your theme, there in the main.dart
file, besides setting a primary swatch and accent color, you can also set an error color but the
default here is red already, so you don't need to set that but you could if you wanted to and especially
if you want a different color than red of course
and then onPressed, I of course want to trigger a method that removes that element. Now for the moment,
let's do nothing so that we can see whether it's displayed and that's looking good,
we have that
icon here, we can press it,
so let's now also make sure that when we press it, we do delete this transaction. Since we managed the
transactions in main.dart, here in our MyHomePage state class where we also have the add new transaction
method,
this is also where we should have the delete transaction method.
So let's add delete transaction here, doesn't need to return anything because the place where we call
it doesn't really need a return value
and now the question of course is, how can we delete a transaction? How do we identify a transaction?
Now of course you could identify a transaction by its name, by its title
but the problem is the title here is not necessarily unique,
so is the amount and the date, all of that could be duplicated.
We could have the same transaction twice on the same day with the exact same amount,
that would be valid.
So rather than doing it like this and trying to delete the transaction by name, we can use another trait
of our transaction. If we have a look at the model, we see that we have an ID there and the ID should
be unique
and indeed, it is, at least almost, of course in our app here in the main.dart file when we create a new
transaction, we do generate the ID based on the current timestamp
and in theory, we could have the same transaction added twice at the exact same time
but in reality in this app that won't really happen.
So it's a good enough ID for now and therefore we can use this ID as an identifier.
So when this method here gets called, delete transaction, I expect to get that ID as an argument by
whoever is calling that,
so whoever calls this method needs to provide the ID of the transaction that should be deleted
and then in here, we can delete this transaction by that ID.
For that, we will call set state because we certainly will need to rebuild our UI thereafter and inside
of that function you pass to set state, we can reach out to our user transactions, to our list of transactions
and there as you learned,
since this is a list, we have multiple methods that allow you to manipulate that list and generate a
new list
and I want to use remove where. This manipulates the existing list, just like add manipulates the existing
list and it removes an item where a certain condition is met.
Therefore we parse in a function and that function gets the element, each element of the list because
this runs this function on every element in the list
just like where did, so we get our transaction in here
and we have to return true if it is the element we want to remove
and that of course is the case if the ID of the element I'm looking at is the same ID as I'm getting
here.
So if tx.id is equal to ID, then I know this is the element I want to get rid of
and since we only have one expression here which value we return, you could also use the shortcut of
using that arrow without the curly braces and without the return statement and use this inline notation,
also without the semicolon and have this shorter syntax here, that's optional but you can use it here
because we have only one expression and we want to return the value and use that value of that expression.
So this allows us to remove an item with that ID,
now we need to call delete transaction and that happens from inside the transaction list.
So let's pass delete transaction to the transaction list
now here as a second argument maybe
and of course we now need to tweak the constructor of transaction list
now to accept that.
So here I now expect to get a function, delete tx, whatever you want to name it and I bind the second
argument I'm getting to this delete tx property here in the transaction list widget. And now delete
tx is a pointer at that delete function,
so in our transaction list we can now use it here
on that icon button to trigger that deletion.
Now important, binding it like this won't work because delete tx actually points at our delete transaction
method here and that requires an argument,
the ID of the transaction that should be deleted. The onPressed method by default doesn't pass any arguments,
so we would be missing that argument which we need. The solution is to wrap this into an anonymous function
so that we pass a reference to this function, to this anonymous function, to onPressed
and then when this anonymous function is executed in there,
we have our own function which we call and there we can now pass our own argument and the argument I
want to pass here is my transaction ID, so I can use transactions and then for the given index.id
and forward that. With that, let's give it a try.
Let's save it all and
let's try deleting the new shoes here and that works and you see the chart also updates.
So now, we have a set up where we can not only add transactions but where we can also delete them.