[Autogenerated] now will make some changes to the serverless
template file to ensure that your serverless application has
the right permissions that it needs.
As you've experienced before this AP,
I needs to be able to access the systems manager to read the
parameter store and it needs access to the VPC where the rds
instance and her database live.
That means the serverless application needs to have a few more sets.
Permissions weaken.
Tie the application to some of the standard policies in
AWS notice under the A S p net core function properties
that the role property is No.
But there is a policy listed inside the policies property and
this is where we'll add two more policies.
One is called Amazon S S M.
Read Onley access.
Where S S M refers to the systems manager There's an extra s there.
That's because the service used to be called simple Systems Manager.
The second policy we need to add is called AWS Lambda VPC access execution role.
The purpose of this role isn't for giving access to the RTs vpc Instead,
it gives the function permission tow wire up a connection to the VPC.
If you preferred you could create a role that encapsulated all three of these
policies and then add that to the role property instead of having these three
policies listed under the policies property. But this is the path I'm choosing for the demo.