[Autogenerated] deploying the serverless application will be
like the other deployments in two parts.
The first part will be pushing the APP and settings up AWS,
which will then build up the serverless application components.
The second part will be setting up the last bits of
security similar to the other deployments,
where we need to make sure the function and connect to the
VPC where the databases remember that earlier I explained how
in the serverless application,
you'll have a specialized lambda function in front
of your asp dot net application.
After the toolkit sends the code and serverless template file to AWS,
AWS will build all of this infrastructure for us,
thanks to the details in that template pile.
And those settings are instructions to a service called Plowed Formacion,
which lets you describe what resource is air needed and
then acts on the instructions you provide.
The objects and properties described in the Jason of the Serverless
Template file is particular to cloud formation.
The tool kit has recognized that we've included Lambda
Function AP eyes in our project,
and there's a new option on the menu published to AWS Lambda.
When we start that task,
the toolkit reads some of the needed information from that AWS Lambda Tools
defaults Jason file and then asks us to provide some naming.
One name is for a cloud formation stack.
That's the set of a W s resource is needed by your
application and the second name, just like with the far gate deployment.
The tool kit will push the compiled PO'd for your
application into an s three bucket.
So we also need to provide a name for that book it.
And to be clear,
this has nothing to do with that sample s three Proxy controller.
This is just AWS using s three to stores and piles.
The bucket name does need to be lower case and the tool kit will be sure
to let you know that if it needs to And with that now, I can go ahead and click the publish button