[Autogenerated] the authors controller isn't working yet because
we need to tell the VPC where the artist database is that the
function is allowed to access it.
This will involve a few steps, and the first time I did this, it was confusing.
Now that I've done it a few times, it doesn't seem like a big deal.
So I hope you'll trust me to help you through this first
pass and that once you've done it, you'll also think it's not a big deal,
either.
Let's start with a bit of trouble shooting by looking
at the function in the tool kit, I'll open up a view into our lambda function.
The first thing you'll notice is this test function page.
When I first saw this,
I thought maybe it was a way to debug the deployed function from visual studio.
But it's not.
It's functionality isn't quite relevant to my particular function,
so I'm going to skip that and head to the logs.
Click the download button next to the log,
which pulls the log down from AWS and opens it up in note pad well
for me because that's my default text editor.
If the problem with authors controller was related to my
code and an exception had been thrown.
I would see the stack trace details in here, but this is clean.
There's a little bit of reporting from AWS about its activity and a
little bit of logging information from Kestral,
but no problems reported here.
So that tells me the problem is outside of my coat and
the issue is once again about a bill.
US.
Resource is needing permission to interact with each other for a function.
We saw that differently than we did for the Far Gate
Container or the elastic Beanstalk website.
And you can do this in the tool kit on the configuration page
of the function view or in the console,
and it's a lot simpler to do right in the tool kit.
Well, to be honest, if you don't mind hand coating at all,
you could even specify these details in the Serverless template file.
But I prefer taking advantage of the drop downs and check boxes that I get from the other sources