[Autogenerated] you can create these instances directly in the online
console as well as from the toolkit for visual studio.
And while I won't be working with him in this course,
I do want you to know that there is a command line interface for
AWS as well as the AWS Tools for Power Shell.
Two other great options not only for creating RTs database
instances but also for performing myriad tasks on AWS.
So I'll do it from the tool kit and once it's created,
will take a look at what the tool kit exposes about that instance.
Then we'll jump to the console to see what the consul
management allows you to see and adjust related to.
That instance.
If you're following along, be prepared toe,
wait about 10 minutes for that database to be ready to work with.
Once AWS begins the creation process,
the options you choose will impact the amount of time
so we'll go for minimal options.
Since this is just for demo purposes, why does it take so long?
AWS isn't just creating a database server.
It also has to create a W s resource is for that
server to be running on for example,
it needs to create a virtual machine for the server to be installed in,
and also set aside what's called a V P C or virtual private cloud.
It's also allocating storage as well as other resource is.
And these are all things that allow your RTs
instance to be fully managed by AWS.
I do want to be clear about the terms I'm using related to RTs databases.
There are database instances, which is essentially a database server,
So this is where you specify the database engine,
the compute power of the region and other facets about the instance.
Once the instance exists,
you can then create and work with data bases inside the instance,
and you can create multiple instances.
But again, because of the free tier,
you should really be aware of how many hours the instances using Remember,
you get 750 hours free each month.
If one database instance is running for a month with 30 days in it,
that 720 hours.
If you've got multiple instances running as you
might be when you're experimenting,
you'll need to be diligent about removing instances that you don't
really need when I first began with AWS and RTs.
I did create a whole bunch of instances.
I wanted to see things like if it took longer to create one from the tool cat,
then from the console, which it doesn't they're about the same.
Or,
if choosing automated backups extends the initial start up time and
it does because it creates a backup right away.
I was also curious of sequel Server took longer to create than,
for example, my sequel.
And yes, it does.
But not by much time.
Because of all this, I had about five instances running,
and it didn't take long before I got an email from A W s warning me
that my 750 hours was already dwindling down. So do pay attention to that.