[Autogenerated] so let's go ahead and create a DB instance.
Begin by expanding the Amazon RDS note in the AWS Explorer.
There,
you can see the instances security groups and subject groups
related to RTs instances will be empty.
If this is your first time around the block,
right click instances and choose launch instance to create a new database.
Instance.
You'll need to configure the instance it's gonna be created.
And this just a few short forms.
So start by selecting the database engine.
I'll choose Sequel Server Express,
which doesn't require license If you're looking for sequel server.
Local DB.
Remember that that's just a subset of sequel server expressed,
so you'll be able to use that.
Next.
You need to configure the compute size for the instance,
and this is called the Instance class.
So that's compute power memory, etcetera.
Choose Micro because that's the option that's covered by the free tier.
Next, leave the storage at 20 gigs again.
That's what's covered by the free tier.
And then you can give a name to the instance letters.
Numbers are hyphens, Onley no spaces, and there's a 15 character limit,
so I'll just stop there.
Then you need to add credentials for logging into the server.
And they don't really enforce any rules for the password other than it
has to be at least eight alphanumeric characters.
In fact, I just typed 12345678 and it didn't complain.
So that's not really good password.
Instead, I'll paste in something a bit more complicated.
We'll need to do some more configuration here,
so don't just skip to finish on the next page.
You'll set up the network and security.
If this is a new account, you won't have any resource is yet.
So leave those defaults for creating a new VPC.
Remember,
That's virtual Private Cloud and Sub Net group and a 78 group is dedicated.
Allocation of A W.
S s network resource is you definitely want this test
database instance to be publicly available.
In other cases,
you'd want it private if it was on Lee going to be access from other
resource is with in AWS and notice down at the bottom.
It's also going to make sure that the VPC,
where my database instances going toe live will
allow my i P address to access it.
So even though he made it publicly available.
It's still totally locked down by default,
and it's up to you to configure what public resource is are
allowed in the tool kits helping me out here because it's making
an assumption that I will want to connect to the database from
visual studio on my computer.
I'm creating this database instance in the US East region,
and that's because the tool kits filtering on that region,
but that region has three zones.
You can specify which zone you want this database instance to be available on,
but I'll leave the option at the default,
which is no preference, and let AWS pick the zone.
Now let's go to the final page.
Normally, it's a great idea to allow the default of backing up automatically.
But for this demo, I'm going to change this to no automatic backups.
And the only reason is that when the instance is first getting spun up by AWS,
it will also create that first backup,
which will add a little more time before the database instance is available.
And since this is just a demo database,
I don't plan to have that database around prolong anyway,
so I'm not gonna waste the time of the backup.
That's the only change on that page,
and the next and very last page is just a summary of your choices.
So I'll go ahead and click launch and right away a window
with a list of DB instances opens up and shows the
instance that is now being created.
And I think the most interesting thing here is that it shows the
status of this instance is creating with the yellow dot You can
see some of the other settings I chose.
A swell just in case you've been experimenting,
I want to alert you to a possibly confusing error you might get if you've
exceeded the limit for VP sees on the free account,
which is five after clicking the launch button.
If there are already five V PC's and you're letting the tool kit
create a new PPC for you with this instance,
you'll see an air message saying Error launching DB
Instance db Sub Net group default Not found.
It's not saying Oh, you have too many VP sees,
which is really the problem in this particular case.
This happened to me a number of times and it was a little confusing,
so I just wanted to let you know,
in case you do get into this position while we're waiting.
Let's go to the management console to see a little bit of what's going on,
because I've done some work in the console already.
It shows shortcuts for some of the services I've recently accessed,
and RDS is among them, so that's an easy way to get there.
But you could also find RTs under the database section,
or just use a filter to find it quickly.
Once you're in the RTs view, if you look in this resource is section,
you can see that it shows you're using one of 40 allowed DB instances.
That one is the one that's getting created right now.
Click on that to get a list of all your instances.
And even though this says thes your databases,
what it really means is it's your DB instances,
and here it shows that the status of our new instance is still creating,
and it will be for a few more minutes.
Remember, overall creating the database will take about 10 minutes,
so if you're following along,
you can put the video on pause for a few minutes while you're DB instance is
still getting spun up and then come back to continue exploring a bit more
about working with the instance in the tool kit and seeing just a few more bits of info about it here in the console.