[Autogenerated] thanks to the AWS tool kit and the
simplicity of using elastic beanstalk,
it's fairly easy to publish an s p dot net core application to AWS the
Toolkit as a context menu option to the project,
which will then walk you through creating a configuration file.
And then you trigger the tool kit to run that.
What's nice is you can use that same configuration file to
publish using the AWS extension to the dot net cli.
In other words, publishing from the command line as well.
Let's start with that context menu option published to AWS Beanstalk.
It's right under Visual Studio's published option,
both in the Context menu and in the build menu in the toolbar.
There are a few short pages for configuring the published details.
First,
you need to let it know if you're going to deploy to a new
application environment or redeployed to an existing one.
In our case, we don't have any existing ones,
so, of course, will be deploying to a new environment.
You'll need to provide a name for the APP,
which defaults to the project name and then a name for the
environment that the application will be published in this
is an E C to environment.
In other words, a virtual machine.
The drop down provides some suggestions for that name,
but you can use any name you want.
I'll grab the suggestion.
Net core AP I def.
Next is the or else that the application will be available on.
You need to provide a unique sub domain on the elastic beanstalk dot com domain.
I'll toss the word plural site in front of Net core AP I
Dev and that domain name is available.
Of course, for a production up,
you can hide this behind your own neural on the next page.
Yield.
To find the compute power and security settings for the
EEC two instance For the environment,
you can choose from a lot of Windows servers versions,
and the limits environments are just starting to become available is well.
Since this is a dot net core application and cross platform,
I'll choose the Lennox option.
It's a little faster than creating an environment with
Windows Server and for production APS.
You also want to be considerate of licensing.
However, the instance type he select is important.
The free tier supplies T to micro and t three micro instances of easy to,
so I'll scroll down, down, down and select T to micro.
Next, you'll have the deployment process.
Create a key pair of private and public keys where the private key gets
stored on your computer and all name mine plural site demo.
Now it's time to take into account the fact that when I
created the artist database instance, I chose to do so in a new VPC,
not the default vpc.
Because of that, I need to check the use in non default VPC check box,
which will give me the chance on the next page to indicate
the correct VPC to use for the environment.
If you don't check this,
then the environment will go into the default VPC and you'll
have to do a little extra work to enable it to connect the VPC
where the RTs instances start.
The next setting is really important,
but it's a little bit hidden by the size of the publish options window.
The relational database access setting at the bottom is
critical to make sure that you're deployed.
Application will be able to access the artist database that the
APP is relying on when I expand the window,
you can see there's a drop down box there,
and when I drop it down, since I only have one RDS instance,
there's only one item.
It's the security group that's tied to the VPC,
where my RTs sequel server instance lives by selecting that the
deployment process will modify the security group on that vpc so
that the EEC two instance where the application lives is allowed
to connect to the database.
Next Issa Page for specifying the non default vpc.
If I hadn't checked the non default VPC check box,
the wizard would skip over this page completely.
The VPC drop down is showing the Onley non default VPC available in my region,
and that's the one that created for the database.
And I also gave it this nickname plural site RDS,
so I could identify it more easily as a post remembering its assigned name V P.
C.
O.
Two etcetera,
The Wizard also pre selected the default security group tied to that VPC.
You'll need to choose at least one public sub net and by default,
the VPC has one for each zone in the region.
I'm selecting all three,
although for simple demo where set up any one of them should suffice.
The next pages pre populated with some AWS roles that the application needs.
The first one.
The role for the deployed application will default to
AWS Elastic Beanstalk E C to roll.
But watch out for this.
It does look just right.
But if you don't have any rules yet, it will create this default for you,
but it's gonna be empty with no permissions at all.
And then it's gonna be your job to specify this permissions.
So let's not go that route for this demo.
It will be a lot easier if you create a new role
based on the power user role again, not for production up,
but great for this demo.
So click the drop down and there two sections On the top is a
list of templates for new roles and on the bottom custom URLs
that already exist in your account.
We're going to create a new one based on the power user access,
so I'll choose that and then close to drop down.
The default role that we've got for the service permissions is just fine.
So now we can go to the next page.
This next page also is pre populated correctly,
so I'll go to the next and last page, which just shows a summary of the options.
And here I can finally click on Deploy to get this
going as it starts doing its job.
I want to point out the status messages in the lower left hand corner.
They do go by quickly,
but I think they give some interesting insight into how the application
is uploaded and how the environment is constructed.
So here's a quick review of them in advance.
First, it tells us it's publishing the configuration.
Not only does that get stored on your computer,
but it will get stored up on AWS is well,
then it tells us it's creating the key pair plural site demo.
And then the status says it's starting deployment to the
AWS elastic beanstalk environment.
Net core AP.
I dash deaf.
The next status message is up.
Loading application deployment package to Amazon is three.
It zipped up the necessary components of the
application and is storing them on us three.
And when the environments ready,
it'll deploy from the S three container into the EEC two instance.
Then we see the progress of the upload 1%.
2% 3% etcetera.
Once the upload is complete, the next status messages are creating application.
Net.
Corey P I created E C two security group.
Then the message says it's creating the new environment.
This is the E.
C.
Two instance.
At the same time, a new file pops into the project.
It's a Jace on file with the configuration options I
selected in the Polish Wizard.
So the environments there now it's time for elastic being stock to get the
application that it sent to S three into the new environment.
After everything's been uploaded,
the toolkit opens up the environment status window,
and we can watch the rest of the steps in its events window.
Once I click the deploy button,
the whole process took a little under three minutes.
And if I had chosen to create a Windows environment
that would be closer to five minutes,
and at the end we get a status message telling us the environment is healthy and
the event also indicates that the application is available.
And at the top of this window is a you Earl for the application.
Of course, I've got to click on that.
Once I'm at the base URL,
I'll start by checking the weather forecast controller to
make sure that the A p I is working.
But it's not working. I know exactly why not.