All right.
Here we go.
Let us build our convolution old news network with tens flow 2.0.
And first we're going to start the exact same way as for the artificial neural network.
We're gonna start by building the model object as an instance of the sequential class which is still
taken from the morals module by the caris library taken from tensor flow.
So as a reminder the sequential class allows you to build a new network which is a sequence of layers
as opposed to computational graph like for example both man machines and so you initialize your model
like this and then as before we're going to add the different layers which this time are going to be
some convolution of layers and Max putting layers.
All right.
So are you ready.
Let's add the first convolution or layer so as before I gathered here the hybrid parameters that we're
gonna have 30 to filters a kernel size of three so that's actually the size of the filters.
You know a filter can also be called the kernel.
So we're gonna have 32 filters of size three by three and that as a reminder is exactly what allows
to do the convolution operations from the input images to the convolution layer and then from the convolution
layer to the next convolution layer or Max pulley layer.
So you have your filters then padding is going to be the same.
And there is actually something to understand here with the padding because the padding can neither
take most of the time the same value or the valid value.
And so I wanted to explain the difference between same embedding.
There are actually a lot of questions on this online and I looked at all the sources and the best explanation
I found where we can clearly visualize this is from this blog core will come.
So thank you so much for providing such a great explanation.
We can clearly see it at the end the difference between valid and same.
So imagine your array has an odd number and you know the size of your filter is an even number.
Well as we can see you're adding this column of zeros here so that when you're is trading you are taking
this column of zeros and you see that here the max is five then the max is six.
We're gonna see six then the max here is gonna be eleven and then the max is twelve.
So basically the size of the output is the same as the input and that's why it is called same.
However and valid.
Well you're not taking this column of zeros and so instead you're losing information because you're
basically ignoring this column and you're just taking the maximums each time of the squares here.
And that's why we only end up with five and eleven.
Right.
That's difference between same and valid.
It's good that you know it because indeed we're gonna see that we will provide a different patterns
in our convolution all layers.
So for our first convolution all layered Well the bearing is going to be same meaning we're adding this
column of zeros which will be including when trading the filter in the tensor.
So same pairing and then rectify activation function.
That's the same as before.
Usually in the hidden layer as well we use a rectified activation function which has the parameter name.
And then the input shape well that's the shape of our input images which have a..
Dimension 32 by 32.
And the three channels for the colors red green and blue.
And that's what you have to provide when you have colored images you have to include that final dimension
for the color.
All right.
And so where do we get.
Well as usual we use the ad method to add a new layer whether it is a fully connected layer or drop
out layer or convolution or layer.
You use this add method from your model object and to which you input Well the layer you want which
this time account to these layer meaning a convolution in two dimensions.
And the cons to this is actually a class taken from the layers module by the carer's library from tensor
flow.
But once again you don't have to remember all this.
This is a notebook that you can keep close to you whenever you're working on your project so that you
can just take this and paste it by making sure to change the right input shape for your particular application.
Right then as we say we have 32 filters that's all the arguments you have to input into comms through
the class.
We have 32 filters of size three by three that's the kernel size.
Same padding erected via activation function and the input shape you know the shape of our input images
which are 32 by 32.
And the three channels because they are colored images.
All right.
So very very simple now let's add the second convolution layer and actually the max pooling layer Max
pooling consist of only keeping the highest value when striding with a filter so as to reduce the size
of the output tensor and therefore reduce the complexity in the training.
But however we saw that we still keep the information so that our model can still be able to learn.
Right.
So let's do this let's add the second convolution layer.
Here are the hyper parameters we're gonna use again 32 filters of size three by three.
Again the same padding and erected fire activation function and then for the max pool layer we're going
to have the following hyper parameters a pool size of 2 astride of 2 so it's going to stride every two
cells.
And this time a valid bearing which I remind is when you don't consider a column of zeroes and therefore
you only take you know all the columns except the last one and therefore you lose information of the
last one.
You don't add a column of zeros here and so there we go when going back to our second convolution layer
we use this valid bearing.
And so where do we get in terms of coding.
Well once again we use the ad method from our model which for the second convolution will layer will
input again the comes to the class and which takes as input.
Well all these parameters here the hyper parameters 32 filters of size 3 by 3 same padding and rectify
activation function.
And then once the second convolution layer is added Well we choose to add a max pulling layer and to
do so we use to add methods once again and then the max pool to the class.
That's a class that will create a max pooling layer with Max pooling applied on your last layer.
And so as we saw well we have a pool size of 2 as tries to and this time a valid padding.
All right.
So now you know how to add a convolution layer and you know how to add a max balloon layer.
And now let's add a third convolution or layer.
So in case you're wondering how did we choose such an architecture.
Well you know the data set is so classic.
So for 10 data set that there are actually many architectures which were already identified as good
ones and this is just one of them.
This is a good architecture for the C for 10 data set that allow us to have good results.
However I just changed some little things inside so that you can then practice and try to improve the
final accuracy that will get in this section.
So let's add the third convolution layer where I'm gonna be the hyper parameters this time.
Well this time we're going to add 64 filters of size three by three a same batting rectify activation
function and nothing.
This is actually something I forgot to remove from the copy paste of course for the second or third
or next convolution layers.
Well you don't have the input shape argument because this is only for the input images at the beginning
and so there you go.
As you can see very practical and Google collab you can just modify your text very easily.
And so when we add the third convolution layer we use the N method once again that comes to the class
once again which takes as arguments 64 filters of size three by three the kernel size same patting and
erect rectify activation function.
All right.
And now we're going to add a final fourth convolution layer and a final Max pulling there.
And that will be the end of the convolution all part of the CNN because then remember we have the fully
connected part with the fully connected layers.
And so let's scroll down a bit.
Here is what we get for the hyper parameters of this fourth convolution layer.
Well once again 64 filters of side 3 by 3 a same pairing once again and a rectify activation function.
And then for the max pooling layer.
Well we had the same hyper parameters with the pool size of 2 astride of two and a valid padding which
can remember if you like rule of thumb is that you're going to use the same padding for the simple convolution
of layers and valid padding for the max pulling layers.
And the reason for this is that it's OK to lose the information when doing Max pulling but you want
to keep the maximum information inside your convolution all layers and since the same padding includes
this zero columns which allows to take all the different cells in your tensor well you're keeping the
maximum information as opposed to the valid padding.
All right.
So now.
Well that's the same.
We used to add method comes to the class for the convolution layer 64 filters of side 3 by 3.
Same padding and rectify activation function and for the max bullying there.
Well we use the pro size of to strive to an invalid padding.
All right.
So now that's the end of the convolution all part.
We're now ready to flatten the final output of all these convolutions and Max pulling into a one dimensional
layer.
And that's exactly what we do here.
Adding the flattening layer and to do it well sense of flow 2.0 will do everything for you.
You just have to use the add method once again and then from the caris layers module by tensor flow
you're going to take the flatten class.
And you know you don't have anything to input here it will automatically recognize what was here before
and therefore understand what to flatten you the output of all the operations that happen here.
So very easy to add the flattening layer.
And now you're ready for the full connections.
Now you're going to recognize everything because this is just basically the same as what we saw before
with artificial neural network.
Basically since the flattening layer is now a one dimensional input it can go into a new fully connected
neural network.
And so that's exactly why we're adding a first fully connected layer of 128 hidden neurons rectify activation
function because this is still not the output layer.
And so there we go.
You recognize this.
We used to add method from our model object and we use again the dance class which is used to build
indeed a fully connected layer.
And it takes as input 128 headed neurons the unit and rectify activation function.
And we don't have to specify the input shape because we have something before which is the flattening
layer.
You know we already used this add method so that sense of flow understands what's here before because
as opposed to the previous section it's not something we provide as inputs like the input images.
So you only use the input shape when nothing was added yet into your model object.
All right.
And finally we add the output layer which is going to have 10 output neurons of course because we have
10 classes in total and a soft Max activation function to get the probabilities for each of the classes.
And so well you know how to do this you use the add method.
Once again the dance class once again because we want to establish full connections between the previous
layer you know the hidden layer here and the output layer and a soft Max activation function indeed
for the probabilities.
And so well now we're going to get a pretty cool summary of our model because it's actually pretty big
compared to before.
Let's see here it is.
Here is a model we've just built with.
Indeed first convolution all layer.
Then a second convolution layer then a first Max pulling layer.
Then a third convolution layer a fourth convolution layer and then a second Max pulling layer.
Then we flatten the whole output of all these operations that happen here which therefore gives us a
one dimensional layer which we can fully connect to a first dance hidden layer and then finally which
we connect to the output layer through other full connections and so well we have in total five hundred
and ninety one thousand two hundred seventy four weights there are trainable you know there are gonna
be a data that's where we had the same number through the iterations and once again no hyper parameters
inside the neural network.
So there we go.
We can clearly call it a deep learning model it's actually pretty deep with many hidden layers.
And that's usually the case for CNN.
And luckily we have today powerful enough computing resources to be able to train such a model to classify
some images.
All right.
So we're going to take a little break now.
After having built this huge deep learning model and I'll see you in the next tutorial to of course
train it after which we'll get some first accuracy of the training but it's not a victory yet.
Remember what we want to get is a great accuracy on the evaluation set as well you know on the test
set.
So we'll see what we'll get and then no worries if you're not satisfied about the result you'll get
the opportunity to practice and try to improve the accuracy and we'll of course provide an improvement
solution for this.