Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
And now just before moving on to the more exciting applications of tensor flow 2.0 which are of course
related to the neural networks let us finish with some final basics about the strings.
How to handle strings with tons of Loot 2.0.
That's what we about to discover.
So first of all first things first let's start with the basics the very basics the way to create a string
which tend to flow is by using once again the constant function.
You know this is not only used to create tensor with tensor flow you can also create a string constant
which same you create through this constant function by tenths of law.
So once again you take your tensor flow library from which you call the constant function which takes
as input your string instead of the tensor as before and indeed then when we call R T A string variable
which is the name of the viable I gave that gets the string.
Well indeed we get the different informations you know of the properties of this tensor flow object
such as the shape so the shape is now this time and the type is of course string and the value of the
string inside is indeed tend to flow right.
That's your string tensor flow.
All right so that's how you define a string with tensor flow.
You don't have to do it with stencil flow but if you want to do deep and LP for example well you might
want to create your strings with tons of flow.
And now that we define a string Well let's see some simple string operations starting with the first
one which is widely used especially well in natural language processing and which is to get the length
you know if you want to get the length of a string the number of letters composing your string and to
do this well you have a certain path to get to first.
You start with the tensor for library form which you get the strings module from which you call the
length function which takes as input of course your sense of low string object T F string and so by
calling this well we get once again no shape because this time it's just a number and the value of ten
you know ten because there are 10 letters intensive.
All right.
So very simple string operation.
Now a less simple one well it's still very simple to do it.
It's the decode operation or if you want to decode your string into another format and as an example
here I took the UTF 8.
So this is something you might not use but it's just in case you're doing some pretty advanced LP and
you need to decode anything.
Well you're gonna use the unicode decode function again by the strings module by the tens of Lew library.
Right.
And this Unicode decode function takes two arguments.
The first one is your string and the second one is the format to which you want it to code your string.
All right.
And indeed by calling this we get this time a shape because indeed when you decode a string into UTF
8 you will get one number for each of the letters of your string.
And that's why here we get 10 numbers which are resulting from the UTF 8 format.
And each is indeed an integer.
All right.
So just some simple string operations.
And now another thing that might be very useful for you if once again you wanted to keep an LP or even
simple natural language processing with sense of flow.
But you know if you're using tensor flow you might do deep MLP in the sense that you might build and
use a tensor flow new network.
So it is how to store some arrays of strings right.
You know imagine you have several strings and you want to put them into an array.
Well the way to do this is once again to take the constant function by tensor flow you create your array
which is this time one array with a single pair of square brackets containing your different strings
so the first one is tensor flow.
The second one is deep learning and the third one is A.I. and that will create an array of string very
simply an array of strings which you put into a variable but which is in fact actually a constant in
which I called T S string array.
All right and then once you have an array of strings while you might have to iterate through this array
you know iterate the different elements of this array you know just to get the different strings separately
one by one.
That's something we do many times in LP and well to do this you can do a simple for loop.
I provided the full loop here you know you iterate the different strings inside your array of strings
and then I just printed the different strings just to show you that indeed we are well iterating our
array of strings and we get each of its elements first one extensively indeed.
Second with deep learning and the third one is a I.
All right.
So I just provided that as extra you know if any of you is interested in LP and want to do deep and
happy with tensor flow 2.0 so you have the basics.
And besides we will have a great deep end of the application in this course.
So it's even greater that we actually introduce the basics of the strings intensive flow 2.0.
So now I guess we are ready to move on to the real and more exciting applications of tensor flow.
This was just the introduction.
Now we're going to move on to new networks and we're going to start with artificial neural networks.
And each time they're going to apply to a real world problem or you know to an advanced application
so that you can see how useful can be tensor flow 2.0.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next sections on the new networks.
And that's not all.
Then after the rule networks you'll see we're going to have some more applications of tensor flow 2.0
and even more advanced features of tensor flow.
I remind that this is a very very complete course on center flow 2.0.
So you'll get everything and you'll get a variety of applications.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next section.
And until then enjoy tons of low.