Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning.
I hope you're tracking along with these intuition tutorials just fine and that you had a chance to play
around with everything we've learned so far.
And today we're talking about flattening and the good news is that this is a very simple step.
And this material is going to be very quick and then we'll be able to move on to the next interesting
things.
All right.
So so far we've got the pooled their pulled feature map and that is after we apply the convolution operation
to our image and then we apply pooling to the result of the coalition which they can involved image.
And so what are we going to do if this pool feature map.
Well we're going to take it and we're going to flatten it into a column.
So basically just take the number as row by row and put them into this one long column.
And the reason for that is because we want to later input this into an artificial neural network for
further processing.
So this is what it looks like when you have many pooling layers or you have the pooling layer layers
with many pooled feature maps and then you flatten them so you put them into this one long column sequentially
one after the other and you get one huge vector of inputs for an artificial neural network.
And so to sum all of this up we've got an input image.
We apply a convolution layer and let's not forget the relook or rectified rectified linear units.
Functional we apply after the convolution there as well.
And then we apply pooling and then we flatten everything into a long vector which will be our input
layer for an artificial neural network.
And exactly how that works we'll find out in the next tutorial.
Hope you enjoyed today's session and I looked forward to you next time.
Until then enjoy deep learning.