Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous video we created our dataset loader
function that takes the name of a company and retrieves stock prices for that company.
And now in this video we have to create a function that takes that data and generates states from it.
But before we start with the implementation of our state create their function let's see how to transform
the problem of stock market trading to a reinforcement learning setting on this graph right here we
have information about Apple stocks prices from 2010 until today on the x axis.
We have time information but on the y axis we have prices of stocks on a specific day which is not visible
right now on this graph this graph right here is taken from Yahoo Finance's as you can see here and
these blue main line on the graph shows how the value of a company changes over time let's see how to
modify these data.
So a reinforcement learning algorithm can't understand it.
Each point that his graph is nothing more but the floating number that represents the price of stocks
on the Today our task is to predict what is going to happen next is the price going down or going up
and the next day based on that information our agent will determine what to do sell by or state and
do nothing.
Let's zoom at this part of the graph.
And as you can see here we have information about six data points or six days for example.
Now let's zoom even further and transform this part of the graph to numbers this red path right here
is what we are trying to predict and that is our target.
Well let's take this red line and transform it to number and let's say it is forty seven point six just
to mention these numbers are totally random.
They are not taken from the graph in this example right here we have the window size of 5 which is also
the argument of the state create their function based on this argument we determine how many previous
days we consider before predicting the current one and now we have our state made of five numbers where
each number represents one day in the past.
But based on this it doesn't look right this is nothing more but a regression problem.
We have some numbers and we are predicting our target which is also continuous No.
Well let's modify these solutions so we have our actions instead of the real number of targets for our
estate part.
We can still use a row numbers but that won't help us anymore.
Since our target is not the real number or real price but an Action Now let's change our state to use
the differences between days as our state this information will represent price changes over time and
potentially catch the trend in the future as well.
Now we have a stately this and this new state has only four numbers and our window size was five.
We will handle this in code.
This was just demonstration on purpose only and now because we have changed formation over time our
action and the new estate is buy because price was pretty high and we expect to drop again.
So based on that information we are going to perform buy stocks at the new estate and that's pretty
much it.
Let's go back and implement this in the code and welcome back.
Let's implement this strategy.
Here we have a function called state creator that takes three arguments data which is the stock market
data downloaded with a data set loader a function timestamp.
This is the day in the data set that we want to predict for.
It could be anywhere from zero to the landfall data.
And lastly we have window size.
This argument determines how many previous days we want to consider in our state to predict the current
one.
This argument goes anywhere from one to the line of data.
You can play with this window size parameter and see what is the best size for the company that you're
trying to trade for in this section.
Let us work with window size of 10 okay.
The first thing that we have to do is to calculate the starting I.D. So let's write starting Ida is
equal to and now we have to calculate the new starting date of our state.
It is calculated like this timestamp minus window size plus 1.
For example when the time step is zero or our age it is just starting and then window sizes is then
the starting idea is minus nine.
This plus one is added because of the way we create our state.
We don't want prices on certain days but as we explained differences between the current price and the
previous price to see that change between dates and that's why we start with a plus one.
Okay now that we know our starting idea we need to handle two different cases when the starting idea
is negative and when it's positive.
Right.
If starting idea is bigger than or equal to zero.
This will handle the case when the starting idea is positive.
When we have that situation we create state like this.
We know data is equal to a data of starting a day until timestamp plus 1 if that is not the case.
And our starting idea is negative.
We will append the first day info as many times as we need to match with the window size of a data window.
Data is equal to then put minus in front of starting I.D. because starting idea at this point is negative
then multiplied by then list of data of 0.
This will replicate this member many times and now we need to spend the rest of the elements to have
the full window size of data right.
Plus then list of data from 0 2 timestamp plus 1.
Now we have our data from which we can create our state of data.
Let's define an empty list call state is equal to empty list.
And after that we can iterate through the whole window data list for i in range window size minus 1.
This minus 1 here because we have differences between the current element and one after.
Right.
State that append.
And now we have to normalize the difference between the next day and the current day because prices
can be very different.
We want to scale the difference between prices on the same scale.
So we have the same difference no matter the price.
We are going to do that with sigmoid function.
So let's write sigmoid of window data of IE plus 1 minus window data.
I and now we completed the function that is going to create the state for us the same state in the same
method that we explained on the graph to complete the function just the return and num pi array of the
state and now we're done.
If you have any questions or comments so far please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen the next tutorial.