Hey, everyone, and welcome back.
Now, this is going to be a pretty exciting lesson.
We just created some wireframes and I have several of those wireframes here, as you can see.
And we're going to use them to actually create our first prototype.
Now we're going to get into the basics of it and how you can link together something really quick that
you can test with users, or you can just show to your clients, or you can just show off to your team.
So let's go right over here.
You'll notice that when you want to design, this is what you would click.
You would click this little design tab.
But if you want to get into prototyping, you click the prototype tab.
Now we are going to be working on mobile.
The first thing you want to do is select a device.
Now they have a bunch of different variations.
You can even create custom sizes if you want.
If I'm on mobile, I'll probably use like a phone size depending on maybe the type of frame I'm using.
So in this instance, I'm going to use the iPhone 11 pro device over here.
You can even like.
Select the model, whether that's gold, midnight, green, silver space, gray, like let's just go
for space gray, keep it really relaxed.
And you can even like adjust the background color.
You can see like a little preview of that.
So.
There you go.
I just changed it to, like, a very light grey over here.
We can just see a preview of what that could look like.
If we go to present.
So this is our presentation view.
So now we can see, like, our app is actually in here.
Wow.
And.
But, like, we can't click anything, so it doesn't really work.
We can, like, tap through it.
Like, if we press our arrow keys, we can, like, go through all the different types of options there
are, but that's about it right now.
So let's get out of here.
So it opens up a new tab.
Like we'll I'll show you again.
Just opens up a new tab right there.
You can close that.
You can keep it open if you want.
And the updates you make here will reflect in that presentation, which is also awesome.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to show you like you can also switch the orientation if you need
to.
This orientation like determines which way your prototype is presented.
Typically you just leave a vertical so you can leave that like that.
Your background color I mentioned, you can change it to whatever you want.
I like to keep it like a little bit of contrast between that and the device.
It really depends what I'm prototyping.
If I'm like prototype interaction outside of like a device just on a frame of its own, I probably may
keep it like white.
I don't know.
It's up to you, really.
And another very important thing is your starting frame.
So this is essentially.
Like a frame that your prototype should start on.
So I'm going to select home.
That is my starting frame.
So you can like set or update the starting frame from the prototype settings if you want.
There you go.
There's our starting frame.
Ooh.
So you can you can change that if you want.
But just because I made a connection, it goes away.
If there's no connections, apparently.
If I link it to this item, then it'll definitely stay.
So let's get right into it.
Triggers.
Now the trigger determines what type of interaction with, like, the hotspot will cause the prototype
to, like, advance.
So I'll show you what I mean.
So if I clicked on this little heart at the bottom here, this heart icon to go to the wish list page.
This is the trigger, this little dropdown.
So there's different triggers right now we have on clicker on top and that basically like when a user
clicks on desktop or a user taps on mobile on the hot spot, and I'll show you what that looks like.
So there's my hotspot right there.
If I click that, that's what's going to happen.
So let's go back to our designs so you can use them for navigation, opening links, using menus or
exploring websites, or when you need input from a user to click on buttons, fill in forms, or confirm
and dismiss alerts.
You also have on drag.
So that allows you to perform an action.
When you drag an element on the screen, this can be like an entire frame or like a single element.
I'll show you what that looks like.
So.
I'm just going to create a copy here.
I'm going to remove this selection.
And.
I'm actually going to go into my design and I'm going to select these.
I'm going to Option Command G.
I go top, I'm going to option command g.
All right.
That's a frame one.
So that's another option.
I'm going to show you what that looks like.
I'm going to select this whole frame.
I'm going to go to my prototype and I'm going to do on drag.
It'll go to this.
So I'll go to this page and should drag the element.
Let's go take a look.
Whoa.
There you go.
You can even do on drag.
So that's another trigger.
The next trigger on our list is while hovering.
And what I'm going to do here, I'm going to select these.
I'm actually going to make a copy of this home page and I'm going to make this fill.
Let's just turn it.
There you go.
I think that's fine.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to go to my prototype.
I'm going to select this.
And when I hover, I'm going to go to this page.
Look at that.
You can see that it is actually hovering really awesome.
That's the next trigger.
The other trigger we have in store.
So let's delete this kind of just creating like home page variants so we can show off all these triggers.
We can have like while pressing.
So triggers this action basically like you hold the mouse or trackpad on a desktop and when you tap
and hold on a mobile device.
So you can use this for navigating like dropdown menus or replicating long press interactions, you
know, like viewing a preview on iOS.
When you release this, we will take the user back to the original frame.
So I'll show you what that looks like.
Actually.
Let's do something with this over here.
We are just going to make that block.
So when we do.
While pressing.
We are going to go to this page.
Let's see what it looks like.
I just clicked.
And there you go.
You have a little interaction.
Some really simple stuff.
Let's see what else we can do here.
The next one is key or gamepad.
I mean, I'm not going to go over that one right now because we're not necessarily creating a game.
There's Mouse Enter, which basically shows the destination frame that you selected when the mouse enters
the hotspot area.
This could be like a small area, like a button or like an entire section.
So you can also like set up what happens afterwards.
So what I'm going to do here is.
I'm going to do something similar to what I had.
Let's change this, Phil to like red.
Ooh, that's really harsh.
Let's change the black.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to go into my prototype, I'm going to select Mouse Enter,
and that's going to go here.
And when I select, I'm going to go back.
I'm going to do on mouse leave.
So let's take a look at what that looks like.
So as you can tell, like mouse enter most mouse sleeve works perfectly and you can create a little
interaction like that.
This is great for like stuff like on desktop, the same concept applies to the next two which are like
touch down and touch up.
So all you need to do is like when you click and when you release or when you tap and remove the tap
so we can do the exact same thing.
Touch down.
Touch up and if we were to preview that.
So it's just going to always default to this one.
Touch down, click.
Touch up, gone.
Touch down.
Click a touch up.
Gone.
So really easy to use.
The triggers are pretty awesome.
Another cool thing is.
Let's just remove this altogether.
What we're going to do is we're going to create, like three frames.
Okay.
So I'm going to connect this to this.
Just by clicking.
Maybe we'll have a state change so we know that we're on this page.
So we'll change it to black.
And then after a delay, this is going to happen.
So let's go to our prototype.
It's going to go back to normal after a delay.
Or, you know what?
We can even, like, shift this whole thing over after a delay.
I don't know.
It's just something to show you how it works.
So I'm going to click the whole frame and I'm going to click after DeLay.
And I have 800 milliseconds.
And it's going to go to it's going to navigate to home.
So let me show you what that looks like.
So I see my hot spot there.
I'm just clicking.
I click.
And you saw that it changed after 800 milliseconds.
So if we go back to our frame you again.
Boom.
Gone.
So those are the different types of triggers you can use within Figma.
I mean, use them wisely.
Don't like do what I just did there because that's kind of confusing.
But you may want to use that for like if you're building like a email notification list and like a new
email pops up and you want to show what that interaction looks like, does it fade in and fade out?
I mean, we can get more in detail in terms of like what that looks like in a later lesson when we get
into like micro interactions.
But for basic prototyping, this is just really good to just do like instant actions just to get it
done quickly.
You don't necessarily need to spend so much time figuring out all these triggers.
I typically only use like on tap for like everything at this point because I just want to get like a
prototype link together to test.
We're going to learn a little bit more in our next video.