Hey and welcome back.
We're going to talk about the grid today.
Now, what is a grid?
Lots of people are scared of it for some reason.
You know, I get it.
Grids kind of look really restrictive and they look scary.
I mean, just look at this thing.
Wow.
Even though they look like prison bars, they aren't as restrictive as you may think.
The grid is a structure comprising of a series of lines that divide the page into columns.
We have vertical and horizontal, and this structure helps designers arrange content on a page.
Like you can see here, everything is sitting on a grid.
This is something we never include in our final designs.
You'll never see somebody print a poster like this and have a grid showing, or you'll never see a website
with a grid showing unless somebody purposefully did that.
But usually that's incredibly rare.
Maybe as a stylistic approach, but I don't really recommend it now.
It serves as a skeleton for your layout, and originally the grid came from print design.
But if we ever think about where there are our grids, I mean, they're basically applied in a lot of
places.
Let's take a look.
We've got bookcases.
We even have subdivisions.
I mean, they are everywhere.
I want to show you more about grades, but I want to teach you a little bit about history, because
I think understanding the past will really help you understand the basics.
Now.
Grids have always been linked to typography over here.
They were first used to arrange handwriting on paper, and then later on we're transformed into the
manuscript layout.
You could see this over here and we're going to get into what the manuscript layout looks like and what
it comprises of.
Since the early days, grids were used to help aid readers in reading.
Now let's fast forward all the way to the Renaissance.
Now, this era had a profound impact on great systems.
I mean, many artists strived for perfect geometry.
Many paintings resulted in the centered, symmetrical layouts like this.
We have very centered layout.
You can see all the symmetry and hidden geometry within this painting.
You wouldn't necessarily notice it if these guidelines were in here to show you, but this was a lot
of Renaissance paintings really strived for.
You ever heard of the golden ratio in the 13th century?
Vlad DeJong created the diagram to achieve harmonious design.
This diagram was a merger between the grid system and the golden ratio, and it was created to produce
page layouts based off of margins with fixed ratios.
And this technique is still used in today.
You can see that this is a fairly recent layout and it is in fact using it.
Jumping forward to the industrial revolution, getting of mass production and the rise of newspapers,
posters, etc. with so much content on one page like Look at this, it's hard to read as is even with
a nice little grid layout, but with so much content on one page, designers needed to develop a way
to communicate their message while allowing for natural reading behaviour.
They've achieved that here.
There are newspapers that were much worse than this.
Now last stop, the grid.
We know when used today is very much tied to Swiss design.
It doesn't look like much, but many systems were born from this.
I want you to pitches World War One and Switzerland was neutral.
Of course, they all kind of became a common meeting ground for creatives.
And because publications had to set three separate languages, which were German, Italian and French,
because there were so many, or there was such an influx of people.
Designers needed to come up with a solution.
Typographer is like John Child and Herbert Bayer.
They stepped up to address that and for the first time, white space was used as an element in layout
design.
And you can see that in a lot of layouts today, a lot of white space, and they all kind of came from
that.
Even if you look at the print design that we saw earlier, showing that first grid, that kind of system
was born from this and Swiss design had a profound impact on layout.
Now we're going to jump into some more basics.