Hey, everyone, and welcome back.
We're going to be talking about a big topic and that is typography.
Now, where do I even begin?
There are so many different things to talk about, but what I want to do is I want to start right at
the basics.
So let's talk about the different categories of type.
Now, the first category is something we're all familiar with, and that is SERP typefaces.
Now, the first word that comes to mind when I'm thinking about serif typefaces is traditional.
Now the little curls at the end of the letter forms are called serifs.
Now these are these little, little curls.
You see them on the edge of the SE, you'll see them at the bottom of the are the even on the top of
the R you get the point.
Now Sarah's are generally used in body copy and they embody a more traditional feel.
Some even say elegant.
It really depends on the typeface.
Now, even though they have their standard applications, we usually can bend the rules if it needs
to suit our need.
And you'll see that later on in these lessons.
Now, you may be thinking, Daniel, there are so many different types of serifs and some look so different
from each other.
And you know, you're definitely right.
Serifs are categorised into four categories, so let's jump right in.
So that first category or that first subtype is called old style.
Now also serifs.
These are generally referred to as humanists or, you know, the oldest typefaces in the classification.
And this will date back all the way to the mid 1400s.
Now typefaces in this category include Jenson, Center and Goudy.
Now we're using Goudy over here.
It's a really nice typeface.
The next subtype is transitional.
This is a transitional type phase where we're using.
Here is times in your Roman now, times near Roman Baskerville.
Now those are both transitional serve fonts.
And one thing you'll notice is the difference between thick and thin lines over here.
These strokes, they're bit more pronounced here.
If we're going to compare this to like, say something like old style, you know, we start seeing a
little bit more contrast between those strokes when in comparison, but not as much as modern or didn't.
And that is our next subtype.
So don't enter modern.
And this includes typefaces like Dido Bertone.
Right here we have Dido.
And you can tell that these strokes are very, very contrasting.
They're much more pronounced.
You'll see them right here in the counters in the O, like in the inside of the E over here.
That thick to thin up here.
In the end, you'll see the difference between the strokes on the the left side of the M and the the
far side of the M So you'll see much more contrast with these types of typefaces.
And lastly, we have slab serif now slab serifs.
They have little to no contrast between thick and thin lines.
You also notice that at the end their serifs are much more rectangular or boxy and typefaces.
In this category they include typefaces like Archer.
We're using courier over here, and that's going to be it for serif typefaces.