Hello, everyone.
So I want to take a break here and talk about something that well, I think it's really exciting and
should get you excited.
That is that technology is evolving.
What does that mean?
It means that what you're learning is going to change over the years because everything in tech is fast,
is moving fast, is changing fast.
But the good news for you is that you're learning the latest and greatest right now.
So if the best developer in the world stopped to learning three years ago, they're going to be behind.
Your advantage of just getting started to code is that technology is moving so fast that for you to
catch up to somebody, well, you can do that in a really fast time.
As a matter of fact, if really good coders aren't always keeping up to date with the latest trends
they fall behind.
This is a good thing for you because text editors, dependencies, APIs, libraries, best practices,
even programming languages are constantly evolving and changes.
Some of these words on the screen may not even mean anything to you.
Maybe you don't even know what they are.
Don't worry.
We're going to learn in the course all about these.
But you see, the reason I created this course and I created this course back in 2018.
That's a long time ago.
Since then, every year I update the course because technology is evolving.
I want this course to be up to date.
I want this course to teach the latest trends so that you finish the course and you can go off on your
own and get hired.
That's the goal.
But you see, every year, as I was updating the course, I realized that the old videos are actually
extremely valuable because all the courses out there, all the other courses out there teach you just
that, a snapshot of what the current development practices are.
But what I can do with my course, since it has been around for such a long time, is provide a historical
snapshot.
I can take you from the very beginning of a popular library like React and show you how it evolved,
how the best practices evolved.
And this way, the way you learn with this course isn't that you just learn all these new things.
You also get to learn the all things and then how to update them.
It's as if you were working for years as a developer.
You have these battle stories to tell of the old ways of doing it and how we do it in a newer way.
So as you'll see in all of our projects as we learn new technologies.
New APIs, new best practices.
I'm going to start off with how we used to do it and then show you how to update, for example, libraries,
how to update projects to the latest version.
This way you actually experience what a developer does.
A developer is maintaining software, maintaining programs.
When you finish coding a project, it's never done.
It's constantly evolving.
New things are being discovered in the world.
New technology is being created.
Even small little libraries are being improved upon.
So your job as a developer is not just to write code, but to also maintain it, to constantly improve
it, to make sure that it's running years and years from now.
So as you go through this course, I want you to see every video that I show you how to update something,
every video where I show you how we want to maybe change a version of a library or how an API such as
in the final project are clarify API changes over time and we have to fix things in order for our projects
to work.
That's the life of a developer.
You're a problem solver.
You are constantly fluidly changing, evolving with the technology, and if you're able to do that,
then you're a great developer.
And I'm really excited about this course because I've kept these old videos and then shown the updated
videos right after that video to show you how you would have experienced it a few years ago and how
you experience it now.
And I think that's a great way to learn.
I think that's an exciting way to learn, to give you experience without necessarily having that actual
experience.
All right, I'm talking too much.
Let's get back to coding.
Bye bye.