So before we can even jump into actually building it, let's talk about some of the basics that impact
all the different decisions surrounding sizing, measuring and spacing.
The first thing base units.
What is a base unit?
This is our starting point.
This is ground zero.
Let's define a base unit.
Now, this is what defines what every single measurement will be.
A multiple of why this makes our designs consistent, improves how we hand off to developers and reduces
the amount of decisions we need to make as a designer.
So what should you set your base unit to?
I use an eight pixel base unit because it makes scaling for a variety of devices really easy.
Most screen sizes are divisible by eight.
It's also divisible by itself.
Eight divided by two equals four.
Eight divided by four equals two.
There are even four pixels, five pixels, six pixels, and even ten pixel increments.
There is no wrong answer here.
Like I said, I like using pixels and spacing icons by four pixel half step.
Right here we have an eight pixel base unit and you can see it spaced out to 16, 24, 32 and so on
and so forth.
Up next is sizing.
Now, all UI elements should be measured in increments of our base unit.
This helps us with a bunch of things like clear alignment, consistency and hierarchy.
Let's take a look at the difference between the two here.
One is using an eight pixel base unit.
The other one isn't really using anything, and there's just no rhythm.
You know, it may seem minuscule, but if I were checking out an A product or a website and I came across
a credit card input like this paired with all these different UI elements, I would think twice about
entering my information padding.
This is the space between all of our elements and you guessed it, it is measured based off of our base
unit.
This makes spacing consistent, readable to our users.
Think about this card over here.
All elements are spaced using increments from an apex or base unit.
It creates uniformity.
We have 16 pixels on this side, 16 pixels over here.
We got 16 pixels here.
You see on this grid, on the bottom, these rows, which we'll get into soon, we've got four pixels,
four pixels, four pixels.
Next is layout.
So what do all these lines and boxes mean?
What are they?
These are some questions you may be asking.
Let's talk about the anatomy of a grid.
All grids are made up of three key things columns, gutters and margins.
The first one is called let's cover that, our vertical blocks right here, that span left to right.
So right here on this page, we've got a little four column grid.
And generally the column width won't change, but the number of columns change from 12 on desktop,
maybe eight to tablet.
Some people like four on mobile.
I mean, you can use anything you want.
I like to use six on mobile because it gives me a flexibility to place three elements in a row on the
screen.
I even like to use eight on mobile.
Like I said, if you want to hang things off the screen, we'll see that later on.
But nothing is set in stone.
Gutters.
This is the whitespace right here, right between columns.
They're dedicated, based off of your base units.
So some designs will increase that size as you scale up or decrease it as you scale down.
Other grids can stay fixed.
It's not really set in stone.
So right over here, this is probably like a 16 pixel gutter based off of a pixel base unit.
Margins are the whitespace between the edge of your column and the edge of your frame.
You can combine all these elements to build different types of grids.
The manuscript grid, we saw this before.
It kind of looks like a grid for a manuscript, right?
Well, it could be useful for defining margins and for large blocks of text.
This is the most popular one.
The column grid kind of looks like the grid you see today, kind of what we've shown off.
Now, these are the types of grids we mostly use and these columns are spaced evenly, and that is where
we start to align our content.
Most grids utilize 12 columns and you may be asking, well, why 12?
Well, 12 columns can be divided into halves, thirds, fourths and six.
This helps for designing for responsive screens, the modular grid.
This is a variation of the column grid we saw before.
You'll notice that they have both vertical and horizontal rows.
So we have vertical columns going left to right, horizontal rows and top to bottom.
And this creates these modules that provide some additional options for single or larger box.
The baseline grid.
Now, this one's important.
You just want all the time as well.
I like to couple this with my column grid.
They consist of these horizontal rows that you see here from top to bottom, and these provide guidance
for typography and UI elements.
They create vertical rhythm.
And think of when you were in school and you used to write on a piece of paper.
Yeah, it's similar to that.
And yes, it's based off of your base unit.
I like to use a four pixel baseline grid.
Now placing typography on a baseline grid you use line height and this is that bounding box right around
your type.
So say your font size is something like 16 pixels.
You know, your line height could be something like 24 pixels.
We have maybe like a 40 pixel type set over here for the headline and our font size for the headline
and for the line height, we have something like 48 pixels, so multiply by eight and on that baseline
grid, so we got four pixel here for pixel here.
So we got eight pixel spacing between the top and the bottom here.
We got 12 between the sub header and the copy.
So this creates this vertical rhythm that really helps to create consistency throughout your whole piece.
Let's jump into responsive grids and figma.