Hey, everyone, and welcome back.
So I want to get right into the foundation.
So if you take a look at here, this is my color palette that I've built out.
These types of things.
We have to understand that design systems will continue to evolve with feedback that we get from users,
from overall feedback that we get from different types of stakeholders.
And generally our product will evolve over time.
But what I've done here, you can see that I have a primary color palette which is like the primary
yellow, and I have a yellow that is just like a 20% version.
So I've basically created these sections and I'll show you how I've even structured it.
And you have this file as well.
You'll see that I have these all in auto layout grids.
You have a color row and I have each individual color and then text and the color.
So even within the text I have the name of the color, I have the hex value and I have the actual color.
Now what I've done here is once I pick the color, I'll go into my styles and I can create a new style
if I want to.
I have a bunch of styles here already, and you've seen me do that a bunch of times already.
So this one is under the primary section.
I've also given myself a couple of secondary colors if I need them, which are a blue and a blue variant,
kind of like the yellow green and a green variant just like the yellow.
One thing you don't want to do is give yourself way too many options.
I'm not saying that I will use all these variants.
It helps to kind of have them, especially when you're building out an interface.
Now.
I'll show you how.
I'll use those in later videos.
Another thing that I've done as well is I've given myself accent colours.
Now, do I need them?
Maybe.
These accent colors will help us bright in different parts of the app.
So if we want to build like an animation with like confetti, like we can use a lot of different colors
like that.
And I don't see myself using these colors in many other instances, but you know, they're fun, playful
colors that we can use if we need to just inject some of that into the application when we want to.
And that's what I've done here.
I've created all these different accent colors and they're in my styles, my color styles over here.
So you'll see I have my primary secondary, I have my accents and I have my user interface colors as
well.
Now what are user interface colors?
And I mean, you can name them whatever you like.
I like to break these up into different sections because when I'm applying them to something and I'll
get into that as well, it's easier to pick that apart.
So if I have like a background that is white, I'm going to use the background white style, not just
the UI white style.
If I have an icon that's white, I'll probably use the white UI style.
If I have text that's white, I'll use the text white style.
So that's definitely the reason why I've decided to break these out and duplicate them.
That is just so that we when we're using them, we have a lot more flexibility.
Now, it might take a little bit more upfront work, but you'll have all these different styles to use
and you'll be able to easily swap out the ones that you intend to.
Instead of swapping out one UI color and affecting everything, you'll be able to pinpoint.
If I'm touching a button, I'll be able to just touch the text or the UI colors or the background colors
if I wanted to, and I'll show you how that works.
But what I've done here is I've taken out the grayscale palette and I've broken it into just different
increments.
So I have like a gray 100, which is basically like a block gray, 80, gray, 60, gray, 40, and
so on.
So this will give me a lot more to choose from when I'm using grayscale within our application.
In the background.
I've given myself a couple of different options, one being white and a nice little grey here.
And in the text section here, I've given myself a bunch of different options.
Now, when we spoke about accessibility, these colours may not be accessible and I may not use them,
but yellow can be accessible if we're using it over like a dark block or like an image.
So I've given myself that option if I ever need it.
I've given myself definitely a green and red option for success and error colors when it comes to things
like forms.
And I've given myself a lot of variance in terms of scale because that is going to come in handy when
we're trying to distinguish like just create hierarchy within different text applications.
So title subheadings and so on.
So when you're building out a colour palette, or if you want to call this a colour system, remember
to give yourself enough variance, not too much.
You don't want to highlight 20 different grays.
I mean, that's going to muddy your design.
But I've given myself, you know, five variants of gray, and I probably use just the majority of the
time for text.
I'm using these three.
BLOCK is when I maybe need something that's really, really dark.
But I'll use mostly this to be my darkest, which is the great 80.
And if I want to create more hierarchy, I'll use something like a gray 60.
Then once we get into the 40 and 20, we have a little bit of diminishing returns because we just have
legibility issues.
So this is how I've laid out my color system.
And another thing is I've created it in a way where it just looks really nice.
If you can see over here, everything is spaced out like 40 pixels between each other.
Everything is even.
The borders are all very nice and spaced out perfectly.
So if you'll see if I change this like 50.
Left and right will be closer.
The horizontal spacing.
Will tighten up, but I've decided to just use 80.
Obviously a multiple of our base unit and I'll get into that next.
So that is how I've actually laid out our colours system.
And you'll notice that this is what it looks like when you're using your design system and when you're
using it elsewhere in other files.
So this is it.