I want to teach you about overflow behavior.
So this is pretty cool if you want to like incorporate some horizontal or horizontal and vertical scrolling
and I'm going to teach you how to do that really quickly.
Now, overflow behavior essentially controls how your users interact with content that extends beyond
a device's dimensions or within a frame's dimensions.
I mean, you can use this to replicate scrolling down a lengthy page of content as well as more advanced
like interactions, like scrolling left or right to switch between elements and a slider.
You know, you can pan or scroll around an interactive map.
It's really awesome.
You can apply the overall flow behavior just to the frame.
So I'll show you what that looks like.
I have a frame over here and there's an overflow behavior which is really easy to use.
Now let's start with just vertical scrolling.
So what I have here is just a long home page.
This is obviously going to be way too long for our actual device.
I fixed the bottom navigation bar.
You'll notice it over here and it's actually reflected in the bar over here in the side.
And we're just going to see what that looks like.
So you don't necessarily need to apply an overflow behavior to everything.
I mean, this is just going to scroll just fine and you'll notice that that's an easy way to make,
like a sticky nav or like a sticky search bar if you want it.
Now, let's see if we combine something like this into a frame, and then we shrink that frame and we
clip the content.
Now all of a sudden, like we can't see that content, maybe we would want to scroll based off of that
content.
Yeah.
There we go.
Maybe you just want to see just a snippet.
Let's clip it.
Snippet and clip it.
That rhymes.
We're going to prototype and we're going to do vertical scrolling.
So let's see what happens.
So you can scroll within this frame as well as scrolling over here.
I don't recommend doing this for something like this, but I mean, gets the point across pretty easily,
right?
So we're going to just reverse what we did there.
Another way to do it is to actually scroll horizontally.
And this is super easy.
We just need to ensure that this frame is within.
And we need to clip the content.
I mean, we can clip it right there.
Perfect.
There we go.
Now, users can easily, like, swipe through.
We can even just, like, touch this up just a smidge.
If we go to our products inside this frame, so we have like three.
We can adjust the constraints.
So that way they don't.
To move while we touch this frame.
Perfect.
And so when we do swipe, it's going to go off the device.
So that is super cool.
So I mean, we can refine this some more, but you can tell that we can just easily simulate that sliding
and scrolling without necessarily going to a new page.
So super awesome if you want to do something like that.
Now, if you do want to do here, let's duplicate this frame.
We'll keep that there.
Let's just go back, actually.
Okay.
Let's duplicate this frame.
We'll keep that one as our original.
And what we're going to do is we're actually going to remove all this, remove this.
And we're going to create like a massive.
Nap.
Actually not here.
I will show you how to do this.
Let's create a frame.
And we're going to go to our plugins.
I have a great plugin over here called Map Cycle, so I'm going to open it up.
And you can just kind of set like any position you want 500 by 500.
So it's definitely big.
We're going to create a frame for that and we're going to shrink the frame in.
And we're going to clip the content.
And we're going to move that over here.
So we have San Francisco, beautiful San Francisco.
And what we're going to do is with our overflow behavior, we are going to do horizontal and vertical
scrolling.
And when we go into our prototype, oh, it's not in our prototype because it's not in the frame.
So let's push that in the frame.
There you go.
And we go into our prototype, we can easily scroll.
Or drag.
Horizontally and vertically.
So this is really great if you're creating an application with a map that you want to be able to do
that with or with whatever content you deem necessary so you can stick whatever size image in here.
And nice thing is it kind of has like this nice animation when you kind of drag.
So it really allows like users to swipe through both left and right, up and down within like that particular
frame.
So go ahead, go out there and test these little things out.
I know a lot of people like to do like horizontal scrolling, especially with images like over here
and products.
I mean, this is pretty cool.
Kind of like you don't necessarily need to get into any animation in order to create like a pretty awesome
prototype.
So that's overflow behavior within Figma.