And welcome back.
In the previous video, we went over the basic rules that all HTML files must follow, and I kind of
glossed over this doc type HTML tag and I did that on purpose because I want you to develop another
developer fundamental concept.
And that is the fact that most of the time as developers, there's so much information out there, there's
no way that you can keep all of that in your head.
And as developers, we must get really, really good at problem solving.
So for the doc type, let's say if I was working and somebody gives me this file and I say, okay,
I got this, that's good, but I'm not sure what doc type is.
Well, again, we want to get really good at googling here and I know it sounds silly, but trust me
as a developer, you're going to be googling a lot and going to get really, really good at looking
for answers and understanding meanings behind code.
So if I go into doc type HTML and we Google that, one of the first things we get is the double E three
school.
And this is a resource that I highly, highly recommend.
It'll actually explain what the dock type is and even show you a demo of what it does.
You can read into this and get more familiar with it, but the general rule and the concept behind dock
type is that dock type says to the browser, Hey, just a heads up, this file is going to use HTML
five and we'll get into what HTML five is.
But right now, HTML has evolved from back in the day when Tim Berners-Lee invented it to where it is
now and it has developed and evolved so that it has a few more tags, it has a few more features, and
this is the way for us to say, Hey, browser, we're going to be using HTML five, so please make sure
that you load the website properly and we'll get into what those new tags are and some of the new syntax
is.
But again, most likely in your day to day job, you're going to be writing this at the top because
we're writing in HTML five.
If that ever changes and something new comes along, we might change this.
But dock type, that's what it is.
But the key concept here is that I really want you to start Googling at any time you see in my video
something that you don't fully understand or you want to dig a little bit deeper.
You really want to grow those roots of your foundation so that you really understand how the landscape
works.
Okay, so I just wanted to get that concept across that as a developer you really want to understand
how things work and what they mean, and you'll come across in your day to day many things that it's
very easy to just on the surface copy and paste or just look at an example and do it without fully understanding
what it does.
But the developers that give really, really good salaries, really good jobs and are considered senior
developers are the ones that fully understand all the meaning behind the things that they do.
We're going to be taking that throughout the course and making sure that we develop those fundamentals.
But any time, like I said, you have any questions or you don't understand something fully, I do encourage
you to Google and get the answers because there's a ton of free resources out there for you to get fully,
fully comfortable with a topic.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.