Welcome back.
And the last section we talked about how we have Google.com and if we enter an IP address, we essentially
get all these files from Google.
So if we look back at the diagram that we had, we see here that the Google servers just send us a couple
of files which are HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
Again, something that we'll cover later on.
But for now, based on that knowledge, we should be able to break Google.
So let's play something.
If you open up Google Chrome and you go into view, then developer, then developer tools.
You're going to have a screen over here that pops up.
You might want to move it up and down just so you can see better.
Let me just scroll this down a bit so you can see you'll see over here that there is a little icon on
the left with a pointer and a window.
If you click on that and now go to the website, you'll see it selects a bunch of different things.
So it's just an element selector.
So let's just click on this.
So when I click on this, it takes me to the part of the HTML file that essentially tells Google to
put in Google search here.
So based on that, we can do something fun.
We can get the valley over here of google search and let's change it to Andre search press enter.
Look at that.
We have we now just changed Google to have Andre search over here.
That's very, very cool.
I want you to play around with that and see what you can do.
For example, if I now select this, I'm just like, I don't want this.
I'm going to press the delete key and just delete it.
Look at that.
I can delete that.
I don't like that either.
I'm going to press delete on that as well.
And let's see.
You know what?
On the entire website.
I want this entire body thing gone.
Delete.
Look at that.
We just completely deleted Google now you must be freaking out.
What happened?
Am I going to get sent to jail?
I just deleted Google Wallet.
No, not really.
Press enter and Google is back now.
Why is that?
Well, if we go back to our diagram, we have Google servers and we were playing around with one of
these files and we just modified it.
We essentially just set delete, delete.
So Google was gone.
But when I made that request, again, Google servers, no problem.
We have these files.
They send these files all over again back to the server.
Hopefully that made sense to you.
We see that the browser essentially is a tool, a piece of software that can receive files from servers
and it knows how to read them.
So that look that we get pretty Google and we can type in all the searches that we want in the world.
All right.
Let's get to the next section where we talk about the Internet backbone.
See you in the next one.
Bye bye.