Hey, everyone, and welcome back.
So we're going to be continuing this basics of typography portion here.
And the next type of category we have here for typefaces is display typefaces.
Now, you may have heard that before.
You may be wondering, wow, this is a typeface like how do I even use something like this?
Let's get into that.
Now, this includes typefaces like lobster or Abril.
Now this category is the broadest and includes the most variation, as you can see over here.
The most consistent characteristic, though, is that they're generally unsuitable for body copy, and
it's best that we kind of keep these for things like headlines, larger text, maybe even shorter copy
for a little brief.
Definitely use us if you need to draw attention to something.
So this is lobster.
This is a really, really nice one.
I like it a lot.
And you can definitely see this being used in like a website or a marketing website or something like
that.
Same with something like maybe this one over here, I can see something like this.
This is I think this is a Braille right here.
And one great thing about this typeface is even though it is a serif, it definitely has that contrast.
That is just like very, very pronounced here, kind of like a throwback to a Disney or modern serif
typeface.
You may look at these display typefaces and think, Well, Sarah, for us and Serif and in reality you're
definitely right.
Like I mentioned before, they do have serifs, but technically it would still be categorized as a display
typeface because you wouldn't use it as body copy.
And in this example, you may be thinking, Well, how do I use it?
Now, this pulled from dribble and this is by Isaiah Arafat.
And they do a great job contrasting typefaces here on the Web.
Let's take a look over here.
Now, the display typeface here is very elegant and there is some extreme contrast between that thick
and thin line.
You'll notice you could try to use this as body copy, but it would be really, really hard to read.
I guarantee that display typefaces have their use and this is a great example of that.
So you'll see over here use as a headline like the main hero copy for this kind of landing page and
you'll see over here just as a title.
Now, I couldn't imagine using this pretty consistently to typeset like all this copy.
It would just be really hard to read, like I mentioned before.
But this is still a great example of how you could utilize that even for the web.
And the last category I have is called mono space.
Now you may be thinking, what is mono space?
These kind of look like sans serif.
And you know, they are variants of censor for serif types of fonts.
Now, Roboto mono space is one example of amount of space typeface, and these are fixed pitch or fixed
width or non proportional fonts.
It's letters and characters each occupy.
You'll notice that over here, each occupy the same amount of horizontal space.
Narrower characters simply get a bit more spacing around them to make up for that difference.
So you'll see like a narrow character like the N but or like a T.
I don't have a T over here, but these are pretty similar and you'll see they still have the same width
right across horizontally.
You'll notice that they all take up the same amount of space regardless of their letter.
These are best used for areas where you want to evoke some sort of technical feeling.
Now let's take this, for example.
Now this is just a simple feature within GitHub where people can collaborate over code reviews.
So there are some code here and people are just chatting about it.
We got some reactions to that.
Pretty cool.
Now, mono space fonts have widely been used for coding because of the higher importance of reading
the individual characters.
Mono space typefaces are used for programming because they are widely believed to be better due to the
common treatment of skinny letters and punctuation and alignment.
You'll notice that right here in the code that they're reviewing, it's very, very easy to read.
Now, if we were to compare that with something like this, when I'm trying to look at each individual
letter where one letter left out could mean the difference between a code that works and code that doesn't.
It's very important that I have a very legible typeface or a mono space typeface, which would allow
me to actually read that in a much more clearer way.
It's a very, very functional typeface and like I said, mostly used by programmers.
And within that kind of realm, there are definitely other use cases for it.