Hey, everyone, welcome back.
So we're going to talk about our cart and checkout compositions that we've created based off of some
of the components that we've created in the past and recipes that we've created.
So you may notice that we have our cart here.
And what I've done with our car is I've made it really simple.
I've used it as just an overlay.
Now I have just my header.
Now this is a component that I've created, but I actually didn't use the component in this instance.
We can use that because I just pulled this because I had a previous design of cart where it took up
the whole page and I thought that wasn't necessary and I thought a better implementation of CART would
be to actually have it just pop up from the bottom as an overlay and to keep that really simple and
small, not have that take up too much of the screen.
Because if we think about cart in general, when we buy stuff off of like different types of marketplace
websites, we don't necessarily buy like ten things at once.
I mean, that's a rare occurrence.
Maybe if you're shopping for a holiday or something like that, but generally you're buying like maybe
one or two things, maybe three things at once.
And what I wanted to do is I want to make that very simple in terms of the experience.
I want them to press that cart button, see this pop up.
They can add to it really easily.
I have these two variations here.
Like I said, when you were starting to like build out the design a bit more, we have to start thinking
about all those different types of scenarios.
We also think about those scenarios in the beginning as well.
When we're building our site maps, when we're building, we're sketching still when we're, you know,
building out user flows.
The thing is, user flows and sketching that's kind of thing is going to just happen throughout the
entire design process.
So don't worry about forgetting something in the past because new features will come, new problems
will need to be solved and you'll need to kind of go back to the drawing board, quite literally, share
those with your team or your stakeholders like clients, and come to some sort of solution.
So this is my solution for CART, and I've used the same type of recipe that we created back in our
design system, which was like our cart list.
And I have the different car components.
So you'll notice that this is not a component.
That's the default component over here.
That is just because of when I was using it within a prototype.
So if I go to actually update this, like I'll need to do is copy that.
I can bring that down the list, I can remove that one.
Now we're going to do is I'm going to command see and I think I have this price that 75, 99 and like
you can just easily update it like that.
Perfect.
So there you go.
Now we have a component.
You can even have that reflected.
And here it's pushed out all the way up.
Let's get rid of the one that isn't a component.
And there you go.
Everything's kind of back to normal now.
Now, like I said, I have two variations here.
I have a variation where we have the cart when the user first pulls it up.
And then I have a variation where we have a cart where somebody swipes.
And I just want to show that because when you're working closely with developers, they want to see
all these different types of interactions and we'll get into prototypes later.
But they want to see the different types of use cases we have for different types of models, overlays
or just like compositions in general.
So at the bottom I've decided to kind of go with just showing off the total.
Like I said, like we haven't seen this all types of version yet as typographic elements, but we've
seen them in the pill.
So I found like maybe like a double use case for this.
So I may create another style just to have for something like this.
I have the checkout button with an arrow trying to create a little bit of like FOMO, which is fear
of missing out or just trying to create some sort of urgency like, come on, let's go in this direction.
So when this happens, we're going to push them to a new page, which is the checkout.
So they've already reviewed their cart at this point.
And in checkout, what we want to just kind of focus on is do we have the right type of payment method?
You'll notice that I'm using the same card that we've created in the cart section.
So if we kind of go back to our design system, I'll take a look there.
Let's go back to cards.
You'll see that we've created a Bank of America card, just something small that we can kind of change.
If you want to like add a new bank, you can do that.
What I've done is I've just created a standard card that kind of fits our brand, but I've also just
kind of slot the name on there.
I've also kind of swapped like a MasterCard logo, and you can you can do that too.
It's there for you to kind of go ahead and edit.
Now I have that.
I've also added like a carousel at the bottom.
So if users want to swipe through cards, maybe they have multiples.
There's a cool interaction to be had right there.
We want to make this really nice, really exciting even through the checkout process, because if we
take a look at all the different types of checkout processes that we've participated in, a lot of them
are really boring.
We don't even read anything.
We are just kind of like, Yeah, yeah, whatever pay.
But if we do need to change credit cards, that kind of stuff becomes a little bit more, less exciting.
And also sometimes the experience there is not nice.
So we want to make sure that these cards are right up in the user's face.
They're very familiar for the user, so they can understand that, oh yes, this is my Visa or my MasterCard
that I've put into this application.
So I can see that very vividly over here.
I can swipe it if I need to add another one or if I need to use another one.
I also have like the important shipping information right up front.
Like I know where this is getting shipped to.
Below.
I've also added a very small section for adding a promo code, making that very simple.
The CTA like a bright yellow button.
But I mean, it's not necessarily the primary thing users need to do here, but I've kept it there just
so it will reflect in the total price right away.
And users can see that connection between here and here.
But like I said before, I'm using my placeholder unselected button, and if we want to show this interaction
in more detail, we would create another screen and have like a selected input as well.
And I'll show you what that looks like later.
I have my apply button over here, which is just kind of like my primary button that is a default.
And then I have like my delivery fee.
I have the order total and at the bottom I'm using our footer.
And like I've noticed that I'm starting to use a footer very much like I'm using a header within the
application.
And I thought, you know, maybe this footer becomes an actual component now.
So I may actually go back and create like a footer component section where I add this and I maybe add
different variations like you've seen in the cart where there's like a footer where there's a button
in text.
Over here we have just like kind of the primary button.
You'll see it also in like product pages as well.
And once that happens, this is the exciting part.
We have like a confetti pop at the end, you know, just showering down on our users, like, woo hoo,
you place your order.
And what will happen here is just a continue button would pop up and it would just go back to the home
page.
But we want to kind of make it a little exciting right now.
A lot of applications don't make it exciting when you do something really well.
And this is kind of goes back to what we talked about with motion and animation.
You know, it's okay to create these screens and like reward your users in a way.
They kind of love that kind of stuff.
And we want to make sure that it's reflected in our designs, you know, gives our product a little
bit more personality, especially with like the bright colors, you know, just the animation of the
confetti flying down whenever you actually complete in order, you do something successful.
So I wanted to reflect that also in the designs over here.
And like I've noticed that, well, I have a confetti frame and I may actually have to make this into
like an animation with fake motion or another type of application, like principal or something like
that or after effects.
So I'll just create this and I may actually put this in there assets within our components in our design
system if I want to reuse this elsewhere because we do use this screen a couple of times.
Yeah, you'll just realize that.
Okay then this is some sort of reusable component or animation that we can kind of keep to the side
and reuse whenever we want to.
And again, like we have the footer cut in here, it's a little different this time.
It's still a fixed footer.
As you can tell, it's fixed position over here, but it's not a primary button and it doesn't have
like a thin horizontal rule that we see at the top of this, that little gray line.
So there are different variations to be had for those components.
And we'll probably go back and actually create more components based off of all the different variations
we come up with.
So it's okay to start creating high fidelity mock ups without components and stuff like that?
Totally fine.
That's actually normal.
When you start kind of adding components to your designs and stuff like that, you'll start to realize,
Hey, like this is starting to come together.
It's really neat.
Everything is like in its own place, but like I'm finding that I don't have enough flexibility, so
I have to go back and think about maybe some more typographic elements and stuff like that, or more
recipes that can help bring this all together a bit more.
And that's it for cart and checkout.