Hey, everyone, welcome back.
So I'm going to give you some really helpful tips when you are creating color palettes.
And then we're going to jump right into Figma and do it ourselves.
So when we're looking to create a color palette, we need to follow some proper color harmony.
So using the color theory formulas, basically those color schemes that I showed you before, now I
love Couleurs Eco.
It really helps with generating harmonious color palettes if you need it.
It's just a great resource.
There's a bunch of other resources out there, like Adobe has one.
I mean, there are resources even within Figma like plug ins that will help you create color palettes
and we'll get into those later.
But if you need help there, definitely resources out there to help.
You actually come up with some ideas for color palettes.
You should always know that your colors should be scalable and additive within your color system.
For your UI.
We need to make sure to always have multiple shades of gray and low saturated colors to work with.
There should be some sort of systematic pattern in place that can be added to as your color system grows.
In this case, we see that each hue over here has its own kind of palette or mini palette that can be
expanded on when needed.
This could be my main palette over here, and I can get darker variations of that, you know, for accessibility
reasons or just I have a lot more flexibility within my interface.
You don't necessarily need to stick to maybe like the three or four brand colors that you may have or
your brand may have.
You have to build off of that in order to make a really great user interface.
I think one of the big things is to always kind of tend to your grays and your blacks with a hint of
your brand color.
It adds a little bit more depth to your blacks and grays, and if you leave them untouched, it could
come off as too harsh.
You know, sometimes you could add a little bit of blue.
I mean, this could be a little bit too light if you want something really dark.
But if you look at this gray, if you had a little bit of blue to this gray, it just looks that much
better and it matches your brand much better.
And the last tip that I have that is pretty huge is that you have to be aware of the contrast between
colors.
Contrast helps with proper visual hierarchy like we have here, like a headline and a sub headline.
I touched upon this a little earlier in terms of wanting to read a darker color before you read a lighter
color.
And it's also a big part of ensuring accessibility.
There are a couple of tools that we can use to check, like conscious ratios of our colors.
Color is a great web tool that you can use just to get a quick glimpse of what is accessible.
If you just type in two colors in terms of like a foreground and a background, and it'll definitely
tell you if it is accessible and there's a bunch of resources within Figma that we can take a look at
when we're creating our own color palette.
Those are some really helpful tips that you can use when you start creating and building off of your
color palettes.
We're going to jump into Figma next and do it ourselves.