Welcome back.
So in our last video, we talked about hierarchy and just style exploration for our cards.
We did some very interesting stuff in terms of our image over here, even though we kind of admitted
to ourselves that this may not be a scalable feature, we also talked a lot about just typography in
the hierarchy that we have within our card.
So we started working with what we wanted to be like in terms of what we wanted to be the main source
of like a user's attention.
So when I first come to this card, the first thing that pops to me is the actual price.
I mean, stand out much more in comparison to like the product, the product name.
We also added just some description content over here.
But as you can tell, there is a bunch of great hierarchy here in terms of color between something like
this, but also in terms of just size within elements.
So I have a larger card here.
The next thing I want to do is I want to think about like just user interests.
So that's a big part of this current application that we're building for habitual.
So we haven't really touched upon that a lot and that's what I want to do next.
So I'm just going to make sure that's affixed to the bottom.
Okay.
Let's just bring this just a little bit more.
So I'm kind of like, I'm digging this this style a bit.
We may not go with this color in the background, even though it's pretty interesting, but let's think
about some other elements that we could build.
I'm going to steal one of these elements, bring it out, and I'm going to have a section maybe called
like your interests.
And over here, I'm going to change that.
To like a more bolded.
Uh.
Well, did copy and I may have another that says like.
Seymour.
And I don't know if I have an underlined style.
So when I'm creating these textiles, I may have underlined styles, I may have all that kind of stuff.
I do have a link.
I think.
I do, yes.
Perfect.
I try to create like for different use cases.
I'm not too like strict, but I want to set some stuff up early just so it makes my life so easy.
And for that, I mean, we can maybe make that yellow.
I don't want to have our page exploding with color.
I want to keep things really simple because just the nature of our product.
Let's take a step back.
If we think about our product, there's a lot of images in terms of product images that could introduce
a bunch of color that we can't necessarily control.
And if we start splashing color everywhere, it'll muddy down the experience.
It'll make it really, really amateurish in a way, make it seem kind of childish.
So, you know, think about that when you're incorporating color.
I'm just kind of using like a dark yellow.
I know that's accessible.
So this shouldn't expand beyond here and this is fine where it currently is.
It's going to set the constraints on that and we're going to do is I'm just going to grip this in a
frame.
I like to keep things really neat while I'm designing, so that way I can reuse all of these types of
things.
So I've title and
link.
So this link is going to push them to like a new page, possibly
beautiful.
Next one I'm going to do is I'm going to think about like your interest.
So I want a little kind of feature that maybe it has little cards in there where users can just like
maybe swipe through.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create like a larger frame.
Okay.
And I'm just going to give it a radius of like ten pixels.
I want to give it a fill of, like, whites and an effect.
See, I have like I have shadows here built out as well, which is a great.
So we have large shadow.
Look at that.
Perfect.
So you can even make your effects shadows.
And we're going to get into all that much later.
This is just so it speeds up my workflow.
It'll speed up your workflow.
Don't get married to anything too early, but we'll have something we can work with.
So that's really subtle, really beautiful.
The way that card just kind of pops up just a little bit.
We can start thinking about, do we want our elements to be really flat like this or do we want to actually
start building cards that have actual shadow?
So I know I'm mixing and matching a bit here and that's totally fine.
I mean, this is totally about exploring what our options are, but I want to start thinking about what
cards can look like as well.
Like these types of cards.
It could translate to me building out this card differently in the future.
Okay, so what I'm going to do here is I'm going to give this an actual layout grid.
I don't think I have a layout grid for this, so I'm just going to create one from scratch and I'm going
to go to columns and just give it like three.
Three simple columns will have a margin of 16 pixels and gutter 16.
Okay.
Perfect.
And I'm just going to steal this.
Bring it into my frame.
So this can be like a little navigation that we can build.
So we have gaming.
I know we're kind of just defaulting to stuff like that, but it really helps.
Just to think about the different types of options we can have.
So if I think about this as a container, it can have multiple things like that.
Maybe tech is one of them.
Travel?
I don't know.
I'm just kind of spitballing here and what I'm going to do is I'm going to actually make this a frame
and call this like my nav, and we can do auto layout on it and we can space it by like 48 pixels so
we can have like a carousel thing going on here.
Like, I can have another one that bleeds off, as you can tell.
Like I have a clipping content, so anything that bleeds off, it will show up.
So I have education.
So this is fine for just like a dynamic nav that we can swipe through.
We're going to make a line just to let the user know that, hey, you were on this line.
Sorry, this section.
Och.
And what we're going to do next is we're actually going to have some product images in here possibly.
Whoops.
That was too large.
So, you know, I'm probably just going to take this.
Make a copy of that.
Bring it into here.
Just to show you what it could look like.
So we're starting to think about like just like style from the perspective, just different types of
styles like we have like this full image instead of this.
And I'm going to start to see like, you know, what do I like more?
What's something that I should probably take into account?
So we've been going with like price as the larger.
The larger element and we can stick with that.
I guess the more prominent element.
So we have product name.
What I'm going to do is I am going to just.
So.
Perfect.
And I'm just going to make sure that's there and this is not going to bleed be on that.
So this is going to be a frame.
I know there's a lot of frames, right?
And that's just so we keep things really clean and it helps us as we build fidelity, we can easily
edit all these different types of things.
Like once we start building our A design system, we can start thinking more about like, Oh, what
are the different types of elements we need?
What are the sizes?
Oh, I have this already built within a frame, so I can just pull this from that and just reuse and
make a much more consistent design.
So we got product details.
Beautiful.
Let's make that auto layout.
I mean, I like using auto layout.
You don't need to use all the layout.
Like in this case, we can probably get away with just, like, zero.
Um.
Okay, what else do we have here?
So we can even make this a frame?
We don't have to make it out of layout because it is adhering to our larger frames layout grid.
We can just call this x small card.
So we're starting to see like the details.
And I'm not having a description over here because it's way too small.
If there is a scale, then I have to think about what that looks like as well on this card.
So making sure this is centered.
This will be only affected by the left and this should only be affected by the right.
So if I start to move this.
Oops.
Interesting.
That's just because of the auto layout.
So that's another thing, although isn't necessarily responsive.
So keep that in mind.
I'm not worried because I'm using a mobile only.
So 16 pixels, perfect spacing.
And now we can actually start spacing the whole thing.
We can use auto oil for this whole thing if we wanted to.
So I'm actually going to.
To that.
I'm not going to actually use auto layout, but.
If I go up here and I hold a shift and down, I'm going to move in increments of four.
And I can just.
Easily position this so we have enough space.
Okay, so I'm going to turn off my grid because I can't really see what I've been doing.
So we're going to create hierarchy within this, this level of the that.
And as you can tell, like we started to create something really interesting here, like maybe this
is like a your interest card.
And what happens here is that for each of your interests, they'll provide like the top three products,
so you can just swipe through.
So very interesting feature that we built and I'm starting to like this kind of exploration in terms
of very nice, subtle shadow of the card.
I may actually go back to this card and update that.
This probably needs like maybe a light stroke.
What we can do here is just add that.
Um.
Perfect.
And maybe we can even think about, like, what the background could look like.
I mean, right now, it's standard white.
What happens if I just add, like, a light grey like that?
Things look a little differently.
What happens if I, like, add like a gradient?
So different things to think about.
I think White's perfectly fine right now, and that's how you create, like, just a little feature
from scratch, but also just kind of building upon your style exploration that we have here.
We can start seeing, okay, this may work.
I actually may like these images.
This is the right amount of hierarchy and I'll probably go back and test with users on this to see if
this interaction makes sense.
Like, are they swiping on the whole card?
Are they swiping on these little, little things?
And then have what is this interaction look like?
Is it confusing for them?
But that's how you kind of start to build that level of fidelity.
We're going to keep on doing that in our next video.