Hey, everyone, and welcome back.
We're going to be talking about how do you pick a typeface?
But the first thing that comes to mind when I'm thinking about picking at typeface is the emotion of
type.
Now, that may seem like a weird way to think about typefaces because, you know, typefaces kind of
feel, but they definitely do have their own mood or personality.
Now, the mood of a typeface is in a very important part about how it should be used.
You'll notice that some different typefaces have strikingly different moods.
Some typefaces are very formal or traditional.
Others seem more light and modern.
And a lot has to do with the way that that typeface has been designed.
You know, sometimes it could be that there's a lot of contrast within that typeface like we saw before,
or sometimes typefaces just have really distinct moods like we've seen in some display typefaces.
For example, let's think about times in your Roman.
It's pretty much always a traditional font, and some typefaces are a little bit more transcendent,
and they can pretty much convey almost any mood.
And when I think about that, I think about Helvetica.
So when I'm looking for typefaces for a specific brand or purpose, I think about how it could represent
that best.
Some typefaces could be perfectly suited for a fintech company or a bakery, or like the Swedish furniture
company over here that we just came up with before.
Typefaces can really help to represent and reinforce the voice of a brand.
Now let's see how we can choose our own typeface based off of mood.
In a couple of different scenarios.
We're going to jump right into the figma in our next lesson.