Hey, and welcome back.
Today, we're going to be using Figma to create our very own grid.
Figma is a pretty powerful and flexible tool when you're working with grids and there's so much you
can do because of the way you can nest frames and styles and constraints.
So let's jump in so I can show you what we can do here.
So let's utilize the frame.
Now, this is super cool.
We're going to create our own grid with a base unit of six.
So we're keeping our base unit in mind at all times.
So I'm going to press F and over here I have a bunch of grids I can choose from and I'm just going to
pick a standard grid.
This one looks good.
I've got a MacBook right there.
And let's just name it.
So command are for quick shortcut.
So.
Ah.
Love it.
Very original name.
Now, what we're going to do is we're going to select our frame and we're going to go over here and
we're going to go to live grid press the plus sign.
And automatically, when you press the plus sign, you get this grid based off of ten pixels.
If you zoom in there, ten pixels.
Now, we don't want to use this.
What we do want to use this.
We want to go over to here and we want to select columns.
There we go.
Now, here we can kind of set the amount of columns, the gutters, the margin, any other types of
settings that you really want.
You can make your grid blue, make it whatever color you want.
Typically, red is what I set it to.
It's helpful if you have other grids laying on top of each other.
What we're going to do is we're going to set the number of columns to 12.
Let's just exit out of that.
So here we go.
We've got 12 columns here.
We're going to set the gutter to 16 and the margin to 16, and we're going to keep this to stretch.
So that way it stretches when we move it.
Perfect.
There's our grid.
Let's take a look.
See, it stretches as we move.
It does look confusing.
There you go.
Now, another cool thing is that in Figma, we can start to apply grids even to frames within our layout.
So that means we can apply it not only to the main frame that dictates our screen size, but we'll be
able to apply it to individual containers or even like components like UI elements.
So let's make a card element.
So I'm going to do is I'm going to press F for another frame.
Make this right here.
And what I'm going to do is the same exact thing.
I'm going to create a little grid.
So go over here, select columns.
And this is a good case where you would want to probably change the color because it gets a little confusing.
Sometimes I like to even like make the opacity just a little bit darker.
So I have a set of 20 there.
Now, this would be a container and you could set it to whatever you'd like.
Typically, you don't want to have 12 columns on this.
But.
There we go.
And we can set like even a margin of 16 if we wanted to.
But let's scale down the amount of columns we have.
So over here we have four.
I think that's that's okay for now.
Like I said, nothing's really set in stone but set that grid.
So there's our grid.
It's on our elements over here.
You can see it's attached to that grid.
Now, this is pretty cool, right?
Like you could create cards and those cards could be really uniform in style based off of your grid
with integrate.
And they'll be able to scale.
Now.
Oh, see, it's not fluid.
And let's get into constraints and I'll teach you how that works.
So now they're sitting on the grid.
Now the constraints are much more interesting.
So you remember, like when we were trying to do fluid layouts, like we were just doing right now and
things weren't working as we expected to or as we saw before.
Now, Figma allows you to apply a thing called constraints to a frame.
Let's look this frame over here.
Perfect.
And these are constraints on the right side.
This will help you control hung element resizes in relation to the actual parent frame.
So this is our parent frame and this is going to resize in relation to that.
So this card element, what we're going to do is we're going to just set, we're going to shift and
click on here and you'll see that it's left and right now.
So that means that when I resize my parent frame, it's going to change with that just so you can better
see it.
What we're going to do is we're just going to set that to Gray and we're going to you can turn off grids
by pressing for Mac users control g.
So I'm going to take off that grid.
I'm going to create these ones and give them a fill.
I could just do something like that.
So this one is the one with the constraints.
These ones do not have constraints.
And you'll notice that that stays perfectly on our grid while the others don't.
You can even do this for the top and bottom as well.
So you'll notice that if I'm going to do this, this will scale top to bottom with my parent frame.
The others won't do that.
They'll only move with the top because the constraint they have is top and left, and they'll only move
with the left because that is what the that is what the constraint is set to.
So applying these constraints allow us to maintain a fixed layout based off of our columns and gutters.
Please, for the sake of your own sanity, you should save your grids as styles.
That way, we aren't constantly repeating ourselves when we create a new frame.
Also, it keeps things neat in one place.
So when you need to apply it to a frame, you just select a style easily like this.
This is where you would select your style.
We don't have any styles set here, and let's just go and create one quick.
So let's just delete these cards.
This is our 12th column Standard Grid.
And what we're going to do is we're going to click that style button.
We are going to click Create a Style and we're going to name it.
Naming conventions and Figma are really cool as well.
So what we're going to do here is this is how you would set and break up your grid styles.
I'm going to just write layout grid and I'm going to separate it like that.
And the actual name of the grid, I'm going to call it my 12 colors and I'm going to create that style.
There it is.
And you saw that title that I gave.
It is Layout Grid.
We can even create another grid here.
Or create a baseline grid.
So that's an auto to the top.
And like I said, I like using a four pixel grid here, no offset and the gutters will be four and you
can combine grids.
I can create another column grid on top of this.
So set my margin to 16, set my gutter to 16 pixels if you want.
You can set the colour just to differentiate between both of them and you can see these two as a style
as well.
Right there.
And we can just name these combined and we can call it 12 call layout and four pixel baseline and there
we go.
So they're under combined and you can name them any which way you want.
We'll get into that much more later.
But this is just a perfect way to create a new frame.
Go into my layout grid, apply a style.
Change styles easily.
So please do that for your own sanity.
It will help you in the future.
Just kind of not have to recreate the wheel over and over again because it's not really fun creating
the grid, but just to apply it easily to your layout.
And another great thing is, if I want to edit that grid, I can do so.
I can go right here, edit the colors, and it's going to edit everywhere else.
So what you do is you just press this, you click on to this edit style section and you can edit it.
You can even give it a description like really awesome grid.
And there you go.
That is how you make a grid and figma.