Hey, everyone, welcome back.
So the last thing I want to talk about, really, is that what happens when you have your content written,
you have the imagery picked out, like, what do you do?
Like, you know, how to code?
Do you want some website builder to really help you?
And I'm going to give you the rundown a couple of different options that you can go through when actually
posting your portfolio website.
So last video we talked about Ryan Scott and his kind of like case studies and they're really thorough,
they're really beautiful.
I love them and I can see that like this.
This person has a lot of experience.
They know what they're talking about when it comes to just like coming up with thoughtful solutions.
Now, they've actually used Squarespace to build a website.
They haven't coded it themselves.
It's very simple.
So they've used Squarespace.
So you can tell by that little icon up there.
And Squarespace is a great way for you to just come up with a quick design template and just get it
live really quickly without worrying about it being responsive, without worrying about coding, without
worrying about all that kind of fuss.
Now, I view Squarespace in the past.
I don't anymore, but I would definitely recommend it to somebody who just wants to get something up
and running.
They don't want to fiddle with code.
You can if you want to, but they provide beautiful templates for you to just showcase like your work
really, really easily and make it look beautiful.
Now they have their own way of hosting websites, so you don't even have to worry about that as well.
They have, like I said, a bunch of different templates.
So if we go through kind of their template over here, we can just.
Like pick.
Different types of things that we may want over here.
So design.
Showcase work and expertise.
Right now, where are you in your process?
So I think I'm I'm just going to replace my site with one from Squarespace.
Here are the different types of kind of portfolio based sites that they offer.
And all of them are nice.
Like this one is really nice.
Let's choose this one.
So let's a preview, Nolan, and you can see what it looks like.
So we have an artwork section.
Very easy, nice little animation.
So I'm going to click one.
And really it's just really easy to kind of place and drop content into something like Squarespace once
again, like it's already responsive outside of the box.
It's actually kind of looks like my site, which is really funny, but I would definitely recommend
something like Squarespace for people who don't want to fiddle with anything or any problems with code
and stuff like that.
And it's really nice and aesthetically pleasing right out of the box.
So that is one option, Squarespace.
There are other options similar to Squarespace, like WordPress and stuff like that.
But I digress.
I think Squarespace is probably one of the better options out there just for out of the box functionality.
Next is something like GitHub pages.
So this is what I use.
I've coded my own website and I just hosted on GitHub and I've turned that repository into an actual
website.
So that's what GitHub pages does.
So you can host it there for free.
It's just really, really easy.
A lot of times people have trouble with like, where do I host my website?
Where do I like access all my files if I want to kind of redesign it or like update it and stuff like
that.
And you know, the thing about GitHub pages, like if you're not constantly coding and like if you're
not in that realm, which I'm not anymore, like I haven't really updated my portfolio website in some
time and I may actually switch back to something like Squarespace just for the, the actual ease of
use.
But in this case, GitHub pages is really great if you're already integrated with like the GitHub ecosystem
and you've already familiar with it and you can easily just kind of upload all your files there and
create a public website and it will automatically be hosted.
So easy way to do that.
And you can also like easily download those files and run them in your terminal and use whatever code
editor or text editor that you have, whether that be something like Sublime or Adam, it doesn't matter.
I mean, you can just easily edit and then push once again to that repository and have it update and
be live.
So if you're into that, if you want a more tactile approach to building your website, this is what
I would definitely use.
But like I said, if you don't want that, you don't want the fuss, go with something like Squarespace
where you can just automatically get your website and your portfolio up and running easily.
So that's how I would approach getting your website up and running really quickly.
And yeah, go ahead, go out there.
And remember I said about content like you don't need any projects, only several and build some beautiful
case studies and beautiful websites for potential employers and just for colleagues to kind of look
at and give you some feedback.