Hey, everyone, welcome back.
So what I want to do is I want to start creating some screens for our product, which is habitual.
So we went through the process of like sketching some ideas out.
We also started sketching like user flows.
We started like way back when we were sketching, we were thinking already about let's find it some
navigation trees and how certain things are connected.
And I really want to start thinking about our homepage in much more detail.
So this is our homepage.
We're definitely going to have a search.
We're going to have something around, like shopping interests and habits.
Republicans have a place for them to get to categories, maybe deals we have like a navigation, which
is like wishlist orders profile.
We have the cart as well and we have a way to log in or sign up.
So let's jump right in and start thinking about what this could look like.
So I'm going to just create a frame.
I'm going to press F and I'm going to just select that and I'm going to call this home page perfect.
So the easiest way to start is like, let's take a look at our sketches and where we kind of left off.
So for our home page, we can tell like we were thinking about like having some text at the top and
be like a profile.
We can see like we could start thinking about the navigation as well.
We have some images there.
Those are some rough sketches.
So we do know that we were thinking about a search there.
I know at some point we were thinking also.
About search in the navigation.
I don't know where that is.
I think it's here somewhere.
Anyways, we start thinking much more in terms of screen states.
So we have like a save icon.
We have the name, we have price, maybe some categories, possibly looks like alternate funnels.
They can get into these maybe categories, maybe interests, other things.
Okay, so this definitely gives us a lot to work with and I'm going to start building based off of my
sketches like we don't need to match them directly, but I think they'll allow us to have a good starting
off point.
So.
Let's get started.
So the first thing I'd like to do with my sketches and my wireframes is start building out some of the
most basic things, like navigations and stuff like that.
So I'm actually just going to go to my assets tab.
I'm going to go up to UI elements and let's see where it is, navigation and containers.
And just like that, we have like a navigation bar.
So I think we should kind of start thinking a little differently.
Maybe let's go to our assets and icon social.
That's okay.
Let's just replace that nicely.
So we've got icons, we have social, heart filled.
Perfect.
There we go.
Easy.
Let's think about profile.
I know we said like we could have orders down here and that's very possible.
I was thinking about that, but we should probably test some different options as well.
We shouldn't necessarily just like stick.
To just one.
There's a count.
That was a good guess.
And icons.
Uh.
What else do we have here?
Shopping, maybe.
Yeah.
Cart.
There you go.
Okay, cool.
So there you go.
We have our very own navigation, and we can just like.
Just to show that we are on the home page.
Okay.
And what I want to start doing is actually.
Let's see.
We got here.
We got a search.
There we go.
So we have our search up here.
Third is good.
And I think we should probably have some text, so we could just start typing some text in here.
So we have like maybe like a big hello.
You know, some apps are really, really inviting like that and I kind of like that.
I mean, I think we should kind of test our messaging as well so we can go into here in our font styles.
Let's see how big some of these are.
Ooh, that's way too big.
So let's just go down here.
I think that's fine.
Perfect.
Let's zoom in.
Okay.
So I'm going to grab some more and I'm just going to write.
We have some recommendations.
Oops.
For you.
Okay.
So that's just going to trail off and we're just going to have to bring that in and let's set that to
like 16 regular.
Okay.
That's going to work for now.
So we're starting to build out a bit here.
Like I said, it's kind of like sketching, too.
I mean, we're being a little bit more thoughtful about the type of content we have.
We're also thinking much more about, like, the hierarchy of the information.
So I know that I really want search to be prominent in some way.
So for now, I'm going to bring it up here and see how it performs when I test it with users.
I'm also going to just hierarchy in terms of our copy as well.
It's just like a big hello, like a welcome and then some recommendations.
Maybe this could lead into some images or like some interest based stuff just for you.
I can bring that in just a little bit.
So just auto with brings it right to the width of the content.
I like using that.
Okay.
So we got a size 16.
We can do regular.
Let's do size 16.
Bold.
And right now, look, I'm not thinking too much about style.
I just want to kind of get everything on the page.
Then we'll refine.
Design has a very iterative process, and you're not going to get everything right in the first go.
100%.
I will bet on that.
And that's okay.
I mean, it's all about just like learning, building, learning, building and learning over and over
until you get it right.
And you're definitely not going to get it right on the first try.
And that's okay.
So what do we got here?
Content?
No, we don't need that.
Menus.
Menu's option.
Chips.
Maybe we'll switch up image.
Perfect.
Look at that.
So we have an image placeholder.
You know, we actually may want to bring in a grid here, so I'm going to bring in a grid because it's
going to help me lay things out a bit more.
So what have we got here?
We got six.
Bring it to eight.
The margin can be 24.
The gutter can be 24.
And don't worry, we are going to learn all about grids and how awesome they are.
But they're going to really help us.
To determine how we kind of lay things out.
Perfect.
Okay.
There you go.
So we may have, like, a larger image.
I was thinking.
Hmm.
Something like that.
I like just hitting them with something really nice right away.
To toggle your grids.
If you're using them right away, we will get into it at a later lesson.
But Control G.
Is really your friend here.
So control g just to hide and show.
Okay.
So we're just going to duplicate that.
And so when I'm thinking about the type of content I'm going to need for each product image, I'm thinking
about like the product name.
We don't need that to be bold.
It could just be like regular 16 pixels.
I'm also thinking about price.
So we could just write like $25.
Maybe this is bold.
I know people like to read a name first, but price is like one of the bigger motivators.
So we can do like a size 16 bold.
And like, you can tell, like, I'm whipping through this pretty quickly.
And maybe we have.
Some information.
I like that.
Okay.
So we got a size of 14 regular plug ins.
I like to use Lorem ipsum.
It's just a plug in.
It's really great.
One sentence is probably more than enough.
So one sentence, maybe we'll bring that down to 12 pixels because that's taking up a lot of screen
real estate.
Let's bring that down.
Okay.
So.
Let's just space things out just a little better.
So we got something here, and I'm just going to call this large product.
Large product card.
So now we definitely have.
We have to you'll notice that that just kind of sticks on that grid, which is great.
And it's using a base unit of eight pixels.
So it's just going to move in increments of eight.
We'll get into the reasoning for that.
But nice.
That looks really clean.
What else should we have here?
We should definitely have categories as well.
Let's think about those deals and categories.
So deals are pretty big.
Oops, I actually forgot something.
Let's think about.
We also wanted like a heart.
So let's just bring that.
I'm going to search for heart icon.
Perfect and.
Let's just make that white.
Huh?
And like I said, I mean, use something to make your work flow much more quicker, much more easier.
I mean, we're not worried about being perfect right now.
We're just worried about making sure we can get these designs kind of done, get them into a place where
we can start testing with them.
Because you will most likely throw these designs out.
It's just the nature.
Of designing wireframes.
Okay, that's good enough.
Cool.
So we have the product image, and as you can tell, we have like the name, we have the amounts.
We can just duplicate this here.
We're going to fix this to the bottom.
And we're going to brag this over.
And yeah, so we can start thinking more about just the type of content we'll have for maybe smaller
images as well.
Make sure that's inside.
Okay, cool.
I want to start thinking about smaller images to.
So if I turn on my grid again, it's going to help me figure out what is the perfect size.
So yes, it's definitely going to have a product name.
We're going to group this and you can actually start creating your own little components here, your
reusable patterns.
So I'll make this a small product card.
And just to speed up your workflow if you plan to use these throughout your entire app.
So we got that.
You can even bring that in just a bit.
Cool.
There we go.
So, like, we already have, like, deals laid out.
And what else is next?
And next, I do want to have something different.
I want to have categories.
Okay.
So what we're going to do is we're just going to grab assets over here.
Grab a card.
Cool.
And I like the idea of letting them kind of fall a bit off of the page and like letting the user scroll
horizontally.
So we can definitely do that.
We can definitely prototype with that.
Okay.
You just call this, like, tech or something.
Let's do, like, a size 14 bolt.
Perfect.
When you're creating these wireframes, remember, just constantly reference your notes, reference
your sketches, your user flows.
I mean, you shouldn't be going into like something like this blind.
And I think that's like that's a good starting point, 100%.
I mean, that's definitely enough to kind of get us testing.
We have a categories here.
We have our A navigation that we can use.
We definitely have like deals and we do have something around like our interests and stuff like that.
But I do think we're going to need to improve on this.
Like maybe this can stay, but maybe down here, you know, maybe deals is deprioritized or it's not.
To who?
Hi.
In terms of like the order of hierarchy.
So, you know, there's different things we're definitely going to figure out while we test.
And you shouldn't necessarily just design once and be okay with it, validate your assumptions, go
out, just ask people questions, talk to your client.
Does this necessarily, like fulfill the goals?
Will users actually?
Be enticed to start clicking on certain things.
Does this make you seem like a more personalized shopping experience?
I don't know.
I don't honestly know just yet.
And that's fine.
I mean, we are going to create many variations and you should be doing that, too.
Don't just settle on one.
So this is the home page that I've just wireframe too really quickly using all those components, and
you should definitely give it a try yourselves.
You don't need to copy exactly what I did, but go ahead and try to think about other ways that you
can incorporate special interests or like recommendations.
Think about ways that you can get users like into our funnel in terms of like purchasing.
I know we kind of have like shopping interests and habits over there.
We kind of knocked everything off in one way or another.
And you should really think about.
I know the goal of this project is really to kind of drive the point home of a more personalized shopping
experience.
So come up with your own feature.
Think about different ways you can kind of achieve that goal.
And that's it for our home page.
In our next video, we're going to figure out what else to build with our wireframes.