Hey, everyone, and welcome back.
So I often get the question, how do I pick a typeface for my project?
And that's a very good question.
I mean, we always face this dilemma when starting a project that doesn't necessarily have typeface
chosen.
Sometimes a client will come to you with an established brand guideline, with established typeface
guidelines, and, you know, sometimes they're okay, and that's an optimal scenario.
Sometimes they aren't necessarily optimized for web.
Sometimes the typefaces don't have enough variance, and they really stop you from creating enough contrast
on the screen.
And, you know, they may not be good for mobile and whatever type of application or product you're
trying to build.
That does happen.
And I feel like sometimes you just need to sit down with your client and have a real good discussion
on what you can do to extend that type family or extend that type system.
Another scenario is often people come to you with just one typeface and it happens often.
Sometimes that typeface is very good.
It has a lot of styles and it just doesn't suit the tone of their product or their company or their
organization.
So let's come up with a little, little fake organization over here.
So so if we call something like the Phillips.
Foundation.
So I did have a client come up to me one time and they were a charity and we were building a new website
for them.
And their font was monserrat.
Don't get me wrong, I love this font.
But to be your only typeface.
I mean, even if the font family is huge, let's take a look at this.
So many different styles.
It doesn't necessarily mean that it's going to suit what you're trying to achieve.
So let's just.
We're going to create a quick logo over here.
So.
I'll use similar colours to their brand.
They had this, like, yellow, like that and like a teal.
So we'll just grab like a teal over here.
Okay.
Cool.
So this is their logo.
Looks cool, right?
Not really.
I mean, it's quick, but so we have the logo for them and we noticed that OC there are type system
isn't necessarily the best they may have like a headline.
They may have some body copy.
And what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to lie plugins and grab Lorem ipsum.
We'll do this really quick.
So we have one paragraph.
That is huge.
So it's just going to go down in size just like 16.
And we are going to go to regular and to make sure the line is around 150%.
So, you know, they may have a headline like that.
They may have like other.
Types of things like a button.
So let's just create a quick button.
We're going to make that a frame.
And then what we're going to do here is going to go to auto layout.
And we're going to we're doing this really quickly, just so I can show you what this kind of looks
like.
So a 48 pixel button in height is good.
So you can see the frame over there.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to give it a border radius of five pixels.
Still can't see anything.
The selection colors is the text.
So I'm going to change that to White and I'm going to turn this on the fill and make it black.
And we can even, like use.
You can use the color.
We can make a little darker.
And let's make that typeface bold.
Too bold.
Okay.
So you may get, like, something like this and for like a foundation that wants to really evoke a sense
of, like, tradition.
I mean, something like this is just it's a good font, but it's just not enough.
So what I usually do is the first step is to kind of break this out a bit.
So I start thinking the headline can be like, What can you do to help?
So maybe this is like a section on their website.
And I think maybe that's one of the main titles and I may bump that up a bit to like 40 pixels and then
I may have like a subheadline and I could be like charity.
Our donations.
I may keep that in all caps.
What I'm trying to do here is create a lot more variance in the types of like headlines.
We have body copy just to see if there's enough variance in here that would actually like match the
tone of the brand.
So what I'll do here is I'll just create a little more letter spacing.
I may bump this down to like 24 pixels.
You know, start matching the brand colors, maybe using those a little bit more could help.
And, you know, they can.
They definitely can.
So what I'm going to do here, I'm just going to keep on extending this out because we're going to we're
going to work here.
So we have learned more.
But in.
Let's stop moving.
There we go.
I may grab, like, a pillow quote.
Maybe this is like a.
Medium metallic, and this can be pumped up to like 24 pixels.
It's all about experimentation.
In the end, you really want to kind of have fun with it, try to figure out like different ways you
can create a little bit more visual interest.
You know, that's starting to work.
It's not looking too bad at all, but I don't think it's enough at this point.
Right now.
What I would do is I would go kind of searching for different fonts.
And when I think about charities and when I think about different types of organizations that have been
around for so long, I start thinking about like the different types of typefaces that would really,
you know, capture that.
So I'm going to do is I'm just going to copy this and I'm going to start thinking about maybe some serif
typefaces.
So one serif typeface that I like a lot is called Palladino.
So let me grab like a serif typeface like that.
And all of a sudden, you know, it starts to have a little bit of a different feel, maybe something
else.
Let's search for it all the way.
Allegra is a really nice one.
A really nice Google font.
So we're just going to search all the way up.
All the way up.
What do we got here?
We're getting closer.
Okay.
There it is.
So, like, this is nice.
And, you know, it's it's a little bit modern.
Which is totally fine.
100%.
Maybe that's not enough.
Line height.
But the goal here is to start creating a little bit more contrast, but also introducing another type
pairing that could work really well with something like Montserrat.
I think this is still fine.
We could even bump that down just a bit.
Over here.
We can also apply that the.
That typeface.
Like, look at that.
And all of a sudden, like we start thinking about this now looks like an organization that has more
history, organization that's much more traditional, you know, not too traditional.
It still has some modern elements to it.
So when I approach like type pairings like that, I'm really thinking about the brand.
I'm always going back to that and like the utility of the typeface and how they work together.
Is there enough visual contrast here?
Another test I'd like to do is I like to use the squint test, I call it.
So I'll just squint very, very hard and I'll look and I'll start seeing if if everything starts to
blur together and then make adjustments based off of that.
So over here we kind of start to build a little bit of a type system.
We start to see that, okay, this may be like our body copy, this may be like our sub headlines,
our main headlines.
This will be like a quote or button text and you just keep going based off of what you know, based
off of the wireframes you created, based off of the like the sitemap that you created and all the different
type of content that you believe will be on the product that you're creating.
So that's one way to handle a scenario where a client comes to you and they may only have one typeface
to work with.
We went from something like this.
To something like this fairly quickly.
And I think if we are going for a sense of tradition, if we were going for to match that the tone of
the brand and what they stand for, then something like this probably works a bit better.
When you come into that scenario, remember to just talk with your client, explore all your options,
like go through.
Go through the process of building, trying to work with what they have and to see if that typeface
can work.
Is it versatile?
Does it match the tone of the brand?
And then, you know, explore beyond, you know, maybe this isn't the right font for here.
Maybe it's like a medium.
Maybe it's a different font altogether.
Those are the types of things that you can do to really help your clients out in terms of picking typefaces
for them.