Welcome back.
So we are on step four, which is dissecting that pattern.
Now, the last step, like I said, dissect the pattern.
In other words, we need to analyze other websites that use social login and basically we can use that
to customize our modifying the pattern for our needs.
Let's take a look over here.
So we have Etsy again, and I'm just going to add another item to our cart.
What do I need to do here?
Let's actually pick another item.
Okay.
Let's just pick a quick item here.
Perfect.
So we're just going to pick that OC so we're going to add that to our basket.
And I really like how it pushes us right to checkout really quickly.
I kind of really like the PayPal and how that's very up front.
So for users that do have PayPal, so I really like that about this, this type of checkout process.
So if we pay with PayPal, we can automatically jump right in.
But if we don't want to do that and if users don't have the account, which is very convenient, so
if they want to use something like American Express, Visa or MasterCard, they can just go proceed
to checkout.
And they're right here.
And the great thing is they are automatically hovered over.
I mean, like the input for the sign in is automatically in-focus, which is great, but the primary
action is to continue as a guest or to log in socially, which is really, really great.
I think this kind of gives you like the best of both worlds.
It gives you the ability to use PayPal and just check out quickly with that.
But also it gives you the ability to check out as a guest sign in if you do have an account really easily
and also potentially sign in or sign up with like a social media platform.
So I think this is a really, really strong design pattern that they've built and they've kind of modified
a bit.
Let's take a look at Cb2.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to pick something.
Here.
We got some very, very overpriced furniture.
Okay.
So I'm going to pick this lovely sofa, going to add that to my cart and that's really nice.
It brings it right up so I can kind of like continue shopping or checkout.
Now, I like that better than how Etsy just throws you right into the checkout page.
I don't know if I'm going to be done shopping and I don't like how they kind of redirected me right
to that shopping basket over here.
So like they allow you to kind of keep shopping and go back, but this allows you to kind of keep your
process or your scroll position on the page if I just remove this.
So it's really easy to kind of get back.
So I kind of like that implementation.
So let's take a look at our car over here.
And they have something very similar, actually.
They have the ability to check out with PayPal right away.
I like that.
They allow you to apply a promotional code right off the bat.
And if I want to check out now, this is very interesting.
So they kind of have like a sidebar with the guest checkout, the returning customers section and this
is actually very similar and signing in with Google sign in and check out so you can so they have something
very similar, but they're limited the options to just Google here, which I think is I'm not sure if
that's the best pattern to use, but.
No, it may it may work.
So let's take a look at guest check out.
So yeah, checco is a three step process.
I do like how they've handled this though.
So they allow you to see what that process looks like.
You're going to have to enter like shipping and gift options.
So like your name, your street address in Canada would be your postal code town, city, province and
phone number.
And like I said, like when users go through your guest checkout, they're going to have to be there
and have to constantly do that process over again.
So I don't think that's the smartest way.
They do have PayPal, so you can click PayPal and just automatically check out through there.
And like I said, they do have.
So this is very interesting.
So if I click checkout now, again, it's bringing me to guess checkout and it won't let me go back,
which is very interesting.
So I think I'm personally going to stick with the Etsy pattern.
Like I'm going to tweak it for my visual style.
But I think I like the idea of giving them the up front ability to distinguish how they plan to pay
and how they want to sign out.
Because, I mean, if they have a PayPal account, everything's kind of handled for you in one shot.
But if they don't, they give you three other options.
So that's essentially how I dissect the patterns.
I take a look at very similar options.
I take a look at options that do like employ something like a social login, especially for like e-commerce
or something like this.
So in this case, like I took a look at like Cb2 Canada and I found that they are very similar, but
this one behaves much differently than Etsy's.
And for that reason, like I would probably follow Etsy's and you know, I can keep something from Cb2
here.
Like, you know, when you add something to the cart, it doesn't necessarily take a full screen and
put you in like a cart screen.
But I can take a look and analyze if each pattern which one is going to be best for my needs.
So when you're trying to find a design pattern, I mean, go through that same process, figure out
what your problem is, figure out the different types of websites that like are your competitors that
are very similar to you, that have some sort of pattern that solve the similar issue.
Step three, jump right in and figure out which pattern is going to be right for you and then dig a
little bit deeper and find websites that all employ that kind of similar pattern that you actually think
is best for you and figure out which one is going to be best.
And that's how you pick a design pattern.