And welcome back.
We left off with our really quick website that we built using Bootstrap.
But I want to show you one thing that I've kept from you, and that is the layout feature in Bootstrap.
And this was the primary reason that Bootstrap was so popular because layout was so difficult and we
didn't have Flexbox back in the day.
Bootstrap allowed us to create very responsive websites using these ideas of columns.
To show you what I mean.
We're going to create our own column system.
We're going to go back to our website and I'm going to delete everything that we created so far.
In a save and refresh.
Everything's empty.
So in bootstrap, you can do something like this.
You always want to wrap everything in a container.
And again, if you go to the documentation.
They'll show you what to do, and we'll just grab the top once.
So let's just copy these.
Fix the indentation a bit.
There you go.
And if I refresh?
Well, we need to have a bit of a background so we can see them.
So I'm going to say column.
We'll do a background.
Color gray and the border will be two pixels.
Solid black.
Save.
And go back and refresh.
We have our borders.
Now, here's something interesting that you can do.
You can do a column, small six and then column small three.
Don't worry, I'll explain what that means.
I'm going to refresh and look at that.
The size of this.
Just got smaller.
And that is because Bootstrap has the idea of a grid system, and this grid system has 12 lines.
So six plus three is nine.
So it's saying that I want this column to have six spaces out of that 12 and this column to have three
spaces out of that 12.
So if we add another column.
And six plus three plus three is 12.
I'm going to say extra here.
I refresh.
You'll see that it fills in this gap.
What if I put in four here?
So that is 13, which is over 12?
Well, if I refresh, this goes down to the next level.
So you see how easy it is to control things in bootstrap.
I can also do something like column.
Extra small will do.
12 and then column.
Extra small six column.
Extra small six.
And actually we'll do.
Medium here.
Save.
Let's refresh and see what happens.
Whoa.
What this is saying, that if the size of the window is medium, then I want the whole 12 grid system
to the first diff and then six of the 12 to the second and then the extra one six.
So you can see here that that's medium.
But because we have these small properties in here, if I make it smaller, you can see that it resorts
down to the 634 grid.
Let's change this back to three so it looks better and show you that there's a few other sizes that
we can add.
You can see over here that we have grid options and we have small, medium, large and extra large.
So let's do large and see what happens.
So for large, I want to have everything on their own so we can do this.
And safe.
Let's refresh and see if we can guess what's about to happen.
I'm going to go from.
Medium to large.
Do you see that?
12, 12, 12.
So I want each diff to occupy 12 spaces, 12 grid systems, which is the full thing.
If I go to medium, I now occupy with the first 112.
The second one, six and six.
So they should be one after another.
And if I go down to even smaller.
The small will have six, three and three.
So this is how you can create really responsive websites.
And that was the biggest selling feature of bootstrap.
It was solving this really, really hard problem of making sure that our website looked good no matter
what the screen size.
So I want you to play around with the grid options here.
This is the hardest concept to grasp and bootstrap.
Once you've learned this, it's very, very easy to create websites extremely fast.
I'll see in the next one.
Bye bye.