Hey, everyone, and welcome back.
So I just want to kind of start to finish off filling up this page.
I'm going to start thinking about a couple of different like UI elements that maybe we, you know,
maybe we didn't think about too much.
So maybe let's start with thinking about so the profile we kind of remove different than NAV and I think,
you know, maybe we should have like a static, persistent, like avatar in the top.
So let's see where we are on our grid so we can start thinking about if we do have avatars, what do
they look like?
I'm going to use the plugin over here called Content Reel and I have this selected.
I'm just going to select an avatar and there we go.
We have our avatar that I just plops right in and that's pretty cool.
I mean, that's something to think about.
Do we need something like that?
Maybe.
Maybe not.
I don't know.
Maybe we need to rework our NAV a bit.
What about this?
I mean, what happens if people want to see more?
Do we have a title here and do we have another link?
Is that too much to kind of have that over and over again on a page maybe?
I don't know.
What we can do is we can start thinking about some alternatives.
So I'm going to do I'm actually going to create a large button.
And within that button I'm going to place within that frame, I'm going to place some text and I'm just
going to just say, discover more.
Like Maybe I'm here.
I'm also exploring different things, like just our language.
What type of language do we want to use?
Do we want to entice users like that?
Do we want to stay more standard?
Like just saying stuff like see more?
These are the types of questions you should be asking yourself.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm just going to make that like that.
I'm going to actually make this an auto layout.
So I switch at the vertical so I can adjust the width and that's fine.
The top, we want to make this like a 48 pixel, so we're just going to have to do a little bit of testing
to get it there.
So we got 48.
Hmm.
Let's roll with 48.
I think that's fine.
This needs to go in the middle, so we're just going to adjust that to the middle.
Let's make this reach the end of our.
Our grid.
So it's centered.
That looks good.
We don't need any space in between.
And we need a fill 100%.
We need a fill so we can start thinking about like buttons.
We have this kind of this yellow from our app.
Let's actually just grab that logo.
So we have this this yellow that we're using.
We're sticking very much with the branding, the color palette that we've kind of expanded upon.
I don't know if I'd like this teal that much.
It's making things look really kind of dull.
But let's just keep going and we will figure it out 100%.
We will figure it out.
So you'll notice how I've broken up my color styles and I'll get into that later.
But it just makes it easier when you kind of break it up by use.
Case I'll look background text.
Even if you're repeating the colors, you'll notice like I've repeat white a bunch.
So that way if I'm in a very complex component like this, I can easily just pick off like, what's
a UI color, what's a text color?
And if there's multiples, I just want to change the text color.
I can easily just find anything that says like UI or text and just change the base off of that.
I haven't been using that here.
It makes it really easy to go back and make some of those changes.
Okay.
So for color, I think white will be fine in terms of accessibility, I think like that's pretty good.
We'll need to test that for sure.
I'm sure this is not accessible.
So like I said, we'll just test.
But I'm kind of liking this nice orange button, like what happens if we kind of add an effect to it?
So what I like to do is I'll just create a copy over here, usually like this as well.
I'll just create a bunch of different copies of things and I'm starting to see like, okay, this is
where we're kind of going in terms of our exploration, just general hierarchy.
Like when you see things separated away from the page, let's just remove this image and you start to
kind of like, Oh, this is looking very interesting, and I can see if these little pieces can kind
of survive on their own.
Let me go back to this image here.
This needs to be refined a bit.
I can start seeing like just the general visual direction of my designs, much more easier than just
kind of viewing it in a page, one after the other, as they're kind of secluded to where you're viewing
them on the screen.
So I'm trying to make one like cohesive language.
We have a button here.
I really like the button a lot.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to add an effect.
Maybe this will work, so I have a default shadow.
So that's really nice.
So I'm starting to think like, okay, what happens when it's active?
What happens when somebody taps on it on desktop?
What happens is somebody hovers over it.
I'm trying to think about all these little micro interactions as well at this point.
Like, does somebody just click and the shadow kind of disappears, kind of like the buttons being pressed
to the bottom or maybe nothing happens.
I don't know.
So just something to think about to incorporate that early.
I kind of like the shadow.
We'll leave it for now.
We'll place that up there.
Let's also think about some secondary cards that we have here.
So right now we have a bunch of different elements.
We're starting to think about our typography structure.
We're starting to think about just cards, buttons, links, all of these different things, avatars.
We have navigation and icons and just the general style of icons.
And we've done this all just from the homepage.
Not every homepage is going to be like this, but I like to pick a page that has a bunch of or just
a variety of elements that I can start to build.
And actually it'll help me dictate what that visual style will be going forward.
So the last thing I really want to do here is I want to create some cards, maybe they're category cards.
I was thinking actually what I want to do is I just want to name that button.
So what I'm going to do is I'm actually going to create another frame, surprise, surprise, she's
going to call it card.
And what we can do here is we can start thinking about what this card could be.
So we have like a light grey.
I mean, we can use like secondary colours here.
I'm not entirely sure just yet, but what I'm going to do is I'm just going to.
Stealing from there.
And I'm going to start thinking about what these cards can be.
Shopping habits and interest.
Maybe another way for users to get into that kind of funnel.
Maybe that's just not large enough.
20 pixels looks good.
That's fine.
What I'm going to do is I need an icon.
So I'm going to actually first I'm going to create a circle within here, and that's going to be the
background I want to have like a Chevron.
A Right.
Chevron making it look like you can click on this and just making that look really apparent.
So let's just set the background to that to White and let's go and find a Chevron.
So you've got feather icons.
Do we have it under arrow?
I don't think so.
It's actually under Chevron.
Sometimes it's under Arrow.
So we're going to click that.
There it is.
Thank you.
And we can take this.
This frame here is perfect.
And we're going to plop it right there.
And we're actually going to make this another frame.
And we're just going to call this Chevron and that will link to another page.
Let's just change the color of that.
We could do something like a yellow.
Like that looks pretty interesting.
And we could also just kind of keep it like a dark like a dark block.
This can also be like just like a dark gray.
I don't necessarily know what's going to work, but I'm just trying a bunch of different options here.
Let's let's see what our grid looks like.
So we want to make this want to make this just a little smaller.
This needs to get on to our grid.
So we got four, four.
This also needs to think about this.
So if I actually.
I'm going to shift one too.
That's a pexels.
To 16.
Can shift control option and using arrow.
I'm going back the other way and I'm actually shrinking it.
So I've got 16 pixels and from here 100 and.
Trying to keep this very similar in height as well, kind of like a square.
So we're just going to
816.
So we got square here and there you go.
Like let's call this title.
Actually, it's already title perfect.
So we have a little card that is really nice.
And if we just copy that, we can start like making other cards based off of that.
So.
Another tip.
Today's trending items.
Perfect.
We can also, like, make this a different color.
Like it could be like that bronze.
I don't know what's going to work just yet, but I'm starting to create some interesting reusable cards
that I'm really liking.
Incoming.
Kind of like that.
It can be flash deals and this can be a white text.
Oops.
And that will be like a blue maybe.
I don't know.
I'm kind of I'm kind of using a bunch of colors here, but it's all about just exploring what may work.
So we got browse are categories like maybe this just throws them into the category screen instead of
just having a bunch of different categories out there.
But it also gives us a bunch of different options in terms of like like, you know, they can view flash
deals.
It doesn't need to muddy up that home screen.
They can be like the trending items.
They can get into like habits and shopping interests.
So, like, there you go.
Look, we're already creating a bunch of different UI elements, and, you know, I'm not sure if I'm
really, like, going to settle with something like this because I don't know if it suits the style
and just the general tone of the brand.
So I may just do a little bit of a pivot.
I need to think about that a bit more.
And you should definitely you should too, because this is your design as well, and you're going to
have to figure out what you think is best for you.
So just from the homepage, we have a lot of different typographic elements.
We have a large card, we have some smaller cards.
I think we need to find something in the middle, like maybe like a middle card that we may use in terms
of size.
We have just typographic hierarchy in terms of like the cards themselves.
And this is just only using one typeface and you can see the variation that we've created already.
It hasn't taken us a bunch of time.
We have an avatar over here, we have buttons, the links, and we have a navigation as well.
You know, pick a screen that you feel will give you a lot of different elements to work with.
That could be different for you.
It could be different from the home screen in the way you set it up and use that to kind of create those
reusable elements and we can even create them into components.
If you really settled on something and use that throughout your product over here because you can actually
use like those elements to create other elements with some variation.
Like I have buttons here that I've used.
I have different types of elements in terms of typography that can be reused, like in terms of the
product name and like just the size that I've used here can just be reused here.
So it's all about like figuring out what style you're kind of, you're liking, what's going to work
for the user, what's going to resonate from them.
But also, once you've settled, you need to actually think about reusability.
You don't want to create 100 different types of cards.
That's fine.
Like, I mean, if you have different slight variations, like a button in there or maybe like a link
or like some sort of, I don't know, some sort of price or pill like we have in ours.
Like just for an example, we have like just price changes that's going to happen regardless.
But think about reusability just so you can make your life and developers lives much more easier.
And plus, when a user is looking through an application and they see something or a style that is just
incredibly consistent, it makes that user experience so much more better if they're going to a new
page.
And every time they get to a new page, everything is entirely different, whether that be just hierarchy
in typography or even just use of color.
Something as simple as that could really just make a horrible experience for the user and it's just
incredibly jarring.
So think about that as well.
Yeah, that's it for visual design and just visual style and exploration.
So go out there and have some fun, experiment with typography, experiment with color, experiment
with all the different UI elements that you want to build.
And I'm sure there are many more pages to build from here.
Just take a look at our wireframes so you can have just so much fun doing that and figuring out which
ways you can kind of build just reusability and consistency within our product.
And that's it.