Let's do a really, really quick exercise just to get our hands dirty and get us excited about the course.
What we're going to do is build our first logo.
Now we have a whole section where we're going to create logos from scratch ourselves and learn what
the best practices are.
But just for now, I want us to have something created right away, and what we're going to do is create
our logo for the product that we want to build.
So in our case, if we want to build a shopping experience that beats Amazon, well then let's create
that.
If you have a logo that you want to do on your own for a different product, let's do that as well.
And what we're going to use is some online logo makers.
Again, this is just the first step.
Don't worry, we're going to get into the nitty gritty later.
But for now, I'm going to link to some resources after this video.
But as you can see here on zero two Mastery Audio, we have a resources page and at the very top we
have some free logo makers that we can use.
So there's four options here.
It doesn't really matter which one you pick.
I want you to click on one of these and create your own custom logo.
Now after this lecture, we're also going to include a bunch of design resources that we're going to
use throughout the course.
Just so you always have a reference and you can always get inspired as we're creating our product.